<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-204</num>
  <heading>Restrictions on the use of official vehicles.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, no officer or employee of the District may be provided with an official vehicle unless the officer or employee uses the vehicle only in the performance of the officer’s or employee’s official duties. For purposes of this subsection, the term “official duties” shall not include travel between the officer’s or employee’s residence and workplace; except in the case of (1) an officer or employee of the Metropolitan Police Department who resides in the District or is otherwise designated by the Chief of the Department; (2) at the discretion of the Fire Chief, an officer or employee of the D.C. Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department who resides in the District and is on call 24 hours a day; (3) the Mayor; (4) the Chairman of the Council; (5) at the discretion of the Chief Medical Examiner, an employee of the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner who resides in the District and is on call 24 hours a day; (6) at the discretion of the Director of the Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency, an officer or employee of the Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency who resides in the District and is on call 24 hours a day; and (7) at the discretion of the Director of the Department of Corrections, an officer or employee of the District of Columbia Department of Corrections who resides in the District and is on call 24 hours a day.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No officer or employee of the executive branch of the District government, except the Mayor, shall utilize the services of any District government employee for use as a chauffeur from residence to work or vice versa, unless such use is authorized first, in writing, by the Mayor. All such authorizations and the cost thereof shall be reported to the Council on a quarterly basis and made available on the Department of Public Works’ website.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No officer or employee of the executive branch of the District government, except the Mayor, shall utilize the services of any District  government employee for use as a chauffeur during the work day unless such use  is authorized in writing, by the appropriate agency head. All such  authorizations and the cost thereof, shall be reported to the Council on a quarterly basis and made available to the public on the Department of Public Works’ website.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>No District employee shall offer or accept, as a perquisite of employment in hiring or contract negotiation, an assigned chauffeur.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director shall make available on the Department of Public Works’ website an inventory of vehicles owned, leased, or otherwise controlled by the District government, or any of its entities, excluding vehicles falling under the guidelines of paragraph (4) of this subsection, as of the end of the fiscal year. The inventory shall be distributed to the Council and made available to the public on the Department of Public Works’ website by December 15 of each year. The inventory shall be completed annually for each fiscal year ending on September 30 and shall be distributed to the Council and made available to the public on the Department of Public Works’ website by December 15 of the next fiscal year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The inventory shall include the following for each vehicle:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The agency to which it is assigned;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Its year, make, and vehicle tag number;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Its acquisition date and cost;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Its general condition;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Its annual operating and maintenance costs;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Its approximate current mileage; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Whether it is allowed to be taken home by a District officer or employee and if so, the officer or employee’s title and state of residence, and a written justification explaining the public interest served by allowing the employee to take a vehicle to the employee’s residence.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Director shall update the inventory on a quarterly basis to reflect any changes in fleet composition resulting from vehicle acquisition through purchase, lease, or transfer or disposed of through sale, demolition, disposal, or transfer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Metropolitan Police Department may submit, under separate seal, the total number and acquisition cost of vehicles used for undercover operations directly to the Chairman of the Council, the chair of the Council committee with oversight of the Metropolitan Police Department, and the chair of the Council committee with oversight of the Department of Public Works.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History" path="§3602">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 3602, 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-223" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-223, § 201, 59 DCR 13537</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3602 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of <cite path="§40-951" proof="true">§ 40-951</cite> 1981 Ed., see § 3602 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of <cite path="§40-931" proof="true">§ 40-931</cite> 1981 Ed., see § 3402 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-223">D.C. Law 19-223</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-223">D.C. Law 19-223</cite> provided that §§ 101, 102, 104, 105(a), 105(b), 106, 107, 201(a), 201(b), 201(c), 202, 203, and 301 of the act shall apply as of Mar. 5, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-223">D.C. Law 19-223</cite> provided that §§ 103, 105(c), and 201(d) of the act shall apply upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) No officer or employee of the District of Columbia government (including any independent agency of the District but excluding the Office of the Chief Technology Officer, the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia, and the Metropolitan Police Department) may enter into an agreement in excess of $2,500 for the procurement of goods or services on behalf of any entity of the District government until the officer or employee has conducted an analysis of how the procurement of the goods and services involved under the applicable regulations and procedures of the District government would differ from the procurement of the goods and services involved under the Federal supply schedule and other applicable regulations and procedures of the General Services Administration, including an analysis of any differences in the costs to be incurred and the time required to obtain the goods or services.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) INVENTORY OF VEHICLES.—The Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia shall submit, by November 15, 2001, an inventory, as of September 30, 2001, of all vehicles owned, leased or operated by the District of Columbia government. The inventory shall include, but not be limited to, the department to which the vehicle is assigned; the year and make of the vehicle; the acquisition date and cost; the general condition of the vehicle; annual operating and maintenance costs; current mileage; and whether the vehicle is allowed to be taken home by a District officer or employee and if so, the officer or employee’s title and resident location.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) RESTRICTIONS ON USE OF OFFICIAL VEHICLES.—Except as otherwise provided in this section, none of the funds made available by this Act or by any other Act may be used to provide any officer or employee of the District of Columbia with an official vehicle unless the officer or employee uses the vehicle only in the performance of the officer’s or employee’s official duties. For purposes of this paragraph, the term ‘official duties’ does not include travel between the officer’s or employee’s residence and workplace (except: (1) in the case of an officer or employee of the Metropolitan Police Department who resides in the District of Columbia or is otherwise designated by the Chief of the Department; (2) at the discretion of the Fire Chief, an officer or employee of the District of Columbia Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department who resides in the District of Columbia and is on call 24 hours a day; (3) the Mayor of the District of Columbia; and (4) the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 120 of Pub. L. 107-96 provided:</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
