<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-421.09</num>
  <heading>Collection; interest; exception to requirement of advertising.</heading>
  <text>The assessments provided for in §§ <cite root="9-421.01">9-421.01</cite> to 9-421.12 shall be made and collected as provided in § <cite root="9-401.06">9-401.06</cite>, relating to alleys and sidewalks. The rate of interest to be charged upon any assessment, levied under § <cite root="9-401.06">9-401.06</cite> relating to alleys and sidewalks, or any instalment thereof, is reduced hereby from 8 per centum per annum to 6 per centum per annum; provided, however, that any instalment of any such assessment not paid within the time provided in § <cite root="9-401.06">9-401.06</cite> shall thereafter bear interest at the rate of 12 per centum per annum; and provided further, that the advertisement by publication of the intention of the Mayor of the District of Columbia to perform the work and the formal hearing in respect thereto required by law as to alley and sidewalk improvements shall not be required as to roadway, curbing, and gutter improvements.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Feb. 20, 1931, 46 Stat. 1198, ch. 246, § 9</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 7-635.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 7-630.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
