<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-107.52</num>
  <heading>Bond authorization.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to 1-204.90, the Council approves and authorizes the issuance of one or more series of GARVEE Bonds to fund the Qualified Transportation Project Costs of the Qualified Transportation Project; provided that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The aggregate principal amount of GARVEE Bonds that may be issued is the amount that can be supported by Debt Service equal to the annual GARVEE Revenues received by the District, but shall not exceed $430 million;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The GARVEE Bonds may be issued from time to time in one or more series;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The GARVEE Bonds shall be tax-exempt or taxable as the Chief Financial Officer shall determine and shall be payable and secured as provided in s 9-107.54.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to pay from the proceeds of the GARVEE Bonds the costs and expenses of issuing and delivering the GARVEE Bonds, including, but not limited to, underwriting discount or fees, rating agency fees, legal fees, accounting fees, financial advisory fees, trustee and paying agent fees, collection agent fees, bond insurance, letters of credit and other credit enhancements, liquidity enhancements, and printing costs and expenses.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-54" type="History">Sept. 23, 2009, D.C. Law 18-54, § 3, 56 DCR 5694</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-124" type="History">July 16, 2014, D.C. Law 20-124, § 2(b), 61 DCR 5383</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-124">D.C. Law 20-124</cite> substituted “shall not exceed $430 million” for “shall not exceed $200 million” in (a)(1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Transportation Infrastructure Improvements GARVEE Bond Financing Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-69">D.C. Law 20-69</cite>, February 22, 2014,  61 DCR 22.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Transportation Infrastructure Improvements GARVEE Bond Financing Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-218, November 26, 2013,  60 DCR 16528, 20 STAT 2610).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 301 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-110">D.C. Law 20-110</cite> provided: “Findings.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) The Property is located at the intersection of Naylor Road, S.E., Good Hope Road, S.E., and Alabama Avenue, S.E., and consists of approximately 18.7 acres of land and is further defined in section 101(22).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The Property was acquired with the intention of eliminating blight by redeveloping the underused site into retail and residential space to benefit the surrounding community and the District. Therefore, the Property is not required for public purposes and the Property needs to be declared surplus in order to dispose of the Property for redevelopment purposes.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) A public hearing was held on June 26, 2013, at the Francis A. Gregory Neighborhood Library located at 3660 Alabama Ave. S.E., regarding the finding that the Property is no longer required for public purposes.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 302   of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-110">D.C. Law 20-110</cite> provided that the Council determined that the  Property  is no longer required for public purposes.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-110">D.C. Law 20-110</cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Findings.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a)   The Property is located at the intersection of Naylor Road, S.E.,   Good Hope Road, S.E., and Alabama Avenue, S.E., consists of approximately   18.7 acres of land, and is further defined in section 101(22).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b)   The Project shall include affordable housing, such that 20% of the   residential units shall be reserved for households with incomes at   or below 80% AMI. An additional 10% of the residential units shall   be reserved for households with incomes at or below 120% of AMI.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c)   The Developer shall enter into an agreement with the District requiring   the Developer to, at a minimum, contract with Certified Business  Enterprises  for at least 35% of the contract dollar volume of the  Project, and  requiring at least 20% equity and 20% development participation  of  Certified Business Enterprises.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(d)   The Developer shall enter into a First Source Agreement with the  District  that shall govern certain obligations of the Developer pursuant  to  section 4 of the First Source Employment Agreement Act of 1984,  effective  June 29, 1984 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 5-93">D.C. Law 5-93</cite>; D.C. Official Code  Section 2-219.03) and Mayor's   Order 83-265, dated November 9, 1983, regarding job creation and  employment  as a result of the construction on the Property.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(e)   The Developer shall comply with the terms set forth in Zoning Commission   Order No. 09-03, July 12, 2010, pertaining to the following properties:   Square 5640, Lot 33; Square 5640, Lot 35; Square 5640, Lot 816; and   Par 0213, Lot 64.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(f)   The Land Disposition Agreement to be executed between the District   and the Developer shall:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1)   Incorporate the District's right to reacquire the Property at the   price originally conveyed consistent with section 1(e) of An Act  Authorizing  the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia  no longer  required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53  Stat. 1211;  D.C. Official Code  Section 10-801(e)); and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2)   Except as provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, be consistent   with the terms in the documents submitted by the Mayor to the Council   in conjunction with the Skyland Town Center Omnibus Act of 2014.  Any  substantive change shall be submitted to the Council consistent  with  section 1(b-1)(6) of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain  real estate  in the District of Columbia no longer required for public  purposes,  approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code   Section 10-801(b-1)(6)).”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
