<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-105.01</num>
  <heading>Relocation of Michigan Avenue authorized.</heading>
  <text>In order to relocate the line of Michigan Avenue from Franklin Street as laid down on the plan of the permanent system of highways for the District of Columbia to Lincoln Road, bordering the southeast corner of the grounds of the United States Soldiers’ Home, and to straighten and shorten the route of said Avenue, the Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to close, vacate, and abandon the portion of Michigan Avenue known and designated as Parcel E on map filed in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia and numbered as Map 1429, containing 54,380 square feet, said part so closed, vacated, and abandoned to be transferred by said Mayor of the District of Columbia to the United States as part of the grounds of the United States Military Asylum, known as the United States Soldiers’ Home.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 4, 1929, 45 Stat. 1543, ch. 682, § 1</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-101.15">9-101.15</cite> and § <cite path="§9-105.04">9-105.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-127.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-127.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Extension and widening of Michigan Avenue: See the Act of April 22, 1932, 47 Stat. 135, ch. 133, §§ 1 to 5.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
