<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-107.03</num>
  <heading>Contract authority.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to enter into contracts in connection with projects undertaken as federal-aid highway projects under the provisions of the Federal Aid Highway Act of 1944 in such amounts as shall be approved by the Federal Highway Administration, Department of Transportation.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-140">Oct. 26, 1973, 87 Stat. 507, Pub. L. 93-140, § 15</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 7-136.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 7-135b.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>The Federal Aid Highway Act of 1944, referred to near the middle of this section, was repealed by § 2(28) of the Act of August 27, 1958, 72 Stat. 919, Pub. L. 85-767.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
