<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-105.03</num>
  <heading>Portion of Michigan Avenue abandoned.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to close, vacate, and abandon the portion of Michigan Avenue known and designated as Parcel D, containing 69,336 square feet, and Parcel H, containing 7,279 square feet, as shown on map filed in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia and numbered as Map 1429, title to said parcels so closed, vacated, and abandoned to revert in fee simple to the owner or owners of the parcel numbered on the assessment records of the District of Columbia as parcel 120/1, said closing of said street and the transfer of title thereto to be upon the condition and with the express stipulation that the owner or owners of said parcel 120/1 shall dedicate to the District of Columbia for street purposes all of the parcel known and designated as Parcel F, containing 43,161 square feet, as shown on map filed in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia and numbered as Map 1429 and shall further, in consideration of the increase in area of the property of said owner or owners of said parcel 120/1 by reason of the transfers as provided herein, dedicate to the District of Columbia about 36,000 square feet of land, the location of which shall be mutually agreed upon by the Mayor of the District of Columbia and the owner or owners of parcel 120/1, and that said owner or owners of said parcel 120/1 shall transfer to the United States as part of the grounds of the United States Military Asylum, known as the United States Soldiers’ Home, all of the parcel known and designated as Parcel G, containing 1,543 square feet, as shown on said Map No. 1429 in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia; provided, however, that the Board of Commissioners of the United States Soldiers’ Home, or the proper authorities having title, control, or jurisdiction, shall transfer to the owner or owners of the parcel designated on the assessment and taxation records of the District of Columbia as parcel 120/1 all the land comprised within the parcel known and designated as Parcel C containing 4,517 square feet, as shown on map filed in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia and numbered as Map 1429.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 4, 1929, 45 Stat. 1543, ch. 682, § 3</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-129.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-129.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
