<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-1113.04</num>
  <heading>Immediate grants.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Secretary should determine that immediate action is urgently required to protect the public interest in the national capital area, he may waive any or all provisions of the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964 (except § 13(c) thereof), and immediately grant to the Transit Authority from funds available to the Urban Mass Transportation Administration of the Department of Transportation such sums as are contemplated under § <cite path="§9-1113.03">9-1113.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Secretary, after determining that immediate action is necessary in the public interest in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, may, in accordance with subsection (c) of this section, advance from funds available to the Urban Mass Transportation Administration of the Department of Transportation such funds as he determines to be necessary for payment to the Transit Authority to provide temporary financing for that portion of the cost of acquisition of the mass transit bus system or systems contemplated by this subchapter, together with associated improvements to or replacement of acquired equipment and facilities, which are not provided for by the Secretary pursuant to § <cite path="§9-1113.03">9-1113.03</cite>. For this purpose, such advance shall not be construed as a loan made under § 3 of the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964. Funds advanced pursuant to this section shall be considered as “other than federal funds” within the meaning of § 4(a) of the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Secretary shall not advance funds under this section until he has determined that the Transit Authority has the capacity and ability to arrange for repayment of such advance in accordance with § <cite path="§9-1113.05">9-1113.05</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-517">Oct. 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 1002, Pub. L. 92-517, title III, § 302</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-1113.05">9-1113.05</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-2474.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 1-1464.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>The “Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964,” referred to throughout this section, is now codified at  49 U.S.C. § 5301 et seq.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
