<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-111.01</num>
  <heading>District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund (“Fund”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, the monies in the Fund shall not be a part of, or lapse into, the General Fund of the District or any other fund of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall deposit into the Fund, on a monthly basis, an amount equivalent to all receipts from taxes, fees, civil fines and penalties collected by the District after September 30, 1995, pursuant to Chapter 23 of Title 47.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All monies in the Fund shall be used first to comply with the requirements of § <cite path="§9-109.02">9-109.02</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>As of October 1, 2011, all monies in the Fund designated to be used to comply with the requirements of § <cite path="§9-109.02">9-109.02</cite> shall not exceed 22% of the proposed annual federal-aid highway project expenditures.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any excess monies remaining in the Fund after the requirements of § <cite path="§9-109.02">9-109.02</cite> have been met and remaining balances not necessary for the purposes outlined in Title 23 of the United States Code, based on the 6-year projected trust fund performance audit conducted by the Inspector General pursuant to § <cite path="§9-109.02">9-109.02</cite>(e), shall be deposited into the Local Transportation Fund established by § <cite path="§9-111.01a">9-111.01a</cite>, and used exclusively for the purposes provided therein.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor annually shall determine the excess amount based upon the audit of the Inspector General issued pursuant to § <cite path="§9-109.02">9-109.02</cite>(e) and include the amount in the budget for the fiscal year beginning on October 1 of that year that is transmitted to the Council pursuant to § <cite path="§1-204.42">1-204.42</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-184" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-184, § 102, 43 DCR 4265</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 1702(a),(b), 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20" type="History">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 6002(a), 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 623(a), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 6053, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 6023(a), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-361">47-361</cite> and § <cite path="§50-921.02">50-921.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-134.4.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite> added subsec. (e) relating to excess monies.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite>, in subsec. (e), substituted “shall be deposited into the District Department of Transportation Unified Fund established by § <cite path="§50-921.11">50-921.11</cite>” for “shall be deposited in the Local Roads Construction and Maintenance Fund established by § <cite path="§9-111.01a">9-111.01a</cite>”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> rewrote subsecs. (d) and (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> repealed subsec. (d)(2), which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) All monies in the Fund designated to comply with the requirements of § <cite path="§9-109.02">9-109.02</cite> shall not exceed 22% of the proposed annual Fund expenditures.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added (d)(3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Highway Trust Fund Establishment Temporary Act of 1996 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-116">D.C. Law 11-116</cite>, May 3, 1996, law notification  43 DCR 2707).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-97">D.C. Law 19-97</cite> added subsecs. (d)(2A) and (3) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2A) As of October 1, 2011, all monies in the Fund designated to comply with the requirements of section 3 of the District of Columbia Emergency Highway Relief Act, approved August 4, 1995 (109 Stat. 257; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§9-109.02">9-109.02</cite>), shall not exceed 22% of the proposed annual federal-aid highway project expenditures.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) As of October 1, 2011, all unobligated and unexpended revenues at the end of fiscal year 2011 that would have been deposited into the District Department of Transportation Unified Fund shall be deposited into the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 6(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-97">D.C. Law 19-97</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see § 2 of the Highway Trust Fund Establishment Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-169, December 8, 1995,  42 DCR 7069), § 2 of the Highway Trust Fund Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-223, March 7, 1996,  43 DCR 1418), and § 2 of the Highway Trust Fund Establishment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-464, January 9, 1997,  44 DCR 620).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">Section 3 of D.C. Act 11-169, § 3 of D.C. Act 11-223, and § 3 of D.C. Act 11-464 provided for the issuance by the Mayor of rules and regulations necessary to carry out the purposes of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1602(a), (b) of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3502 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6002(a) of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 623(a) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of District Department of Transportation Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-254, December 21, 2011,  58 DCR 11215).</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of title I of Law 11-184: Section 101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-184">D.C. Law 11-184</cite> provided that title I of the act may be cited as the Highway Trust Fund Establishment Act of 1996.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 6001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite> provided that subtitle A of title VI of the act may be cited as the “District Department of Transportation Unified Fund Amendment Act of 2007”.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 629 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> provided: “Sec. 629. Applicability. This subtitle shall apply as of October 1, 2011; except, that sections 622 and 623(a)(2) shall apply as of the effective date of this act.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 103 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-184">D.C. Law 11-184</cite> provided that the Mayor may issue rules and regulations as the Mayor finds necessary to carry out the purposes of title I of the act pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
