<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-1111.04</num>
  <heading>Approval for construction required.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No portion of the adopted regional system shall be constructed within the United States Capitol grounds except upon approval of the Commission for Extension of the United States Capitol.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Construction of the adopted regional system in, on, under, or over public space in the District of Columbia under the jurisdiction of the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall, in the interest of public convenience and safety, be performed in accordance with schedules agreed upon between the Transit Authority and the Mayor, to the end that such construction work will be coordinated with other construction work in such public space; and the Mayor shall so exercise his jurisdiction and control over such public space as to facilitate the Transit Authority’s use and occupation thereof for construction of the adopted regional system.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Dec. 9, 1969, 83 Stat. 322, Pub. L. 91-143, § 5</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2456.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1444.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) Metro Matters funding requirement provisions, see §§ 7012, 7013 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) Metro Matters funding requirement provisions, see §§ 7012, 7013 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle B of Law 15-205: Section 7011 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> provided that subtitle B of the act may be cited as the Metro Matters Funding Requirements Act of 2004.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Sections 7012 and 7013 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> provided:</text>
      <text>“Sec. 7012. The Council authorizes the Mayor to conclude a funding agreement with the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (‘WMATA’) by January 1, 2005, for the purposes of funding capital projects identified in Metro Matters, which is a public outreach campaign launched October 23, 2003, to raise awareness about Metro’s financial crisis and urgent need for $1.5 billion in capital funding.</text>
      <text>“Sec. 7012. By October 1, 2004, WMATA shall have no fewer than 78 rail cars assigned to the Branch Avenue portion of the Green line during morning and afternoon peak periods.”</text>
      <text>Appropriations authorized: Public Law 104-194, 110 Stat. 2362, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1997, provided for construction projects an increase of $46,923,000 (including an increase of $34,000,000 for the highway trust fund, reallocations and rescissions for a net rescission of $120,496,000 from local funds appropriated under this heading in prior fiscal years and an additional $133,419,000 in Federal funds), as authorized by §§ <cite path="§34-2405.01">34-2405.01</cite> through <cite path="§34-2405.08">34-2405.08</cite>; §§ <cite path="§34-2413.08">34-2413.08</cite>, <cite path="§34-2413.10">34-2413.10</cite> and <cite path="§34-2304">34-2304</cite>; and §§ <cite path="§10-619">10-619</cite> and <cite path="§47-3404">47-3404</cite>; including acquisition of sites, preparation of plans and specifications, conducting preliminary surveys, erection of structures, including building improvement and alteration and treatment of grounds, to remain available until expended: Provided, That funds for use of each capital project implementing agency shall be managed and controlled in accordance with all procedures and limitations established under the Financial Management System: Provided further, That all funds provided by this appropriation title shall be available only for the specific projects and purposes intended: Provided further, That notwithstanding the foregoing, all authorizations for capital outlay projects, except those projects covered by the first sentence of section 23(a) of the Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1968, approved August 23, 1968 (82 Stat. 827; Public Law 90-495;  D.C. Code, sec. 9-107.01, note), for which funds are provided by this appropriation title, shall expire on September 30, 1998, except authorizations for projects as to which funds have been obligated in whole or in part prior to September 30, 1998: Provided further, That upon expiration of any such project authorization the funds provided herein for the project shall lapse.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
