<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1101.01</num>
  <heading>Agreements with Maryland and Virginia to develop continuing comprehensive transportation planning process.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor is authorized to enter into such agreements with the States of Maryland and Virginia and with political subdivisions of such States as may be necessary to develop a continuing comprehensive transportation planning process for the National Capital region for the purpose of complying with the requirements of § 134 of Title 23, United States Code  , except that no such agreement shall require the District of Columbia to pay more than its pro rata share of the costs of such planning process. In developing such transportation planning process the Mayor shall consult and cooperate with the National Capital Planning Commission and the National Capital Regional Planning Council. For the purpose of this section, the term “National Capital region” shall have the same meaning as is given it in § <cite path="§1-1401">1-1401</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-610" type="History">Sept. 30, 1966, 80 Stat. 859, Pub. L. 89-610, title X, § 1006</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2401.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1401a.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 1-1401, referred to at the end of the last sentence of the section, refers to former § <cite path="§1-1401">1-1401</cite> which was repealed by the Act of December 9, 1969, 83 Stat. 322, Pub. L. 91-143, § 8(a)(1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
