<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-1113.06</num>
  <heading>Jurisdiction for condemnation proceedings.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall have complete and exclusive jurisdiction over any proceedings by the Transit Authority for the condemnation of property, wherever situated, of D.C. Transit System, Incorporated (including its subsidiary, the Washington, Virginia, and Maryland Coach Company), the Alexandria, Barcroft, and Washington Transit Company, and the WMA Transit Company. Such proceedings shall be instituted and maintained in accordance with the provisions of this section and the provisions of subchapter IV of Chapter 13 of Title 16, except that the court may appoint a commission in accordance with Rule 71A(h) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure in connection with the issue of compensation arising out of any such proceedings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any such condemnation proceedings shall be commenced by the Attorney General of the United States, upon the request of the Transit Authority, by filing with the United States District Court for the District of Columbia a complaint and declaration of taking containing a description of the land and other assets to be taken, together with a sum of money deposited with the Registrar of such Court in accordance with the applicable provisions of law set forth in subsection (a) of this section. Upon such filing and deposit, title to the possession of the assets described in any such complaint and declaration of taking shall pass to the Transit Authority and the value of the assets so acquired shall be determined as of that date.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The trial of any such condemnation proceedings shall be a preferred cause and shall be commenced at the earliest date convenient to the Court.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any proceeding brought by the Transit Authority under this section against the Alexandria, Barcroft, and Washington Transit Company shall be transferred, upon motion made by such Transit Company, to the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia, and such District Court shall have, upon such transfer, complete and exclusive jurisdiction over such proceeding. Any action brought by the Transit Authority under this section against the WMA Transit Company, shall be transferred, upon motion made by the WMA Transit Company, to the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, and such District Court shall have, upon such transfer, complete and exclusive jurisdiction over such proceeding.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-517" type="History">Oct. 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 1003, Pub. L. 92-517, title IV, § 401</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2476.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1466.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
