<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-1117.01</num>
  <heading>Mayor authorized to enter into Compact; purpose.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to enter into and execute on behalf of the District a compact with any state or states legally joining the Potomac River Bridges Towing Compact (“Compact”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The parties to this Compact are the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Virginia, and the State of Maryland (“Parties”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The purpose of this Compact is to facilitate the prompt and orderly removal of disabled and abandoned vehicles from the bridges by giving all 3 Parties jurisdiction to exercise appropriate authority anywhere on the following bridges which pass through the territory of 2 or more of the jurisdictions: the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge, Rochambeau Memorial Bridge, George Mason Memorial Bridge, Theodore Roosevelt Memorial Bridge, Francis Scott Key Bridge, Chain Bridge, and American Legion Memorial Bridge.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-63" type="History">March 31, 2000, D.C. Law 13-63, § 2, 46 DCR 9217</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>For temporary (225 day) authority of Mayor to execute Compact, see § 2 of Potomac River Bridges Towing Compact Temporary Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-4">D.C. Law 13-4</cite>, May 28, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 5304).</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) authorization of the District to remove disabled vehicles from any portion of the Potomac River Bridges, see §§ 2 to 6 of the Potomac River Bridges Towing Compact Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-16, February 10, 1999,  46 DCR 2349).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) authorization of continued participation in towing compact, see §§ 2 to 6 of the Potomac River Bridges Towing Compact Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-88, June 4, 1999,  46 DCR 5319).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) authorization of continued participation in towing compact, see §§ 2 to 6 of the Potomac River Bridges Towing Compact Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-222, January 11, 2000,  47 DCR 470).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
