<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1113.01</num>
  <heading>Acquisition of bus companies; franchise cancelled; charter bus service by Authority; corporate status of D.C. Transit System, Inc.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Based on the findings set forth in § 2 of this Act, it is the sense of the Congress that the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Transit Authority”) should initiate negotiations as soon as possible with the ownership of D.C. Transit System, Incorporated (and its subsidiary, the Washington, Virginia, and Maryland Coach Company), the Alexandria, Barcroft, and Washington Transit Company, and the WMA Transit Company for acquisition by the Transit Authority of capital stock or facilities, plant, equipment, real and personal property of such bus companies of whatever nature, whether owned directly or indirectly, used or useful for mass transportation by bus of passengers within the Washington metropolitan area. It is further the sense of the Congress that representatives of the Transit Authority should participate in any labor contract negotiations undertaken prior to acquisition by the Transit Authority of such bus companies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The franchise to operate a system of mass transportation of passengers for hire granted to D.C. Transit System, Incorporated, by the Act of July 24, 1956 (70 Stat. 598) is hereby canceled, effective upon the date immediately preceding the date on which the Transit Authority acquires the transit facilities of D.C. Transit System, Incorporated.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Transit Authority, and any transit company owned or controlled by the Transit Authority, may operate charter service by bus in accordance with Title III of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact only between any point within the transit zone and any point in the State of Maryland or Virginia, or a point within 250 miles of the Zero Mile Stone located on the Ellipse.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term “transit zone” means the area designated in § 3 of Title III of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>D.C. Transit System, Incorporated, a corporation of the District of Columbia, may:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Continue to exist as such a corporation and amend its charter in any manner provided under the laws of the District of Columbia;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Avail itself of the provisions of Chapter 3 of Title 29 in respect to a change of its name; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Become incorporated or reincorporated in any manner provided under the laws of the District of Columbia.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed so as to cause or require the corporate dissolution of D.C. Transit System, Incorporated.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-517" type="History">Oct. 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 1001, Pub. L. 92-517, title I, § 102</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 3(c), 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-1113.02">9-1113.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2471.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1461.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-378">D.C. Law 18-378</law-cite>, in subsec. (d)(1)(B), substituted “Chapter 3 of Title 29” for “Chapter 1 of Title 29”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“This Act,” referred to in subsections (a) and (d)(2), is the Act of October 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 1001, Pub. L. 92-517.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
