<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1111.12</num>
  <heading>Payment of bonds.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Transit Authority shall maintain a sinking fund to be used for the accumulation of assets for payment of principal on bonds issued by the Transit Authority and guaranteed by the Secretary as provided in § <cite path="§9-1111.06">9-1111.06</cite>. The fund shall be administered in accordance with the provisions of the Compact providing for funds established by the Transit Authority, and moneys in the fund may be invested by the Transit Authority in accordance with the Compact and with the Agreement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Transit Authority shall use assets of the fund to pay the principal paid or to be paid after October 1, 1979, on bonds issued by the Transit Authority.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Subject to the conditions of the Agreement, the Secretary of Transportation is authorized to make contributions to the Transit Authority, or its fiscal agent, in amounts sufficient to provide for the payment of two thirds of the principal paid or to be paid after June 30, 1979, on bonds issued by the Transit Authority which are guaranteed by the Secretary as provided in § <cite path="§9-1111.06">9-1111.06</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>There are authorized to be appropriated beginning in fiscal year 1981 such sums as are necessary to carry out the requirements of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Subject to the conditions of the Agreement, the local participating governments shall make payments to the Transit Authority in amounts sufficient to allow the Transit Authority to make contributions to the fund established pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection in amounts sufficient to provide for the payment of one third of the principal paid or to be paid after June 30, 1979, on bonds issued by the Transit Authority which are guaranteed by the Secretary as provided in § <cite path="§9-1111.06">9-1111.06</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Transit Authority shall maintain a Bond Interest Fund to be used for the accumulation of assets for the timely payment of interest on bonds issued by the Transit Authority and guaranteed by the Secretary as provided in § <cite path="§9-1111.06">9-1111.06</cite>. The fund shall be administered in accordance with the provisions of the Compact providing for funds established by the Transit Authority, and moneys in the fund may be invested by the Transit Authority in accordance with the Compact and with the Agreement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Subject to the conditions of the Agreement, the Secretary of Transportation is authorized to make contributions to the Transit Authority or its fiscal agent, in amounts sufficient to provide for the payment of two thirds of the total amount of interest paid or to be paid after June 30, 1979, on bonds issued by the Transit Authority which are guaranteed by the Secretary as provided in § <cite path="§9-1111.06">9-1111.06</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>There are authorized to be appropriated beginning in fiscal year 1981 such sums as are necessary to carry out the provisions of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>With respect to interest payments due prior to July 3, 1983, the Secretary of Transportation, if requested by the Transit Authority, may make accelerated interest payments in amounts sufficient to provide for the payment, as any payment becomes due, of not more than an additional 181/3 per centum of the interest due on such bonds at the time of such payment, so long as the total amount of contributions by the Secretary under this subsection does not exceed the amount specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection. Unless otherwise provided in amendments to the Agreement, any accelerated payments made shall bear interest from the date of accelerated payment until liquidation at a rate to be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration the current average market yield on outstanding United States marketable obligations which have maturities comparable to the period of time between the time of accelerated payment and the time of liquidation.</text>
      <text>13</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Subject to the conditions of the Agreement, the local participating governments shall make payments to the Transit Authority in amounts sufficient to allow the Transit Authority to make contributions to the fund established pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection in amounts sufficient to provide for the payment of one third of the interest paid or to be paid after June 30, 1979, on bonds issued by the Transit Authority which are guaranteed by the Secretary as provided in § <cite path="§9-1111.06">9-1111.06</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>If as a result of the retirement of the principal of such bonds (or of any portion of such principal) before maturity the total amount of contributions by the Secretary of Transportation after June 30, 1979, for payment of interest on such bonds is at any time in excess of two thirds of the net present value of the total amount of interest paid or to be paid on such bonds after such date, the Transit Authority shall pay to the Secretary the difference between the total amount contributed by the Secretary and two thirds of the net present value of the total amount of interest paid or to be paid on such bonds after such date.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Dec. 9, 1969, 83 Stat. 320, Pub. L. 91-143, § 15</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 96-184" type="History">Jan. 3, 1980, 93 Stat. 1320, Pub. L. 96-184, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-1111.08">9-1111.08</cite>, § <cite path="§9-1111.13">9-1111.13</cite>, and § <cite path="§9-1111.15">9-1111.15</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2464.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
