<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1103.03</num>
  <heading>Duties of Mayor; appropriations authorized; Congressional approval required for Compact amendments.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and directed to enter into and execute on behalf of the United States for the District of Columbia a Compact substantially as set forth above with the States of Virginia and Maryland and is further authorized and directed to carry out and effectuate the terms and provisions of said Compact, and there are hereby authorized to be appropriated such funds as are necessary to carry out the obligations of the District of Columbia in accordance with the terms of the said Compact; provided, that the said Mayor shall not adopt any amendment to the said Compact for the District of Columbia under the provisions of § 1 of Article IX of the Compact unless the said amendment has had the consent or approval of the Congress.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 86-794" type="History" path="§2">Sept. 15, 1960, 74 Stat. 1050, Pub. L. 86-794, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2413.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1411.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The reference to “§ 1 of Article IX of the Compact,” found in the proviso, was made prior to the revision of the Compact. The information is now found in § 1 of Article VIII of the Compact.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
