<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1111.02</num>
  <heading>Federal contributions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To provide the federal share of the cost of the adopted regional system, which system supersedes that heretofore authorized by the Congress in subchapter III of this chapter, the Secretary of Transportation is authorized to make annual contributions to the Transit Authority in amounts sufficient to finance in part the cost of the adopted regional system; except that the aggregate amount of federal contributions for the adopted regional system, including the $100,000,000 authorized to be appropriated by § <cite path="§9-1105.02">9-1105.02</cite>(1), shall not exceed the lower amount of $1,147,044,000 or two thirds of the net project cost of the adopted regional system.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Federal contributions for the adopted regional system shall be subject to the following limitations and conditions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The work for which contributions are authorized shall be subject to the provisions of the Compact and shall be carried out substantially in accordance with the plans and schedules for the adopted regional system; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The aggregate amount of such federal contributions on or prior to the last day of any given fiscal year shall be matched by the local participating governments by payment of the local share of capital contributions required for the period ending with the last day of such year in a total amount not less than 50 per centum of the amount of such federal contributions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Transportation, without fiscal year limitation, an amount not to exceed $1,047,044,000 to carry out the purposes of this section. The appropriations authorized by this subsection shall be in addition to the appropriations authorized by § <cite path="§9-1105.02">9-1105.02</cite>(1).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Dec. 9, 1969, 83 Stat. 320, Pub. L. 91-143, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-1111.10">9-1111.10</cite> and § <cite path="§9-1111.11">9-1111.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2452.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1442.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Appropriations authorized: Public Law 104-194, 110 Stat. 2362, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1997, provided for construction projects an increase of $46,923,000 (including an increase of $34,000,000 for the highway trust fund, reallocations and rescissions for a net rescission of $120,496,000 from local funds appropriated under this heading in prior fiscal years and an additional $133,419,000 in Federal funds), as authorized by §§ <cite path="§34-2405.01">34-2405.01</cite> through <cite path="§34-2405.08">34-2405.08</cite>; §§ <cite path="§34-2413.08">34-2413.08</cite>, <cite path="§34-2413.10">34-2413.10</cite> and <cite path="§34-2304">34-2304</cite>; and §§ <cite path="§10-619">10-619</cite> and <cite path="§47-3404">47-3404</cite>; including acquisition of sites, preparation of plans and specifications, conducting preliminary surveys, erection of structures, including building improvement and alteration and treatment of grounds, to remain available until expended: Provided, That funds for use of each capital project implementing agency shall be managed and controlled in accordance with all procedures and limitations established under the Financial Management System: Provided further, That all funds provided by this appropriation title shall be available only for the specific projects and purposes intended: Provided further, That notwithstanding the foregoing, all authorizations for capital outlay projects, except those projects covered by the first sentence of section 23(a) of the Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1968, approved August 23, 1968 (82 Stat. 827; Public Law 90-495;  D.C. Code, sec. 9-107.01, note), for which funds are provided by this appropriation title, shall expire on September 30, 1998, except authorizations for projects as to which funds have been obligated in whole or in part prior to September 30, 1998: Provided further, That upon expiration of any such project authorization the funds provided herein for the project shall lapse.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
