<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1107.04</num>
  <heading>Congressional consent to amendments — Articles I, III, VII, IX, XI, XIV, and XVI of Title III.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Congress hereby consents to amendments to Articles I, III, VII, IX, XI, XIV, and XVI of Title III of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact substantially as set out in § <cite path="§9-1107.01">9-1107.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and directed to enter into and execute on behalf of the District of Columbia amendments, substantially as set forth in subsection (a) of this section, to Title III of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact with the States of Virginia and Maryland.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-349" type="History" path="§301">July 13, 1972, 86 Stat. 466, Pub. L. 92-349, title III, § 301</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2434.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1431a.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The amendments referred to in subsection (a) of this section are to §§ 1(g), 5(a), 21, 35, 39, 51, 66, and 79 of the Compact.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
