<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-1115.04</num>
  <heading>Compact provisions as law.</heading>
  <text>The following articles of the Compact set forth in § <cite path="§9-1115.03">9-1115.03</cite> shall be a part of the law of the District of Columbia as in the case of any other act on the effective date of the Compact as described in Article V of Title I: Articles I, II, III, and VIII of Title I; and Articles I through XIII of Title II. Upon termination of the Compact as set forth in § <cite path="§9-1115.03">9-1115.03</cite>, the foregoing articles shall be repealed, and any other laws of the District superseded or suspended by virtue of conflict with these articles shall be reactivated without further legislative action.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-96">Feb. 28, 1996, D.C. Law 11-96, § 5, 42 DCR 7185</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-2484.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) authority of Mayor to execute Compact, see § 2 of Potomac River Bridges Towing Compact Temporary Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-4">D.C. Law 13-4</cite>, May 28, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 5304).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary addition of § 1-2485.1 1981 Ed., see § 2 of the Potomac River Bridges Towing Compact Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-16, February 10, 1999,  46 DCR 2349).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary authorization for the District to remove disabled vehicles from any portion of the Potomac River Bridges, see §§ 2-6 of the Potomac River Bridges Towing Compact Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-16, February 10, 1999,  46 DCR 2349).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) authorization of continued participation in related compact, see §§ 2 to 6 of the Potomac River Bridges Towing Compact Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-88, June 4, 1999,  46 DCR 5319).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) authorization of continued participation in related compact, see §§ 2 to 6 of the Potomac River Bridges Towing Compact Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-222, January 11, 2000,  47 DCR 470).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
