<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1171</num>
  <heading>Aerial wires for streetcars.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other law, the Mayor is authorized to install aerial wires in accordance with this chapter for the sole purpose of powering or supporting wires that power streetcar transit where aerial wire power is necessary or, in the Mayor’s determination, is more feasible than other currently available forms of propulsion.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The installation of aerial wires authorized by this section is limited to the H Street/Benning Road streetcar transit line, between the intersection of North Capitol Street and H Street, N.E. on the west and the Anacostia River on the east until the requirements of § <cite path="§9-1173">9-1173</cite> are met.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-339" type="History" path="§2">Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-339, § 2, 58 DCR 618</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-1173">9-1173</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Sections 2 and 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-258">D.C. Law 18-258</law-cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Aerial wires for streetcars.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Notwithstanding any other law, the Mayor is authorized to install aerial wires in accordance with this act for the sole purpose of powering or supporting wires that power streetcar transit where aerial wire power is necessary or, in the Mayor’s determination, is more feasible than other currently available forms of propulsion.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The installation of aerial wires authorized by this section is limited to the H Street/Benning Road streetcar transit line, between the intersection of North Capitol Street and H Street, N.E., on the west and the Anacostia River on the east until the requirements of section 4 are met.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Transportation Infrastructure Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-486, July 19, 2010,  57 DCR 7164).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Transportation Infrastructure Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-583, October 19, 2010,  57 DCR 10129).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
