<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1203.04</num>
  <heading>Extensions through public grounds authorized.</heading>
  <text>Subject always to the approval of the Council of the District of Columbia, all such railroad tracks, turnouts, branch tracks, spurs, and sidings may be located and constructed in, upon, along, and through public grounds, space, and streets of the United States and/or of the District of Columbia as same are now or may hereafter be located and established; provided, that except as in §§ <cite path="§9-1203.01">9-1203.01</cite> to 9-1203.09 expressly authorized no tracks, turnouts, branches, spurs, or sidings shall be constructed along or through South Capitol Street or 1st Street Southwest in the north and south direction, at grade or otherwise, but each of said streets, with prior approval of said Council of the District of Columbia, may be crossed to such extent as may be necessary for the establishment of adequate railroad facilities; provided further, that no permit for the construction of tracks, turnouts, branches, spurs, or sidings shall be issued with respect to squares 600, 602, 604, 606, 608, 610, and 612, or any of said squares, until the particular square or squares for which a permit is sought shall have been zoned industrial; and provided further, that the plans for any building fronting on Canal Street from the Anacostia River to P Street Southwest shall have the approval of the Fine Arts Commission as to height and design.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 72-1-ch269" path="§4">June 18, 1932, 47 Stat. 323, ch. 269, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-1419.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-1219.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(177) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
