<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-1203.08</num>
  <heading>Use of track extensions by other carriers.</heading>
  <text>The authority to establish, construct, acquire, maintain, and operate the tracks, switch connections, extensions, turnouts, sidings, branches, spurs, and other facilities provided for in  this subchapter is given upon the following conditions, to wit: The said facilities shall be open to any and all freight traffic by rail whether originating within or without the District of Columbia either on the said The Philadelphia, Baltimore, and Washington Railroad Company or any other common carrier railroad, upon such just, reasonable, and nondiscriminatory rates, terms, and conditions as may be embraced in public tariffs, subject to the jurisdiction of the Interstate Commerce Commission as provided for other rates under the provisions of the Interstate Commerce Act; provided, that no greater charge shall be made for deliveries to be made upon said facilities than is or are or may be made for delivery of like traffic consigned for delivery at any other delivery point on The Philadelphia, Baltimore, and Washington Railroad Company in the District of Columbia; special, free, or reduced rates or charges for deliveries of property consigned to the United States or any of its departments, bureaus, or subordinate branches or to or for use of the municipality of the District of Columbia not included; and provided further, that any common carrier by railroad now or hereafter authorized to operate in the District of Columbia shall, upon application to and approval by the Interstate Commerce Commission, be permitted to use jointly all such facilities as provided in this subchapter on such terms and for such compensation as may be prescribed by the said Interstate Commerce Commission in accordance with the provisions of the Interstate Commerce Act, as amended.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 18, 1932, 47 Stat. 324, ch. 269, § 8</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-1423.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-1223.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The Interstate Commerce Act, referred to throughout this section, is codified throughout Chapters 1, 8, 12, 13 and 19 of Title 49, United States Code.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
