<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1209.01</num>
  <heading>Employment of temporary special and technical employees.</heading>
  <text>The services of draftsmen, assistant engineers, levelers, transitmen, rodmen, chainmen, computers, copyists, overseers, and inspectors temporarily required in connection with sewer, water, street, street-cleaning, or road work, or construction and repair of buildings and bridges, or any general or special engineering or construction work authorized by appropriations may be employed exclusively to carry into effect District of Columbia appropriations when ordered by the Mayor of the District of Columbia in writing, and all such necessary expenditures for the proper execution of said work shall be paid from and equitably charged against the sums appropriated for said work; and the Mayor in his budget estimates shall report the number of such employees performing such services, and their work, and the sums paid to each, and out of what appropriation; provided, that the expenditures hereunder shall not exceed $42,000 during any 1 fiscal year; provided further, that, excluding Inspectors in the Sewer Department, 1 inspector in the Electrical Department, and 1 Inspector in the Repair Shop, no person shall be employed in pursuance of the authority contained in this section for a longer period than 9 months in the aggregate during any 1 fiscal year.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 78-2-ch300" path="§2">June 28, 1944, 58 Stat. 530, ch. 300, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-1235.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-1435.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
