<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1209.02</num>
  <heading>Employment of temporary laborers and mechanics.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia, or his duly designated representatives, are authorized to employ temporarily such laborers, skilled laborers, drivers, hostlers, and mechanics as may be required exclusively in connection with sewer, water, street, and road work, and street cleaning, or the construction and repair of buildings and bridges, furniture and equipment, and any general or special engineering or construction or repair work, at per diem rates of pay to be fixed and adjusted from time to time by a wage board and approved by the Council of the District of Columbia, and to incur all necessary engineering and other expenses, exclusive of personal services, incidental to carrying on such work and necessary for the proper execution thereof, said laborers, skilled laborers, drivers, hostlers, and mechanics to be employed to perform such work as may not be required by law to be done under contract, and to pay for such services and expenses from the appropriations under which such services are rendered and expenses incurred.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 78-2-ch300" path="§2">June 28, 1944, 58 Stat. 531, ch. 300, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(178) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-1236.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-1436.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-1209.03">9-1209.03</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
