<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-203.07</num>
  <heading>Improvement of streets — Rules.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 6 months of May 10, 1988, the Mayor shall, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, issue rules to govern the procedures and standards for acquiring and improving streets and alleys in the District of Columbia. These rules shall include the establishment of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Procedures by which notification and opportunity to comment shall be provided to the Advisory Neighborhood Commission within whose area the street or alley is located;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Procedures by which notification and opportunity to comment shall be provided to each owner of property within the squares adjacent to the street to be acquired or improved and within the square in which an alley is to be acquired or improved; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Standards for making a determination that the acquisition or improvement of a street or alley would be in the public interest, for evaluating the comments received from the affected Advisory Neighborhood Commission and property owners within whose area the street or alley is located, and for assessing the criteria set forth in § <cite path="§9-203.06">9-203.06</cite>(c)(2).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to a proposal that consists of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Rehabilitation, repair, or reconstruction of a street or alley that is already being used as a public right-of-way for vehicles at the time of the proposal; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Widening, realignment, or extension by 10 feet or less of the pavement of a street or alley that is already being used as a public right-of-way for vehicles at the time of the proposal.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-201">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, § 307</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-106">as added May 10, 1988, D.C. Law 7-106, § 2(a), 35 DCR 2170</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 7-447.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <annotation>Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-106">D.C. Law 7-106</cite>, “New Street or Alley Amendment Act of 1988”, see Mayor’s Order 88-162, July 11, 1988.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
