<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-204.03a</num>
  <heading>Symbolic names.</heading>
  <text>The Council may designate a symbolic name for any public space, which shall be in addition to and subordinate to any name that is the mailing address for the public space, and which shall conform with the requirements of this chapter pertaining to the naming of public spaces. A symbolic designation shall not duplicate any name which includes the following words within its name: “Avenue”, “Street”, “Road”, “Drive”, “Place”, “Circle”, or “Alley”.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-201" type="History">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, § 403a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-236" type="History">as added Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-236, § 2(b), 44 DCR 917</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-204.03">9-204.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-453.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) designation of street, see § 2 of Kivie Kaplan Way Designation Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-13">D.C. Law 15-13</cite>, June 21, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 5457).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Kivie Kaplan Way Designation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-54, April 4, 2003,  50 DCR 2967).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-106">D.C. Law 13-106</cite> provided: “Pursuant to section 403a the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective April 9, 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-236">D.C. Law 11-236</cite>;  D.C. Code § <cite path="§7-453.1">7-453.1</cite>) (‘Act’), and notwithstanding the requirement set forth in section 405 of the Act ( D.C. Code § <cite path="§7-455">7-455</cite>), that no public space shall be named in honor of any person who has been deceased less than 2 years, the alley running east to west between the 100 block of 10th Street, N.E., and the 100 block of 11th Street, N.E., shall be designated as ‘Al Arrighi Way’, in honor of Mr. Al Arrighi’s contributions to the quality of life of the Capitol Hill neighborhood in the District of Columbia.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-46">D.C. Law 14-46</cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Pursuant to section 403a of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-236">D.C. Law 11-236</cite>; D.C. Official Code 9-204.03a), the Council of the District of Columbia symbolically designates the northwest corner of Barry Place, N.W., at Georgia Avenue N.W., as ‘Ed Murphy Way, N.W.,’ by placing a street sign on the northwest corner of Barry Place, N.W., at Georgia Avenue, N.W., which reads ‘Ed Murphy Way, N.W.’.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-70">D.C. Law 15-70</cite> provided: “Sec. 2. Pursuant to section 403a of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective April 9, 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-236">D.C. Law 11-236</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§9-204.03a">9-204.03a</cite>), the Council symbolically designates 21st Street, N.W., between Massachusetts Avenue and Q Street, N.W., as ‘Kivie Kaplan Way.”’</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
