<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-301</num>
  <heading>Control of bridges; exception.</heading>
  <text>The control of bridges, except the Aqueduct Bridge across Rock Creek, in the District of Columbia, is hereby conferred on the Mayor of the District of Columbia, and the Council of the District of Columbia is hereby required to make such proper regulations as it may deem necessary for the safety of the public using said bridges, and for the lighting and the police control of the same.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 52-2-ch199" path="">Mar. 3, 1893, 27 Stat. 544, ch. 199</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Highway plans, jurisdiction of mayor over roads and bridges, see § <cite path="§9-101.02">9-101.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Regulations necessary for the protection of lives, limbs, health, comfort, and quiet, see § <cite path="§1-303.03">1-303.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Street lighting, costs charged to railroads, see § <cite path="§9-509">9-509</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Street lighting, generally, see § <cite path="§9-501">9-501</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-501.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-501.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(169) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
