<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-305</num>
  <heading>Anacostia Bridge.</heading>
  <text>The Anacostia and Potomac River Railroad Company shall pay the entire cost of the pavement between the exterior rails of its tracks on said bridge (the Anacostia Bridge) and for a distance of 2 feet from the said exterior rails of said tracks on each side thereof and the cost of the entire floor system supporting said pavement, to be collected in the same manner as the cost of laying pavements between the rails and tracks of street railways as provided for in § <cite path="§9-401.01">9-401.01</cite> and paid for each fiscal year into the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the General Fund of the District of Columbia; provided further, that any other railroad company on or after April 27, 1904, authorized by Congress to use said bridge shall have the right to use the tracks of the Anacostia and Potomac River Railroad Company thereon upon such reciprocal trackage and such compensation as may be mutually agreed upon, and in case of failure to reach such an agreement that the Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall, upon petition filed by either party, fix and determine the same. And after April 27, 1904, one-half of the cost of the maintenance and repairs of this bridge shall be borne by the said railway company or companies, and shall be collected in the same manner as the cost of laying pavements between the rails and tracks of street railways, and paid into the treasury, as provided for above. The entire cost of maintenance of such underfloor construction as may be necessary in order that the cars of said company may be propelled over said bridge by underfloor electrical conductors or cables shall, after March 3, 1905, be borne by said railroad company, and no cars shall be propelled across said bridge unless all electrical conductors or cables furnishing power for the propulsion of the same shall be placed under floor of said bridge.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Apr. 27, 1904, 33 Stat. 372, ch. 1628</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 3, 1905, 33 Stat. 893, ch. 1406</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 22, 1921, 41 Stat. 1144, ch. 70, § 7</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 28, 1944, 58 Stat. 533, ch. 300, § 18</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 571, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(c)(23)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public utilities, multiple company use of utility infrastructures, see § <cite path="§34-1102">34-1102</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-505.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-505.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
