<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-323</num>
  <heading>Subway under Baltimore and Ohio tracks in vicinity of Chestnut Street, Fern Place, and Piney Branch Road.</heading>
  <text>One-half of the total cost of constructing a subway under the tracks and right-of-way of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company in the vicinity of Chestnut Street or of the intersection of Fern Place and Piney Branch Road, extended, and thereafter the cost of maintaining the structure within the limits of its right-of-way shall be borne and paid by the said Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company, its successors and assigns, to the Collector of Taxes of the District of Columbia for the deposit to the credit of the District of Columbia, and the same shall be a valid and subsisting lien against the franchises and property of the said railroad company, and shall constitute a legal indebtedness against the said railroad company in favor of the District of Columbia, and said lien may be enforced in the name of the District of Columbia by a bill in equity brought by the Mayor of the District of Columbia in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, or by any other legal proceeding against the said railroad company; provided, that from and after the completion of the said subway and approaches, the highway grade crossing over the tracks and right-of-way of the said Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company at Chestnut Street shall be forever closed against further traffic of any kind.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 71-2-ch848" path="">July 3, 1930, 46 Stat. 963, ch. 848</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1936, 49 Stat. 1921, ch. 804</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1948, 62 Stat. 991, ch. 646, § 32(b)</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 24, 1949, 63 Stat. 107, ch. 139, § 127</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 571, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(c)(26)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-523.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-523.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Office of Collector of Taxes abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§9-310">9-310</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
