<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-401.08</num>
  <heading>Service connections with water mains and sewer.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized whenever the roadway of a street is about to be paved or macadamized to make service connections in such street for all abutting lots and premises with the water mains and sewer provided for the service of said lots and premises. The entire cost of the said connections shall be paid from the current appropriations respectively for the extension of the sewer and water-supply systems and shall be assessed against the abutting property and collected in like manner as assessments which are levied under the compulsory permit system; the sums so collected shall be credited to the respective appropriations for the extension of the sewer and water-supply systems for the fiscal year during which said collections are made.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 53-2-ch40" path="">Mar. 14, 1894, 28 Stat. 44, ch. 40</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Taxation and fiscal affairs, special assessments for public improvements, see § <cite path="§47-1201">47-1201</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Water mains and service sewers, see §§ <cite path="§34-2401.01">34-2401.01</cite> and <cite path="§34-2405.01">34-2405.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-611.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-610.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
