<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-401.01</num>
  <heading>Cost of construction and repairs; payments.</heading>
  <text>The cost of laying down said pavement, sewers, and other works, or of repairing the same, shall be paid for in the following proportions and manner, to wit: The United States shall pay one-half of the cost of all work done under the provisions of this section, except as hereinafter provided, which payment shall be credited as part of the 50 per centum which the United States contributes toward the expenses of the District of Columbia for that year; and all payments shall be made by the Secretary of the Treasury on the warrant or order of the Mayor of the District of Columbia, in such amounts and at such times they may deem safe and proper in view of the progress of the work; provided, that the Capital Transit Company herein provided for shall bear the entire cost of paving, repairs, or replacements incident to track repairs, replacements, or changes made at a time when the street or bridge is not being paved, and shall bear one-half the cost of other paving, repaving, or maintenance of paving between its track and for 2 feet outside the outer rails, and shall bear the excess cost of construction and maintenance of public bridges due to the existence or installation of its tracks on such bridges; provided further, that nothing herein contained shall relieve said Capital Transit Company from liability for street paving as owner of real estate apart from right-of-way occupied by its tracks as provided by § <cite path="§9-401.10">9-401.10</cite>; and if such company shall fail or refuse to pay the sum due from them in respect of the work done by or under the orders of the proper officials of said District, the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall issue certificates of indebtedness against the property, real or personal, of such railway company, which certificates shall bear interest at the rate of 10 per centum per annum until paid, and which, until they are paid, shall remain and be a lien upon the property on or against which they are issued together with the franchise of said company; and if the said certificates are not paid within 1 year, the said Mayor of the District of Columbia may proceed to sell the property against which they are issued, or so much thereof as may be necessary to pay the amount due, such sale to be first duly advertised daily for 1 week in some newspaper published in the City of Washington, and to be at public auction to the highest bidder. When street railways cross any street or avenue, the pavement between the tracks of such railway shall conform to the pavement used upon such street or avenue, and the companies owning these intersecting railroads shall pay for such pavements in the same manner and proportion as required of other railway companies under the provisions of this section.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 45-2-ch180" path="§5">June 11, 1878, 20 Stat. 106, ch. 180, § 5</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Jan. 14, 1933, 47 Stat. 759, ch. 10, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Anacostia Bridge, Anacostia and Potomac River Railroad Company, construction and repair costs, collection, see § <cite path="§9-305">9-305</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Bridges across Rock Creek, railway installations, construction and repair costs, collection, see § <cite path="§9-303">9-303</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Bridges, construction and repair costs, collection of liens against railway and canal companies, see § <cite path="§9-302">9-302</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Special assessments, power of mayor to alter, see § <cite path="§47-1202">47-1202</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-302">9-302</cite>, § <cite path="§9-303">9-303</cite>, § <cite path="§9-305">9-305</cite>, § <cite path="§9-401.09">9-401.09</cite>, and § <cite path="§9-401.10">9-401.10</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-604.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-604.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The Capital Transit Company, referred to twice near the middle of this section, has been succeeded by the D.C. Transit System, Inc.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
