<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-401.09</num>
  <heading>Paving or resurfacing roadway of streets, avenues, and roads.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Whenever under appropriations made by Congress, the roadway of any street, avenue, or road in the District of Columbia is improved by laying a new pavement thereon or completely resurfacing the same not less than 1 square in extent, from curb to curb, or from gutter to gutter where no curb exists, where the material used is sheet asphalt, asphalt block, asphaltic or bituminous macadam, concrete, or other fixed roadway pavement, such proportion of the total cost of the work, including all expenses of the assessment, to be made as prescribed by § <cite path="§9-401.10">9-401.10</cite>, shall be charged against and become a lien upon the abutting property, and assessments therefor shall be levied pro rata according to the linear frontage of said property on the street, avenue, or road, or portion thereof upon the roadway of which said new pavement or resurfacing is laid; provided, that there shall be excepted from such assessment the cost of paving the roadway space included within the intersection of streets, avenues, and roads, as said intersections are included within the building lines projected, and also the cost of paving the space within such roadways for which street railway companies are responsible under their charters or under law on streets, avenues, or roads where such railways have been or shall be constructed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All of the expenses of maintenance and repairs shall be paid from the revenues of the District of Columbia and in addition, such sums as may be appropriated out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as relieving street railway companies from bearing one-half the expense of paving streets or avenues between the exterior rails of the tracks of their roads in the District of Columbia and for a distance of 2 feet from and exterior to such tracks on each side thereof and of keeping the same in repair, as required by § <cite path="§9-401.01">9-401.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 21, 1914, 38 Stat. 524, ch. 191</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 29, 1914, 38 Stat. 565, ch. 215</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Jan. 14, 1933, 47 Stat. 759, ch. 10, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Taxation and fiscal affairs, special assessments for public improvements, see § <cite path="§47-1201">47-1201</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-411.03">9-411.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-612.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-611.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
