<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-401.02</num>
  <heading>Removal of street railway tracks.</heading>
  <text>On and after July 1, 1941, when any Capital Transit Company street railway operation shall have been ordered abandoned by the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia and the Council of the District of Columbia shall have ordered the removal of abandoned tracks, the Capital Transit Company shall pay the entire cost of removing such abandoned tracks and regrading the track area, and, if the street or bridge in which the said tracks have been ordered abandoned is not being paved, the Capital Transit Company shall pay the entire cost of paving the abandoned track areas, which cost, however, shall not exceed the cost of repaving such abandoned track areas with the type, character, and thickness of the paving of the adjacent roadway left in place, and, if the roadway of the street or bridge is being paved at the time of removal of said abandoned tracks, the Capital Transit Company shall pay one-half of the actual cost of paving the abandoned track areas, irrespective of whether the paving is of the type, character, and thickness as that existing at the time of said removal. The Council of the District of Columbia is authorized to settle in conformity with the principles herein set forth, any claims it now has, or in the future may have, for the paving of abandoned track areas, upon such terms and conditions as to time of payment or payments as the Council may determine.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 77-1-ch271" path="">July 1, 1941, 55 Stat. 533, ch. 271</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-503" type="History">Aug. 30, 1964, 78 Stat. 634, Pub. L. 88-503, § 21</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-605.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-604a.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The Capital Transit Company, referred to throughout this section, has been succeeded by the D.C. Transit System, Inc.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(170) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
