<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-421.01</num>
  <heading>Amount assessed; levied pro rata.</heading>
  <text>Whenever under the appropriations made by Congress, the roadway of any street, avenue, or road in the District of Columbia is paved or repaved with sheet asphalt, asphalt block, asphaltic or bituminous concrete (except penetration macadam), cement concrete, granite block, vitrified brick, or other form of permanent pavement, one-half of the total cost thereof shall be charged against and become a lien upon the abutting property, and assessments therefor shall be levied pro rata according to the linear frontage of said property on the street, avenue, or road, or portion thereof, upon the roadway of which said new pavement or repaving is laid; provided, however, that when such new pavement or repaving is laid solely on 1 side of the centerline of such roadway, the one-half cost thereof shall be assessed, as herein provided, against the property abutting the side of the street, avenue, or road, or portion thereof, so improved.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 20, 1931, 46 Stat. 1197, ch. 246, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Street construction and maintenance, streets with concurrent railroad tracks, allocation of costs, see § <cite path="§9-1203.07">9-1203.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-411.03">9-411.03</cite>, § <cite path="§9-411.04">9-411.04</cite>, § <cite path="§9-421.02">9-421.02</cite>, § <cite path="§9-421.07">9-421.07</cite>, § <cite path="§9-421.09">9-421.09</cite>, § <cite path="§9-421.11">9-421.11</cite>, and § <cite path="§9-421.12">9-421.12</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-627.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-622.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
