<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-425.02</num>
  <heading>Notice and design requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall provide notice to affected parties, the affected Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, and the Councilmembers of the affected Wards, prior to designing and constructing new sidewalks. At a minimum, this notice shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A statement of intent to design and construct a new sidewalk no less than 60 days before construction is scheduled, including a 30-day period for public comment on the proposed design;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statement of how affected parties can comment on the proposed sidewalk, including a statement on how Advisory Neighborhood Commissions can submit resolutions on the potential impact of the proposed sidewalk; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A construction schedule.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall maintain for public review comments from affected parties received pursuant to subsection (a)(2) of this section and responses thereto.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall design sidewalks in a manner that preserves the health of existing trees wherever possible.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The recommendations of the affected Advisory Neighborhood Commission shall be given great weight, as that term is described in § <cite path="§1-309.10">1-309.10</cite>(d)(3)(A).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Whenever feasible, the Mayor shall consider pervious materials for the design and installation of sidewalks.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “affected parties” means residents with property abutting the road segment under consideration.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-227" type="History" path="§3">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-227, § 3, 57 DCR 6923</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
