<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-503</num>
  <heading>Failure to provide required illumination; testing facilities.</heading>
  <text>Proportionate deductions shall be made from the amounts due lighting companies for failure to furnish the illumination required by law for public lighting in the District of Columbia, and each company shall furnish, at its own expense, when and as required by the Mayor of the District of Columbia, all proper and necessary facilities, testing places, and apparatus at its plant, and such help at points on its mains or circuits as to enable the said Mayor to determine whether the required illumination is being furnished. For each and every lamp which shall be extinguished or not lighted during any portion of the scheduled time of lighting, a pro rata deduction, based upon the period of nonillumination and the price per lamp, shall be made from said amounts.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 61-3-ch192" path="§8">Mar. 2, 1911, 36 Stat. 1011, ch. 192, § 8</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-703.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-703.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
