<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-508</num>
  <heading>Washington Terminal Company to pay for certain street lighting.</heading>
  <text>The Washington Terminal Company, its successors, or transferees shall pay to the District for the lighting of the streets, avenues, alleys, and grounds over and under which its right-of-way may cross, as well as for the lighting of those streets, avenues, alleys, and grounds bordering on its right-of-way, under the direction and control of the Mayor of the District of Columbia and in case of default of payment of such bills, actions at law may be maintained by the District of Columbia against said terminal company or its successors, or transferees therefor; provided, that not more than $85 per annum shall be paid for any electric arc light burning from 15 minutes after sunset to 45 minutes before sunrise, and operated wholly by means of underground wire; and each arc light shall be of not less than 1000 actual candlepower; provided further, that no more than $18 per annum shall be paid for each gas lamp equipped with a self-regulating flat-flame burner so adjusted as to secure under all ordinary variations of pressure and density a consumption of 5 cubic feet of gas per hour, nor more than $20.85 per annum for each gas lamp and $22.80 per annum for each oil lamp equipped with an incandescent mantle burner of not less than 60 candlepower.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 26, 1908, 35 Stat. 287, 288, ch. 198</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-509">9-509</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-708.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-708.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
