<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-606</num>
  <heading>Failure of owner or occupant to remove — Suit to recover cost.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon finding of a violation of § <cite path="§9-601">9-601</cite>, the Mayor may issue a notice of infraction to a residential or commercial property.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person authorized to issue a notice of infraction for a violation of § <cite path="§9-601">9-601</cite> shall not issue the notice to a residential property owner for a violation unless the violation continues to exist 24 hours after the snow or sleet has ceased to fall.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For a residential property, the fine for a violation of § <cite path="§9-601">9-601</cite> shall be no more than $25.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For a commercial property, the fine for a violation of § <cite path="§9-601">9-601</cite> shall be $150.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding a residential or commercial property owner’s delegation of the owner’s responsibility to comply with § <cite path="§9-601">9-601</cite>, the owner shall remain liable for payment of a fine issued in accordance with this section; provided, that a property owner may seek reimbursement in the amount of the fine from a tenant, occupant, lessee, or other individual pursuant to the delegation of the owner’s responsibility in a written agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No property owner shall be fined more than once per day per property for a violation of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A residential property owner who is 65 years of age or older or who has a disability shall not be found in violation of this chapter, and shall qualify for an exemption.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, a residential property owner shall qualify as having a disability if the owner has been determined to have a disability pursuant to a government assistance program or has evidence from a medical doctor that he or she is unable to, or should not, undertake the physical activity required to remove sleet or snow.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>On or before December 1st of each year, the Mayor shall publicize through public media the obligation to remove sleet or snow pursuant to § <cite path="§9-601">9-601</cite> and the penalties that might be enforced for failure to comply.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Infractions of this chapter shall be adjudicated pursuant to Chapter 8 of Title 8 [§ <cite path="§8-801">8-801</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 67-2-ch318" path="§6">Sept. 16, 1922, 42 Stat. 846, ch. 318, § 6</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-211" type="History">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-211, § 2(d), 61 DCR 13074</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-906.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-806.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-211">D.C. Law 20-211</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
