<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-701</num>
  <heading>Administration of Airport; definitions.</heading>
  <text>That for the purposes of this chapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Airport” means the Washington National Airport, which shall consist of, and include, the tract of land, together with all structures, improvements, and other facilities located thereon, lying partly in the District of Columbia, and partly in the State of Virginia, particularly described as follows: Commencing at a point of beginning, said point being the intersection of the property line of property owned by the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad Company, and dredging base line at station 0+18.99 referenced south 6,808.21, west 9,078.02, running in a southeasterly direction on a bearing of south 22°51′18″ east a distance of 6,270.91 feet, more or less, to station 62+89.90 of said dredging base line. Thence 13°30′ right on a bearing of south 9°21′18″ east a distance of 1,332.29 feet, more or less, to station 76+22.19 of said base line. Thence 11°04′19″ right on a bearing of south 1°43′01″ west a distance of 1,231.20 feet, more or less, to station 88+53.39 of said base line. Thence 12°40′41″ right on a bearing of south 14°23′42″ west a distance of 2,409.32 feet, more or less, to station 112+62.71 on said base line. Thence 1°15′44.3″ right on a bearing of south 15°39′26.3″ west a distance of 4,938.38 feet, more or less, to United States Coast and Geodetic Survey Station WATER, referenced south 22,220.86, west 8,395.54. Thence 17°09′25.6″ left on a bearing of south 1°29′59.3″ east a distance of 85.58 feet, more or less, to a corner of the property line between the United States of America and Smoot Sand and Gravel Corporation. Thence 85°59′59.3″ right on a bearing of south 84°30′00″ west a distance of 1,516.41 feet, more or less, to a monument located at a corner on the property line of the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad Company, said monument being referenced south 22,451.75, west 9,902.73. Thence 85°50′06.7″ right on a bearing of north 8°09′54″ west a distance of 442.68 feet, more or less. Thence 5°00′12″ left on a bearing of north 13°10′06″ west a distance of 578.64 feet, more or less. Thence 4°57′25″ left on a bearing of north 18°07′31″ west a distance of 462.94 feet, more or less. Thence 1°34′50″ left on a bearing of north 19°42′21″ west a distance of 943.56 feet, more or less, to the point of a curve having an angle of 27°52′45″ right radius 1,241.15 feet, long chord 597.98 feet, on a bearing of north 5°45′58″ west. Thence along the arc of said curve a distance of 603.92 feet, more or less, to the point of tangency of said curve. Thence along a tangent to said curve on a bearing of north 8°10′24″ east a distance of 232.33 feet, more or less, to the point of a curve having an angle of 36°59′09″ left, radius 1,046 feet, long chord 663.56 feet on a bearing of north 10°19′10.5″ west. Thence along the arc of said curve a distance of 675.22 feet, more or less, to the point of tangency of said curve. Thence along a tangent to said curve on a bearing of north 28°48′45″ west a distance of 256.75 feet, more or less. Thence 30°33′10″ left on a bearing of north 59°21′55″ west a distance of 287.84 feet, more or less. Thence 40°45′20″ right on a bearing of north 18°36′35″ west a distance of 1,142.08 feet, more or less. Thence 5°43′29″ right on a bearing of north 12°53′06″ west a distance of 118.02 feet, more or less, to the point of a curve having an angle of 26°20′50″ right, radius 3,665.71 feet, long chord 1,670.85 feet on a bearing of north 0°17′19″ east. Thence along the arc of said curve a distance of 1,685.66 feet, more or less, to the point of tangency of said curve. Thence along a tangent to said curve on a bearing of north 13°27′44″ east a distance of 2,002.11 feet, more or less, to the point of a curve having an angle of 10°36′25″ left, radius 2,864.79 feet, long chord of 529.59 feet on a bearing of north 8°09′31.5″ east. Thence along the arc of said curve a distance of 530.25 feet, more or less, to the point of tangency of said curve. Thence along a tangent to said curve on a bearing of north 2°51′19″ east a distance of 124.53 feet, more or less. Thence 6°57′52″ left on a bearing of north 4°06′33″ west a distance of 571.33 feet, more or less. Thence 7°22′39″ left on a bearing of north 11°29′12′′ west a distance of 811.63 feet, more or less. Thence 8°16′52″ right on a bearing of north 3°12′20″ east a distance of 70.41 feet, more or less, to the point of a curve having an angle of 7°43′12″ right, radius 5,479.58 feet, long chord 737.75 feet on a bearing of north 7°03′56″ east. Thence along the arc of said curve a distance of 738.31 feet, more or less, to the point of tangency of said curve, said point being on the old property line between Mary E. Cullinane and Milton Hopfenmaier property. Thence along said property line on a bearing of north 75°11′50″ east a distance of 204.72 feet, more or less, to a monument marked U. S. D. 1-N. P. S., reference south 18,419.16, west 10,829.26. Thence along the same bearing of north 75°11′50″ east a distance of 215 feet, more or less. Thence 34°36′06″ left on a bearing of north 40°35′44″ east a distance of 1,509 feet, more or less, to the point of a curve having an angle of 5°45′ left, radius 7,239.41 feet, long chord of 723.20 feet, on a bearing of north 37°53′14″ east. Thence along the arc of said curve a distance of 726.51 feet, more or less, to the point of a compound curve having an angle of 6°00′ left, radius 2,217.01 feet, long chord of 232.06 feet on a bearing of north 32°10′44″ east. Thence along the arc of said curve a distance of 232.15 feet, more or less, to the point of a compound curve having an angle of 57°01′20″ left, radius 1,303.74, long chord 1,244.62, on a bearing of north 0°40′04″ east. Thence along the arc of said curve a distance of 1,297.22 feet, more or less, to the point of a compound curve having an angle of 7°59′54.3″ left, radius 2,217.01 feet, long chord 309.23 feet on a bearing of north 31°49′33″ west. Thence along the arc of said curve a distance of 310 feet, more or less, to the intersection of said curve with the property line of the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad Company and the United States of America. Thence in a northeasterly direction along a bearing of north 34°30′00″ east a distance of 340 feet, more or less, to the point of beginning; excepting, however, such portion thereof as the President may, by executive order or orders, prescribe, which portion shall be added to, and administered as part of, the Mount Vernon Memorial Highway, authorized by the Act approved May 23, 1928 (45 Stat. 721), as amended.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>June 29, 1940, 54 Stat. 686, ch. 444, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-726">Aug. 23, 1958, 72 Stat. 807, Pub. L. 85-726, title XIV, § 1402(f)</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 7-1101.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 7-1301.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Transfer of Functions</heading>
      <annotation>The functions of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Agency were transferred to the Secretary of Transportation by § 6(c)(1) of the Act of October 15, 1966, Pub. L. 89-670. The Federal Aviation Agency was abolished and a new Federal Aviation Administration in the Department of Transportation was created by §§ 3(e)(1) and 9(f) of that Act.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority established: <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-67">D.C. Law 6-67</cite>, effective December 3, 1985, endorsed on behalf of the District government the creation of a regional airport authority to acquire Washington National Airport and Washington Dulles International Airport from the federal government. <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-67">D.C. Law 6-67</cite> was amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-18">D.C. Law 7-18</cite>, effective July 25, 1987.</text>
      <text><cite doc="D.C. Law 6-67">D.C. Law 6-67</cite> was amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-179">D.C. Law 8-179</cite>, effective October 2, 1990.</text>
      <text><cite doc="D.C. Law 6-67">D.C. Law 6-67</cite> was temporarily amended by the District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985 Emergency Amendment Act of 1991 (D.C. Act 9-72, July 24, 1991,  38 DCR 4959) and by § 2 of the District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985 Congressional Recess Emergency Amendment Act of 1992 (D.C. Act 9-275, July 23, 1992,  39 DCR 5849).</text>
      <text><cite doc="D.C. Law 8-179">D.C. Law 8-179</cite> was temporarily repealed by § 3 of the District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985 Emergency Amendment Act of 1991 (D.C. Act 9-72, July 24, 1991,  38 DCR 4959) and by § 3 of the District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985 Congressional Recess Emergency Amendment Act of 1992 (D.C. Act 9-275, July 23, 1992,  39 DCR 5849).</text>
      <text><cite doc="D.C. Law 6-67">D.C. Law 6-67</cite> was amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-158">D.C. Law 9-158</cite>, effective September 29, 1992.</text>
      <text>Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority established: <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-67">D.C. Law 6-67</cite> was amended, on a temporary basis, by § 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-48">D.C. Law 9-48</cite>.</text>
      <text><cite doc="D.C. Law 8-179">D.C. Law 8-179</cite> was repealed, on a temporary basis, by § 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-48">D.C. Law 9-48</cite>.</text>
      <text><cite doc="D.C. Law 8-179">D.C. Law 8-179</cite> was repealed by § 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-158">D.C. Law 9-158</cite>.</text>
      <text>Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority established: <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-67">D.C. Law 6-67</cite> was amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-8">D.C. Law 12-8</cite>, effective August 1, 1997.</text>
      <text>Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority established: <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-67">D.C. Law 6-67</cite> was amended on a temporary basis by § 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-199">D.C. Law 12-199</cite>.</text>
      <text>Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-199">D.C. Law 12-199</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
      <text><cite doc="D.C. Law 6-67">D.C. Law 6-67</cite> was temporarily amended by § 2 of the Regional Airports Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-436, July 31, 1998,  45 DCR 5746),§ 2 of the Regional Airports Authority Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-502, November 10, 1998,  45 DCR 8125), and § 2 of the Regional Airports Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-578, January 12, 1999,  46 DCR 964).</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
