<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-808</num>
  <heading>Authority to make arrests; Park Police patrol.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Administrator and any Federal Aviation Agency employee appointed to protect life and property on the airport, when designated by the Administrator, is hereby authorized and empowered:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To arrest under a warrant within the limits of the airport any person accused of having committed within the boundaries of the airport any offense against the laws of the United States, or against any rule or regulation prescribed pursuant to this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To arrest without warrant any person committing any such offense within the limits of the airport, in his presence; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To arrest without warrant within the limits of the airport any person whom he has reasonable grounds to believe has committed a felony within the limits of the airport.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any individual having the power of arrest as provided in subsection (a) of this section may carry firearms or other weapons as the Administrator may direct or by regulation may prescribe.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The United States Park Police may, at the request of the Administrator, be assigned by the Secretary of the Interior, in his discretion, to patrol any area of the airport, and any members of the United States Park Police so assigned are hereby authorized and empowered to make arrests within the limits of the airport for the same offenses and in the same manner and circumstances as are provided in this section with respect to employees designated by the Administrator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The officer on duty in command of those employees designated by the Administrator as provided in subsection (a) of this section may accept deposit of collateral from any person charged with the violation of any rule or regulation prescribed under this chapter, for appearance in court or before the appropriate United States Magistrate; and such collateral shall be deposited with such United States Magistrate.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Sept. 7, 1950, 64 Stat. 772, ch. 905, § 8</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-726" type="History">Aug. 23, 1958, 72 Stat. 807, Pub. L. 85-726, title XIV, § 1402(g)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Arrests without warrant, see § <cite path="§23-581">23-581</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">United States Park Police, authority to arrest, see § <cite path="§5-206">5-206</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-1208.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-1408.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
