<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-910</num>
  <heading>Revenue bonds.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Authority may provide by resolution for the issuance, at 1 time or from time to time, of revenue bonds of the Authority for the purpose of paying all or any part of the cost of Authority facilities, including the refunding of federal appropriations not reimbursed to the United States Treasury by the Metropolitan Washington Airports. The principal of and the interest on these bond shall be payable solely from the funds provided for this payment. The bonds of each issue shall be dated, shall mature at times not exceeding 40 years form their dates, as may be determined by the Authority, and may be subject to redemption or repurchase before maturity, at the option of the Authority, at prices and under those terms and conditions may be fixed by the Authority before the issuance of the bonds. The bonds may bear interest payable at times and at rates as determined by the Authority or as determined in the manner as the Authority may provide, including the determination by agents designated by the Authority under guidelines established by it. The Authority shall determine the form and the manner of execution of the bonds, including any interest coupons to be attached to the bonds, and shall fix the denominations of the bonds and the places of payment of principal and interest, which may be at any bank or trust company within or without the District of Columbia. In case any officer whose signature or a facsimile shall be valid and sufficient for all purposes the same as if the officer had remained  in office until delivery. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or any recitals in any bonds issued under the provisions of this section, all bonds shall be considered to be negotiable instruments under the laws of the District. The bonds may be issued in coupon or in registered form, or both, as the Authority may determine, and provision may be made for the registration of any coupon bonds as to principal alone and also as to both principal and interest, for the reconversion into coupon bonds of any bonds registered as to both principal and interest, and for the interchange of registered and coupon bonds. The Authority may sell bonds in the manner, either at public or negotiated sale, and for the price, as it may determine will best effect the purposes of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The proceeds of the bonds shall be used solely for the payment of the cost of Authority facilities, including improvements, and shall be disbursed in the manner and under the restrictions, if any, as the Authority may provide in the resolution authorizing the issuance of the bonds or in the trust agreement securing the bonds. If the proceeds of the bonds of any issue, by error of estimates or otherwise, shall be less than the cost, additional bonds may in like manner be issued to provide the amount of the deficit, and, unless otherwise provided in the resolution authorizing the issuance of the bonds or in the trust agreements securing the bonds, shall be considered to be of the same issue and shall be entitled to payment from the same fund without preference or priority of the bonds first issued. If the proceeds of the bonds of any issue shall exceed the cost, the surplus shall be deposited to the credit of the sinking fund for the bonds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before the preparation of definitive bonds, the Authority may, under the same restrictions, issue interim receipts or temporary bonds, with or without coupons, exchangeable for definitive bonds when the bonds have been executed and are available for delivery. The Authority may also provide for the replacement of any bonds that become mutilated or have been destroyed or lost. Bonds may be issued under the provisions of this section without obtaining the consent of any agency of the District and without any other proceedings, conditions or things not specifically required by this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-67" type="History">Dec. 3, 1985, D.C. Law 6-67, § 11, 32 DCR 6093</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-1260.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
