<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-107">
  <num type="law">7-107</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Fund Amendment Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-05-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-107.pdf">D.C. Law 7-107</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 2176</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-107, “District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Fund Amendment Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-266, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 16, 1988 and March 1, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 16, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-149 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCil OF THE DISTRICT OF COL UMBIA IIOTl CE D.C. LA W 7- 107 Olst rict of Columbia Taxicab Com miss ion Fund A.endmen t Act of 1985 Pursua nt to Section 412 of the Dis tr ic t of Colurabta Se l f- Govern~ent ~nd Go vernm en t al Re o rgan lz~tjon Ac t. P. L. 93-1 98 the Act t he Council o f th e Dist ri c t o f Co\ ulllbi a a dop te d Bill No. 7- 266 on f i rst and second r eadings February 16. 1988 an d MarCh 1. 1988 r@spect lvel y. Follo wing th e signa t ure of the 'b yor on 4fCh 16. 1988 this l egis l at io n as ISs igned Act No 7-1 4 9 published i n th e MHeh 25 1988 edition o f the D. C. Re g i ster Vol 35 page 2176) and tran sraitted to Con 9 r ess on Mar Ch 21 1988 for a 3D day r ev i ew, In ac cordance wi th Section 6 02(c)(l) of the Act. The Coun ct l of the District of Co lull bia hHeby gives noti ce that t he lD day Con&amp;lt;j r esslonal Review Period hu uptred and the r e fo r e, cI tes this enae tme nt as D.C La w 1-107 effettlYe Ma y 10 1988 DAV I O A. CL ~RK&amp;lt;,r-\P"!1"l halrman of the CounCil Dates Co unted Dur ing the 10-d ay Cong r essional Revie w Period: Mar t h 21 22.23 ,24, 25 28 ,29,3 0 31 Apr il 11.1 2 13.1 4.15,1 8.19.20,21.22,25.26 27,28,29 !tay 2 3 .4, 5 6.9 D.UAW 7- 1 07 Enrolled Or 181~ol AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 14 9 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA lIAR I 19113 To a~end the Dtst ict of colu~bia Taxicab Como issto n Es t ablishmen t Act ot 19 85 to establish the District of col umbia Taxicab Commission Fund. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THC DISTRICT Of COLr;'llBIA, That this act ~4y be ci ted as t he District of Columbia Taxicab Conmis~\on Fund Amendment Ace o f 1988 sec. 2. The DistCict of Columbia Taxicab Commi ssion ElStllblt sh""ent Act of I H!5 effect we ~larch 25 1986 (D C Law 6- 97 D.C. Code, sec. 40-1 701 at seg. J, is amended by addinq II. new section 200 to read as tollows Sec 20a a l The re 15 established within the Dis tr ic t of Columb ia treasury a f iduciary fund t o be known as the Dis trict of Columbia Taxicab Comm ission Fund Fund This Fund shall consist of all assessments lev ied by the Public Se r vice Commission o f the O\strict of C0 1 u~bta against taxicab operators upon the issuance and renewal of a publ ic vehicle operatot's identi fication lIcense I ssued pursuan t to pa~agraph 3 1 o f section 1 o f An Act making apptove~atiOn5 t o provide for the expenses ot the 90vernmen t at the Dis te ict of Columbia for the tiscal year ending J une t hir t ie t h, nineteen hundred and three and fo r other pueposes approved July 1, 1902 (32 St at 626; D.C. Code sec 4 7- 2829\e held in a i scellaneous teust f undS by the Publlc Service Com~i sston of t he Disteic t of Co l u~bia a nd t he Office of the People 's Couns e l p t \o r to the effec tive date of the District. of Colymbia Taxicab Cor.tmisslon Fund Amendment Emergency Act of 1987, effective June 23 1987 D.C. Act 7- 42; 34 OCR 4507 pu o:suant t o parllgraph 4 2 11) of sect ion B of An Act ktng apvropr iations to provide f or the e xpenses of t he 90v ernment of the District o f Co lu~bia for the fisca l year endin9 June thlrtieth, nineteen hundred and f ou e teen. and for other pu eposes. approved a rch 4, 1913 7 Sta t 974; D. C. Code sec 43- 612(01 hese fund S sh a ll be accounted for unde r procedures establiShed pursu ant to thu 1 lt;elol D. C. Cod sec. 40- l720 (1989 pp Luro~1'4 Orig1D~1 District of Columbia Fund AccQunting Act of 1980. effective June 14, 1980 (D C Law 3- 7 0 D. C. CoCle, sec. 47- 371 seg o r any or.her ~pplicab le law b The Fund shall be used exclusively by the Commis sion f o r the payment of i ts expe nses arising fr om any investigation or proceeding by the Commission concerning tax icab ratea and regulations e) Afte r June 2 4, 1987, continued resou rces fo r t.he Pund shall be provided through an assessment levied against taxicab ope r ato rs as dete~lned by Commission rul e. Monies deposited into the Fund after June 24, 1987, Shal l b. used by t.he COGmlssion for a ny investigat.ion or proceeding by the Comm ission concerning t.axicab rates and regu la tions as dete~ined by rules p romulgated by the Com~isston and submitted t o the Co uncil for approval, in whole or in part, hy resolut ion. No a s sessment imposed by the C~mission on an operator pursuan t to this subsection Shall exceed $50 per year. Nothi ng in thi s subsectio n shall affect any require~en t s imposed upon t he Commission by title I of the District of columbia ~mtnistrative Procedure Act, approved Octobe r 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, lIIec 1-1501 et .ll.!l d he COQmiss ion sha l l not continue t o assess whenever mo re than $4 00 00 0 i, accumu lated in t he Fund e) On October 15th of each year the Commissi on Shall submit to the Council a plan for the use of all monies in the Fund he proposed plan sha ll be sub~itted to the Counc tl f o r approval, in Whole or i n pa rt, by resolut ion. The expe ndi t u re o f monies in the ~und shall be sub j ect to Council approval of the annual plan. NOthing in thi s subleCtion shall affect any reguirements impoled upon the CommiSSion by title I of the Oistri&amp;lt;;t of Columbia Admin l.strative Procedu ["e A&amp;lt;;t, app["ov e d October 21, 1968 182 Stat. 12 0 4 D.C Code sec. 1- 1501 et "eg 1 tf) On November lst at each year the Commission shall submit an annual ["eport to t he Council on all ass es sment income ["eceived and disburse~ents made from t he Fund dU["ing the p["evious fiscal year Sec. 3. This act shall take ef fect after a 30- day pef~od of Congressional [" eview follow ing approval by the Mayo r (0[" in the event of veto by the ~Iayor, action by the Counc. l of t he District of Co lumbia t o override t he veto l as p o v ided in sec t ion 602Ic)11 o f the Olstric t of Co l u~bia Self -Government a nd Governmental Reorganization Act approved December 1- 2JJ(c)(1 24, 1'17J (87 Stat. 813; D. C Code, sec. Council of the DtStcict of Columbia APPROVED: March 16, 1988 3 \ CQU:&amp;gt;ICIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUl\mIA Cuuncil Period Seven 110m on Co n t COl RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTe DOCKET NO, Z OTION &amp;amp DATE lt;:lopted First Reading, 2-16-88 t VOICE VOT E cA P'P 02'!v dL Recorded ,ote on "Quo" Schwartz Ab.on1: C ROLL CALL VOTE RES ULT 11 a n Conse n' Calendar B7-266 Dale Il&amp;lt ACTION &amp;amp DATE A":dCO"Pctc"d,;F,!i,n,.c R d"i,n"gL 3e 8,8 l( VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded 'oto 0" req uest Ab,.nl' Crawford o.t C nl Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; D"'TE C VO ICE von: R, cord ed "ole on « quo Ab.en Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
