<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-106">
  <num type="law">7-106</num>
  <heading type="short">New Streets or Alleys Amendment Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-05-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-106.pdf">D.C. Law 7-106</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 2170</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-106, the “New Streets or Alleys Amendment Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-100, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 16, 1988 and March 1, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 16, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-148 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>• COU~C1L Of THE DISTRICT Of caL~ H8IA KOT ICE o.c. LAW 7-1 06 'Me w Streets o~ Alley. Amendment Ac t of 1988 Pursuant to Section 412 o f tne Dis tr ict of Colu ilbh Sel f- Gove rn me nt dn d Gov~rnment~l ~eo rg.n jz at lon A,t, P. L. 93 }98 the Act the Counc i l o f th Dis tri ct o f (o lu.bla adopted Bill Ko 1- 100 on first dnd seconJ re a di ngs february 16, 1988 and l1 a r c~ 1. 1988. res pectiv ely follo wln 3 the signature o f the May or o n fot arch 15, 1988. t hl i legisl a tion \; u assi gne d Ac t o 1 148, pub lished In t he Marc" 2S 1988 e d ition of t he D. C. Register Vo l. ]5 page 2170 n d trd"s~ ttte d t o Co ngress on Harch 21 1988 for a lD day rev ie w, in acc o r d~n c e wI th Section 602(e)(l) of the Act The Council o f the Distric t o f Columbi a h@reby 9iveS notiLe tlldt tile 3 day Con9ressional Revi e w Period hdS expired, dnd t~e efore ci tes t~l s !Hctment as O.C l dW 1-106 effe&amp;lt;;t l ve Ma y 10 1988 G L DA~ID A. CLA~KE Clld irman of t~e Counti] Oate$ Cou nted Ou r in9 the 30·day Congr ess i o na l Revle Per io ol: Ma r cil 21 22 23 24 ,25 28 29 30 31 Apri Itt 12 13 14 15 18.1 9 20 21 22 25 26 27 28,Z9 May 2 3, 4. 5 .6.9 D.C.LAW 7-106 Tj MAY! 0 1988 AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 -14 8 IN THE COU~CIL OF THE DIS~RICT OF COLUMBIA lIAR 1 6 1988 o amend the Street and Alley Closing and Acqui.sition Procedures Act of 1982 to requi.re Counci.l revie~ of proposals to construct ne~ streets t hat have not been constructed withi.n 10 ye a rs of acqui.si.ti.on by the District of Columbia, to requi.re promulgation by the ~layor of stan daT;ds governi.ng the acquisition and construction of new streets and alleys in the District of Columbia, to require publ~cati.on by the Mayor of a map del i.neat ing all acqui. red 'and unacqu i. red streets tha t a Ce functi.oning Or planned as streets in the District of Columbia, to ceguixe the ayor to submi.t a report to the Council on the highway plan for the District of Columbia, to require solicitation by the ~jayor of comments from affected advisory neighborhood commissions on any proposals to acquire or improve land for street or alley purposes, to require solicitation by the Mayor of comments from affected advisory neighborhood commissions on any proposals to close streets or alleys prior to submission of these proposals to the Council, and to shorten from 30 days to 15 days the notice of public hearing that the Council is required to provide the public and the affected advisory neighborhood commission o n proposals to close streets or alleys; and to revise the procedures for public not ice of proposed changes to the highway plan BE I'i' ENACTED BY THE CODNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF CCLD~1BIA hat this act may be cited as the "New Streets Or Alleys Amendment Act of 1988 Sec 2 he Street and Al ley Cl osing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March la, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-201; D.C. Code sec 7-411 et seq is amended as follows: 1 Enrol led Or18~ael (a) By aoc lng new sections 306 to 309 at the end of sabchap ter III to read as foll ows Sec. 306 a Pri o r t o the lcprovelDent o r issuance o f a yerci t: t o t roprove a street that has been aCGutred f o r street purposes b y t he Oistrict but has neithe r been tmpr o ved no t u see as a ublic r ight-o f-way for vehicles within 10 years o f l ts acqutsaton, t hl laYOt shall submi t a proposed s treet tmp rovement a proposed resoluti on to conSider the pro~osed il:1provement, and luppo tting documents regarding the proposed im~rovement t o tne CounCil for a 4S- day period of revi ew, exclud lng ~aturdays undays, holldays, and days of Counci l recess If the Counct l does not approve or disapprove the p r o posed ir.lp r over:Jen t, in Wh o le or tn pa ri b y reso lution wi thin t h is 4 S- day r e v i ew period, the proposed t~provement Shdll be deemed appr oved, and t he ~1ayor roay ~prove o r i ssue a pe r l:1 it: to lmpr o ve the stteet [b) Pt:i o r t o submitting the tesolution t o t he Counc i} requ ired in Subsec tion (a) of tnts section the Mayo r shall Bolic Lt comments on the proposed tmprove~ent from ap~ ropriate e~ecut~ve branch agencies and public u tili tie the advisory neighbothood commi ssion within whose area the s tree t is l ocated and each o 'mar of property with.in the s quares adjacent t o th.e street t o be i~proved c) The suppo rt inq documents required to be submtt ted t o th Council by subsection (a) of this section shall t n c l ude a t a mt n i mum I) A SU t"veyor s plat showing the street ~topo sed to be impt"oved; a listing by name addres s and lot and sgua re numbet" s of each owner of property wi thtn the squa res adjacent to the street to be improved; and t he date a nd method of acquisition by the Ci strict of the s t reet 2) Comments on the proposed improvement f[o~ appropriate Oistric t agenc ies and pub l ic u ti lities, inc lud ing info rmation regard ing A) Any buildinq or develop~ent plans a nd any ft led ~oni ng eases related t o the proposed im~roveme n t B) rhe ccnf o t: r.l i ty of the proposea im~rovement and any associated develo ~ment with the polictes and land use designations set f o rth in the Distri c t of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 198 4, effect ive April 10, 19B 4 (D.C Law S- 76; 31 OCR 1 0 49 ane 32 OCR 873 C) r he presen t a na future traffic needs t o be se rved by the proposed improvement, any alternat ive means o f s ervin g those needs that have been considered and an a~sessment of the unpact o f the p r oposed imp r o vement and any aSJocia ted ceve l o pment o n tta ffic circulation, parking avatlab ility, and envl[o ~ental conditions in the s urro unding arca 2 D.C. CodE s ec. i 6 (1989 supp Enrolled Or1~t H D he total costs associated wi th the 2ropo sed l~frovement, including the costs of the pro~osed i~provement and future malnten~nce of the street, and whether those costs are to be borne by the District or by a t:-r"lvate r;-drty 1 The probable assessed value of the land to be improved for street purposes, and the existing condition and uSe of this land F he assessed values of the land and oUlldings on property within the squares that abut the street to be improved; and G) Any requirements or easements to be establiShed as conditions to approval of the proposed improvement; and 3) Certi.ficati.on by the ~layor or the ~jayor s agent that the affected advisory neighborhood commission and each owner of property within the squares adjacent to the street to be improved has been notified about the proposed improveme nt, and copies of any comments on the proposed improvement that have been received by the executive branch from the advisory neighborhood commission, property owners, or any other persons d r'h"ls section shall not 'apply to a proposal that cons,-sts of 1) Rehabllitat"lon, repalr, or reconstruction of a .street that is alreaey being used as a public ri.ght-of-way for vehicles at the time of the proposal; or 2) \.idening, realignment, or extension by 10 feet or less of the pavement of a street that is already being used as a public right- of-way for vehicles at the time of the ~roposal Sec. 307 a) Ilithin 6 months of the effective date of the Ne\; Streets or Alleys Amendment Act of 1'188, the Nayor shall, pursuant to title 1 of the Dlstrict of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat 1204; D. C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq lssue rules to govern the procedures and standards for acquiring and i~proving streets and alleys in the District of CaluQbia. These rules shall inclUde the establiShment of 1) Procedures by which notification and opportunity to comment shall be provided to the advisory neighborhOOd commission within whose area the street or alley is located 2) Procedures by which notification and opportunity to comment shall be provided to each owner of property within the squares adjacent to the street to be acquired or improved and within the square in which an alley is to be acquired or improved; and 3 New, J .C. Coc.e, sec. 7-&amp;amp;47 (1989 SUClTL 3) Standards for making 11 determi.nation that the acquisition or i~proveQent of a street Or alley ~ould ce in thO) pub lic interest, for evalc;ating the comments received from the affected advisory neighborhood co~mission and propet:ty O~l\erS ~ithin whose at:ea the stre et Or a1ley is located, and for assessing the criteria set forth in section 306(c)(2 b) Th ,g section shall not apply to a proposal that consists of 1) Rehabilitation, repair, Or reconstruction of a street or a lley tha t i.s already bei.ng used as a public right-of-way for vehicles a t the time of the proposal; Or 2) I,idening, realignment, or extension by 10 feet or less of the pa vement of a street Or alley that is already being used as a public ri.ght-af-way for vehicles at the time of the proposal Sec. 308 a) Ilithi.n 1 year of the effective da te of the New Streets Or Alleys Amendment Act of 1988, the ~layor shall submit a report to the Council on the highway plan for the Distr,ct of Columbia b he report shall includ 1) An updated list of each street that has been acquired but has nut been improved and does not function a s a public right-of-way for vehicles, including the locati.on of. the street, the date and method of iipproviil of the street On the highwa y plan if a pplicable, and the date and method of a cquiSitiOn of the street by the District 2) An updated list of each street on the highway plan that h as not been acquired by the Distri.ct, i ncluding the location of the street and the date and method of appt:oval of the street on the highway pliin; and 3) A list of each unimproved iicquired street and of eiich uniicquired street on the highway plan deterQined by the ayor to be no longer necessa ry for present or future street purposes iiccompanied by proposed legisliition iind sup~orting documents to close these unimproved acquired streets iind to remove these unacquired streets from the highway plan Sec. 309 a) \hthin 2 years of the effecttve date of the New Streets Or Alleys Amendment Act of 1988, a nd every 5 years thereafter, the ayor shall publish an official street map that delineates each street and property square in the District of Columbia b) 7his map shall distingu,sh between 1) St reets tha t hiive been improved, constructed, Or paved 2) Streets that have been acquired but have not been im~roved, constructed, Or piived; iind N D.C. Code sec. 7-448 (1989 supp lie D.C. Code 7-449 (1989 supp 3) Streets that are on the h ig hway plan but ha ve not been acquired and have not been ipproved, constructed, or Faved c h1S map shall be availab le for review in every public 11br~ry 1n the District and be availab l e for sale by the District of Colupbia Office of Documents b) By apending section 202 (D.C. Code, sec. 7-422) by addlng a ne paragraph (5) t o read as follo 'ls 5) Refer the applicati.on to the advisory ne i ghborhood commission in hose area the street Or a lley t o be closed lS located for i ts review, and provide the Counci.l ith a copy of any comments submitted by the a ffected adviso ry neighborhood oompissi.on and (0) By a.mending section 207 (D C. Code, sec. 7-427) by striking the number "30" and inserting the number "IS" in its place Sec. 3 a) Section 6 of An Act to a.mend an Act of Congress approved ~larch second, eighteen hundred dnd ni.r.ety-three, entitled "An Act to provide a permanent system of highways i n that part of the District of Columbia lyi.ng outside of cities a nd for other ~purposes, approved June 28, 1898 (30 Stat 520; D.C. Code, sec. 7-115 is amended to read a s follows Sec 6 a) At least 30 days prior to the submissions by. the 'layor of the Distri.ct of Columbia to the National Cap ital Planning Copmission and to the Council of the Distr i ct of Columbia for approvals of a proposed mod i f lcation to the permanent system of highways, the ayor shall provi.de written notice of an opportunity to submit comments on the proposed modification to 1) Each owner of land within the squares in WhICh or adjacent to which the proposed modif1cation is located by cegistered pall to the address to whiCh taxation not ifications are sent by the District of Columbia Department of Finance and Revenue1 2) Each advisory neighborhood commission within whose commission area the proFosed modIfication is locateC1 "oct 3) The publiC, by publishing the proposed modification in the District of Columbia Register b) Copies of comments received by the ~jayor shall be lncluded in any subsequent Submission by the Nayor to the Council of the District of Columbia of a resolution to conSIder the proposed modificatlon to the permanent system of hlgh\.Jays Sec. 4. This act shall take effect a.fter a 30- day period of Congressional review following approval by the "layor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the c. Code. s~c 7-427 (1989 SU?p D.C. Cod sec. 7-115 (1989 'lU9P Counc tl of the Dts t~tc t of Co l um~i4 t o ove~~tde the veto Frovid ed 1n SQc t ton 6 02 jc)il) of t he Olst~ict o f CoLumbia S~ l f -Gcve~nmen t and Governme n tal Reorgani za t ion AC t lt;1Ff t cved Decemoe~ 2 4, 1973 187 St at 813: D.C Code, sec 1- 233(cJ J lt;1n~ publtc&amp;lt;1 t ion tn eithe r the Ols tttCt o f Colu~bla Regi s ter, the Dl strict ot Columbia Statutes at- Lar90 o r the Distri.ct at Columbia ~lul'l i.c i.pal Regu l.!tlons yo~ DlSttlct f Col u~bi APPROVED: March 16 1988 6 COU~CI L OF THE DISTRICT OF COLmlBlA Council Ptriod s..v~D RECORD OF OFFICIA L COUNCIL VOTE DOCKEr 0 ACQ?te~i :st Read ing 2- 16-9 8 8 7- 100 K 'JOICE OTE soved ooroe&amp;lt on 0 nl Jarvis and §..c hwart.2 ESUU I i X Ilem on C nl C OM x OC f lON OATE X VOICE YOrE R&amp;amp;CO 0 O~ reou es t CTION A OAa VOIC E von II.=o'&amp;lt;H&amp;lt;I ue" 3 n r a Adopte~ f i na l Reading 3- 1-88 Apprqyed Crawf o rd </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
