<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-128">
  <num type="law">7-128</num>
  <heading type="short">Tenant Assistance Program Low-Yield Cooperative Association Amendment Temporary Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-128.pdf">D.C. Law 7-128</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-128, the “Tenant Assistance Program Low-Yield Cooperative Association Amendment Temporary Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-438. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 22, 1988, and April 19, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 6, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-177 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU:ICI L OF THE D;S~R1CT Of COLUMa:A ,O TICE D. C. LA Ioi 7 128 'Tena nt Assistanc~ Program Low-Yield Cooperati;e Associ~tlon Amendmen t Te~porary Act of 1988 Pursua nt to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Ga,ernment dnd Go,ernlllental Reo r ~dniz, t i on Act P L. 93- 1 98 the Act the CouncJI o f the Dis ;ri ct of Columbia adopted Bill No. 7-438 on first and second re adJ ngs, Karch 22 Ig88 Jnd Ap r il \ 19,1988 r especti,ely Followi ng the sigr.ature of the I~dyor on May 6.1988. this legisl~ t ion was assigned Act No 7 77 publis he d in the June 3 1988 e~jtion of th~ D.C. Registu {al. 35 page 4099) and t r dns t~ed :n Cor.,ress on )1dj 11 988 for a 30 daj re'ii~w, in acco r oanc~ wi th Sectio n 602(c)(I) o f tht Ac t. The Co un c il ,of the Distr i ct of Columbia he r eby gJ,es notice thdt the 30-day Congre,s i ;}n Re'li P~riod has e1pired, and the r efore, cites this e~dCt:tlent as D. C. La w 7 128, effecti,e 4d t l 1 Y k2&amp;amp 1:1&amp;gt [/ I' Dil'll D CLARKE Chair man of t he CounCi l June 24, 1988. D~~es Counted During t he 30-d.oY Con'lressian~l PeV1e w ?eriod: Hay 11 .1 2,13,16,17,18 19,20,2 3, 24,25 26 27 June 1,2,3.6,7,8,g,10,13.14,15, 16 ,17,2 0,21 22,23 D.C. lAW 7 -128 r:t JUN 2 4 i998 A1I ACT W TL CQUI:C IL Of' THE DISTR I CT OF COLUfo:BIA MAY 0 6 19a5 1 \ 0 2n" nd, on a tempor 3ry c asis, the rten~al lIousir.g Act o t 19 85 to authorize tt-.e use of Tena t Assi s t ar:ce Pr g J.r:l f unc$ to r:Jar.:e assis I::e paYIr,en t s on ~eh.!l o f t:"a r es l dents of d ellir:g units Qllned by t hese resieents as m&amp;lt bers of l ow-Yl e lc cooper a t i ve as sociatlons and to prcv ~de fo r the ass:g~.abilit o f Te t As si tance ?rog r dr:l contracts. aE I CtlALTCD D tlE COUflC:L 01 I E D!S RIC'r O COlUt1S That t hls act may ci t ed as tho enant Assistance Prog r al:'l t.ow- Yi e ld Cooperativ Ol Assoc iation Amend;;lOnt Temporary Act: of 19 88 Sec 2 Sea tier 02(a) of the "en t al OU511:9 Act o f 1985, e f!c c t i ve July 17, 1985 I D.C. La 6 1 0 t o be codifi ed a D. C Cede sec. 4 5- 2 53 2 (d is ane"ded b adding r.e pat"«gra~hs (3) a"c (6) t o eild as follo s 5)(A) f o r the p ut"pOS S o this title the term "hous ing ~rovlder" shal l include il low-yield coope rative associat io n that 1 Is i o q o rated u~.de~ the Distrtct o f Colurebla Coope r ative Associa t1.on Act, d?prOVed June 19, 194 0 (3 4 Stat. 480; D.C. Ccce sec 29 01 e e sec o r lnde the 4£=plicable 14w o f a:lot:-ter Ju rlsdict on fet" the ?uI"t:ose of o'ln~ng a no ope t"a&amp;lt;:lng a hoo sl:1g a&amp;lt cor.orr.odation ~n wr ch lt S lemb.:J r s r es :dc i r. the :listric t; ar:d il Re?rellonts at l east a llljority o f the headS of houscholc in the housing accor.l1r.odil. tlo n excluding t ho se households ir hicr. no n;crncc r r.as l"esideu ~n the housln9 acco~oda ~l on f Ol" at l oast 90 days aoc t hose househo ld s u: nhich any r.lePlbel" has been an ernE- l oycc of he o ner: du n n'] he pr:ccedi.ny 120 d.!lYs 2) 1 the cas\ of an assi~t d unit Ln &amp;lt;1 hcu. s r.y ,lcco odati c:1 oolTled "Y a l ow-yield coo cr.1.tiv e 0 50,,1.1I:lon t:l" t"rr r\lnt [;l"an s h lon ll'l ca rrying i J .C. ex sec 5 1989 chacges payable to t~e low-yield coopera~ive association with reslOect to occupa cy of the unit C lm yield cooperati.ve assoc:'aticn ~s a cooperative i:l w'hich ehe tcans:er value of tr.e members~,ip s limited oy the articles of .lnCocpocael.on and bylaws of the coq.;oration to the SUr:l of the following i) The membersr.ip price unCier the occupancy agreement or its eguivalent at an aocrued rate of retucn set by the board of directors of the corporation not to xceed a 10% inorease compounded Ilnnually; plus ii) The v alue as deterr:lined by the board of directors of the oorpora t i on of any iDprover,lents installed at the expense of t!-le r.lember ith prior approval of tho bollrd of directors of the corporaeion under a valuation forr:tula that provides for reir:lDu rser:lcnt in an amoun t not to exoeed the initial cost of the irn rovel:lcnt; m~nus l.ii) The cost or estil:l a tec cost of all deferred maintenance rei?a irs as deer:leG: necessary :oy ehe &amp;lt oard of cireotors of the corporation to flace L'le Gw=lling unit in s~itable ocndition for another occufant D) In the ever,t of dissolution and liquidation of the assets of a 1m yield cooperative association that is a party to a contra ct wi h the Jepartl:lent fursuant to this tit'-e, any surplus re",aining after the distribution required by para gra phs (1) a nd (2) of section 36 of the District of Col~mbia Cooperative Association Act, approved June 19,1940 (54 St a t 489; D. C Code, sec 29-11]6(1) ar.d (2 shall be paid to the District and allocated to the a ccount of the enant Assistance Program established by this titl e 6) A housing provider ~ay pledge, or offer as security for any loan or obligatio a contract entered into pursuant to tbis title if A ehe security is in conr:.Olction w'ith a rental unit, incl~di g a unit in a r.ousing acoor:1modation owned by low-yield cOCf;erative association, that lt;las acqu ired rehabilitated or constructed with aSSlstance rom the Di5trict goverr.r:lent and (E) the ter s o! t he financing or any refir:ancing are a",proved by the Dc,)art:nent. Any pledge of t conc.raot or payrr.ents ~nder the co~tract shall be lir:tited t o the amounts payable under the contract in aocordance i th its terT:1s Suc. J. Section ]6(3) of the District of Colurr.bia Coopcra t ive Association I'Ict, apr;rovcd June 19, 1940 (54 Stilt. 489; D. C. Cede, sec 29-1136 is amended by inserting the phrase "txcc:ot as r uirec by section 302(d 5 D) of t 2 I{ental CUSH,g Act of 19 8 5, effective Jd 1 7, 1985 (O C Law 6-1C; D. C Code, sec. 45-2501 at sec at che b"g:nn i ng. 2 D.C. C:X sec 29 1989 S.l, Sec 4 (01.1 hl.S act shall t ake e~:ect a~ter a 30- day period o~ Cor.grcs" iona 1 r elli e fo 1 10Ioli g a proll!!l by the Iayor [or i~ the clien t 0: ve t o by &amp;lt e ayo ac ti on by t e CO\l:lc~ l of the Jist r l Ct o f Col unbia to over de t e ve t gt as rcvidec. i:1 sec t lon 602jc) j I i of t he wistrice of Coll rnbia S~lf Government an d Gover~roeneal Reor9ll.n i~ation Act appro\'ec Oecer ber 2 4, 197 3 (87 Sta t 813 D.C. Coce, sec 1- 233(c)(1 and publica tion i n dither t h e Distric t o f ColLar.bla Regis t f'r the Dis tric t of COlul:loL St atutes at- Large, or the District of Colul1lb1a ~lUn icipal Regul ations 0 h is ace shal l eXFir e on eh~ 225 th eay o ts l'.av i ny taken effect t::e Dis trict o f Colur.,bla Col ur:tbia AF?RO'l::D: J tb e, D.C sees 0 5- 25 1989 s OU:-OCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU:'I.IB IA C(H.I nd l P xl s..w n RECORO OF OFFIC:AL C UNClL VOT XX:I&amp;lt NO 3 43S c'ccopte&amp;lt;i r s t ~ead 1g 3 22 lt; VO'CE ,on App ov e d Ae&amp;lt;:oroe 0 J 11 9reser. t It ACTION orE It VO ICE VOTE o,a 0 f e ACTION &amp;amp; OA.TE- VOICE lt;C T&amp;lt e:c'C vol&amp;lt;&amp;gt n t ~a~c C.\L lion lt;I dl q Ado E.1::ed E'i :1~ l Reac n cr H S i.oor o v e d oLc,.k l"i leon a nd H!l.ter I 5</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
