<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-12">
  <num type="law">7-12</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1987-07-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-12.pdf">D.C. Law 7-12</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 3783</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE OISTRICT OF COLU MSI A HOT IC E D, C, LAW 7 -1 2 'D istri ct Of Columb ia 8j c en te nial Commiss i on Ac t of 198i l,Irsuan to Section 412 of the &amp;lt;listrict of Columbia Self Gove r nme~t ~nd Go ver nmen ta l Reo r gan atton Act p, L. 93 198 th e Act th e Coun c il of th e District of Colum ~id adopted Bill No 7 135 on first and second r eadln&amp;lt;;p A~ril 14, 1987 nd May S 1987 r espec t i vely Follo wing t he s!gnature o f t he M~y o r on June 1 1987 t lli~ l eg i~la t ion was anigned t 7- 25 p'Jbllshed in t he June 12 1987 edi t ion of t he.!k.h Reg15 t er Vol 34 pa ge 3783) and t r an smItted t o Congr ess an June 10 1;87 for a 30 ldy r evie w, in a cco r dance 1t h Sect ion 60 2{c l) of tr Ac t. The Council o f the ill strict of Columbj~ hereby gives notice t~H the 30 day CQngr es~i()n~l evie e r iod has e plred and t "nerefo r e CiU i t hi s enHtment as D.C Law 7 -1 2 effec the J'Jly 25, B8i DAVID A. CtARH Chai rma n of the Council Dates Cou nt ed Durin g th e 30 day Congressiona l Revie w ~eriod June l(}, 11 12 15. 16, 17 la, 19 .22 .23 24 ,25 26 ,Zg ,3 0 July 1 l a g 0 ,13,14,15.16,1 1 ,ZO Zi ,22 23 ,24 D.C. LAW 7 1 2 g:v JUL 25 1997 ~rQlled Original IN ACT D.UCT 7 -25 CocilfLcation, New Ch"pter 35 of title 2 IN r COUNCIL OF TSE DIS~RIC7 OF COL~3IA JUN 0 1 1987 To establ:sh a District of Columbia Bicentennial Commission to develop a plan for the celebration of the bicente~n:al of the Constitution of the United States and of the transfer of the seat of the federal government of the United States of America to the D~ strict of Colu~:a. BE IT EN.'I.CTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be c:ited as the "District of Columbia Bicentennial Commiss :on Act of 1987 Sec. 2 The Council of the District of Col~~ia finds that 1) The per:od comme ncing in 1987 and ending in 2004 embrac e s the bic e nte nnial annive rsaries of significant events of g::eat importanoe t o the history of t he l:nited State s of America and to the development of the City of Washington, Dls~riot of Col~mbia 2) The goverr~ent of the District of Coluw~ia is responsible for the preservat~on of the history of the Di str~ct of Col~rr~ia as e seat of the national government and as a city having Congress io n al:y- mandated au~ority for "el f gove::nment 3) The United States is celebrating t~e bic e nte nnial of the Const:cution of the Un:ted State s through state and local celebrations beginnin g in 1987 4) The Dis trict of Columbia is approac~ing t~e bicentennial of its founding as the seat of the f e d e ral government and anni-;ersa::ies of othe events of great national ar.d local significance; and (5 t i s appropriate and fitting to p:an the c e lebration and commemoration of these hi s toric eve nts tr.rough observances and activi ties planned by a COmmlSS l on composed of repre sen1:Cati'les of public and pr late authoritie s and organizations. 1 New D.C. Cod sec. 2-3501 1988 SUDp Enrol led Orig i n al Sec 3. Defini tions. For the purpo se s of this a ct e term 1 Commi5sion" meano :he District of Colur.ll ia B~c.nter~ia l Co~~i ss~an estab l i shed by section { 21 nCour.cil means t~e Council o f the Dist=ic t o f Coiu:nbi.l 3 Oi s i c,:w ~eans e Oi s ri c of Columbi a 4 ft Gov.rnrne ~t means the gove ent o f e Di15t=i t of Co l'.lml::ia 5 Mayo me ans t~e Mayo o f tile D!:s ri ct o f Co lu:rr.bia 6 Secre&amp;lt ary" mean s Secreta=y of tile Dist ric t of Colu:nbia. Se c. 4 ta~li 5hcer.t of t~e Di s trict o f Co l~~i a gicen:e~~ia l Co~~i ss i or a There!s establishe d a commi s on t o b e own .IS t l".e Dist=ict of Col1.lmbia 3icenten.nial COllmi ssion const i t·.ltec for tl".e pur p ose o f ~evelopin9 and coordinatin9 plan s for e c ommemoration o f t he bice ntenni a l of the United States Con s t i tu t ion, the tran s fe r of the eeat of the f ede r a l iove ent to the Dis tr i ct of Col~~ia, a nd the annive rsari es of o~~er r e l ate d even~s o f nati onal and local s i gnificanc e oce u ing cur ing the bicen:ennial perio d commencing in 19S7 and ending in 2004 b The CommiSSion shall be comp iseci of 39 merr.be r s, all o f ~ho~ shall be residents o f the D~s trict as f ollows 1) One Ci t i z e n fr om each e Lection ward of the Ois trict appointed by t Mayor, none 0: whom shaLL ~e o fficers or em o ~ees o f :he qove rn~en t or of any of it s ir.dapencient ager.cie!&amp;gt i 1 the exc ept i o n o f Advi s ory Neighborhood Commi asi ons 2 Four t een members 1 af whom sh a ll be appo i n~ed ~y t he Chai=man o t t he Council, anc 1 each by e ether Councilmembera and one of whom shall b e a eouncilme~er a~pointed by e Chair~an o f the Counei l t o represe nt t he ~nt erests o f the Council 3) One member ap~ointed by the Dist r ict's delegate t o the House o f Represent a ti ves of the United St a t es 4) Nine me mbers appoin t ed by the Mayo r to repres ent appropriate public and private organizations a nd the Dist rict's ~u sineas community 5 o ~embers appo~nted by the Chi e f Judge o f the District of Co lumbi a C01.lrt 0: Appeals 6 o Members appoi nted by the Ch~e: Judge of e Superior Cou=t 0: the Distric o f Col~~i.l 7 Cne membe r appo i nted by the District of Columbi a Bar and l'ev. D. C. CQc!e, sec 2· 3502 (l9a8 1 11;0 New, D.C. Coc!e, sec. 2· 3503 (1988 SU?p Enrolled Orig i nal (8) Two members, 1 of whom shall be the Secre~ary of the District of Columbia, appointed by the Mayor to represent appropriate agencies of ~e District of Colu~ia Goverl'.ment c) All ~embers of the Co~~ission Shall be chosen within 60 days of tr.e effective date of this act d) A chai"person of t~e Commissio~ shall be chosen by the l1ayor, and the members of the Commission shall elee from among their ~embership a vice-chairperson and other officers as deemed necessary el Each membe r of the Comt:'Lission shall serve ithout compensation, but shall be reimbursed for all r e asonabl e expense s pursuant to section !108(b) of the District of Columbia Gover~ent Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2 139; D.C. Code, s e c. 1-6:2.8(b» f lembers of the Commission appo:'nted pU 5uant to subsection (b) of this section shall serve for a period of 4 year s from the date of the installation of a majority of the rr.emb rs f:'rst appointed, except that members appointed pursuant to section 4(b)(8) shall serve at the pleasure of the Mayor q) The Co~i ssion shall be dissolve d 4 years from the date of the installation of a majoeity of its first members, but the life of the Commi s sion may be ex~ended at t he pleas ure of the Mayoe h) Vacancies on the Commission s hall be filled in e same manner in which the original appointments were made i) A majority of the :nembere of the Commission shall consti~ute a quorum j) The Commi SSion may appoint ho~orary members, and may es~ablish an advi s ory commit~ee to assist the Ccmmi ssion in its work. The membe rs of any advisoey committee shall serve wit~out compensation k) The Commission may establish pecial committees and invite cit~zen representatives from public agencies and pri ate o ganizations to assist the Commis e ion in carryin9 out it s work as the Commi ssion deems appropriate 1) The Commission may adopt by-laws to govern its internal ope ration and p~blic meetings ml The Commission may adopt and use a sea l upon approval by the Mayor. The Commission shall be the repository for the officia: emblem issued by the Commiss i on On the 3icentennial of ~he Uni ted States Constitution, e s tablished pu:-suant to the Commission on the Bicente nnia: of the United State s Cons titution Establishment Act, approved September 29, 2983 (Pub L No. 98-101; 97 Stat. 719 Sec. 5. 3 i:I D.C C~de sec 3504 (1988 SU;lD Snrolled Original (a) There may be appropriated o~t of revenues available to the Distric~ sums necessary to carry out the purpose s of this act b) The Co~ission is au~~orized to apply for and eceive grants to fund s activities c) The Commission may solicit and accept private gifts and donations to carry out the pu=pose s of this act d) The admini~trative support for the Commission, including personr.el and procu:-ement services, shal l be provided by the Office of the Secretary and shall be $ubject to all the statutory and regulatory requirements applicable to the Office of the Secretary. Sec 6. Es tablishment of a District of Col~~bia Bicentennial Co~~ission Fund a) A Di s trict of Col'.lmbia Bicentennial Fund Fund shall be e stablished by the Mayor to r e ceive a l l ~oney from whateve= source derived to c a rry out the purposes of this aot. The Fund shall be accounted for under procedures estab~ished pursuant to the Dis trict of Col~~ia Fund !\ccounting Act of 1980, effe c ive June 14, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-70; D.C. Code, sec. 47-371 et s ea. L or any other applicable la All mone y generated by the Commission shall be deposi ted in the Fund b) All money in the Fund shall be fo~ the s ol e use of the Commissi on c) The Commission shall submit to the Mayor and to the Counoil a monthly ~tatement of r e c e ipt s ~nd di s bur s ements from the Fund d) Upon ~he eXpiration of this act and after all obligations of ~he Commi ss ion have been satis~ied, any mone y r emaining in the Fur.d shall b e paid ove r to the &amp;lt;;e!1.eral f-.md of the District as general p~rpo ses r eVenueS. Sec. I 7. Duties. The Commission shall 1) Plan and deve lop appropriate activities and publications to oe lebrate the bicentenni al events identified by the Co~~ission for commemoration 2) Select and deve lop proposals for p ojec s to be undertaken by the Government that are design to ha:-monize and balance the important goals of scholar ship and education 3) Invol e and actively encourage tr.e participation 0 ocal and national private organizations e d e r al District, and adjaoent s ate &amp;lt;;overn:nent s in planning for the bicentennial events and commemorations 4) Se r,re as the District' s cle arin gr.ouse f or the r esea rch. co l!ection and dissemination 0: the official 4 ~e D. C. Code Sec 2-3505 (1988 sU':lp Ole D.C. Cod sec. 2-3 506 (1988 sUDp Snrolled Grl gl information used as ~he ~asis !o: developing e plans {or bi~enter~ial co~emorations; and (5) Complete othe r p r ojec t s anc approac~es iden t ified by ~he Co~i on as being significant to ~he successful deve lopme n t of the bicentennial p lan for t he Distric t to c~ lebrate its bi~entennial and ~ha t o f the Cor.s tit tlon 0: the Uni t ed Sta t es b) The Co~ission s~al1 conside r apFropriate means by r.lc tr.e District should ~elebra te the b:'center.nial of t he Constitu ~ion of ~e Uni~ed States and shall s sue a r eport detal lin&amp;lt pl ans fot' this ~eleb rat ion ithin 3 months o f the da t e o f the first meetinq held by the Commission f ollowing i t s esta':ll r_"ent e) The Co~=iss! on s ha l l subm!t to the Ma yor and t o e Counc il an i nte ri~ repo rt of the Co~~ission o n ~he pl an f or co:r:me:'llorating bicent.ennial e ven ts of sigr.i!!car.ce t o ne Constitu tion o f t~e United Stat es and ~o e history o f t~e Dis~ric t thin 9 months Qf e cate of the fi~st meetH.q heLd oy the Commis s ion fo l lQwinq i ts estab lishment. The inter l~ report of the CQ~!ssion shal l nc l ude 1) An identific a t ion of the bicentennial and related events to be comme~orated and celebrated, includ1nq a master s chedule of tar;et date s 2) A de scription of the nature of the celeb r a ti ons to be developed for each event ident i fi e d for COII'JI'lel1lora t.10n 3 A state~ents o f hi ato ri~a l a~d other scholarly d ata t o suppo rt the seiec t ion o f each eve~t proposed ~o r co=.e:l:ora t on 4 A descr:pt10n of the scope and extent of Inte r ac t1 0n BI:l gt;ng the faderal, Cis tr ict, ar.d state gover~~ents and private or9ani a t i ons participat in&amp;lt in ~he for mulation and p~e sentat1on of the bicentennia l plan S) Cost pro j e ctions f or each even: proposed f or CQm:r,emera ti on and a pl a r. for allocat !on of fi:lancial and adm i nistrati ve respo~s :bil i ty among the pub lic and priVa te e nt ities recommende d fo~ participation by the Commi ss ion 6) An outline of pubLications n eeded ~o promote, c ecumer.t and e ncour age the interes t and part icipation o f the public and private s ectors in the bicenten:lial events proposed for commemorati cn; and (7) A s~~a~y o f r eco~endations fo~ adni~istrative ac~ ion5 ane a n y add:'t~ona l le9isla~10n that may r. t he judgement 0 e Co~~ission, be necessa~y o~ ees:'rsble in i"'p lr.ent!r.&amp;lt t e b1center_"lial p:an s e t :or't n t !le inte~i:n repo t d) The !1ayo~ sr.a11 SUbmit to e COlrJ:li ssion the Mayo r 's v~ew s en ~he interi:n report of ~icen~enn~al plans wi~h ~n 3 :nonths of the Mayer's receipt of the int. e r n r epor t 5 t0ge~~er wi t h any rev:s:ons, additi ons, or o~~er r e eomm da ti ems Drolled Or1g1~al (e) The Commission shall submi t to e Mayor s final repo r t, s"tti~q o rth t~e ~as ter p l an for the e e~eb r at:on o f t h e bi:=e ntennial .vents o f t~e Constitutior a:l.d of the District no~ more than 4 ~onths from e da~e t he Co~~1ssion r.ceives the Mayor's r~port o! fi nd:nqs o n e Co~~lssion s int.erim repo r t T~e Mayo r sha ll s~bmit t o e Council a r eport o n the plan for celebrati ng the bieentanni.l o! the adoptio n and rati fication of the Cons~itution 0 he United States and o f the transf e r o f the seat of t h e f ederal government to the District, and r elated commemo rati ons Wi t hin &amp;amp;0 d a ys from the dat.e t he Mayor rece ives t 1na1 report o f t he Cel!lr.'l i sSl on q) Th' 11ayo r h .ll d istr i bute copies e the re;J0 rt 0 the ayo r t o aU aqer:cies o f t he Dis t rict c t.hO 015tr1ct of Colu:nbia Public Library, lind t o all e c",r" l a lel state qover~~ental agenc10!:s and privat e o rqani z a ~i ons that p arti cipated i~ t.h O wo rk of the Commissi on. The Mayo r s hall al s o make cop i",s of the report ava il able to a l l Adv!so ry Neiqhbo rhood Co~issions and int.e eBted citize n s Sec. 8 ff tc t.1ve Date This· aC shal l ~ak effec t. af t e r a 30 cay ;Jeriod o f Cong s s ior.a l rO!:view followinq appr oval oy he Mayo r (o r ~n event o f veto b y e Mayor, action by t~e Counc~ l o f t he Dis t~ict of Co!~1a to overrice the veto) a s proviced i n sec~ion 6C2(c 1 of the Dist. ric t of Columbia 5elf- Governr:te:'l amp;r.d Gov e".tal Reo r ganization Act, approved December 24 137 3 (87 Stat. 813 D.C. Coce IUtc 1-233{ c 1». Chai tIan Counc il of the Oi. t~ict of COlumbia Mayor D~st rict. of Col~~ia ~POJill une 1, 1987 6 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Periorl Seven RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO B,7c-Cl 3"5 lt;&amp;gt ACTION &amp;amp; DATE AS-opted ?irst "eadina, 4-1 8] 1 vO ice VOT Una!1imous A .cor a yot. on "Q Winter AESU~T S~o rotar' to ,h Cour&amp;gt;C tl 1Iem on Conoon' Cal ~ndu :If ACTION &amp;amp; DAT E_ 11: VO ICE VOTE Ac.opted ri:M.l eadinq, 5-5-87 UnanlltlOUS Reoord ed ot. an reQu Abse nt- all prese:lt ROl~ CALL VOTE RESULT 5 r 0 0 'n" Callne il C ACTION &amp;amp; DAT 1 0 'Ci' VOTE Re co ,de u 'ot~ 00 000" RO LL CALL VOTE RESULT J 1 Oa I j </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1901"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1902"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1903"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1904"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1905"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1906"/>
  </section>
</document>
