<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-136">
  <num type="law">7-136</num>
  <heading type="short">Day Care Policy Act of 1979 Amendment Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-07-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-136.pdf">D.C. Law 7-136</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 4259</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-136, the “Day Care Policy Act of 1979 Amendment Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-291, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 3, 1988 and May 17, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 1, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-186 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>, CO UNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMS IA 1I 0T Ie E D.C. LAW 7- 136 Oa, Care Po l l~y Act of 1979 Amen4ml~t Act of 1988 Pursuant to Section 412 of tht District of Colum~ ta 5. 1 f the Act lnt Counctl of lhe District of Col umb i a a~o~ted 51 11 No 7-291 on first and second readings, May 3, 1988. an d 1'1 41 17, 1988, respec.tively. Fo ll ow lnS the s fgnatur. of the Mayo r on J une 1. 1988. this "gis1at i on WIS assigned Act No. 7-186. published In the Jun, la, 1988, edition of th Q f Rlglst.r, {Vol. 35 page 4Z59 } and trans_ftted to Congress on J~ne S, 1988 for a 30.day r.~I.w. In accordanc. wllh Stetien 602 1 of the Act. The Counc i l of the DistrIct of C o lu~b t a h,r,by gives nottce that the 3D-day Congr.,slon.l Review Period has expired. and therlfore. c i tes this Inactaent as O.C Law 7-136. ef fectiv e July 29, 19BB. VI 0 A. CLARKE Chalr lu n of the CGllncl 1 Oates COlin ted During the 30-day Ccn q resslon~l Review Period June 6 7.B .9. 10 .13, 14 .15.16, 17 2 0 ,2 1 ZZ ,23 .24 .2 7 ,2B,29.3 0 July 6,7,B,11,lZ,lJ,14,2S,26.Z1,2 B n~l.AW 7-136 VI JUl2 9 1988 AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 -18 6 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE OISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To am~nd the Day Ca~e Foliey Act of 1979 to increase payments to licensed child development centers and child development homes BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That t lis a ct lIIay be cited as the "Day Care Policy ot of 1979 Amendment Act of 1988 Sec. September seg is (a) follows: 2. The Day Care Policy Act of 1979 effective 19, 1979 (D.C. La 3 16; D. C Code, sec. 3-301 at amended as follows: Section 10 (D.C. Code, sec. 3-309) is amended a s (L) The introductory language of section 10 is designated as subsection (a) and subsection Cal is redesignated as paraqraph (1) of subsection (al 2) Ne ly redesignated section 10(a)(1 D.C Code, O5e&amp;lt 3-309(1» i s amended to read as follows 1) S~ject to subsections (b) through (h) of this section, payments to child development centers for Care of these children Shal l be made on a monthly basis according to the following rates A or full care other than that provided under subparagraph (S) of th~s paragraph, child development centers shall reeeive $18 00 per day for each ehild, plus $1.00 per day for eaeh child to whom the ehild development cent er p r ovides transportation B) For full cal;"e prov_tded only during summers and vacations to children who otherwise do not receive care under this section or who otherwise receive only part-time care, child development centers shall reeeive $14.40 per day for each Child e or part-time care, child development centers shall receive $9.00 per day Cor each eh~ld 2) No child development center shall be paid more than its stated rate prior to the application of its 1 D.C CCe 3-309 (1989 sUB l { sli~lnq fee Ical. for children not aliqibl e for 5ubsid~ze~ c&amp;amp;r 3) A new subsection (h) il sddld to read .s fol to"'l l hJ(l) On or before January 31st o[ each year beqinnlnq January 31 1990, the Mayor shall calculate and submit to the Council. determination of the pareentlqe increa dUrinq the precedinq ealendar ye.r, 1n the consumer price index for urban consumers [or all ite=a tNblished by the t1n1t States Oep,artment of Labo r Consumer Price tndex J. R(2) aeqinnlnq OCtober 1, 1990 rat.s established pursuant to sub ctlon (a 1) of this section .h.ll be adjusted ~u.lly by an amount equal to the percentaqe incr if any in the consumer price index for urban consumers [or all iteml, as determined by the Mayor The Mayor shall publish notice of any p~oposed a nnual incr in pa~'Qts to child d.v.lopment c ent. rs in e Distriet of Columbia aeqister 30 days prior to the proposed i ncrea b) S.ction 11 (D.C Code sec. 3-310) is amended to r t follows S.e. 11. Payments to child development homes and to in-ho~e car.qiver a) Payments to child development homes and to in-hom. c.reqivers shall b. mad. accordlnq to ehe follovinq \"ates 1) lor f~ll care fA) Child development home. shall receive $12 pe\" day for ch child 3) In-home careq lvers shall r$ce!ve $7.25 p.r day for eaeh child for care durinq the d.y end $8.25 per nlqht for each child for niqht care 2 For part-tilll. care A) Child development homes shall r.ceiv 6 00 p.r day for ch child for before nd aft.e-school care B) In-hom. c.r.qiv.rs shall r eceive $5.75 p.r day fo ach child for befo\"e-.nd after-school care and $4 00 par DiQht tor ,ach child for niqht care of les. than 6 hour b)(l) On or betore Janu.ry 31 s t of each yea\ b.qinninq January 31. 1990 the Mayo r s h.ll c.lcul.te and submit to the Council a d.te rmination of the incre durinq the precedinq calendar y r 1n the con.~er pric, index tor urban consuaers tor I I ite ms published by the United States Departm.nt of Labor Consumer Price Index 2) B'qinninq October 1. 1990. the rate tablished pursu .nt t o subsection f of this aection shall be ad justed annually by .n amount equal to the perc.ntag O.C. Cc:Ce 1 3-31Cl (1989 !fI.4 gt in~rea~e, if any, in the ~ons~er price iocex for urban consume~s for all items, as determined ~y e Mayer. T~e Mayor shall publish notice of any p~op0ged annual increase in payments to child development homes and in-home caregivers in the Oistriee of Columbia Reqister 30 days prior to the proposed inerease Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review followinq approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of e District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(01(1) of the District of Columbia Self~Government and Governmental Reorqanization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1~23J(c)(1 Ch~ Pro Tempore Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: 3 I COl.rNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF CQLt,fMBIA Cauaa Ptriod $ovu RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE OOCIII!T NO C l S .o.CT!ON &amp;amp; 0 Tl A O O l i t J'~M",d~i"n cJlc L VO IC E YOU C AOFE O"'V M C.c C m w"f"OC V O E n 11""0 C I gt;Son Thomas Win t e r ane. SChW4rt and Wi lson III ACT1QN" OATI A,d.o p il~"t M i"n.'C J1J U m V vo~ CCCC,-dA P v reOll 1:I:I.n\: Clalice IIno! Kane II oft Con C Acn ON l OATIi VOIei VOTE: Aoc Oft _ot C IIOU. CAll VOTI </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
