<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-131">
  <num type="law">7-131</num>
  <heading type="short">Boards and Commissions Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-07-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-131.pdf">D.C. Law 7-131</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 4106</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-131, the “Boards and Commissions Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-139, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 14, 1987, and May 5, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 1, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-26 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>, COUNCIL OF THE O!STRICT OF CO LU MBIA NOTlCE D.C. LAW 7-131 "Community Residence Facllitie~ Licen~vre Amendment Tempor~ry Act of 1985 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia 5 lf- Government and Governme ntal Reorganization Act. P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the Ojstri~t of Columbia adopted Bill No. 7-469 on first and second read;ng April 19. 1988 nd May 3.1988. respectively. follo wing the signature of the Mayor on May 19 1988. this l egislation was assigned Act No. 7-181, p ublished i n the June 3. 1988 dition of the D,C. Register V ol. 35 page 4106) and transmitted to Congress on Md Y 20, 1988 for a 3D-ddy revie w, in accordance with Section 602(c I) of the Ai: t. The Council of the Distri ct of Columbia hereby gi ves notice that the 30-d ay Congresslon al Revielll Period has expired, and therefore, cite s this ena ctment dS D.C. La lli 1-131, effective July 8,1988 z DAH D Ch airman Council Dates Counted Durinq the 30-day Congressional Rev ielll Period J June J u 1 y 20,23,24,25,25,27 1,2,3,6 7,8,9, 10, 13,14 15, 16 ,17 ,2 0,21,22 23,24,27 28,29,30 6 7 AN ACT D.U eT 7 1 8 1 IN 'ThE COUNCIL OF niE: DTSTRl.C-r Of' COl.,lI MB1A MAY 1 t 1988' TO ~mend. on a te~porary basis, the Health Care Faci lities Regulation t o p r ovide that community re~ldence faC llit ies may a cce p t r esidents h (} have mobil I t y Ilmltll;tions or \,rho are in need of m()r~ tn lU'l f.linimal IIs ;iist.lI.nc e wit.h t he a ctivi t i es of d il y liv_\ng and to mend. on a t.f'.rtIp&amp;lt gt;I.&amp;lt;lry basis th f! He.llth -CII.Lt' and Community R~~idenc~ Fac j l~ty Hospice and Home Ca r e t. i c e n lure Act of l!Hlj t o allow community rel'li.d e nce faCilities to seek a waiver. of 1i censvt e requiI-ement s in order to accO!pt re iaents unde r 18 ye.H's ot 1I.9a BI IT E!I ACTED BY THE COUNCIL Of THE OJ STRICT OF COL UMBIA, Th at this act may be ci ted 11.8 t h e "Community Residenc e Faci li ties Licensu~e Amendmen t Tempo~a~y Act o t 1988 Sec 2 The de f lni t.ion of "ComJllunit.y Residence D.C I.R. Fac i lity· in section 3 o f Ti t le I of the Health Ca~e Fac il i ties Regula UOT1 is!5u ed June 14, 19"74 (Reg. 74-1 5, 22 DCMR 3099.l is amende d a~ to l 1ow a) ey s trl.lun9 t he pll~,ue ged elghteen ye s o r ol de b By 5 t~ ik ing t he phr ase "lI&amp;lt l:e ambula t ory and ol.b le t o pertorm the ac tlvities of daily I l Vil1g with mir"limal a ssis tallce The de fini tion l nctude$ facil i tH!S inc h Iding halfway houses h.ich provide a shel terfod livl ng acrang erne n t t o per~ons who a nd t e) By i nserting at t he end t he fo l lowing sentenee Al l residents of a c ommunity resider"lee faci lity sha ll be 1 8 years o f age o r ol de r, unle ss this r eqU lrement is waived in accor danee with sec t ion 6 t b 22 D.C. M.R 3015 Sec 3 Sect ion 2{ a 4 o f U le Heal t h-CarR a lld D.C. Cede Y. Coremuoit.y Residence Facility, Hospi.:e allo Home Ca re 3 1301 L.i eellsure ACt o f 19 8 3 ef.fec t ~ve Feb r uary 2 4 1984 j O. C. Law n 989 supp 5-48; D. C Code, sec. 32- 1 301(&amp;lt;1 4 ill a l:lended as follows 1 (a By strikinq the pnJ:ilse ~ag ed 16 or olde r (except that in tile case of group homes for mentally r e tarded persons no min imum age shall apply and (b) By insert .ing at t.ne end the follow1 no sentence \11 resident.1I of a community r ewidence facility shall be 18 yea rs of age o r o lder (except t.hat, in t he cas* of group home s for ~entally retarded persons no minimu~ age shall apply unless this requir ement is waived in accordance wit h sect.ion 6 (eJ Sec. 4 a) Thie act shal l t ake ef f ect after a 30-day period of Congressional review f ollowing approval by the Mayo r l o r i n the event of veto by the Hayor, action by t he Cour\cil o f th e Oistr tc t. of Col umbla t o ove rr ide the ve.to) as prov id ed in s{Jction 602 (c 1) of t he Di s t.rict. of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorgantzation Act, approved Oece.:\beJ: 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 8131 D. C. Code sec 1-233(c)(1 and publica~ion in either the Oil~rict of Co lumbi a Regi ster, thd Distr ict of Columbia Stat.u t.es -at- LaJ:qe. or the DistrlCt o~ Columbia Municipal Requlllt.ions b) This ac t shall &amp;lt xp ire on the 22St.h day of iu havlng taken e ff ect. Council o f t.he Distr ic t of Columbid o f Colum ia APPROVED: May 19. 1988 Note, D.C Cede. sec. 32- 1301 (1989 supp. l S COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Couucil Period Seven RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCtL VOTE DOCK~l NO I 00 Co",e"t Ca l"Mdr X ACTION &amp;amp; DATE o~ed First Rea&amp;lt;;lirrgL3_-J S 8 5 VO IC E VOTe A r ed F!ocor~aa ve on "QU~'1 B'I-469 R"ocl k, Wint,er Schwart.z and Wi.l son r: ROLl CALL VOTE I1ESUlf X ACTION &amp;amp; DATE. Ad2.l2~ed Fin~1 R~adtr:!g 2 1::S 8 I Approved :s: VOCE VOTE Re&amp;lt;;Ofded vote G ue Ab.ent: Thomas, Winter, Kane, Schwartz and Wilson Date C{ m on eon nt Ca l. M ar C CTION &amp;amp; DATE V O IC~ VOT Rocorn ot. on reQues t </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
