<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-141">
  <num type="law">7-141</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Conformity Amendment Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1988-09-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-141.pdf">D.C. Law 7-141</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 5398</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-141, the “District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Conformity Amendment Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-445, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 14, 1988 and June 28, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 30, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-193 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NCI L Of THE DIS TRIC T Of CO LUMBIA NOT ICE D. C. UW 1- 141 "Dl$trlct of Co lumbj I nco me and Fr anCh ise Tax Conformity Amend lJ ent Act o f 1988 Pur sUdnt to Sectlo~ 412 of th e Distri ct o f Culumbia Sel f- Gov e rn lll nt d od Go ver ome nt dl Reor9~ nizatio n Act. P. L. 93- 198 the Ac t th e Counc il of th e Dis tri c t of Coluaabi d dopted Bi ll No. 7-445 on fi r s t a nd second r eadings J une 14 1988 and June 28. 1988 r e spH the l y. Fo llowi ng t he sign ture o f t he M yor on Ju ne 3D, 1988 thi s legisla t hn wa s assigned liLt NO. 7- 193 publish ed in the July 15 1988 edi t ion of the f Reg i ste r Vol. 35 page 5398 and t ransmi tted to Co ngr eH on July 1. 19 88 f o r d lD day r evi ew, in dctord~nce with Sec t io n 602(c)(I) o f the Ac t. The Coun c il of th e Dist r ict o f Co lu mbia he reby gives noti ce tha t t he 30-day Co ngre ssional Re v ie w Pe ri od has expired, dnd therefo re, c ites this enaC t ll.ent 4$ D. C. L~ w 7- 141 effe c t iv e $ep t e ~be r 21 1988 Oa te s Coun ted Du r ing th e 3D-day Co" g re~sion~l Rev i e w Pe riod: J uly 7 8 .1 1 12 13.1 4, 25 16 27 28 29 August 1 2 4 5 8 9 10,11 Septembe r 7 8 ,9. 12 ll 1 4.1 5 16 .1 9,2 0 b.C. 1AW 7 -1 4 1 stP Z 1 IS8B AN ACT (bjificati Distr ict of Gol~i3 D.C.ACT7-19S (1989 Sur:plffie."l t J I N THF. CO UNC IL OF THE DISTR I CT OF COLUMBIA JtnI G fmlB To a mend the Dist ric t o f COl umb13 I ncome a nd Franchise Tax ~ct o f 19 4 1 t o ame nd t he definition o f I nterna l Revenue Code o f 198 6 t o provide for continued conform ity, on a limi ted basis to federal income tax and to make ce rta i n c l a rifying amendments BE rr ENACTED BY THE COUNCI L or T HE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA That this a ct may be cited as the "Distr ict of CO lumbia r ncome and Franch ise Tax Confo rmity ~endment Ac t of 199 9 Sec 2 he Dis trict o f Columbia I ncome and Franch ise Ta x Act o f 194 7 appr ove d Ju l y 16, 19 47 16 1 Stat. 331 D.C Code scc 4 7- 18 0 1. 1 e t seq i s mended as f ollows a ritle l, s ect ion 4 (ob-l D.C Code sec Section 7-1 1101.4 47-lIJ 0 1.4 (28-1 i s a mended t o r e ad as followlI bb- l Tha te rm "Internal Revu nue Code of 19 8 6" means the Internd l Revenue Code of 1986 pproyed October 22, 1986 1I00 Sta t. 2085; 26 U. S C 1 e t sag I, as nended through December 22, 1987 b l Title 3 section 3(a 8 D C Code sec Scetien 4 7- 1~OJ 3 47-180 3 3 (a I (8 i s il.l'lend ecl by s t riking the ph rase the activities o f whiCh are carried on to a substa n t lal extent withi n the Distric t c Ti t le 5 section 2 1b ID. C Code, sac Section 47 05. 2 47 1805 2 (2 i s amended by a ddi ng a new parag raph (4) to read as fo llows 4 Every trust fo r which h e or she .let s the g ross inc ome o f which f or t he taxable year is S100 o r o ver d) Tit le 12 sec t ion 8(b )1l 1 iC D c Code sec 47- 1812.8 (b)ll)(C is repea led a Title 12 section B(e){8)(A D C Code sec. 47-1812. 8(e 8)(A is amended by striking the wo rd "or" afte r the semicolon and inserting the word "ove r" in its p lac e. 1 Section 4 i- 18t2 Section 4 1- 1~12 S t.l lled Or ig inal (f Tit le 12, sec tion 11 (c 2) tD. C code, sec 4 7-1812 11( c l(2 i~ ame nded to r ead as f o llows 2 Pro sumption a s to o.ate of paymont for the purposes of th is sect i on AI Any tax ac t ually deducted and wi thheld at t he s ource du r i ng any cal e ndar year u nder this article sha l l in r espect t o t he r ec ipient o f t he inCOOIe, be deemed to h ave been paid on the 1 ~th day o f t he 4th ~on th f o l lowing th e cl o~ e of the t axabl e year wi t h respect t o whic h the tax i s all owabl e as a c redit under th is a rt ic Le B) Any ~ount paid a s est imated taxes p rior t o t he 15th day of th e 3rd month fol lowing the c lose ot t he tax able ye ar in the case of corpo r a tion' and prio r to t h e 15th day Of t he 4th month foll owing the c l ose o f the taxabl e year in the case o f indivio.ual s and un incorpo rated bUsi nesses s hall be de emed t o h ave been pa id on the 15 th day of the 3rd or 4th mont h as the case may be g) Ti tl e 12 sec t ion 16 (O. C Code, sec 47-L8L2 16) is a me nded to rea~ a s f o llows Sec 16. The t ax es pr ovided under th i ll artic l e sha ll be col l ected by the Mayor h Title 1 3 s ection 4 (D C Code sec 47- 1813 4) i s amended as fo llows t l Subsectio n a l i s amended by s t riking the ph rase -at the rate i nte rest sha ll b e co l lected 2) Subsect ion (a 2 is amended by s t r i k ing the phra se int eres t at the rate 3 Subsect ion (b i s aQende d by strik ing the ph raso "a t t he r ate int nr est i T i tle 1 3 se c t l.on 5 (O. C Code, s e c 47-1 813 5) is am~nded by st r iking the ph r ase ~one and one-foorth~ and insert ing the phra s e ~one a nd one ha lf" in its p la ce Sec 3. This act a ha ll take effe c t a ft e r a 30- day per iod o f Cong ressio na l review following approval by t he Mayor (o r in t he event of veto by the l1ayor action by the Cou ncil o f th e Dist ri ct o f Columbia to ove rride the veto) as p r o v ided in sectio n 602 (cl (l o f the Distr i ct o f CO lumbia Sel f- Gove rnment and Gove rnmen ta l Reo rganiza t ion ~ct, app rovod December 24 1973 87 Stat 813, D. C Code, s e c L-2 )] (c L and pub li ca tion i n either the Dist r i c t o f Col u~bia Req i s ter, the Dis tr ic t of Columbia E;ecti&amp;lt;r. 47-1~12.11 Sect ion 4i- i912 Section 47- 1813 5ecti nn 4i- 1R13. co l uo,bjf l cjip.1 S t&amp;lt;lt l,l t es at uge or t he Rcgulliltions of the District of Columbia District AP?ROVED June 3D, 1988 l I AS ON X ACT ION DATE COU C II OJ' TH E UISTR1CT OJ' COLU gt;I1lI A Co un t il Period Seven RECORO OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOC ET "0 M&amp;amp t..ai Ei .rst Rmd1n g f&amp;gt 14-Sa X VOICE VOtE Approved O'~0(1 011 t&amp;lt;i'QU X It on Coo caJen&amp;lt B7- 445 lt cnON &amp;amp; DAfE Ado et..W. Final Readin9 ti 2 a- as x' VOICE von. q oot\l e on ItoQUfIoSl Approya 0 00 a.ll present 4C-ION 0A1E VO,Cf VOrE Ao&amp;lt; n'o e ete on ve" Anunt ROll C"'U VOlE IlESl.LT I I 1</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
