<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-155">
  <num type="law">7-155</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-09-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-155.pdf">D.C. Law 7-155</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 5718</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-155 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-414, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 28, 1988 and July 12, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 15, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-210 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUM BIA NOT ICE O. C. LA\/ 7-\S5 Olstrlct of Colu.bia Traffic A~en~~ent Act of 1988 Pursuant to Section 41l of the DIstrict of Columbia Self GOfe rn.en t and GOfe r nmental Reorganlutlon Act. P. L. g3 1g8 the Ac t the Councn of the 015 t rlct of Colullbh ado pted BIll Ho. 7-414 on first and second re~dln9s. June 28. 1988, and July lZ. 1988. respective ly. Following the signature of tile Mayor on July IS 1988 tills l&amp;amp;gis lat lon IOU Hsigned Act 110. 1_210 publi s hed In the July 29. 1988 edition of the..Q f Reg iste r Vol 3S page 571 8) and transmitted to Co ngress on July 25, 1988 for, 3D day reyle in acco rdan ce Ith Sect Io n 602(c 11 of the Act. The Council of t he District of Co\ullbla hereby give s no ti ce tll.t the 30-d.y Congressional Reyiew Perfyd has e1plre dnd therefore. cl tiS this enactme nt as D. C. Law 7-155. effecti ve Septe.ber 29. 1988. Oa te s Coun ted Du rln g t he 3 D ay Congress i onal Review Period: July 25.26.27,28,29 Augus t 1.2.3,4,5,8 9.10 11 5epte-bf'r 7 .8, \I ll.13 .14 15 ,1 6 19,20 .Zl.2l.21. 26 27 28 D.C. IAW 7 B 5 amp;W.'oUed Orll~ Codification. Oi strlct of Columbia Code (1989 Supplement) D.UCT7-2IO IN 'ntE mUNe tL Of' WE OI STRICT OF' OJLUMBIA u JUL 1 5 1988 TO ame~ the Oistrict of Columbia Traffic Act of 1925 t o r equ ire the Mayor t o permit indivl~ua ls t o r egister to vote in the Di strict. of Colu~bia when they apply f o r o r renew their Op&amp;lt;H"l!Itor 's pam!t o r ide'ltificatio" c r d. ee IT ENACTED BY TaE COUNCI L OF' THt DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be ci t ed as the "Dist rict of Columbia Traffic Amendment Act. of 1988 Sec 2 Section 1 of the District of Columbia Traf f ic Amendm.'1.t Act. 1925, approved Mi rch 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1121 D. C. COde, sec 40-301 is amended by adding a new subsec tio"la (a- I to re ad as fol lows a-l l) The Mayor and the BOard ot &amp;amp;1ectio~s a~d Ethics .hall jo l t1y develop a" app1icatio"l form a"ld a cha"g. of arne a d ad dress form by Ja"tuary 1. 1989 hich .hal1 allow a applica"tt ~i.hi"9 to regi,ter t o vote t o do .0 by the u.e a t a 8i"g1. fo~ CO"ttai n i 9 the ec sary iTlforma t ioTl for oter r egistratio'l a1\d the informatio'l requ i r.d for the issua.,ce re"tewa l. or cor1;'ect.io" of the applic."tt s d1;'iver's permit or ide"ttiticatio'l card 2) Comme c i"tg Tlot later tha May 1. 1989, the Mayor shall pro ide .ach qualified e l ecto r who applies f o r the l ua'lce. re al. o r C01;'r.ctio of a y type o f dri r permit or for a'l ide"ttitlcatio"t card a opportu ity to compl.te a applicatio to register to ~te by us. of a sing le torn cO"ttai"i"g the nece,.ary requir ed i"formatio"t tor t he issua"lce, re al, o r correctio o f t he dri er pennJ.t o r ide t.iticatio card 3) The Mayor shal l tor ard all 'Ie applica t.lo'l. tD the Board ot E1ectio'ls a'ld ethics wi thi'l 10 days of receipt. W( 4) Applic atio"a rece1.ved trOll! t he Mayor .hall be cO'lsidered recei ed by the Board ot E1ect.io a"d Ethic. a s at the dat.e the applica tio 1 made,w, 1 Sec t 10n 40&amp;lt;l' larolled Original Sec 3. This act shall take effect after a 3~-day period of Congressional rev i ew following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Gover~ent and Gover~ental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. l-233(c}(1», and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes- at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Mayor Distric APPROVED: of Columbia July 15, 1988 the District of Columbia 2 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBLA CoWlci1 Period 5 0 RECORO OF OFFICIAL COU NCIL VOTE OOCI(ET NO 7_-4 4 z 110m Oft Co cal e ar C"CC C C'CiC C C CC C [X AC'TlON &amp;amp; 0 ,0. reo Kv vorE ilK 101_ 011 HI all present l[ It 0" COtIuttI CaI.ooar ClI CTIO OATE: Adopted Final Rl!adlrog 7· 12· 88 JI: VOICE ~ore 2A p p'Y'l!d IO!e 011 quest ThoMas and SK'ela'Y 10 In. Coon",1 :J 1\ eon c.u_ Winter 15 L, C~jIjH C ACTION D"'TE C vOK~ vorL Il 1. 011 q Aboont: o RESULT</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
