<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-177">
  <num type="law">7-177</num>
  <heading type="short">Economic Development Zone Incentives Amendment Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-10-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-177.pdf">D.C. Law 7-177</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 6158</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-177, the “Economic Development Zone Incentives Amendment Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-208, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 28, 1988 and July 12, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 2, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-237 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NCI L OF IHE OISl~JCl OF COLUKO! A NOT IC! O.C L.UI 7·117 "E:CO l1 ic Deve l o p ~ont Zone In ce ntive s Ane ndmen t Ac f 1968 Pursu~nt t o S.,c t ion ~12 of t~e Oi.tdet of Colunnl~ Self Gove rn.,ent ~nd Gove r"~ent~l ReorganiZition ~c t, P. L. 93 ·19 8 t h e Act t he (oundl o f the DiH d ct o f Cotuabi. adopte d 0111 No. 1- 208 on fir s t a nd second r e~din9" June 28 1988 nd Jul, 12. 1988 res pHI; vel Follo w in~ the s ignatUre o f th e /layor on Aug us t 2 1988 this legislation was Hslgn.,d Act No 1- 2li publish ed In the August 12 1988 edi tion of the Regi st er Vol. 35 pag e 6158) and tr~Hrnitted to Congress,on August I 1988 f o r a )O- d~y review h accordance with Sec t ion 602(c)(I) o f th e Act T e Council Of t h~ District o f Colunbla be re b, 9l ve. not i ce th~t the 30 day Cong reHi on a l ~e ~lC re r io d hU ex pi re d a nd t~frefo r e c ite s t h is f nHuent oIS D. C. L 7-177, effec tiVf Gdf,4l Chair~in Of t h e Council Ddt Coun t ed Durln9 t he 3D .da y Con9 r e ssl onal Re v ie w PeriOd: Septe"ber i.8 g. 12 .13 14.15.16 .1 9. 20 .21 .22 .23,26 21 2B 29 .3 0 OttobH 3 ,C 5 6.1.11 12.1 3.1¢ 11. I B .I'J D.C.LAW 7 ~177 amp; OCT 2 0 1988 AN AC'i' D.C. ACT 7 237 &amp;amp;lIroUed Origin Ccdification Olapter 14 of l'itlo 5, Di5trict of Colunbia Oxic (l989 SUW1emantl IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DlSTRlCT OF COLUMBIA AUG a l 199~ To create economic development zone to a ist in stimulating the expa~sion of commercial and industrial bu~i ne e long-term employment, and homeownership in disadvantaged areas of the District and to amend the District of Col umbia Re~l Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, An Act R~l ating to the l e vying and colle cting of taxe s and as s essments, and for other purposes, An Act To provi de for the a b a tement of nuisance~ in the District of Columbia by the Corr~is$ionerG of ~ai d District, and for othe r purpo ~e the District of Columbia Public Works Act of 1954, the Di etrict of Columbia Income and Franchi s e Tax Act of 1947, and the Lower Income Eome ownerBhip Tax Abatement and Ince ntives Act of 1983 to make conforming amendment BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cite d as the "Economic Deve lopment Zone Incentives Am e ndment Act of 1988 Sec. 2. Establi s hment of economic development ~onee a) The Council establishes the followin9 economic de velopment zones, which shall be e ligible for tax a nd othe r d e velopment incentives 1) The Alabama Avenue economic development zone, which is bordered on the north by the east s ide of Fort Stanton Park, S.E. and Suitl and Parkway, S.E. a nd the northern property line of St. Elizabeths Hospital and Alabama Avenue, S.E on the aouth by Southern Avenue, S.E on the northeast alon~ Port Baker to 28th Street. S.E s outh on 28th Street to Denver Street, S.E south on Denver Street, S.E to Naylor Road, S.E and southeast on Naylor Ro a d, S.E to Southern Avenue, S.E a nd on the west by South Capital Street, S.E a s deeignated in l1ayol"s Order 86- 19 dated Octobel' 27, 1986 (33 DCR 779B 2) The D.C. Village economic de velopment zone hich 1s bOl'dered by 1-295 on the west and south, Martin Luther K1n\i, Jr \Ve nu S W on the t, anel. Labor"tory nro11~d Orlg1Dal Road, S.W on the north, a$ de~ignated in r-:ayor's Orde r 86-193, dllt."d October 27, 1985 (33 DCR 7798 3) The l'.naco~tia economic development zone, from the west span of th 11 th Street Bridg ol.lth to Ma rtin Luth"r King, Jr. Avenue, S.E and S Str"et, S.E ea t on S Street, S.E to Naylor Ro ad, S.E south to Altamont Place, S.E outh to Good Hope Road, S .E outh along the wes t boundary of Fort Stanton P a rk to Suitland Parkway, sotothwest along the north Side of Suitland Parkway, S.E crossing Suitland parkway, S.E at Robinson Place. S.E northwe~t alonq the north property- line of Saint Eliz~beth~ Ho ~pital to the s tart of the prope rty lin" of Barry Farm th'!ll to that portion of the west camp~s of Saint Elizabeths Hospital tha t i nclude approximately 40 acres adjace nt to Ba rry Farms on the north property line, inc~ud~ng the r "a in and around the Point, and adjacent to the I-295 expre ay r iqht of wa y on the s outh property line, to th" we~t prope rty-I i of Saint Elizabeths Ho ~pital outh to the ~outhern property-li~e of Sa int Eliz abe th~ Ho~pital east to Mi lwauke e Pl ace, S.E Gouthe.st to Ma rt Luthe r King, Jr. Ave nue S.E outh to Portl d Stree t, S.E west to South Capitol Street, S.E north to Anaco~ it. Drive, S.E ea~t to the west span of the llU, Stre "t Bridge, provi:d"d that the inclus ion of the approximately 40 acre portion of St. Elizabeths HO Bpita l in the Anacosti a conomic development zone ~hall not be con ~trued to affect in an y manner the prepara tion and implem"nta tion of the master plan provided for by section 8 of the St. Elizabeths Hos pital and Diatrict of Columbia Mental Hea lth Service.&amp;gt; Act, approved Novembe r 8, 1984 (98 Stat. 3359; D.C. Code, s e c 32~627 nor shall it b e construed to in an y way inte r re with the policy ~et forth in ~ection 2(3)(L) of th" Fir,al Menta l Hea lth System Implementation Plan Comm"nt Resolution of 1986, effect~ve December 16. 1986 (Res. 6~950, 34 DCR 179 and (4) Any other economic development zone within the Di s trict of Columbia tha t i~ r e commended by the Ma yor pur"uant to ction 3 a nd approved by the Council. by r.,solution. Sec. 3. Requirements for ne W economic development zones al ~he Mayor may r"commend as a n e conomic d e velopm"nt zone ellQ1ble for tax and other d ev elopment incentives any area within the Dl~tr1ct of Columbia in which ~xist&amp;amp; p~rvA~ive poverty. Une mployment, or Q"nera l economic di"tr a" evidenced by 1 or ore of th~ followlnQ factor 1) The une~ploy~ent rate of the area is equal to a t lea st I S0% of the ~nnua i avera~e unemployment rate in the Di!ltrlc cf Columbia for the i d:'ately precedlng c a l e ndar SoCtion 5-1402 year, as determined by the Distrlct of Colurr.b ia Departmen t of Employment Services 2) The poverty rate fo" fM.ilies in the area is at lea ~t 20r" as determined by the United States Census Bureau 3 ne income of t le t 70r, of the resident" of the area i not more than 80r, of the me dian incomo of r e"i dent of the Di s trict of Columbia, a dete rmined by the Unite d States Censu Bureau 4) The popu~alion of the a rea h a" d e c"ease d at least 20 between the 2 mo t 1·ecent decennial c e n "U2 date as determined by the United States Censu s Bureau b) B" fol recommending a ny a rea as an economic d velopment zone, the M1lvor hall m" ke the following findings 1) That comm~rcial or indu'"tri a l development i i9'lificantly lacking in th" an but that ther" is a likely prospect of d"velopClent if the incenti tabli h"d by thi" act ar" available; and (2) That there is a lack of owner occupied housing in the area c) B" for commending any "rea as an economic d"v~lopment zone, the Mayor shall 150 consider the following factor s 1) The delfre" to whioh the residents of the area may benefit from the job opportuniti"s of an economic d ev e lopme nt zone 2) The trength of n "i lfhbo,·hood support for development efforts; and (3) ThS l vel of private sector commitments to an economic development zone. Sec 4 Tax and other development incentives for real property in economic development zones a) Any improv"d rea l property located within an eConO lC development zon" shall be qualifi ed for tax and othe dey"lopment incentives if 1) The qU a lification i s r"commend" d by the Mayor and approved by th" Council, by resolution 2) Th" real prop""ty i" cl ified a5 Cl a ss III or C:a~5 IV r"al property under ction 2. of the Di s trict Of Columbia Rea l Prope rty Tax Revision Act. of 1974 pprove d S"pternber 3, 1914 (88 Stilt, 1051; D,C. Cod sec. 41·813 3) The real property 1e u d in conformity with the zoning regulation and (4)(A) Rehabilita tion of th" real property begin fter the effectlve date of this act and th" actual CO!!t" of the ehilbilitation of the property exc""d 50r, of the value of t e prop"rt.y s a:,c" 5 ~ed by tl Depa rt nt of E"inance Section 5-14D3 «nrolle~ Orlg1c41 and Revcnu~ for the t x year ena ng i rnediately prior to cOl'lU1lencement of &amp;lt;ehe rehabilitation; or (B) Construction on the real property b egins after th ffoctive date of this act b) The resolution approving the qualification for tax and other development incentive~ pu, su a nt to ~ub~ection (a)(l) of this section sha~l 1) Ide ntify t~e qualified real property by lot and square 2) lde"tiiy the o·,mer or o,me rs of the qualified real prope rty 3) Identify each tax or c;~arg to b e reduced, deferred, or forgiven 4) State the applicable tax year or tax period for each tax Or cha ge to be reduced, d e f e n;ed, 0 fOL-given nd (5) State tr dollar a Dunt of each tax or charge reduction, deferr~l, or fo givcness c) The followin~ tax and other development incentives ehall b e a v a ilnble to the wner of ai~fi"d real property 1) A r e duction in r al prop&amp;lt;&amp;gt;r&amp;lt;ey t x a" provide d in ~ection 413(f) of the Di9trict of Coluw~ia Re al Prope rty Tax Revision Act of 1974, approv",d S" ptew.be 3, 1974 (88 St~t. 1052; D.C. Code, sec. 47-815{f 2) Deferral or forgiveness of any r ea l prope rty tax owed a s provided i n section 435a of the Di s trict of Columbia Real Prope rty Tax Revi~ion Act o! 1974, Olpproved Septe mbe r 3. 1974 (SS Stat. 1051 3) D" f e rral Or £or9 e n e of any special a,ue srnent owed a" provided in ~ection 2" of An Act Relating to the levyi~g and colle cting of taxes a nd a e"srnents, and for other purpo s es, approved June 25 1938 (52 51Oat. 1198 4) Deferral or forgiveness of any cost or fe a~se$~ed to Correct any condition th~t exist" on real property in Violation of law a s provided in gection lie) of An Act To provid" for the ~batement of nuisance s in th~ Dl rict of Columbia by the Commi ionc of aid Di trict, and for ot11er purposes, approved April 14, 1905 (34 Stat. 114; D.C. Code ec. 5-513 and (5) Deferral or forgivone5 of any water Or s a ni tary sewer charges due provided in 3eetlons 104 and 210 of the Distl t o! Colu ia Publ~c Works Act of 1954, approved M y 18. 1954 (68 Stat. 102, 107; D.C. Code, aecS 43-1529 43 -1610 Sec. 5. Tal&amp;lt; incentive for bu ine~~ea in economic de\'elop",ent zone a) Any incorporated or unincorpora ted businesa entity that ha a place of bu ine loca t ed within n economic d"velopm"nt zon haH be qual, Oed rOt· t. aK inc ntiv if oo 5-1404 (1) The qualification i recommended by the Mayor a nd approved by th Council, by r oluti on 2) The bu ~ine en~i ty ha ente red an employment aqreement with the District of Columbia pursuant to the District of Cobmbi a Fir!lt Source Agreement Act of 1984, e ff e ctive JUn" 29, 1984 (D.C. L"w 5-93; D.C. Code c. 1-1161 t 5 and (3) The business entity is subject to franchi ee taxes unde r e ither title VII or tit le VIII of the District of Columbia Inc ome and Franc}-"i ~e Tax at of 1947, approve d July 16. 1947 (51 St at. 345; D C. Code, e ec s 47 _1807. 1 "t q b) The resolutior. approv~"q the qUllliiication for t ll X incentives pur ~u ~nt to 'mb~e ction a 1) of thi s section ~hall gt uni:lcorporated \!rllnte d, and Identify busineell Identify the qu"l ified incorporated or entity, e a ch fr~nchi ee tax credit to be (J) Include an e ~timate of the annua l dollar value of e a ch franchis e tax cre dit c) For purpo ~e5 of an ~ncorporated or unincorporated bu~ines~ entlty el~glb~l~ty for the tax credits provided under ection 3 and 4 of title VII and section 4 of title VIII of the Di ~trict of Columbi a Income a nd Frar"chiee T Act of 1947, approved July 16, 1947 (51 Stat. 345; D.C. Code. sees. 47-1807.1 and 47-1808.1 e t $eg he Mayor s hall certify any employee who i s r eSlde nt of the Di s trict of Columbi a who rece ive d an annu~l income equal to or l ess than 150~ of the lowe r living standard income level as that term is defined in section 4 of the Job Training Partnership Act, approved October 13, 1982 (96 Sta 1325, 29 U.S .C. 1503 in the 12 months imm",diately precedinq the commencement of his employment by the qualifi ed incorporated or unincorporated bu~ine a nd i~ not qua lified s ummer youth define d in ~ection 51 of the Internal F..wenue Code of 19B6, approved y 23, 1977 (91 Stat. 1&amp;lt;;1; 26 U.S.C. 51 d) The follow ing tax inc"ntives shall be available to a qualified incorporated or unincorporated bUsinese 1) Credits agai net the corporate franchi s e tax under "ection 3 and 4 of title VIr of the Di~trict of Columbia Incom~ and Franchi ~e Tax Act of 1947, approved July 16, 1947 (61 Stat 3 5; D.C. Code ec. 47-1807 apd (2) Cl'edi t s a gainst the unincorporated businellll franchi~e tax under ~ection 4 of titte VIII of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tay. Act of 1947, approved July 14. 1947 (61 Stat. 345: D.C. Code I&amp;gt;ec. 47-1808 S c. 6. The Dj trict of Cob bia R 1 Prop rty Tax R"vislon Act of !974. apP"oved Septe",ber 3. 1974 (88 Stat. 1052 D.C. C~de 4 7·80\ i mend~d aa (oUo a Sect.i on 4 13 (D.C. C~de, gee 47·915) is amende d by addin&amp;lt;,l a new ~ub ct1on (t to read as foum f) For th~ rell l p:'opc r ty tax yell I' be\l"in"1 9 J l y l, 1989 nd ending J une 30, 1990, lI."d he each tax e at tl'.arc a fter, the tax :J.II,l;lility resulti n g f.om applylnq the ra t es e ~tabli shed in this saction a n d s ecti en 41 2 ef t his act, to quali f ied r""l pr gt;crty ~pprov"d ;m t'"u~nt to eeetien of t~.e Eee'1om,c Dcvelo;&amp;gt;men: Zone In&amp;lt t~ye~ Att,endment I.et o f 1988 l) Sr U bo reduced by 80X ir. t he st taK year beqinning ft the da':e o la"u~nc" of the e t1fieate o f occupancy for t~e qual l ed r rope ty; a"d 2) Shall be reduced by &amp;amp B J2:'1 and 16X 1n t h e eeor.d. t.h~ rd, f eurth, and fifth t. a l&amp;lt; 1 1, reap&amp;lt;lc t.lv l1 b gi""i"9 a ft.e r t.he i3saance o f th" c e ti!ie at.e o f o=~upa"c fo r e qu ali f~ed real prope r ty b) By adding a n a W Boc t ion 43601 t o re ad !lS f ol low Sec 436 he g !o, yor may de t er fo r g i v e i hol~ or in part, any p re p erty taK ow~d to t h e Di~ t. r i ct o f ColW'rl.b ia wi h r pect t e ny qua l ified r l p"eP(l ty approved purs u a nt te Boction 4 of t he Ecenemic Development 20 Ince ntive" Amen&amp;lt;lm.nt Ac t of 198B See 7 An Act Relat i n to the lev yin; a n d co11.ct1n; of t a Ke" a n d sment s. ar.:i f o r ot r p u poses, appr oved June l5, 1938 (51 Stat 119&amp;amp D.C Code ee. 4 7·1201 et I g_j is mended b y adding new 8ectioo la t o re"d as fol10"s Sec_ la Th. Mayo r 1' d r 0 [ o qive, in whole or part any s pecial aaseBsrnent l evled by he Dist. r ict o! Cel umb l a with sp"et to any qu li f i e d 1 1 prope r ty appr oved purs"an t to ct l on 4 of the Economic Dov.lopm.n or.e Ine entive~ A dme"t i'.ct of 1998 Sec. 9. S" ction 1 of An Act To p re\' i d e t e r the il!:late m" nt ef n"i ~an~o i ll t he Di"tnct of Col umbia by ehe CCl"Jl',i 8 a ien ef ~o.i d Di aeric t a nd fer other p""peaea a p p r o y e d April 14, 1906 34 S t a 114, D.C. Code, s e e. S 13 i ame nde d b y "ddlll9 D n s"b ct i on e t o r",ad aa !ollow e) The Ma yer may deC.r or f o r g i v e i n who }_ o r 1 n p t ny cos or Ce sse8aed pureuant t e t h is a c t wi t h ~e.p e t t e a ny qua llfied r eal prepe rty e p proved purs",a n t to c t l0n 4 of t he Econo~i c Oev.l epmc Zone l nee~t iv03 J enci n t Act o 19&amp;amp;8 Sect ion 47- 815 Section 47·846.1 Sectic:n 47· 1 02 1 Section 5· 513 nroll'4 O'I~fb&amp;amp;l Se c g Th Dis t ri c t of Co l umbia Pub~ic iorka A~t o! 1 954, apprcvad May l B, 1954 (68 Stat. 102; D.C. Code, eec 3 -152 4 et eg i~ a""nded 6 !o~ l O" 8: ta) Se~t1on 104 (D.C Cede, Sec, 43 1529 ill mended by designa ting the e~!3t ing te~t as ~ub~oction (a) and adding a new eubsee t lon b to read a3 follow b) Tho Hayor a y de!"r or fo r g ive. i n "hole or in part, any wate r cha rges duo the Di3tr t o f Columbia with re~pec t to Ilny qualir,ed "oa1 gt;tape r ty ~pprovo &amp;lt urauant to ~cction o! the Ec:momic D"velop nt Zo o Inc"r ve Amename n t Act of 1968 b) s ection 2 10 (D. C. Co Se c 3 -1610) is R::umded by deSign a t i n g tho iati ng ex t a s s ·Jbse c i c a) and ad ing ana sulaec i o n (b) t o r a d a5 {&amp;lt;&amp;gt;ll o s b) Tn&amp;lt l1~yor m3 Y cofer or {argive. in "hole or in par t a ny sanitary ~o"er s&amp;lt;:rv e charge" due t~~e Distru: t o f Colu~i~ wi~h re p e t to an, qualified rea operty rov~d pur~u~n~ to s e ction o{ the Econamlc D&amp;lt;:velo~mo~t Zone c nt~ve" A:f,endmcnt c~ o~ 1988 Sec. 10 the OiBt. r ict o f Colur.lbia Income mild Franchi se T Act o f 1947 a pproved July 16, 19 61 Sta t 34 5, D.C Code e c. 4 7 1601. 1 1~ amended a~ [0110 B) S&amp;lt;:ct10n 3 11) o f Titi. III (D C. Code. aec. 4 7 1603.3 (a 11 i a nded to e ad to r ct a s o ll o 11 Rea",on"ble l1o nce fo l ri re o le al10" ance t or sa larie or othe com?en5a t. ion for pereona l gerv i cea a ctually rendered. e"ce p t No al!O'o/ance ahall be ma de f o r .alari s or a q e s in an oun t equal t o the ant o f t he c r e di t allo" ed u nder s ec t ion 4 (a of tU:le VII O.C. Code. aec. 47- 1808.4 and sect ion 7 o f Utle VI II (O .C Code. a" e 7 -1808 ,7 and 5) In th" c all e of ~n uni ncorpo~ated bus ine a u bject to th" t i r.lposed by tit le V I I I of th!s Ac t the aq9re911te d e duction ~o r ~er~'ice!l rendered by individua l o"nors or members actively e nqagad i n the conduct o he un'nc orp o r ated bu"ine Ahall n o t. exce od 30X o f ~h. ne t income of t he bU3iness, comput.ed vi t hou t the benefit o f ~hl~ d e ductl on.M b T't l e VI D.C Code. aec. 4 7 1807. 1 ~a~3 i ended by add t n9 ne e c t lon" 3 alld to r e.ad 8 5 f o U o v Se c J a) Except a s p r ov i ded in 31.:b ection (bl o this s ection. ror ta bl" y e u bcoginnin;r a ft o r Decem!)er 31- 198B any inco r pora t ed bu~in"8B a ppro'le d s qu. l ifi e d p&amp;gt;lrau lnt to s e ct i on 5 o f t h o EconO"lC: Deve lopme n t Zone I ncontive endrn.nt Act. Qf 900 a h All b e l l o~ed a cre dit. a qa ins t the ta" J I!:po d by th la act In an a:nount squal to S~ o f t h e ge5 paid b y the quali!i o~ incor p ora t e d b ua i n e !l e to a n e mp l o'l"'o ce f ed by the '1 °, under s e c t ion S i c) o section. 4.:HS29 5eCt.io&amp;lt;l n-1610 47- 1803.3 the Economie OoveLopment Zone \centive~ Amer.dment Ac t o f 1988, durinq tho !ir~t 24 calendar rr.onths in "h1 e h the employer employed the certifi ed employee b he c redit unde 1I'~b8ec t ion 'a) of this 811c tion shall not be ~l :owed 1 To Kceed. for ~ny ce~ ti!ied e ployee, a total of $1.500 in any 1 taKable yea 2J Untl} the q\'al1{ied n:.corporatod bus1ne 88 ha" employed the ce rtif d employee fo at leaBt 760 hour 3) For a!:y cal Ilcar mon t h in hieh the qualified incorporat"d bu ~ine s~ has not 1ploy"d the certifi d mployee for at l east 90 hou lt;0) If th~ qualifJ.ed i ncorporat~d bU Bt ne.e pay~ t~e eert i f 1ed emp loye~ le~9 than the ~r"ater of ths le9~1 ~inimum wa9" or the w~ge the qualified incorporated b"!in p~ya other emplo'lee" in ~i=11 job 5) It th lt;r.l8 11!1ed lncor.,o~ated bU5ine accords the cert lfi ad l oyoo le88er b"n t$ o~ r :q~t8 t h an it a ccord. other e~?loyees 1n s~milar )obe 6) If the certlfiac em?loy~e w eoploye d th~ r~"ult of the di .plAc~mnnt. othar than Cor C8~.O, of another ployoa, or a~ the r lt of trik or lo lt;out o~ a layotf in which oth employeas are awaitinq recall, or a redUction of the regular waqes. benofits, or riqhts of o ther ploy"e i.n aimll!r joba 7) If the qua li fiod incorporated b ln doe~ not me"t, with rospect t o t he e~plo~ont of the certifi ed e~ployee. ell fed"ral and Oiatrlct of ColuQbia la and roqulations. including those conc~rning h ea lth. safety. child labor, vork/hour. and qual employment opportunity e If th~ certified employ i meMOer of the hoard of directore of the quali!ied incorporsted busineas, directly Or ind i re ctly O\oln~ II majority of its sto~k, or is related t o a ml'mber of tl board of directors or a majori ty otockholder as a spou~e or a. nny relative li s ted in the definition o f dependent" in a e cti on 152 of the I ntornal R"v"nue Code of 1986 pprov d August 16, 19S4 (68,1. Stat. 43 6 U.S.C. 1!2 without regard to "ourCe of income Ic) Whenever a qu~11{1ed incorporat"d b~.i nes, 1" prev"nted £rOITl clai~i ng t redIt Cor wag paid becaus" the certi f Ied e~ployel a not ~mployed !o~ t he period of time ~equired by pan. graphs (b and (b){3 o f thie section, the c r edi t for waq paid y 0" clai~ed '981nl" the ta~ for the immedlately aucc d l nq taxable period in hich the peri od o f "mploymont .a ti.a'!l th" r"quirement of paragraph (b)12) of thi" lubft"ction d) If the amount of the cr"dit llo bl und.r thia oction .xc dft the tax othery!!e due from a qualified IlcorporBtod l»I"lne the o\Ont o{ th" cr"dit not "l".d as an o!f t aqalnat t h" t "x ay be c arri.ed !orward or bac k for up t o 5 year eKcept th at no p tlon o[ tr.e ~redlt 'hal l be: rt(l) C~rrled b a c k to any t~Kable year end1nq b efore January 1, 1990: o 2) Cla1~od f or al\y taxab le y"ar in whi c h the qualified inco,porat~d t&amp;gt;u~inoss W~9 not located wi th:'n an econo"'lic development zone or did not employ a co"ti!ied e mpl oyee See. 4 al E"cept a. provided in ~ubBecti on (b) ot th io ec tion, [or t_a"t~l.e year~ beginnl- ng ~fter ~eceonbe r 31 988, the ount of t pay le unoer thi t~tle by an lncorporated bu"ine r.s approv ed all. qu ified under ac tlon 5 o f the Economic De~'e lopment Zone Incent ives Ame nd en t Act o f 1986 "h,~ll be reduced by credi t e q.1 111 t o o f the lnaUtance ?remiuma a~tributa~le t o a c~rt:f~ed e~ployee pai d t o insure e mployer" against Ilabl lity ior cc~penaa t ion t o ~eaident~ of the DI~tr1ct of ColumbIa under the Distric t o r Columbi a Work~r CG~per.s"tion ~c~ of 1979, efC~=tlve Jul y 1. 199 gt D.C La 3 71, D.C. Code ec 3£-3 01 C;[ for each of the fi 3t 24 onth e dur~n;r whic th" qua1~ f l e" incorporated busine ss 1'11 e mployed a c ertified employee tb h credit l.:ntier SUbllection tal of t i e c tion 3 a 11 not be al10 ed ll Until the qua. l.J. fi"d ~nco porated budneSIl has e",ployed the certified employeo for at l"a~t 760 h o urs 2) F ny le"d"r on&amp;gt;oh in which the qualified incorpo t"c b \.:e ines s has no t omployed the c ertified employee for a t least SO hour HI) If the qualifIed incorporated business psys the certified e",p loyee 1ea5 th~n the greate~ of the le9a' mlni~um ~n9" Or the we g e t h e q~a 1 1 d incorporated busines pays othe r ecployees in imilar jobs; ft 4 J Jl the qualified i co ~po:'ated blaine accorde the certified employee leaaer b~ne t" Or r1 ghta than i t accord" other amployeea in ai lal· jobs S) If the cert ified ployee Wll a emploi'ed a8 the result Of the displ~c~mQnt, o ther than for caus e, of ~nQther emplo yee Or s tho l' o ~ult o[ a strike or l ockout. or a !ayoff 1n whiCh other e mployee" are a ait ~nq recalL or II reduction of t he requlllr waqes benefi ts, or rightB o! other employ s in a1m11llf jobs 6) If the qualified inco rporated buain e do not moet. w, th re 8pect to the employment of t he c ertified e~ployee, all federal and District o f Colucbia lawa a nd requlat. on£, includinq thoae ~one.rn; n9 health. 8afaty, Chlld 1&amp;amp;1&amp;gt;or ork/ h o ur. and equal ploymenc opportunity; n (7) If t~e eerti! i~d e~ployee .8 a ~omber o! the board o f d,rect.ora of tho q u a llfi ed ,nco,·porll:ed bus ,nes l:ectly or i ndIrect ly O&amp;gt;ln a jor) t y 0 jts atock. or lS ated to a t&amp;gt;er o f the boerd o f d lt;"e to or ajori ty amp s&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt im 47- 1907 Dtoekhold 119 11, Dpoac~ o r 11,3 rolllth li~ted ~ll the d efinition of ~dep"ndent" ill 3'Jctioll 152 of the lnternal Rever,ue Code o f 19!1G gt;p l'ovcd AUqIJ"t 15, 1951 (6901. Stat 3; 26 U.S.C. 15 2 ltho\.l t. l'cq rd to seu of in~ome If th mOU:'lt of the ct'edi t 11o 1I,bl pur~u~nt to thH c t\On "xc"ed the lmpo d by thi" act o thena due f l:'om qUQlifoed ineo,'po,'ntcd bu~ine the amcu~.t of the eredi t not used 4 0 gt;n of (Get ag"j t the t a" may be earl ed for re or bac k f or \'lp to 5 years, ex~ept that \\0 po~tior. of the c:,ed B ll be 1) Carriod back to ar.y t,l&amp;gt;,able year e"d:no;l before January 1. 1~90; o r 2) Cla imed for Ilny ta"abl" y"al n \lhi c h tl".e qualifi ed incorpor~ted busine WD~ not located with in an economic dev~lopm t ~One Or did not pl0'l a cortlfied employee Sec 5 20~ ta"ab yean; begin a~t 1 gt;ecember 31 98B. an quallflec1 !ncorponlted bu&amp;lt e l under lIection S of the Econoll',ic C e!o gt;men ZOlOe tncentives i'.mendment ,\ct o f 1988 ha~'iwi t""able ineotlle t!tat incluce r,t chu'ged to a l i cens"d, non-p,;ofit c~lld 6evel opr.1ent cen hn!.l be nIlo" e&amp;lt;l c Ut a'Jain~t the tI impo d by til l" act in an mount e\l" a l to th mOunt by hieh the f air market Ville:\! Of tho pae l ased to the ~i&amp;lt n d, non-po'ofit child deve l opment center e"cood~ the rent chll"ged by th bu~lno 'n to t l'le 1icen~ ed, non-pro!i t eh ild de,'elopmon t Center b or pu::posea of thiS ~ec lon t he t"rm I Fa ir mllrket rental valu m"nn A) The aVer ren char Qed by the I ncorpor ated huaine to :enantll in t hft lIa~&amp;amp; building otner than the licensed on- prOfi t chile developmont cent r. for comparabl e spat or 8 When a licen ed. non- profit Child clevelopt ent Cent ill the aole le:5see oCC'.1[)YUIo;I space in the building, o r "hen the building conta ins no space comparable o t occupie d by the llcenlled. n~n-prof~t ch~ld development c nter. an IImelUnt as det"l-m;'ned by the Mayor h refer-"nc~ to tha aVera"e rent "hlll'\led to t"n~nt5 for oecu"a"c y of con:parable ~pace jll o·;he: b lding~ In tho cr.:mic d e v"lopmen t zOn 2 Child deve l opment c "nter" m"ana elu ld developm t cento as that ter i e de."il\"d in sect i on 2(b) o he nay C c Poll ey A~t of 1979. ef fective Septembe" 19, 1979 (D_C. La 3-16; D.C. Code. lIee. 3 -301 (2 t) If the amount of the credi t Uo ahle under thla ect'o" e"c"ect h othe n' i du" f ~o a U!ied erp orl&amp;gt d bu.&amp;gt;ino::n the amou"t of t h crftdl t not ulled 1 c;.ff~et "9 t t he Iny be ca,'rlftd forwa rd or back for p to !o ye gt;!c"pt that n o p "rtH&amp;gt;n of the credit ahall b.n lt;'tt!.o:t -17-11137 .6 Cnrri ed b ack to Y r ble yaar endi!\ befo re Jiln n l"Y 1. 1~9C; or n(2) 1:1&amp;amp;1 eo f or "ny &amp;lt;;auble yoar in hieh tho quali L ed 1:'1corpo a~"d l&amp;gt;\l c no located l t d" 1I conomic d eveL0J on t ~onl! o r ,h d not ploy iI cet· t ilied employee,n e T itle VIII (D.C. COde. sec. 47 ~1808 et s eq u T.enc"d by Acdi r.q 1:ioll 7 to :c"d as f oUe Sec 7. For t.axabl.e yearl&amp;lt; b"&amp;lt;;i ning I1fter O()cembe r 31, 198£1, t ou 0 co x p3y~blo b y an u c;)rporatad si n ess appro'~ed liS q.a.l~fi d undo s eeti N' S o! t~le 3co,,0:111c Develop t Zo r"centh'es 1T\ nck~nt lIct o 1988 a11 be ad d by crectit eC ftl to the cre:l~t ail"bl tf) qualified incorpo rat" d "u e 8 pu r n t o section. 3 4 d S of ti&amp;lt l ill S 11. 5"octio" J oC ~ho Lo r come Homeo;tnet"sh:p "tilll I.bate",ent and \ccm Je s o f 1ge3, e tl \'e Octobc e, 1983 (D.C. La 5 3 D.C Code c. 47 3502 15 "mend",d b y d"~i q"at.nq t h 8 existing tellt as ,ul:&amp;gt ct~on (a) and adding b~.ctlon (b) t o r .ad ftS !o llo b) NC \oI itl:at."di ng t;,e rcqu~n'm"nt" o f cib "Qocticn 0 of th IInctior a hou ~oho l d Ine.y quali f y as &amp;amp;I 10 lt;lr i com hou~ ehold H n Di t" itt o Co lumbia if t meG!;A Ac h o f the !ollo g requlre r-.er.t l) The household oceupi a "esi&amp;lt;ient ia l property lncl :Jd.nq a "ing amp;I il ho condomini um o r c ooperative, l oc.ted in an conO c dov l0t nt to ap;&amp;gt;ro ed puraua to ction 2 of he I::conolll1 Dftve lop t Zon" l"c"n101 Arnencim"nt Act o C 1988 2) 7"e operty i" the prinCipal p lace of e"ide "ce o! i t" o e 3) The prope ty aO'n(td in fee m?le or t e qui va lent th r pect to o c cupancy i'l"ht" in a coope,·ati by a t t e home buyer a"d 4 r~.o h"'L ho1d incamo doe not "xteed 110 of th 11 me dl"n income 9uideline~ eatabli"he d pureu~nt t o "ec t ion 5 o! thQ Home FUTch \" t nc" F,md .o.&amp;lt t ot 19:'8 fect.ve Septemb&amp;lt;lr 12, 1976 (D.C. L 2 -103 D.C. Code e 5 _220 Sec. l2. r otluT:q in tha. act hall be con~trued AS c eat 10 an pel'Bon, c orpora ti on, uninco.-pot"ated a ~aoci~ti on, p t n h ip, or otller entity ~ny r iqh t ot" en':itleme nt t a the ~a y. and o t her dovelopment incent ive 8t.bl i~hed by thia ac t 5 1 3 TI M~yor ~h ldl. p uant ~o '0''01 1 o f the Dl/,tn c t &amp;lt gt; i Co~u".b dm i ni"tr e gt oc"&amp;lt;:1 i.e approc'ed K&amp;lt c ctlon 4 7-leO 7 :l f-«'t1on 5- 1405 ~to, SoctionB 47-1115, 47-Mfi.l 47-1 20 1 1 43-J52&amp;lt 4 3 1 5 2~ 4.l lO 7 ISOJ 1 11l07 .4, 47- le07.5 47- 1P.(J7.6 47 JllfIR .7 :vw 47-J'Xl2 Enrnl!o~ Orlg1n~1 O tober 21. 1968 {S2 St at. 1203; D.C Ced sec. 1- 150 1 a t :l g i,uu u le a t o implement t he prov!"ion" o f thi" act. 5"0 l 40. n ut t shll11 t eHo e t fte r /I 30- day i a d of Cor.grosllio l evie \! fo llow!n approv a l by tho t1ayor or i n t:r ove"t o f v o to by the ayor a c t ion by the Council o f the Distric t o f Colm'hia t o ove rr i d e the o provided in s ct~on 602 (c 1) o f r.e Distr lct ot Colu~i" 5 1 Gover"ment and Co~-errun"nt" i Reor&amp;lt;;lan iltlon Act. approved Oec"mbgr 2 4 9;3 (8 7 St 1113 D.C. C"de ge e. 1 23 3 0 1 a:K; pub~ icat~on in 8i ther th" Pi ~tri cc o f Co l umb i a R.,gi5':er, th l i~ t ic t 0 Columb Statutc c t-Lal"'l'e, 0 1' th l"trict of Col"OIb M"J.n~cipal 9" 1 1 Q:l 0&amp;lt; Di t ~i" t cf o lumbia ilPP~OVEO; AuguH 2. 1988 w \ v gt;I I\ I l 11 1111 IlI h 'llt\ I' OF &amp;lt 1 1I .l II!I ndl I I s lt;'11 fl~COAO OF OFFICIA. COUNCIL OTE r.'X:Kf 0 1&amp;gt;7 -1 08 n on Co r C1"'N &amp;amp \I £ VO'Cf vOH Com x ACTION &amp;amp; DArE K VOIC~ VOl L fI to 0 \doptc.t s~ Rmdi'l&amp;lt;J 2S 118 !\ mv ] i Ado!"t&amp;lt;l'd f il 1 "pprnllcd Re",ding 7~ 12-88 A.o T_horn flPcl gn_t_cr c "o O~ IE VOOC E O to OQ.o 1 1 </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1501"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1502"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1503"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1504"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>12</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1505"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>13</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1506"/>
  </section>
</document>
