<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-189">
  <num type="law">7-189</num>
  <heading type="short">Health-Care Decisions Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-189.pdf">D.C. Law 7-189</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 8653</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-189, the “Health-Care Decisions Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-131, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 25, 1988, and November 15, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 1, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-251 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU C!L OF PIE O:S TR:C1 OF :O~Uf'!B1A oil !C D.C lA 7-1 $9 -Healt h- t H O&amp;lt;tchlo n o.ct o r 1988 r$u n t o c t lon 41Z c f ~h Dist r ic t of Colu~bi S l f- Qo rn,"e n t ~nd Go vtrnme nt31 horg4njll~fon Ac t, P L. 93 1~S o vellbe 15 198 8 r pec t1v ely Foll o&amp;gt;l in q the sjgn4tur of th e M4yor o~ Dece~bf r I J988, th i s le9! s l .tlon M ~S dis l gn d Ac t Mo 7 Z51 publfshed i n th e Dtoer!l~er 16, H8S, edition o th e n.C, R"9ister Vo l. JS pag 8653 1 a nd t~a nu. ttt d to to ngr e u on J~ nuary 23 1999 for a 3D -do y r e v le M, in .cc ord.nce tth Sect ton 602(c l( 1) of th e At Th~ Council of t ht ~i str tc t of Colu .bia he re by gives no tice th' t the 30 dly Co ngr tsllo n.l R e v le Pertod has pfred d th ref ore, c It this en, ct nt .s D. C. Mar c h 16, 1989. O~ t e, CQunted During th 30-d8y C on9 r e ss \on ~1 R e je Pe rtod: Ja nuary 2 Z5, Z6,27 30 31 Ftbr~.ry 1 ,2,3, 6, 7,8,9, 21 ,22, 23 ,Zl,21, 28 rch 1 2. J 7 g 9, 10 13.1 4, H D.C, LAW 7· I 89 MAR 1 6 1989 OIrolled Or lgiDal conln rAT !O~l lie Chap:er ~2 of title 21, District of Colu~bl a C':ode (I O S pp D.C. ACT 7 -251 l 11 &amp;lt COutl(!L e~ T~ E (llST T or COUJ I1 A iIlt 1 1Se! T~ e.tabl1sh p r oc edu'e; fo r Ung healt c He dec ision s on be half of Inca paci ta ted Indioldy els. IH l N ACHO ev THE COUt.GIL d. 1H( 0;SIIUC1 Qf COLU~B!A. Tn~t th IS act Y be Cited S t he e~lth-C~re Dec isio ns Act of 1988 Sec Purpose a l The ~u,po'e of t n ls l e t 1. t o .ff lrm the rlgnt of a'l competent ad wlts to c ont r ol ceclstons rel ating t o tt.e o n he alth can and t o have t neir rl9ht s and Inten tion s in hellth ore tter s respectH and i~p l e~en t ed by e th e rs If they ~e eone lnc apt ble of maU 0 omo~ nl[~tin9 d e~i\lo n~ f o r t h Ise\Yts S~c Oe f lnl tl o nL For the purp OlfS of thIS act t h. t erm: 11 Attor ney In fact elnS: {A) Tne person who recei ves the Powe, o f att o ncy f Or hea lt h- c arl' dee ls l ons pursu~n t to the p r (l vh ,ons Of th is Ht n "oinT;,t ins tne DIstrict of Co lumbh 3 Durable powe r of att orney fo, ntaltn carc' m, l n. 1 legll1y e ~forcuble GocU fl e t ~l t Il exec ut ed In tht DI~ t r;ct I n I nne~ con"ltent wltn t nl~ i~t ur 1101 y e~e cut eo In a no tner Jurl~Oict ion pursHn! t o s!mllar pr{}v;~lons o f H e 1 o f that j urhd lc 1On; and (bl Cre ltes I po wer of attorney f r health e ar l' decisions, which Is e f fectl .e upon nO only Ou,ing lnca plcltftion and 15 un.f f eeted by the sub~tQuert disa bilI ty or incapa c ity of the prinCipII a s dtfln ed In tn' s let 4 H~.lth- o.r ooide r e ln' any ~e~.on or 1'nt7.tl 0~ al entity, inclu~ ln 9 he~lth cl re 'ac t lltle I Oe Intd 1n section 2 of t he Health Care and Co~nu n ity 1 gt;c&amp;lt;:t!on'1 220 1 New. Section 2l·11r'J2 I I r$ld e n (e r ac ,IHy H pi(c 3n d f'Ol"e tHe ,i( r n~HC ~tt 0 ]983 ef fective FCl&amp;gt UH l ]ge4 { !i e 1!l; o.c o c rt. 32 13Cl li(ense~ o r oth~~I&amp;lt e .JtnO H to prov,de ~e ltl c rc $c r eC l~C n r ,ct Oil 'InC'PH dt e l~Ud 1~~ns q n I t indl"~Ud' I&amp;lt; hl H s~ f( 1C;ent e ntal up y tr Dpr~:i~l th e C r I pll ca~io n l o f he,I ur e cc l lio n j':e &amp;lt;I h olcr. r e d' n g e dl t ern,tin s p rese n t~j r o.,rr n :c~ t c t h~l choIC e 4" Yn~nb' g~ D Y \ "a~ne r 6 P rl n:;p~ l e~n A p on hO h r tn t t o a~ e he a e r e d e C l On or h hcr n. n benef or on h o r her o c,o~n S ec Pr esul';ti')r, of c~pHity. lin indivl d y 1 s~'lj b e p rt lymeC cH. h :e o f Un'i IIC &amp;amp;lth-cH e d ecisio Unlel~ cer t,f a d o tn~r w H und e r sec t io~ 5 of nl s H Mental n C Hity to lt;e a lIetlth_c.re decl s o n I ~r l ll not ~e Inferred f r Q" the fa c t th~t an ;nci,i d YI 1 I) fU \ Ot e n olu~ tar il y or l nv o lunt.rll hosp; ul d f o r I:Ieflu l ll1n r pursuent to c h o Pler S of t;tl~ 21 of t~c D1S l rlc t o f Lolumbia Code; [2) II ~e n t4 11 re rded o 5 bee n et er~in e d hy a cou t to be 'ncor.p~le n te refy~e CO~I:Il lment ynGe r the Men la ll c t d e d (It e n s Constltutlon.1 \I gh U ne Digni t y Act of l 'HU ef hclI. r Uarc h 3. 197 9 (D C. l 2 _131; D.C Co de. He 9~ ] et..liS or (3 1 Has-r ccrserntor or 9UHdi.n ~pp l n t e d pursuan t o the AppOintme nt of Co nse rvatorl Ac t o f 1 96 a pprovtd S~pt e"b e r H, J965 P 9 Sut. 714; DeCod e se c. 2 1-J5 0 1 t_LJ t9 o r tht nlstr i e! Of ~O\ Ij b i GUH d! H l p P r Q t ~c t h r·ocH·Qiny a nd Dur a ble PO \ol ~r o A torne Ac t of 19&amp;lt;16. dfec the J a nuo'y I. HOo; [D.L L 6 63 D.C. COGt a e. 21 20!l1 H Ug e oc ~i o" 2]-'203 S e c. S. Cer :1f ic a tion 0' InC d Pdcit y c&amp;gt;&amp;lt [ a lena I Inetpa ci t y to H e a n e a l c .r~ de eis'(ln Sect I.n s na Il be ~c rt jfj ed by 2 r hy, iclons wna ~re \ :ce n&amp;gt;c~ to practi ce in the D15 tr i ct and quali fi e d t o rak d e ter ln ~tion of e n\41 I ncop.cHy O~r of to e eertifj;1\9 p~y ci n hill be e y c h;otr H t t le·~t 1 of th e Ct'tifying p~ysl cl on h~l l M l n c tile in~id u l I n 'I~ e l o wit nln I d. j p rfcee lo'l ce r flc at' o n h c e r t yi n9 phy stc tdn s sh aJ J 9i ve an op l n,on r e g a r l(1; th UH ~nd n~tu r e o t me n td l i C P H t~ as Re ll s it s e.:en t and prob a bl e dur.t ion tl 1 pr o f n;ona i fin d i1\9S d opt"i" n\ f or"'I ti tll h o f en ifjc lt' on IIn de r ~lI b~ e C \l on a f t h h e t lo 1ft 11 be f p rf d in writin 9 in,l u~td in thf pa tlent-Cir f record~ of t he in djvjd u l. a nd pr ovic t clear e v iaenc e t h t he penon i s Inc apab le 01 vndenUn!l lng the he. l t re Choic e. r l n 9 a deci~ion concern l n~ the ~4rt lcul .r treatmen t or se r vice~ I n Qu e~t lon. o r 'OQ~unlc.t ;n9 decision ev~n if e Habl e of mak in9 i t {c) Ctr~ Hic4tio" of ineapHlty u nder thh Hetio n ~hall be 11 1ttd in IH effe ct to the c.poe i ty t o mak e health-c l r e decisions and shall not be constru e d as a f inding of incc.,pe t.ncy f r .ny o t he r ~urvose. Se c. 6. Ourablt po _er o f .tt orn ey f o r hul th u re a competent a dul t may designat e In T l t ing. a n Ind i v idu .1 ~h O snail be e QPowe red to n .ke he. lth c r e dec l .l ons on blh.lf o f th omp.tlnt d l t. I f the co~p~l~n t ad~ lt be~O"eS lnc,plble by rei son o f ~ent.l di s a b i li ty. o f g lking or c o~mvnlc~tin9 choice r eg drdln9 a pa rt ic u l ar h~~lt h "care dteis ion {hI A durlO le po er of I,torn~y for h dlt h Cl r e s nal I lnciude In 9 u e which clear ly communi cat e s that th e princip,] i ntends t he attorney In fact to hue th e authority t o IIlIke h tl l th care ~ecls;on~ on bellilf o f the g ri nclp '] I nd ~h lll Inclu6e hn gu a ge Id e nt ic a l or subsUn t l.lly slmllir t o t ht f ollo.dng 11 Thts IID"e r Df I ttor" e y sh a ll no t be Iff ec tea by the subse qu ent i "c l pl city of tne pr incip II or 2 ThI S po we r o f attorney become s effe c ttoe upon t he Inc ,pl cl ty of th e prlnclp.l e) A durable pn e r o f at t o rn ey f or h ealth tHe sh al l be dated ilnd ~i9 n ed by the prinCipII and Z adult ttnesas who dfflrm thlt the principal 15 Of so und mind and free from dures s It the t h e of l19nln Th~ 2 ~dult wHne!5fs Sh il l not lnclUQt the princlp,l. t he h e ,lt h- care pr ooldtr of the pr ncip i l or n employee o f t he h d l th ca r e pr o older of the pr lncipi l d) Of tne Z ad ul t witnesses re fe rred to In sect i on S{c at l ea H 1 s n, ll no t be hted t o tne princiP II by b lOOd 4rrilge or adopti on In d ~h.ll no t be e ntit l ed t o 4 ny art of tht estHe of the ~r lncip i l by 4 current will or op~r 't lon of II e Any durlble po"er 0 1 Itt o rn ey e &amp;lt;ecute d prIo r to the e ffe ct h t dHe of thi s .et and s pecific~lly writt en to inc lude hea lth_c.re dtCiSio~ n.&amp;lt;1n 9 afHr incompetency s h.11 be fle ctl if the execut ion of th e prior do :u~ent n e e t, the requl re&amp;lt;llel"lU Of t hi s act. Sec. 7 I gllts inc dllt l e s of t t o r ney In flc t I Subje c t to ny express l lmlt .t lo"s In tile c u ra ~l e po" er Qf H torney for he l th e i r e n tHorney tn f. t t 1 1l hl .e I I the rl9hts po wen nd IH ho rity re I tid to J i:e\ol Secti on ~ell th -c ~H decision\ thdt Di s trict o nd fed~q l j l"1inlmu th e pr ln ci pa l wo u l j ~a&amp;gt;"e un~er j h, s 4'J t ritj o;h~11 in cl 'Jdt, at (I) The ~u: hv'ity to ~rHt r tfule or it ~d~&amp;amp CDn ~ent t o the prov;&amp;gt;1 0n o f a nj neait&amp;gt ca r e Hn lc tr eatment, or pr O(ed~re 2) Tn e rignt tQ r~v ie t r hea l th c.r e r eco r lS of l hr ~rin(jp a l 3) ln e rig h t 0 be prod&amp;lt;:e&amp;lt i h o i l in f o~t:lH' on nete\\, ry t o na ~e i~ f o rmtC hta l th- c a d ~cisjo~ s The l t ho r 1 t j t o $elect nd a l ~c~6rge hulth.e ar e professjon~h; an" IS) Tne u thor;ty to nak r de ci s ions regtr" ing 4~1$$lon t o Or i ch.~ge f rom h e llth·c a re f ac ili~'e~ and c o tHe H 'y wf ul Ht iDns that y be ne' essary t o cury Oll t t neU dtc I 5 i on b)(l) EHept s pr oddeC In pH,graph (2) of tn i u b S ect lon ~nd "nles~ a dura cle Dow ~r of attorney for heal t h ,a ~e provides oth e rw ile t he designat ed dttorne, in' fa ct i own to 0 he.lt"_c e p~ ovide r to be oil.bl. ond tllln to mak e, particu lar health_care ~etis ion. 5h~11 hav e pr io r i ty Over an, o th e r p e so n to act f or tn e principal in 111 catten r e9 i1r~ in9 healt n r e. {2) A ~e ~i9n ate j a tt orn ey I n f~ct hall not n il ve th e 6utho r ity t o 4~e,l part ic ula r he 6 lth eHe decision, if the p r 'ncip a l i. a bl. t o 9' ye o r wtt nh old ,n f ormed con s e n t .lith respect to t nU "eels ion c In e~er ,ts t n~ a t~ortty und e r J dur il ble power o f a tto r ney fo r h ea l t h c il re. tht att orney tn fil tt sh .1 1 htye a du ty t o HI In acc ord a nc t tth I) Tht wis!\n Of t he pr i nc ipal oS u,l. essed 1n the "urilc l e po we r o f att o r ne y for h e alth c ~re; Or (l lne go od f a i t h bel i ef of the attorn ey i n h e t OS t o th e best i nter U cf th e pdnc lp~l, if tne ishes of t he pr inci pi I ~re n o n a na Cln ne t be a"ert~in e 0) NothIng In thi s H t Hil l a ffect a"1 right that an att o rney In fact 1 n l\l e l~depenQe nt of the ~esl9natl o n In I d urab l. po cr Gf att o ~n ey for he alth cor to l"1 i1k e o r o th e rw ise pa rtici pa te in heal t n c are decl~ion~ on beh lf Of til e prlncl p ll. Sec. 8. f orns f o r c ~uting duub le PQw r of .tto r ~ty fo health c are. An, wr tt l e" f o r~ mee t i ng the r eou l r epe n ts o f .ec tlo n y b~ u. e d 0 crelt e c u raD le PO~tr o f .ttorney f o~ h t lth Cilr e. Tn" f 01 10 ng o ff a ~a.,pl tor onl, a na It s in(lu lon In t hl~ se ct,on no t con~t r ~ed to p~ecluJ~ t he us of alt t rn at l" I 1~ IS H SJ(j, NI~ G e SeCt;On ]1 _220; THIS DOCIIHENT, IT IS VIrAL FDR YOI: Til rllOW hiiD UNDERST~IIJ Hi:st FMTS TrilS DOCU~[IIT G!V[S THE P[R SJII VOL! I,~II[ AS lOUR ATTOR~EY 1'1 FACT THE POWER TO ~ArE HEALTH -CA RE DECISIDIIS FOR YOU IF YOLI CANIIOT HIKE THE CECISIO:IS fOR YOURSELF AFTER YOU IlAVE SIGNED T'IIS DOCUH[lll YOU I I~V [ TII[ RIGHT TO MAn HEALrll-C!.RE OECISIOIIS FOR YOURSEJ lr YJU AR~ M£'ITAlLY cDM?UE I; T Tv no SO. ill MonlO II, AFT!:P. YOLI H,\\'E SIGNED TH IS DOCU'IEIIT, 1&amp;lt;0 Hoe.THEIIl H~Y BE GII'E'I ~O YO" OR STOP PED OVER YOUR OBJECT I ON IF YDU AR IEIITALLY COMPETE IIT TO IIAKE THAT DECISIOII ¥aU MAY S~AH IN THIS DOcUMIIiT AllY TYPE OF TREATMETIT THI\T YOU DO NOT D£S I H A~J p-rn THAT YOU WAHT TO KE SURE YOU REeElI'&amp;lt YOU HA~E THE RIGHT TO TAK[ AY TH[ AUTIIORI,Y 0, YOUR ATTDRHf Y Itl FACT UNLESS YOU ~AVE BEE N AD J UD ICATED INCO MPEHliT, BY IIOTrrYUIG YOUR HTOR II EY lli FACT OR H(AlTH-tAR~ PROVIDER EITHER ORALLY DR IN IIRITING. SHOU LD .I TIS OF THE YOU REV OKE THE AUTI10RITY OF YOUR ATTORNEY IN FACl ADV I SAB LE TO REVOKE I II WRI TI IIG AND TO PLACE COPIES REVOCATIMI WHEREVER TH IS OOrUM£liT IS LO CATED IF THERE IS ANYTHING IN HIS DOCUHENT THAT YOU 00 IIOT UNDERSTAND, YOU SHOULD ASK A SOCIAL IIORKER, LA II YER, OR OTHER PERSON TO EXPLAIN IT TO YOU YOU 'liDUlD KEE P A COPY OF TH:S DOCUMENT AFTE9 YOU HAvr SIGtl£O I ClH A COPY TO THE PERSO II YOU NA E AS VOUR ATTORHEY 1 fACT. IF YO U AR: UI A HEALT,l _CARE FAC I LIT Y, A tOP Y OF THIS OOCUME II T SHOULD BE INCLUDED IN YOUR MEDICAL RECORD POWER Of ATTORNEY FOR HEU TH C~RE hereby ~proint: n me hDr:I~-teTep~o~e n umber d, mv dttorn ey in f~ct t o k e he' lt h -c~re decision, for me jf I b.OOOle u n I e to ke ~y o n h lt c~r e deci~1on Thj~ gj .e Iny at t o r o~y i" fdct t ~e po~cr to grant, refu.e, or it~dru co nse nt On TO y be n. l f for any n~.ltn c~re &amp;lt;er "i c tr t.,c nt 0 procedu r e, Hy ~ttor y in fact .1so 0 1100 Or hH the j u th prlt y t o H t o he .lt h. cHe p er ~on ne l ge t lnfor t lo n .n t ig n forns necess.Jry to cHry ou t nese dech lons f t he penon n.Ma jS y uto r ney In l.e t 1~ no t iva l1 4 ~le o is un ab l e to t el r~ attor ney in f I appoint t hC f ollo in9 n on t o 5e~v~ in I'e o r lh t~&amp;lt;l bel 1 name hOr'lt Idarns h om. telePh one nU mb H 0 ~l alepnon numb~r Z no home .ddrtlS hOllle telephone n""b eT telepho ne or k nu ber "Wi t h th ts docunent I intend to create a pO"er of a ttor ney f o~ hea l th care hl cn snaIl take e ffect if I become inc apa ble of ot in9 0 0 he a l th,cl re deeisions I~d shall con tinu e during that I ncapacity l1 y attorney in fact s hall mak~ h e. lth·care decisio ns IS I direct belo Or 4~ I m a ~e ~no~n to my jttorney in f act in ~o~ e O t~er ~6y a SH H MENT OF OI N ECT! H~ CO NCERtH NG llF~.PR OLO II GI G t ARE. TRtAT HEN T, S ERVICU N O ~o r. CEOUR[S B Y 11 Y 5IG~ATURE I IIIOICATE TIIA: U~ OERST A:I O r·IE PURPOSE AND EFFECT OF Til lS DOCU MENT I 5 i gn r:1y ame to tl';1 forrn un H ad dress WIH;ESSES "I d~cl.re tllat t~c person who Ilgned or acknowledg ed thi&amp;gt; doc ent i&amp;gt; penon~lly known to Ole th.t the perso n sIgned or acknow I~ dg.d thi s du r"nle pow~r of attorney for h~ a l th car e in my pr~senc and that tne p. rson ~pp rs to be of sound mi nd ~nd ~nder no duress, fraud, or und~e lnfl~ence. I" rt not the perso n ~ppolnted a s the attorney in fact by t hl document, nor .rn 1 the health-c~r~ provider of the prlnclpdl or ~n e ~pl oyee of t n e ne"lth-care pro,lder of t he principal. FIrst W1tn ess Signature: Hom~ Addr!B: PrInt Ihne: Odte: Second III tn ss SignHure: Home Addres Prj nt e Va t e AT LEAST 1 OF THE ITNESSES LISTED ABOVE S~ALL ALSO SIGH THE FOL LOWING DEC LARATION I further dtchre t ha t J an not related to th e prlncip~ l by b lood a rr1a g' or adoption, and to the best of my kno wledge, I n not ~nt it le d to ~ny part of the es t"te of t he pr i ncipal under curr~ntly edstlng ill or by oper.t lo n of law. Slgnatur Signature Sec. 9. Re.ocat i on. New 0) At "ny t1m! that t he principal has the capacity t o Section 21- create a durable pow e r of attorney for h e alth car t~e principal II1ay 7 ~ollod Orlg1nal (11 R~yo e t he a"poi n t~,cnt f the ~ttorn ey In fHt under d u rtb l e power o f attorn~y for hea lt h c.r~ by not lfy;ng t he Jt torn ey 11' fac t o r a l ly or ir ritin 9; o r Rey okt !hC 6ut crftj tD r'l.k~ h e.l t h· c re de(ls;cn~ grar. t ed o t~e attor r cy ;n fac~ und cr a d r~ble er c, tttDrney for health 'ire by ~o~t( y j~g t hulth rc provide r.l1y (or .1&amp;gt rillng b) If 3 ~e~ l t r rovjd~r ~5 nn lt;jed of a r e o t ion pursu nt to ~u~~fe tl on 1_I (Z) of this section. the he~ l t ca re prO.lder ~n~ll Cotur.ent thi~ f,ct in t~ e ;l.t ient- c~ r e recoro~ of lnc pd nc.pol 4nd m. ke a TeasonabiC ~tfon lO notify the ~t t crncy in tHt of t he r evocal.on el Tn er hd ll be a rellutt d tll lrc .umpt ion feelin9 tne bur&amp;lt;l e n of proQf ln ~t prinC i pal nas the c apacIty t o v o e a dJr~bl e p ~w~ r o f to rney for h Cdlt h c e. {d) \Jnl e i~ e.pr e ly p r oda~1 o t herwf l e a Hlid auraole pO IO' er of ~tt or n fy for he ~1th c~ re re vo el any p r i or du r. ble pa w r of ~tto r ney f or n e~l th- ca r e decisio n s onl lei Uni e H a d"ra le po we r o f attorney f o r hul t n CH e e. pr e l y pro vid e, ot her wli e. Ind f ter i t e xe cution the :na rrfl gt of t he prin Ci pa l H d hlO h H or "n nulled. t dISsolution Or a nullnent sn ,l l lu t o"'lt ic~ l ly r e vok e a ces;gn l t ;un o f t ne for",er spoule al an att o r ney in f act to ake nult h-c.re d~cisfon~ t or t he p-incipal. If a de i 9n tion i s r e vo ked soll1, on I cco~n t o f th is s u bsection. i t ~h al l be rev i ved by the remlr .i. ge of t he pr Incip a l t o th e f or~tr Ipou~e but noy be ~ub~~quentl y rev o l ed by a tt of the prinCipAl. Se c. 10. He l t h c are pr O&amp;gt;lt &amp;lt;!er tt"ttHion tlo h ealt h'CHe pr odde n.y require d n ind tvi du l l t o e xecute a dura b l e pO~ fr of a tt o rney f or he~lth c ~re a s a CO d i t;on for t he ~rovhion o f he~ l t h car f jces o r ,d iB ion to he a lth _eire fHllity, as d f f in d in Heti o n Z of t he lie a l t h -C re and Communi t y ReSide nce FacIlity H o~p i ce nd Hone r e Li c ens u re ~ct of 19A 3 e f f e ct i ve f eb 24 19B 4 10.C. La 5-4 B; D.C. Code HC 32 -1301 c) Aft er H indl v icH l ha~ He,t at le ast B ho ur s In e n e~ lth ore fHi l l, y hul th (H~ pr o v id e r O'1'y r e Qu e s t he lnd;vjd~"l t o e l e e" te 4 durable pow er o f ~tt orne f o r h t t lth Cl r e subj e ct t o the limi t ations ~et f o rt h in th .s ac t The hf~lth c a r e pr o vl de m. y not be n med s t he .tt or ne in hct c. 11. Sul&amp;gt;stltwteO consen t in the tlSfnCt Of a du r able po~tr o f ttorney f or ht. lt c .re a nd "ro~idtd U'dt th~ lnca p6 c ;ty o f t he ,rjnc l e e n c~ rl \l i ed in 4Ceordance l c li on th f l o o n~ ind t d ~a\ S n l ordH of p r io rity U l r n ~e\o h a l I b th od zed t o 9 q n t, r e f use o r lo: e!J Seetio 1 20 c&amp;gt;&amp;lt St'etio gt gt; l w ;th~r~w co Or&amp;lt e h.lf of th e p.t!~nt with relpect t o t pro_ilion of any h c~ lt n-c~r e ~e r" c t reat ~ent, or procedure J A cou rt·ap()o i nted 9U 6rdlon o r ,onsc n-Ol o r Of the p.t l ~nt, i f t he tonsen t h wi th i n th HO~e O~ t he q u. r d l n\hip o r co~\er .ators h ;p 2) l ~e ~pou~e of tne p,t i ent 3) An ad ult child o f the patient 4 PI r en t of tne p atient 5) An adult ~iblln9 of the pn lent or (6) The nea res t .i_ln; r ela ti_ e of the p~tient b) A dec1l1on t o grant, r efUH or w tt h dr~w consent de pu rS ll i nt t o ~Yb~ ettion o f thh Hct ton Shall be b. s e~ on t he known i s~n of the plt i ent o r. tf th e i ~hes o f t he patlent .re unk~own .nd t'n~ol be ee .t' in ld, on good f, i tn beli e f IS to t he be~t tn tere\t~ of the l'atie~ t c) ThHe Inall be H lHs t 1 i tneH present wheM er a perlon specified in pH aQ f a phs (a)(2 6) of th is IHt l Qn gr~nt refu~e s or w1t hd r~w s conse nt on beh o lf of t.he ~4t ten t d) If nO tndhidu al in prior class IS reH onably ,v, ll able, ment c ap a ble ,nd wi lling to o~t r lupon\l bllity f o r ~e thlon U nQ ~h. ll rest wll~ t ne n f t r e sonably ~v. l1 .b l e, nental l y c lpab l e, a nd tl lt n pe rson o n the prio r ity l ht e) Any perloOn Hs t~ d in subSection (al of t."s section sha ll hHe le 9~1 st n ding t o cn ~I IHge in the Su~e r io r Court of the Distri c t 0' Col umbia any ~ec jsion node by a person of h Ig her priorlty as l' sad thin thAt sub sec t i on. S e c 12. ll~ltltlons. It o pen on auth o rlled t o att p r~u4 n t to seC t ion 11 of th ts l e t sh a ll nave the po er a) To consent to an a bortion s ter iliu t io n or psy cho-su rgery un l ess ~u th orizc d by a court b) To consent t o con_uhh e thuapy or benldo r mOdi l 'c.tlon prograns I nvoly in vers j st 1 11 unless utnorl l~ d by a ~ourt; Se c. 13. Effect of I Ct. Notn lng In tht~ I Ct ~h.ll be con~ t rue d t o conDone autll o rite Or ap prO ve l1ercy-Ull i n g or to per",tt a~y a'flrm!t ive or de libe r! te ct to end d hUDI~ life o tft er than t o per""t th e na t url l proceSi o f d,i n9· Set. 14 Connru ction. Tnl~ act shall be l ibe r al ly co n str ue d a nd HPlled to o o te jts undtrlyin pu rpos e s anc pollct es Sec. 15. Effe ctl ~e dat e T~I~ a ~t ~h ll tlk~ eff~'t after. 3 D-da y period 01 CongreSSion a l rtv1e fo l10 i n9 appro l by tile 111yor (or In Iew Sr cUon 21-2 e Se c tion 2\-2 Ie ct ion 21 2 th vent cf e:o by th Y f a:tio n h th o u nc'l of nr 015 Ct o f Colurbi. t o o r r id e he ve J pro.1r.~d i n ,eltian 602(t)(11 u f t f Di, t~ l' t 0 Clu~bl S el Go v~ cnmfn l .n d liv v crnment 1 R!'o r 9.nH d~l nr. f,c t ppro ve d Jecenber 2 4, 1913 (S 7 5tH. S D. C. Cod e se 1-233( 0 )0 n C pu~l1[ Hl n" In e1t~er :ilc D'std t t 0 Co lu b i. Regi s t e r, th e Diqrict o f Co l h S t~t ute t -L4r9t. o r tile DHtn C Co lurh ft4 uni c ;pa l R~9ul ion A b n d lrr.an Cou nCil o f t f ~IH r ~c t o CCll u l M~y or Oi' t r 1c t f Colu~~i i I II I'\ CII Of' Till: I)!ST I! 1L1' OF COI.II MR 1.4 L'o r; 1 rrriod S.nn RECOIW OF OFF!CIAl COU NCil VOTE :xx 1 0.;0 on Ce C OOCl VO "E .r.(loPt"d Fi r n Read,n I O·2S 8A d Chair r. C t a nd ~o b"r ppr(lve emL"r Ia l voted l o!.5&amp;lt;'n 7 131 0 0 l&amp;lt O&amp;gt;C~ VOTE 0 lbo:n/l n mH.h v O&amp;lt;C 0 O&amp;lt; O vot.ed no b </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
