<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-204">
  <num type="law">7-204</num>
  <heading type="short">Frigid Temperature Protection Amendment Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-204.pdf">D.C. Law 7-204</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 454</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-204, the “Frigid Temperature Protection Amendment Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-401, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 29, 1988 and December 13, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 6, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 7-275 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DIS T~!C T OF COLU MBIA None: D. C. LA 7·204 "Frigid Te~pl rAture Pr~t ect lo Ame~d~e n t Act of :98S ursu&amp;amp;nt to Section 412 of the District of Co l umb l a S~lf Gov ernment and Govlrn~en ta l Reorganizat ion Act L. 93 38 tilt Act tile C~unc:f1 Jf tht Di str i ct of Cll l umbLt a&amp;lt;:1 op ~ed r No. 7-401 on f i rst and second readIngs Novemb.r 29, 19 88, and Decflllbtr 13 1988 rupec:tively. Fol lowi ng till s i gnature of tn! Mayor on January 6, 1989, this legIslation was assign ed Act No l -27S published in tile January 20 1989, eclltlclI of tile D.C. il.egfsh r hI. 36 plgt 454 Ind tra ns~i tted to COln gress on January 23, 1989 for a 3D-day review, In accordance with Secti on 602 c 11 of the Act. The Council of the District of Colu~bl. ha r!by qlv!S not lC' that the J04d lY Con~rus ion l l Review Period has expirtd, an d t her.fore, cltls th i s enact~ent as O.C Law 7-2 0 2, eff.ct i ve Mlrch 16, 1989. DAVIO A. CLARKE Chllrman to the Council Da t81 Co unttd Durin g tht 3D 4dly Co ngre1s ional R.vie P.rl od: J anuary 24,25,26,Z7,30,31 FebrUlry 1.2,3,6,7,8,9,21,22,23,24 ,27 ,28 rch 1,2,3,6,1,8 9, TO 13.14 15 D.C. LAW 7 20 4 lfaR r 51988 D.C.ACT1-27~ C::C.i!"iation iI!'W Sute"aon:e: c e 3. Ci=ii of CO b:'a CXe 91!9 $U IN THE COU~CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To Ulur~ that t~ere Is d pl.ct for t he homeless t o suk protect io n from the cold on nl9hU when tile temperatur-e falls be lo w ~6 dtg ree s fa~renhe\t and t o ami~d An Act To est4blish a Olstrlct of Columbia A.-mory Board, and for oth er pu rposes An Act To aut ho r i ze the cons truct ion maintenance, and operat i on by the Ar~ o ry Soard of the Oistrict of Columbia of a stadium in the Ot !trtct of Colu~bta. and for other purposes, and the Washington Conv ention Cen ttr Management Act of 1979 to specifically includ e Imergency protectIon as permlssable fu nctions E IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF CO~U~BIA That t nl s a c t =41 be cited .s tnt "F rig id Ttope rat ure Pr otec t i on Ame ndme nt Act of 1988 Sec. Z 4) E~cept.s provided In subsection (b on ~ne nlg-nts linen ~ne tlmperH url falls belOIl a degrles fa hr enne i t, tne "a),or sha ll make a va il able appropriate sp a ce I n Dlst r j ct of Colum bia District buildings and faci l ities for an p'rson In thl District IIho does not have a ny otne r shelte r. Fo r t h l purposes of this section n l gllt me ans tllit ti lle betlleen tht lIo urs of 6:00 p. I:I. on a g i ven day and 6 00 4 m. on tile (0110111n9 da b The "ayor sha ll no t USIT District of Co\u~bla Pu bll c Sc lloo\ blilld i ngs currlnt1 being used for Idu cat ton l p"rpOS IS II j tllout thl prior approval of the Board of Education Se c Sec t ion I of An Act To establ i sh a District of Columbia Armory Board, and for other purposes, a pp roved June 4, 1948 62 Stat 3J9~ D.C Cod e. sec. 2-301 is a me nded b in serting .fter the pllrase 'SUCh other act i vit i es .s ma be I n the Interest of th e District of Columbia the phrase Including but not l i mited to, the p r ovision of emlr glnt protlctl on n e n t h e H.-pera ture hi ls belo 26 degrees fahrenhe i t 1 New 5- J21 o J..cn 2- 301 i &amp;lt; lDroll,d Or!gi:&amp;amp;l Sec, l Secelon 5( a of An Ac t io author i ze tH constr uct io n, ma in tenan ce a nd o ~er! tion by the ~r:l1 ory 80Hd of t~e District of Colu bia of d stadium i n t he District of Co l umb i a, and for oth er pur,oses. appro~ed S e Dte~ber 1. 19S7 (1 1 Slat 620; D.C. Cod e, sec. 2·)2 is amended ~y aao ln 9 new paragrap h 12 to read as fol l ows 12) To pr ovid e emergency protect iO n hen t~e temp erature h1ls be low 26 degrees fahrenh ei t Sec. 5. Stction 2( d) of t t Was hington Con~en t io n Ce nter flanagl!lIIlnt Act of 1979, effect iv e September 17 1979 D.C. La j·36; D.C. COClt. sec. 9· 601 4 1s amended by i nserting a f ter the ohr ase nd such ot her a ctt tle s as mly be i n the in terest of the C! ltztns of the Di stric t o( Colu mb t &amp;lt;1 tile pnrase 'incl ud ing but not li mited to, the ~rovl$jon o f emergency pr ot ection wnen t hl ttmperatyre f~ 11, be l ow 26 degrees f a h r enheit Sec. 6. SectIo n 2(0) of t he Emer91ncy Shel ter for Faml1ies R.eform Amendment Act of in 7, effecthe Harch 1l, 1988 D.C. Law 1- 68 D.C Code, uc J- Z0 6.J Is amended by .dding new paragrapn (3 to rtad as fo l io 3 the May or sh a ll not pI Ice homeltSS families In congregate she l terL For purposes of this section c ongregate 5he lt, r" mea ns a flcility itn 1 or more of the fo ll owing ch ara ctlri,tlcs 11 Sleep i ng arran ge",ents wl'lere different families share a co mmo n sleepIng area o r h ~ve In ol~ ldual cubicles that do not ha~e fl oor to c e l 1in9 d i viders and a doo r that un be 1 0c~ ld; o r ° 2) No pr lv a tt bltl'llng or t oil et facilitits a s ~rucrlbed by 14 O.C. H. R. sec 401. 2 \967) or arra ngement s wh e re mo rt t nan 6 I ndividuals sha re a bathtub shower, or to ile t as prescribed by \4 O.C. H.R SiC. 602.2 196 71. Sec. 7. Nothing In th i s Ht shal l be c o ns trued to r educe t he r i ght s reCOj"IZtd by the Dist rict of Columbia Ri ght t o Ov ernight She ter Initiative af 1984, efflcti~e May 14 1985 O.C. La w 5- 146 O.C. Code, sec. 3- 601 e t seq.l Sec. S, This act shall take effect aft e r a 3D day ~erlod of Congr e s sion al re view follow Ing ap~roval by the Mayor (o r i n th e even t of veto by the Mayo r action by the COl,lnc.il of tile Dlst r lc.t of Col l,l mbh to o~errlde the VitO as provided In se c t ion 602{c)O) of t he Oistr l ct of Columb ia Self·~o~e rnment and ~overnment.l Reorganization Act, a~proved Dec em be r 24, 1973 8 7 Stat. 813; D.C. Code sec. 1-2]3 c I a nd publication In either t h e District of CclueDI Reg i ster, the Dist r ic t of ColumDl a dC 1~ J 4 5ect.i.on 3~206.J S r..s 2- 101 2-324, 9-601 3-206. Su t!J te t La rge t9\.d at jo/'ls. Distritt of Co u~D i 1 1 tv- l \Qti I ma !lor gt IIun l t t;u 1 Cou nt!1 of e Dl strit t Of Co l umbia APP~OV ED; January 6, J COl"NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLlJ")tBfA COIUlc:il Period ~tll IIECORO OF OFFrCIAL COUNCIL VOTE 'oc ° 3~7 40~1 K~ I CTICN 1 OAfE AOoOO Od Ci O'OO l"O·gC C'C-C lt;I 'IOICE VOTE v 0 c re QtI Ro lark. fIOLl C\.l1 lore esULr 6.t. ZI ACTION &amp;amp; D"'T lt 1'Ji o."qIL l jl o'l'L ZI V~E VOT V q Wilson ar4 S~ith on Con 1 C C aCTION &amp;amp; eATI C "OK von o&amp;lt; or on </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-731"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-732"/>
  </section>
</document>
