<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-203">
  <num type="law">7-203</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-203.pdf">D.C. Law 7-203</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 450</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-203 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-44, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 29, 1988 and December 13, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 6, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 7-274 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>~.c 10/ 7-203 PurSud~t to Sectio 12 of t~e District of ~o umb i a Sel Go~ernme~t and Go~ernmenta l ReorQa~iz!tion ~ct, P. L. 93-198 the Act t he Counci l of the Dis trict of Columbia adopted 3i NO.7-44 on first and second reddinQs No~ember 29, 1988, dOC December 13, 1988, respecthely. Follo ing the Si gnature of he ~ayor on January 6, 1989, this legislation as assigned ~ct No. 7-274 pub li shed in the January 20, 1989, edition of the D.C. Reg i ster Vol. 36 plQe 450) and trl~s~'tted to Congress on Ja~uary 23, 1989 for a 30-d~y re~ie in accordance fth Section 602(c 1) of the ~ct. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby 9i~es notice that the 30-day Con9ressionAl Rev;e Period has e~p'red, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Maro;h 15, 1989. Dates Count During the 3a-day Congressional Revle~ Period: January 24,25,26,27,30,31 February 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,21,22,23,24,27,28 March 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15 O.C tAW 7- 2 03 MARl6 19i9 AN '\'CT D.C. ACT 7 ·2701 iN TH E COU C[ l OF iHE DiST RiCT OF COl UMSIA. JAit iji amend tne Dis tr ic t f C~iu m~ j G~ vern me nt p re h e nsiv i Mer i t P ,r s~n ne l ,\,ct of 1915 t o revi s e the res i dln cy r eQ uirem,nt previsions t o create a sy stem to give Di str ic t r i dentS a pref,r.nce f r Di str i ct g o ver"~e t e ~ployment I n the Career and Educat i on a l Se r vic es BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUN Ci l OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU MB iA Th at tn l s I ct may be c i t.d as the "Res l d' ncy Pr.f. renc. A~e ndme nt Act of 1988 Sec 2. The District of Colum bia Government Comprehensive Kertt Personnel Act of 1918. effect ive H,r ch 3 [91 9 (D.C. L,w 2-139; D.C. COde sec 1-6 01. I et seg is amended as f o l lo s a Section SOl O.C. COd e, sec 1-6 0S. I {e I s ~mended t o read as f ol lows 1) Notwlthitlndln9 any provi sion of the Human Ri ghts Ac t of 1911 efh t the D.cember 13, 1911 D. C. Law 2- 38; D.C. Cod t, Ut 1-2501 tt uq .J. an appl1tlnt fo r Di stri c t goy ern m,nt ploy. ent I n tnt Career Ser vic e whO I s a bon. f id e r,sldent of the Distr Ic t at the t Ime of appl ica tion s~'11 be given a hiring pre'erence ov er a n~n resld ent llc.nt. Thts preference sha ll e In addition to not Inltlld of, qualif i cation, utlbllsll,d for the posIt 2) An Ippllclnt clal~lng a hiring prefer.nc. shill submit proof of bon. fld. residency I n m.nner determ ined by the Mayor pursuant to par.graph 5) of this subsection If hlrld, th ployet 511 agrll In writIng t o lu ln tlln bani fld' DIstrict res idency for a perIod 0' 5 cons.cutlve yl.r$ fro. thl eff.ctivi d,t, of hlr Failure to Iintaln Dona f i de District r.sldency for the conSlcutlve 5 ye.r period sh,ll r.sult In forfeltur. of l~p l01~ent 3) Any dhldual hired under I previous res i dency la h o subject to a residency requlre nt sh a ll ~e treat.d .s If th' I ndlvldu. 1 claimed I preference 1 a~d "IS nlred p ur su~~t to t he Re s 'd cy @f!~en,e ~m e~d~ent AC t of lSS8 { 4 Cyct l cns l f o rce, 4 ~esident Dt n rl,t .mp l oy ee s ha ll Da praferr ed fo r r.tant i on ~nd re l n, Ute me nt of am plo yment ov. r a non_reS id ent DISt r Ic t e~ployee fo r pureos es of th i S para9raph onl y a non-resioent Di st r i ct e.,o loye e nir ed pr IO r t o Jinuary 1. 1980 snaI l be con,iOlred a ~Ist ri t t res t d,nt hen tne pr pvls ion s of t l115 par·.9r a o~ conflic t Hh an effHt l ve ,o l l ec t lv. ba~g i n i ng agrt,m,nt, t ~e t,rms of the cO "lc t l ve b'r lnt n g Ig r eement sh al l ;overn 5 A Oln r lc t employ" h l r ,d i n t he Career ServIce orlor to th a .ffec! lve dlt. of th e Res i d.ncy ~refertnce Am l nd nt Act of 1988 who elects to IPoly for a com oetit i ve pr omO tion In th e Care.r Service and t o c l a im a preference, si 11 tI bo und oy tn pro vis io ns of plr a9 r aph 2 of th is s ub section 6 The Mayor Shall pursuan t to t i t l e 1 of the Dis tr ic t of Col umbi a Admlnlst r. t \ ve r ocl d u r e Act app royed Oc totler 21 1968 (82 Stat 120 3; D.C. COde, sec 1- 1501 ~t ill APA "j, is sue pr oposed ru l u t o Imp l emen t th e pr e f erenc e sys t 'm es t ablished by thiS subsect i on Th. pr oposed r u les sh 11 be subm i tte d t o t ~e Co un ctl no h t er th,n Febru a ry 1, 1989, f or. 45- day per iod of 1'1'1 1 c l udln 9 Sa tu r days Sund .ys, I t ga l hol days nd cI ys of Cou nci l reC 55. If th t Co unc i l do.s not ap prow e or d1upprove tn e propo sed r ules, in .ho h or In par t by res o l uti on wIthi n thls S- day r vl pe ri od, th e propos ed ru I n $h a ll be deemt d ap proy ed ti l Sec t ion 80I A(d D.C. Cod e sec 1.509 1( d I s am, nd, d t o rel:d as f o l l o.s d l o t tthstandlng .ny pr ovISio n of t il, HUlllan RIg hts Ac t of 1977 ffec tht D. cembtr 13 19 77 (O.C. L 2- 38 C.C. Cod e, SfC 1-2501 .t seg n .pp llcant fo r Ci strlct gov.rn.,nt p l oy ment I n t ht Educ at l on. 1 S'l'v lC t no IS tlone r.sidtnt of the DiS tr Ic t at t he tl of a pp l i cat Ion 11 be giwtn hl rl n9 pre f e r t nce OVII' a non r es l dlnt leant Thi s pr,fer, nc e Sha ll b, I n add i tio n to not instl.d of, qu ll f lcati ons ,stab ll s hed fo r t nl posltt 2) An appllc.nt cl. l mln9 a hirln9 pr,ftr.nc, sh a ll submit proof of bonl fld, rl, i dlncy in a IIIlnnll' dlt'l'lIIl ned by till Boards pursuant to pH' graph 5 of this subs t c t lo n. I f hll'.d, the Imp l oy,e sh.l l agr.e i n .rlt l n9 to ma ;nt l n bona ftde Di str i ct res i de ncy for I ptl'lod of 5 cons ecu t l v, years fr o. the IfflctiY. date of hll'l Failure to ma i nta in tlo n, fide District I'.sldtncy fo r the conse cutlvl 5 yea r period s h.ll result I n for f e i t ur e of employment 3) Any I nd i Yi d.u.l hi red under. previOuS r eside ncy l ho .as s ubj ect to a res i dency requlrlmlnt 0 1-609. 1 s~dl l ~e tr~at.d as i f t~e l~di~ i dY.l c l i med 4 preference n d a s ni red ~yrsuan t to t he &amp;lt H i de n,y referen,e ~mend",e n t c t oJr 1988 4 1 In reduct io ns _in _f orc e re~ id ent ilh t nc t e~ploye. sn a il e prefer red for retent ion and r e i nst4t.~e nt o f emp ioym ent over a non-re si dent Di strict emoloyee or pyrposes of t~ l s p ar49rap~ on l y. 4 no n_res i d.nt Ols tr i ct emp oy. e hi red or i or t o J anyary 1. 1980. snai l tte cons i aer.d a Ois tr i ct r'1tdent. When the provisions of thts p.r 49rap n conf l ict i t h n ef fective collective b!r~atntn9 agr eement t~e terms of tne col l ect i ve bar9ai ntn9 agreement sn. 11 goye rn 5 A District employee htre in the Ed uca t ion a l Se rv ic e pr i or t o tne effective date of the Residency ?r eferenc me namen t Act of 1988 w"o ell cts to aop l y for a eo~o et i t l ye pro~o t i on i n tn e E4 uc .t lon a l Service .nd t o c laim a pr!!ferlnce n.ll 1 btlynd by the provis io n, of par' grapn Z of this sybsecti on 6 Th e 80ards sh.l 1, purlyant to tlt l 1 of the Distr ic t af Co lumbl dmln l' trat i YI PrOCedure ~ct, loorovid October 21 1968 (82 St.t. 1203; O.C. COd e. sec. 1-1501 !l S P iSSYI proposed rylu to impl ement thl a reference 5yste_ establis hed by this subsection. T" e pr oposed r u l es SMall be sybmltted to tMe COyne ll no hter th.n February 1. 1989. for I 'S-day periOd of review, elcluding S.tyrd lYS, SYndlYS, l eg. l holldlYS. and days of Coufle tl r ec ess If the Council does not aoprove or dls,pprove tMe proposed ru l es, I n who l e or In pert, tty res ol ution wi thin tnls 'S-d.y revllW p.rlod. the proposed r u l es Sh a l l be deemld approvld e) Section 906 (D. C. Cad" sec 1-610 6) Is a_ended t o re.d IS follows I) Notwithstanding ,ny provlson of the Hum.n Rights Act of 1971 D. C. l 2-38; D.C. Code. sec 1-2501 It 9 uy person _110 .ppllu for. pos ition In the ueepted Slryice and WftO accepts appointment or Is hlrld to fill a pOSition In til, helpt,d Servlc.e sh.ll become I bona fld. reSid ent af t Dlttrlct wtthin 180 d.ys of the efflctlvi dati of the tnt nt nd sh.l l m.lntaln thts esidence for the duratto of the e ployment. F.Ilure to becolne Di str Ict resld.nt or to Int.'n District res i denCy, sh.ll result In forfetture of the posltton to wh ic h the person h beln appointed b p.rson hlrld In thl E_cepted Service prior to the eff.ctlve d.te of the Re,ldency Preference ndNent ~ct of 1988 wl'lO w" reqytred to be 01' beco District resident wltntn 180 dlYS of .ppolntment .nd maintain th.t resid ency or forfeit .lIploy~ent. shl11 continue to tte bOynd IIy tne reslden.cy requirement Ifttr tn. effective date of the Residency Preference Amendll.nt ~ct of 1988 1 5oction 1-610. 6 (1) Section l OOl (e O. C Code, sec. 1-5U.l(e i s a~e e d read as fol l ows e e provi si ons of section 906 (D.C oae, se c 1- 6 0 .6 snail a o l y to employment in ue Eacutive Serv i ce e A new section til l B added to read as fol l ows Sec 1 17. B@g i nning in fIscal year 1992 and i n the i ub s eQu ent fiscal years, eacn employee of tne District "ho is a Dona f de reS i d!nt of the Ohtrlct s hall receive a hous i ng ~onus f r om the District government not to e~ceed 5~ of tne e~p l aye@ s annua l base salary f) Section 32 03( a)(9 D.C Code, sec. 1-633.3(1)(1 is amended by s tr i king tne phrase 'Section I and" and i ns erti n; the word Sect i on in its place Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 3D-day per i od of Congressional review follo 1ng approval by tne ~ayor (or i n th! event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Counci l to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c I) of the Oistrict of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 and pUblIcatIon i n eit~er the District of Columbia Register, tne District of Columbia Statutes-at-large, or the Distrtct of Columbia Municipal Regulations I I jllrYd /1 0 1 "L Chair an Council of the District of Columbia strict Columbi. APPROVED: January 6, 1989 ew c 1 6lJ SeC r 633 CO L ClL or THE DISTRICT U F C OLL~I B IA Cnuoo~ Pen oQ ~v.o ECOIIO OF OFFIC IAL COU NCIL VOTE oc 0 I lt c c~ I r d,O'2ta; Fi r Re ac i ng 1 29 sa lC .a en: ° oo~r: e App r oved tC s ih:l~e and 7hc:Ilas VOto no jil _C TION UE X C,ef ~on Q.o eQ ,0 n u Adoptea Final Reeding. 12-1 3- 99 Apcrov.d, M s Rolark int.r ana Thomas voted :10 Oto OA fI VOle! VOTil 0 Of&amp;gt </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
