<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-209">
  <num type="law">7-209</num>
  <heading type="short">Division of Park Services Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-209.pdf">D.C. Law 7-209</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 476</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-209, the “Division of Park Services Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-300, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 29, 1988 and December 13, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 6, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 7-280 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NCIL OF THE O!STIH CT OF CO LU MB!A NOT! CE D.C. LAII 7- 209 "D iv i s i on of Park Services Act of 198 8 Pursuant to Sec ti on 412 of the District of Co l u~bla Se l f Govern~ent and Governmental Reorgan ization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Ac t the Council of the District of Colu mb ia adopted Bi l l No. 7-300 on f i rst nd s econd r e",d i ngs Non.ber 29 1988, and Decellber 13 a88, respectively. Foll o'lt i n9 t he signuu r e of the Ma yor on January 6 1989, this l egislat ion as as si gne d Act No 7-280 published in tne January 20, 1989, edit i on of tile D. C. Reg i ster Vol. 36 page 476) and transmitted t o Congress en J anuary 23, 1989 for a 3D-day review, In accordance with Section 602( c I J of tile Act. The Council of tile Distr i ct of C o l u~bia lIe reby g i ves notice that the 3D-day Congressional Rev i ew Period h",s exp i red nd therefore, Cites this enactm ent as D.C. Law 7- 209 effective March 16, 1989. DAVID A. CLARKE Ch airman to the Council Dates Count ed Ourlng the 3D-day CongreSSional Rev iew Period: January 24,25 26,27,30,31 February 1,2,3,6,1,8,9, 21,Z2 ,23,24 ,21,28 M",rch 1, 2,3,6 ,1,8,9,1 0,13 ,14,15 D.UAW7-209 MAR 1 &amp;amp;-f988 ~olled Original CODIFICATION 01s:ric t of Colu:nb ia Code (1989 Sl!?p AN ACT D.C. ACT 7·280 IN THE (aU/leIL OF THE OISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JAN 6 laBi To tran sfer j urisdiction over certai n a'str'ct of Co lumbia Park s from t h e De pa r t me n t of Pub lic Works t o the De part_e nt o f Rec r eation. BE IT ENA CTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU MBIA That tni s act may be cited as the "Division of Pa rk Services Act of 198 8 Se c. 2 a Pursuant t o secti on 1-144 (b) of t h e Dist rIc t of Co lumb i a Sel f Government and Governmenta l Reo r gan ization Act. ap prov ed De cem ber 2 4, 1973 (81 5tH. 787 D. C. Co de, see. \ 227 b effect I v Ju l y 1, 1989, j urisdict io n over all public space park areas, ma I ntained by the Department of Public o rks before Jul y 1. 19 89 shall be transferred t o and be come the responsibility of the Depart ll1ent of Recreat io n For purpGses of th is act, the phras e ~all public spac e pa rk ar eas parkS In c l udes a ll parc e ls, lots. squa r es of la nd. gr ee n spaces, and aon u ent s loc ated within and owne d or ma i nt ained by the Dis tr i c t of Columbia gowe r nment and not owned ar m~lntained by the federal governm ent b) Th e Department of Public W or s Divis ion of Roadside and P a r~s Maintenance, shall ret a in ju r isdictio n over and responsibility for maintenance l a ndscaping, bea utifying promo ting, and r egulati on of road sides, Int erstate ga teways, and cl overleafs c The Facil i ty Ma i ntenan ce Adlllinistration with i n the Department 0' Recreat io n shall have ju risdi ction ov er, and be respon Si ble for the maint enan ce landscaping, beautifying promotion, and re gulation of the park s t rans ferr ed pursuant t o this act d Funds and e. is tlng contin ui ng full time employee s and pos i tions author iz ed fo r t he Department of Publ ic Works, Di vision 0' Roadside and ParkS Ma ln tendnce Respon s lb 1li ty Cen ter 4044 w1t hin the PUbl i c Spa c e Ad min istratio Co ntro l Center 40) In the Fi scal YeH 19 89 Budget for the District 1 Ne Sec tion 8 Si fbrolled Or lginat of Col umbi a and a l located for the Ba l nte na nce land scap i ng, beautify i ng promotio n, and regu l atio n of parks tr~n sf er red pursuant to this act, shall be tr nsferred to the Departl:lent of Rec reati on Facility Mai nte nan&amp;lt e ,\dmlnlstratlon IResp ons lb i llty Ce nt e r 2700) wit hin Recreati on Operat ions Cont r ol ent er 20 e The Fa c il i t y Mainten a nc e Adl:li nls trat l on IReS POnSibi li t y ente r 27 00) within Recreat Ion Operat ions (o ntrol Center 20) is ren amed the Pa rk s and Fa c ility Ma intenan ce Admin istrat io n 1 The Oepartlllent of Recru.tl on i5 renamed t he Department of Re c reation and Parks. Sec. 3. This ac t shall t ak e effect aft e r a JO d~y period of Congressional rev i ew foll owi ng a pp r oval by the Hay or (or i n the eve nt of vet o by the Mayor, action by the Co unci l of th e Dis tr ic t of Columb i a t o override the vet o) a s pr ov id ed In sec tI on 602(c)(I) of t he Distr ict of Co lumb I a Self Go ve r nment and Go ver~~ental Recr g ani~at lon Act, approv ed December 24, 19 73 (87 St4t 813; D.C. Cod e, se c. 1· 233(c I and publ ication in either th e District of Co lu mbl d Register the Distr i c t of Coluab i a Statute s at Large or the Dis tr ict of Colu mbia Muni ci pa l ReguJa ti o"5. r ay o r Di strict APPROV ED: n L 6 gt; r Cn::a:t'l"ru n v p Ccull c il of the District of Colul!\bia f Co lu bia JanuHY 6, 1989 2 lC ACTION I CUE COU CIL OF THf: DISTR ICT OF COLU:'IIBIA Council P.riod Solve RECORD OF OFFICIAL COU NCIL VOTE gt;OCKU too· Adop t_ed First Reading, 11-29-8 8 B7-300 /I: VOteE VOTE Aoprove"o W&amp;lt;e'OOQ Ie 0 u 1 Crawford Rolark 4nd Smi th r ROLL CAU. VOTE RESULT I ClIOt&amp;lt OUE lt VOICE VOTE R.~orQO&amp;lt;l 'Ct. On r~Qu. 11 A C I'OLL CALL von lte CcnMtII CoI Adopted FiMl Reading. 12 13- 88 Approved Wi lson and Smith Oot. r ACTIOt&amp;lt amp; OHE r VOIC£ von 11 II </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-166"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-166.01"/>
  </section>
</document>
