<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-218">
  <num type="law">7-218</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Long-Term Care Ombudsman Program Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-218.pdf">D.C. Law 7-218</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 534</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-218, the “District of Columbia Long-Term Care Ombudsman Program Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-334, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 29, 1988 and December 13, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 6, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 7-293 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA !j OT :C£ D.C. LAiJ 7-218 ·O.C. Lon g- T er~ Ca re Ombijds~~n Progr Act of 1988 Pursuant to Section 412 of the Dist r ic t of Columbia Self- Gov er n~en t and Govern~ent al Reorg ani zat ion Act, P. L. 93-198 tlte Act t he Council of tlte Dhtrict of Columbh ldoptea B111 No. 1 334 on f i rst ona secona relaings, November 29, 1988, and O e c e~ber 13, 1988, respectively. Following tne si gnature of the Mayor on Ja nuary 6 1989, thi s leglslotlon was assi gned Act No. 1 293, publil~ed In the Janua ry 20 1989, edition of tlte D. C. Registe r Vol. 36 plge 534) ond tran s~ ltted to Congress on J anuary 23 1989 f or a 30-day rev i ew, in .ccordanee witll Section 602 (e 1) of tlte Act. TIte CounCi l of the Dist rict of Columbia hereby give s noti ce tllat the 30 -day Con gressi onal Review Period lias e~plred. and therefore, cites this enactment as D. C. Law 7-2 18 effect i ve March 16 1989 OAVID A. CLARKE Cha i rman t o the Council Oates Counted Ouring the 3D-day Co ngressional Revle~ Period: January 24.25 26 27,JO 31 February 1, 2,3 6,7,8,9,21,22,23.24 27,28 Harch 1.2 ,3, 6,7 8,9,10,13,14,15 D.C. LAW 7 2 18 n MAR 1 6 1988 AN ACT DU CT 7 2 9 3 ~rQlled Original Ca:lification Chapter 33 0: ti~le 6 District of CQ1~hia ,nde (19R9 SUpp IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA IAN 0 6 1989 To estab l ish a Long~Term Care Ombudsman Program ithin the Office on Aging, for the District of Columbia BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Long~Ter m Care Ombudsman Program Act of 1988 TI TLE I DEFINITIONS lew, Sul:x:hapte Sec 101. Definitions tion For the purposes of this act, the term: 6-~lOl (a AdmInistrator eans the person who is responsible for the day-to-day operation and manage ment of a lon g-te rm care faci l ity including. in the case of a community residence facility, the residence director b Court" means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia c Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs" means the District of Columbia Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs established pursuant to Reorganization Plan No.1 of 1983, effective Ma r ch 31, 1983 (D.C. Code, Vol. I d D epartment of Human Services" means the District of Columbia Department of Hu man Services established pursuant to Reorganization Plan No.2 of 1979, effective February 21,1980 (D.C. Code, Vo l I and Reorganization Pl an NO.3 of 1986, effective March 31, 1983 (D.C. Code, Vol. I e Desi9nee" means a person who 1) Has received a minimum of 15 hours of certified training in accordance with section 204(a)(15 2) Is an employee of the program established pursuant to section 201 or has written authorization to act on behalf of the ombudsman pursuant to section Z04(a)(3 £aroll ed Original f Di rect or Means t he E~ecutjye Dfrector of the District of Columbia Off ic e on All og e5t~ bli shed by sect ion 302 of the District of Colur.1bla ct on th e Aging effect;~e Oc t ob er 29. 1975 (D .C. law 1· 24 D.C. Code, sec. 6- 2212 9 Long-term care facility· means 1) A ·comlJlunity res i dence facility· as defined I n section 2( a 4) of t he Healt h- Car e and Community Restdence Fac ility Ho~pl c e and Home Care licensu re Act of 198 3 effectIve FebrUHY 24, 1984 (O.c. Law 5_4 8 D. C. Cod e, s e c. 32 1301 a 4 or (2) A "n urs i ng IIome as deflrled in secti on 2(a)(3) of the Heal t h-Care an d Commun ity Residence Facility, Hospice an d HOllie Care Li ce nsure Ac t o f 1983 effective fe bruary 24 198 4 D.C Law 5-48; D.C. Code sec. 32 -1301(a)(3 n Ombudsma n~ mean s t~e Dist rict of Co lu~bj Long Term C~re Omb~dsman establi shed by se c ti on 202 (a and deSi gnat ed under sec ti on 307 a) {12) of t~e Olde r Americdns Act of 1965, approved OctOber IB 19 78 (92 Stat. 1525; 42 U.S.C. 3027(a 12 to pe r form t he mand ate d functions of the lo ng- Ter Ca rl! Otlbudsman Pr09raQ \ Office on Agi ng" mun s th e District of Columbi&amp;lt;l. Office on Aging es ta bliShed by se c ti on 301 of t he Di strict of Co lulllbia Act on th e Aging, effe c t i ve October 29 19 75 (D.C. La w 1- 24; D.C. Code sec. 6-2211 j Pers on" mea ns an Indivldu.I an 'gent, a corpo rat io n, a par t ners lp, or any other org an i zat io nal entity k P r ogram" mean s the Dis tri c t of Columbia lo ng Term Care Ombudsma n Pr ogram es tab lished by s ect i on 201 1 Re co rd" means 1) Med i c.l social persona l or finan cia l I nf or mati on ~a intalne d by a he a lth ca r e f.cllity co ver ed by the Health-Care and Comlllunity Residence Fac l lty. Hospice and Home Car e Licensure Act of 1983 effe c tiv e February 24, 1984 (D .C. Law 5-'B; D. C. Code sec. 32 -1 301 et seq or by a Distri ct of Columbia Dist r ict gov ern men t ageocy t~at h~s respoosl bili ty f or the care and mainten a nce of a re~jd e" t I n a lo n t. r~ care facility; and (2 n ad ~l nlstratlve record, cos t or Inciden t r e port, or a repo r t of a civil in fra cti on Inspection Gr defici en cy maIntained by a long -t e rm care facn lty or a Dis t rict government agency Resident" me ~ns a resident of a lo ng-term care facllitl n "Representative of a resident" means 1) A per s on who Is kn owledge able about the ci r cumstances of a resident and has been des ig nated by that resident to represent him or he r or larol lDd Original (2) A person, other than a f;j.ct1it who has been appointed by a court to ad~injster the fln~nc1al or personal affai r s of a resident or to protect and ~d~ocate for the ri gh ts of a resident; or 'f (3) The ombudsman or hiS or r designee, no person has been designated or apPOinted 1n accordan ce wit h paragraph (1) or (t) of this subsection. TITlE II THE ESTABLISHMENT OF A LONG·TERH PROGR AM. CARE OMBUDSMAN Sec. 201 Th ere is established a long Ter m Ca re Ombuds~an Prog ram for the Dis tri ct of Colum bia wit hin the Off i ce on Aging. The prog r am shall p r o~td e a comprehen si ve continuum of advocacy servi ces for older persons and oth er persons who are residents in the Dis trict, Which sha ll include 1) Advocating for th e rights of older perSons and other persons who are residents 2) Investigating and resolving any complaint made by or on behalf of an olde r person or other person who i s a re sident; and (3) Monitoring the quality of ca re, services pr ovi ded, and quality of life e~perl~nced by o lde r person s and residents to ensure that the care and services are in acco rd ance with appl ic ab l e Dist r ict and fed era l l aws. Sec. 202. long ·Te rm Care Ombudsman; appointment; vacancy a) Th@ program shall be administered by a full t i me ombud sma n and shall be under the Director of the Office on Aging Director or hi s or ner designee. The Direct or s hall a ppoint the ombudsman for a term of 2 years and approve af the designee of the ombud sm an. The ombudsman Shall be I reSident of the District b) Th e Director ml y contract wi t h a nonprofit pr ovid er other than the Di st r ict go vernment to ope rate the pr og r am The provider shall h,ve e~perlence advocating fOr the ri ghts of older persons and residents. The ombudsman sha l l be an e~ployee of the nonpr of it prov ider c) The Director shall ensur e that the fol lowi ng are provided to t he ol:'1budsman or his or he r design ee to impl ement the prov i s io ns of this .ct 1) Lega l counsel for adylce and consultation 2) Legal representation, 1f legal action Is taken to Implement the pro~i s ion s of this act; and (3) Clerical and administrative support s taff and ma ter ials Sectior. 31- 1112 £crolled Original (d The primary responsibility of tne om budsmilll or his or lIer designee shall be the invest iga tion and re solution of any complaint made by or on be llalf of a residellt. Sec. 203. experience. Long Term Care Ombudsman; training and (a) The ombudsman shall have training and ex perien ~e i ll the f o l lo w111 g are&amp;lt;1S 1) Gerontology, 10llg te rm care, health c~re, or relevant social services programs 2) The lega l system 3) Dispute res olution tec hni ques, l nd udl ng in vest igat ion mediati on or negotiation and 4 tong-term care adv oc acy b) No person who has been emp loyed by a l ong-term o. re fadlity or a corporation t~ut directly or indirectly owne d or operated a 10llg-term care fa cility within the past 2 years shall be an ombudsman cl Ne i ther the omb u ds~an no r any me~ber of his or her Immedia te family shall have any pecunIary tnterest i ll a long -ter~ care facillty. Sec. 204. Powers and Du t ies of the Long-Term Care Dm buds~an a Tile ombuds man sh al l 1) Investigate and resolH cemplatnts and concerns made by or on behalf of older persons and othe r residents tn t ile District 2) Premote the well-being and qualIty ef ltfe of each resident 3) Encourage the development and t he expansion Of the act i vities of tn e program in all wards of the Dtstrict suf fici ellt to serve tile residents in those wards 4) Submit annually, to the Off t ee on Aging f or submission to t he Counctl and the Mayor, a wr i tten repert docume lltlng the complillnts r eceived and resolved and recommendtng policy, regulatory, or legislatlye cllanges 5) Enter in to, on behalf of the Office on Aging and with tile approval of t ne Director, wrttten agreements of understanding. cooperation. and collabo rattoll with any District governaent agency that provid es funding oyer slght or inspection of, or ope rate s a lo ng tel ca r e facility 6) Establi sh and i mplemen t program poltci e s and procedures for eltc l ting rece i vi ng, illvestigat l ng, verifying, referring, and re solving complaInts of residents 7) Develop an on going prog r am for publIcizing the program 8) Identify document, and address solutions to prob l e~s affecting res id ent s Section 6- 13.V 9) Serve as the l egal representative f or re side nt s pursuant to sections 302(e 303(al{1 a~d 307{ a) and (b) of the Nursing o me and Communlty Reslden ce Facility Residents' Protections Act of 1985, effecti ve April 18, 1986 C. La 6~108; D. C. Code, sees. 3l.1432 e 3Z.1433 (a}{ l and 32·1437 {a and (b ID Report any instance of suspected abuse neg lect, or e~ p l o itati on of a re sident t o t he Office of Adult Pro t ec t ive Servi ces wi t hi n t he D e p art~ent of Human Services, and t he Serv ice Fac il 1ty Re gu lati on Ad mi nistration wi th i n the Departme nt of Co~su ~e r and Re gula tory Aff.Jlrs wit h i n 24 hO\l r s of recelpt of a compl a in t or in fo rma tion conce r ni ng susp e cted abuse, negl ect or e~ploitat ion ll Establi sh a system for coordinating a un ifo r District -wide systeln t o record data on compla in t s and co nditions In long-term car e facilities l l) Monitor the development and implementation of Distr i c t and federal law s rules regulations, and poli c ies that affect residents 13 Make specif i c recom mendat i ons, through tne Offic e on ~ging, to the operator or agent of the operator o f a ny lon9 tenn care fa cili ty wh ene ver the om bu dsman believes that co ndit ion s hl ch adve r s e l y affect the hea l th, safety, we l far e or right s of a r esi dent exi s t wi thin t he l on9-t erm care fac ll lty 14 Report t o the appro pr i ate enf o rcemen t agen cy any ac t of an operator of a lon9 ~ter m ca re faci lity that t he ombuds an be l iev e s to be a vio lat io n of an app l icab le fede r al or Dist r i ct hw, regu latio n, or r ul e IS) Establish and condu ct d training program f or per so ns employed by or associated with the program, wh ich sha ll include, traininQ in the follo wing areas A) The review of ~edl~al records 6) Regulatory requ i rements for long_t erm car e facilities C D E Confidentia l ity of records F) The special nee ds of the elderly 16 Ass i st I n t he for mat ion devel opme nt, and us e by re siden ts, the i r familie s and friendS of f orums that permit reSidents, their fallille s and friends t o discuss and cOllllunicate on a r eg ular and co nt i nuing basis their views on the s trengths and weakne sses of the op eration of the factltty, the quality of ca r e pr ovided, and the quality of life fo s tered in long -term care facilities: Techniques of comp laint invest igati on Th e effect s of Instit utiona l izati on: and (17) EstabliS h and maintain procedures to prote c t th e co nfidentiality of the rec ords of residents and 5 l ong·term care faci li t i es where access is ~ut h orized pur s ua nt t o sect ion )Ol 18) Prohibi t any em ploye e, desIgnee o r represe ntat i ve of the program from I nvest l ~atln g any c ompla i nt o r represent f ng ttle ombuds man IHIIeSS that pers o n has rec eived training In acco rdance with paragraph i5) of t h is subsecti on; and 19 Desi gn.te local ombudsman progra ms t o act on behalf of the ombudsman wIt hin speclf1c geographical area s b No pe rso n agen cy, or l o~g terlll care fac l 11ty Shall obstr uct the OMbuds man or his or her des i gnee fr o~ the la wful performance of any duty or the exercise of any power. Sec 20 5 Compla i nt i nv e stigation a Th e ombudsman and hi s or her deSignee shall htve access to a ny record that Is ne cessary t o c a r ry out his or her respon Sibil i t i es under thi s act bJ The ombudsman or his or her designee may Initiate an i nvest igati on of lonll-term c~re f ct1lty independent of t he receipt of a specific c a~pla l nt. Sec 206. Confidentia l ity of r ecords and Identities of r es idents. ta) The program s hall pr otec t th e confiQenttal1ty of the re co rds of the re si dents anQ employees. fb No inf ormat ion or records mal n taineQ by the program shall be disclosed to the public c The pr og ra fll shIl l not disclose t he Identity of ony compla i na nt, resident Involved In a coaplalnt, witness, or r ep re sen tat i ve of re s ident, unles1 the complainant, resident, or representative of a resident authorizes the disclosure. Sec 20 7 1!I(!Iunlty from liability a No eMployee, designee, or representative of the program shall be held liable for the good faith perf o rma nce of re s ponsibilities under t his I ct, e~cept that no Immunity 1hal1 eltend t o crim i na l acts b) No dhcriminatory, disciplinary, or reUlhtory action sh~ll be t~ken aga inst an e~ployee of a long-term care facility or age ncy resident or representative of ttle prog ram, f or any coml!lunic~tjon made t o a id ttle pr09r~m in c arry in g out its duties anc! responsibilities, unless the com~unication wa s made aalicious ly or in bad fa i th Thi s s ubsection sh all not be cons trued to infringe upon ttle r ig hts of an employer to supe rvise, discipline, or termlnote an e~ploye e for o ttler rea sons. tc o communication made by the ombuds~an or his or her designee, i f reasonably related to the reQuirements of 6 l'ew s.=ctix 6-3315 New, Section 6- 3117 Zn~Oll'd Or1g1nal his or her re spo ns i bilitie s shall be subje~t t o ~jy il a~ti o n f or l1be l or slander d) A co urt may order th e disclosure of ln f ormatlon made con f iden t i al under thi s act, if it deter~ ine s th a t tne disclos ure is necessary to enfo rc e th is act. TITLE III ACCESS TO lONG·TERM CARE FACILITI ES AND TO RE CO RDS. Sec. 30 1. A~cess t o l ong Term CHe Facilities a The op erator o f a l ong.ter care facility sh all permit the ombuds man or his or her des i gnee access to t he facllay t o I Visit ta n wi th or make personal soch l or l ega l s erv i ces available to all re side nts, or l nvest lg ate complaints 2) Inform re sidents of their ri ghts or entitlemen t s and corresponding Obliga t io ns under applicable federal and District la w by mean s of dis tribution of educational materials or d isc uss i on In groups and wit h individual re side nts 3) As s is t re sid ent s in ass ert ing their legal rights re ga r ding cl a ims for pub l ic as sistance, medic a l assistance soc i a l secu r ity benef t ts or ot ll er matt e r s In wh i ch residen t s a re ag grieved a nd 4 Inspect a ll areas of t he f acility except t he l i Vln! ar ea of a re sident who protests I nspect i on b Access unde r t h is s ect ion sha l l be pe rm i tted bet ween t he hours of 8:00 a .m. and 8: 00 p da ily un l ess the n4ture of a complaint r equires I nvestigation at other times c) Upon entering a l ong term Care facility in acco r dance with this secti on, th e omb udsman or hi s or her desig nee Shall promptly adv ise 1 of th e following per sons of his or he r pre sence: III Tile ad ministrator or acting admini s trator Z Th e residen ce di rector or (3) Ano ther ava i lab le supervis o ry agent of tile facilltr d A pers on wll o has ac cess under this section sha l l not enter the living ar ea of a re Sid ent wi thout identifying him or hers elf t o the resi de nt and re ceiving the permi ss i on of the reSident t o en t er e l A resident shall have the r ig ht t o termin.te, at any time, any visit by a per son or re presentat i ve of t he program wh o has access under t hiS section f) A communicat ion between a r eside nt and a pers on wh o ha s access under this sec ti on shall be confidential, unl ess the resident authorize s th e release of the commu ni cati on. 7 I.O 6- 332 9) rI o res iden t shall be pu nish ed or lIa rrassed by t il e operator of a fac fll ty or an agen t or employee of th e operator of the fac ilIty because 0' efforts of the resident to avail himsel f or hers elf of his or her r igh t s purs uant to this act h) A written not ice, pre scr ibed by the om bu dsman that describes the rights of a resident pursuant t o t hIs act and the telephone II lI mber of the ombudsman sh a l l be post!!d in a conspicuous place at or near the entran ce to the lon g- term can facility and on eac h floo r of til e facility 1) The operator o f a lo ng-ter car e faci li ty shall p r ovide each resident a personal wr i tten copy of the notice re qu i red IInder su bsect ion (h Ea c h new resident sh all be pr ovid ed a wr itten copy of the noti c e upon ad mission j) If a res id en t cannot rea d t he notice require4 under subsection (II the contents of the notice sll all be communiC dt ed to t ll at re s ident orally dnd in wr i t ing Tile wr itten notice re qui red under subsection (II) shall be proy ld rd in tile dPproprhte language to tllo,e residrnts who do not spedk or un4erstand Eng liS h 1) A notation Uldt penonal notice u required by s ub sect ion (1 lias bern p r o~i d rd sh a ll be entered I n the cli ni cal record of each re side nt m) Nothing in thh sec ti on shall be construed to re st ri c t any rigllt or pr i Yl lege of a r esident t o rec ei~e a y l sltor wh o is not a representati ve of a c om~un lty organization legal ser~i ce s pr og ra m. or the progra m. Sec. 302. Ac cess t o recor ds 6 Section a Ea Ch Distri ct a gency sh all pr oyi4e co op er at ion. 6-1122 assistance data. and t he aC Ces S to rec ords necessary t o rnable tile ombud sman t o perfor= h is or her duties under this act and other applic able federal and Di strict law. This sec t io n Sllal1 not be cons t rued t o supercede the laws or rule s go vern ing access t o unexpug ated ar r est re co r ds ma i ntained by tile Metropo litan Pollee Department or In terfere with ongoln~ criminal inYestlgations b) Jhe o.buds mln or his or her designee ~h ~11 lI. ve t he s~ m e acc.ss t ha t is provided t o til e Mayor to review. I nspect or ph ot ocopy the reco r ds of a r es ident of f cl l lty co ~ered ~y the Health-C.re and Commun i t y Res id e nce Facility Hospice nd HO"e C~re licensure Act of 1983 effect he Feb ruary 24 1984 (D.C. L~w 5-4 8 D.C. Code, se c. 32- 1301 or the Nursfn9 Hoge and Commun ity Residence ·Facll i ty Resident' s Protect io ns Act of 1985 effective April 18 1986 (D .t. Law 6- 108; D.C. Co de, sec. 32 -1401 et seq t o c arry out tile pr oYi Sl ons of th is ~ct cl The ombud sman or h i s or her designee ~ay request a subpoena pursu ant to the i ndepend ent Personnel SysteT:ls Imp lementation Ac t of 1980 effectiYe Sep tember 26 1980 s Ctlrolled Or1g1na1 D. C. Low 3-1 09; D.C. Co de s ec. 1- 338 t o obtain a ccess to r ecords covered by this s ec tion dl An owner, employe e or agent of l ong term ca re f"e lli ty lIno lawfully dhclos u i nformation Of per:n1ts acc ess t o records pu r su ant t o tilts s ec ti on shall no t be l i able f o r c iv il pe na l t i e s or c r imi na l pr os ecut ion. TITLE IV ENFORCEMENT; PENA LTI ES JlIDIC I AL REVlE Ij s\lbc apter ,v Sec. 401. Enf o r celle nt; pen a l tieS" d a Civil fines pe n l t 1es or fe He cos t s may be im pose d ag a i nst any lo ng-t erm care fa cili ty own er leW, Sec ion 6- 33J1 ex ecut i ve officer, ad~ ini s tr a t o r. em~ l oye e. or a gen t, f o r til e vi ol a tion of any pr ovis iO n of thlS ac t or any r ul e i ssu ed pur suant t o t his act b Procedu res (o r adjudication an d enforcement and applicable civil fi ne s pen a l t ies or costs sha ll be those prescr i bed for a Class 2 c i vil infra c tion, pur s uant to t i tle s I Il l of th e Depart ment of Co ns umer an d Regul atory Aff a i r s Civil Infr acti ons Ac t of 198 5, eff ec t iv e Oc t ober 5 1985 (D.C. Law 6· 42 D.C. Code, sec 6- 210 1 et Seq c l If th e om budsm an or his or he r des i gnee knowing ly viol!t es sec t io n 206 by re l easi ng a con f i dent ial doc ument r ecord, or other inf o rmation Obtained pursuant t o secti on 302( b the ombudsman or h is or her des i gn ee may be pr os ecuted fo r a misd e~e ano r and, upon co nvi c t io n, subj ect t o a f in e of no t mo r e t han 51, 500, i mprisonmen t for not mo re t han 30 days or both. TITLE V PRIVATE RIGH TS OF ACTION. Ne&amp;lt;-J Suk:chacter v Sec 501. Inju nc t ive r eli ef A resid e nt a r epre s entat iv e of a re sid e nt, t he ombuds men or the Co rpo r~t; on Co unse l may br ing an c ti on cou rt f or a tempo rary restra i ni ng orde r, preliminary injUn c tion, or permanent injun ction t o e njoin a lon g-term care h c il i ty fr om vi olat ing a pro v ision of title l Iar 11 1 or a ny r ul e i ssued by the May or pursu an t t o th is ac t Sec. 502 Chil ac t iOn fo r da ma ges a A resident, a reprt se ntat l ve of a res Ident, or th e om buds man, on beha l f of a re si dent, may bring an ac tion In co urt t o r eco ver ~c tu al ~nd pu nit i ve da na ges f o r a n in ju ry that r es u lts f r om a v io l ~t lon of t i t l e I I o r III or any r ul e iss ued by t he May or pu r sua nt t o t h i s a c t Upon proof Of a vi ol at i on, t he re s ide nt s ha l l be awarde d 3 t ime s t he ~c t u a l danag es o r 5100 wh lc ht ver i s gr eater, and ~ay be awarded pun I tive dam ages of up to $5, 000 b The fir s t $3 000 of a damage awa r d re co vered by a re s ide nt I n an a ct io n brough t under t his s ect ion sh al l be gt;ecticn 6- 1341 ion 6-3142 Enrolled Original ter W excluded from consideration when determining the eligibility of the resident for Medicaid, the amount of assistance the resident is entitled to under Medicaid, or the assets of the ;resident that the District may subject to a lien, set-off, or other legal process for the purpose of satisfying indebtedness created by the receipt of Medicaid or other public assistance payments. Sec. 503. Court costs and attorney's fees. New, Section The court shall award costs and reasonable attorney's 6-3343 fees to a resident who prevails in an action brought under section 501 or 502. TITLE VI MISCELLANEOUS. New, Subchapter VI Sec. 601. Rules. New, Section Within 90 days of the effective date of this act, the 6-3351 Mayor shall, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1203; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq issue proposed rules to implement the provisions of this act. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved. Sec. 602. Amendments. The Nursing Home and Community Residence Facility Residents' Protections Act of 1985, effective April 18, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-108; D.C. Code, sec. 32-1401 et seq is amended as follows: Section 101(11)(B D.C. Code, sec. 32-1401(11)(B is amended by inserting the phrase "other than a facility" immediately following the phrase "Any person" and by striking the phrase "or government agency Section 302(e D.C. Code, sec. 32-1432(e is amended by striking the and inserting the following phrase and the Long-Term Care Ombudsman in its place. Section 303(a)(1 D.C. Code, sec. 32-1433(a)(1 is amended by striking the phrase "that resident or his or her representative" and inserting the phrase "that resident, his or her representative, or the Long-Term Care Ombudsman" in its place. Section 307(a) and (b D.C. Code, sec. 32-1437(a) and (b is amended by striking the phrase "the resident and the resident's representative" and inserting the phrase "the resident, the representative of a resident, and the Long-Term Care Ombudsman" in its place. 10 Section 32-1401 Section 32-1432 Section 32-1433 Section 12-1437 (Qrolled Or1g1a41 e Se c t i on 40 4 O.C. Code se c. 32·1454 Is amended by strik i ng t he wo rd "subchapter" and by Inse rtin g the wo r d "act" In its ph c e. Sec. 603. Effective date This act sha l l take effect af ter a 30- day period of Cong r essiona l review fol l owing approval by the M~yor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the Di str ict of Columbia override the veto as provided by section 602( c l of the Dis tr ict of Columbi a Se l f Go vern ment and Governmental Reorgan i zat i on Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code sec 1- 133 (c 1 f I May or District 0 C o lu ~b i a Chairnan Count i1 of APPROVED January 6, 1989 \ the Dist r ict of Columbia secticr. 32- 1' 54 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT or COU'MBfA Cotu!ciI Period StVtD RECORO OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKEr NO B~7 J]~4 x ~cnON&amp;amp; D~ TE A copted First Reading 29-88 :x VOiCe: VOTE' Approved l'leeoroe&amp;lt;:ll'Ott On 1!&amp;lt;Nl5t Rolar k ­ Iou AU VOTE FrESIJLT 1 1--1 OM It on eo..Mnt c a@2 a~R~a Ll~~Si ]1 ACTtON &amp;amp; DAn ]I VO tC E VOTE M&amp;gt;l Rec to 0&amp;lt;1 _ot liii lson aMl'i Lth c7r2. C ms i&amp;lt;f cC ACTtOH&amp;amp;OATl C VOICE VOTl l_L_J i l </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>101</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-701.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>201</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-702.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>202</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-702.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>203</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-702.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>204</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-702.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>205</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-702.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>206</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-702.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>207</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-702.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>301</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-703.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>302</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-703.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>303</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-703.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>401</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-704.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>501</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-705.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>502</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-705.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>503</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-705.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>601</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-706.01"/>
  </section>
</document>
