<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-215">
  <num type="law">7-215</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-215.pdf">D.C. Law 7-215</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 517</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>:J C. LA~ 7 5 "Day Ca re f or Chtj dre n in Foster Care Pl ace me nt A~endment Act of 1988 P rsu a ~t t o Section 412 of tne Dis tr ic t of Columbf~ Se lf Go vernment and Go~ernmen ta l Reorganiza t ion Act L. 93 198 th e Act the Co un ci l of tMe Oi strt ct of Columb ia adopted 9i l l No 7-4 59 on f i r s t and sec ond re adings 1\ove.'1be r 29, 1988 and DecellIber 13, 1988 respective ly Following the sig nature of the Mayor en Janua r y 6, 1989, this l eg isl at ion wa s a SSigned Act No. 7 gO published in the January 20 1989 edit io n of the D.C Register Vol. 36 page 517) and t ransm itted to Congr ess on Janu ary 23, 198 9 f or a 30 day rev iew, in acc orda nce wit h Sect ion 602(c 1) o f t he Act. The Council of the District o( Columbi a hereby gives notice t hat the 3D day Congressional Revie w Pe r iod ha s e~p f r ed an d th e r efore cit es th i s ena ctm ent as D.C, Law 7-215, effective I A i_I f I A'&amp;gt \ \ \ I DAVID A. C ARH ~Chairma n t o the Council March 16 1989. Oates Counted Durin g t he 3~-day Co ngr es siona l Revie w Period: Jan uary 24,25,2 6 27,30 ,3 1 Febru a r y 1, 2,3,6 7,6,9,21 ,2 2,23,24,27 ,28 March 1,2 3.6 7. 8. 9,10 13 14, 15 D.C. lAW 7 2 15 il ACT D. C. ACT 7-290 a m Di~t of biil Cc6 o p IN THE COUNCIL Of TH E OrSTRICT OF COLUMBIA JAN 0 6 JSa9 To mend t h~ Day Care Po licy Ac t o f 1979 to e x te nd tne pr oviSion of day care s e rvices t o children In foster care plactlllent. BE IT [lIAtTEi) ill' TilE COUt{Cll OF THE DISTRICT or COLUMBIA, That th is ac t ~ay be cited as t he Oay Ca re for Childr en in Foster Care Pl acement Amendne nt Act of \ 988 Se c. 2. Sectio n 4 (k) of th e Day Car e Pol lcy Act of 197 9, effe c t i ve Se p te~ bH 19, 19 79 (D C. Law 3· 16 D.C. Cod e, H e. 3- 303(11 is anended t o r e a d a s f o1101ol5 k) Ch ildren r eceiving pr otect ive ca re s ervices an d child re n In foster ca r e placemen t whe n t he f oster care provider Is working if only ont f os ter care provide r is i n tne nome, and when both fo ster care prov i der s ar e wor ki ng i f Z f oster ca re pr ovid e r s are in tn e h o~e and day ca re ser vice s are i n the b ~st i nterest Of the child In the f ollowing l1I a ~n er I) For f isca l year 1990 the Ma yo r sh a l l prov i de day car~ services for 150 ch ild r en 2) For f iScal year 1991, the ~layor shall pr ovide day care s erv ic es f or 200 child re n and (3) For f iscal year 1992 the Mayor s hal l provi de dgy care se rvices f or 300 Chi l dren. Sec. 4. This act Ihall tgke effect after a 3 d ay per iod of Cong ress iona l review f ollowing app r oval by the ~a yor (o r i n t he even t of veto hy the Hayor. act i on by t he Council of t he Distric t of Columbia t o overr ide the vet o) as provide d in sectio n 602(c I of t he Dis tr ic t of Columbia S e lf- Gov ern~e nt and Go_ernnen tal Reorgan izati on Act ap prove d Decembe r 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813 D.C Code sec. 1- 233(c)(I and public~tlon in either thO! Dist r ic t of Columbia Rtgiste r t he DISt ri ct of Colu~ bia 1 Statu t es 4 at rge, Regulations. 4oyor Ois trict of Columbia aIrman L&amp;gt; v Councll of til Dis t rict of Columbt40 APPROVED: Janua ry 6, 1989 2 COU CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLDta l C cil Period ~HD rlEC P.O O::F OFF 1 Cl~L CCtlNCll 'lOT" JQ lt; o- Accoted ?i= s Read:'l!-g 2,-aS iii VO ICE 'IOTE AP,?E,ved At Of&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;d te On LJt'1 2 ~C~ION &amp;amp; CAT Ro lar~k 11; lIe on C&amp;lt;&amp;gt;n c al Jt CT ION !DA.T i\qopt ec Fina l Reading 12-1 98 fl: VOIC E VOTE; AK ord. d ot. on r n' Approved W"i lson and Smith r eliOt CAH r. VO'CE VOTE Ao&amp;lt;Or&amp;lt;lM ,ot. 00 Q ot ROLL CAll VOT A~SULf 5&amp;lt ca </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
