<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-226">
  <num type="law">7-226</num>
  <heading type="short">D.C. Solid Waste Management and Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-226.pdf">D.C. Law 7-226</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 595</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-226, the “D.C. Solid Waste Management and Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-378, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 29, 1988 and December 13, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 10, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 7-301 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>caU!IIC IL OF THE OIST!I!:r OF COLUMBIA NOTICE O.C LAIl 7~226 "O.C. So li d Waste Manage.ent an d Multi Mater i a Re cyc li ng Act o f 198B Pursua nt t o Stction 412 of the Dist r i ct of CollJtlbia Se l f- Governme nt and Gov er nlll en U l Reorga ni zati o n Act P. L. 93~198 the ACt the COlJ nc il of the District of CollJlllbi a ad opted Bil l NO. 7~3'8 on f i rst and sec ond reading s, No vember 29, 1988, and Dece mbe r 13 1988 respective l y. Followfn9 the si9natIJre of the Mayo r on Janu,"y 10, 19B 9, this legi slat io n wa s as si9 ned Ac t No. 7 101 pu b lis hed in the Janu ary 20, 1989, edi ti o n o f the O.C Re g iste r Vol. 35 page 595 and tra nuitted to Cong ress o n J an uary 23, 1989 for a 30-day revie w, In accordance with Sect io n 602(cl 1 of the Act. Th. CounCil of the Dh trict of Colu mbia hereby g i ves no t i ce t h at the 30 day Cong ressi on al Review Per i Od h as expired, and ther e f o re citu this enactment u o c Law 6, Ma r ch 16 1989. Date s Cou nted DU ri ng the-lO d ay Cc nq J anuary 24,25,26,27,30,31 u it c an t o th e lo na l ~ev l ew Per lo d: February 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,21,22.2 3, 24,27, 28 March Z.3 6, 7,8 9 10, 13 ,14, 15 D.C LAW 7 2%6 AN ACT c. ICT 1 3 0 I CO::i t l Tew ChaE'tElr 14 O dele 6 District of COh~ia C':o e 1 i IN THE COJHCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COL UMB IA .IAN I 0 i; IJ To esta bllsn coli c:1 for th e Di str ic t of Columb 4 for the compre ll l! ns i ve nana ge~en t of sol id lt;Ia st e 4nd a mu l tl lIIateria l recyc li ng program. require the sour c e s eparatio n of certain rec yclab l e ~a ter ia1s. e s tablish targH dHIls 'or a percentage reduct ion i n munic ip a l solld wa s te Inc! e s tab l ish an OH iC I! of Recy cli ng within the Oep art r.1 en t of Public Worlts. BE IT ENA CHD ay TH E CO UNC IL OF THE D!ST RICT OF COlU HB Th at thls act &amp;lt;'lay be c ited as th e Olstr lc t of Colu mbia So lid ast l! Mana&amp;lt;]enen t and Hu l t i Mater l a l Re cycl I ng Act of 1968 Sec 2, Find i n~s The Cou ncil of t he Dis trict of Col umbia C oun cil f i nd s thH 1 Tn e Di st r i ct of Co l umb Dist r ic t dispos e o f itS o'i d was u by I llc i l'!e r~t lo l t t he Ben n i n ROdd Sol i d lIaste Reduct io n Ce nt er .fl SWRC .H o r burying it ~t t he Lorto l landfill l ocated o n I nter sta te 95 2) Appro:l;i mately 2,000 tons af solid aste fr om t he District is buried i n the Lo rt on Land fill ed ch day and app roximately 700 t ons 4re bur ned at $IoIRC H each d ay 3) The i l'!crea sing yo lune a nd va r iety o f so l id waste gener ated in th e Dist r ict c r e a te co nd itions t hat thre aten th e publ i c hea l th ufety, and we ll o e i ng by con tributin g to hnd pollution d wa ste of res ou rce s the pr oduction of f1ie rodents, li tter, and the gene ra l deteriorat io n of t~le environ me nt 4 The traditional ~eth o d s o f solld wa ste na ndgeme nt fo r th e Dis trict, wh ich a r e di rected la r gely at l and d is posal and incineration lay not meet the future d emand s o f the gr owi ng amount of muni ci pal s o lld wll st e lI d t he increase in no n·bi ode9fdd d b l e ma t e ri a l s co ntd i ned i n sol id wa s te {S Met nods of so lid wa ste managemen t that em pna sia ource r~duc t lo n dnd re cycl i ng a.-e e s s e ntidl t o I ~olled Or1g the lo ng range ~rfS!rV4 of nt!It safety, an d well-being of the public the e conomic prodlicth i ty and e nvir onmenta l qu a lity of the District and the conservation af re sou rces 6) Removtng ce rU i n materi a ls from the Di stri c t so l id aste st.-e will decrease tile fl ew of solid waste to til, Lorton Landfill, aid in the conservat io n of va lu ab l e res our ces, a nd reduce substanti a lly the r!quired capacity of pr oposed so lid waste dlspoHl facillth s 7) The.-e 15 no off i Ce, division, o r personnel, wi tnin the Dist.-1ct government, devoted ueclfically to the issu e s attendant to recyc ling 8) The Council can most appropr iat ely aemo ns trate I ts long term commitment t o en vironme nta l pro tection and effective solid aste ma nagemln t by establishing a proper solid wast! separation and recycling prog ra m a nd inc r easing the purchase of recycled products by a gencies and Inst.-umen t allties of the District government 9 Many othe r jurisdictions, inc l ud i ng Fairfax Co unty, Vi.-gl"i Montgome.-y County, Maryland; and many states, including New Jers ey, Califo r nia, and Wasll in9 to n inc lu de recycling as part of their solid aste s tre nunagement 1 0) Private g r oup recyc ling efforts with in the Dist ri c t s hould be en c ou.-aged and coord i nated wi th the e ffo rt s of the District 90~ernment 11 Effo.-ts s hould be made by the District go ver nment to e~pl o re the feasib i l i ty of estab l lshl n9 joint re cyc l in g progr ams i th neighboring ju r is di cti on s. Sec. 3 Purposes. In enacting tlli s a ct t~e Counc i l suo po r ts the f o llow i ng purpOSeS 1) To inc ease the life-expectancy of the ntentate 95 Landfill an d decrease the need for future expansion of a l ternat"'e efuse disposal facilities through d comp rehensive pr og.-am of solid ~aste strellm reducti on 2) To develop a l ternatfYe metllods of recovering re so ur c es from solid wast e, rec ommend uu~ for the recovered re so u r ces a nd deter~lne the illlpact of toe distribu tio n of the re s ources in exis tin g mll r~e t5 3) To Ide nt ify Iletllods o f coll ec tion. reduction and separltion that will promote more efficient use of so lid wast e disposal facil i ties and contr i bute to lIIo r e e ffective p.-og ra ms fo the reuse of solid ~aste 4 To employ Cistrlct govern~ent procurement proc edures to deyelop mark et demand for ecovered rnources it h speelal emphasi s on ma ximum DiStrict gov er nm ent use of re c yc l ed paper. 1 5ect o!'l 6- l~02 S w C O 1 oe pUO.1C agenci es, or i H~@ c r gan lz ati ons nd i ndiv idu a l s t o pa r ticip at@ in he rec l~ mat io n ~nd r@cyclin9 of r! so ur~es from ~olid wa t es 6) To p r omote pol ici es of en~r~y conserv~t lo n, env iro nmen t al protection eco nomic pr od uct iv ity, a nd cost e ,fe c tfveness 1" the DIs tr ic t Sec. 4. Definitions. Fp r the pu rpos es of this act, the t@rm 1 C omr.'ler ci al soli d waste part o f thl! s oli d waste stream that i s Dis :r i ct governm en t. HreaP.1" mea ns no t collected tha t by th e do es no t Dist r ic t l Commerc i al property" l'Ieans any pr op erty tnat re c eive 50 1 i d wa s te co l lection sen ices fr o the governr.1ent 3 C ompost" mea ns t~I! substanc e produ ced th r oug h the decompc.sition of o rgan ic mHer i als, inclu din g wood paper mulch, yard and food wa ste, that is capab le of be i ng used as a soil amend ment 4 Composting" mea ns the decomposition of org ani c mate rials t.o form com post 5 Co nstru c ti on and demolition wastes mean s the waste bu i lding mater ials and rubble resulting fr om co nstruction remO~l!linQ re pai r a nd demolition operation o n hou ses, COr:lmercial bul1d l ngs pave ments, and other structur e s 6 Disposit i on" mean s the transport, placeMent, re us e sa l e, donation transfer or tempo rary Storage for a per iOd no t e.ceeding 6 1I10 nths of recyc lable ma teria ls for a ll poss1bl e us es e.o:cept disposal as so li d waste 7 Intermed i ate pr ocessing faci lt ty" mea ns a fac ili ty where coming l ed solid waste can be s @parat@d, processed, s tored, as sembled, and prepa re d for sale or Other disposition e .o: c ept incineration or bur ia l S Market" means the disposition of recyclable materials that are source separated in t ne District an d e l cnanged fo r fair marKet value g Mult i mate rial re cycling buy b3C k center eans any p Ub l ic l y or p r i ¥ate l y operated facility that pays the public fo r r ecyclab l e mat e r i a l s 10 Office bu i lding" means a ny ccamerei. l e stablishment where the primary fl,lncti ons dre the tran sac t to n of adm ini strat i ve, bus lne\s, civic, o r prof eSSiona l s ervices incll,lding any lib ra ry musel,l m, unive rs i ty or oth er facil i ty where hand l i ng goods wares, o r mercha nd ise i n limi ted quantiti es is acc es sory to t he pri mary Gc cu pancy or use ll Paper" means all ne wsp aper, high grade o ff1 ce paper, fin e paper, bond paper, offse t paper lt;:er Og rap MiC pdper memo paper duplicato r pa pe r con t in uous l lelo Sec 6-3 C· } &amp;amp;crolled Orlgi:&amp;amp;l form pap er en~elopes, pr int ed mater i a l a ated c el l ulos i c "ateda l c ont a inin'l no t more than 1 0 by e lq ht o r vol~:ne of non·cellul o siC mater ial s u ch a s laminates, tli nders, coa~ ings J r saturant s I Z aper product" means any paper item or c ommod ity. hcluding :uper na p k i ns t owe l s co rrug.tted dnd o t he r c ardbH r cons t ru ct i on mattrial. toilet tissue, and rel~t ed ce lbl osic pr oducts con ta inin'l not mo re than l O by e igh t o r vol ume of no n.cel l ulosic mat e rhls such .t S lami nat e bi nd er s, coating, or saturant s \JJ "Re cyc li ng" mea ns a resource recovery met ho d ,I,d t involves the coll e c t io n (lnd t re at!:le nt of was te r:ldterial Ch d t can r ep r oc e ss ed a nd r eturned t o the economi c r~a i n s treu as r aw nat erlal or pr oduct s 14 Recyclable 1at er1a l mea ns :uterial t hat ~ou 14 ot huwis e bec ome mun ici cal solid loIaste, a nd that ma y be c oll ect~d se parated o r proc essed .t nd r~turne d to the ec on omiC fu i nstrum as a r.tw material or pr'Oduct lj Re cycled paper mellns a ny paper t h e t o ta l ~e j~ l!t of &amp;gt nlch is no t l e ss Uan 40 se c o ndary was te paper Ia ter i a 16 Recycle d paper product" mea ns any paper pro du ct consi st i ng of not less than 4 0 s ec o ndar y wast e o.tpe r at eri l l 1 7 Re cycling serv i ce" mean s the se rv i ce pr o v i ded by' pers on engaged in the business o f re cy c li ng, l nclud ing tH collenion, pro cessing sto ra 'l e pur c hll se ul e. o r dispositio n o f re Cyc l a b l e mater1a l s liS Residential so lid wa s te strea m" mean s that pa rt of tile sol id loIa st e streae tll.tt is collected by the Di str ic t qovt rnment 19 Res i dential property· mean s p r o perty that receiv es so li d waste collection servlc!!s f r om th Oistrict go ver nme nt in c lu d i ng, si ngle fa mily dwell i ng s and any )uil d i ng or st r uc ture contain ing) or fewer d wel ling units used exc l ushely for resident i al purposes. Resld enti&amp;lt;l l pro pert i es hl ll a lso Inc lude condo miniumS and cooperatives. i f he occupants choos e to part l clp .tte in t h e recy c l ing pr og ra m ~sin q is tr l ct co ll ecti on s ervice s 20 Source separ~ted recyclaO l e mater i al" means &amp;lt;1 recyc1a~h IIIt er I i nc l uding paper me tal l a yard st e off i ce paper, or plastiC tn a t i s s tor ed se parate l y from re s l d e t i a l 41'1 4 COlilmerci a l s ol id wa s te for the pu rposes o f c oll tc t ;c n, disp os ition, dnd r ec ycl in 21 Soll d wa ste eans ga r bage, refuse. or any o t ner waH e product including, solid, liQu id, semi so lid, or con ta ined 9ueous materia l res ulti ng fr om a n ind ustrial c')m~er cl l or qo ver,ment o perati o n or a c ommun it y act i v i ty 2 2 So li d aste s trealll ean s all e s de nt a l and c o~mer C ldl qarbage o r r e fu s e ge ner!ted within t~e Enrolled Origt is tr ic t tnH Jnhss r ecyc l ea ou Il e di sp os ed o f Oy l Hc f illi n; o r in ci nerat io n 23 h i te goo ds e ans refrigeratlJrs, stoves, tc e f ree !ers or appliances that ~ay co ntain eh 1 or of l uo r oc ~rbons 2 4 Yard ste mea ns a ny organic llaterta l excep t food and includes O Od, mu l ch leilves, o r p lant s. SH. 5. Soli d lOa s te ma nag e~ent polity f o r t he Jist r ic t a Tilt f ollo ll inq sti! ma nagel"lent hierarchy \5 estao l i$he4 fo r e Distric t II) Volume re duc ti on at th e sou r ce 11 R~cycling compos~ l n9 and_r us e; o r (3 Di spos a l i n l a ndfill faCiliti e s b Seqin ninq on Oc tober I. 1989 and eve ry 2 years after tha t date, t ne Mayor .n a ll s ubm i t to t he Co unc il fo r revh w. a comp renensive solid was te managem ent plan tons i s tent,;1tn the purpo ses i n sec tion J ~nd the h le r achy in subsec t io n (aJ of th is se ction Hie phn shall Inc l ud e the f llowing 1) A co:n preh e nsive analysis of the 5011d aste s tre4 comp os itjo f the DIst r i c t f o r the ne~t 10 year s 2 comp reherH.he a naly sis of t ne solid wa s te disposal a nd recycli ng systems o f the Dis tr i ct f o r the nu t 20 years, including a n asseSSllent of th e li fe e.pe c tan cy o f the Lo r ton L nofj l l l An a na ly s i s of t he ma r ket for re c ycled .r.ater ials 4 An a na lysis of recyc l ing oppor tun it ie s in the flas hing t on Metropolit an Ar ea 5) An analys i s o f the feas i bility of eSOI)1iS Min g local :narlets for re cy clabl e materals I n a nd ne ar the Dist rict; ind (6) An ~ssessment o f the risks of ste m~ na geme nt alterna tives c) The Mayor shall co ns ult Ith the Litter and Solid H e Reduc tion Commission es tab lish ed pu rsuant to s ect ion 2 of tn e Lit te r and Solid Wa ste Red uct io n Act o f 1985 effect i ve Febrll uy 21 1985 (O.C. La 6- 84; D.C. Co de, sec. 2 1201 and p r i v.t ent i tie s and i nd i v id uals I n impler:le ntlng tile pro vis ion s of th is act. Sec. 6. Prio r i ty for r ecycling. The Mayor sha ll not co nstr uc t o r retrofit any fa ci li ty i n tne Dis tr ic t fo r t ia purpose o f solid a ste i nc i ner a tion or r esou rc e recovery thr oug h Incine rat io n until a ll o f the prQv is 'o ns of t~ i&amp;gt; Ht are I l"Ip]emented or a 251. re ductio n i n tne SOlld aste s tr~ar.l is Hh 1ev!d t nrough Distrj c t wlde r e~yc;'ng, w~i c '1ever come s f i rst. 5 e c }.1(l le'w. Section 6- ]~OS e C. 7. Rec yclable matHilh o w!rY targets a Th e Mayor shall adh e n to recove ry t argets fo r re cyclatll~ mat e r i al s whlc n s ha ll i~ctyde at a rn ini mun. t he follo wing schedul e IJ The r ecycling of It lu s t 10: of t he t ot a l comm e r c i al solid wast e s tream of t he pr io r year by the end o f the first full yelr th a t the ma ndato r y sou r c e s epa r atio n r equi re ne nts of s e c t i o n 8(a) are i n effecti 2 Th e recycling of hu t 151 of t'1e t o tal solid wa s t e 5t r e4 m of the prio r yur by t he end of the fi r s t f ull y e a r t h a t th e lII! ndatory sour~ e separation requirements of section S(c are In ef f ect j (3) The r e cy c li ng of H l us t 3S~ of the t a tal loll aste St r eam o f the Dist r i ct by Oc t ob er 1. 199 2 alld 4 Th e recycling of at l s t ~5~ o f t ~1! to ta l s o l id loI as t s tr eam of the DIs tr ic t by Oc t l) be r 1. 1994 b For th e purpose of t his Hetion the t e rm 'to t~ l s olid was t e s tr e ~m m ea~ s the sum of th ll sol1d wastll st r ll m dis ol)sed of as so li4 wast e by t h e Di strict. l'Ius\l r ed in tons pl u s t he to ta l numbe r o f t o ns of rec ycl ab le lTT ~t e r i 1s r ecyc l ed. S e c. B. Man dato ry s ou r c e sepHat i o~ pr og r am a By OctOb er I 1989 occupants of c ornle rcl a l property shall sep" r!t e f r om their solid wa s t ll bu nd le or c ontaine r ize a nd pro v ide for the r ecyc li ng of all newspaper In add i t io n, occu pants of offic e buildings incl~ di n 9 the Dis tr ic t go ve rn r.l e nt, s hal l s eparate fo r collect io n and p r ovide fo r t h e recytllng o f a ll paper as req~;red by th e Ma yo r by ru l es issued pu r SH nt t o s e c t io n 10 b By Octobe r 1 1990 o ccupa nts of commer ci a l prope r ty s hal l sep &amp;lt;l:r&amp;amp;te for c ol le ct io n an d pr ovide fo r th e re eyCll ng of al l glas s and met a l c By Oct ob er 1 1969 oc cup a nt s of r esi de ntia l p r ope rty shall s eparate fr om their Sl)lid waste and separate l y bundle or c onta Ine r ize al l y ard u te a nd ne spape r f o cy c lin g a s requ i r ed by t h e ~ayo r by rul @ pursuant to s@ ct i o n 20. ihe K~,or sh a l l provId e r e cyc l ;n9 coll ect io n s ervi c es f o r yard wa s te and newsp ap e r no less tha n t wic e eac h month and n o t ify a ll res i de nts r e ceivinq coll ectio n s e r vices f~olll t he Dis t r i ct of scheduled collectio n d~ ys as requ ir ed by SUb se ct i on e of t h is senlon d By Apr i l 1. 199D oc cu pa nts of re Si dent ia l p r ope rty shal l s epa ra te fr om their Sl)l1d waste a nd co nta in e r ize a l l ~eta ls and 9 1 ss in 1 bin as r equi r ed by tne Mayo r by rul es Iss u ed pur s uant to section 20. The ayl) r Sh a ll p~o v ld e coll e ctio n se rv ices and eH a blhh a coll ection 6 eo ec c 5-]~06 ew ion 6 1~07 ch td ul l! to i ll!p i e n h h i o5 I!ct ion ?u rs udnt t o u tlS l!ct jo n e of thh s e ct i o n e l The Mayor sh 11, by J u l y 1. 19B9 dn d at l ust once eye ry 6 months after t hat date natify all per s ons o c c~pyjng residentia l pr emises wi th in the Dist~ ict of local r ecy c ling op portunities, the da t es for co llectl0n of sou rce s eparated materials and all o ther sourc e separation requ i rem ent s of this act. In o r de r to fulfill the not i fiCat io n requirements o f th i s SUhHction the May o r s hall a dvertise i n a newspaper i t h wi de c i rcu l at lo n in the Dist r i ct post in pub li c places. d nd na il not i ce lI i t n the re sidential Iter and se er b ills as t he Mayo r deems n ec es sary an d a p pr o p ri at e. Se c. 9. Esta b lishme nt o f Off ic e of Recyc li ng Sec a l The Office o f Recyc l1 ng is established as a s i ngh 6- 140B '} clr.li nls trative unit wi th i n the executive office of the Dlre c to r of t he De partment of Public ~orks to admln ls ter t~e re cycling pr og ram in the Dlstrict e) Th e du t i es of the Office s hall include, to i) Coordinate, s upe r v1$e, an i mplemen t the "1andat o ry source s epa ra t ion p r og r am esublished by sec t ion 3 incl uding a sys tem t o respond to citizen inquiries 2) Ensu re the adherence of the Distr ic t t o t arget dates for so li d a ste r,ducti on oursuant to Hct lo n 1 3) Develop a n edu c at i ona l anO pr omoti ona l c '} mpa i gn, i n co njunct i on with the Li tter and Sol i d Waste Redu c t i on Com"liss i o n, for COl:1me r c h l a nd residential s o lid wa s te ge nerators on the ma nda t ory s ou rce 51!para t i on pr og r a m and r ec y cli ng 4 Re sear ch the techno l ogy availab le for 50 l1 d wa s te utilization, inc l uding re cycling 5) Id ent ify po t ent i al ma rkets fo r r ecyclable mate r ials a nd obt ain statements of i nterest for recovered mater i als 6) Id ent ify the amount and ch H!cterist lcs of the so \ l d aste stream In th e Distr i ct 7) Provide an a ss essment o f th e potential Impact o f a l te r nat iv e met hods of so li d waste management Includ i ng the pub li c he a lth phy s i c a l soc ial, eco nom i c fiscal, env i ronmental and aesthetiC i~ p l i catio ns; I S) Co nduc t and evaluat e the resu l ts of public foru ms o r Surveys of loc al citllen opi n ion on so l1 4 wa ste ~a n o g eme n t pra c ti c es f n con j unctio n ith the litte r a nd Sol id Waste Reduction Commission g l1ake site ana l yses 10) Coordinate eff o rts to sti mula te mar ket fo r re c yc led ma terials, including Dts tr i~t go vernment pur~hasing pol ici es 1 11 rv as l i a ison between tile Dis tri ct and ne 19 hoo r H ju risd l ct ie ns In deve lo p ing a regien recyc li ng ~l1 d wa ste r educ t io n c al:1pa iqn, a nd (lZ) De ve lo p a Mo nt hly household h aza rdous wa ste c ollection d~y to educ ate c i ti ze ns on househo l d hazard ous a s tt and co~ wenient a lld safe d i s po sa l thr ough sepa rate c ollecti on 0 it~ l n 90 days of t ile efhctive date o f t h1s ac t, the Hayo r sn.l l1 dlli9n ate R ycl\ng Coo r dlrat o r ho shal l he ad t~e Off i ce o f R:t!'cyc\ing. Sec. 10 \ i;lli te d. Right to r ecych Ind ivi d ua l soli d wa s te nOt No t n;n~ i n t~ is act sh a ll In divldu&amp;lt;ll to do n&amp;lt;l te, s el l o r h er r cychb l e materia l s. II i t t il e otnerw is e right of an dispose o f II i s o r Sec. 11. Hult i mate r ial recyc ling buy-ba c k. centers and I nter "ledldt! processin9 fac ili tiu lt;l Tne Mlyor sh a ll e s ta blish on o r bl!fore Octob e r 1. 1989 a t l east 1 r.lu l tl- rlateria l buy tll c k cente r in the Distri c t I'n lch slla11 be publicly o r pr l nte l y o perated nd pay the puo llc for re cyclabl e mate r ials tI T~ e May or h d ll e s tab lish at l east I interrudhte pr ocess i ng facili ty in t he Dis tr ic t t o re c e ive re c yc l ab l e mate ri~ ls de~;gnated f o r sou rce s eparati o n pu r s uant t o tnis a c t nd 4 11 Y o t he r rec ycla ble rnater l l s d es i gnated by t he "Iay o r. Se c H Co ntract i ng aut hority. Tne Mayor may e nter i nt o co ntracts o r a g reement s Oil belial' of tn e Dlstritt for recyc l ing s ery; t e s o r till! operation of I. I'IlIl t l lllaterh l retyc l lng buy ba c k. c e n ter ~nd an i nter::lt d i He pr oceuin9 f acil i ty fo r tile coll e c ti on s to r a ge. pro cessing. and dispositi on o f r",cyc\ab l e materials design ated t o lit sou rce sepa rat ed pu r suan t t o this a c t if t n e s e Sl rvic e~ are no t otherw i se pro v i ded by the Di st ric t government. Sec. lJ Compost t:later i &amp;lt;l Js us e requ i rements. ille Mayor ~h a ll. to the r.la:otimul!I e~ tent practic",ble a nd f e a sib l t use compost materials ill any l a nd ma i ntenan ce activity op erat ed wi t h pub lic: funcls and ma~e C:Olllpost a te r \ a ls ava il abl e to tile pub li C. Sec. 1 IHst r lct pr oc u reme nt pol ic i e s a me I\~yor 5h",\1 mo dify all bid s pecific ui o ns re l ati o the pu r chu e of pap er and p.t per products t o p r omOH :ne nu mum purclld s e of paper and p r od ucts "la de fr om recyc l ed pape; and re cJcl ed pa per p r oducts. Prefl!rence 8 'lew, Sec ior. 6 D9 6- 3"-10 ~Jew. Section 6 \&amp;lt;112 'lew. See't.i.on 6- 141 1 slu l1 to recyc l ed pa r 4 r ecv~:i!d paper r~ouc t S unless the pr ice of t e pa oe r a nd pa per products i s no t C Olll p!ti t i ~e for t he pur pose intended. For t he pu r poses of th is section, t he term ·competitiv e mean s a price it h in IO~ of the pr ice of i tems that are manufac t u r e d or prod uced from virgin paper products 0) me )1"'yor sh~ll make a yea rly written determI nat i on as to 'ojh etliel t he p r i c e of recycled paper and l'"ecy c 1ed "per pro ducts is c ompetithe, and on the pe r:e nta ge of recyc l ed pijper and r ecycled paper pr od uc t S pur ch ased by h e D i~tr ic t so vern~ent dur i ng the pr i or yea r. Th e May o r 51'1 11 sub mi t a c opy o f the rep o rt to the Co uncil on Janu ary I. 19 90 and on Janu ary 1st of each subsequent j e a r c Un le s s the pr i c e of recyc l ed pape r a nd recyc l e d paper p r Odu ClS i s no t c ompetit i ve as det ermi ned by the Ma y o r gt;unuant t o ~u~s ect io n b) o f t hi s s ect i on t h e pe r c en ta ge of t he t o t l ~nount of pa pe r or pape r pr oducts made fr om r e cyc led p e r o r recycled pa per products pu rcha sed by the Di s tri c t sh~ll be as follow s I) Not l es s t h4n 151 by Octo ber 1, 19 90 0) Not le ss than 30'f. by Oc t obe r 1, 1991; an d i l l Not l ess t ha n 4 51 by Oct o ber 1, 1992 d Tilt ~ayor, a fte r forma l ad vertisement and ioli cttat ion of pr oposals f o r re c yc l ed paper o r re cy c l ed paper pr oduc ts may awar d a co ntra c t for pa per o r paper p r oducts ma nu fdctu re d or produced from vtrgln paper pr oducts In t e n n e r pre sc r ibed by I if no competitive pr o posals f o r r ec yc h~ paper o r r ecy cled paper p r odu c t s are re c e i ved. The a ard of a c ontract for v i rg i n pap er p r od u cts shall no t rel h we the it l yo r of a ny future obligation t o cont rl ct for re cycl ed paper o r recyc l ed piper p r oducts e The Mayor s~ a ll investigate o ther produ c ts th.t a r e reeyc l nle or composed, in whole o r in part, of re cycle d mat e r i als that c an be purcha s ed f o r use by the Di s tr i ct ~overnme nt and s ubmit a report on th e findings of the i n·l estig at t on and a plan for th e pur ch a s e of other r ecycled produ c t s I ncl uding glass pla sti cs and tires within 6 mont~ s afte r the effect ive date o f this ac t Sec. IS Annual repo rt in g r eq ui rements; submissio n of p I an a Beg l nnin g on J a nuary 15. 199 1, and o n ea c h January 15 t h o f u ell. subse quent year the Ma yo r s hall sub mlt a recyc li ng r epor t to t he Councl1 for revie whi c h sh a l l co nta i n the fol l o lf l n g 1) Th e tonn age o f s o lid gt;Ia st e generated. dhpo u d of nd recy cl ed by t'e Dist ri c t; 12) An evaluat io n of t he mand~tory recycling pr 09 ram e s t~blh ned pur ~u~ nt t o tn i s a c t J Th e t o nn a ge of paper 1;0\ Jet ted a nd t c l ed f ro~ Dis tr ic t 90vern~ent o ff i ces The reve nu e generated thr ough t he di sp os i ti on of c y tl ed ~aterials f or t he Dis tric t The approJt i mate c ost H ol dana ac hi eved t h r ou gh the Di stri c t's ma ndatory re cyclin g pr ogrl 6) The overal l su cceSS Of meet i ng the re co very tar gets s e t fo rth In sect ion 1 of th h act 1) An I!va \,,I&amp;lt t lo n of lII ar~ e t5 fO r recyc l ed materials a nd how Dis trict polici es have sti:luhted. r:l a"~ets a) An eva luat ion of t il e edu cat ion a l and p r omo t io na l ca mp a. f gn on t~e mandatory sou r ce s epa r.t to n p r og ra lll 5 deve lop ed by t h e OB tr le t of Col uln tda Ihcy tl 1n g Coord l nat o~ PUr SU/lllt t o Se c tion 9 of t his act b By Oc t Ober I 1989. t h e M.tor s lu ll s uh r!li t to the Cou nci l 4 plan f o r tile fo llo wi ng I) Tile re covery o f i re s f r OIll tile s oltd wute st re arl fo r r e u s e re&amp;lt yc l1 ng or o Uter d i s pOSi t i on 2 Tne segregation treattlent. labe l ing t rack i n g tra ns port !o n nl) d i sposit ion of med ic a l i nfe c t io u s and hazardo us "a st f 3 Th e recy cling ,lnd r euse o f c onstructi on and d emo li t i on w.ste s 4 The pr ovis i o n of U.t inc entives nd 10 in teres t l oans to District businesses that use recycl ed p r od uc ts or purc h a se or l ease recy cl i ng equ i pme nt 5 Tile r e cyc l ing of p l a stic polystyrene and polyvin al c hlo r i d e conta i ners. Se c. Hi. Recycl1ng s urcharge Th e May o r sha 1 1 I 1 n U i n I r ecy, l1 ng su rC!\H ge on a II Dr l vat e haule r s of 50110 a ste ho o h ~ose of SOli d aste through t h e s ol id wa s te dispOHI systelll of tne Distr ic t t o o f fset the c ost of dev e lop i ng ne nd ad dit i ona l ~e thod5 of sol id s te ~ana9ulent Money genented f r OIll t his surch.rg e sh.l l be used to fund recycling a c tiv i t ie s I n t h e Distric t, no mo re t h an 2S 1 of wlllCh s h a l l go t o fund tile recyc li ng e du cat i onal and promot lo "a l Htivit i e s of t il e LI tter .nd Sol id ~a s te Redu ct i o n Co.m i ss i o n Sec. 17 nfo r ill at ion clear l ngh auSt Tne M'yo r sh ~1 1 main ta i n a cen t ra l clearingh ous e fo r in f o r ill ati on regolrding t he il'lp1e l'lentat i on of this .ct .nd r ec ycli ng i n general The cl ear l ngMO Use s ha ll pr ov i de dolt. re g ard in g so l id w. ste resea rch nd pla nn i ng. 501ld "a s te m. n. gt me n t poll Cit s markets for r ecycli b1e mater i a ls nd re9lo n ~1 coope rat ion Se c 18 f nforc m n t ew Sect ion 6 15 The provisions of tll B ac t. I nc ll'Min [ne est ab li shment o f a sch edule of fln1 fe r ~io 1 4t j o n s of this act shal l be e nf o r ced by tht \410 1" purSU il'lt to the Litter Co ntr e l Admi n is trat io n Act of 1985 effective March 25 1986 D.C. la w 5· 100 D.C. Cede, sec· 6· 290 1 et seq {b } In addi t ion to the pena l t i es impos ed pursuant t o s ubsect i on a of this section, t he Mayor may re fuse t o co l l!!c t o r d isp o .e of any s ol j d &amp;gt;l u te that i s no t sepa rated as r eq uired by t his act or any ry \e s Issu ed pursu a nt t o s e c tio n 20 e The May o r may deny the I ss uance or renewal of li cense to en gag e In commerc i a l col1 e t t ion or transportation o f s ol id wa stes by veh i c l e i f tnl! ap pl ican t doles ne t uarantee that r ecycl ab l e ma ter i al s s eparated as re quired by t his act o r by r u les i ssue d pu r s ua n t t o sect i on 20 o f t~ j s Ht 11 1 be recy c l ed. Sec. 19. Confo rming ame ndment a) Se c t ion 3( a)(l) of the Li tter Control ,l,dmi n istr ation Act o f 1985 effective March 25, 1986 D.C. La w 6-1 00; D. C. Code sec. 6- 29Q2 is amended by add i ng the ph r ase "the District o f Columbia Solid loIaste Mana gement and Hu l tl-Hateria l Recycling Act of 1981 after the ord "enfo r ce b) Section 3 of th e U tter and Solid Waste ~ct o f 198 5 eff e c t iv e Fe b r uary 21, 1986 D.C. La w 6 84; D. C. Co de, sec. 2- 3202 is amtnd e d by add i ng the phr ase "and recyclin g" after the word "reduct io n" wherever it a ppears el Sect io n 3(c) of the Litter and Solid ~a s te Act of 1985 D.C. Code sec. 2 3202(c is amuded by addin g a ne w parag r aph (8) to read as foll o s 8) The developr:lent of a comprehensive educational and pr Olllot io na l cam pa ign on recycl i ng fo r gen erat ors of comme r cial and re s identi a l so li d wast e Se c. 20. Rules With i n 90 days after t he effective date o f this a c t t ne May o r sh a ll pu r su ant to t1t l e I of th e Dis tr ict of Co l um bia Adm in istrative P~ocedure Act, appro~ed Oc t ober ZI 1968 82 Stat. 1203; D.C. Code, n c. 1· 1501 et seq 1ssue proposed rules to implement the provi sio ~s of tnl s a c t. The pr o posed rules shall be sumitted to the Co uncil for a 45-day pe r io d of rev iew e~ c l uding Saturdiys, Su ndays, le gal holi days, and days of Co uncil r ecus. If t he Council doeS not approve o r disap pr ov e t he proposed r u l e~ i n whole o r in pa rt, by resolut io wit hin th is 'S d ay rev i ew peri od the p r oposed rules sh a ll be dee med approved. Se c 21. Effect i ve date. 11 Sect.ien 6- 2 ~02 secti= 2- 3202 Sect:ior. 2- 3202 lew. Section 6- 3&amp;amp; 111 In t s~"i I take effect &amp;lt;lfter &amp;lt;I 3 D- day pe r i od of =O n9rHSion nvhw following !pprOHl by tne Mayor (o r i n tne .vent of v~ to by t~e Mayor act ion by the Cou nC i l of tne Dist r ic t of Co l umbia t o ov errictt tile veto a s provicted in se ctlon 602(c)(1) Of the Dist r ict of Columbia Sel f_ Government dnd Government al Reor9ani ,ati on Act, approved December 24, 1973 S7 Stat. 8 13; D.C. Cod e, s.c 1- 2)3 c I CII i rman Coundl of tile Dis trict of Colullibid ict a f umbia APP ~OYEO: J anuary 1'J 1989 \2 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Cauncil Period .seven ReCORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTe ~OCKET NO; 3--378 'il ~CTIQN OAT l'&amp;amp;lark. CAll vor RESULT I t DOle Adoptec. Final Reading, 12-13-88 K: ACTIO J UE. X. VOICE VOH 0 cWi1son Smi th ROLL CALL 'Iore RESUlT Date ACTION &amp;amp; D~T OICE "OTE RecO'de d '0 roQuest b nt: ROll elll VOTE ESUlT I</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1001"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1002"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1003"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1004"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1005"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1006"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1007"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1008"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1009"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1010"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>12</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1011"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>13</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1012"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>14</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1013"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>15</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1014"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>16</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1015"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>17</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1016"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>18</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1017"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>18a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1017.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>20</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1018"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>22</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1019"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>23</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1020"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>24</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1021"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>25</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1022"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>25a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1022.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>26</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1023"/>
  </section>
</document>
