<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-27" flag="true">
  <num type="law">7-27</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1987-10-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-27.pdf">D.C. Law 7-27</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 5079</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-27 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-228, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 16, 1987 and June 30, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 17, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-49 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE OISTR!CT OF caLUMB NOTICE D4 C. LAW 7-21 "Oistrict of Col~mbi4 Government Comprenenstve Merit Personnel Act of 1978 Employee Senefits Amendment Act of 19B7 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Sel f Government and Governmental Reor9ani~ation Act, P. L. 93_lga the Act the Cauncll of the Oistrict of Columbia adopted 3 1 No, 7-228 on first a]1d second readings. June 16, 1987, and June 30, 1987, respectively. Follo wing the signature of the dJOr on July 17. 1987. this legislation was assigned Act 7-49, publish. ed In the August 7.1987, edition of the.Q f Register Iol. 3~ page 5079) and transmitted to Congress on July 21, 1987 for 1 30-day review. in accordance with Section 602{c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Con9ressional Review PeriOd has expired, and therefore. cites this enactment as D.C. Law 7_27 effective J 0P \,!4L'l i Me of the Counci 1 Ilctaber 1. 1987. llaUs Counted During the 30-01&amp;lt;11 Congressional, Review PeriOd: July 21.22.23.24.27,28.29.30.31 August 3.4.5.6.7 September 9.10.11.14.15,16,17,18,21.22.23,24.25,28.29,30 ZarGl1e4 Or1g1::41 d OCT 011987 D.C. ACT 7-49 IN TEE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JIJL J 7 1987 To ilmend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to provide heal and l~fe insurance-benefits for employees of the District gove~ent and retirement benefits for certai~ employees of e District government first employed after September 30, 1987. BE IT ENACTED BY TEE COUNCIL OF TEE OISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "OiJStrict of Columbia Cove~ent Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 Employee Benefits Amendment Act of 1987 Sec 2. Th" District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. LOl 2-139; D.C. Code, sec. 1-601.1 et seg is amen4ed as follows a) Section 201 (D.C. Code. sec. 1-602.1) is amended as follows 1) By designating the eXisting language as subsec~ion (a) of section 201 2) By striking the word "Unless" and inserting in its place the phrase "Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section or unless By striking the phrase "S~perior Court ot the District of Columbia Court of Appeals w and inserting in its place the phrase "S~perior Court of the District of Columbia and the District of Columbia Court of Appeals and (4) By adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) The Mayor may enter into an agreement with the District of Columbia co~rt system Or with any independent agency of the District to provide to their employees any or all of the benefits established ~nder the District of Columbia Compre hensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 Employee Benefits Amendment Act of 1987 b) Section 405 (D.C. Code, SeC. 1-604.5) is amended by insertin'l the phrase "other than niles and regulations 1 D.C s e c 198 8 D.C. Coe ec. 1-t (1988 5t issued pursuant 0 1'i tle ;ocr, XXI! and XXVI rr after 1e phrase "such rules and requlations e) Section 2101 (D.C. Code, sec 14622.1) 15 amended by 1nsertinq the phrase "first employed before October 1, 1987" after 1e phrase "all employees of the District qovernmosnt d) New sections 2102 ouqh 2113 are added to read as follows Section 2102. 01striet health benefits. The District shall provide heal~'1 benefits as set forth in section 2105 to all employees of the Oist:1et first employed after September 30, 1987, except those specif1eally excluded by law or by rule Sec. 2103. Definitions For the purposes of sections 2104 throuqh 2113, the term 1 Annuitant" means an employee first employed by the District after Sept=mber 30, 1987, who has sul:&amp;gt;=sequently retired pursuant to title XXVI 2 Carrier" means a voluntary association, corporation, partnership, or other nongovernmental organization that is lawfully engaged in providing, paying for, or reimbursing the cost of heal services under group insurance policies or contracts, medical or hospital service agreements, membership or subscription contracts, or similar group arrangements, in consid~ation of premiums or o~~er periodic charges payable to the orqanization 3 Dependent child" inc:ludes A) An adopted child; and B) A stepchild, foster child, or natural child of an employee or annu:i.tant 4 Employee" means an individual first employed by the District after September 30, 1987 5 Health benefit plan" means a group insurance policy or contract, medical or hospital service agreement, membership or subscription contract, or si~ilar group arrangement provided by a carrier for the purpose of providing, paying for, or reimbursing expenses for health services under section 2105 6 Member of f~ily" means A) The spouse of an employee or annuitant; years of Olge B) An unmarried dependent child under 22 e) An urunOlrried dependent child under 25 years of age who is a fu114time student; and D) An unmarried child regardles s of age who is incapable of self4support because of mental or physical disability that existed before age 22 Sec. 2104. Contracting authority, 2 D.C. C Sec 1988 sc NlOw. J. l Cod so 6 Z2.2 988 Ne D Code s. 1-622,] (1988 lIew, ll. C Cod se, 1-622.4 (19 8&amp;amp; SUI "The Mayo~ may cont~act wi~ qualified ca~~ie:s ~o p~ovide h~alth eenefits under lawa of e Oist~ict fo~ periods of tim~ to oe de~ermined oy th~ Mayo Any contrac~ under this section shall b~ in accordance with provisions of e Dist~ict of ColYmbia Procurement actices Act, 21, 1986 (D .C aw 6-85: O.C. Cede, sec it lenefit plans The Dist~ict may contract for o~ app~ove the following health oenefit plans 1) An Indemnity aenefit ~lan: One Ol strict-wide plan offe~ing at least 3 levels of benefits Tone of which shall be deemed by the Mayor to be a standard option) unde~ which a carrier aq~ees to pay certain sums e oney, not in axC9SS of the actual expenses incurred, for health benefits 2) aealth Maintenanc~ O~qanization Plans including A) One o~ mo~e group p~epayment plans at o!fe~ health benefits, in whole or in substantial part on a p~epaid basis, with professional services provided by phYSicians representinq at least 3 major medical specialties p~acticinq as a q~oup in a common center o~ cente~s who ~eceive all or a substantial part of eir p~ofessional income f~om the p~epaid funds; and a An inciividual practi prepayment plan that offe~s health benefits in whole o~ substantial pa~t on a prepaid basis, with p~o!essional services provided by individual physicians who agree, under rules promulgated by the 1ayor, to accept the payments provided by the plan as full payment for covered services. that. include in-hospital services, qeneral care provided in eir offices and in the patients' homes, out-of-hospital diagnostic procedures, and preventive care. w(3) Preferred Provider Organization Plan: An individual practice plan at offers health benefits in whole ar~5tantial part with professianal services provided by individual phYSicians, hospitals, and other health care praviders who agree under rules_promulqated by the Mayor ta accept contractually reduced payments for the covered services they provide. wSec 2106. Types of benefits a) The benefits provided under the health benefit plans shall include benefits for costs associated with care in a qeneral hospital and for health services of a catastrophic nature and may in.;lude at a minimum the followinq bene!i ts: w(l) Hospital benefits 2) Manaqed care 3) Office Visits; o. C. C Sec 1988 New. D.C Cod e 1-622. r 1988 S"l 4) Substance al:iuse 5) Well bal:iy car 5 rescription ~r~gs 7) Obstetricilll b~nefi tIS 8) Mental heilllth benefits; an 9) I!ospi&amp;lt;;e care b) Each contract issued under section 2105 shall comply with e provisions of the Drug Abuse, Alcohol Abuse, and Mental IllneslS InlSurillDce Coverage Act of 1985, effec~ive February 24, 1967 (D.C. Law 5-195: to be codified at D.C. Code, sec. 2301 et seg Sec. 2107. Election of coverage al Unless an employee or annuitant affi~atively waivelS heal insuranca coverage, each employee or a~~uitant shall enroll in 1 of the approved health benefit plans under section 2105 either as indiVidual or for self and family or provide eVidence satisfactory to the MaYQr that the employee or annuitant is covered under another health benefit plan bl If an employee or annuitant has a spoulSe who is an employee or annuitant, either the spouse but not both may enroll for ISelf and family, or each spouse may enrol l as an indiVidual. An individual shall not be enrolled as an employee or annuitant and al IS O alS a member of family cl An employee or an annuitant enrolled in a health benefit plan may change coverage by an application filed within 60 days of a &amp;lt;;hange in family status or as otherwi s e permittad. by rule promulgated. by the Mayor d) An employee or annuitant may transfer enrollment from one health benefit plan to another health benefit plan under s e&amp;lt;;tion 2105 as permitted by rules promulgated hy e Mayor Se&amp;lt 2108. Employee deductions and withholdi ngs a) Ouring each pay period in which an employee or an annuitant is enrolled under 1 of the health benefit plans there shall be Withheld from the compenlSation of each employee and from the annuity of each annuitant or there shall be paid by each annuitant Who received. his or her benefits as a lump sum payment an amount equal to the co s t of the selected health benefit plan less the amount of the Di.stri&amp;lt;;t &amp;lt;;ontribution for the employee or the annuitant. The amount withheld or paid by the employee or the annuitant, together with the District s contribution, shall be transferred to the carrier of the health benefit plan .selected by the employee or the annuitant b) DUring each pay period in which an individual re&amp;lt;;eiving d i sability compens ation benefits pur.suant to title XXUI is ~nrolled under 1 of the health benefit plans, th~te IShal l be withheld from those benefits an amount equal to the cost of the s e l e&amp;lt;;ted he a l th benefit plan less the amount of t he Di .s trict contri bution f or the enrolled individual. The 4 New, J. Code 3 6 HaS" Ne j C Code u 1-622 .8 (1988 St1 amoun~ withheld from the employee or the annui~an oqe~~e~ with e District's con~ri~ution, shall be transferred to e carrier of e heal benefit plan selected by 8 indiVidual receiving disability benefits Sec. 210S. District contribution a e District's contribution to the cost of any health benefit plan shall be an amount equal to 7S~ of e subscription charge of the standard option o! the indemni t y benefit plan and shall be paid on a regular pay period basis b) Tl1e Mayor shall determine the amount of e District contribution for individual and for self and fami: y nro1lments before the beginning date of each contract period Sec. 2110 nfo=ation to employees a e Mayor shall make av~lable to each employee information as may be necessary to enable the employee to exercise an informed choice among the types of health benefit plans offered b) The Mayor shall make available to each employee annuitant enrolled in a health benefit plan a written statement or summary of 1) The services or benefits, including maximums limitations, and exclusions to which the emp l oyee, annuitant, or member of the family of the employee or annuitant are entitled 2) Th. procedures for obtaining benefits; and 3) The principal prOVisions of the health benefit plan affecting the employee, annuitant, or member of the family of the employee or annuitant Sec 2111. Coverage of r restored .employees An employee enrolled in a health benefit plan under section 2102 who is r~oved or suspended without pay and l ater reinstated or restored to duty on the ground that the removal or suspension was unwarranted or unjustified may at the employee s option, enrol l as a new employee or have th~ employee s coverage restored, with appropriat$ adjustments made in contributions and claims, to the same extent and effect as though the removal or suspension had not taken place Sec. 2112. EValuations; reports; audits. weal The Mayor shall make periodic $valuations of the operation and administration of th$ health benefit p l ans provided under section 2105 b) Each contract $ntered into under s ection 2 104 s hall require the carrier to 1) furnish r e a s onable reports as the 'Mayor determines nece s sary to $nable the Dist~ict to carry out its functions under thi s title and 5 Ne'.oI. J Code s 6 Z2 1'188 51 Ne D Cede sec 1-6 {1988 5u New D. C Code. se 1-6 22 11 198 8 suo N D.C. Code. Se' 1-622. 12 (198 8 s u 2) Per:ti t the Mayor to exami e rec:lrcis :If t 1.e carriers as may be necessary to carry out 1.e purposes of this title. wSec 2113. Rules; eliqibility. weal In order to ensure proper implementation of e health ben~fit lans under section 2105 by October 1 1987, the Mayo:r: ma ue temporary rules regarding t e health benefit pl t ahall not be ~ject to Council review. These temporary rules shall remain in effect only until the p:r:oposed rules have been approved or been deemed approved by the Council in accordance with subsection (b) of th~s section b) The Mayor shal l, pursuant to title I of the Dist:-ict of Colt!mbia Admi ni :n:.rative Procedure AC1 approved Oct:lber 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C Code, sec 1-15 0 1 e issue proposed rules to implement the provisions of this title. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 4S-day period of review, excluding Sa~~rdays, Sundays, leqal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules in Whole or in part, by resolution within thi s 4S-day review period, the proposed =ule s shall be deemed approved c) The proposed rules ~mitted pursuant to subsection (a of this s ection shall prescribe the time, manner, and conditions UDder which employees and annuitants are eligible for coverage The proposed rules may exclude employees on the basis of the nature and type of employment or conditions of employment such as- short-term appoin~ent, seasonal employment, intermittent or part-time employment or employment of a similar nature, but shall not exclude an employee or group of employee souly. on the basi o! the ha~ardous nature of employment e) Section 2201 (D.C. Code, sec. 1-623.1) is amende d by in=ertinq the phrase "first employed before October 1, 1987" after the phrase "all employees of the District government w f) New sect10ns 2203 through 2214 are added to read as follo s Sec. 2203 District life insurance benefits The Di=tr'ic:t Shall provide the group 11fe insurance benefits set forth in section 2207 to all employees of the Di=trict first employed after September 30, 1987, except those specifically eXCluded by law or by rule. wSec. 2204. Definitions. wE'or the purposes of sections 2205 through 2214, the term 1 Annuitant" mean= an employee first employed by the District after September 30, 1987, Who ha= subsequently retired pursuant to title XXV 2 Dependent child" i nc ludes 6 :i"e D. Cede, 5, 1 1988 s' D. c. red s ec. 1-1 1 988 s u N D. C Ced s 1-623. 3 (1988 SU I N w, D. C Ced e, 1-623. 4 (1988 SUj ehi1d of employed A) An adopted ehi d and a) A stepehi1d, foster ehi1d, or ~a~ra: an employee or a.nnui ant. w(3 Emp10yee W meanll an individual fi=st by the District after September 30, 1967 4 Member of family" means, w(Al The spoulle of an employee or ar~uitant; W(a) An unmarried dependent child under 22 years of age C) An unmarried dependent ehi1d. under 25 y~ars of age'who is a full-time student; and D) An unmarried ehild regardlell s of age o is incapable of self-suppor ecause of ~ental or physical disability that exi s ted before age 22 See. 2205 Contrac'Cing authori y a) The Mayor may purchase from 1 or more life inlluranee companies a policy or polieiell of group life in~ranee to provide the benefits set forth in sec 'Cion 2207 from a life inllUranee company licenlled 'Co provide life and accidental death and d.i$membe~ent insuranee under e laws of the Distric'C. Any under thill section shall be in accor~ance with e of Columbia Frocurement Fractices Act, effective 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 5-85; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1161.1 b) The Mayor may at any time a policy purchased from a company under subsection (a) of this section Sec. 2206. Automatic coverage; description of benefits a) Except as provided in subsection (b) of is section, an employee is automatically insured on e date the employee becomes eligible for insurance. Eac~ policy purchased by the Mayor under section 2205 shall provide for this automatic coverage b) An employee who does not wish to be insured shall give written notice to the employee's employing office or such other office desiqnated by the Mayor on a fo~ prescribed by the Mayor. If no'Cice is received before the employee becomes insured, then the employee Shall not be insured. If notice is received after the employee has become insured, the insurance will end at the end of the pay period in which the notice Was received. W(c) The Mayor shall make available to each insured employee or annuitant a written statement or summary o 1) The benefits to which the employee, annuitant, or member of e family of the employee or annuitant are entitled; effect 2) The procedures for obtaininq benefits; and 3) The prinCipal provisions of the policy in 7 Cod 5 1-623.5 (1.988 New. D r~d 3 1-62:1 1988 u "Sec. 2207. Group insurance; amounts a) The qroup life insurance amOU.D:ts purehased ~y t.'le Distriet under seetion 2205 shall be no less than the insuranea amounts provided under the Eederal Employees Group ~f. Insuranee (HF.Z.G I.~l plan pursuant to An Ac~ to enaet title 5, United States Code Government Orqanization and Smployees codifyinq the g-eneral and permanent laws relating- to the org-anization of the Government of the United States and to its civilian officers and employees, approved Septaml:&amp;gt;er 6, 1966 (80 Stat. 593; 5 U.S.C. 8702 in effect as of the effeetive date of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 Employee Benefits Amenement Aet of 1987 b ployees shall be offered the option of pUrchasing- additional coveraqe for themselves, and for their spouses and dependent children, and the eost of the additional coverag-e shall be borne solely by the employees purchasing- that coveraqe Sec. 2208. Death elaims; order of precedence tal The amount of g-roup life insurance in force for an employee or annuitant at the date of the employee or annui~ant death shall be paid, on the est~lishment of a valid claim, to the person or persons surviving- at the date of the death of the employee or annuitant, in the followinq order of precedence 1) To the beneficiary or beneficiaries designated by the employee or annuitant in a signed and witnessed writing- executed and filed before death 2) If there is no designated beneficiary, to the Widow or widower of the employee or annuitant 3) If none of the above, to_ the child or children of the employee or annuitant and decendants of a deceased child or children by representation 4) If nOne of the above, to the parents or parent of the employee or annuitant 5) If none of the above, to the duly appOinted personal representative of the estate of the employee or ann'Lli tant 61 If none of the above, to the other next of kin of the employee or annuitant under the law~ of the domicile of the employee or annuitant at the cate of death b) If no claim has been filed by any of the set fo~th in subsection (a) of this section within years of the date of death of an employee or the funds Shall be deposited into the District of Columbia to be kept diSbursed in accordance with the of Unclaimed Property Act of 1980, 1981 (O.C. Law 3-160; D.C. Code, sec Sec. 2209 Termination of e.w Code l-62J 198S 3 N l. Code s 1-623. S (1988 &amp;lt; New, O.C Code lt; e 1-623.9 (1988 St A poliey pure~ased under sec~ion 2205 shall contain a provision, approved by e Mayor, providinq a~ insurance on an employee ends 1 month after separation from the District or after discontinuance of pay, with provision for temporary e~tension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to an individual policy of life insurance under conditions approved by the Mayor b) An employee in a group life insurance plan under section 2205 who 1s removed or suspended Without pay and later reinstat~ or restored to duty on the grounds that the removal or suspension was unwarranted or unjustified may, at the employee's option, enroll as a new employee or have e §mployee coverage restored, with appropriate adjuostmen'ts mace in contributions anc claims, to the same ex~ent anc effect as ou9h the removal or suspension had not taken place Sec. 2.210. Employee deductions; withholdings; New, D. l payntents a) During each pay period in which the employee or annuitant is insur~ under a policy of insurance purchased by e District under section 2204, an amount determined by e Mayor shall be withheld from the compensation of e employee or the annuity of the annuitant as his or her share of the coost of the group life inosurance benefits purchased under se:tion 2205. The amount Withheld from an employee or annuitant paid on other than a biweekly basis shall be determined at a proportional rate adjusted to the nearest cent b) During each pay period in which an employee receiving disability compensation benefits pursuant to title XXIII is insured under a policy of group life insurance purchased by the District under section 2205, an amount determined by the Mayor Shall be withheld from the disability compensation benefits of the indiVidual as his or her share of the cost of the group insurance c) There shall be paid by each annuitant who received his or her benefits as a lump sum payment an amount equal to the cost of the life insurance plan less the amount of tne District contribution to the life insurance plan for the annuitant Sec. 2211. District contributions Ear each pay period in which an employee or annuitant is insured under a policy of insurance purchased under section 2205, a sum computed at a rate determined by the ~ayor shall be contributed from the appropriation or fund that i s used,to pay the employee or annuitant to the carrier of the plan that the employee or annuitant has selected. This sum shall not exceed one-half the amount that i s Withheld from the compensation of the employee or annuitant under s e ction 2210 for basic life insurance coverage. Cod 3' 1-623. 1 1988 s\ Nev, D.C Code, se 1-623.11 (1988 SU "Sec. 2212 Annual accoun":inq epor 3 a Each policy purchas.a by the Oiseric unce s.c~ion 2205 shall proviae for an accouneinq b y co~pa~y f:ooll. yhich 'to 1:'1.surance a3 purc."ased to t.l::I. Mayor no t l .tar 't 90 days .fter 't cl o f each policy y.a:o The accoun ing sha ll s.t for in form .pproved by 't Mayor 1) Tha ~ounts o f premiums actually acc=ued under the policy from its data of issue to the end o e policy ye.r l 2) The total of all mor a11ty and o~er cl.im ch.rges incurred for that period l .nd 3 Tha amounts of the company' s expans e. and risk charqe. incurrad for thit perlod b) Each con~r.ct en~sred into under ssc icr C5 ll requi r s tha co~pany t o ell ?Urni$h reasonabla repor s as the M.yo r 4etermines to b. necessarj to enabl e the Distric to c. rry OU~ i~s !unc~i ons und.r this titl and 2 rmit the Mayor to xamine recorda of e company as may be necessary to carry out the purpo ses of this title Sec. 2213 Speci a l cont1n&amp;lt;;a ncy reserve a An excass of the total o f 'Iecti o n 2212 a 1 over the 'lUll. of 'Iec~ions 2212 a and (a)(3) shall ba hald by tha cC3pany lssuing the pollcy as a speci.l contingenc y resarve to be u sed. by e company only for charqa. under t e po licy purchasad under sec~ion 2205 b) Th. special contln;en~y reserve Shall b.ar interest at a rate determined in advance of e.ch pol i~y period by the company from which the in'lurance was pu rc~a5ed under section 2205 .and approv. d by_ the Mayor all bei nq c onSistent with e rates q.ner.lly used by the c o mpany fr om which the in.u r nce s purcha.ad unde r sect~on 2 205 fo r similar f unds held under other g r oup li!e in.uranc. pelicie c Wh.n e Mayo r dete~in.s at the amount o f the special cont lngency reserve Is sufficient to provide fo r adverse f luctuatlons in future charqas under the po licy any funds in exc o f th.t amount may be used to incr benefits, to r.duce premiums or both, or may ba d.posi ted in the Cenaral Fund of the 01.trict d) When a policy purchasad under section 220 5 is discontlnued, a n y balance remalnin; in the special c ontinqency re a.rve .fter all charqas h ave ba.n p ai d sh.ll ba d epo'lit.d in Cene r. l t und o f t e Oi stri ct Sec. 2214. Rules eliq~blli.ty a l I n orde r t o e nsure proper implementa tio n o f the q roup life in.urance under s.ction 2 20S by Oc~ob.r 1, 1987, the Mayor may issua temporary rules r eqardinq the q r oup life insu rance ha t shall no t b subject to Councll revi.e 10 a Cod a. H 1- 6: 3 l9Se s a Cod r 1-62 1988 Sew, D.C Coda. sa, 1- 623.\4 (19S8 1 !h~5e temporary rules shall r~ai e!!ec~ only ur.t!l :he proposed rules ~ave been approved or been deemed approved =y e Council in accordance wi~ subsection (b) o is section b) The Mayor ahall, pursuant to ti~le I of ~e District of Columbia Administrative ?rocedure Act, approved October 21, 1969 (92 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, SO!!C. 1-1501 et issuO proposed rules to i~plement e provisions of tbis ti~le. T.he proposed rules shall be submitted to e Council for a 45-day period of reView, excluding Saturdays, sundays, legal holidays d days of Council recess. I! the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed r~les rn whole or in part by resolution wi~~n this 45-day reView period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved e) The 9roposed l lles "hall pre"cribe 1.e ti:ne, manner, and conditions under which employees are eliq~b:e for coverage. The proposed rules may exclude employees on the basi" of the nature and type of employment or conditions of employment "uch as short-te~ appOintment easonal employment, intermittent or part-time employment, and employment of a similar nature, but shall not exclude an employee or group of employe e s solely on the basis of the hazardous nature of employment f) SO!!ction 2602 (D.C. Code, sec. 1-627.2) is amended by stl:"ikinq the period after "all employees" and insertinq the phrase except that the Civil Service Retirement "ystem pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 6331 shall not be applicable to employees first employed af er September 30, 1967 q) New sections 2603 through 2612 are added to read a follows Section 2603. District ret~rement benefit The Di!'Strict Shall pl:"ovide retll:"ement benefits to a ll employees first employed after September 30, 1997, who would o~,erwise have been covered under the Civil SO!!rvice Retirement System pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 8331 except those specifically excluded by law or by rule Sec. 2604. Definitions For the purpose of sections 2605 throuqh 2612 e term 1 Creditable service" means the period of employment to be recoqnized for purpo"es of eliqibility fOl retirement benefits, which shall be "et forth for in rules promulqated by the Mayor pursuant to Section 2607 2 Detention officer" means an employee who is not covered by the Police and Fire Retirl!ment System hose dutie!'S are primarily the investiqation, apprehension, or detention of individuals su"pected or convicted of offenses aqain"t, or Violation of, the laws of the United State" or the District and who"e duties may require frequent contact supervision, inspection, traininq, employment, care, 11 D. C. Co ec 1 1988 l D.2 Cod gt 1-627.3 (1988 f,e le D. C Code, s a 1-627.4 (1988 SUI t:an$Portat~on, or rehabilitation of individ~ais in detention. The term "detention officer" includes A) Employees engaged in the activ:ties listed ~ove who are transferred to a supervisory or administrative position B) Employees of e District of Columbia Department of Corrections, its in u~rtries and. utilitieos who are engaqed in the activities listed ~ove eC) Employees of the Department of E~an Services who are engaqed in the activities listed above; and D) Members of e Board of ?arole, parole officers, and probation officers who are engaged in t~e activities listed ~ove 3 Employee neans an indiVidual first employed by e government of e District a=ter Septe~er 30, 1987, who would have been covered by the Civil Serv~ce Retirement System pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 8331 had e employee been first employed prior to October 1, 1987 4 Internal Revenue Code" means e Internal Revenue Code of 1986 Sec. 2605. District retirement benefits program The retirement benefits program of the District shall consist of 1) A defined bene·fit plan, as provided in An Act to provide for the general welfare by establishing a system of Federal old-age benefits, and by enabling the several States to make more adequate provision for aged persons, blind persons, dependent and crippled children, maternal and child welfare, public health, and e administration of their unemployment compensa~ion laws, to establish a Social.Security Board to raise r"'v",nu and for other purposes, approved AQqust 14, 1935 (49 Stat. 624; 4 U.S .C. 301 at seq Social Security Act 2) An employee deferred comp",nsation plan pursuant to s ection 457 of the Internal Revenue Code qoverned by the Deferred Compensation Act of 1984, effective September 26, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-118; D.C. Code, sec. 47-3601 et seq and 3) A defined contribQtion plan pursuant to section 401(&amp;amp of the Internal Revenue Code Sec. 2606. Contracting aQthority The Mayor may select 1 or more contractors to provide services as may be part of the defined contribQtion plan Qnder section 2605(3 Any contract under section 2605(2) and (3) s hall be in accordance with the prOVisions of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act, effective february 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1181.1 et se Sec. 2607. Eliqibility. N w Cod 1-627 1988 i" New, D.C Code 1-627.6 (1988 U New. D.C. Code s 1-627.7 (1988 su a) An ~mployee is eliqible to partic~pa~e in e deferred compen~ation plan under section 2605(2) upon commencement of employment with the District b) An employee is eliqible to participate in e defined cont=ibution plan under section 2505(3) upon e completion of 1 year of employment rith the Ois1::rict Sec. 2608 Rules; eliqibility In order to ensure proper implementation of e District retirement program under section 2605 by October 1, 1987, the Mayor may issue temporary rules reqardinq e District ret1rement proqram t shall not be subject to Council review. These temporary rules shall r~main in ffect only until e proposed rules have been approved or been deemed approved by e Council in accordance subsection (b)-Of is sectien b) The Mayor shall, pursuant to title I of the D1strict of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et issue proposed rules to implement the proviSions of this title. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 4S-day period of review, eXcludinq Saturdays, Sundays, 1eqa1 holidays, and days of Council recess. If e COUDcil does not approve or disapprove e proposed rules, in Whole or in part, by resolution within this 4S-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved c) The proposed rules shall prescribe the time, manner, and conditions under which employees are eliqible for coverage. The proposed rules may exclude employees on the basis of the nature and type of employment or conditions of ~loyment such as short-term appointment, seasonal employment, intermittent or part-time employment, and employment of a simila~ nature, but sh~ll not exclude a~ employ~e o~ qroup of employees sol~ly on the b~sis Of haz~~dous natu~e of employment Sec. 2509. Cont~ibutions The District and e~ch employee sh~ll cont~ibute to the defined benefit plan under section Z50S(1} the social security amounts mandated by federal law b) Each employee may Voluntarily contribute to e deferred compens~tion plan under section 2605(2) in amounts not exceedinq the limits set by section 457 Of the Inte~~al Revenue Code c) The District shall contribute an amount equal to not less than 7% of the base salary of each employee participatinq in the defined contribution plan under section 2605(3 The Di s trict contribution shall be made not less frequently than quarterly and shall be placed in the Section 401(a) Trust established by section 2611. M(d) In addition to the cont~ibution under subsection (c) of this section, the Oi st~ict Shall contribute no less 13 Ne S Codt 1-627 3 (1988 SL New, D. C C&amp;lt;&amp;gt;de, 5" 1-627. 9 (1988 ~U an ~n additional .5% Ot a de tion of e ba~e sala=7 e&amp;amp;e~ pay period to Section 401(&amp;amp;} Tr~st established ~y seet10n 2611 Sec. 2610. Ve.tinq a l Th_ e=ploy.e s contr~u~1on t o e deferred compensati on plan under 'ec~!on 2605(2 and the ea~i nq, on o contributions shall vest i~.diately b) The District contributions to the defined contribution p lan under s ection 2605{J the earni nqs on District contribut ions shall vest when en emp loyee comp l etes 5 y r s of c r ed itable se rvice with e Oistrlc die o r l:&amp;gt;eeome3 e:11::1 t 1.&amp;lt;:1 to disability benefits under e Soc ial Securlty Act. H(e } !he emplo yee's i nterest in e benefits in e defined ~ontribution ~lan shal: be for:e:~ed ~pon se~a='t:o~ f:o~ employment if separati on oc curs prior to completi o n o f 5 ye.rs of creditable service. An employee in a de!ined contribution pl&amp;amp;n ~der section 2505(3 who is removed o r suspended wi~~out pay and l ater reinstated or restored to duty on e qrounds that the removal or suspension was unwarr.nted o r unjustified shall be entitled to res~e immediate ly parti cipation 1n e rle!1ned eo~tri~utien ~lan, v1 appropriate increase ade 1n e Secti on 401(a) Trust to re!l ect e Oistr lct contribut ions at would have been ~ade had the emp loyee not been removed o r suspended An employee who i. othe~ise separated from e mp loyment and is later reinstated to e mp loyment with the District within 1 year of separation shall be enti t led to i mmediately r .sume partlci?ation in e de!1ned contribution plan S c. 26:1. Esta.bl s r;lent and lId::linist r tion o f Sect ion Olta) Trust a) There shall ~e establi,hed an irrevo able tn.:st a11ed the S.I t.1on 401 (a r'rust, that. shall b e managed $0 as t o be exempt from income tax under section 501 a) of the Int e rna l Revenue Cada. The f unds contributed by the Ois tr ict under the de f ined con tribu ti on plan of section 2605 3 shall be p h ed in the Sec t ion 401(&amp;amp Trust. The asse t s of the S t10n 401(a) Tr4 s t shall be administered by the Mayor, M(b) The cost of any contrac t for prOVisions ot se rvices as ~ay be part o f the defined ontribution plan unde r 2605(3) shall be paid solely from e a.s ta Qf tbe Sectio n 401(a) Trust o fro a f und o r funds estabUshed to adlnlnister the de f ined contr ibution p l an S"c. 2612. Payment. of bene Hts The payment of benefi t s unee r the i .ernent p r oqrarn s under sections 2505 2) and 3 sha ll be in e cordanca ith the appUcable provis ion s o f se t iol'ls 401 a and 457 of the nte r nal Re'/anu e Code Na J C de o 9S8 0 Code, S 1- 6Z l 1988 Sl N O.C Co&amp;lt;J 5" 1- 621.12 (1988 au (h Sec ion lil7 1 D.C. Colie sec l~Sla.li l » is amenced to read as follows Not i ls d.i q a ny provis ions of ei:;les ;CC XXII. o r XXVI 0 the contrary le health li~e amp;nd retirement proqrams .u~'lori~.d =y les e title, are p r oper subjects 0: col:eeeive bargaining under ~s ction Sec. J. This act shall taxe e!Iect aLte r ;I. JO- day period of Conqressional review following approval ~y le ~ayor (or In ~e avent o f veto by l. Mayor actio n b y Council of the District of Co lumbia to OVerride the veto p~ovided i n section S02 {e l of the District of el vernment and Oov.rr~ent.l R.orqani~.tion Act, approved December 2 1973 (87 Stat. 813; O. 1- 233 lt 1 » Council of the Di s trict of 7 MaYOr Oi U'ict of Col\.l1!lDia r--r i'ro'JEIl July 1 1987 J A J. C sec l 88 i c0ttl00a Oft COU:-ICn. OF TKE Disnucr OF COLUMBIA Co ci1 Period Sev_ RECORD OF OFF!CIAL COUNCIL VOTE CCCKI!'T NO z C "CrICH o r: VOIC VOTl: IIOC Or&amp;lt;lod Oft </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
