<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-29">
  <num type="law">7-29</num>
  <heading type="short">D.C. Income and Franchise Tax Conformity and Revision Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1987-10-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-29.pdf">D.C. Law 7-29</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 5097</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-29, “D.C. Income and Franchise Tax Conformity and Revision Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-183, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 16, 1987 and June 30, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 17, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-51 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRlCT OF COLUKBIA NOTICE O. C. LAW 7-29 C. Inco me dnd Franchise Tax Conformity and Re'/ision Amend ;nent Act of 1987 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columb ia Self_ Go,ernment and Go ver nmental ReorganiZJtion Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Cauncll af the District of Columbi dopted 8 il l No. 7-183 on first and second readings, June 16, 1987, and June 30,1987, respective l y. FollolOing the signature of the Kayar on July 17, 1937, this legislation IOdS as.signed Act 7 51. publish- ed in the August 7, 1987. edition of the.!l f Register Vol. 34 page 5097) and tnnsmitted to Congress on Ju ly 21. 1987 for d 3~-day review, in accordance lOith Section 602{c){l) of the Act, The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 3D day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. LalO 7 29, effective October 1, 1987 L ~lD A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30·day Congressional R~vi~1O PeriOd: J u 1 y 21,22,23,24.27.28,29,30.31 i\ugust 3.4.5.6 7 September 9.10,11,14,15,16,17.18.21.22.23,24,25.28.29,30 D lAW 7 -2 9 OCT 0' 1997 AN ACT D.C.ACT 7 -51 IN THE COUNC I L OF TH~ DI STRICT OF COLU~B[A JIlL 1 7 1997 To amend the Di strict. of Columbia Income and Franchise Ta x Act o t 194 7 ~nd the Distr Ict of Columbia In coro~ and neh iu· Tall Confor:nity Ac t o f L983 to 'con t inue conformity on a l imited basis with t he Tax Refo r m Act of 1986; to replace the ro bracket amount wtth an increased standard ded uct ion; t o increase personal exemptions; t o 10 e r t3X rat l to pe nnie a deduction for net ope r ating l o sses; t o r edllce the franchiae tax sur tax; to amend the treatment of suochapter S corporations: to continue an i ncome exclusion for feder/.l d nd Di. tr ict reti rees; t.o clarify the c"lcu l ation o f the dependen t care credit; t o con form t o an exemption i n t he franChis tax and to ~ke Othe~ change" in the inccme a nd f nmch i s e tal{ p r ovisions 8E IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCl~ OF THE DISTR1CT OF COLUMBIA That thlS act may be c ited as the Dis tric t; of CoiUlllbia [ncame and Franch ise Tax Con fo r mi ty lind Revi sion Amendment Act o f 1987 S e c 2. The Ois tr iet of COlumbia Income a nd F r anch ise TIlX Act o f 19&amp;lt;17, appr oved July 16 1947 (61 Stat. 33 1, D. C COOe, s e c 4 7 180 1.1 e t s~q i, amended a!l toUo we d){l) Tltl' 1 ection 4 (D C Code leC. 4 '1 180 1.4) Js amended by adding d new &amp;gt;lube.etion [bb- l to relld a s follows bb-l) The t e rm I n ternal Revenue Code of 1986 means the Internal Re venue Code of 1986. approve d October 22 1986 (100 Stat. 2085; 26 u.s.c. 1 et seg 2 T lt1e 1, sectlon 4 jl k s t u v nd (all D .C. Code. s e c 47-1 801. 4 (10 ll l9 20 21 22 ll and 27) is end~d by st rlking th phr ll se "Inter na l Revenue Code o f 1954" o,;he rever it appea rs and inserting the phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" in its place D. C, axle €C 47-1801.4 (1988 su p 3) Title 1, section 4 (p D C. Cooe, sec 47-1801.4(16 i' amended to read a, fo llo.,s 1 Th e term corporation includes any trus t, IIssociation, joint stock compllny, small busine ss co po~at i or. liS defined in section 1371 o f t ne Internal Revenue Coce of 19!14, appr oved Septembe r 2, 1958 72 Stat. 1650: 26 U.S.C. sec 137L 1n effect as of Oc t ober 18, 1982. S cor po~atlon lis defined in section 1361(a of the Inte r nal Revenue Code of 1986, partnership that is claued or should "oe clas6ed as a corporation fo r purpose o f federal income t a xation a ny enti ty organized under t he District of Columbi a Professional Corpor a tion Act a pproved Dec emb. r 10 1 971 (85 Stat. 576 D. C. Cod e, sec 29 601 et seq or a fore lgn professional corpo r ation that has obt alned a ce rt ificate of authority under section 14 of the District o f Columbia Pr ofessional Corporation Act. approved December 10 1971 (85 S tat. 576. D.C. Cod e, s e c 29 11 0 1 e" sea to render p r ote"ional services in the Oil tric t f o r any taxable year beqinning lifter Decemb&amp;lt;er 31, 1984 4) Title 1, s ect ion 4 (z D .C Code. sec 47 .1801.4(26) is amend ed to reed as follows z) The tenn "sta ndard deduction means A 2,000 in the case of a return f iled by a single individ ual, by a head 01 househol d, by a surviv ing spouse or joint ly by husband lind wit 8 1.000 in the ease o f a married person fil inq separately: o r C) In the cale of an individual who ia it resident, ilS defined in sUbsection (q) of this ~ection fo r less than a full 12· month taxable year, the amounts spe ci fied in subparaq raphs (A) and (8) a t thi s pa r agraph prora t ed by the number of months that the individual was a res i d ent 5) Title 1, section 4 (D C. Code ec. 41·1801 .4 is amended by addinq new subsec t ion (ff) at the end to read aa follows Neff) The tenn "blind ana a taxpaye r hoae cen t-rll1 vlaual acuity does not exceed 20/200 i n the better eye i h c o r recting lenses or whose visual acuity i s qr.ate r than 20 200 but is accOIIIpenied by II. limitati on in the field o f vision !uch that the wide a t diameter o f the v isual field sub tends a n a ng l e no g reater than 20 deq rees b Title 2, section 1 (D.C. Code s e c. 4 7-1802.l) is amended as fallows 1) ay striking the phrase "Inter nal Revenue Cod e o f 195 4" wherever it appe a r s and inSert l nq the phrase "Internal Revenue Code o f 1986" in it s p l ace; lind (2) 8y adding a new SUbsection (12) to reed as follows D.C. COde. sa 47- 1802 1 (1988 stipp 12) An organization described in section ~Ol (c 25) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 c)(1) Title 3, section 2(a D.C. Cooe, sec. 47-1803.2(a is amended by striking the phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1954" wherever it appears in the first 2 sentences and inserting the phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" in its place 2) Title 3, section 2(a)(2)(12 D C. Code, sec. 47-1803.2(a}(2)(L}) is a mended by striking the phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1954" wherever .j.t appears and inserting the phrase "Internal Revenu e Code of 1986" in its place 3) Title 3, section 2(a)(2 D.C Code, sec 47-1803 .2( a 2 is amended as follows Al By amending subparagraph (N) to read as follows N) Pension, military retired pay, annuity lnc ome, or survivor beneflts received from the Oistrict of Col~bia or the federal government by persons who are 62 years of age or older by the end of the taxable year, except that i) The exclusion shall not exceed the lesser of $3,000 or the actual amount of the penSlOn, military retired pay, or. annuity received during the taxable yea rs; and ii) The pension, military retired pay or annuity is otherwise subject to taxation under this article and (B) By adding a new subparagraph (O) to read as follows 0) Prizes from lotterie s daily number games, bingo, and raffles awa rded pursuant to the Law to Legalize Lotteries, Daily Numbers Games, and Bingo and Raffles for Charitable Purpos e s in the District of Co lumb ia, effectlve ~Iarch 10, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-172; D.C. Code sec. 2-2501 et se1. and 22-1516 et seT'} 14 Title 3, Section 2 b D.C. Code, sec. 47-1803.2(b) is amended by striking the phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1954" wherever it. appears and inserting t.he phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" in its place 5) Title 3, section 3(a)(1 D C. Code, sec. 47-1803.3( a I}) is amended as follo s A) By strlking t.he phrase including the ent.ire amount. expended for meals and lodging and (E) By adding a new sentence at the end to "Any business expenses allo ed under this p a ragraph shall be subject to the same limitations as provided tor in the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 3 D.C. eoce, sec. 47 803.2 (1988 suw D.C. Cede, sec. 47-1803.3 (1988 SUFfl.l (6) Ti~le 3 ection 3 4 2 D .C. Code ec. 4 7 1903.3(a){2» is a"'end ed by strikinq t.he phra.e "In tern a l Revenue Cooe o f 1954" wherever i t appears and l.nserti ng the phrase "Internal Revenue COO, o f 1996" in its place 7) Ti tle J, section 3( a){3 gt C. Cod e sec. 4 7 1903 3(4 3» is amended by striking the phuse "Inte r nlll Re v en ue Code of 1954" whereve r it appe"r~ and inserting the ph res rnternal Revenue Cod, of 1996" in its place S) TiUe 3 section 3(a 4 D .C. Cooe, sec 4 7 -1 80 3. J(a 4 }} i s ame nded 118 folio ws A By arnend in9 3ubparagraph (c l to read a3 follo C) or bu,ine3 if t h e shipwrec k, o r o ther 'el paraqraph 4 Of p r ope rty not connectea with a trade 10 3 ell arise f r cn fire. storm casualty, or from theft and By IItrik i ng t he last 2 sentences o f 9 Title 3, s e c ti o n 3 a 5) [D C Code, sec 4 7 1903.3(4 5» is amended t o read a~ f ollows 5) Debt a3cer t a ln,d to be worth l 3. and d etermined as deductible under .ection 166 and r e lated sections o f the Interna l Revenu. Code of 1986 10) Title 3, sec tion 3( a 7 D.C Code sec 4 7-1S03.3(al(7» is amended by Itrik ing the last sentence in ite ent i r et.y ll Ti tle 3 ec t10n 3 a 9 D C. Code sec 4 7 1S03. 3 a 9 is amende&amp;lt b y Strikinq t h e phra3e "Sec tion 231p) ot the Federal Internal Revenue Cod e wherever it appears and i nsert.ing the phrase Mseetion 404 o f the I nterna l Revenue Code o f 1966" in its place 12) Title 3, secti o n 3 a 11 D. C. Code see. 4 7- 180J .3(a)II1 is amended by addinq a n e w sen tenc e at t he end to read a s fol lows Not hing: contained in t h is lubll:lction s h a ll be cone trued t o exempt any salary o r o ther compensation t or pe r e o nal services from ta xation under title 6 of thi$ ac t 13) Title 3 ect i on 3(a} (12 D.C. Code, 3 QC 4 7-1803 3(a 12» is amended by s triking: the phrase "Inte rnal Revenue Code of 1 954" wherever it appears and insert ing the phrase In te r nal Revenue Code o f 1986" in its p l ace l 4) Title 3, sec tion 3 a 13 D .C. Code. s ec 47-1603 3( a 13 is amended b y s trikinq the phrase "In t e r na l Revenue COO e ot 195 4 wherever t appear ll a nd ineerting the ph rase "In terna l Revenue Code of 196 6 i n its p l ace 1 5) Title section 3(oll (D C Code ec 4 7- 1803.3 a i a amended by add ing new paraqraph (14) at the end t o read as follows 14) In computing the net income of a corporation, an unincorporated busineS or a financ1al 1nst.itution, there shall be allowed a deduction for net operating los ses, in the Same manner as allowed under section 172 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and as cepor1-ed on any federal tax return for the same taxab le period, except that nO net operating losses may be carried back to any ye a r ending be fore January 1, 1988. H 16) Title 3, section 3(b D.C. Code, sec. 47-l803.3(b is amended by striking the phrase "Internal R venue Cooe of 1954 wherever lt appears and insertin9 the pr.rase Internal Revenue Code of 1986" in i ts place 17) Title 3, section 3(c D.C. Code, sec. 47-1803.3(c» is amended by striking the phrase "zero br a cket amount" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "standard deduction" in its place d) Title 4, section 4 (D.C. Code, sec 47 1804.4) is amended by $triking the phra se "Section 44 of the Federal Internal Revenue Code" and inserting the phrase "section 453 of the Inter nal Revenue Code of 1986" in its place e 1) Title 5, section 1(e D.C. Code, sec. 47-1805.1(e» is amended by striking the phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1954" wherever it appears and inse rting the ph rase "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" in its place 2j Tit.le 5, section 2(aj (D.C. Code, sec. 47-1805.2(1 is amended to read a$ follows a) Every nonresident of the District receiving income subject to tax pursuant to this article a nd every resident of the District, except a fiduciary, who is required to file a feder a l return under the provisions of section 6012 of t.he Internal Revenue Code of 1986 3) Title 5, section 2(b D.C. Code, sec. 47-1805.2(2 b 1'1 amended to read a s follows b 1) Every individual, if single, or if married and not living with spouse, for whom he or she acts, having met the filing requirements of section 6012 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 2) Every individua l, if married and living with spouse for whem he or she acts, having met the filing requirements of section 6012 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, except that if the fiduciary elects to file a separate return, t he provisions of $ection 6012 of the Interna l Revenue Code of 1986, relating t.o filing requirements for separate returns, shall be fallowed 3) Every estate for which he or $he acts, the gross income o f which for t he t a xable year i s in excess of its personal exemption of $885 for taxable years beginni n g after December 31, 1986 1,025 for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1987 1,l60 for taxable yea rs beginning after December 31, 1988 1,270 for taxable ye a rs beginning 5 D.C. Cede, sec. 47-1804. 4 (1988 supp D.C. Cede, se 47-1805. 1 (1988 SUFf D.C. Cede, sec 47-1805.2 (1988 supp fter December 31, 1989 nd $1,370 for tax~ole years beginning after December 31, 1990 f)(ll Title 6, section 2 (D.C. Code, sec. 47-1806.2) D.C. Cede, sec. is amended to read ~s follows 47-1806.2 "Sec. 2 In the case of a resident, the exemptions (1988 supp.1 provided by this section shall be allowed as deductions in computing taxable income 0) An exemption shall be granted for the taxpayer ~nd an additiona l exemption f or the spouse of the taxpa yer if the spouse, for the calendar year in whiCh the taxa ble year of the taxpayer begins, has no gross income and is not the dependent of another taxpayer c) There shall be allowed an additional exemption for a taxpaye r who qualifies as a head of hous e hold d) There shall be allowed an additional exemption for a taxpayer who is blind at the close of his or her taxable year, and an additional exemption fo~ the spouse of the taxpayer if the spouse is blind at the close of the taxable year of the taxpa yer and, if the spouse, for the calendar ye ar in which the taxabl e year of the taxpayer begins, has no gross income and is not the dependent of a nother taxpayer, except that iE the spouse dies during such taxable year the determination regarding blindness shall b e made as of the time of dea th e) There shall be allowed an additional exemption for a taxpayer ho has attained the age of 65 before the close of his or her tax~ble year, and a n additional exemption Ear the spouse of the taxpayer if the spouse has attained the age of 65 before the close of his or her taxable year and, if the spouse, for the calendar year in hich the taxable year of the taxpayer begins ha s no gross income and is not the dependent of another taxpaye r £)(1) There shall be allowed an addi t ional e xemption for each dependent A) Whose gross income for the calendar year in hich the year of the taxpayer begins is less than $885 for t a xable years b eginning aft"r December 31, 1986, less than $1,025 for taxable y"ars beginning after December 1, 1987, less than $1,160 for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1988, less than $1,270 for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1989, and less than $1,370 for taxable years beginning aft"r December 31, 1990; or H(B) \l&amp;lt;no is a child of the taxpayer and who: H (i) Has not attained the age of 19 at the close of the calendar year in which the taxable ye a r o f the taxpayer begins; or iil Is a student 2) No exemption shall be allowed under this subsection for any dependent who has made a joint return with hi s or her spouse for the tuxable year beginning in the 6 Enrolled original calendar y~ar in ~hich th~ taxable yea r of the taxpayer beg ins J) t'o r purpose of t)-u.s sub ction A The tenn ~chi.ld eao~ child as define d 1 0 section 151(e 3) of the Intern&amp;lt;ll Revenue Code of 1986 8) The tenn "studen t~ me&amp;lt;l ns student as defin~ in sectio~ 1 51 4) o f the I nternal ~evenue Cod e of 1986 g) In the case of a retu r :1 made for a fraction&amp;lt;ll part o f II taxa ble year, the personal exemptions shall be redlJced to droounts th t bear the same ratio t o the fll ll a x emptlonll p r ov l ded as the number of months in the period for hich the r e turn is made bear to l2 monthll h) In the cas e of an 1ndlv id IJal for h(Xll a deduction IJnder thl.s ~ectior; i. allolOlible to another ta xpayer for 1I taxable yea r i n wh ich the taxab l e year beg i nni ng in the ca h:ndar year in IoIhich the individual's taxable year begins, the exempt 1an amount appl i cable to t he individual for his or her taxable year shal l be ze ro i) for purposes o f this section the dedlJct ion f o r personal exemptions shall be as f o llows l) for t a xable ye a r s beginning a ft er Decllmber 31. 1 966 885 2) For t a xab le yea r s beginn ing after December 31, 1987 l,025 3) Fo r taxable year. o.ginn i ng after Oecember 31. 1988 l,160 4 For taxable years beginning afte r Decembe r 31, 1989 1.270; and 5) r"or taxable years beg inning after Dece!ober 3 1, 1990 1,370 2 ritle 6, section 3 (D C. Code, sec 4 7-180 6.3 (a i s amended to read as fo llo",s Sec 3 a)(l) I n the case at a ta xable yesr billginninc; a fter December 31, 1986, there is imposed on the i.~ncome of e very resident a tax determined 1n wi th t he fol l o wing tablel is The tax 1" Ove r 10 000 but no t over $20 000 6\ of-ehe~xable income 600 plus 8% o f th e exces s over $10,000 Over $20,000 1,400, plus 10 \ o f the excess over $20,000 2) In thO! case of a taxable year be91nnin9 after December 31. 1987. t her e is i mposed on the taxlIt&amp;gt;le Lncome o f every re,ident a tax dete rmine d i n accordanc~ with the tollo",ing table' 7 D.C. Caee, sec 4i- 1S06.3 (1"88 sl:pp oll ~d Or!g1na1 If the t.axable i~come 1.5' Not. over ~IO, OOO Ove r $10,000 but not ovar S20,000 ThO t.ax is, 6% oTthetaMble i ncome. S600, plus 8% o f the excess over SI0 000. Ove r S20,OOO S l,400, plus 9.5% of the excess OVe r S20,OOO 3) Tl.t!e 6, section 5(c D C. Code, s ec. 47-1806 .4 (c») is amended by striking the phrase "sect.ion 44A of t.he Internal Ravenue Code of 195 4 henever i t appears and i ns erting the phrase "sect ion 21 of the Int.ernal Reve~ue Code of 1986" in its place 4 ti t le 6, sectior. 5 e)(1 D .C. Code, see 4 7 18 0 6.4(c I is amended by inserting at the end the phrase r ega r dless o f t he amount o t the credit a ctually used to Offset tederal tax liability 5) Title 6, section 5 (D .C. Code. sec. 47-1806.4) is amended by addi ng a ne~ s ubsect ion dl t.o read as !ollo~s d 1 th e amount of tax payable under this title by a resident af the District in respe ct to the taxable year ,hall be reduced by a lo~ im:arne c r edit designed to make the District's income tax threshold equal to the federal income tax threshold. r or purposes of this sub.section, the term "tax threshold means t h e point at wh i eh a ta payer begins t o cr inc-eme tax aft r allowance ot the stlHldard deduction and 11.11 personai exemptions to ~hic-h the taxpayer is ent i tl e d but befo r e application of any itemi~ed deductions or cradi ts. Tht credit shall be calCulat ed in aceor&amp;lt;:1ance it.fo a table p r eserihed by the Mayor 2) The cred it. provided for in panlgraph (1) of thl.s subsection shal not be al1~ed to any resident ~ho has a federal tax liabili ty dete rmined in accordance ~ith section 55 of the Internal Revenue Code o f 198 6 I n no event shall the c redit allowed under paragraph (I) at this subsection exceed ~he amount o t the tax other~ise due wit.hout reference to t his section 1)0) Title 7 ection l c D .C. Code. sec. 47-180 7.1 1 ») i. amended by striking the phrase "occurring after September 30 198 4 2) T itle 7, section 2(11 3 D C. Code, sec 4 7-180 7.2(a 3) is a mended by etriking the phras e "5 pe r cen t um of t.h t.a M determined under paragraph (2 and inse rting the phraae "5i of the t ax determined under paragraph (2) o f th1$ subsection. and that for any ta xable period after Septembe r 30, 198 7 the rate o f surtax ahall be 2 1/2 'i o f the tax de tennined under poragraph 2) of this subsect i on 8 :I.C, COde, sec 47-1806 4 (1988 s i D.C. COCe, sec 111)7.1 (1988 5uW.1 D.C. Cede, sec. 1807.2 (1988 s 1 (h)(l) Title 8, section 1 (D C. Code ec. 47-1808.1) i~ amended by striking the phrase other than a Sma ll Bus ines s Corpora tion as defined in section 1371 of the Internal Revenue COde of 1954, approved September 2, 1958 72 Sta t. 1650; 26 U.S.C. sec. 1371) making a n election under section 1372(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, approved September 2, 1958 (72 Sta t. 16501 26 U.S.C. sec. 1372(a in effect as of October 18, 1982, or an S Corporat~on a s defined in sect ion 1361(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, approved October 19, 1982 (96 Stat. 1669126 LS.C. sec. 1361(a 2) Title 8, section 2(b D.C. Code, sec. 47-180 8 .2(2 b is amended by striking the phrase occurring after September 30, 1984 3) Title 8, section 3(a)(3 D.C. Code, sec. 47- t808 3(a 3 is amended by str i king the phrase "5 per cent_urn of the taJl; determined under paragraph 2 and insert.ing the phrase 5% of the taJl; det.ermined under paragraph (2) of this subsection, and for any taJl;able period after September 30, 1987, the rate of surtaJl; shall be 2 1/2% of the tax determined under paragraph (2) of this subsection 4) Title 8, section 6 (D.C. Code. sec 47-1808 6) is amended by adding a new sentence a t the end to r e a d as follows The phrase a ccounting period" as used i n th is s ec t ion refers to the calendar or fiscal year of a partnership i) Title 9, section 10(a D.C. Code. sec. 47- 1809.10(a is amended by striking the phrase "Section 165 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954" wherever it a ppears a nd inserting the phras e section 401 of the I nternal Revenue Code of 1986" J.n i ts place j) Title 10, section 1(a 2 D C. Code, sec. 47-1810 1( a 2 is amended by striking the phrase "title III Section 2 (b 13 and insert i ng the phrase "ti tIe III, section 2( a 2 I in its place lt;J(l) Title 11, section 1 (D.C. Code, sec 47-1811.1) is amended by striking the phrase "Internal Revenue Code o f 1954" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "Internal Rev e nue Code of 1986" in its place 2) Title 11. section 2 (D.C Code, sec. 48-1811 .2) is amended by strO;ing the phrase "Internal Revenue Code o f 1954" wherever it appears and in se rting the phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" in its place 3) Title 11, section 4 (D.C. Code, sec. 4 8 -1811.4) is amend ed by striking the phrase I nternal Revenue Code o f 1954 whereve r it appears and inserting the phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" in its place 1)(1) Title 12, section 8(b)!I D.C. Code. sec. 4 7-1812.8 (b 1 is amended by s triking the phrase "Internal J.C. CCde iCc; 47- 1 808 1 (1988 Stlf } D.C ecce, soc 47-lBOil 2 (1988 SloW D.C. Code. soc 47-1803.3 (1988 sew D. C. Code, sec 1808.6 (1988 supp D.C. Code, sec 47-1809.10 (1988 su D.C. Code, sec. 47-1810 1 (1988 sUW D.C. Code, 5ec 47- 1811 1 (1988 SUW D.C. Code, sec. 48-1811. 2 (1988 suq&amp;gt D.C. Code, se 48--1811.4 (1988 sUW D.C. Caie, se 47-1312 .8 (1988 sqp Revenue Code of 1~5 4" Io'herever lts appell r s and inserti.ng the p hrase Interna l Revenue Cooe of 1996" in i t5 place 2) Title l2, sec tion S(ej(S D C. CO&amp;lt;:l.e, sec 4 7- 1912 8(e)(8» is amend e d t o read as fol10lo's a) An employee ehall be flntitlEtd to add itional Io'ltnholding exemptions under this subsect ion ~i th respect t o payment o f Io'age$ equal t o a number detennined by dividing by S685 for taxabl e yean; beginninq after Dece mber 31. 1986, S1.D2S fo r taxable years beginning afte r December 31. l~a7 Sl. 160 for tlnable years beginning after December 31. 1988 1,2 70 for taxable years beg inning after December 31, 1989, and $1 ,370 tor t a xab le years beginni ng af t e r December 31, 1990, the excess o f AI His or her estimated itemiz ed deduc t ions: o r R(S) The applicable standa r d de&amp;lt;luction a!DOunt specifie&amp;lt;1 in s ection 4 of title I 3) Ti t le 12, section 8 (i)(1 D C Code, sec. 47 UH2 8 i 1 » i a amended to r ead as f o l low i)(l) Eve r y person r es i ding o r domiciied in th Dist rict lit the timea prescri bed in paragraph (4 of thi s subsec tion shal l, at these time s make decla ration of his or her estimated taK fo r the taxab l e year if the perSOn c an reasonably be expected to receive g r oss income not a~bject t o the Io'ithholding p r ovi sions of t his secti on tha t wili result 1.n a t ax liability of more than S100 This requi r ement shall no t appl y to any elective o ff icer o f th e qovernme nt o f t he Uni ted States. o r any employee On the staff of a n elected officer i n the legislative branch o f t he govercnrnent o f the Unitsd States if the employee is a bona fide r esident of the state of relidence of the elected officer Or any offi ce r of the e xecu tive br a nch of the gove rnment Io'hole appointment to t he o ffice held by h i m or he r Io'a s by the Prel ident of the united States nd aUbjec t t o conf irmation by t h e Senat e of th Uni ted Statea, and Io'hose ten~ re of of fi c a i s at the pleaau re o f the Pr es i d e n t of the United S tat.,a or any Justice of the Supreme Cou rt o f t h Un ited States ~nless the offic rs o r Just i ces are dOMic i l e d within t he Distr ict at any time duri ng the taxable year 4 Title 12, s e ction 10{e D .C. Code, sec 47 -l812 10( e ») it a mended by striking the phras e "dete rmined ith in t he l aat santence of the subsection a nd inserting the phra se "determined i thin" in its p l ace. IS) Title 12 s ection 1 1(11 2 D C. Code, sec 41-1S12.11 (a 2 is amended 8 follolo's A) By striking the phrase fil ed by the taxpaye r in the firs t sentence and i nserti ng in its place f iled by the taxpayer o r such taxpayer is entit t ed t o d.,duc t a net op..ratinq loss car rybac k de termin..d pu rsuant to D. C. COde, sec. 47-1912. 10 (1988 s\lP9.1 D.C COOe, soc. 47-1812.11 (1988 $lQp sec~ion5 3(a)(14) and 3(b) of title III of this act and sectl.on 6511(d)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 n B) By striking the phrase a llowance of such credit or refund" and inser ting the phrase "allowance 0: t h e credit or refund, except that in the case of a credlt or refund that results from a net operating loss carryback, the 3 yea. l imitation shall not apply m) Tl.tle 13 section l(d D.C. Code, sec. 47-1813.1(d» is amended by striking the number "80" ana inserting the number "90" in its place Sec. 3. Section 8 of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Conformity Act of 1983, ef.tective October 8, 1983 (D C. Law 5-32; D.C Code, sec 47-1816,3 is amended as fol10' iS a By designating the existing section as subsection (a b) By striking the phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1954" wherever it appears and inserting t,he phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" in its place; and (c) By adding a new subsection (b) to read as £ollows b) On or before July 1, 1988, the Mayor sh"ll rep,n·t to Council concerning t axp&amp;lt;l yers who e t x liability exceeds the amount by which the i r t a xable income exceeds the tax threshold as defined in section 2(f)(4) of the District of Co lumbia Income and Franchi s e Tax Conformity and Revision Amendment Act of 1987 The report shall include 1) An assessment of the number ana income levels of the taxpayers affected 2) Methods for, and the revenue impact of eliminating these ta" liabilitie s~ and (3) The Mayor's recorrunendation as to what action, if any, S110uld be taken Sec. 4. Section 3(b 4) of title 3 of the Dis trict of Columb ~a Income and Franchise Ta x Act of 1947, approved July 16,1947 (61 Stat 331, D. C. Code, sec. 47-1803.3(b)(4») is repealed. Sec 5. Section 204 of title 2 of the District of Columbia Individuals Estates and Trusts Federal Conformity Tax Act of 1982, effective June 11, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-118; D.C. Code, sec. 47-1801.5 is amended as follows a Section 204 is redesignated as section lA of tl.tle 1 of the District of CollJlubia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947, approved July 16 1947 (61 Stat. 331, D.C. Code, sec. 47-1SU1.1a b) Subsection (a) is amended as follows: Or1g1!lal D.C. Cooe sec 47-1813 1988 su p D.C. COO Sec 47- 1816 3 (1988 suj:p Repaa led, D.C. Cooe, sec. 47-1803.3 (1988 SUW D.C. Cooe, sec. 47-1801. 5 (1988 SUW D.C. Code, sec. 47-1801.1a (1988 SUW 1) By strikil'.g the I;hrase The repeal ana l~serti~g in its place the phrase "Unless otherwi se provided by law, the repeal nd (2) By striking the phraee "a s heretofore amended c) Subsect ion (b) is amended by striking the p h rase "District of COlumbia Individuals, Estates, and Trusts Federal Conformity Tax Act of 1982 nd inserting in its plac e "repeal or amendmen t Sec. 6 a) The provi si ons of sections 2(a 1 2(a)(2 2( a 3 2(a)(4 2(b 2(c)(1 2(c)(2 2(c){3 2(c)(4 2( c ){6 2(c)(7 2(c)(8 2(c)(9 2(c 10 2(c)(1l 2(c 13 2(c)(14 2{c)(16 2(c)(17 2(d 2(e)(I 2( e 2 2{e){3 2(f){1 2{f){2 2{f){3 2(f)(4 2(h)(1 2(i 2(k 2(1)(1 2(1)(2 2(1){3 2( m 3, and 4 sha ll apply to taxable years ~eginning af t er December 31, 1986 b) The provisions of sections 2(c){IS) and 2(1)(5) shall apply to taxable years beginning fter December 31, 1987 c) The provisions of sections 2(9 1 2(9 2 2(h)(2 a nd 2(h)(3) shall apply to tax",ble period s beginning a fter Sept ember 31, 1987 d) The provisions of sections 2(c)(5 2(c){12 2( h 4 2( j 2(1)(4 5, 6, and 7 shall apply a s of the effective d a te of t h is act. Sec. 7. Severabil ity. The General Ru l e o f Severability Adoption Act of 1983 effective March 4, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-561 D.C. Code, sec. 47-6 01 is a pplic ab le to this act. Sec. 8. This act shall take effect after a 30-da y period of Congressional revi ew following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by th e Council of the District of Columbi a to override the ve t o) as provided in section 602(c 1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government a nd Governmental Reorganization Act, Note, D.C. ex sec. 47- 1801.4 -1802 1 180 3 -1803.3 1803 -1804 4 180S -180 5 .2 1806.2 1806 -1806.4 1808 -1809. 10 1811 -1812.8,-1813 1816.3 (1988 sUp app ~oyed Decembe~ 24, 1973 (8 7 S~at. 8ll: D. C. Code, sec 1-233 (0 1 Chai~man Council o f 0&amp;lt j2 if: Ois tflct of Columbia APPKlVID: July 17, 19a7 1 l t he Di strict of Col umbi a COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLCMBIA CO Utl cU Period ~vetl RECO AD OF OFFICIAL COU NCIL VOTE OOCKET NO l&amp;gt 3L Adopted FJ~lt Beading 6-1 6~87 VOICE VOTE �Oln li&amp;gt I'I SL oco 0 on rc&amp;lt;l o,:wfor d and Willian @ O C~I.L VOTE RESUI.T lI:l CTION &amp;amp; DATE: J:J VO ICE VOTE O'O'd '010 00 &amp;lt;lQuo.1 Adopted F i na l Reading 6- 30-8 7 Unanimous gt all pt:e s ent r c,o,LL VOTE RESlJLT:.co i7 6 7 If i m on Con, en, Cojen dar J CTlO N &amp;amp; DAlE gt J VO ICE VOTE c- 1I&amp;amp;e&amp;lt;&amp;gt on _OSl Sect. l 10 \M Co&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Joc Oa </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
