<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-36">
  <num type="law">7-36</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1987-10-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-36.pdf">D.C. Law 7-36</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 5321</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-36 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-221, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 16, 1987 and June 30, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 23, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-64 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>• I COU NCI L or TH[ DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOT Ie E D.C. L AI&amp;lt;I 7·36 "Precinct BOl/notary Cnanges ApprOHl and Pr ocedu ra l A. e nd_ent Ac t of 1987 Pu r su a nt to Section 412 o f t ~e Di str ict o f Colu~b la Self Gover nment and Go vernlllental Reorganization Act L. 93 _198 the Act the Cou ncil of the Dhtriet of Columbia ado pt e d Bill No. 7- 221 on first illnd second reading s, June 16, 1987 and J un e 30, 1987 r espe ctivel y. Follo wing the s ig nature o f the Ma yo r On July 23 198 1, th is legislatI o n was assigned Act 7- 64. publis hed In the August 14, 1987 edit io n of the Reg ister Vol. 34 page 5321) and transmitted t o Congress on July 29 1987 for 3D- day rev ie w. i /l Heard.nce wit h SH tion 60Z (e)(1) o f the Ac t. The Coun ci l o f the Distri c t of Col umbia hereby gives no tice th.t the lO _day Cong res sional Revie w Per iod ha, elpl red and therefore. cites this enact _ent a s O. C. law 7- 36 e ffecthe October 9. 1987 f OAVIO A. CLARr Ch air an of the Co ncl l Oate s Counted During the 3Q day ,Cong reSSi onal Review Pe rio d: J uly 29 30 3 1 AU gHt 3 4.5.6.7 S e~te. be r 9 .1 0 1 1, 14,1 5 16 11 18.21 22 ,23 ,24 25 .28 29 30 Dc tolber 1, 2 ,5.6 7 8 D,C, LAW 7-38 U UCTIYC OCT 0 91987 At: ACT D,C, ACT 7-64 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRI CT OF COLUMBIA JUL. 2 3 1907 To approve precinct boundary changes proposed by the Soa rd of Elections and Ethics and t o emend the Distrtct o f ColumQia Elect i on Code of 195 5 t o permi t future a ppr oval s by resolut ion BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNC IL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA. That this act may be ci ted as the Prec inct Boundary Changes Appr o val and ProceC. ura l Amend ment Act o f 1387 Sec. 2 Pursu&amp;lt;!Int to lIectl.on S { a 8) of the D:i!itrict of CoLumbia E1 tion Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stilt 700 D.C. Code sec I-lJ06(aj(ajj, the Council o f the District o f columbia appr oves the p r oposed boundary divisions fo r Pr eC 1nct s 50 71 and 11 2 s u bmi tted by the Board of Elec t ion lind Ethics on Apr il 21. 1987 a nd a pprove s the proposed bound"l·Y line between Precinct s It and 12 s ubmitted by the Boa rd o f Elections a nd Ethics on June 4. 1987. Se c l. Section 5( a 8) o t t h District o f Col umbia Elec tion Code of 1955 approved Aug ust 12, 1955 (69 S t at 700 D.C Code s ec. 1-130t,(a)(8», is 1WIended by striking the phrase ~subject to the approval o f the Co uncil" and inse t"t illg i n its plac e t h e phrase "sub j ect t o the a ppr ova l of the Council, i n whole at" i n part b y re.ol ution Sec 4. Thi s act shall take ef fec t af t er a 30-(\sy per iod of Congressional revi s w foll o wing app r o v ill by the yo r (or in th event of ve t o b y the Hayor. IIc t ion by t h e Council o f the Di st ri c t o f Co l umbla to over ride the veto a s prOVIded in ect ion 602(c)(1) of t he Di s tr i ct o f Calumbi Self- Governmen t a nd vovernmen tal Reor9ani~a tion Act. Not D,C Code, slIe 1-1306 0988 s"pp D. C. Code, n c. 1-1306 (1988 9ullp approved Decern~r 24, 197 3 (87 Sta t 8 13; D. C. Code SIlC 1- 233(c)(1 aJti€;¥l Chairman ~­ Council o f the Di strict of Col ~mbia COlumbi a APPROVED JULY Z3, 1987 COUNCIL OF 'THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA C&amp;lt;&amp;gt;u llcil P eriod Seven RE CORO OF OFFIC IAL COUNCIL VOTE OOC~ET &amp;gt;«1' B7 221 :II: ACTI01oI4 DATE Adopted Fir s t Rea_ding 6 c-O'C l VOICE VOTe Aocoro.&amp;lt to" M roQuI" Unanimous C r fo rd lind Wilson 7 i 7 iIC lI.m on C wn, o II AcnOtl &amp;amp; OATE d'QRted Fi nal Reading 6 }O- 87 II: VOIC E VOH" Unanimous AecC&amp;gt;f&amp;lt;l-.l on 1 all prese nt J ACTIO N l OAH VO~E VOTE R«Q M' s.oc""ary Co 0 </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
