<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-38">
  <num type="law">7-38</num>
  <heading type="short">Litter Control Expansion Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1987-10-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-38.pdf">D.C. Law 7-38</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 5326</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-38, the “Litter Control Expansion Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-169, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 30, 1987, and July 14, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 23, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-66 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 7-38 "L itter Control Expansion Amenament Act of 1987 Pursuant to Section 412 of tne District of Columbia Self_ Government ana Governmental Reorganization Act, 1 L. 93_198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 7-169 on first and second readings, June 30, 1987, and July 14, 1987. respectively. Folloliing the signature of the Mayor on Ju ly 23, 1987. this legislation lias aSSigned Act 7-66, published in the August 14. 1987, edition of the Register 01. 34 page 5326) and transmitted to Congress on July 29. 1987 for a 3~-day revleli, In accordance lilth Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice t hat the 3D-day CongressIonal Revieli Period has expired. and therefore. cites this enactment as D,C. Law 7-38. effective October 9, 1987. Ii \ o-t\~-i -D A. CLARKE Chairman of the CounCil Oates Counted During the 3D-day Congressional Review Period: July 29.30.31 August 3.4,5.6,7 September 9,10,11,14,15.16.17.18,21.22,23.24.25,28,29.30 October 1,2.5.6,7.8 LAW 7-38 OCT 0 9 1997 ~oll.d Drislnal AN ACT D.C. ACT 7-68 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUlZ'S7 TO amend the Lit tsr Cont r ol Administrati on Act of 1985 t o dec r iminalize additional p r ovisions and t o redefi ne c er ta in provi sions in the 01.tri.:t o r Col umbia Health Regulations, t h e So l id W"'SI Collec tion: Conta i nec s t o be Used. and ti tle 24 o f the Di st rict o f Columbia Municipal R~ulation s and to amend An Act Author i z ing the acquisition of land in t he Distr ict o f Columb i a an d the c onstruction tha reo n o f tWO modern h i gh temperatur e i ncine rato r e t o r the destruction of combust ible r etuse lind fo r othe po,arpQses to l i ve tohe Mayor the author ity t o se l ect s uita b le sit f or the d isposal of r efuse B E I T ESACTED BY TliE CCU NCI L or THE DI STRICT OF COLUMDIA, That this act may ~e c ited as the ~Litt er Contro l Expan sion Amendmen t Act of 1987 Se e 2. Section 3 o f th Lit t",r Con trol Admini 'll t r a!Oion Act o f 1985 effectiVe Ma r ch 2 5, 1,}86 (D C. La 6 -1 00; D.C. Code, s e. 6 -2902 is amend",d a folIo a) Se c tion a)(l illl ame nded t o read as foll o s 8( a 1 Th. Mayor at t h O i.tr~ct o f ColUIII~ia Mayor t h r ough the Oepllrtlnen t o f Public Wo rks hall en f o rce se c tion" 601 ,60 604, 605, 6 06( a e and (h 607(a c d e f l h and (j 60 8(a 6 0 9 a and 612 of chapter 3 in t i tl e 8 o f the Distri c t o f Col\ll!l~ia Health Rt9ulat i o nlll, e n a cted June 29, 1971 (R"g. 71-21; 21 DCHR 700.1 .ec tion 4, 5 6 and 7 of Solid Waste Col to be Used, effe ctive Fe~rllary :21 DC:-JR 708 a nd a number of r u l recor ded 101, 10 2. 10 3 104. 108 900.7 900 8 900 10 1 000 100 1, 1002. 1005, 100 8, 10 0 9 2 000 2 0 01. 2002, and 2 UIO of 24 OCMR, The Depa rtment of Publi c Wo r ks shall hear conte sted c ase r~s in9 fr om v i o latio ns of t he reg Ulations listed in t hi ec t ~on 1n accor danee ith the ad j ud i cative .ystem p r ov ided in s ections 5 6, and 9 D.C. Cod s ec. 6- 2902 1988 s upp. enrolled O.lgl b) sect.ion 3(d) is iUTlend ed to read dS fo110lO5 d) Th. first ntence of sect.ion 61 2 in chapter 3 of title B in the District of Col~bia Health Regulations. enac t.ed June 29. 1971 Reg 71 21 21 DCMR 700.6 is amended to read as fOllow Any person who faila to comply wit.h sections 601, 603, 604 60S, 606 (a c and (h 607( a b e d el f g h a nd (j 608(a 6 0 9 a and 612 of this Part s hall be sub ject to civil sanctio ns provided in t.he Litt.er Control Administration Act of 1985 Any person who fail' t o comply with any other .ection of this Part shal l upon conviction, be punished by a fine not to exceed $300 or ~pri sonment no t to sxceed 1 0 dayx. o r both cl Section 3 (e) ix dlnended by adding a new parag r aph (3) to read as follows 3) Section 1 00 6 i. amended to read as foll o ws Any pereon viola ting any provision of sections 101, 102, 103, 10 4 l OB 1000 1001, 1002 1005. 1008. 1009. 2000. 200 1 and 2002 of this titl. shall be s ubject to civi l sanctions pr ovided in the Litt.r Contr o l Admini. t r ation Act of 1985. Any person violeting any other provision of thi s titl fo r whic h a speci fic penal ty is n o t provided shall. upon conviction. be punished by a fine of not ~re than S3 00 Sec 3 Chapter 3 in ti tle 8 of the District of Co lumbia Hea lth Regulations enacted Jun e 29, 19 71 Reg 71 21 21 OC!'lR 700 .1_ tit s eq is ame nded oS follows a) Section 6 0 2 2l DCMR 799 .1 is ame nded as oI10"'6 1) By adding the f ol l Owing sentence ilIt the end o f the definition of "Waste F"r purposes of t hese reg ulations the t e rm "wa ste" i ncluQss. but is no t limited to. notice handbills. leaflets. flyers. and any othe r advert lsing or infor-mat ional ma terial ins e rting in alphabetlcal sequence the ioo means small quantit ie s of h and similar sources ilI r e exempt r egula tions, bu t exhibit dangerous characteristi c s Such as ignitability, corrosivity reactivity. o r toxicity b) Sec ti" n 603 (i 21 DC MR 705 5) i s amended t o read dS follo s i) Residen t s of properties he r e solid waSt e s are collected by t h. Distr ict. e xcludlng bulky wastea handl e d by special coll ec t ion. shall 1 P lace the so lid W/lste in legal contain.rs. in II. manner so as t o prevent litter. at the poin t at c o l le" tion no earlie r than 6,30 p.m. on t he day p r ior to the COll e ction day; and 2 r eturn to p r iva t e D,C R EDro~l&amp;amp;d Original property by 8,00 p.m. of the collection day all empty solid waste containers, including Supercans. M c) Section 603(j 21 DCMR 705.6) is amended by deleting the phrase "Hazardous liquid" and inserting in its place the phrase "Household hazardous wastes dl Section 603(k 21 DCMR 702.1 702.2) is amended to read as follows k){l) Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each owner, tenant, or lessee (or the agent of that person) who has control of or occupies any building, lot, or land within the District shall maintain in clean condition the public space from the property line of that building, lot, or land and extending 18 inches from the curb line (or the lateral lines of the roadway) into the abutting road""ay 2) Each owner, tenant, or lessee (or the agent of that person) who has control of or occupies any building that contains 3 or fewer dwelling units within the District shall maintain in clean condition the public space between the'curb line (or lateral lines of the roadway) and the property line of that building e) Section 603 (21 DCMR 702.1 et seq is amended by adding a new subsection (1) to read as follows 1) Construction and demol ition wastes and mat rial shall not be collect..a by District collection services fl The first sentence of s ection 60S (b 21 DCMR 706.1) is amended to read as follows Persons occupying premises where solid waste collection service is provided by the District shall set out bulky wastes for COllection in accordance with the schedule published by the Mayor, and place the bulky wastes at the point of collection no later than 7:00 a.m. on the Monday of the scheduled bulk COllection wee~ and no earlier than 6:30 p .m. On the Friday prior to the scheduled bulk collection week Sec. 4. Section 6 of Solid Waste Collection, Containers to be Used. effective February 21, 1'.173 (1'.1 OCR 4'.17; 21 DCMR 708.2 is amended to read as follows 6. Designation of Collection Points I wThe Public Space Maintenance Administration of the Department of Public Works shall properly inform residents of the District ~hether their authorized point of collection is in the front of or the rear of their properties. If COllection is from an alley. the point of COllection shall be on private property Urumediately adjacent to public space, except that when Supercans are collected from the alley, the po~nt of collection shall be on public space immediately adjacent to the private property line. If collection is not J D.C.M.R. IDrolled Or1ainAl from ~n alley, the point of collection shall be on public spac immediat.ly adjacent to the premises Sec 5 Titl. 24 of the Di.trict of ColUlllbia Munieipal Regulations is am.nded as follows al Section 101 is ~nded by adding a ne sub ction 1 0 1 6 to r ead all fo110 101.6 Any pernit issued by the Mayor und.r the provisions of this title must be displayed a t all time, at th e address of work indicated on the permit b) Section 102 is amended by adding a ne subsection 102.8 to read &amp;amp;&amp;amp;1 tollo s 102.8 Public parking means that a rea of public space d.voted to open spac greenery, pa rk s, o r parking that lies betw n the property line hich mayor may not coincide wi th the building restriction line, and the edge o t the actual o r planned sid.walk that 1s near.r to the p r ope rt y line. as the p r op.r ty line and sidewalk are shown on t he r.co r d s ot the Dilltrict Sec 6 Section 1 of An Act Authorizing the acquisition of land in the District of Columbia and the construction th.r.on o f two mod.rn. high-temperature incine rators for the d.struction ot combustibl. retuse nd for o ther purpos.s, IIppr o veO March 4. 1929 (45 Stat. 1549: D. C. Code, sec. 6 50 5 io amended as follo a By redesignating t he existing language as sUbs.ct ion Ill: and (b) By adding a ne sub.ection b) co read as folIo b) Nothing shall prevent the Mayor from d.signating eeleeting or acquiring another site or .i tes that may be uitable for the purpose ot retu dispos al Any p r oposed slte eelect ed by the Mayor after the e:fective date of the l.itter Control f.:ltpansion Amendm.nt Act of 1987, shall be submitted to the Counci l of t he 01.t rlct at Columbia Council for a 45·day period of review. eXcludi ng Saturdayo, Sundeys. legal holidays and d~ys at Council r.c If the Council does not a p prove o r dis~pprove the propo d s i'Oe, in whole o r in part, by resolution ithin this 4 5-day r.vi period, the proposed ei'Oe sh~ll be d.emed approv.d. Nothing in this oection shall effect ~ny requirementa impo.ed upon the Mayor by title I at the Dis trict of columeia Administrative Procedure Act. approved o&amp;lt;:tober 21. 1968 (82 St~t 1204; D.C. Code, sec. 1 15 01 lit l S Sec 1 This ac t shall take eff.ct ~fter a 30-da y p.riod of Congres. i onal reVIew [ 0110 1n9 approval by the Mayo r (or in the even'O o f ve'Oo by the Mayor, action by the Counc il of the Oiatrict o f Columbia t o override 'Oh. veto) as 4 D.C.M.I. D. C. Code sec. 6- 505 (1988 IUpp rolled Original provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Beorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. l-233{c)(1 Columbia APPROVED: JULY 23, 1987 COUNCn. OF THE DISTRICf OF COLUMBIA Cotmeil Period Seve J Item on Con.ent Calendar RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: B7- l6'1 X CTION &amp;amp; D.o..TE A"d"o"pc'c.,d i"&amp;lt R a,d"i"n"g'-c C-,3"Oc-08,7 Kl ~OICE ~OTE U'n"'a'n"i"m"o'u ROCOnlea te on Alo"est At.eent: all present Z CTION &amp;amp; DATE A"d~o~p dcc'Cienc 1-'R a"dC'c""e 7c C4 8,,7 X ~OIC~ YOTE U"n"'a"n,'crn"o"u Roeo oto on quo Kane, Smith a nd Clarke o ACTION &amp;amp; DATE o YOICE YOTE Roc o",eC1 .ot. on Qu ost Absont L ROLL CALL YOlE RESULT s.c a"f 10 In. Coune li</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
