<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-39" flag="true">
  <num type="law">7-39</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1987-10-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-39.pdf">D.C. Law 7-39</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 5331</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-39 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-189, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 30, 1987 and July 14, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 23, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-67 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUMCIL OF TlH OISTRJO OF COLllMBIA HOT ICE D. C. LAW 1. 19 'Soil and \later C(l ~s er Htion !listri c t Rees t ab l ish_ent Amend_en t Act of 1981 Purs udnt to Section 41 2 o f the Dis trict of Coh_b1a Sel f- Gover ent and Govern~e n t ~l Reorganiz" ti on Ac t, P. L. 93 198 the Ac t the Co uncil o f the Dis trict of Coluillbh "dopted. Bill MO. 1 _18 9 on f i rst "nd second readings J une 10 1987 a nd J uly 14, 1981 respect i ve ly Follo 'll ln9 the signature of the Mayor on July n 1987 th is legls1at lon as assigned Act 7 _67 publis he d In th e August 14,1987 edition o f the hh Register Vol 34 page 5331) and transm itted to Congress on July 29, 19B7 f o r a 3D d ay revie w, in acco rd ance with Sen i on 602(c l o f th e Ac t. The Co uncil of the District of Columbi a lIereby gi ve s no t ic e tll"t th e 3D day Co ngre ssional Re view Pe r iod ha s t.l pl re o:l a nd t he r efore c i les th i s e"4 c tm~n t .s D.C l~w 39, @ff@ t t I Ye Oc t obe r 9 1987 UL DAVID A. CLARKE Chair~ an of the Council Dates Counted Duri ng the JD day Congressional Re v le w Pe ri od 29 30.31 3 4 5.6 7 September g 10 11 .14,15 16,11,1 8 21 ,22 23 24, 25.28.29 0 October 1,2 5 ,5, 1 B D.C. lAW 7 39 n Or,T n Q 1981 D.C. ACT 7 67 IN THE COUNCI L N THE DIS'I'R ICT OF COLUM BIA To amend the District of Co lumbia So lI and Wa ter c o nse rva t ion Act r.d to reesta b li sh the SO il a nd Water Conse r vation Dis t ri c t. BE I T ESACTED BY THE COUNCI L OF TnE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this a c t may be ci ted illS the "So l.l and Wa ter Conservati o n Ihs trict Ree s tabl i shment Ama nnme'll Act of 1987 Sec 2. The Soil li nd Wat",r Cons e r vati on Distri c t es tab lished by section 4 o f the Distri c t o f Columb i a So il II na I ater Conser v a t i on Act O f 198 2, e ffective Septe'~ber 14, 1':182 Ll C La 4-14 3: D.C. Code, alli e 1-2803 ill re established as II Diatric t of Columbia government agency. Sec. 3 Section 5 o f the Distri c t o f Columbia Soil "n ct W4ter Con s e r vation ACt of 1982 effec tiv e September 14, 1982 (D .C La 4- 14 3; D. C. Code s ec. 1-280 4 i s en&amp;lt;ltd by a S triking the IoIO r d Restabli she d" and i n ae r dng in Lta place the 1o'Or&amp;lt;:1 "reesta b lishe&amp;lt;l b) St riking the title "Direc t o r of the Department of Environmental Service and inserting i n its pillce the titl e "Director of the Department o f consume r and Regulator y Affllirs t c Striking the title "Direc t o r o f the Department of Transportation a nd i nse r ting i n i ts p lace the title "Director o f the DepartJnent o f Pub li c Works and d) Str iking the title "ASSI s tant City Administr ator for Planning and Development" and inserti ng in i t s pla ce the title "Director of the Offic e of Planning sec. 4. The Dist r ict o f Col umb i a $oil and Wate r Conservat ion Act o f 1982, ef fective September 14. 1982 (D.C Law 4-14 3; D.C. Code, s ec. 1-2801 e t .eq i lt;\m"ndfld to add a new s e c tion 17 t o read as f ol lo 6 Sec 17 Terms D. C. Code c l Z803.1 1988 "upp Sote. D. C. Code C 1- 280.1 (1988 Sllpp D.C Cod e 1- 2804 (198B supp Nt"&amp;lt D.C. Cod, R lt 1-1814 (l 988 sup J::ach member o f tho Soil lOne 1.;btCr ConservlItion Board appoin ted by t he Mayor o f t he Distr i ct of Colu.nbia o r by t he Council of the Distr ic t o f Columbia shall !fer-ve a 2 yea te rm, whi ch shall begin o n the da te tha t a ma jor it.y o f t he e mernbers are sworn in and e xpire at the onclusior, of the Council period Thi s oate shall be the a nniver ury nate f or all subsequent !oIayora l and Council appo intments Sec. S Section 15 o f the Dis tric t o f Colu/Ilbia Soil a nd Wa te r COllsen/&amp;lt;lti on Act o f 1982 ef fe c tLve September 14, 1982 (D C La 4-143; D, C Code, sec. 1-2813 iii repealed. Se c 6 This act sha ll take effect after II 30 day pe riod o f Congressi ona l r eview f ollowing approval by the Iayor (or 10 the even t of v eto b y t h e M.!oyor, action by t he cou nc i l of the District o f Columbia t o override tne ve t o) a s p rovidell 1n sec-t i on 6 02(c)(l of the Di s tr ict of Columbia Self- Go vernmen t and Governmenta l Reorq ani~ation Act approved December 24 1973 (87 stat. 9 13; D C. COde s ec. 1-2J3(c 1 APPROVED JULV 2J, 1997 \ el'ea!e &amp;lt D. C. Code C. 1-2B13 (198B allpp COUNC IL. Of THE DISTRICT OF COLLMBIA Council Perioo S.v~n X It om on Co n' C.le RECORO Of OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE OOCKH NO B7 1o x Ac n ON 3. DATE: x VO ICE VOTE Recom o le on Qu oS! Adop t ed F irst Reading 6- 30 Unaninous all present RO~L CALL VOTE RESUlr I, i K ACTlON DATE Adopted Final Reading C-c'c c X VOICE YOT E; Re cord 01. on Quo" Absent l:nanimous Kane, Smith and Cl arke ROLL CA LL VOTE RESU LT ยฃ yJcJJ S i A is S e&amp;lt y to 1M Counci l !tem DO eoo""ot Ca l.r&amp;gt;dar ACTION &amp;amp; [lATE: c.J VOIC~ von: c R.coroO&amp;lt;l &amp;lt;01. on quo 1 ROLL CALL VOTE RESU LT s to th. Counci l </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง8-1721"/>
  </section>
</document>
