<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-44">
  <num type="law">7-44</num>
  <heading type="short">Penalty for Prostitution Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1987-12-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-44.pdf">D.C. Law 7-44</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 5310</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-44, the “Penalty for Prostitution Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-74, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 16, 1987 and June 30, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 23, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-59 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNC I L OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUM81A MOT ICE O. C, LAIoI 7_44 "Pe ~al ty for Pr ostitution A end e nt Ac t of 1987 Pursu a nt t o Section 4 12 of the Distri c t o f Coluillbia Self Go vern ll e nt and Gov ern lle nt al R@orglnlzation Act. P. L. 93 198 t he Act the Cou n cil of th e Dis tr ic t o f Colu bla &amp;lt;Iodopted Bi ll Ne 7_7 4 on first &amp;lt;llId sec o nd rUdin gs. June 16 19 87 and Jun e )0 1987 respeCt i vely Fo l l owing the slgn ~ture of the M ~yor on Ju ly 23 1'187 this legishtiGn wa s ass l 9ned Att 7_59 published in the Au ust 14, 1987. edition of the L.I Registe r Vo l. 34 page 5310 a nd t rans itt ed t o Con gr es s on July 29 198 1 f or a 60_day review, In a cco rdan c e dth Sett i en foOl(c l) of the Ac t ae Co uncil ef the Distri c t of Celumbi a hereby g iv es noti c e th at the 6 0_day Congressional Review Perie d ha s expired and ther e f o re, cites th ts enactllent as D, C. la w 7 _4 4 eff ec tive Oec elllb er I, 19 87. Ce un c i Da te s Co unted Du ri ng th e 60 d ar ConqreS5lon a l Rev i t w Pt r lod: J u 1 Y 29.30.31 Au 'l u s t 3, 4, 5.6 7 Se p t e_ber 9.10 11.14 ,1 5 .1 6 .1 7 .18 21 22 2 24 2S 28.29 30 Oc to be r 1.2, 5.6 ,7, 8 9,1 3 14, 15. 16 19 ,l O, 21.22 ,23 .26,27 ,28 29 30 No velJce r 2 ,3,4. 5 .6, 9 ,10,1 2 ,1 3 16.17 18,19,20,30 D.C. lAW 1- 4 4 enr oll ad OrigUla 5 DEC 0 1 1981 AN ACT D.C.ACT 7-59 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DI STRICT OF COLUMBIA JUL U I9i'7 To amend lection 1 of An Act For the suppressio n of prostitution in t he Oi5trict o f COl umbi a. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL or THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this a ct may be c i ted as the "Penalty for Prostitution Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. Section 1 o f An Act f o r the s uppress ion of p r ostitution in the District of Columbi a. app rove&amp;lt August 15. 1935 lt;19 S t t. 6 51: D.C Code. sec 22-270 1 i8 amended to read as fo llows Sec. 1 a) It s hal l not- be lawful for any person to invite. en tice. persuade or address tor the purpose of invit ing, enticing or persuading. any person o r persons in the District of Columbia for the purpose of prostitution or any o ther iml1lO al o r l d purpose. The penalt i es for any violation o f this .ec tio n Shall be ill. fine of $300 f o r the first o ffense. a fin. o f $30 0 a nd 10 days imprisonment f o r the second offense. and a fine of $300 and 90 days imprisonment for eac h SUbsequent offense Any person convicted of a violation of this section may be 'entenced to community service a. an alternative to. but not in addition to. any term of imprieonment author ized by this section b Invitin9. ent i c i nq. persuadin9. or addressinq for t he purpoee of inv i ting. entic i n9 or persuad i ng f o r t h e p u r pose of prostitut ion includes. but is not limited to. remainin9 or wandering about a public plac e and 1) Repeatedly beckoning to. stopping. attempting to s top. o r attempting to engage pa.sers-by in conversation for the pt.l rpose of p r os titu t ion 2) Stopping o r attempting to sto p motor v e hicl es fo r the pu r pose of prost itution; o r 0) Re pe a t edl y i n terfering with t he f ree passage of other {)G rsons f or the purpose of prostitution D.C. o:rle, sec 22-2701 (1988 supp rol l~d Orig 1nal Sec J This act sh"'ll t"'ke e ffe ct after 60 d",y per i od of Congress i ona l review fo l l owing approval by the Mayor (or in the event of ve to by the Mayor. action by the Council of the Di strict of Columbia t o overr ide the vetol p r ovided in section 602(c 2) of th e Distr ict of Columbia Sel f- Government and Gov e rnmental Reorganization ct. appr oved Pee-e mb.n 24 1973 (87 Stilt 8 13; D.C Code sec. 1 233(c 2 1 1I Xl1 L Chai~y Council of the Distl'ict o f Col umbia APPROVEO JULY 23 1987 COUNCIL OF 'THE DlSTRIC'T OF COLt)MflIA Council Poliod Seven RECORD Of OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET ~O x ACT OATtL Ad.opted fiLs..t. Read; n9 6-16 aL IX VOICE VOTE C--c_Un",nimou AecOl vol&amp;lt Oft Crawford and wi1IiOO""L ACTlON3. oAfE Adcpted pin,.l Re.ding 6 10 87 Xl VOICE VOTE Unanimou lSi" C ACTION 3. OAT B7 -74 VO ICE VOTE lt;I&amp;lt;ooo,CIe&amp;lt;I OIl 't&amp;lt;lUfl! 5 amp 0 I CO"oo </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
