<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-45">
  <num type="law">7-45</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1987-12-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-45.pdf">D.C. Law 7-45</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 6845</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-45, “District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-47, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 14, 1987, and September 29, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 16, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-78 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE O. C. LAW 7~45 "District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987 PursHnt to Section 412 of the District of Co l umbia Self~ Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93~198 the Act the Council of the District of Co l umbia adopted Bill No. 7~47 on first and second readin9s, July 14. 1987. and September 29, 1987, respectively Following the signature of t he Mayor on October 16, 1987, this legis la tion was assigned Act 7~78, published in the October 30,1987, edition of the ll L. Register Vol. 34 page 6845) and transmitted to Congress on October 21, 1987 for a 30~day review, in Hcordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The CounCil of the District of Columbia hereby gives not i ce that the 30 day Congressional Revie&amp;gt;l Period has expired. and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Ln 7 ~4 5, effective December 10, 1987. A. CLARKE of the Counc i 1 Oates Counted During the 30~ddY Congre~5ional Re~iew PeriOd: October 21,22,23,26,27,28,29.30 No~e ber 2 ,3 ,4 ,5 ,5 ,9,10 ,12 ,13 ,15,17,18,19,20,30 December 1,2,3,4,7,8,9 D.UAW7-45 DEC 10 1981 AN ACT D.C.ACT 7 -78 IN Tn COUhCIL Of' Tlil; DISTRICT OF COLUfoinIA OCr J 6 1987 To r equi re regis t e r ed nurse servi~es a t a l l publ ic schools and at all a t hletic events sponsor ed by public school In IT I:tl AC'l'ED ElY THl: COUNCIL OF THE: DI STR I CT OF COLUNSIA I'hat this act mIIy be ci t ed as the Oi llt r ict o f columb i a Fub l ic School Nu r se Ass i g IlJ:len t Ac t o f. 198 7 Sec. 2 s A reg istc r {ld nur se I; h a ll be assigned t o each Dis trict ot columbia Di stric t el ementary and secondary publ ic school II mi nimum of 12 hours pe r week during each semes t er and during su~e r school if a summer school pr ogram 1s opera t ed b l ~he minimum hour s per week of regis t e r ed nurse services at each school sha l l inc r ease from 12 to 16 hours pur lOee k beginning 1 year af t er t he e f fec t ive dat e o f this ac t The ~inimu~ hours per week of regi s tered nurse service s at each achool s hall increase f r om 16 to 20 hours per week beg inning 2 years af te r t he effective dat e of this act c) Any SChool t hat, on r:ay 1, 1987, exceeded t he s t anda r dS fo r r egis t e red nurse services ~rescr ib&amp;amp;d by subsection (a or (b l o f this lIection sha l l con t inue that level o f service o r t he level p rescr ibed by s ubsect i on a) or Ihl of t his sec tion Whicheve r is greater. No reduction shall be ~ade in t he leve l of reg~s te red nur lle services a t any sc hool exce~t i n r espons e to 11 reduced ne e d based on 11 reduc ed stude nt enr o l l n e nt or a reduced proportion of students requiring spec i a l services because of h and i capping condit ions d A registered nurse a cer t ified ath le tic t r aine r, o r bot h sha ll be ~re .ent a t all a t hletic e vent s sponsored by t he Dist r ict e l ementary or secondary public schools t ha t occur in t he Distric t. These ~edica l serv ices s hall be in addi t ion to the minimum hourll of regis t ered nur se services r equired by subsection l a) o r (bl o f this se c t ion 1 New, D.C Code. sec 31-2421 (1988 supp e) Sufficient funds to carry out the requirements of this act are authorized to be appropriated out of the general revenues of the District Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30- day period of Congressional review following approval by the tayor (or in the event of veto by the ~layor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1} of the District of Columbia Self- Gover~ont and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec l -233(c I} of the District of Columbia !layor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 16, 1987 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council P~riod Sltveo \&amp;gt RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTe 7 4,,7 DOCKET NO U I t~n'l on Consent c.oler&amp;gt;d cA,d,o~p e"d. First Reading, 7-14 87 A CTION &amp;amp; OAT Ili: VOICE YOTE ROOOr&amp;lt;lM ,ole on req 1 Ab w n" Unanimous Ka ne and Clarke RESULT ;0 11 0m o n C00150nt Calendar O.te ACTION &amp;amp;OATE Adopted Final Reading 9- 2 9- 87 X VOICE VOTE' flecor~ed ,ole 00 re Q t Absent RO LL CA LL VOTE: Unanimous Kane Itom on Con.ent Calendar [1 ACTION &amp;amp; DATE' r] VO ICE VOTE R. cord od vole on Qu t 500'e lO&amp;lt;y to tM Coono,1 6 7 O~te</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-621"/>
  </section>
</document>
