<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-54">
  <num type="law">7-54</num>
  <heading type="short">Wastewater System Regulation Amendment Temporary Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1987-12-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-54.pdf">D.C. Law 7-54</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 6895</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-54, the “Wastewater System Regulation Amendment Temporary Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-281. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 14, 1987, and September 29, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 16, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-87 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF TME DISTRI CT OF COLU M8IA KOilCE O. C. LA~ 7- 54 ·Wd st~ w~t~ r Syste. Rpgutftion Amendment Te.po r try Act o f 1987 Pursu4.n t t o Sec ti on 4 12 of the Dis tr ict o f Co lu mbia Self- Go~erfi.ent and Go~ernllental Reo rganization Ac t P. L. 93 198 t he Act the CoYncl1 o f the District o f Cotu.bia adop t ed 8111 MO. 7· 281 o n fint and cond rudings J u ly 14 1987 a nd Sep temb e r 29 1987 respe c tively. Folto wing the sign a ture of tile Mayor on Oc t obe r 16. 1981 this legislatio n as 4.ssigned Act 7- B7 published in the Oc to ber 3D 198 7 edi t ion of th e D. C e gi5ter ol 34 pag e 6895 a nd tr.ns itted to Con g r ess on Oc t obe r 2 1. 1981 fo r a 3 day r evie w. in a cco rdan ce with Section 6DZ( c)(I o f the Act, The Council of th e Dist r ict of Columbia hereby gives notlte ~hat the JO ddy Cong ress ional Revie w Peri od has exp i red. a nd th e refore. c ites this ena ct~ ent as D.C. Law 7- 54. effective Dec ember 10 1981. OAVID A. CLARH Ch a i r n of t he Cou nCi l O~tes Co~"ted O~r i n 9 the la da y COng ression al R eyi@~ Pe riO d Octobe~ 21 .22 23.26.27.28 29 30 N o~e mber 2.3 .4. 5 6 9.10 12,13 .1 6 .1 7 18 19. 20 .30 DEtemher 1.2,3.4, 7 8 9 D,~lAW 7-54 ou~u OEC l 01987 AN ACT D,C ,IT 7 8'7 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DI Sl'RICT OF COLU~lInA ltT .l i 198'1 To amend, on a temporary basi s, the ~1.as tewater Syet e m Regulatlon Amendment Act of lSB5 to provide l egal autho ri t y to impose fee s and cha rges for t he issuance o f p r etreatment permits and the administrat ion o f t he p r e treatDent program BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCI L or THE DISTRICT O COLU~lBtA. That thi ac t may be c ited as the ~\Iastewater System Regulation Amendment Temporary Act of 1987 Sec 2 The Watitewater Syste~ Regul ation Amendmen t Act o f 1985, e ffect i ve March 12 19 96 D.C La 6-9 5; D. C Code, sec G-951 is a~ended a. t ollows al (D C Code, liIec 6- 95 7 4 is amended by adding new sentence a t the end The yor ma y and collec t fees and charges as may be necessary or approp riatB to ensure compliance with th is act 0) Sec tion B(b 6 D C. Code sec 6 957(b 6 lS amended by st rik i ng the phr ase nd and inser ting a s emicolon ~n i ts place c) Section B(b 71 (D.C Code sec 6-9 !17(b 7») is a mended by str iking the per iod and inserting the phrase I!.nd in ~t&amp;amp; place d) Section a lb D.C Code, sec 6- 95 7 b is amended. by addin9 a ne w para9raph (B) to read as f ollows B) Re9ulations irnposin9 fees a nd char ges for the i ssuanc e o f wastewate r p r etreatMent per~its and the administrat i o n o f the p r e t reatment p r ogram Sec J a This act s hall t a ka ef fec t a ft.ar a 30-day pe riod of Congressional r eview f o ll ow ing approva l by t he I-iayor (o r 1n t he event of veto by t he Hayo r lt;l c t ion by t he Council o f the Distric t of Co l umbi&amp;lt;l t o o verr ide the veto) a s ~rovided in s ection 6 02(e 1) o f the Dis trict o f Columbia Self- Government and Government al Reor9anizat~on ACt 1 O. C. Cod sec 6-9!1} (1988 IUpp Earol led Or1g! nal ap \,lroved Dece mber 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D. C. Code, sec 1- 233 (cl (11 b) This act shall expire on the 2Z5th day of its having taken effect t il Dililtr ict o f Co l l.lmbia APPROVED: October 16 COUNCIL OF THE n1STRICT OF COLUMBIA CouDcil P eriod SeveD RECO RO OF OFFICIAL COUNCil VOTE DOCKET NO AC110N &amp;amp; DArE Adop t ed Fiu.LR~~n'i H il vOice vore una nimouii 87 -2S 1 K~a 9a I on eon 1 c..lendi.r ;X ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Adopt ed _F.l..na l Re a d ing 1 ll-S'7L VO ICE VO~ E on Unanimous Kane 1 AcneN &amp;amp; Du e [ VOICE, vorE Ro&amp;lt d vol. 011 flI q""Sl ou CAlL VOT E ESULT </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
