<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-57">
  <num type="law">7-57</num>
  <heading type="short">Day Care Policy Act of 1979 Amendment Temporary Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1987-12-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-57.pdf">D.C. Law 7-57</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 7081</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-57, the “Day Care Policy Act of 1979 Amendment Temporary Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-305. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 29, 1987 and October 13, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 26, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-90 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 7-57 'Day Care Policy Act of 1979 Amendment Temporary Act of 1987 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self Government and Governmental Reorg anization Act, P. L. 93 198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 7-305 on first and second readings, September 29, 1987. and October 13, 1987, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 26, 1987, this legislation was assigned Act 7-90, published in the November 6,1987, edition of the.Q f Register Vol 34 page 7081) and transmitted to Congress on October 27, 1987 for a 30_day review, in accordance wit h Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. Th e CounCil of the District of Columbia hereby give"s notice that the 3D_day Congressional Review Period has expired. and therefore. cites this enactment as D.C. Law 7_57, effective December 16. 1987. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted DUring the 3D-day Congressional Review Period: October 27,28,29,30 November 2,3,4,5,6.9.10,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,30 December 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15 £Crolled Origlnal u DEC 1 61987 AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 90 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLOMBIA OCT Z S 198'7 TO amend, on temporary basis, the Day care policy Act o f 1979 t o increase payments t o ch ild development centers, child_ devel opment homes and in-home caregivers. BE IT ENACTEO BY THE COONCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLO/IBIA That this act may be cited aa the "Oay Care Pollcy Act of 1979 Amendpent Temporary Act of 1987 Sec 2. The Cay Care Policy Ac t of 1979, effective September 19, 1979 (D.C. Law 3- 16) O. C. Code, see. 3- 301 et S is amended f Ol lows a) 541etion 1 0 a D C. Code, sec 3- 309 (1) I is amended to read as follows a) Subject to subsections (b) through If) o f this section, payments to child development centers fo r care of these children a hall be made on a monthly basia according to the following rata s, effective OCt ober 1, 19S7 I) rull day care 15.50 per day for each child, plus $1.00 per day for each child when the center provides transportation 2) Part-time care 7.75 per day f o r each chi ld 12 40 per day for each child tor full-time care p r ov i ded during vacations and summer to a child who o therwise receives only part- t ime care or does nOt receive c are; and 3) No child development cent er shall be paid more than its stated rate, p rior to application of its sliding fee seale f o r childre n no t eligibl e f o r subsidized cace bl gt;ection 11 (D. C Code sec 3- 3101 is &amp;amp;mended to read as follows Sec. 11 Payments t o chil d development homes and t o in- home car egivers shall be made according t o the following rates, effective Oc tober 1, 19S7 I) ru ll day care 1 1 D.C. Code, sec. 3-309 (1988 supp A) Child development homes S10.50 per child per da y IBI In- home care iii For care during the day 5.1S per chi ld per day1 Iii) For care during night hours S6.75 per child per night 12) Part-time care A) Child development homes SS 2S per child per day for before- and aft er schoo l care B) In home care i) Sefore- and after-schoo l care S4.25 pe r c hi l d per daY1 "I ii) For night car e of le.s than 6 hou rs S3 50 pe r child per nigh t Sec. 3(a This act shall take effect after a 30- day pe r iod of Congressional review following approval by the !layor (or in the event of veto by t hl!l a.yor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to overr id~ the Vl!lto) as provided in .ection 602(c)(1) of thl!l District of COlumbia Se lf- Government and Governmenta l Reorganization Act, appr oVed December 24, 1913 (87 Stat. 813; D. C. Code, sec 1-233 1cJ (1) J b) 7his act shal l expire fits having taken e ffect of the Oistrict o f Columbia APPROVED October 26, 1987 2 Notf D. C. Cod sacs. 3- 309 3-310 (1988 supp COt'NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period SeveQ RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO B"7_-C3COC5 C ltem on Con nt C Mar g; ACTION;1 O"'TE: Adopteg First Reading L 9 9"-08'7 Unanimous VO ICE VOTE' CCc:CC R. ooraM ,ole on r&amp;amp;que.l Crawford and Jarvis /0 9 7 rJ: 110m an Coo nt A"d~o"o d~'c"·n lcCR"e",d"'icn"J l,,OC 3C-O',7 X ACTI ON &amp;amp; O TE x VOICE VOTE C:CCCJu,n n m""oJu c R&amp;amp;&amp;lt;;onlll&amp;lt Ie on fflqunt all Present C eTION &amp;amp; DATE [J VO ICE VOTE Rocordod vote rOq ot C RO LL CALL YOTE RESULT Soc r.t~ry 10 the Council •</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
