<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-6">
  <num type="law">7-6</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1987-06-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-6.pdf">D.C. Law 7-6</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 2637</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-6 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-117. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 17, 1987 and March 31, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 15, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-16 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NCIL OF THE ~IS T RIC T J F COLU~ 8 A 1I(l"lICE D. C. tAW 1·6 Dis t rict of Colu~bia Gov e rnmen t Compreh@nsi v He r i t Pe rS Ol'lnel Act o f 1918 Collectiv e 8ar q i n ing Am@ndm en t T em por~ry ~mendment Ac t of 19 81 Pu rs uant to Ste t i on 41 2 o f the District o f Colu~bi a Self the Ac t the Coun c ll o f th e District of Col umbh adop t ed Bill 11 0 7 ll7 on fint and sec oM re adings, Ha r eh 17 1987 nd Ma r Ch 31 1987 re spec tively. FollO loli ng t he s ign Hure of th e Ma yor o n Ap ri l 15, 1987. t hi s le gis lat io n was ass ig ned Ac t 7·16 pub 1ls hed i the Apr il 2£ 19 87 ed i t h n o f t he Reg iu er Vol 4 page 26~7) and t r an Sl&amp;amp;i tted t o Con9 ress on Ap r ll 20 1987 f o r a 3oJ da y r e de w, in ac cor can ce with Sect i on 602( c 1) o f the c t he Co un cil of the Dis t ric t of Co lumbi a he reby gives notice t"I~t the JO ·day Cong r e s s/o nd l Rede Pe r iod hJ.s e ~pjr ed and ther e f o r e, Cites t hi s e~ ac tm en t as D.C. Law 7- 5, @ff ec tiv e ,I une 5 l SB7 Ch~ l rmd n the Counti I Oa te s Counted Duri ng tne 30- day Con gressional ~e vle hrlod: Ap r i I 21 22 23 24,2 7 28 29,30 Hay 1 ,4,5, 6 7 8 11 .1 2 1 J 14 15 ,1 8,1 9. 20 21.21 28 2 9 Jun e 1,2,3.4 b.C. LAW 1 6 ACT D.C ~IT Ie HI THE CQ U)I.'CIL OF THE DISTR ICT OF COLU~Hl!A fR J 19111 To amend, on tempor a r y basis t he pr o visi ons o f the Di strIct o f Col ufIlbi Gove rnment Compr e hen s ive Merit Personnel Act o f 1978 re lating t o COllective bargaining BE IT ENACTED BY THE COU NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA That this a ct may be cite d ae the D i'trict of Columbia Govornment Comprehensi ve Merit Personne l Ac t of 197 8 COlLec tivo Barga ini ng Amendment Temporary Amendment Ac t o t 19S1 Sec 2 Sec t ion 1117 ot t.he Dl.!ltric t of Colutnbill Government Compeahen ve Merit personnel Ac t o f 1978, effeedve ~l!lrch 3, 1979 (D. C Law 2 139; D. C. Cod e, sec 1- 619.11 is ame nded a s f ollO'ols a Subse ct i on (el (e c Code. sec 1-6IS.17(c IS amended by [ (ll In the fir st sen teence, s teriJd ng te he phrase "manag ement shall" and i n serting in i ts plac e the phr ase "te tle pa r teie, mlly agree teo and (2) I n the tehird sente nce. steriking the ord "shall" a nd insert in i n i t s pLace the o rd "may b) Subeection (d D.C. Cod e, sec 1-6 18 .17( d 18 s tric ken i n its en t1re tey c) Sub.e cti on (tl D C. Code, sec 1-61 8 17{ e » u; amended by LI Stri king t he phr a s e ~t40 hte r tl,an 9 0 d"y s ~tore the e x p iration o f any e xisting negotiated ag ree men t bet e n th e pa rtei es and i n.erting in it~ pl ace the phras e "I f the parti e s choose t o conduct an annu al t Udy purs uan te to subsect i on t e o f this sect i on and (2) Insert ing lifte r the o rd ~negotill teion th e phr ase "for lu ch use a~ t hey may mutuall y agree upon d) S":ha ecti on (f l D.C Code sec 1 618.l7(f)(1) i s "mended by striking t h e firs t sentenc e a nd inse r ting t h e f ollOlo' ing sentence in i t s place I D.C Cod sec 1-61 8.17 (L988 p Ncgot. i tions among t.he part.ies to e xist.i ng cont ract s sh~ll commence no later than 9 0 days befo re the expiration of the existing contr ac ts e) su b ct i on (g D.C Code, sec 1-618 17( g» H amended by stdking the phrase the annual s tudy a nd f) Subsection (i O,C Code, sec. 1-618 .1 7(0) lS amended to add i n the las t sentence, after the word "bodies t he phras e "provided that the ~layor s hall no t be required to suppo rt an arbitrator's a",a rcS g) SUbsection (j D.C Code ec. 1-618.17{j») is amended by add i ng the follOWing sentences a t t he beg inning Within 60 days aft er the pa rties have r eached agreeme n t or a bolIrd o f arbit rat i on h,u issued its award, the Mayor shall transmit the se t t leme nt t o t he Council for its review, If the Mayor fails t o transmit the settlement to the Council within the 60- day period. i t shall be d eemed t o be SUbmi t ted on the 6ist day n) Subsection (m D C. Code sec. 1-618.17(m» i s amend ed Oy str i king the fir.t and ae cond sentenc es and Inserting t he following sa ntenc p 1n thei r place When the Public Employee ile lat i ons Board B rd~l i s :oequired to determine an appropria te ba r gaining unit for t he p~rpose o f c ompensa tion n egotiat ions p~~suant t o s ec t ion 1716. negoti ations fo r compensation between management a nd the e~ elus ive r epr esentati ve shall begin no la ter than 90 day s after the bo.,rd s determina.tio n Sec. J al Th is act shall take effect. aft.er a lO- day per iod o f Congressional r eview fo llowing appr ova l by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by th e Council o f t he Distric t o f COlumbh to ove rride the veto) aa provided in sec tion 6 0 2(c)(lJ of t h e Dist ri ct o f Columbia Self- Government anQ Gove r nmenta l Reorganizat i on Act. approve d lJecembe r 24, 1973 (87 Stat 813; D. C Cod e SeC. 1- 233(c l 2 Inrolled Ori8 inal (b) Thia ac t sha l l expir e on the 225 t h day of its Not D,C. havi n g taken effec t. Codr. ser Mayor Dist r ict APPRNED: ai e man Counc il o f the Piateiet of Columbia lt O f£::COl ur.lbi April IS, 1987 1-~1 8.li (1988 su;&amp;gt l!§ COt:NClL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Cou dl P ioo s"vu B7 117 RECORO OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCK£T 010 Ite m on Con nl Ca l dor :II 4CTION30A T£ Mgpted Fint Rea~i il=8 VOI CE YOTE 1I~_a on 0 Unanimous Cl~rke Kane and Rol ark fIO\ C4U. VOT E RESULT 11 on C M Cal X VOI CE VOTE Unan imous and Crawfo rd CTIO amp; DUE VOICE von t&amp;lt; o o!e queS S;Cr.'ory 10 1 CO </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
