<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-67">
  <num type="law">7-67</num>
  <heading type="short">Real Property Credit Line Deed of Trust Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1988-01-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-67.pdf">D.C. Law 7-67</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 7441</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-67, the “Real Property Credit Line Deed of Trust Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-163, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 13, 1987, and October 27, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 5, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-100 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>• COU NCIL OF rHE DISTRICT OF COLU MbiA NOT ICE D.C LAW 1- 67 "Red1 Prope rt y Cr edit L1nw Deed of lruit A. ct o f 1987 Pursuant to Se ct io 412 of the Dist ri c t of Colum~ia Self Govern nt a nd Go yertlmen ta l Reorgan f ution ct P L. 9 198 the Att the Cou nc il uf thl! Olstri c t of Columbla a dopted 8j11 NO. 7-H J on first an d acond readings. October 13. 1987, dnd Oc tober 27 1987, resprcthely. Follo wing the s lg ndture of the Mayor on Nnwtmoe r 5, 1987, this 1 '91s l~t ion wa s ass i gned Ac t 7-100, publlsh.a In the NoveMber 20 1987. edition of the O.C Re i l ster tol. 34 page 7(41 and t r ~nsmitt.d to Congress on Nove_ber 198 7 for a 3D day review In acc ordance wi t h Section ~02{ c Hl) of the Act. The Counci l of the Dh t rlct of Colu.bh hereby 9ives notice t hat lhe 30 1 COII'.l ressi o 1 Revie w PeriOd h.s e:o.p i red. dlld th~refore ci tes th h enactlllen t a s D.C. la w 7- 67, effe c tive J an~arJ 28. 1988 D {/C'f1L ARH Chaj rm~n of th~ Co ncl 1 DaU I Co~nte" D~rln9 the 30 y Co n 9r ~55 io nal Revie w Peri Od: Novulb er 6 9 .1 0,12 ,13 ,16 ,1 7 ,18,19 ,20,30 Oecube r 1,2. 3 ,4 ,7 ,8. 9,10 ,11. 14. 15, 16,17,18 21 22 IIJ: lAW 7 6.7 JAN2819BB AN ACt D.Ui:r 7-100 IN 'tHE COUNC IL OF THt: DISTRI CT Of' COLUMBIA To deflne credit line deed of trust secured by real property in the Oistrict of Columbia. t o ~rov1de no tice to consu~r6 of t he eonsequences of default, and t o set thft rel a tive prio t"ity u f ct'f;!dit line deedS o f erllse 9~cured by r~al ~roperty in the Di strict o f Columbi BE _tT ENACTED BY EE COUNCIL OF HE DISTRIC OF COLUMBIA Tha t t his act oay be cited as the "Rea l Pr oper t y Cr edit Line Deed ot Trust Act of 1987 Sec 2 Defin itio n For the purpo5es o f th i s act the term 11 Credit lin. d eed o f t rust means any deed of trust in wh ich tit l e to r esident ial real p r operty located in t h e D18trict of Calumeis i s conveyed, transferred, encumbered, o r pledged to aecu~u repdyment o f money t hdt i &amp;amp; 10doed i n the f o rm of ~riodic advance s by t he no t eho lder nar::w;d i n the rtdit line deed o f tt"IHlt 2 al flrOPflety has U!CI I:ledninq s et foeth in sec t ion 402 (1) ot t he District of ColUQb 1d Redl Property tax ReviSion Act at 1974, a pproved Septel:lbe~ 3 197 88 Stat. 1 051; D. C. Code e c 47-802(11 Sec 3 Noti ce requirements amp A credit line deed of trust .sha ll inc l Ude 1 on the front paqe either 1n capital letters o~ undGr sco~ed, the words XliIS I S A HOm EQUITY CREDIT LINE OtEO OF TRU~T otFAULT ON PAYNI:NTS AY RESULT IN TH1: LOSS 0 YOUR HOOE 2 Language t o convey notice to all parties t hat the noteholder, the q r antors, and othe r borr owers identified have an agreeme nt whereby the noteho lder QaY meke o r contemplates ma~ing advances from t ime t o time aqainst the securi t y de scribed in the credit line deed of trust 3) Tha maximum aggregate arnoun t of principal t o be secur ed at any 1 t ~e; a nd 1 Cod ii i c tic New c t pter 1.9 Ot ti t. le fOW. D C Code, sec 4 9 C (1 988 lope, Nflw I C Code, s 29 198&amp;amp mp 4) An explicit stater:Jen t ot the ri9ht~ and obli9atlons ot t he borrower and the consequences of default bl railure to provide the notice required by subsection (11.1 o f t h is section shall be deemed. an unlawful trade p ractice punishable under Chapt.r 39 of title 28 of the District ot Columbia Code. Sec. 4 Priority of. credit line deed ot trust a) From the date ot the recording ot a credi t line deed ot tr~st, the credit line deed o f truet ShAll have p riorlty 1) OVer all o ther deeds, conveyances or other instruments, or contract. in writing, that ar nrecorded as af tha t date and of which t he noteho lder haa no knowledge or noti ce and (21 OVer judg nt lien&amp;amp; lucsequently recorded, except that a judgment creditor who gives notice of the judgDent to the noteholder of record at the addre.s lis ted in th. credit line deed ot trust ,hall have priority over the c r edit line deed at trust in the case of advances that are mada after the date of the noteholder's receipt of the notice and that were not irrevocably committed prior to this dat b) Ilechan ic 's liens establish.d pursuant to section 1~37 at An Act To II cOOO ot law tor the District of Columbia, 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1384: D. C. Code, s ec. shall hav. priority over all ildv ce made line d d of truet subsequent to thO tiling o f notice of aechanic's lien, but shall not have prio rity over advance I ~de prio r to t he filing of notic. of meChanic's lien. Ie) Except as provided in .ubsections (al and (bl of thi. section, the priority of a credit line deed ot trust shall extend t o all advances made followi.ng the recordation at th. credit line deed of trus t. Amounts outstanding toql:!ther with i ntarest, shall continue to have pr ioTi ty until paid or otherwisa settled d Nothing in this act shall apply to the priori t y of purchase monay aecurity interes ts in goods and fixtures. Sec. s. Confor~inq ame ndQent. Sec tion 28- 3904 of the Distr ic t ot Columbia Code i s am.nded by replaCing the period at the end with a semieo lon and tha word "and and adding a naw aubsection (cc) to raad as follows ec) vio late any provision of the Real Property Cradit Line Deed o f Trust Act of 1987 Sec 6. tHective date. 2 New rl .C. Code c 4 S- 2 l9~!1 sUPF D.C ode see. 20 -39 1198 8 SU!=l9 This act shall take effect aft e r a 30-day per i od o f Congres s i onal review !o1 1owing approval by t he Mayor (or in th ven t of vet o by th~ Mayor. action by the COuncil of the Dis trict of Co l umbia ~o override th~ veto) as Frovidea in sect.ion 6(l2(c)(1) of the Diftt.ric t of ColllJUlia Selt-Gov.u:nl'le nt; and Governl:lell t~l Reocgan i.'Zo/I. t ion Ac t a pIJroved Oecelllb",r 24, U 13 (87 Stat 813; D. C Code s c 1-2J3 (c)(1 touncil of t he Distric t of Columbia APPROVED J COUNCIL OF TIlE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Caundl Period $even RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUN CIL VOTE OOCI( [T NO 7C-:1C6 2 ~cnON &amp;amp; CUE CA~d P dCJFC lt R d'l q I"00-0IL 1 III VOICE vore CU"'C'o cuC on I all pr e s e n t c~ ROll C.o.ll VOT ft£SULT Ii .o.CTlO amp; c.o. TE p d FCi"'O I-,R dCi 1~OC C7C-O L VOT c:c-cU o Ue ioIKtIodltd on t o ACTION" n.o. li c: VOICE ~on C 111000 r.qL&amp;gt;ftt a </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2301"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2302"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2303"/>
  </section>
</document>
