<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-68">
  <num type="law">7-68</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Public School Support Initiative of 1986</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-02-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-68.pdf">D.C. Law 7-68</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 7737</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-68, “District of Columbia Public School Support Initiative of 1986,” was submitted to the electors of the District of Columbia on November 3, 1987, as Initiative No. 25. The results of the voting, certified by the Board of Elections and Ethics on November 17, 1987, were 54,729 for the Initiative and 16,223 against the Initiative. It was assigned Act No. 7-102 after certification and was transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review on November 23, 1987.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NCI L OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA N OTI~E O, c. La 7· 65 District of Colu mb i a Pub lic School Support In iti ath e o f 1986 Pu r su a nt to Anendme nt .1'1 of t he Di str i't of Col umb ia Se lf GovernJlerlt an GOYl"r nen t al Rl! or!jan ild t 'on Ac t, P.l. 93· 1 98 tlle '\ct t il e e l e cto r s o f the District o f Colum oia voted an l n iti d t l ve No 25 o No ve mber 3, 19 87 On November 17 19 87 th e Bo ard of El e c t ions nd Ethic cer t ifie d lhe Elec t ion r esults 4$ 5 4, 129 f o r the Ini t id t ne aM 16 223 4 in s t tile In1tl~ti Ye. Follo ng t he cert If ica t Ion u f tn t' r e 1t s this irl1 l .t h e lS usl~ned Act Ho 7 102 putdnhec i n the DH e mbe r 4 1987 ed i t io n f t he D. C. R e glst e r o1. 34 pa ge 77 )7) a nd tr a n~mitt e t o Cong r e £s on No ve mb e r 23 1987, f e r for 3C day r e v i e in dCconfjnce wi t h Se ctio n 602 1) oJ f l 'l e ~c t he Council o f th e o;n~lc t Of (olumbi a hereby h es notl~e thJt the 3 0 d ~y C o n 9 r essi o n~1 Re v i e w Pe ri od ha5 e p1 r ed dnd t he refor e c 1l es s ~nd c t ment Febru ary 17 1988 \ ~s D.C La w 7· 58 e ffectiv e f i ,V;-I O"k'I' d A. O ~t e&amp;gt; Count e d Ouri ng t he J oaJ CQn res'ii ona l Re vi e Pe riO d: Mo vembe r )0 De c embe r I.Z 3 ,4 .7 8,9 1 C l IS 16 11 .1 8 21 ZZ Janu ary 25 2 ti,21 28 29 Fe br u",y \ 2 3 5 8 9,1 6 b.c. LAW 7 6 8 D £ FEB I 1989 D.C. m 7-10 .2 'leV 1 7 1987 INITIATIVE MEASURE NO, 2S SHORT Till[ "DISTRICT OF C~lU~SlA ~UBL IC SC HOOL SUPPD RT IT IArI~E OF 1986" INITIATIVE MEASURE NO. 25 ·OISTRICT OF COLUMRIA PUBLIC SCHOOL SUPPORT INI TIATIVE Of 1986" SUMMARY STATEMENT Tnis measure establishes, as a matter of public policy, that fund i ng for public schools in the Oistrict of Col ll1lbia be of the highest priority. It also establishes a schedule of public hearings before the Board of 'Education, the Mayor, and the Council of the District of Columbia at which members of the public m~y express their views on the needs of the public SChoo ls. INITIATIVE MEASURE NO. 25 BY T~£ ELECTnRS Of THE DI S T~IC T OF COLUMBIA To est~bli,h as a matter of pub li c pol icy that fuMill~ for t he pu,l1c sc~ool s of t he Dist ric t Of Col umnia be of t~e highest pr iori ty Ild t hat It; len~ be ~ffo rded a full opportun ity to ~press the ir views on t ne appropriate leve ls of funding required t o assure quali t y educat ion as pa rt of the annua l Di str ic t of Colu:nb la budget prates!&amp;gt BE IT ENAC!E D ev r ~E E L EC~ORS OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA T~ a t thi, me~sure may ~e cited as the Di st r i ct of Col um bia ~uh l i c School Suppo rt Init iative of 1986 Sec 2. Oechr.t lon of Policy In r@'C ogn iti on of l The cr iti cal Impo rtance of high qual ity pub lt c educat ion for all stuaen ts in t he Distr ict of ColU111b la j The need i n Di strict of Co l umb i a Public Scnool s for sma l ler cl asses and suppl ementa l inst ruct ional resour~e s to address the Il t eds of the m~ny stuaent s requiring soeci dl ~tten t lon c) Th~ need t o att ract and re td in ~\ghly qual if ied t eaChers and principals {dl ,ne need for Dt strict of Columbi a Public School gr aduates to pO$Ses~ educat ional s il1s t hat render t~em compet ithe lt h graduates ot s ubur~an schools as rega rds ~ploymen t and higher educ at ion e The need to rest ore and repa ir sc hool fdcili t i es t hroug~ou t t he Oi str tc t of Co lumbl and f) The hct tha t In recent years the budget for the ll i str le t of Colu~~ia Publ ic Sehao l has increased at a rate substanti all y be low that of almost al l other Gls trl ct of Columbi a agencles IT IS HERESV DECLAR ED, that fun di ng of t h@ Public Schools be c kno~­ l!dged as of the highest pr io rity by the Dist r ic t of C oluntli Th is priori ty stat us fo r public education fundi ng will be given due consi dera_ t ion by the Distr ict of Col umoi a 90ard Of Education the Council of the District of Col~ota 4nd the Ma yor of the Dis tr ic t of Col~bia In all fu ture proposa ls recQmmend~t ions. and le91 s 1 ati v enact~e n ts d f fectj~g f ln~ncia l .up per t of the Pub lic SchoolS. Ptlbl tc Hea rin2s In f Ur therance of th is decl~red policy and in order to afford t ne people of t he DIstr ict of Col~bi a d full oppor t uni ty t o express their .iews on t he f isca l need s of he Publi c Schools t he following pub l ic hearin9s and transmissions of nNri ng rec~rds are requi red a) Withi n a per i od or not more t n,n gO or l ess t han 45 days prior t o the annual sub~issio" by the Dist r ict of Col ia SOard of Educat ion of a proposed budget t o t~ Mayor of t he Dis trict of Colu3bia and upon IS days publi c notice the Boa rd of EducHion s hall con duct a public hearing f o r the pur pose of so licit i ng t he vi s of the pub lic on programs &amp;lt;l nd levels of p~bl i c funding t o be SOlJght for the Public Schools The budget proposed by the Board of E~uC4t ion s~a ll cons i stent ith the publ ic pol icy dec la red In th is measure, gi ve due cons iderat ion t o the record establ i shed by t he test i any and Uh lbi t s on the subjects lh ted In s ubs ection (d of t his sect i on. The 90ard of Education shal l transmit the record of t his hearing t o the .ltayor of the District of Columbh and to t he Council of the District of Columbia at or be fore t he hear i ngs held by t h~ pursuant t o subsect ions (b) and (c) of tn i s section l b) Within a period of not more than 60 days or l ess than 30 days prior to t yor s annual \ubmission of a ~udget retonmendat lon w j h res pec t t o tM Publi c School s to th e Council Of the Di s tr ic t of Colum:Jia, and upon 15 days publ ic notice the Mayor of the Distri ct of Colu~j a shall conduct a publ ic hear ing for th e pu rpose of soli ci t i ng the ~le s of the public on levels of public funding to be ~nught for the Public SchoolS In no e ~ent shall th1s hearing be prior t~ t he annua l SUbmission by the District of Colu~il Board of Educati on of its proposed budget to the ~ator The Public ScI'Ioo1 s budget recom:1lendation sub ittl!il by th e Mayor to tile Council of the (li strict of Colu1lt.lj Sh411 cons istent &amp;gt;lit h t he puoli, polity decl ared in t his ~asure. gi ve due consid@rat i on to t~e r@cord establi shed by t he testimony and @xh;bit s on the subj ect s lis ted in Subsection (d) of t~15 section The ~ayor sha ll t ransmit the record of this hearing t o the Council of the l ;trlct of Columbi a t or befo re the hearing ~eld pursuant to subSection (c of t~is section c) At th@ pub H hearings requl r@d oy Section 446 of the Dist ri ct of C31u.bia 5@ l f -Government and Governmental ~eor9anilation Act approved Dec 24 1973 [ 87 Stat 801; D. C. eaoe 47 -304 1981 ed dnd Supp 1985 the Counci l of the District of Columb ia, not ~re t han 30 day~ or l ess than 15 days be fore the adopt ion of t ne 3udget Requ@st Act Shall solicit tes tinony and e lhlbi t s on t he suojec ts li sted at subsect ion (d) of this sect l en, dnd cons i stent with tM@ public policy declared in this measure sha ll adapt! budge t 91 1;og due consideration t o the record established by the t e~ tlmony and @~hibit5 on t~ose Subjects 4 d) The hearings required by subsections (a b) and (e) of this section shall solicit and recei~e testimony and exhibits on the following subjects 1) The current and prospective educ~tional needs of pupils in t he District of Columbia Public Schoo l s, educational programs that can address these needs and support systems needed fo r safety and efficiency 2) The relative l evels Of sup~rt provided in recent years and sought in the current budget requests for the District of Columbia Public Schools and other agencies of the District of Columbia Government Particular ~ttention will be placed on the levels of funding provided in the past and sought for agencies such as the 8epartment of Corrections and the Depa rtment of Huma n Ser~ices. wh ich must address the probl ems resulting in part from an educational system that lac~s sufficient re- sources to address fu l ly the needs of all of its students 3) The programs and l eve l s of funding supported by the findings of relen nt professional studies and cOlTlllissions 4) The levels of funding for public schools systems in surround lng ju r isdictions that have reputat ion~ for providing high quality educd- tion to their students. Sec. 4 Severability. If any provision of this initiative or its application to any perso or circumstances is held invalid, t~e remainder of this in itiative, or tne application of the provision to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected s Sec. 5. Effect i ve O~te This measure s hall ta~e effect as provided for initiativ e measures Of the ~lectors of the District of Calumnia In section 3 of Public L~w 9S-256, amending the Initiative eferendum. and Recall Cnarter Amendments ~t of 1977 (O ,C. Law 2_46 and acts of the Council of tn t ~i$tr lc t of Columbia In secti on 602~c) of the Dis tri ct of Col umbia Self-Iioverm@nt and Gover~ntal Reorganizat i on Act.</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-916"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-917"/>
  </section>
</document>
