<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-81">
  <num type="law">7-81</num>
  <heading type="short">Juror Fees Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1988-03-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-81.pdf">D.C. Law 7-81</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 8115</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-81, the “Juror Fees Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-125, which was referred to the Committee of the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1987 and November 24, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 10, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-116 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU~CIl OF THE D]~TRI~T OF COLUMBlA NOTICE D.C LAW 7- BI 'J uror Fees Act of 198 7 Pur s ua nt to Section 41 2 of t he Distric t o f C0 1U llbfd Se lf- GO~@rnl'len t and Governllent~l Reorganization Act, P. L. 93 198 t he Act the ~oun,il of the Dis tr ict of Colu~bfa adopted 8111 11 0 7- 215 on f i r st and ~econd readin9S, Novelllber ]0, 1981 an d Novembe r 24. 1981 r espectively. Follo wing the s l9n uure o f the Mayo r on December 10 1987, ttlis legislation wu ~Bi9ned Ac t 7 _116 publi s hed i n the Decembe r 18, 1987 edition of the D. C. Regi.ter Vol. 34 page 8 11 5) and transmit t ed t o Co ngress o n December 21, 1987 for a 30 _day r e ie w in acco r dan ce with SHt i on 602(e)(l) of the Act. The Co uncil of the District of Columb ia hereby gives no t ic e that the 3D day Congressional Re vi e w Pe r iod tid; up i r ed, and ttle r efo r e, c ites this enac t ent as D. C. l" w 1-81. effecthe Mar c h 9 191111 CLAR KE of th e CounCi l Da tes Counted Du r i ng ttle 30 d~y ~o n9ressional Revie w Period; Decembe r 21.22 Ja~uary 25 26 27.28 29 Feb ruary 1 2 3 ,4 5 6 9 16 11,18,19.22 23 24,2 5 26 29 Mar c h 1 2,3 ,4, 1 6 O.C. U'W 7 81 MAR 0 9 1988 AN ACT O.C. ACT7-116 IN &amp;gt;'Ul: COU NCIL OF THE DI STRlCT OF COL Ut-1EIA DEC I 0 19S'1 To ~rov ide for ju r o r fees f o r Ju r ors se rving ~n the Super ior Cou r t of the District of Columbla BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU~BIA, Tha t this act may be cited as the "Juro r Pees Ac t o f 19Sr Sec. 2 Ti tl e IS o f the District o f Co l umbia Cwe is amended as f o llows 8) By ~endlng the tabl e o f con ten ts for the tit l by s trikIng t he ph ra s 7 Fees a nd COS t s ctions 15- 701 t o lS- 717 and inser tlng in ltS l/lace t he ph ra se 1 i'oes and Cos ts Sectl. ons 15- 701 to IS- 71 8 bJ By anending the tab l e o f con tents f or Ch e te r 7 by adding at the end the phrase "1 5-718 Juror f ees and (c) By adding e. new sect ion 15-718 to read aD f o ll ows Sect ion 15- 718 Juror fees a) A Juror Ger vinq in the Superior Court of the Distr ict of Columbia shall be pa id an attendance tee of SJO for each day of act ua l attenda nce at the ~l ace o f tr i a l o r hearing exc~pt that ju rors em~ l oyed by a fede r al, s tate, o r loca l 90ver~en t o r by a pr i vate e~ploycr who pays regula r co~pen sa tion du r ing the per iod o f Jury service shall not be paid an attendanc e f ee b) A t rave l a llowdnce not to e xceed $2 por day shall be Faid to all juro r s serving in the Superior Court o f the Di stric t o f Columbia Sec 1 This act sha ll take e ffect after a 30- day ~c r iod of Cong ressional review fol l owing app r oval cy the ayo r (o r i n t he even t o f ve t o by t he ayo r, actio n t;y the Council of the Dis t rict o f Columbia t o ove rr ~de the veto as p r ov i d ed in sectio n 602 (c)(1) of the Dis tr ict of Co l umbia Se l f o vcrnroent and GOve rnrr.ental RcOr gan i:o:at ion Act 1 c. e itl" 1~ 091111 f&amp;lt;Upo Toe Chapt e T" 7 t1 tl 15 l9~R i \l N o.c. Code sec 15-11 11 (1988 SlL?p Enrolled Or ig l~al a pFt"oved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat 8131 D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 ayor Distt"ict APPROV ED of Columbia December 10, 1987 of the District of Columbia 2 ASON COUNCIL OF TU£ DISTRICT OF COlL'MBIA C"uncil Period s IX ~CT 'O N &amp;amp; OA I E x ~OIC OTE Fl&amp;amp;co,1letl V01e on oeQu RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCil VOTE DOCKET 1i0 Adopted Fi rs t Re ading 11 10 -87 Un nimous Ro lark and Smith B7 -215 'I 1 7 r Dale x eTlON &amp;amp; CA TE, X ~OICE VOTE ROl l C"ll VOTE cnON OAH VO ICE VOTE tcO d vO 0&amp;lt;1 'OQu 1I0ll CAll ~or£ I Ado:?ted Fin_al Reading, 11- 24 87 Unanimous Jarvis and R~J O&amp;lt;"ei",y 'o In eo'"Cil </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
