<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-82">
  <num type="law">7-82</num>
  <heading type="short">Rate of Interest on Judgments and Decrees Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-03-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-82.pdf">D.C. Law 7-82</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 8117</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-82, the “Rate of Interest on Judgments and Decrees Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-269, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1987, and November 24, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 10, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-117 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUt/CIL OF THE O[STRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTI CE n c LAW 7· 82 "Rate of In ter es t on Judgment. and Detrees Act of 1987 Pur s uant to Section 412 of the Dist r ict of Colum~ia Se1 f Go va r n~ent and Govern.en t a l Reorganllation Act. P. L. 93 198 the Act the Counc il o f the Dlst r lct o f Cohi.bi ad op t ed 8i11 MO. 7· l69 on f irst an d seco nd readi n9s ove.ber 10 1987 and ~o ve.ber 2 4 1981 re5pettive y. Foll ooling the signature o f th e "ayo r o n December 10 198 1 th is le g l sht ion wu assl9ned Act 7. 1 11, publishe d In the Dece.ber 18.1987. edition of th e D.C. Re giste r Vo l 34 p~ge 8 11 l) dnd t r ans mitted to COng reS 5 on De e e.beT 21, 1987 for a lO _day rev i e w. In acc o rdance with Section 602(c}(l) of the Ac t. The Council of the Di st ri c t of Co lu.b ia he re by gives no t ice that the l D· day Con greuional Rev ie Pe r io d has uplred. and therefo r e ci tes thh e ntc tment is D. C. La w 1. 82, effe c t i ve Mar Ch 9 1988. Daus Co un t ed Du r ing the 30 4ay Cong r ess ional Rev ie w Per iod: Oeteabe r 21,22 Jan u.ry 2S 26 17 28 29 Februa ry 1.2 3 .4 .5.8 9 16 17 18 19 22.23 24. 25 26.29 Har c h 1.2 3 4 7.8 IDroll!d Or1,l Dal MAR 0 9 198 1'1 ACT D.t m 7 -117 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DI STRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC I 0 1987 To amend sectio n 28 02 {c l at t he District o f Columb1a Cod e to pr ovide a single rate at i n t eees t f o r judg~ents and decrees When the judgme nt o r decree is not against the District of Columbia and when the rate ot interest is not fixed by contract BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL Of THE DISTRICT OF, COLUMBIA, That this a c t may be cited a s the Rate of I nterel t on Judgpents a nd Decrees Act of 1987 Sec 2 Section 28 02 o f the Dis t r i ct of Columbia code is ame nded a s tollows a) Section 28- 3)02(b) is amended by inserting the phrase or its Office rs or its employees acting within the scope of the ir empl oyment after the phrase "DistrlCt o f Co l umbia and (b) Se ction 28 30 2(c is OJIIended by 1) Inserting the phr ase o r its office r s o r its employees acting within the scope of t heir empl o yment" after the ~hra se "Distric t of Co l u~ia 1 and (2) S t r iking t he phrale "section 6621 ot the Inter nal Revenue Code of 1954, approved January i 1975 (88 Stat 2114; 26 U. S C. sec 6621) for underpaY1:len t !l and ove rpayme nts of tax to the Internal Revenue Service and inserting the phrase "sect ion 662 1 o f the Interna l Revenue Code o f 1986, approved OCtober 22 1986 1 00 Stat. 2744; 26 U.S.C. 6621 for underpayments o f tax to the Internal Revenue Service, rounded t o t he nearest full per cent, o r if e xac tly 1/2 of I t, i ncreased t o the next h ighest full percen t" in its place Sec 3 Applicabil i t y Section 2 shall apply to intere.t rates on judgments and dec rees ente r ed a fter July I, 1987 1 D. C. Code amp;1!&amp;lt 28 02 (1'188 IUpp t1 D. C. Ct&amp;gt;de, sec 2S-JJ02 (1988 aup £nrolle~ Orig1~ Sec 4. The Rate of Interest on Judgements and Decrees Temporary Act of 1987, signed by the yor on October 26, 1987 (Act 7- 94; to be codified at D. C. Code, sec 28-3302 is repealed. Sec 5. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Ilayor (or in the event of veto by the Hayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 Chairl':lan ouncil of the District of Columbia }~:iO'Of APPROVED: December 10. 1987 (J. 2 Repealed, D.C. Act 7-94 (1988 SllPP t'\ 1'fltI :l ACTION Do. f E: IX VOICE votE. R""o 0tI Qu l COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Couacil Pt riod Sevn RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTe DOCKET NO 7C 9 Adopted First Reading. 11-10- 87 UnaniJnou.!5 Ro h:r;:k a nd Smith CTION! DATE A"d~o'p"t dl.JFC 0 d 0 C-,2 lt ]7 VOICE VOTE U,o o"i~rnOo"u fIeco«l J~rvis and Ray r: 0I01t e L VOllE IlESUlT o=l l 1-J n ACOON, OAT VO~E ~f 001 req 1 5« 00 0 tho Gounc Dot </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
