<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-9">
  <num type="law">7-9</num>
  <heading type="short">D.C. Income and Franchise Tax Conformity and Inheritance and Estate Tax Revision Act of 1986 Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1987-06-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-9.pdf">D.C. Law 7-9</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 3283</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-9, the “D.C. Income and Franchise Tax Conformity and Inheritance and Estate Tax Revision Act of 1986 Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-129, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 31, 1987 and April 14, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 6, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-20 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>:OUNCL O~ ToE ~lSHICT OF COLU~Bj~ NOTIC °n .c. Income anc Ff~nchise Tn Qnf o rmi~y a ~j ;nn er a nce and Es!ate Tax "evision Act of 1986 A~end nt Act of !987 Pursud n t to Section 412 of the lIi ~tric~ of Co lu mbi d Sel f. Gov e rnmen t and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93 -1 9a th e Act t he Co un c11 of the District of Columbia adopte d Bil l No. 7-12 9 on first and second readings iarch 31, 1 987, and Apr il 14, 1987, re spectively. Fo ll owin~ the signature of t he Mayor on )oIay 6, 1987. this leg isl ation was assigned Act 7-2 J, publis hed 1n t he )oIay 22. 1987, edition of the D.C. Reg ist er vo l 34 page 3283) and traHmitted to Congress on )oIay 8, 1987 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 60,(c)(l) of tnl! Ac t. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gi~~s nati that the 30-day COngressional Redew Pe r iod has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. L~w 7-9, effective June 24. 198 of the Counci 1 Dates Counted During the 30-day COngressional Review Perio d: Mo, June 8.11,12,13 ,14 ,15,18,19,20,21.27,28,29 1,2,3,4 ,S ,8 ,9 ,10,11.12 .15 .16 .17,18.19,22.23 O.C. LAW 7 S AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 -20 IN THE COUSCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To continue the District o f Co lumbia conformity it~ t edera l i ncome tax prov ision! in the trea~.nt o f certain items of incom. and d.duction. amend.d by the Feeeral Tax Refon'll Act of 1986. to provide an exclulion from taxa ble income 0 t S 3.000 ot taxa ble pen. ions ree. i ved by Distriet of COlumbia and ted.ral employ and t o amend an effeetive date provision of the Inh eritanee and E.tlt.tll Tax Revi. ion Aet of 1996. Br IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DIST~ICT OF COLU~BIA, That this aet may cited a. the "01.trict of Columbia Incom. and Franchis Tax conformity and Inheritanee and Estat. Tax R.vision Act of 1996 Amendm.nt ACt of 1997 Sec 2. The Di.trict of colurobia Incoma a nd Franchise Tax A&amp;lt t of 1947. approv.d .July 16, 1947 61 Stat. 331: D. C. coe sec. 47-1901 et g i. amended as follo s a) Title I, s.&amp;lt tion 4 (bb D C. Code e 41-190 1.4 29 ») is amend ed to read a. tollow bb) Th e t.,rm "Inter nal Revenu. Code at 1986" m.ans the Int.,rnal R.v.,nu, Code of 1986. approved Octobe r 22. 1986 (100 Stat 2085; 26 USC I et g Internal R.venu. Code of 1986 b) Titl.1. nction 4 (j It e l t u v w aa O.C. Cod ne. 41-1801.4 10 11 19 20 21 22 23 ll }) is am.nded by etriltin9 the phu Internal Revenue Code of 1954" wherever it app.ars and inserting the phrase "In ternal Revenu. Code of 19B6~ in its pl ae c titl. 2 etion 1 (O.C Cod sec. 4 7- 1802.0 is amended by .triking th phrase "Int.rnel Rev.nue Code o f 19 54" wher.ver its appears and inserting the phrase "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" in its plaee d title 3, sectiQn 2 e 2 D.C. Cod ee 4 1-1803 .2 a 2 i. amended by adding a new subparagraph I S to r.ad e" follows 1 O. c. Cede, see H·190:.4 (1988 S'.lp9 D.C. Cede, sec 1- 1801. 4 See suo:9 O.C sec. 47"18D2 1 (1988 s1.:W.l o.c. ODe. s 1803.2 (use supp en aio o r an i t:y t m. o r sur-v J n.t .l s r,c ved !rorn t:~e Di i c t. o t o m tl a o r ro eder gove r r.tent y persons he a 62 Y"!l.r s 0 age c r older y t e e nd of t.he t axat:le y" ar, eltcept that i) The eltclus;'or hall no t xceed e 1 r o f $3 000 or t he a c t. u al 6lDC",nt. o f the pe:lsion o r a nnui t y r ecelv.d eurtng the taltat:le year a ne ii I The pension or annu i ty i.'l othe i.'l e lubjec t to taxation nee r t hi, articlll e Tit l 3. s e ctio n 2 a and b D .C. Co de ee 4 7- 1803. 2( a a nd b ») 11 a nd.d by t.r ki~g t.he phn e I n terna l Ilevl!nue Code 0: 1954 her eve r it a ppears "ne in,erting the phr ase "Internal Revenue Code ot 1986" in its place Titl etion 3.3 a lind b D.C. Code. se·c 4 7- 180).3 a a nd 01) 11 amend..d. by .triking t he phra,e Internal Reve nue Code o f 1 954 wher.ve r it app.a r. arod in.erting the phr Int.rnal Revenue Code of 1986" in it.s pllee g) Tit.le 4 eetion 4 D.C Code e c. 4 7 180 4.4 s a",ended by striking the phrase "Internal Revenu. Code of 195 4 wherever it ppear. a nd i n rting t.he phra s e I nte rna l R.venue Code of 1986" in its pla.ee. t h Title 5, sect ion l(d) ID .C. Code c. 47-180S.1 11 amended. by striking the phrase "Internal R.venue Code of 1954 whe r e ver it appe.rs a nd inserting the phrase l n t.rnal Revenu. Code of 1986" in it. place H Title 6 lIIeet ion 5 (c D.C. Code e. 4 1 1806. 4 e is iI.In.nded l:Ff .triking the phr.,e "Int ernlll Revenue Cod e of 1954" wherever it IIppe.rs lind inserting t he phr alle "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" in its place j) Title 9 etlon 10 (O.C. cod ne. 4 1- 180 l O) i amended l:Ff striking the phrase I nte r nal R.v.nue Code ot 1954 wh.rev.r it appeer. li nd ins.rt ing the phr.se lnternll l Revenue Code of 198 6 in it~ pl.ee. Ot) Title 11 e t ion 1 (D.C Code e. 47-1811. 1) is amended l:Ff lIItriking the phra Interna l Revenu. Code of 1954" vh.r .ver it II ppea rs lind i nsert i ng the phrase "Internal R.venue Cod. of 1986" in its place 1) Title 11, section 2 (D.C. Cod see. 41-1Bl1.2) is ~ended l:Ff striking the phrall Internlll Rev.nu. Cod. Of 195 4 vher e ver it a ppellrs ar~ in.ert ing the phr.se I n ternal R.venue Code of 1 986" in its plaee m) Title n. section 4 (D.C Cod sec 41-1811.4) i. amended l:Ff lIItri king the phrase In te r nal Rev.nue Code of 1954" vherever it a ppe ar. and in.e rt ing the phralle "Internal Revenue Code ot 1986" in its place n) Title 12. sec tion 8 (b D .C Cod e ee. 4 7 1812. 8(b i. am.nd.d by striking th. phra In t. r nal 2 D.C 0;&amp;amp sec 7 303.2 (Ina !I:n;&amp;gt D.C COde. sec. 47- 180 3.3 (1988 supp I.C see 7-180 4 (In8 SIJW O.C. COde. sec. 47- 1BD5.l (1988 ,u;:op D. C. COde. sec. 47-1B06.4 (1988 5I.lPP D.C. Cc:x1e. sec H 1809 .10 [1988 supp D.C. axe sec. 41- 18U.1 (1988 l D.C COde. sec. 41- 1811.2 (1988 sv;p D. C. Ca::\.e. sec. 41-1811 1988 S\lPP D.C. cede. sec. 47-1812.8 UgeS Npp Revenue C~c o f 1954 n e ve io; a ppean, a:lc ~r:se i:lg h s~ H I :l~erna l Re venue Cod e o f 19S6" l~ i s pla ce Sec. 3. S c";ion 2 2 and 3 1l o f ehe !nh i~a:lce and E s ea e Ta:o; Revi,iotl c t of 1986 f£ecciv e e!:ln.la:"y 2&amp;lt 1987 (D.C. L.a 6-168; D. C Cooe, ncs. 47-3701(2) lI.:ld 47-37 0 2 a » a re amended by strikir.g t.h phra!le Orl or aft. e: t h e effec ti v da te o f o f t his ac and in$e tin9 ~he phra u "on o r ate.r pril I, 198 7" in io;s pl.c S'c. 4. Applicability a Except fo s.ct io ns 2 (d arld ccion 3, the provisions of this act sha ll apply i n the sam nner a!l p rovid ed i n the Tax R form ~ct approved Oc tober 1986 (100 Stilt. 2085; 26 USC 1 for ~he taXlible years beginning before J nua y b th. p rovision. of d shall apply for 1 taxable year bag innins alter l1, 1985. but be!o r e January 1, 1987 e) The provisiotle of section 3 "hall apply a. of effective date of this act. the S c. S. This act shsll take effect after lO-day pe r iod. of Congressional review fo l(owing approval by the Mayo r (o r in ~he event ot veto by t he Mayor action by ~he Council a t the District at Col~bia e o overr ide ~he ve~o a s provid d in section 602 e lJ of ~h. District ol Columbia Self-Gov rnm nt and Governmental Reo r qani zation Ac t, approved Decembe r 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; O.C. Code, s ec. 1-233(c 1» tharnn..n Coune il of the District of Columbia of tcoL i. APPIOJttI By 6, 1987 J D.C C:;rle sec 3702 :l96a Self C.C. C::Ce. sees 7-laO:.4 ,laO 1602.1,-190 2 IS03.3,-lSO 1805 306 1309 18: 1 811.4 1612. 6 (1996 supp Not e. D.C. COde, sec, 47-1603 1988 SUW No D C::rie NC. 47- 3702 (198 11 COt:NCIL OF THE OISTRI CT OF COLl tBIA C til P.riod Sevtu RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOT E OOGKET NO 0 CTION &amp;amp; nAT Md"l dL C,&amp;lt i lt 3'-oJll il 0: Y~CE VOTE 3 i,m'0 lt;"Ol.a u Clarke Crdwforc and Jd~is t-itC lt;7 Ii ACTION l 010. n AO P 3 cl,'3 i,'3 Unanimous Jt ~O I CE ~OTE c RKOOl on requ Winter C on eor C ACooN' OATe C VOICE YOU K lt lt;&amp;gt on U bO,.</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
