<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-90">
  <num type="law">7-90</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1988-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-90.pdf">D.C. Law 7-90</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 710</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>• COU ~CI OF T~E D[5~RJ:T IF (C~JHB[~ 11 0T ICE Jj s triC t o f C lu mb j~ Ce rt i f ic ate o f !Ieeo act of 1980 A~ e ~dmen t Act of 19B7 t.~e Ae t~e Cou nc i 1 of e Jistric Jf l.·n~l~ J ,j,] j Si\ ~4"U dr S 19a8 reSDect! ve1 Fol10 ln~ the il J Jr2 o~ t 14d:/O f on Jan u~ ry n 1988 t ilts legisl at ion 15 dal"n lt;1 c t 1 132, p bl1;h e n the February 5 1988 ed l :1 o n u f t D. C. Re gister 1 0 1. 35 page 710 and tr ans ll i tt ed to Cong r ess on Ja nu a ry 28 1968 for a 30 day r evie w. i n acc ordant e with Sf t iOn 602(c){ 1) o f th e Ac t. The lu o(:l1 o f the Di s tr ict o f Col "IlObia ~er eb J gl ~es no t ice that the 3D day Congres siona l Revie w Pe riO d has e pired anc t he r e fore, tH e s this e n actment a s D.C: Lol l&amp;lt; 7-90 effec tiv e Harc h 16 198 11. Dato Count ed Curi ng the 30·d Jy Congr essi ona l R e ~ie e rio d: J a nuary 28. 2 9 Feb r lld rl 1. 2 3 ,4 iI, 8 9 16. 1 7 .1 8 ,19 22 ,23 24 2 26 29 H~rcll 1.2 3.4.7,8 9.1 0 11 ,14,1 5 D.C. LAW 7 9 0 i MAR 1 6 1988 AN ACT C. ACT 7 -13 .2 IN THE COl]t!CIL OF THE DI ST lt;IC~ 0 COU::W :l To ame nc the District 0: Col~mbi Certifica o f Need Ac t o 1980 t o aut~.orlze t:'l~ S t:"te Heal:h I':an n&amp;lt and ~evelo9~en t Agency to ado?t cetallec re9ula:io~z conceI:"ning t ht rov1510n of &amp;lt co{:1?ensated ell re r heal th care ?rov iders see kin~ certi f icates c need BE: I T E~ACTEO BY tJE: COUNCIL or THE DISTRIC OF' CCLU nv T~~t t his act ~ay be cited as t he Di s tric t o f Columbia Certifiea te o f Need Ac t o f 1980 Amendment Act of 198 7 Sec 2. The Distric t of Colur::bia Certifica te o f Need Act of i98 0, ef f ec tive SeF t ember 16 1'180 (D. C Law 3 lt;)9; D.C Code, sec 32- 301 et seq is al endec as f o ll o \Os a SeCtlOn 6\a \2 D.C Coae sec 3 2-3 0 5(&amp;lt;1)(2 is amended t o re~d as f o l lows 2 he &amp;lt;lppl ican t, if ~t operates on II ~ec-for-service bas is and has not g i ven assur a nces pursuan t t o sec t ion 603{ti) o r section 1532(c) {6) {e) of the Public health Se rvice Ac t, app r oved July 1, 19 ~4 58 S t a t 6821 4 2 U. S C 291c(e) o r 300n 1(c ){ 6 1 (e )l, has qiven equl.valent a ssu r ar.ces to the SHPDA and is i n compliance wl. t h any a ssurances glven pu rsu ant to this subsectio n in a pre vl.ou s c ertificate of need appl ica tion b Sect.ion 6«1 D. C Code, sec 32- 305(a» is amended by adding a new parag r aph (3) t o r ead as f ollows 3 1 In ad opt l.ng r egu latio ns i n acco rd&amp;lt;lnce with section 17, the SHPDA shall adopt, wi t h in 9 0 days, cCm pr ehens ive, de tailed r egulations t o ens ure th~t com p ll.ance with the assu r a nces given pursuant to th i s ubsec tion is achieved and ma intained by th e applic&amp;lt;ln The SHPDA may adopt iden tical o r sepa r ate r egulation s for acili t l.es cesc r ibe d in parag r aphs (1) a nd 21 a thl.S sub sec tion Sec 3. Thi s act s hall take e f fe c t a ft e r a 30-day period of Congression a l r e v iew f o ll owing apFrov~l by the layo r o r in thlt event o veto by the l:ayor. action by the f c. Coc'iI2. sec. U-Y 1988 s Counc i l o f t he ~i st r~ct o f Co l u~i ve r c the veto as covic cd oy sec t on 602( c 1 0 t t-.e C st r ict of Col r_=l..l self- Gov r nr..ent an cO C:cverr.ma t &amp;lt;l l E",o r gil niza t!.o ct, dfproved DeccmbE 2 4, 1973 87 Stat SU C. C Coce I!C 1- 2 3){c 1 C lt;lI l.=r..a Counc l o f e e i str~c t c iUMbl. a o Co lUr."Ibia APPROVED JANUARY 25, 1988 COL L m' iH f; DISTRICT 0, COt.IJ~IIlL-\ CQu ncii Period en REC ORD OF OFFICI AL COUNCil VOTE IlCCKE l al p e e rt~ 1I0ll CAU OT RE~ULT X VOIC E VOT a. n i:nou s ecO,&amp;lt;Ie&amp;lt;I ¥or all E&amp;gt;.rt:.sent ROll CALL VO TE RESU LT c c c It on Cen nt Cale c riON sCArE YO ICE VOTE ecc 4 en Q ue. t ~Oll CALL VOTE RESULl c i •</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
