<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-92">
  <num type="law">7-92</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-92.pdf">D.C. Law 7-92</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 716</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-92 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-321, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 8, 1987 and January 5, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 25, 1988, it was assigned Act. No. 7-134 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>CCU ~CI L OF THE OISTRICT Of COLU H BI~ NOTI CE Distri c t o f Colu lU o ld Election s Cede o f 1955 II endment Act o f 1987 u r sudnt to Sec t ion 4 12 o f tile Distri ct o f ~ol u'l;bi a Self~ Go ~ern m ent dnd Go~er nmen t al Reoryantzat i on II P. L. 93 198 the Act the Co un c il o f th Olstrin o f Colum bia adop ted Bill NO. 7 321 on fI rst and secon d readings December S 1987. an~ J anudry S 1988 re-s pe c tive l y. Followi ng the i gn~tlJ n' of the Mayo r OJn Janua ry 25 198 8 tills legis lation was assigned Ac t 7-134 published in the Feb r uary S. 1988 ed1tlon of the O, C. Reg ister {'lo l 35 page 716) and transmitted t o Congress on J &amp;lt;lnuary 28 1988 fo r a 30- day re- v ie w. in Hcordan ce with Secti o n 602(cj{1} of th e Act. Th e Council o f t ile- OI~ tr1&amp;lt t of Coiumbi '} hereby &amp;lt;Ji ves nOJt ic e therefo r e cites thi$ enac trn e t as a c L~ w 7-92. e f fect i ve HH ch 16 19 88 Co u nei 1 t es Cou n ted During the JO-dJY Con UreSS -J na l Rev ie w Pe r i od; Janu~ ry 28 29 Feb r u ary 1 2 3 ,4.5. 8 ,9,1 6 17 ,1 8 19, 22 ,23. 24, 25 26 29 I~dr ~h 1 2 3 ,4, 7.8 ,9, 10 11 14 15 n.c. LAW 7 9 2 D"Q MAR 1 6 1988 A" ACT D.C.ACT 7 -134 II lil COUKCIL OF THE DISTRIC OF COLut·:llIA JAN 2 5 19S8 TO a~end the Advisory Neighborhood Council s Act of 1975 to allo\\' 90 days for filling vacancies and to amend An Act To regulate tho election of delegates ~ep~e5entLng the Di~trict of ColuQbia tc na tional political conventions, and for other ~urposes, to update the election law5. l:iE I~ l.:KACTLD BY IIJ COGNCIL OF HE DIS RICT OF COLlJ!lE I A That this act nay be cited 5 the "Distrcict of Columbia elections CoG" of 1955 Amend nt Act of 1987 CGDIFICA.T: Jf D.C. Code (1;88 sunp Sec. 2. Section 8(d 2) of the Advi so r y Ne i ghborhood Sec 1- 2S 7 Councils Act of 19 75 effective Oct-obet" 10, 197 5 (D C Law 1-21; D. C. Code, SeC. 1-257(0)(2 is amended by s t riking the number "60" a;,d i nserting tha nlIDber "90 n i t s place. Sec. J An Act To requlate the elect ion of delegate representing t he District of Columbia to n a tional political conventions, a nd for o t her purposes, approv ed August 12 1955 (69 Stat. 699; D C. Code, Sec. 1 1301 e t seg is amended as follows: l a Sect ion S ib 2 9.C Code, sec. 1-1306(b 2 15 a~endcd as follows 1) Ey striking the hra se "the ca ndidates and 2 By inserting after 1 ,000" the pr.J;ase OJ; 1 whichevcJ; is less, of the b) Section S i b 3 D,C Code, Se c_ 1 1306( b 3 is amended dS follows 1) Subparagral-'h (A i is ended a s fo11ol-i S A) By striki ng the phrase "the c andida te for llor:1ination f or President s u?ported by the slate and E By inserting af t er 1 ,000" t he phrase cr 1 ° hichcver is less, of the Sec. 1- 13J6 Sec. 1-1305 (2) Subparagraph (A ii is Mended by i nserting after "l,OOO~ the phr se or 1 whichever is less, of the 3) Subparagt:"ph (A iii) is amended by ins orting after "1000" the phrase or 1 I&amp;gt;lhichever is less, of the a nd (4) Subparagraph (A iv) is amended by insertir.g after "1,000" the l'hrase or 1 whichever is less, of the c) Section S(b)!J D.C. Code, sec. l-l306(b)(J is amended by adding a new SUbparagraph (C) to read as follows C) The governing body of each eligible party shall file with the Board, no later than 180 days pr~or to the presidential preference primary election i) l;otification of that p a rty s intent to conduct a presidential preference primary; and ii) A plan for the election detailing the procedures to be fallowed in the selection of individual deleg ates and alternates to the convention u~ that party, i ncl uding procedures for the selection of committed and uncommittad delegates d) Section 7(d D.C. Code, sec. 1-1311(d is anended to read as follows d) After J a nuary 1, 1976, the Bo"-rd shall distribute a sufficient quantity of such forms to district libraries firehouses, police stations, and government agencies i n the District of Columbi and whatever other places in the District of Colur.lbia, as the Board dcems appropriate. In addi tion to the above nentioned.locations, the Board shall, where i t deems appropriate, or "Fon request, distribute a sufficient quantity of forms to post offices, schools, churches, settlement houses, and food est a blishments in the District of Columbia e) Section 7(e D.C. Code, sec. 1-1311(e is anended by striking in the last sentence the phrase "mails such registration notification to the applicant" and inserting the phrase "determines that the applicant is a qualified elector" in its place f) Section 7(f D C. Code, sec. 1-1311(f s a",ended as follows 1) fly striking tne number "5" and inserting the nUl:1ber "14" i n its place 2) By striking the number n7" and insertin the number "30" in i ts place; and (3) Dy dding the fo11m"ing af ter the 2nd sentence In the absence of respo nse fran the 2lPFlicant f te r n.e spec~fied 14-ciay period the Boara shall cancel the challenged registration "Fplication and endorse On the pplication tho \;ords "received bot not accepted 2 Sec 1·1306 SEC. 1-.311 Sec. 1-1311 SEC. 1-1311 g) Section 7(f- l)(3) ID C. Cocc sec 1- 131lIf l 3» Sec.1-iJ!1 i s amended by s tr1king t he phrase within 2 weeks" and 1nsertlng the hra:;c -withI~ 30 days in i ts lac e h I Scctlon 8 (a)(D C Code, sec 1- 1312 a l l IS ur.lendcd Sec. \-1312 as follo 11 lr/l&amp;lt;;lraph (lIlA) IS ar.:ended by insertIng tr hrase or 1\, whiChever is less of the" after the nUr.lbcr 50 0 ar.d 2) Paragraph (2) is amended by insertIng the hr a se" or 1 whiChever i s l ess of the" after the m:l7lber lOa 1) Sectlcn 8 1j) 111 (O C Code sec 1-1 312 I j)I1» is Sec. \-13IZ a~ended by st r Iking t ne nu~ber -1 14" and inserting the nunbe r -12 3- 1n 1tS place j gt;ectlon 8(1 D. C Cede sec 1- 1312(1 1 is Sec. 1-1312 anended as follo s 1) Paragraph (1 D C. Code Sec. 1- 1312(1)(1» is anended by s trI king the number "9 0 and inserting the number 180 in its place; and 2 Paragraph (2 D.C Code sec 1-1312(1 2» IS anc nded t o read as follows 2) T noti f ~c tlon shal l pecify scr,arut.ely \) 1\ cOr:J!Jrehensive pia for thu scheduled elec tIon D) Tr.e titles of the o f fices and the tot .i!l number o f members t o be elected t larg e, if any I C he title of t~e cf~ices and t~c total number o f r:.embers to be el ected by wa r d, i f any; and "l U) The proceautcs to be fol1 o ed in nOI:1ina ting and e l ec ting these menl;:e(s p Scct~on 8 lD C. Cod sec 1- 1312 is a~endec l;:y adding new subsection I rl to read as f ol l ows Ir l) In any pr l r:Jary lt;;Iener l or special clectio~ he l d in the Oistrict t o nOr:Jlnate o r elect candidat~ti to pub l ic o ffi Ce a voter nay cast a wrlte-ln vote for candida te other than t hose who ha ve suall f ied t o ppear on the ballet 1:1 pll rtr offic" electIons rite-in votIng "rovi sio may be subject t o the party rul 2 o be eligibl e to ruceive the nom I nat i on of u po l itica l arty for public office a write-in candIda te shall be it duly r eg istered r.lel':lJ::er the par ty from \;r.ich nOmind tec a~d sha l l meet all th~ c r qu al ifleaticns req~ircd Qr e l ections to the o~f l ce 3 0 be elIgIble fo r electIon to ~ub l ic uffIC a ["ltC- in cilnaidata shall be u duly reyHltCrCu elector ana shall pee t all of t he other qualificatiOn s uired for elec t lon to t he off I ce IJ S"et~O 'l 9 lD.c. Code sec l- lJ13(C») I S l:nCI1&amp;lt d Ly "I':lCnOlllg the f irSt 2 ~entcnc "s to r(l.ld "s follow s J Sec. 1-1312 f hrJ. 8A voter s act o f s i gning a challenged bal l ot envelope 5h~ 11 be deemed the filing of an appeal by the voter of the refu sa l o f tho Board to le t the voter vote on e l «ct ion day lly regu lar I;l~llot a nd a \o'aiver of personal notice from the BOard of a ny den ial o r refusal to a later count o f the challenged ballot No earlier than 8 days and no later than 10 dDYs after t he date of a ny electio n held under thLs ac t, the BOd rd shal l conduct a hea ring on the pet ition of any v ote r 'iho cast a chall e nged b~ l lot in the «lection t o have that voter s vote COUnted in the sa~e manner as al l other ballets cast in t hat e l ect~on he Board shall info rl:l the voter of the dates scheduled f or the hearing in the wr i tten notice o f the voter' s righ ts of appual provided in accorda nce 'w'1th thi s s",bsection In addition, o n th e 2nd I.'ednesday fo llo wing the e lecti o n the aoard sha ll publi sh in at lea st 1 newspaper of gene r a l ci r cu l a tion thQ naQCS o f al l per sons hose cha ll enycd ball o ts it has Ln~tLally cetet::o.ine d not to count. 8 r:1 Section 1 0(d D. C Code, sec l-lJ14( d is amended by striking the nu~ber "IS" and inserting the nu~ber 25" i n i t s place Cnl Zection 16 CD. C Cod e, sec 1-1320 is cnded as ~ol lo'w's 11) Subsection (d) is amended by striking tl pcr~od at the end ~nd insertinq t he phrase and publi~h t he summa ry stat~ent, snort t it le, and legislative fo r m in the O.C Register and Ln a newspaper o f q e ner al circu lation in its place 2 Subsect ion (e )II"L is amended by s triking the phr ase "s uch person r eceive s such summary statement, shor t title and leqislative fo r m" and i nserting the phra se "the Board publi shes the sUl'l/'Ja ry s tatement, shoet title, dnd leglSll'l t ive for in the D. C. Register and in II nel/spaper of gene ral Circu l a tion" in its p l ac e 3) Subs ec tion (g) is amended by st riking the Fhrollse 8 ith a ma rgin o f one lind t. h r eo ljua rtar s inches at t he t o gt; t o all o w for bindlng 4) Sub SeC t Lon (I) is ar:1e nded I:;y strlk ing the phrase "that the i ssue presented by the I?ctitio n is a p ro&amp;gt;,er s~b jec t for initiative or r e ferendum, whiChever is a ppl i ca ble, under t.he te r~s o f Tit l e IV of the Dist rlct of ~olu~bla $clf Governocn t a nd Covernmcnt31 Reor~~nl z at ion ACt 5 Subs ec ti o n (g is amended as f o llows A) Iiy insertlng t he phra s c "and surnm",Ci st&amp;amp;tc~ent" af ter the word ti tle B) by inse rtlnq the phrase sumna r y stll.ternent on tr.e lir.e 1 1 0 \ Init ia t~ve b :ll1sure 110 au Ie) By insert i ng the ph rase s mma ry st atu~e nt on the Il ne bel o Referende l!eaSUre 1;0 4 Sec 1-131~ Sec 1-132C ~o ec t.ion 1 7 (e){2 D. C Code Sec 1-1321[ C 21) is amended by str iking the phrase H,dth a r.1argin of one Inc! three guar t s inches at the top to allol/ for binding Sec 4 his act shall ta ke e ffec t af t er &amp;lt;I JO ]OIY penoe! of Congr"ssi onal revie f0110Ioli g aFFlC oval by the ayo r (or in the event o f veto by the r:.ayor action by the Council of the District 0 1' Colur.1bu to Qvel" r ide the veto a&amp;amp rovi6ed by section 602 c l(l) of the OistrLct of Columci&amp;lt;l Se l f-Governmen t and Gove r nmental Reo r ganIzation Act, approvlld Dl ccJ:lbcr 24, 1')73 (87 Ztat. 813; D. C Coda, sec 1-2 33 1) J DistlCict of Co lumbia DIst rI ct o f Columbla PROV[D: J.ll,llliAAY 25 19BB 5 t Sec. 1-1321 if 0 X ACT:ON DATE K VOIC E 'ICE COUCIIUL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU\IBIA COUDci] P eriod Seven RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE OOCKH NO dopt ed Fi_rst Re a ding, 12-8-87 t:nanimous ill1 present RESULT 87-321 Adopt ed Pi""l Reilding 1l i5 S,,8 J X ACTION 3. CATE- l IOICE '10TE- By Berubers Ray, MOason I'h l son "Cla ~aJor t v C irrnan ClarJk,e Q l~Q'Q Po co'd~d ,a1O on reco",1 ROLL CA LL von RESULT AC T IC DAT E J I~ C veH RO' c 0 oto on ron RO c ~A lL VOTE RESULT CER T I&amp;lt;ICAT IC~</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
