<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-105.06</num>
  <heading>Assistant to inspector commanding detective bureau.</heading>
  <text>On and after June 20, 1942, the Mayor of the District of Columbia may assign to duty as assistant to the inspector commanding the detective bureau in the Metropolitan Police Department any officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force and, during the period of such assignment, the said officer or member shall hold the rank and receive the pay of a captain of police and shall be eligible for assignment, by the said Mayor, as chief of detectives. For the duration of such latter assignment such officer or member shall hold the rank and receive the pay of a Deputy Chief of Police.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>June 20, 1942, 56 Stat. 374, ch. 427, § 1</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Merit system, application to police officers and firefighters, see § <cite path="§1-632.03">1-632.03</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-632.03">1-632.03</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 4-108.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 4-106a.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Office of Major and Superintendent of Metropolitan Police abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§5-105.01">5-105.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
