<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-109.01</num>
  <heading>Cadet program authorized; purpose; preference for appointment; appropriations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department shall establish a police officer cadet program, which shall include senior year high school students and young adults under 21 years of age residing in the District of Columbia who are graduates of a high school in the District, for the purpose of instructing, training, and exposing interested persons to the operations of the Metropolitan Police Department and the duties, tasks, and responsibilities of serving as a police officer with the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person successfully completing the required training and service in a cadet program established pursuant to this section shall be accorded full preference for appointment as a member of the Metropolitan Police Department or of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department, if the person shall have met all other requirements pertaining to membership in the chosen Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>There may be appropriated the funds necessary for the administration of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-172" type="History">Mar. 9, 1983, D.C. Law 4-172, § 2(a), (c), (d), 29 DCR 5745</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 832, 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-313" type="History">June 19, 2001, D.C. Law 13-313,§ 20(a), 48 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-194" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-194, § 402(b), 51 DCR 9406</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Cadet training programs, police officers or firefighters, funding and administration, see § <cite path="§38-912">38-912</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§5-109.02">5-109.02</cite> and § <cite path="§5-419">5-419</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-107.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite> rewrote subsec. (a), which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“The Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department may establish a police officer cadet program for the purpose of instructing, training, and exposing interested persons, primarily young adults residing in the District of Columbia, to the operations of the Metropolitan Police Department and the duties, tasks, and responsibilities of serving as a police officer with the Metropolitan Police Department.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-313">D.C. Law 13-313</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “21 years” for “the 21 years”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department” for “District of Columbia Fire Department”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 832 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
