<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-115.04</num>
  <heading>Legal assistance for police in wrongful arrest cases.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In accordance with regulations prescribed by the Council of the District of Columbia, the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia shall represent any officer or member of the Metropolitan Police Department, if he so requests, in any civil action for damages resulting from an alleged wrongful arrest by such officer or member.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the Corporation Counsel fails or is unable to represent such officer or member when requested to do so, the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall compensate such officer or member for reasonable attorney’s fees (as determined by the court) incurred by him in his defense of the action against him.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History" path="§501">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 666, Pub. L. 91-358, title V, § 501</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-143.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-143a.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
