<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-119.02</num>
  <heading>Lost, stolen or abandoned property — Custody.</heading>
  <text>All property, or money alleged or supposed to have been feloniously obtained, or which shall be lost or abandoned, and which shall be thereafter taken into the custody of any member of the police force, or the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, or which shall come into such custody, shall be, by such member, or by order of the Court, given into the custody of the Property Clerk and kept by him, except that the custody of any abandoned vehicle shall be transferred to the Abandoned and Junk Vehicle Division of the Department of Public Works.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">R.S., D.C., § 409</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-24" type="History">Sept. 9, 1989, D.C. Law 8-24, § 6(b), 36 DCR 4575</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Property found in custody of deceased, depositing of, see § <cite path="§5-1408">5-1408</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§5-119.01">5-119.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-153.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-152.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The Police Court of the District of Columbia and the Municipal Court for the District of Columbia were consolidated by the Act of April 1, 1942, 56 Stat. 190, ch. 207, § 1. The Act of July 8, 1963, § 1, substituted “District of Columbia Court of General Sessions” for “Municipal Court for the District of Columbia.” The Act of July 29, 1970, Pub. L. 91-358, § 155(a), substituted “Superior Court of the District of Columbia” for “District of Columbia Court of General Sessions.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority under <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-24">D.C. Law 8-24</cite>, the “D.C. Abandoned and Junk Vehicle Removal Amend. Act of 1989”, see Mayor’s Order 90-11, January 23, 1990.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
