<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-117.02</num>
  <heading>Examination of books and premises.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia may direct the Chief of Police to empower any member of the police force, whenever such member shall be in search of property feloniously obtained, or in search of suspected offenders, to examine the books of any pawnbroker or his business premises, or the business premises of any licensed vender or dealer in secondhand merchandise, or intelligence office keeper, or auctioneer of watches and jewelry, or suspected private banking house, or other doubtful establishment.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">R.S., D.C., § 405</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 11, 1878, 20 Stat. 107, ch. 180, § 6</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">“Pawnbrokers” defined, see § <cite path="§47-2884.01">47-2884.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Pawnbrokers, examination of books or premises, see §§ <cite path="§47-2884.07">47-2884.07</cite> and <cite path="§47-2884.11">47-2884.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-2884.01">47-2884.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-148.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-148.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Office of Major and Superintendent of Metropolitan Police abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§5-105.01">5-105.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
