<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-129.51</num>
  <heading>Metropolitan Police Department Reserve Corps.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish a Metropolitan Police Department Reserve Corps (“Reserve Corps”) in the District of Columbia. The purpose of the Reserve Corps shall be to assist full-time, sworn police personnel in both the day-to-day and emergency delivery of law enforcement services, consistent with applicable law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Reserve Corps shall have as its membership a corps of unpaid volunteers who fulfill police duties and responsibilities as determined by the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The selection criteria required for and training provided to members of the Reserve Corps shall be similar to the selection criteria required for and training provided to full-time, sworn police personnel. When establishing the criteria, the Chief of Police shall review national standards, such as the Commission on Accreditation for Law Enforcement Agencies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this section within 180 days of September 30, 2004. The rules shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Prescribe the duties and responsibilities of Reserve Corps members;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Define the scope of Reserve Corps members’ authority and discretion in carrying out their duties and responsibilities, including any limitations on or restrictions to their authority and discretion; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Delineate the supervision Reserve Corps members are to receive.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-194" type="History" path="§1002">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-194, § 1002, 51 DCR 9406</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Mayor’s Rulemaking Authority Pursuant to the Metropolitan Police Department Reserve Corps Establishment Act of 2004 and the Volunteer Act of 1977 to the Chief, Metropolitan Police Department, see Mayor’s Order 2006-57, May 19, 2006 ( 53 DCR 5313).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
