<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-133.10</num>
  <heading>Rewards, presents, fees or emoluments prohibited; exception; notice to Mayor required; failure to give notice.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Neither the Mayor of the District of Columbia, nor any member of the Council of the District of Columbia or of the police force, shall receive or share in, for his own benefit, under any pretense whatever, any present, fee, or emolument, for police services, other than the regular salary and pay provided by law, except by consent of the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, for meritorious and extraordinary services rendered by any member of the police force, in the due discharge of his duty, may permit such member to retain for his own benefit any reward or present tendered him therefor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon notice to the Mayor from any member of the police force, of the receipt by such member of any reward or present, the Mayor may order the member to retain the same, or shall dispose thereof for the benefit of the Policemen and Firemen’s Relief Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>It shall be cause of removal from the police force for any member to receive rewards or presents without giving notice of the same to the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">R.S., D.C., §§ 357, 358, 359, 360</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 11, 1878, 20 Stat. 107, ch. 180, § 6</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Sept. 1, 1916, 39 Stat. 718, ch. 433, § 12</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Fugitives, apprehension of and payment of rewards, see § <cite path="§24-201.27">24-201.27</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, application to police officers and firefighters, see § <cite path="§1-632.03">1-632.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-632.03">1-632.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-125.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-129.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
