<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-133.14</num>
  <heading>Expenditures for the prevention and detection of crime.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police of the Metropolitan Police Department is authorized, with the approval of the Mayor of the District of Columbia and within the limits of appropriations therefor, to make expenditures for the prevention and detection of crime under his certificate. The certificate of the Chief of Police for such expenditures shall be deemed a sufficient voucher for the sum therein expressed to have been expended.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other law, rule, or regulation, beginning in fiscal year 2007, the Chief of Police may issue grants to individuals or organizations from local funds for the prevention and detection of crime.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, may issue rules to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-140" type="History" path="§9">Oct. 26, 1973, 87 Stat. 505, Pub. L. 93-140, § 9</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20" type="History">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 3002, 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-186.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-188.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</law-cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsecs. (b and (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3002 of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 3001 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</law-cite> provided that subtitle A of title III of the act may be cited as the “Metropolitan Police Department Grant-Making Authority Clarification Amendment Act of 2007”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
