<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-1419</num>
  <heading>Impaired driving program; chemical testing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The CME shall be responsible for ensuring the accuracy of blood and urine testing for the District’s impaired driving program. The CME may test or authorize the testing of specimens, as defined by § <cite path="§50-1901">50-1901</cite>(18), for the purposes of determining if specimens contain alcohol or a drug.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Until October 1, 2012, and after October 1, 2012 if authorized under § <cite path="§5-1501.07">5-1501.07</cite>(d), the CME shall be responsible for testing and certifying the accuracy of any District instrument utilized by District law enforcement personnel to test the alcohol content of breath. A District breath-test instrument shall only be used by District law enforcement personnel if it has been certified by the CME to be accurate. Certification of the accuracy of each breath test instrument must occur at least once every 180 days.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements under subsection (a) of this section, the CME shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Develop a program for District law enforcement personnel to become trained and certified as a breath test instrument operator;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Develop policies and procedures for the operation and maintenance of all breath test instruments utilized by District law enforcement personnel; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Develop policies and procedures for the maintenance of records demonstrating that the breath test instruments utilized by District law enforcement personnel are in proper operating condition.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History" path="§2918b">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 2918b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-266" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 202, 59 DCR 12957</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-260" type="History">Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-260, § 2, 60 DCR 1292</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-260">D.C. Law 19-260</cite> substituted “180 days” for “3 months” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 202 of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013,  60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 202 of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013,  60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-260">D.C. Law 19-260</cite> provided that the Act shall apply as of the effective date of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Breath Testing Program Amendment Act of 2012, signed by the Mayor on October 24, 2012 (D.C. Act 19-489;  59 DCR 12957), which became <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite>, effective April 27, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
