<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-1402</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner; appointments, qualifications, and compensation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a subordinate agency in the executive branch of the government of the District of Columbia, the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner (“OCME”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall nominate, with the advice and consent of the Council, a person to serve as the Chief Medical Examiner (“CME”) within the OCME pursuant to § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>(a). The CME shall be responsible for the management and operation of the OCME. The CME shall appoint a Deputy CME, to be paid at an annual rate of $206,000, and any other medical examiners the CME finds necessary to carry out the duties of the OCME.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The CME, the Deputy CME, and any medical examiners appointed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be physicians licensed to practice medicine in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the CME, the Deputy CME, and any medical examiners appointed after October 19, 2000, shall be certified in forensic pathology by the American Board of Pathology or be eligible for such certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The certification requirement of paragraph (2) of this subsection may be waived by the Mayor for the CME appointed to fill the term beginning on May 1, 2007, and ending on April 30, 2013.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall fix the compensation of the CME pursuant to subchapter X-A of Chapter 6 of Title 1 [§ <cite path="§1-610.51">1-610.51</cite> et seq.]. The Mayor shall fix the compensation of all medical examiners appointed by the CME pursuant to this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The CME shall be appointed for a 6-year term.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If a vacancy in the position of Chief Medical Examiner occurs as a consequence of resignation, disability, death, or a reason other than the expiration of the term of the Chief Medical Examiner, the Mayor shall appoint a replacement to fill the unexpired term in the same manner provided in § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>(a). A person appointed to fill the unexpired term shall serve only for the remainder of the term.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 2903, 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-339" type="History">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-339, § 2, 52 DCR 2283</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-115" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-115, § 2, 55 DCR 1278</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-88" type="History">Dec. 10, 2009, D.C. Law 18-88, § 203, 56 DCR 7413</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 3042, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§5-1416">5-1416</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-2301.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-339">D.C. Law 15-339</cite> rewrote subsec. (c); and added subsec. (f). Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “(c) The CME, the Deputy CME, and any medical examiners appointed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be physicians licensed to practice medicine in the District of Columbia. The CME, the Deputy CME, and any medical examiners appointed after the effective date of this chapter shall be certified in forensic pathology by the American Board of Pathology or be eligible for such certification.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-115">D.C. Law 17-115</cite> rewrote subsec. (c) which had read as follows: “(c) The CME, the Deputy CME, and any medical examiners appointed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be physicians licensed to practice medicine in the District of Columbia. The CME, the Deputy CME, and any medical examiners appointed after October 19, 2000, shall be certified in forensic pathology by the American Board of Pathology or be eligible for such certification, except that the Mayor may waive the certification requirement for any individual appointed as CME to fill the unexpired term ending on April 30, 2007.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-88">D.C. Law 18-88</cite> rewrote subsec. (c)(3), which had read as follows: “(3) The certification requirement of paragraph (2) of this subsection may be waived by the Mayor until October 1, 2008 for the CME. Any individual appointed as the CME to fill the term beginning on May 1, 2007, and ending on April 30, 2013, pursuant to this waiver shall not be eligible to serve as CME after October 1, 2008, and shall not be eligible to serve in a holdover status after October 1, 2008, unless he or she meets the certification requirement.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added “to be paid at an annual rate of $ 206,000” in (b).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Appointment of the Chief Medical Examiner Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-70">D.C. Law 17-70</cite>, January 23, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 1450).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-335">D.C. Law 17-335</cite> amended subsec. (c)(3) to read as follows: “(3) The certification requirement of paragraph (2) of this subsection may be waived by the Mayor for the CME appointed to fill the term beginning on May 1, 2007 and ending on April 30, 2013.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-335">D.C. Law 17-335</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2903 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Appointment of the Chief Medical Examiner Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-643, December 20, 2004,  51 DCR 11833).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Appointment of the Chief Medical Examiner Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-136, October 17, 2007,  54 DCR 10725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Appointment of the Chief Medical Examiner Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-253, January 23, 2008,  55 DCR 1266).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Appointment of the Chief Medical Examiner Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-600, December 12, 2008,  56 DCR 7).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Appointment of the Chief Medical Examiner Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-4, January 23, 2009,  56 DCR 1627).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 203 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-181, August 6, 2009,  56 DCR 6903).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 203 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-227, October 21, 2009,  56 DCR 8668).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3042 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3042 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3042 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
