<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-1404</num>
  <heading>Former duties of coroner; oaths; teaching; other duties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The CME shall be responsible for all the medical functions formerly performed by the coroner in the District of Columbia consistent with the provisions of this chapter. The CME and such other medical examiners as may be appointed may administer oaths and affirmations and take affidavits in connection with the performance of their duties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The CME, other medical examiners, medicolegal investigators and toxicologists as he or she may appoint, may be authorized by the CME to teach medical and law school classes, to conduct special classes for law enforcement personnel and to engage in other activities related to their work.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The CME shall inform the Registrar of Vital Records of all deaths of children 18 years of age or younger as soon as practicable, but in any event within 5 business days.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The CME, or his or her designee, shall attend all reviews of child deaths by the Child Fatality Review Committee. The CME shall coordinate with the Child Fatality Review Committee in its investigations of child deaths.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 2905, 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4619(a), 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-2303.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite> added subsecs. (c) and (d).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 19(a) of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-20">D.C. Law 14-20</cite>, September 6, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 9090).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2905 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 19(a) of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-40, April 25, 2001,  48 DCR 5917).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 19(a) of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-82, July 9, 2001,  48 DCR 6355).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
