<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-1501.13</num>
  <heading>Stakeholder Council.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Stakeholder Council, which shall consist of the following members:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chief of MPD;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Chief Medical Examiner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The United States Attorney for the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Public Defender Service for the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The Federal Public Defender for the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Health;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The Chief of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>The head of any other government agency that regularly utilizes the forensic science services of the Department.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The chairperson of the Judiciary Committee of the Council of the District of Columbia shall be an ex officio, non-voting member of the Stakeholder Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The members listed in subsection (a) of this section shall not be represented by a designee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The chairperson of the Stakeholder Council shall be the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice. In his or her absence, the Attorney General shall be the chairperson.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Stakeholder Council shall meet no fewer than 2 times per year. The chairperson shall fix the time and place of the meetings.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-18" type="History">Aug. 17, 2011, D.C. Law 19-18, ยง 14, 58 DCR 5403</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
