<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-409.01</num>
  <heading>Paramedic and emergency medical technician lateral transfer to Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other law or regulation, the Mayor is authorized to provide for the transfer of Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department personnel holding valid certificates as paramedics or emergency medical technicians to be uniformed firefighters.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Transfer shall be to the firefighter step and class with a rate of pay closest to, but not lower than, the rate of pay earned by the employee prior to transfer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Transferred employees may elect to participate in the District of Columbia Police Officers’ and Fire Fighters’ Retirement Program established pursuant to Chapter 9 of Title 1 [§ <cite path="§1-901.01">1-901.01</cite> et seq.]. (“Program”).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Transfer is conditioned on the transferred employee meeting the requirements for entry-level firefighters, including meeting established medical standards, undergoing a background check, and successfully completing a physical abilities test and the firefighting training program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Transferred employees are required to meet citizenship requirements set forth by law or regulation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Maximum age limitations for appointment shall not apply to transferred employees.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 2 of Title 1, may issue rules to implement the provisions of this title [section].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 202, 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 37(a), 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-356" type="History">Mar. 31, 2009, D.C. Law 17-356, § 2, 56 DCR 1614</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 39, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§5-544.01">5-544.01</cite> and § <cite path="§5-704">5-704</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in subsec. (a)(2), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-356">D.C. Law 17-356</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “technicians, or All Hazards/Emergency Medical Services (”EMS“) Specialists,” for “technicians” in the lead-in language and rewrote par. (2); and added subsec. (a-1). Prior to amendment, par. (2) of subsec. (a) read as follows: “(2) Transferred employees may elect to participate in the Police Officers and Fire Fighters’ Retirement Fund pursuant to §</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in (a-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 202 of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-356">D.C. Law 17-356</cite> provided that this act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">The Budget Director of the Council of the District of Columbia has determined, as of February 15, 2012, that the fiscal effect of Law 17-356 has not been included in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore, the provisions of this section, enacted by Law 17-356, are not in effect.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
