<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-409</num>
  <heading>Firefighting Division — Accruement of annual leave; adjustment of accumulated leave; transfers; maximum accumulations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In lieu of the annual leave to which officers and members of the Firefighting Division of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia are entitled under the provisions of §§ 6302 to 6305, and 6310 of Title 5, United States Code, such officers and members shall be entitled to annual leave which shall accrue as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Four and eight-tenths hours for each full biweekly pay period in the case of officers and members with less than 3 years service;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Seven and five-tenths hours for each full biweekly pay period in the case of officers and members with 3 but less than 15 years service;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Nine and six-tenths hours for each biweekly pay period in the case of officers and members with 15 years or more service.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Accumulated annual leave to the credit of each officer and member of such Firefighting Division shall be adjusted by applying a four fifths factor so that each officer and member of such Firefighting Division shall be given credit for four fifths of a day of leave for each day of such accumulated annual leave, and thereafter accumulated annual leave credited to him pursuant to §§ 6301 to 6305 and 6307 to 6311 of Title 5, United States Code, shall be similarly adjusted when an officer or member is transferred to the Firefighting Division from another agency or from another division of the Fire Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>When an officer or member of such Firefighting Division is transferred to another agency or to another division of the Fire Department whose employees are entitled to annual leave with pay pursuant to §§ 6301 to 6305 and 6307 to 6311 of Title 5, United States Code, the reverse of the formula in subsection (b) of this section shall be applied for the purpose of adjusting accumulated annual leave.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For computation on an hourly basis, all adjusted days of annual leave or fractions thereof, as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, and days of sick leave shall be multiplied by 12 to determine the number of hours of annual or sick leave to which each such officer or member of such Firefighting Division shall be entitled, and the number of hours of annual or sick leave shall be divided by 12 to determine the number of days, or fraction thereof, of annual or sick leave to which such officer or member of such Firefighting Division shall be entitled.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any provision in any other law, the amount of annual leave accumulated on the effective date of this section, if 30 days or more, shall, upon conversion to the new total in accordance with this section, be the maximum accumulation authorized; provided, that if the amount of annual leave accumulated before the conversion is less than 30 days on the effective date of this section, then, after conversion to the new total, leave which is not used shall accumulate for use in succeeding years until it totals no more than 24 days at the beginning of the 1st complete biweekly pay period.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 87-697" type="History">Sept. 25, 1962, 76 Stat. 596, Pub. L. 87-697, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, application to police officers and firefighters, see § <cite path="§1-632.03">1-632.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-632.03">1-632.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-309.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-408b.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “effective date of this section,” referred to twice in subsection (e), is prescribed by § 5 of the Act of September 25, 1962, 76 Stat. 596, Pub. L. 87-697.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
