<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-414</num>
  <heading>Reciprocal agreements for mutual aid; availability of personnel and equipment to federal government; service performed in line of duty.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized in its discretion to enter into and to renew reciprocal agreements, for such period as it deems advisable, with the appropriate county, municipal, and other governmental units in Prince George’s and Montgomery Counties, Maryland, and Arlington and Fairfax Counties, Virginia, with the City of Alexandria, Virginia, with the City of Falls Church, Virginia, and with incorporated or unincorporated fire departments, fire companies, and organizations of firemen in such Counties and Cities, in order to establish and carry into effect a plan to provide mutual aid, through the furnishing of firefighting personnel and equipment, by and for the District of Columbia and such Counties and Cities, for the extinguishment of fires and for the preservation of life and property in emergencies, in the District and in such Counties and Cities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia shall not enter into any such agreement unless the agreement provides that each of the parties to such agreement shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Waive any and all claims against all the other parties thereto which may arise out of their activities outside their respective jurisdictions under such agreement; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Indemnify and save harmless the other parties to such agreement from all claims by 3rd parties for property damage or personal injury which may arise out of the activities of the other parties to such agreement outside their respective jurisdictions under such agreement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized to make available to the federal government personnel and equipment of the Fire Department of the District to extinguish fires, and to save lives, on property of the federal government in Prince George’s and Montgomery Counties, Maryland; Arlington and Fairfax Counties, Virginia; and the City of Alexandria, Virginia; and the City of Falls Church, Virginia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of subchapter I of Chapter 7 of this title, service performed by any officer or member of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia under any mutual-aid agreement entered into by the District pursuant to this section, service performed by any officer or member of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia at any other city, area, municipality, or other location where they shall have been directed to respond for the purpose of saving lives, extinguishing fires, or preserving property on orders of the Mayor of the District of Columbia or of the Fire Chief of said Fire Department or his acting designee, and service performed under subsection (c) of this section by any such officer or member in extinguishing fires, or saving lives, on property of the federal government, shall be held and considered to be service performed in line of duty.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 14, 1950, 64 Stat. 441, ch. 706, §§ 1-4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-473" type="History">Aug. 21, 1964, 78 Stat. 585, Pub. L. 88-473, § 1</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-314.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-414.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Office of Chief Engineer abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§5-402">5-402</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(110) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
