<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-521.01</num>
  <heading>Compensation for working on holidays.</heading>
  <text>Under regulations promulgated by the Council of the District of Columbia, each officer and member of the Metropolitan Police force and of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, when he may be required to work on any holiday, shall be compensated for such duty, excluding periods when he is in a leave status, in lieu of his regular rate of basic compensation for such work, at the rate of twice such regular rate of basic compensation; provided, that for the purpose of this subchapter, each such officer or member who works 8 hours or less on any holiday shall be compensated for such duty in addition to his regular rate of basic compensation for such work, at the rate of one eighth of his daily rate of basic compensation for each hour so worked, computed to the nearest hour, counting 30 minutes or more as a full hour; provided further, that, when an officer or member is authorized or directed to work on a holiday and such officer or member is required to work longer than his regular tour of duty, he shall be compensated for such overtime in accordance with the provisions of subsection (e) of § <cite path="§5-1304">5-1304</cite>. Appropriations for personal services for the Metropolitan Police force, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, and the United States Park Police Force shall be available for payment of the additional compensation authorized by this subchapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Oct. 24, 1951, 65 Stat. 607, ch. 544, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-533" type="History">July 18, 1958, 72 Stat. 377, Pub. L. 85-533, § 4(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 87-399" type="History">Oct. 5, 1961, 75 Stat. 831, Pub. L. 87-399, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-282" type="History">Oct. 21, 1965, 79 Stat. 1015, Pub. L. 89-282, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 95-179" type="History">Nov. 15, 1977, 91 Stat. 1371, Pub. L. 95-179</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 111-282" type="History">Oct. 15, 2010, 124 Stat. 3033, Pub. L. 111-282, § 4(b)(1)(A)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, application to police officers and firefighters, see § <cite path="§1-632.03">1-632.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-632.03">1-632.03</cite> and § <cite path="§5-521.02">5-521.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-402.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-807.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 111-282, in the second sentence, deleted “the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division,” following “Fire Department of the District of Columbia,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(112) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
