<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-525.01</num>
  <heading>Fire and Emergency Medical Services Overtime Settlement Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Overtime Settlement Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Office of the City Administrator in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, there shall be deposited into the Fund:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Excess Fiscal Year 2015 revenues certified by the Chief Financial Officer in the June 2015 quarterly revenue estimate; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Immediately upon completion of the fiscal year-end close, the undesignated and unreserved end-of-the-year fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall deposit into the Fund only the amount necessary to fully satisfy the District’s obligations referenced in subsection (c) of this section. Any excess above that amount shall be deposited into the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia, subject to any allocation required by § <cite path="§47-392.02">47-392.02</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used to pay the District’s obligations arising from the decision of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals in District of Columbia Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department v. District of Columbia Public Employee Relations Board, et al., 105 A.3d 992 (D.C. 2014).</text>
    <text>
      <em>District of Columbia Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department v. District of Columbia Public Employee Relations Board, et al.</em>
    </text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interest earned, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History" path="§7092">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 7092, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7062 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
