<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-542.02</num>
  <heading>Additional compensation for helicopter pilot, bomb disposal, or scuba diving duty.</heading>
  <text>Each officer or member of the Metropolitan Police Force, including, notwithstanding any other law or regulation, each officer or member appointed pursuant to § <cite path="§1-610.72">1-610.72</cite>, and United States Park Police force assigned on or after the effective date of the District of Columbia Police and Firemen’s Salary Act Amendments of 1972: (1) to perform the duty of a helicopter pilot; or (2) to render explosive devices ineffective or to otherwise dispose of such devices shall receive, in addition to his scheduled rate of basic compensation, $2,270 per annum, except in the case of an officer or member of the United States Park Police, who shall receive a per annum amount equal to 7 percent of the sum of such officer’s or member’s rate of basic compensation plus locality pay adjustments, so long as he remains in such assignment. Further, each officer or member of the metropolitan police force assigned on or after August 29, 1972, to the Harbor Patrol division within the Metropolitan Police Department as scuba divers shall receive in addition to his or her scheduled rate of basic compensation, $2,710 per annum so long as he or she remains in such assignment. The additional compensation authorized by this section shall be paid to an officer or member in the same manner as he is paid basic compensation to which he is entitled, except that when such an officer or member ceases to be in such an assignment, the loss of such additional compensation shall not constitute an adverse action for the purposes of § 7511 et seq. of Title 5 of the United States Code. No officer or member who receives the additional compensation authorized by this section may receive additional compensation under § <cite path="§5-543.02">5-543.02</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-584" type="History">Aug. 1, 1958, 72 Stat. 483, Pub. L. 85-584, title II, § 202</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-575" type="History">Sept. 2, 1964, 78 Stat. 881, Pub. L. 88-575, title I, § 103</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-410" type="History">Aug. 29, 1972, 86 Stat. 636, Pub. L. 92-410, title I, § 104</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-407" type="History">Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1036, Pub. L. 93-407, title I, § 101(a)(2), (3)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 95-179" type="History">Nov. 15, 1977, 91 Stat. 1371, Pub. L. 95-179</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-252" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-252, § 2, 46 DCR 1127</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-160" type="History">Oct. 4, 2000, D.C. Law 13-160, § 103(b), 47 DCR 4619</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 106-554" type="History">Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, Pub. L. 106-554, § 1(a)(4), H.R. 5666 § 906(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 111-282" type="History">Oct. 15, 2010, 124 Stat. 3033, Pub. L. 111-282, § 4(b)(2)(A)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§5-545.06a">5-545.06a</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-408.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-825.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-160">D.C. Law 13-160</cite>, after “Metropolitan Police Force”, added “including, notwithstanding any other law or regulation, each officer or member appointed pursuant to § <cite path="§1-611.72">1-611.72</cite>,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 111-282 deleted “United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, ” preceding “and United States Park Police force”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Lateral Appointment of Law Enforcement Officers Temporary Amendment Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-61">D.C. Law 13-61</cite>, October 12, 1999, law notification  47 DCR 1983).</text>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Lateral Appointment of Law Enforcement Officers Clarifying Temporary Amendment Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-102">D.C. Law 13-102</cite>, January 10, 2000, law notification  47 DCR 4339).</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of the Lateral Appointment of Law Enforcement Officers Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-137, August 4, 1999,  46 DCR 6802).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of the Lateral Appointment of Law Enforcement Officers Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-175, November 2, 1999,  46 DCR 9236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of the Lateral Appointment of Law Enforcement Officers Clarifying Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-231, January 11, 2000,  47 DCR 506).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of the Lateral Appointment of Law Enforcement Officers Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-305, April 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(g) of the Lateral Appointment of Law Enforcement Officers Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-137, August 4, 1999,  46 DCR 6802).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(g) of the Lateral Appointment of Law Enforcement Officers Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-175, November 2, 1999,  46 DCR 9236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(g) of the Lateral Appointment of Law Enforcement Officers Clarifying Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-231, January 11, 2000,  47 DCR 506).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(g) of the Lateral Appointment of Law Enforcement Officers Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-305, April 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The effective date of the Police and Firemen’s Salary Act Amendments of 1972, referred to in the first sentence of this section, is prescribed by § 118 of the Act of August 29, 1972, 86 Stat. 634, Pub. L. 92-410.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
