<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-561.02</num>
  <heading>Conversion to new salary schedule, 2000.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Effective on the first day of the 1st pay period beginning 6 months after December 21, 2000, the Secretary of the Interior shall fix the rates of basic pay for officers and members of the United States Park Police, in accordance with this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Each officer and member shall be placed in and receive basic compensation at the corresponding scheduled service step of the salary  schedule under § <cite path="§5-545.01">5-545.01</cite>(c) in accordance with the member’s total years of  creditable service, receiving credit for all service step adjustments. If the  scheduled rate of pay for the step to which the officer or member would be  assigned in accordance with this paragraph is lower than the officer’s or  member’s salary immediately prior to the enactment of this paragraph, the  officer or member will be placed in and receive compensation at the next  higher service step.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Each member whose position is to be converted to the salary schedule   under § <cite path="§5-545.01">5-545.01</cite>(b) and who, prior to the effective date of this section has   earned, but has not been credited with, an increase in his or her rate of pay   shall be afforded that increase before such member is placed in the corresponding service step in the salary schedule under § <cite path="§5-545.01">5-545.01</cite>(b).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>For purposes of this paragraph, an officer’s or member’s creditable service is any police service in pay status with the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, United States Park Police, or Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the total rate of compensation for an officer or employee for any pay period occurring after conversion to the salary schedule pursuant to subsection (a) of this section  (determined by taking into account any locality-based comparability adjustments, longevity pay, and other adjustments paid in addition to the rate of basic compensation) is less than the officer’s or employee’s total rate of compensation (as so determined) on the date of enactment, the rate of compensation for the officer or employee for the pay period shall be equal to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The rate of compensation on December 21, 2000 (as so determined),  increased by;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A percentage equal to 50% of sum of the percentage adjustments made in  the rate of basic compensation under § <cite path="§5-545.01">5-545.01</cite>(c) for pay periods occurring  after the date of enactment and prior to the pay period involved.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The conversion of positions and individuals to appropriate classes of the salary schedule under § <cite path="§5-545.01">5-545.01</cite>(c) and the initial adjustments of rates of basic pay of those positions and individuals in accordance with subsection (a) of this section shall not be considered to be transfers or promotions within the meaning of § <cite path="§5-543.04">5-543.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Each individual whose position is converted to the salary schedule under § <cite path="§5-545.01">5-545.01</cite>(c) in accordance with subsection (a) of this section shall be granted credit for purposes of such individual’s first service step adjustment under the salary schedule in § <cite path="§5-545.01">5-545.01</cite>(c) for all satisfactory service performed by the individual since the individual’s last increase in basic pay prior to the adjustment under § <cite path="§5-545.01">5-545.01</cite>(c).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The rates provided under the salary schedule under § <cite path="§5-545.01">5-545.01</cite>(c) shall be increased by the percentage of any annual adjustment applicable to the General Schedule authorized under section 5303 of title 5, United States Code, which takes effect during the period which begins on December 21, 2000, and ends on the first day of the first pay period beginning 6 months after December 21, 2001.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The conversion of positions and individuals to appropriate classes of the salary schedule under § <cite path="§5-545.01">5-545.01</cite>(c) and the initial adjustments of rates of basic pay of those positions and individuals in accordance with subsection (a) of this section shall not be treated as an increase in salary for purposes of § <cite path="§5-744">5-744</cite> or § <cite path="§5-745">5-745</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 106-554" type="History">Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, Pub. L. 106-554, § 1(a)(4), H.R. 5666 § 905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 111-282" type="History">Oct. 15, 2010, 124 Stat. 3033, Pub. L. 111-282, § 4(b)(4)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 111-282, in subsec. (a)(1), deleted “the Secretary of the Treasury shall fix the rates of basic pay for officers and members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, and” following “2000,”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
