<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-604</num>
  <heading>Lien.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia shall have a lien, to the amount of the reasonable value of the care and treatment, funeral expenses, and wage payments described in § <cite path="§5-602">5-602</cite>, upon any recovery of sum received or collected or to be collected by an injured or diseased policeman or fireman, his guardian, personal representative, estate, dependents, or survivors in a claim or action asserted or maintained by such policeman or fireman or his personal representative against a liable 3rd person for damages.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No such lien described above shall be effective, however:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Unless, prior to the payment of any moneys to such injured or diseased policeman or fireman, his attorney, or personal representative as compensation for such injury or disease, the District of Columbia shall have filed in the Office of the Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia, in a docket provided for such liens, a written notice containing the name and address of the injured or diseased policeman or fireman, the date and approximate place of the accident or incident giving rise thereto and the name of the person alleged to be liable to the policeman or fireman for the injuries or disease received; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Unless the District of Columbia shall also mail, postage prepaid, a copy of such notice with a statement of the date of filing thereof to the person alleged to be liable to the policeman or fireman for the injuries or disease received, prior to the payment of any moneys to such injured or diseased policeman or fireman, his attorney, or personal representative as compensation for such injury or disease.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Where the name of an insurance carrier for the 3rd party tort-feasor is ascertained, the District of Columbia shall also mail a copy of such notice to such insurance carrier. Notice of the filing of the lien shall also be given to the injured or diseased policeman or fireman, or to his attorney or personal representative.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any person, including an insurance carrier, who, after the mailing of such notice, shall make any payment to such policeman or fireman or to his attorney or personal representative as compensation for the injury sustained or disease contracted without paying to the District of Columbia the amount of its lien or so much thereof as can be satisfied out of the moneys due under any final judgment or compromise or settlement agreement after paying the amount of any prior liens, shall for a period of 1 year from the date of payment to such policeman or fireman, his attorney, or personal representative, as aforesaid, be and remain liable to said District of Columbia for the amount which the District was entitled to receive under its lien, and the District of Columbia may, within such period, enforce its lien by an action against the person making any such payment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>When a policeman or fireman, or his attorney or personal representative, receives, as a result of an action or proceeding brought by the policeman or fireman, or on his behalf or a result of a settlement made by him or on his behalf, any moneys or other property in satisfaction of the liability of a 3rd person for the injury sustained or disease contracted, such policeman or fireman, or his attorney or personal representative, as the case may be, shall ascertain and pay to the District of Columbia the amount of its lien or so much thereof as can be realized out of any such recovery or settlement. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, whenever a policeman or fireman, or his attorney or personal representative, receives any payment as described in the preceding sentence and fails to pay to the District of Columbia the amount of its lien, the District of Columbia is authorized to take appropriate action to recover from such policeman or fireman or his attorney or personal representative the amount of its lien, including, but not limited to, the right to counterclaim, setoff, or attach moneys or other property otherwise due and payable from the District of Columbia to said policeman or fireman, his guardian, personal representative, estate, dependents or survivors.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-100" type="History" path="§5">Aug. 17, 1978, D.C. Law 2-100, § 5, 25 DCR 288</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§5-606">5-606</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-504.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-1004.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
