<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-631</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Act” means subchapter I of Chapter 7 of Title 5 [§ <cite path="§5-701">5-701</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Chief” means either the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Chief of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Director” means either the director of medical services for the Metropolitan Police Department, or the medical services officer for the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Full range of duties” means the ability of a member to perform all of the essential functions of police work or fire suppression as determined by the established policies and procedures of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department, and to meet the physical examination and physical agility standards established under §§ <cite path="§5-107.02a">5-107.02a</cite> and <cite path="§5-451">5-451</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Limited duty” means a temporary status for members who, because of injury or other temporary medical disability, are not able to perform the full range of duties, but are certified by a Police and Fire Clinic physician as being capable of effectively performing certain types of work within the department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Member” means a sworn employee of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-194" type="History" path="§621">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-194, § 621, 51 DCR 9406</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 641 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</law-cite> provided</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 641. Applicability subject to availability of appropriations.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“This title referring to Chapter 6A shall be subject to the availability of appropriations.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Titles I and VI of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</law-cite>: Section 1301 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</law-cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Titles I and VI of this act shall apply to pre-1980 employees of the Metropolitan Police Department and the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department upon their enactment by Congress.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Because of the codification of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</law-cite>, Subtitle D as subchapter II of this chapter, the preexisting text, §§ <cite path="§5-631">5-631</cite> through <cite path="§5-635">5-635</cite>, has been designated as subchapter I.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
