<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-708</num>
  <heading>Payment of medical expenses — Total disability retirees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, the District of Columbia shall pay the reasonable costs of medical, surgical, hospital, or other related health care services of any officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force of the District of Columbia, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, or the United States Secret Service Division who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Retires after August 16, 1971, under § <cite root="5-710">5-710</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At the time of such retirement, has a disability caused by injury or disease contracted or aggravated in the line of duty, which is determined by, or under regulations of, the Mayor of the District of Columbia (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Mayor”) to be a total disability.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No payment may be made under this section for medical, surgical, hospital, or other related health care services provided a retired officer or member unless:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At the time such services are provided the disability of the retired officer or member has been determined by, or under regulations of, the Mayor to be a total disability;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Such services have been determined by, or under regulations of, the Mayor to be necessary and directly related to the treatment of the injury or disease which caused the disability of the retired officer or member; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The retired officer or member submits to such medical examinations as the Mayor may require.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may determine that the disability of a retired officer or member is a total disability only if the Mayor finds that the retired officer or member is unable (because of the injury or disease causing his disability) to secure or follow substantially gainful employment. In determining whether employment is substantially gainful employment, the Mayor shall take into account the amount of expenses incurred by, or which can reasonably be expected to be incurred by, the retired officer or member in securing the medical, surgical, hospital, or other related health care services necessitated by his disability, and such other factors as the Mayor deems advisable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In addition to any medical examination required under this subchapter, the Mayor shall require, in each year that payments under this section are made with respect to any retired officer or member, a medical review of the disability of such retired officer or member.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may provide for payments under this section to be made either directly to the retired officer or member or to the provider of the medical, surgical, hospital, or other related health care services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>There are authorized to be appropriated from revenues of the United States such sums as may be necessary to reimburse the District of Columbia, on a monthly basis, for payments made under this section from revenues of the District of Columbia in the case of retired officers or members of the United States Park Police force, the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, or the United States Secret Service Division.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Aug. 16, 1971, 85 Stat. 341, Pub. L. 92-121, §§ 1-3</annotation>
      <annotation>Nov. 15, 1977, 91 Stat. 1371, Pub. L. 95-179</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 4-614.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 4-525a.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act: Section 3(r) of Pub. L. 85-157 provided that this section may be cited as part of the Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act.</text>
      <text>Coverage Under Federal Employees’ Retirement Act: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite root="5-742">5-742</cite>.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
