<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-701</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>Wherever used in this subchapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The term “member” means any officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force, of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, of the United States Park Police force, of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, and any officer or member of the United States Secret Service Division to whom this subchapter shall apply, but does not include an officer or member of the United States Park Police force, of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, or of the United States Secret Service Division, whose service is employment for the purposes of title II of the Social Security Act and chapter 21 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and who is not excluded from coverage under chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, by operation of § 8402 of such title.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>[Not funded].</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The terms “disabled” and “disability” mean disabled for useful and efficient service in the grade or class of position last occupied by the member by reason of disease or injury, not due to vicious habits or intemperance as determined by the Board of Police and Fire Surgeons, or willful misconduct on his part as determined by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “widow” means the surviving wife of a member or former member if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>She was married to such member or former member:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>While he was a member; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>For at least 1 year immediately preceding his death; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>She is the mother of issue by such marriage.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term “widower” means the surviving husband of a member or former member if, in the case of a member who was an officer or member of the United States Park Police force, the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, or the United States Secret Service Division, or the surviving husband of a member or former member who was a member or officer of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>He was married to such member or former member:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>While she was a member; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>For at least 1 year immediately preceding her death; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>He is the father of issue by such marriage.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The term “child” means an unmarried child, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>An adopted child; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>A stepchild or recognized natural child who lives with the member in a regular parent-child relationship, under the age of 18 years; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Such unmarried child regardless of age who, because of physical or mental disability incurred before the age of 18, is incapable of self-support.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The term “student child” means an unmarried child who is a student between the ages of 18 and 22 years, inclusive, and who is regularly pursuing a full-time course of study or training in residence in a high school, trade school, technical or vocational institute, junior college, college, university, or comparable recognized educational institution.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The term “basic salary” means regular salary established by law or regulation, including any differential for special occupational assignment, but shall not include overtime, holiday, or military pay.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The term “annuitant” means any former member who, on the basis of his service, has met all requirements of this subchapter for title to annuity and has filed claim therefor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>The term “survivor” means a person who is entitled to annuity under this subchapter based on the service of a deceased member or of a deceased annuitant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>The term “survivor annuitant” means a survivor who has filed claim for annuity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>The term “police or fire service” means all honorable service in the Metropolitan Police Department, United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, and the United States Secret Service Division coming under the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>The term “military service” means honorable active service in the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard of the United States, but shall not include service in the National Guard except when ordered to active duty in the service of the United States.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designated agent or agents.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>The term “service” means employment which is creditable under § <cite path="§5-704">5-704</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>The term “government” means the executive, judicial, and legislative branches of the United States government, including government owned or controlled corporations and Gallaudet College, and the municipal government of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>The term “government service” means honorable active service in the executive, judicial, or legislative branches of the United States government, including government owned or controlled corporations, and Gallaudet College, and the municipal government of the District of Columbia, and for which retirement deductions, other than social security deductions, were made.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>The term “department” means any part of the executive branch of the United States government, or any part of the government of the District of Columbia whose members come under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>The term “average pay” means the highest annual rate resulting from averaging the member’s rates of basic salary in effect over any 36 consecutive months of police or fire service in the case of a member who is an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia and who first becomes such a member after the end of the 90-day period beginning on November 17, 1979, or over any 12 consecutive months of police or fire service in the case of any other member, with each rate weighted by the time it was in effect, except that if the member retires under § <cite path="§5-710">5-710</cite> and if on the date of his retirement under the section he has not completed 12 consecutive months or 36 consecutive months, as the case may be, of police or fire service, such term means his basic salary at the time of his retirement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(18)</num>
    <text>The term “adjusted average pay” means the average pay of a member who was an officer or member of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, the United States Secret Service Division, the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia increased by the per centum increase (adjusted to the nearest one tenth of 1%) in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers, published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, between the month in which such member retires and the month immediately prior to the month in which such member dies; except that in the case of members hired on or after the first day of the first pay period that begins after October 29, 1996, the increase shall not exceed 3% per annum.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(19)</num>
    <text>The term “full range of duties” means the ability of a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department to perform all of the essential functions of police work or fire suppression as determined by the established policies and procedures of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department and to meet the physical examination and physical agility standards established under §§ <cite path="§5-107.02a">5-107.02a</cite> and <cite path="§5-451">5-451</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(20)</num>
    <text>The term “Internal Revenue Code” or “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” means the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 22, 1986 (100 Stat. 2085; 26 U.S.C. § 1 et seq.).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Sept. 1, 1916, 39 Stat. 718, ch. 433, § 12(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-157" type="History">as added Aug. 21, 1957, 71 Stat. 391, Pub. L. 85-157, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-509" type="History">Oct. 26, 1970, 84 Stat. 1136, Pub. L. 91-509, §§ 1(1), (2)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-532" type="History">Dec. 7, 1970, 84 Stat. 1392, Pub. L. 91-532, § 1(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-410" type="History">Aug. 29, 1972, 86 Stat. 641, Pub. L. 92-410, title II, § 201(a)(1)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-407" type="History">Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1040, Pub. L. 93-407, title I, § 121(a), (d)(1)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-87" type="History">Oct. 1, 1976, D.C. Law 1-87, § 8(a), 23 DCR 2544</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 96-179" type="History">Nov. 15, 1977, 91 Stat. 1371, Pub. L. 96-179</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 96-122" type="History">Nov. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 866, Pub. L. 96-122, §§ 201, 206(a)(2)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 100-238" type="History">Jan. 8, 1988, 101 Stat. 1745, Pub. L. 100-238, § 103(d)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-68" type="History">Feb. 5, 1994, D.C. Law 10-68, § 13, 40 DCR 6311</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 104-52" type="History">Nov. 19, 1995, 109 Stat. 504, Pub. L. 104-52, § 630(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-218" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-218, § 2(a), 43 DCR 6172</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-194" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-194, § 602(a), 51 DCR 9406</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 26, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-356" type="History">Mar. 31, 2009, D.C. Law 17-356, § 3(a), 56 DCR 1614</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-314" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-314, § 2(a), 60 DCR 3466</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District of Columbia employees retirement program management, “participant” defined, see § <cite path="§1-702">1-702</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District of Columbia employees retirement program management, “retirement program” defined, see § <cite path="§1-702">1-702</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District of Columbia police officers and firefighters retirement fund, see § <cite path="§1-712">1-712</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Employee retirement program management, annual report, see § <cite path="§1-732">1-732</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, “annuitant” defined, see § <cite path="§1-621.03">1-621.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, “annuitant defined”, see § <cite path="§1-622.04">1-622.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, “employee” defined, see § <cite path="§1-623.01">1-623.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Office of emergency preparedness, appointment of police or fire department members, see § <cite path="§7-2203">7-2203</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Police, fire fighters, and teachers retirement benefit placement plan, “Police and Firemen’s Retirement Act” defined, see §</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Police, transfer from Metropolitan to Capitol Police, creditable service as Congressional employee, annuity rights, forfeiture, see § <cite path="§10-505.03">10-505.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Police, transfer from Metropolitan to Capitol police, payments into Retirement and Disability Fund, see § <cite path="§10-505.04">10-505.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">“Retirement program” defined, see § <cite path="§1-702">1-702</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Spouse equity, application of law, see § <cite path="§1-529.01">1-529.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Spouse equity, “employee” defined, see § <cite path="§1-529.02">1-529.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Unemployment compensation, see § <cite path="§51-101">51-101</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-632.03">1-632.03</cite>, § <cite path="§1-702">1-702</cite>, § <cite path="§1-712">1-712</cite>, § <cite path="§1-732">1-732</cite>, § <cite path="§1-901.02">1-901.02</cite>, § <cite path="§5-631">5-631</cite>, § <cite path="§5-702">5-702</cite>, § <cite path="§5-704">5-704</cite>, § <cite path="§7-2203">7-2203</cite>, § <cite path="§10-505.03">10-505.03</cite>, and § <cite path="§10-505.04">10-505.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-607.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-521.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite> added par. (19).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in par. (19), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-356">D.C. Law 17-356</cite>, in par. (1), designated subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-314">D.C. Law 19-314</cite> added (20).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the New Hires Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Pension Modification Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-428, October 29, 1996,  43 DCR 6147), and § 2(a) of the New Hires Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Pension Modification Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-10, March 3, 1997,  44 DCR 1633).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Police and Firefighter’s Retirement and Disability Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-33, March 19, 2013,  60 DCR 4630, 20 DCSTAT 493).</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">Title II of the Social Security Act, referred to in subdivision (1) of this section, is codified as  42 U.S.C. §§ 401 to  433.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">Chapter 21 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subdivision (1) of this section, is codified as  26 U.S.C. § 3101 et seq.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">“Chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code,” referred to in subdivision (1) of this section, is codified as  5 U.S.C. § 8401 et seq.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">“This act,” referred to at the end of paragraph (10) of this section, means the Act of September 1, 1916, ch. 433.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act: Section 3(r) of Pub. L. 85-157 provided that this section may be cited as part of the Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Coverage Under Federal Employees’ Retirement Act: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§5-742">5-742</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Titles I and VI of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: Section 1301 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite> provided: “Titles I and VI of this act shall apply to pre-1980 employees of the Metropolitan Police Department and the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department upon their enactment by Congress.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-356">D.C. Law 17-356</cite> provided that this act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">The Budget Director of the Council of the District of Columbia has determined, as of February 15, 2012, that the fiscal effect of Law 17-356 has not been included in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore, the provisions of this section, enacted by Law 17-356, are not in effect.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Law 17-358 amended this section subject to congressional enactment.</text>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
