<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-718</num>
  <heading>Cost-of-living adjustments of annuities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each month the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall determine the per centum change in the price index. On the basis of this determination, and effective the 1st day of the 3rd month which begins after the price index shall have equaled the rise of at least 3% for 3 consecutive months over the price index for the base month, each annuity payable under this subchapter which: (1) is payable to a survivor of a member who was an officer or member of the United States Park Police force, the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division or the United States Secret Service Division; and (2) has a commencing date on or before such effective date shall be increased by 1% plus the per centum rise in the price index. For purposes of this subsection, the term “base month” means the month for which the price index showed a per centum rise forming the basis for a cost-of-living annuity increase under this subsection, except that, until the 1st cost-of-living annuity increase under this subsection, the base month shall be the last month which was the base month for purposes of <cite path="§5-716">§ 5-716</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>With respect to any annuity payable under this subchapter which is payable to a member who was an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia hired prior to January 1, 1980, or to a survivor of any such member, on January 1 of each year (or within a reasonable time thereafter), and for payments of benefits accrued by police officers and fire fighters after June 30, 1997, on January 1 of each year (or within a reasonable time thereafter), the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year by determining the difference between the index published for December of the preceding year and the index published for December of the second preceding year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If, in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, the Mayor determines in a year (beginning with 1999) that the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year indicates a rise in the price index, each annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of the year shall, effective March 1 of the year, be increased by an amount equal to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of an annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of such preceding year, the per centum change computed under subsection (b) of this section, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of an annuity having a commencing date after March 1 of such preceding year, a pro rata increase equal to the product of 1/12 of the per centum change computed under subsection (b) of this section, multiplied by the number of months (not to exceed 12 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On January 1, 1998, or within a reasonable time thereafter, the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index published for December 1997 over the price index published for June 1997.  If such per centum change indicates a rise in the price index, effective March 1, 1998:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Each annuity having a commencing date on or before September 1, 1997, shall be increased by an amount equal to such per centum change, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Each annuity having a commencing date after September 1, 1997, and on or before March 1, 1998, shall be increased by a pro rata increase equal to the product of 1/6 of such per centum change, multiplied by the number of months (not to exceed 6 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <text>With respect to any annuity payable under this section which is payable to a member who was an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Colombia, hired after December 31, 1979, or to a survivor of any such member, on January 1 of each year (or within a reasonable time thereafter), the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year by determining the difference between the index published for December of the preceding year and the index published for December of the second preceding year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-2)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If, in accordance with subsection (c-1) of this section, the Mayor determines in a year, beginning with 1997, that the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year indicates a rise in the price index, each annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of the year shall, effective March 1 of the year, be increased by an amount equal to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of an annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of such preceding year, the per centum change computed under subsection (c-1) of this section, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of an annuity having a commencing date after March 1 of such preceding year, a pro rata increase equal to the product of 1/12 of the per centum change computed under subsection (c-1) of this section, multiplied by the number of months (not to exceed 12 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On January 1, 1996, or within a reasonable time thereafter, the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index published for December 1995 over the price index published for June 1995. If such per centum change indicates a rise in the price index, effective March 1, 1996:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Each annuity having a commencing date on or before September 1, 1995, shall be increased by an amount equal to such per centum change, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Each annuity having a commencing date after September 1, 1995, and on or before March 1, 1996, shall be increased by a pro rata increase equal to the product of 1/6 of such per centum change, multiplied by the number of months (not to exceed 6 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The monthly installment of annuity after adjustment under this section shall be fixed at the nearest dollar, except that such installment shall after adjustment reflect an increase of at least $1.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term “price index” means the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published monthly by the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 64-1-ch433" path="§12|(m)">Sept. 1, 1916, 39 Stat. 718, ch. 433, § 12(m)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 96-122" type="History">as added Nov. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 912, Pub. L. 96-122, § 209(a)(1)(B)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 806, 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 11, 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 718, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11013(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-152" type="History">Sept. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-152, § 207(a), 45 DCR 4045</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000, D.C. Law 13-91, § 136, 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 12-152: Section 209 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-152">D.C. Law 12-152</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 1997.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Changes were made to this section to conform to Public Law 95-179, 91 Stat, 1371, approved November 15, 1977, striking “Executive Protective Service” and inserting “United States Secret Service Uniform Division” in its place wherever it appeared in the United States Code.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Lump-sum payments to certain retired employees: Section 101(d) of Pub. L. 99-591, the D.C. Appropriations Act, 1987, provided that, notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of each employee who retired from the Fire Department of the District of Columbia between November 24, 1984, and April 13, 1985 (both dates inclusive), and who on October 30, 1986 are receiving annuities based on service in the Fire Department, the District of Columbia Retirement Board shall cause to be paid not later than October 15, 1986, to each such employee a lump-sum payment equal to 3 percent of his or her annuity. Coverage Under Federal Employees’ Retirement Act: See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§5-742">§ 5-742</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Full Funding of Pension Liability Retirement Amendment Reform Amendment Act of 1992: Section 302 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-135">D.C. Law 10-135</cite> amends (b) and (c) to read as follows:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) With respect to any annuity payable under §§ <cite path="§4-607">4-607</cite> to <cite path="§4-630" proof="true">4-630</cite> which is payable to a member who was an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, or to a survivor of any such member, on January 1 of each year (or within a reasonable time thereafter), the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year by determining the difference between the index published for December of the preceding year and the index published for December of the second preceding year.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c)(1) If (in accordance with subsection (b) of this section) the Mayor determines in a year (beginning with 1997) that the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year indicates a rise in the price index, each annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of the year shall, effective March 1 of the year, be increased by an amount equal to —</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(A) In the case of an annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of such preceding year, the per centum change computed under subsection (b) of this section, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum; or.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(B) In the case of an annuity having a commencing date after March 1 of such preceding year, a pro rata increase equal to the product of —</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(i) One-twelfth of the per centum change computed under subsection (b) of this section, multiplied by.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(ii) The number of months (not to exceed 12 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) On January 1, 1996 (or within a reasonable time thereafter), the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index published for December 1995 over the price index published for June 1995. If such per centum change indicates a rise in the price index, effective March 1, 1996 —</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(A) Each annuity having a commencing date on or before September 1, 1995, shall be increased by an amount equal to such per centum change, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum; and.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(B) Each annuity having a commencing date after September 1, 1995, and on or before March 1, 1996, shall be increased by a pro rata increase equal to the product or —</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(i) One-sixth of such per centum change, multiplied by.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(ii) The number of months (not to exceed 6 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum.”</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(b) of the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan and Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Act of 1997 Technical Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-432, August 6, 1998,  45 DCR 5920).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 206(a) of the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-155, October 1, 1997,  44 DCR 5896), § 206(a) of the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-240, January 13, 1998,  45 DCR 531), and § 206(a) of the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan and Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Act of 1997 Technical Amendments Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-351, May 20, 1998,  45 DCR 3673).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 511 of the Omnibus Budget Support Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-44, April 28, 1995,  42 DCR 2217) and § 806 of the Omnibus Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-124, July 27, 1995,  42 DCR 4160).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Cost of Living Adjustment Extension for Public Safety Personnel Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-324, August 18, 1994,  41 DCR 6002).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 206(a) of the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan Temporary Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-58">D.C. Law 12-58</cite>, March 20, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 2093).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite> validated previously made technical amendments.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-531.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-624.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§5-716">§ 5-716</cite>, <cite path="§5-719">§ 5-719</cite>, and <cite path="§5-723.01">§ 5-723.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
