<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-722</num>
  <heading>Police and Firefighters Retirement and Relief Board.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In order to carry out his responsibilities under this subchapter with respect to retirement and disability determinations, and related functions, the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall establish a Police and Firefighters Retirement and Relief Board (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Board”). The Board shall be composed of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Members and alternates appointed from among persons who are employees of the District of Columbia, one member and one or more alternates from each of the following:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The District of Columbia Department of Human Resources;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The Office of the Attorney General;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The Department of Health;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The Metropolitan Police Department; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>The Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>One member, and one or more alternates, each of whom shall be a physician, and shall be appointed from among persons who are not officers or employees of the District of Columbia; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>One member, and one or more alternates, who shall be appointed from among persons who are not officers or employees of the District of Columbia.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The member, and one or more alternates, appointed from among employees of the Department of Health shall be physicians.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All appointments shall be made by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The members appointed under subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section shall be appointed for 2 years, and shall be entitled to receive compensation for each day they are actually engaged in carrying out duties vested in the Board in the same manner as persons employed intermittently under § 3109 of Title 5 of the United States Code. Such members shall be appointed within 90 days after September 3, 1974.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish rules for the Board to assure that the Board functions fairly and equitably. The Mayor shall provide the staff necessary for the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In addition to the members and alternates of the Board designated by subsection (a) of this section, in all cases of retirement, disability, or other relief involving a member of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division or a member of the United States Secret Service Division, who is covered by this subchapter, a member and alternate of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division or a member and alternate of the United States Secret Service Division, as designated by the Director, United States Secret Service Division, as appropriate shall sit as a member of the Police and Firemen’s Retirement and Relief Board.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-407">Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1041, Pub. L. 93-407, title I, § 122</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-635">Jan. 3, 1975, 88 Stat. 2179, Pub. L. 93-635, § 19</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 95-179">Nov. 15, 1977, 91 Stat. 1371, Pub. L. 95-179</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-174">Sept. 22, 1994, D.C. Law 10-174, § 2, 41 DCR 5171</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-198">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-198, § 3, 61 DCR 12450</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Employees retirement program management, annual report, see § <cite root="1-732">1-732</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="1-732">1-732</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 4-628.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 4-533a.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment  by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-198">D.C. Law 20-198</cite> substituted “Police and Firefighters Retirement  and Relief Board” for “Police and Firemen's Retirement  and Relief Board” in the section heading and (a); rewrote (a)(1)(A),  (a)(1)(B), and (a)(2); added (a)(3); and, in (d), substituted “who  is covered by this subchapter” for “who contributes  to the Policemen and Firemen's Relief Fund of the District of Columbia”  and substituted “Police and Firefighters Retirement and Relief  Board” for “Police and Firemen's Retirement and Relief  Board.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>Office of Personnel was substituted for Personnel Office in subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section pursuant to Mayor’s Order No. 79-84, dated May 10, 1979.</text>
      <text>Department of Human Services was substituted for Department of Human Resources in subsection (a)(1)(A) and (a)(2) pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, dated February 21, 1980.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <annotation>Delegation of Rulemaking Authority under D.C. Official Code § <cite root="5-722">5-722</cite>(c) Regarding the Police and Firemen’s Retirement and Relief Board, see Mayor’s Order 2010-44, March 19, 2010 ( 57 DCR 2349).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Order establishing Board: See Organization Order No. 48, dated September 25, 1974.</text>
      <text>Coverage Under Federal Employees’ Retirement Act: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite root="5-742">5-742</cite>.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
