<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-744</num>
  <heading>Equalization of pensions of widows and orphans granted prior to October 1, 1949.</heading>
  <text>All widows and children of deceased members of the Police Department or of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia receiving relief under the provisions of <cite path="5|7|I">subchapter I of this chapter</cite> shall be entitled to receive relief to the same extent and in the same manner as is provided by <cite path="§5-716">§ 5-716</cite>; provided, that no relief shall be increased or allowed under the authority of this section for any period prior to October 1, 1949; provided further, that any child or children who had attained the age of 16 years and whose benefits were terminated shall be entitled to receive relief as provided by <cite path="§5-716">§ 5-716</cite> until the attainment of 18 years of age.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 81-1-ch394" path="§3">Aug. 4, 1949, 63 Stat. 566, ch. 394, § 3</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3(b) of Pub. L. 111-282 provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) IMPACT ON BENEFITS UNDER THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA POLICE AND FIREFIGHTERS’ RETIREMENT AND DISABILITY SYSTEM. —</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) SALARY INCREASES FOR PURPOSES OF CERTAIN PENSIONS AND ALLOWANCES.—For purposes of section 3 of the Act entitled ”An Act to provide increased pensions for widows and children of deceased members of the Police Department and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia“, approved August 4, 1949 ( sec. 5-744, D.C. Official Code) and section 301 of the District of Columbia Police and Firemen’s Salary Act of 1953 ( sec. 5-745, D.C. Official Code)—</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(A) the conversion of positions and members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division to appropriate ranks in the salary schedule set forth in this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall not be treated as an increase in the salary of individuals who are members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(B) any adjustment of rates of basic pay of those positions and individuals in accordance with this Act and the amendments made by this Act which is made after such conversion shall be treated as an increase in the salary of individuals who are members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division on the date of the enactment of this Act.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) TREATMENT OF RETIREMENT BENEFITS AND PENSIONS OF CURRENT AND FORMER MEMBERS.—Except as otherwise provided in this Act, nothing in this Act shall affect retirement benefits and pensions of current members and former members who have retired under the District of Columbia Police and Firefighters’ Retirement and Disability System.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(a) of Pub. L. 111-282 provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) IN GENERAL.—To the extent that any provision of any law codified in the District of Columbia Official Code that authorizes an entitlement to pay or hours of work for current members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division is not expressly revoked by this Act, such provision shall not apply to such members after the effective date of this Act.”</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 4-507a.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-604.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§5-561.02">§ 5-561.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
