<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-1012.05</num>
  <heading>Voluntary dissolution by the board and members.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in § <cite root="29-1012.04">29-1012.04</cite>, for a limited cooperative association to voluntarily dissolve:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A resolution to dissolve shall be approved by a majority vote of the board of directors unless a greater percentage is required by the organic rules;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The board of directors shall call a members meeting to consider the resolution, to be held not later than 90 days after adoption of the resolution; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The board of directors shall mail or otherwise transmit or deliver to each member in a record that complies with § <cite root="29-1005.08">29-1005.08</cite>:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The resolution required by paragraph (1) of this subsection;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A recommendation that the members vote in favor of the resolution or, if the board determines that because of conflict of interest or other special circumstances, it should not make a favorable recommendation, the basis of that determination; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Notice of the members meeting, which shall be given in the same manner as notice of a special meeting of members.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a resolution to dissolve shall be approved by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least 2/3 of the voting power of members present at a members meeting called under subsection (a)(2) of this section; and</text>
      <text>23</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the limited cooperative association has investor members, at least a majority of the votes cast by patron members, unless the organic rules require a greater percentage.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The organic rules may require that the percentage of votes under subsection (b)(1) of this section shall be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A different percentage that is not less than a majority of members voting at the meeting; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Measured against the voting power of all members; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A combination of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="29-1001.09">29-1001.09</cite> and § <cite root="29-1012.02">29-1012.02</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1205 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
