<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1015.04</num>
  <heading>Approval or abandonment of merger by members.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a plan of merger shall be approved by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least 2/3 of the voting power of members present at a members meeting called under § <cite path="§29-1015.03">29-1015.03</cite>(b); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the limited cooperative association has investor members, at least a majority of the votes cast by patron members, unless the organic rules require a greater percentage vote by patron members.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The organic rules may provide that the percentage of votes under subsection (a)(1) of this section shall be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A different percentage that is not less than a majority of members voting at the meeting;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Measured against the voting power of all members; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A combination of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The vote required to approve a plan of merger shall not be less than the vote required for the members of the limited cooperative association to amend the articles of organization.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Consent in a record to a plan of merger by a member shall be delivered to the limited cooperative association before delivery of articles of merger for filing pursuant to § <cite path="§29-1015.05">29-1015.05</cite> if as a result of the merger the member will have an obligation or liability for an additional contribution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (d) of this section and any contractual rights, after a merger is approved, and at any time before the effective date of the merger, a limited cooperative association that is a party to the merger may approve an amendment to the plan of merger or approve abandonment of the planned merger:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As provided in the plan; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Except as prohibited by the plan, with the same affirmative vote of the board of directors and of the members as was required to approve the plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The voting requirements for districts, classes, or voting groups under § <cite path="§29-1004.04">29-1004.04</cite> shall apply to approval of a merger under this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-1001.09">29-1001.09</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1608 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
