<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1012.03</num>
  <heading>Judicial dissolution.</heading>
  <text>The Superior Court may dissolve a limited cooperative association or order any action that under the circumstances is appropriate and equitable in a proceeding initiated by:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia, if the association:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Obtained its articles of organization through fraud; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Has continued to exceed or abuse the authority conferred upon it by law; or</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A member, if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The directors are deadlocked in the management of the association’s affairs, the members are unable to break the deadlock, and irreparable injury to the association is occurring or is threatened because of the deadlock;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The directors or those in control of the association have acted, are acting, or will act in a manner that is illegal, oppressive, or fraudulent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The members are deadlocked in voting power and have failed to elect successors to directors whose terms have expired for 2 consecutive periods during which annual members meetings were held or were to be held; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>The assets of the association are being misapplied or wasted.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-1012.02">29-1012.02</cite> and § <cite path="§29-1012.13">29-1012.13</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1203 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
