<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1301.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Benefit corporation” means a business corporation:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>That has elected to become subject to this chapter; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The status of which as a benefit corporation has not been terminated under <cite path="§29-1301.06">§ 29-1301.06</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Benefit director” means either:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The director designated as the benefit director of a benefit corporation under <cite path="§29-1303.02">§ 29-1303.02</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A person with one or more of the powers, duties, or rights of a benefit director to the extent provided in the bylaws under <cite path="§29-1303.02">§ 29-1303.02</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Benefit enforcement proceeding” means any claim or action for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Failure of a benefit corporation to pursue or create general public benefit or a specific public benefit purpose set forth in its articles of incorporation; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A violation of any obligation, duty, or standard of conduct under this chapter.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Benefit officer” means the individual designated as the benefit officer of a benefit corporation under <cite path="§29-1303.04">§ 29-1303.04</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>“General public benefit” means the material positive impact that the business and operations of a benefit corporation has on society and the environment, taken as a whole, assessed against a third-party standard.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>“Independent”, subject to subsection (b) of this section, means having no material relationship with a benefit corporation or a subsidiary of the benefit corporation. A person who serves as a benefit director or benefit officer is not independent by virtue of such service. A material relationship between a person and a benefit corporation or any of its subsidiaries will be conclusively presumed to exist if any of the following apply:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The person is, or has been within the last 3 years, an employee other than a benefit officer of the benefit corporation or a subsidiary of the benefit corporation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An immediate family member of the person is, or has been within the last 3 years, an executive officer other than a benefit officer of the benefit corporation or its subsidiary.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>There is beneficial or record ownership of 5% or more of the outstanding shares of the benefit corporation by:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The person; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>An entity of which the person is a director, an officer, or a manager or in which the person owns beneficially or of record 5% or more of the outstanding equity interests.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>“Minimum status vote” means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of a business corporation, in addition to any other required approval or vote, the satisfaction of the following conditions:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The shareholders of every class or series shall be entitled to vote as a separate voting group on the corporate action regardless of a limitation stated in the articles of incorporation or bylaws on the voting rights of any class or series.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The corporate action must be approved by vote of the shareholders of each voting group entitled to cast at least 2/3 of the votes that all shareholders of the voting group are entitled to cast on the action.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of an entity other than a business corporation, in addition to any other required approval, vote, or consent, the satisfaction of the following conditions:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The holders of each class or series of equity interest in the entity that are entitled to receive a distribution of any kind from the entity shall be entitled as a separate voting group to vote on or consent to the action regardless of any otherwise applicable limitation on the voting or consent rights of any class or series.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The action must be approved by vote or consent of each voting group described in sub-subparagraph (i) of this subparagraph entitled to cast at least 2/3 of the votes or consents that all the members of the group are entitled to cast on the action.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>“Specific public benefit” includes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Providing low-income or underserved individuals or communities with beneficial products or services;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Promoting economic opportunity for individuals or communities beyond the creation of jobs in the normal course of business;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Preserving the environment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Improving human health;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Promoting the arts, sciences, or advancement of knowledge;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Increasing the flow of capital to entities with a public benefit purpose; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>The accomplishment of any other particular benefit on society or the environment.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>“Subsidiary” means, subject to subsection (b) of this section, in relation to a person, an entity in which the person owns beneficially or of record 50% or more of the outstanding equity interests.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>“Third-party standard” means a recognized standard for defining, reporting, and assessing corporate social and environmental performance that is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Comprehensive in that it assesses the effect of the business and its operations upon the interests listed in <cite path="§29-1303.01|(a)|(1)|(B)">§ 29-1303.01(a)(1)(B)</cite>, (C), (D), and (E);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Developed by an organization that is independent of the benefit corporation and satisfies the following requirements:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Not more than 1/3 of the members of the governing body of the organization are representatives of any of the following:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>An association of businesses operating in a specific industry the performance of whose members is measured by the third-party standard;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>Businesses from a specific industry or an association of businesses in that industry; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(III)</num>
            <text>Businesses whose performance is assessed against the standard.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The organization is not materially financed by an association or business described in sub-subparagraph (i) of this subparagraph;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Credible because the standard is developed by a person that both:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Has access to necessary expertise to assess overall corporate social and environmental performance; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Uses a balanced multi-stakeholder approach, including a public comment period of at least 30 days to develop the standard; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Transparent because the following information is publicly available:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>About the standard:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>The criteria considered when measuring the overall social and environmental performance of a business; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>The relative weightings of those criteria; and</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>About the development and revision of the standard:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>The identity of the directors, officers, material owners, and the governing body of the organization that developed and controls revisions to the standard;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>The process by which revisions to the standard and changes to the membership of the governing body are made; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(III)</num>
            <text>An accounting of the sources of financial support for the organization, with sufficient detail to disclose any relationships that could reasonably be considered to present a potential conflict of interest.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For purposes of the definitions of the terms “independent” and “subsidiary” in subsection (a) of this section, a percentage of ownership in an entity shall be calculated as if all outstanding rights to acquire equity interests in the entity have been exercised.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-305" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-305, § 2(b), 60 DCR 2735</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
