<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-103.02</num>
  <heading>Name requirements for certain types of entities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The name of a business corporation shall contain the word “corporation”, “incorporated”, “company”, or “limited”, or the abbreviation “Corp.”, “Inc.”, “Co.”, or “Ltd.”, or words or abbreviations of similar import in another language.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The name of a nonprofit corporation need not contain any particular word or abbreviation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The name of a professional corporation shall contain the phrase “professional corporation” or the abbreviation “P.C.”, or the word “chartered”, or the abbreviation “Chtd”, and may not contain the word “company”, “incorporated”, “corporation”, or “limited”, or an abbreviation of those words.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The name of a limited partnership may contain the name of any partner. If the limited partnership is not a limited liability limited partnership, the name shall contain the phrase “limited partnership” or the abbreviation “L.P.” or “LP” and shall not contain the phrase “limited liability limited partnership” or “registered limited liability limited partnership” or the abbreviation “L.L.L.P.”, “LLLP”, “R.L.L.L.P.”, or “RLLLP”. If the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership, the name shall contain the phrase “limited liability limited partnership” or the abbreviation “L.L.L.P.”, “LLLP”, “R.L.L.L.P.”, or “RLLLP” and shall not contain the abbreviation “L.P.” or “LP”.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The name of a limited liability partnership that is not a limited liability limited partnership shall contain the words “limited liability partnership” or “registered limited liability partnership” or the abbreviation “L.L.P.”, “R.L.L.P.”, “LLP”, or “RLLP”. The name of a partnership that is not a limited liability partnership may not contain these names or abbreviations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The name of a limited liability company other than a professional limited liability company shall contain the words “limited liability company” or “limited company” or the abbreviation “L.L.C.”, “LLC”, “L.C.”, or “LC”. The name of a professional limited liability company shall contain the words “professional limited liability company” or the abbreviation “P.L.L.C.” or “PLLC”. “Limited” may be abbreviated as “Ltd.”, and “company” may be abbreviated as “Co.”.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The name of a general cooperative shall contain the words “cooperative association”. “Cooperative” may be abbreviated as “Co-op” or “Coop”. “Association” may be abbreviated as “Assoc.”, “Assoc”, “Assn.”, or “Assn”.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The name of a limited cooperative association shall contain the words “limited cooperative association” or “limited cooperative” or the abbreviation “L.C.A.” or “LCA”. “Limited” may be abbreviated as “Ltd.”. “Cooperative” may be abbreviated as “Co-op.”, “Coop.”, “Co-op”, or “Coop”. “Association” may be abbreviated as “Assoc.”, “Assoc”, “Assn.”, or “Assn”.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The name of a statutory trust may contain the words or abbreviations “company”, “association”, “club”, “foundation”, “fund”, “institute”, “society”, “union”, “syndicate”, “limited”, or “trust”, or words or abbreviations of similar import, and may contain the name of a beneficial owner, a trustee, or any other person.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(a)(14), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> added the second sentence in (e); and twice substituted “words or abbreviations” for “words” in (i).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-302.02">29-302.02</cite>, § <cite path="§29-307.03">29-307.03</cite>, § <cite path="§29-610.01">29-610.01</cite>, § <cite path="§29-610.05">29-610.05</cite>, § <cite path="§29-702.01">29-702.01</cite>, § <cite path="§29-802.01">29-802.01</cite>, § <cite path="§29-802.06">29-802.06</cite>, § <cite path="§29-1003.02">29-1003.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-1202.01">29-1202.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
