<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-104.10</num>
  <heading>Resignation of registered agent.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A registered agent may resign as agent for a represented entity by delivering to the Mayor for filing a statement of resignation signed by the agent which states:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the entity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name of the agent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That the agent resigns from serving the registered agent for the entity; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The address of the entity to which the agent will send the notice required by subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A statement of resignation shall be effective on the earlier of the 31st day after the day on which it is filed by the Mayor or the designation of a new registered agent for the represented entity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A registered agent promptly shall furnish the represented entity notice in a record of the date on which a statement of resignation was filed by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>When a statement of resignation takes effect, the registered agent shall cease to have responsibility under this subchapter for any matter thereafter tendered to it as agent for the represented entity. The resignation shall not affect any contractual rights the entity has against the agent or that the agent has against the entity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A registered agent may resign with respect to a represented entity whether or not the entity is in good standing.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(a)(24), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-104.03">29-104.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> deleted “or on behalf of” following “signed by” in the introductory language of (a); substituted “the registered agent” for “agent for service of process” in (a)(3); substituted “designation” for “appointment” in (b); substituted “filed by the Mayor” for “delivered to the Mayor for filing” in (b) and (c); and substituted “responsibility under this subchapter for any matter thereafter tendered” for “responsibility for any matter tendered” in (d).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
