<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-1008.04</num>
  <heading>Election of directors and composition of board.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules require a greater number:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of directors that shall be patron members may not be fewer than:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>One, if there are 2 or 3 directors;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Two, if there are 4 or 5 directors;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Three if there are 6 through 8 directors; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>One-third of the directors if there are at least 9 directors; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A majority of the board of directors shall be elected exclusively by patron members.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, if a limited cooperative association has investor members, the directors who are not elected exclusively by patron members shall be elected by the investor members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (a) of this section, the organic rules may provide for the election of all or a specified number of directors by one or more districts or classes of members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (a) of this section, the organic rules may provide for the nomination or election of directors by districts or classes, directly or by district delegates.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a class of members consists of a single member, the organic rules may provide for the member to appoint a director or directors.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, cumulative voting for directors shall be prohibited.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in the organic rules, subsection (e) of this section, or §§ <cite path="§29-1003.03">29-1003.03</cite>, <cite path="§29-1005.16">29-1005.16</cite>, <cite path="§29-1005.17">29-1005.17</cite>, and <cite path="§29-1008.09">29-1008.09</cite>, member directors shall be elected at an annual members meeting.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 804 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act. Edition</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
