<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-1003.02</num>
  <heading>Formation of limited cooperative association; articles of organization.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To form a limited cooperative association, an organizer of the association must deliver articles of organization to the Mayor for filing. The articles shall state:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the association, which shall comply with §§ <cite path="§29-103.01">29-103.01</cite> and <cite path="§29-103.02">29-103.02</cite>(h);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The purposes for which the association is formed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The street address and, if different, mailing address of the association’s initial principal office and the information required by § <cite path="§29-104.04">29-104.04</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The name and street address and, if different, mailing address of each organizer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The term for which the association is to exist if other than perpetual.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to § <cite path="§29-1001.09">29-1001.09</cite>(a), articles of organization may contain any other provisions in addition to those required by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A limited cooperative association shall be formed after articles of organization that substantially comply with subsection (a) of this section are delivered to the Mayor, are filed, and become effective under § <cite path="§29-102.03">29-102.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If articles of organization filed by the Mayor state a delayed effective date, a limited cooperative association shall not be formed if, before the articles take effect, an organizer signs and delivers to the Mayor for filing a statement of cancellation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-101.06">29-101.06</cite> and § <cite path="§29-1002.01">29-1002.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 302 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
