<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1010.08</num>
  <heading>Liability for improper distributions; limitation of action.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) of this section, if a director of a limited cooperative association consents to a distribution made in violation of <cite path="§29-1010.07">§ 29-1010.07</cite> and in consenting to the distribution fails to comply with <cite path="§29-1008.18">§ 29-1008.18</cite>, the director is personally liable to the association for the amount of the distribution that exceeds the amount which could have been distributed without violating <cite path="§29-1010.07">§ 29-1010.07</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person that receives a distribution knowing that the distribution was made in violation of <cite path="§29-1010.07">§ 29-1010.07</cite> shall be personally liable to the limited cooperative association to the extent the distribution exceeded the amount that could have been properly paid.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A director against whom an action is commenced under subsection (a) of this section may implead in the action any:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Other person who is liable under subsection (a) of this section and seek to enforce a right of contribution from the person; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Person that receives a distribution in violation of subsection (b) of this section and may seek to enforce a right of contribution from the person in the amount the person received in violation [of] subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An action under this section shall be barred if it is commenced later than 2 years after the distribution.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(j)(6)(B), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1008 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> rewrote (a); substituted “person that receives” for “member or transferee of financial rights which received” in (b); and rewrote (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-1001.02">§ 29-1001.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
