<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-105.06</num>
  <heading>Noncomplying name of foreign entity.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A registered foreign entity whose name does not comply with § <cite path="§29-103.01">29-103.01</cite> for an entity of its type shall not register to do business in the District until it adopts, for the purpose of doing business in the District, an alternate name that complies with § <cite path="§29-103.01">29-103.01</cite>. A registered foreign entity that registers under an alternate name under this subsection need not comply with subchapter I-C of Chapter 48 of Title 47. After registering to do business in the District with an alternate name, a registered foreign entity may do business in the District under:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The alternate name;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Its entity name, with the addition of its jurisdiction of formation clearly identified; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An assumed or fictitious name the entity is authorized to use under subchapter I-C of Chapter 48 of Title 47.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a registered foreign entity changes its name to one that does not comply with § <cite path="§29-103.01">29-103.01</cite>, it shall not do business in the District until it complies with subsection (a) of this section by amending its registration to adopt an alternate name that complies with § <cite path="§29-103.01">29-103.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(a)(33), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-103.04">29-103.04</cite>, § <cite path="§29-105.03">29-105.03</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-105.10">29-105.10</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “registered foreign entity” for “foreign filing entity or foreign limited liability partnership” throughout the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
