<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1002.01</num>
  <heading>Signing of records delivered for filing to Mayor.</heading>
  <text>A record delivered to the Mayor for filing pursuant to this chapter shall be signed as follows:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The initial articles of organization shall be signed by at least one organizer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A statement of cancellation under § <cite path="§29-1003.02">29-1003.02</cite>(d) shall be signed by at least one organizer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, a record signed on behalf of an existing limited cooperative association shall be signed by an officer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>A record filed on behalf of a dissolved association shall be signed by a person winding up activities under § <cite path="§29-1012.06">29-1012.06</cite> or a person appointed under § <cite path="§29-1012.06">29-1012.06</cite> to wind up those activities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Any other record delivered on behalf of a person to the Mayor for filing must be signed by that person.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(j)(3)(A), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</law-cite> deleted the subsection “(a)” designation; substituted “delivered on behalf of a person to the Mayor for filing must be signed by that person” for “shall be signed by the person on whose behalf the record is delivered to the Mayor” in (5); and repealed former (b), which read: “Any record to be signed under this chapter may be signed by an authorized agent.”</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 201 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
