<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1119</num>
  <heading>Duties of manager.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A manager shall owe to the unincorporated nonprofit association and to its members the fiduciary duties of loyalty and care.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A manager shall manage the unincorporated nonprofit association in good faith, in a manner the manager reasonably believes to be in the best interests of the association, and with such care, including reasonable inquiry, as a prudent person would reasonably exercise in a similar position and under similar circumstances. A manager may rely in good faith upon any opinion, report, statement, or other information provided by another person that the manager reasonably believes is a competent and reliable source for the information.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>After full disclosure of all material facts, a specific act or transaction that would otherwise violate the duty of loyalty by a manager may be authorized or ratified by a majority of the members that are not interested directly or indirectly in the act or transaction.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A manager that makes a business judgment in good faith satisfies the duties specified in subsection (a) of this section if the manager:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is not interested, directly or indirectly, in the subject of the business judgment and is otherwise able to exercise independent judgment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is informed with respect to the subject of the business judgment to the extent the manager reasonably believes to be appropriate under the circumstances; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Believes that the business judgment is in the best interests of the unincorporated nonprofit association and in accordance with its purposes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The governing principles in a record may limit or eliminate the liability of a manager to the unincorporated nonprofit association or its members for damages for any action taken, or for failure to take any action, as a manager, except liability for:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The amount of financial benefit improperly received by a manager;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An intentional infliction of harm on the association or one or more of its members;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An intentional violation of criminal law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Breach of the duty of loyalty; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Improper distributions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 23 of the Uniform Unincorporated Nonprofit Association Act (2008 Act).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-1123">§ 29-1123</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
