<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1204.02</num>
  <heading>Liability of series trust.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In a series trust, a debt, obligation, or other liability incurred or otherwise existing [with] respect to the:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Property of a particular series shall be enforceable against the property of the series only, and not against the property of the trust generally or any other series thereof; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Trust generally or the property of any other series thereof shall not be enforceable against the property of the series.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The association, disassociation, or reassociation of property of a statutory trust or a series thereof to or with the trust or a series thereof, including by a transaction under subchapter VII of this chapter or Chapter 2 of this title is deemed to be a transfer between separate persons under Chapter 31 of Title 28 and a distribution under § <cite path="§29-1206.15">29-1206.15</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The rules pertaining to distributions under §§ <cite path="§29-1206.15">29-1206.15</cite> and <cite path="§29-1206.16">29-1206.16</cite> apply to a distribution from a series trust and from the property of any series thereof, except for a distribution under § <cite path="§29-1204.04">29-1204.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(l)(5)(B), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-1201.04">29-1201.04</cite> and § <cite path="§29-1204.05">29-1204.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite>, in (b), substituted “a transaction under subchapter VII of this chapter or Chapter 2 of this title is” for “conversion or merger under subchapter VII of this chapter shall be” and added “and a distribution under § <cite path="§29-1206.15">29-1206.15</cite>”; and added (c).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 402 of the Uniform Statutory Trust Entity Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
