<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-205.01</num>
  <heading>Domestication authorized.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, by complying with this subchapter, a domestic entity may become a domestic entity of the same type in a foreign jurisdiction if the domestication is authorized by the law of the foreign jurisdiction.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, by complying with the provisions of this subchapter applicable to foreign entities, a foreign entity may become a domestic entity of the same type in the District if the domestication is authorized by the law of the foreign entity’s jurisdiction of formation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a protected agreement contains a provision that applies to a merger of a domestic entity but does not refer to a domestication, the provision shall apply to a domestication of the entity as if the domestication were a merger until the provision is amended after the effective date of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This subchapter does not apply to the domestication of the following entities:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A business corporation subject to <cite path="29|3|VII">subchapter VII of Chapter 3 of this title</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A nonprofit corporation subject to <cite path="29|4|VII">subchapter VII of Chapter 4 of this title</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A limited liability company subject to <cite path="29|8|IX">subchapter IX of Chapter 8 of this title</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(b)(23), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “formation” for “organization” in (b); repealed former (c), which read: “When the term ”domestic entity’ is used in this subchapter with reference to a foreign jurisdiction, it means an entity whose internal affairs are governed by the law of the foreign jurisdiction.”; redesignated former (d) and (e) as present (c) and (d), respectively; and substituted “This subchapter does not apply to the domestication of the following entities” for “The following entities shall not engage in a domestication under this subchapter” in the introductory language of (d).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
