<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-202.03</num>
  <heading>Approval of merger.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A plan of merger shall not be effective unless it has been approved:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By a domestic merging entity:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In accordance with the requirements, if any, in its organic law and organic rules for approval of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>In the case of an entity that is not a business corporation, a merger; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>In the case of a business corporation, a merger requiring approval by a vote of the interest holders of the business corporation; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If its organic law or organic rules do not provide for approval of a merger described in subparagraph (A)(ii) of this paragraph, by all of the interest holders of the entity entitled to vote on or consent to any matter; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In a record, by each interest holder of a domestic merging entity that will have interest holder liability for debts, obligations, and other liabilities that arise after the merger becomes effective, unless, in the case of an entity that is not a business corporation or nonprofit corporation:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The organic rules of the entity provide in a record for the approval of an merger in which some or all of its interest holders become subject to interest holder liability by the vote or consent of less than all of the interest holders; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The interest holder voted for or consented in a record to that provision of the organic rules or became an interest holder after the adoption of that provision.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A merger under this chapter involving a foreign merging is not effective unless it is approved by the foreign entity in accordance with the law of the foreign entity’s jurisdiction of formation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(b)(7), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “debts, obligations, and other liabilities” for “liabilities” in (a)(2); and in (b), added “under this chapter” following “merger”, and substituted “is not effective” for “shall not be effective”, and “formation” for “organization.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
