<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-205.03</num>
  <heading>Approval of domestication.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A plan of domestication shall not be effective unless it has been approved:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By a domestic domesticating entity:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In accordance with the requirements, if any, in its organic rules for approval of a domestication;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If its organic rules do not provide for approval of a domestication, in accordance with the requirements, if any, in its organic law and organic rules for approval of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>In the case of an entity that is not a business corporation, a merger as if the domestication were a merger; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>In the case of a business corporation, a merger requiring approval by a vote of the interest holders of the business corporation as if the domestication were that type of merger; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If its organic law or organic rules do not provide for approval of a domestication or a merger described in subparagraph (B)(ii) of this paragraph, by all of the interest holders of the entity entitled to vote on or consent to any matter; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In a record, by each interest holder of a domestic domesticating entity that will have interest holder liability for liabilities that arise after the domestication becomes effective, unless, in the case of an entity that is not a business corporation or nonprofit corporation:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The organic rules of the entity in a record provide for the approval of a domestication or merger in which some or all of its interest holders become subject to interest holder liability by the vote or consent of less than all of the interest holders; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The interest holder voted for or consented in a record to that provision of the organic rules or became an interest holder after the adoption of that provision.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A domestication of a foreign domesticating entity shall not be effective unless it is approved in accordance with the law of the foreign entity’s jurisdiction of formation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(b)(25), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-201.02">29-201.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “formation” for “organization” in (b).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
