<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-203.05</num>
  <heading>Statement of interest exchange; effective date.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A statement of interest exchange shall be signed on behalf of a domestic acquired entity and delivered to the Mayor for filing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A statement of interest exchange shall contain:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name and type of the acquired entity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name, jurisdiction of formation, and type of entity of the acquiring entity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the statement of interest exchange is not to be effective upon filing, the later date and time on which it will become effective, which shall not be more than 90 days after the date of filing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A statement that the plan of interest exchange was approved by the acquired entity in accordance with this subchapter; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Any amendments to the acquired entity’s public organic record approved as part of the plan of interest exchange.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, a statement of interest exchange may contain any other provision not prohibited by law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A plan of interest exchange that is signed on behalf of a domestic acquired entity and meets all of the requirements of subsection (b) of this section may be delivered to the Mayor for filing instead of a statement of interest exchange and upon filing by the Mayor has the same effect. If a plan of interest exchange is filed as provided in this subsection, references in this chapter to a statement of interest exchange shall refer to the plan of interest exchange filed under this subsection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A statement of interest exchange shall be effective upon the date and time of filing or the later date and time specified in the statement of interest exchange.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(b)(15), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “delivered to the Mayor for filing” for “filed with the Mayor” in (a) and (d); substituted “formation, and type of entity” for “organization, and type” in (b)(2); substituted “record” for “document” in (b)(5); and added “by the Mayor” following “filing” in the second sentence of (d).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
