<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-312.06</num>
  <heading>Known claims against dissolved corporation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A dissolved corporation may dispose of the known claims against it by notifying its known claimants in writing of the dissolution at any time after its effective date.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The written notice shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Describe information that must be included in a claim;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide a mailing address where a claim may be sent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>State the deadline, which may not be fewer than 120 days from the effective date of the written notice, by which the dissolved corporation must receive the claim; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>State that the claim will be barred if not received by the deadline.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A claim against the dissolved corporation shall be barred if a claimant:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That was given written notice under subsection (b) of this section does not deliver the claim to the dissolved corporation by the deadline; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Whose claim was rejected by the dissolved corporation does not commence a proceeding to enforce the claim within 90 days from the effective date of the rejection notice.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term “claim” does not include a contingent liability or a claim based on an event occurring after the effective date of dissolution.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-312.07">29-312.07</cite>, § <cite path="§29-312.09">29-312.09</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-312.23">29-312.23</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
