<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-312.24</num>
  <heading>Election to purchase in lieu of dissolution.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In a proceeding under § <cite path="§29-312.20">29-312.20</cite>(a)(2) to dissolve a corporation, the corporation may elect or, if it fails to elect, one or more shareholders may elect to purchase all shares owned by the petitioning shareholder at the fair value of the shares. An election pursuant to this section shall be irrevocable unless the court determines that it is equitable to set aside or modify the election.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An election to purchase pursuant to this section may be filed with the Superior Court at any time within 90 days after the filing of the petition under § <cite path="§29-312.20">29-312.20</cite>(a)(2) or at such later time as the court in its discretion may allow. If the election to purchase is filed by one or more shareholders, the corporation shall, within 10 days thereafter, give written notice to all shareholders, other than the petitioner. The notice shall state the name and number of shares owned by the petitioner and the name and number of shares owned by each electing shareholder and shall advise the recipients of their right to join in the election to purchase shares in accordance with this section. Shareholders that wish to participate shall file notice of their intention to join in the purchase no later than 30 days after the effective date of the notice to them. All shareholders that have filed an election or notice of their intention to participate in the election to purchase thereby become parties to the proceeding and shall participate in the purchase in proportion to their ownership of shares as of the date the first election was filed, unless they otherwise agree or the court otherwise directs. After an election has been filed by the corporation or one or more shareholders, the proceeding under § <cite path="§29-312.20">29-312.20</cite>(a)(2) shall not be discontinued or settled and the petitioning shareholder shall not sell or otherwise dispose of his or her shares, unless the court determines that it would be equitable to the corporation and the shareholders, other than the petitioner, to permit such discontinuance, settlement, sale, or other disposition.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If, within 60 days of the filing of the first election, the parties reach agreement as to the fair value and terms of purchase of the petitioner’s shares, the Superior Court shall enter an order directing the purchase of petitioner’s shares upon the terms and conditions agreed to by the parties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the parties are unable to reach an agreement as provided for in subsection (c) of this section, the Superior Court, upon application of any party, shall stay the § <cite path="§29-312.20">29-312.20</cite>(a)(2) proceedings and determine the fair value of the petitioner’s shares as of the day before the date on which the petition under § <cite path="§29-312.20">29-312.20</cite>(a)(2) was filed or as of such other date as the court deems appropriate under the circumstances.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Upon determining the fair value of the shares, the Superior Court shall enter an order directing the purchase upon such terms and conditions as the court considers appropriate, which may include payment of the purchase price in installments, if necessary in the interests of equity, provision for security to assure payment of the purchase price and any additional expenses as may have been awarded, and, if the shares are to be purchased by shareholders, the allocation of shares among them. In allocating petitioner’s shares among holders of different classes of shares, the court shall attempt to preserve the existing distribution of voting rights among holders of different classes insofar as practicable and may direct that holders of a specific class or classes not participate in the purchase. Interest may be allowed at the rate and from the date determined by the court to be equitable, but if the court finds that the refusal of the petitioning shareholder to accept an offer of payment was arbitrary or otherwise not in good faith, no interest shall be allowed. If the court finds that the petitioning shareholder had probable grounds for relief under § <cite path="§29-312.20">29-312.20</cite>(a)(2)(B) or (D), it may award expenses to the petitioning shareholder.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Upon entry of an order under subsections (c) or (e) of this section, the Superior Court shall dismiss the petition to dissolve the corporation under § <cite path="§29-312.20">29-312.20</cite>(a)(2), and the petitioning shareholder shall no longer have any rights or status as a shareholder of the corporation, except the right to receive the amounts awarded by the order of the court which is enforceable in the same manner as any other judgment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The purchase ordered pursuant to subsection (e) of this section shall be made within 10 days after the date the order becomes final unless before that time the corporation files with the Superior Court a notice of its intention to adopt articles of dissolution pursuant to §§ <cite path="§29-312.02">29-312.02</cite> and <cite path="§29-312.03">29-312.03</cite>, which articles shall then be adopted and filed within 50 days thereafter. Upon filing of such articles of dissolution, the corporation is dissolved in accordance with §§ <cite path="§29-312.05">29-312.05</cite> through <cite path="§29-312.07">29-312.07</cite>, and the order entered pursuant to subsection (e) of this section shall no longer be of any force or effect, except that the court may award the petitioning shareholder expenses in accordance with the last sentence of subsection (e) of this section and the petitioner may continue to pursue any claims previously asserted on behalf of the corporation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Any payment by the corporation pursuant to an order under subsections (c) or (e) of this section, other than an award of expenses pursuant to subsection (e) of this section, shall be subject to § <cite path="§29-304.60">29-304.60</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-312.21">29-312.21</cite> and § <cite path="§29-312.22">29-312.22</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
