<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-306.53</num>
  <heading>Advance for expenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A corporation may, before final disposition of a proceeding, advance funds to pay for or reimburse expenses incurred in connection with the proceeding by an individual who is a party to the proceeding because that individual is a member of the board of directors if the director delivers to the corporation:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A signed affirmation in a record of the director’s good faith belief that the relevant standard of conduct described in § <cite path="§29-306.51">29-306.51</cite> has been met by the director or that the proceeding involves conduct for which liability has been eliminated under a provision of the articles of incorporation as authorized by § <cite path="§29-302.02">29-302.02</cite>(b)(4); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An undertaking in a record of the director to repay any funds advanced if the director is not entitled to mandatory indemnification under § <cite path="§29-306.52">29-306.52</cite> and it is ultimately determined under § <cite path="§29-306.54">29-306.54</cite> or § <cite path="§29-306.55">29-306.55</cite> that the director has not met the relevant standard of conduct described in § <cite path="§29-306.51">29-306.51</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The undertaking required by subsection (a)(2) of this section shall be an unlimited general obligation of the director, but need not be secured and may be accepted without reference to the financial ability of the director to make repayment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The authorization under this section shall be made:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By the board of directors:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If there are 2 or more qualified directors, by a majority vote of all the qualified directors, a majority of whom shall for such purpose constitute a quorum, or by a majority of the members of a committee of 2 or more qualified directors appointed by such a vote; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If there are fewer than 2 qualified directors, by the vote necessary for action by the board in accordance with § <cite path="§29-306.24">29-306.24</cite>(c), in which authorization directors who are not qualified directors may participate; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By the shareholders, but shares owned by or voted under the control of a director who at the time is not a qualified director shall not be voted on the authorization.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(c)(20), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-301.21">29-301.21</cite>, § <cite path="§29-306.54">29-306.54</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-306.58">29-306.58</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “signed affirmation in a record” for “written affirmation” in (a)(1); and substituted “An undertaking in a record” for “A written undertaking” in (a)(2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
