<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-306.56</num>
  <heading>Indemnification of officers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A corporation may indemnify and advance expenses under this part to an officer of the corporation who is a party to a proceeding because he or she is an officer of the corporation:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To the same extent as a director; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If he or she is an officer but not a director, to such further extent as may be provided by the articles of incorporation, the bylaws, a resolution of the board of directors, or contract, except for liability:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In connection with a proceeding by or in the right of the corporation other than for expenses incurred in connection with the proceeding; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Arising out of conduct that constitutes:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Receipt by the officer of a financial benefit to which the officer is not entitled;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>An intentional infliction of harm on the corporation or the shareholders; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>An intentional violation of criminal law.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a)(2) of this section shall apply to an officer who is also a director if the basis on which the officer is made a party to the proceeding is an act or omission solely as an officer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An officer of a corporation who is not a director shall be entitled to mandatory indemnification under § <cite path="§29-306.52">29-306.52</cite>, and may apply to the Superior Court under § <cite path="§29-306.54">29-306.54</cite> for indemnification or an advance for expenses, in each case to the same extent to which a director may be entitled to indemnification or advance for expenses under those provisions.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-306.50">29-306.50</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
