<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-305.03</num>
  <heading>Court-ordered meeting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court may summarily order a meeting to be held on application of a shareholder:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Entitled to participate in an annual meeting if an annual meeting was not held or action by written consent in lieu thereof did not become effective within the earlier of 6 months after the end of the corporation’s fiscal year or 15 months after its last annual meeting; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That signed a demand for a special meeting valid under § <cite path="§29-305.02">29-305.02</cite>, if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Notice of the special meeting was not given within 30 days after the date the demand was delivered to the corporation’s secretary; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The special meeting was not held in accordance with the notice.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court may fix the time and place of the meeting, determine the shares entitled to participate in the meeting, specify a record date for determining shareholders entitled to notice of and to vote at the meeting, prescribe the form and content of the meeting notice, fix the quorum required for specific matters to be considered at the meeting, or direct that the votes represented at the meeting constitute a quorum for action on those matters, and enter other orders necessary to accomplish the purpose or purposes of the meeting.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-305.02">29-305.02</cite> and § <cite path="§29-305.05">29-305.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
