<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-306.24</num>
  <heading>Quorum and voting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless the articles of incorporation or bylaws require a greater number or unless otherwise specifically provided in this chapter, a quorum of a board of directors shall consist of a majority of the:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fixed number of directors if the corporation has a fixed board size; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Number of directors prescribed or, if no number is prescribed, the number in office immediately before the meeting begins, if the corporation has a variable-range size board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The articles of incorporation or bylaws may authorize a quorum of a board of directors to consist of no less than 1/3 of the fixed or prescribed number of directors determined under subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a quorum is present when a vote is taken, the affirmative vote of a majority of directors present shall be the act of the board of directors unless the articles of incorporation or bylaws require the vote of a greater number of directors.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A director who is present at a meeting of the board of directors or a committee of the board of directors when corporate action is taken shall be deemed to have assented to the action taken unless:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The director objects at the beginning of the meeting, or promptly upon arrival, to holding it or transacting at the meeting;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The dissent or abstention from the action taken is entered in the minutes of the meeting; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The director delivers written notice of the director’s dissent or abstention to the presiding officer of the meeting before its adjournment or to the corporation immediately after adjournment of the meeting, but the right of dissent or abstention is not available to a director who votes in favor of the action taken.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-306.25">29-306.25</cite> and § <cite path="§29-306.53">29-306.53</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
