<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-307.02</num>
  <heading>Action on a plan of domestication.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In the case of a domestication of a domestic business corporation in a foreign jurisdiction, the following rules apply:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The plan of domestication shall be adopted by the board of directors.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>After adopting the plan of domestication, the board of directors shall submit the plan to the shareholders for their approval. The board of directors shall also transmit to the shareholders a recommendation that the shareholders approve the plan, unless the board of directors makes a determination that because of conflicts of interest or other special circumstances, it should not make such a recommendation, in which case the board of directors shall transmit to the shareholders the basis for that determination.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The board of directors may condition its submission of the plan of domestication to the shareholders on any basis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the approval of the shareholders is to be given at a meeting, the corporation shall notify each shareholder, whether or not entitled to vote, of the meeting of shareholders at which the plan of domestication is to be submitted for approval. The notice shall state that the purpose, or one of the purposes, of the meeting is to consider the plan and shall contain or be accompanied by a copy or summary of the plan. The notice shall include or be accompanied by a copy of the articles of incorporation as they will be in effect immediately after the domestication.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Unless the articles of incorporation, or the board of directors acting pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection, requires a greater vote or a greater number of votes to be present, approval of the plan of domestication requires the approval of the shareholders at a meeting at which a quorum consisting of at least a majority of the votes entitled to be cast on the plan exists, and, if any class or series of shares is entitled to vote as a separate group on the plan, the approval of each such separate voting group at a meeting at which a quorum of the voting group consisting of at least a majority of the votes entitled to be cast on the domestication by that voting group exists.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Separate voting by voting groups shall be required by each class or series of shares that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Are to be reclassified under the plan of domestication into other securities, obligations, rights to acquire shares or other securities, cash, other property, or any combination of the foregoing;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Would be entitled to vote as a separate group on a provision of the plan that, if contained in a proposed amendment to articles of incorporation, would require action by separate voting groups under ยง <cite path="ยง29-308.04">29-308.04</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Is entitled under the articles of incorporation to vote as a voting group to approve an amendment of the articles.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>If any provision of the articles of incorporation, bylaws, or an agreement to which any of the directors or shareholders are parties, adopted, or entered into before the effective date of this chapter, applies to a merger of the corporation and that document does not refer to a domestication of the corporation, the provision shall apply to a domestication of the corporation until such time as the provision is amended subsequent to that date.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
