<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-308.05</num>
  <heading>Amendment by board of directors.</heading>
  <text>Unless the articles of incorporation provide otherwise, a corporation’s board of directors may adopt amendments to the corporation’s articles of incorporation without shareholder approval:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>To extend the duration of the corporation if it was incorporated at a time when limited duration was required by law;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>To delete the names and addresses of the initial directors;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>To change the information required by § <cite path="§29-104.04">29-104.04</cite></text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>If the corporation has only one class of shares outstanding:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>To change each issued and unissued authorized share of the class into a greater number of whole shares of that class; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>To increase the number of authorized shares of the class to the extent necessary to permit the issuance of shares as a share dividend;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>To change the corporate name by substituting the word “corporation”, “incorporated”, “company”, “limited”, or the abbreviation “corp.”, “inc.”, “co.”, or “ltd.”, for a similar word or abbreviation in the name, or by adding, deleting, or changing a geographical attribution for the name;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>To reflect a reduction in authorized shares, as a result of the operation of § <cite path="§29-304.41">29-304.41</cite>(b), when the corporation has acquired its own shares and the articles of incorporation prohibit the reissue of the acquired shares;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>To delete a class of shares from the articles of incorporation, as a result of the operation of § <cite path="§29-304.41">29-304.41</cite>(b), if there are no remaining shares of the class because the corporation has acquired all shares of the class and the articles of incorporation prohibit the reissue of the acquired shares; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>To make any change expressly permitted by § <cite path="§29-304.02">29-304.02</cite>(a) or (b) to be made without shareholder approval.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-307.01">29-307.01</cite>, § <cite path="§29-308.03">29-308.03</cite>, § <cite path="§29-309.02">29-309.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-309.04">29-309.04</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
