<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-302.02</num>
  <heading>Articles of incorporation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The articles of incorporation shall set forth:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A corporate name for the corporation that satisfies §§ <cite path="§29-103.01">29-103.01</cite> and <cite path="§29-103.02">29-103.02</cite>(a);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of shares the corporation is authorized to issue;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The information required by § <cite path="§29-104.04">29-104.04</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The name and address of each incorporator.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The articles of incorporation may set forth:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The names and addresses of the individuals who are to serve as the initial directors;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provisions not inconsistent with law regarding:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The purpose or purposes for which the corporation is organized;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Managing the business and regulating the affairs of the corporation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Defining, limiting, and regulating the powers of the corporation, its board of directors, and shareholders;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A par value for authorized shares or classes of shares;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The imposition of personal liability on shareholders for the debts of the corporation to a specified extent and upon specified conditions;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any provision that under this chapter is required or permitted to be set forth in the bylaws;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A provision eliminating or limiting the liability of a director to the corporation or its shareholders for money damages for any action taken, or any failure to take any action, as a director, except liability for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The amount of a financial benefit received by a director to which the director is not entitled;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An intentional infliction of harm on the corporation or the shareholders;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A violation of § <cite path="§29-306.32">29-306.32</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An intentional violation of criminal law; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A provision permitting or making obligatory indemnification of a director for liability, as defined in § <cite path="§29-306.50">29-306.50</cite>, to any person for any action taken, or any failure to take any action, as a director, except liability for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Receipt of a financial benefit to which the director is not entitled;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An intentional infliction of harm on the corporation or its shareholders;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A violation of § <cite path="§29-306.32">29-306.32</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An intentional violation of criminal law.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The articles of incorporation need not set forth any of the corporate powers enumerated in this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Provisions of the articles of incorporation may be made dependent upon facts objectively ascertainable outside the articles of incorporation in accordance with § <cite path="§29-301.04">29-301.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-101.06">29-101.06</cite>, § <cite path="§29-306.31">29-306.31</cite>, § <cite path="§29-306.51">29-306.51</cite>, § <cite path="§29-306.53">29-306.53</cite>, § <cite path="§29-307.03">29-307.03</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-1303.02">29-1303.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
