<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-306.32</num>
  <heading>Directors’ liability for unlawful distributions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A director who votes for or assents to a distribution in excess of what may be authorized and made pursuant to § <cite path="§29-304.60">29-304.60</cite>(a) or § <cite path="§29-312.09">29-312.09</cite>(a) shall be personally liable to the corporation for the amount of the distribution that exceeds what could have been distributed without violating § <cite path="§29-304.60">29-304.60</cite>(a) or § <cite path="§29-312.09">29-312.09</cite>(a) if the party asserting liability establishes that when taking the action the director did not comply with § <cite path="§29-306.30">29-306.30</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A director held liable under subsection (a) of this section for an unlawful distribution shall be entitled to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Contribution from every other director who could be held liable under subsection (a) of this section for the unlawful distribution; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Recoupment from each shareholder of the pro-rata portion of the amount of the unlawful distribution the shareholder accepted, knowing the distribution was made in violation of § <cite path="§29-304.60">29-304.60</cite>(a) or § <cite path="§29-312.09">29-312.09</cite>(a).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A proceeding to enforce:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The liability of a director under subsection (a) of this section shall be barred unless it is commenced within 2 years after the date:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>On which the effect of the distribution was measured under § <cite path="§29-304.60">29-304.60</cite>(e) or (g);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>As of which the violation of § <cite path="§29-304.60">29-304.60</cite>(a) occurred as the consequence of disregard of a restriction in the articles of incorporation; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>On which the distribution of assets to shareholders under § <cite path="§29-312.09">29-312.09</cite>(a) was made; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Contribution or recoupment under subsection (b) of this section shall be barred unless it is commenced within one year after the liability of the claimant has been finally adjudicated under subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-302.02">29-302.02</cite>, § <cite path="§29-306.31">29-306.31</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-1303.02">29-1303.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
