<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-305.24</num>
  <heading>Corporation’s acceptance of votes.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the name signed on a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment corresponds to the name of a shareholder, the corporation, if acting in good faith, shall be entitled to accept the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment and give it effect as the act of the shareholder.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the name signed on a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment does not correspond to the name of its shareholder, the corporation if acting in good faith may nevertheless accept the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment and give it effect as the act of the shareholder if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The shareholder is an entity and the name signed purports to be that of an officer or agent of the entity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name signed purports to be that of an administrator, executor, guardian, or conservator representing the shareholder and, if the corporation requests, evidence of fiduciary status acceptable to the corporation has been presented with respect to the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The name signed purports to be that of a receiver or trustee in bankruptcy of the shareholder and, if the corporation requests, evidence of this status acceptable to the corporation has been presented with respect to the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The name signed purports to be that of a pledgee, beneficial owner, or attorney-in-fact of the shareholder and, if the corporation requests, evidence acceptable to the corporation of the signatory’s authority to sign for the shareholder has been presented with respect to the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Two or more persons are the shareholder as co-tenants or fiduciaries and the name signed purports to be the name of at least one of the co-owners and the person signing appears to be acting on behalf of all the co-owners.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The corporation may reject a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment if the secretary or other officer or agent authorized to tabulate votes, acting in good faith, has reasonable basis for doubt about the validity of the signature on it or about the signatory’s authority to sign for the shareholder.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The corporation and its officer or agent who accepts or rejects a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment in good faith and in accordance with the standards of this section or § <cite path="§29-301.03">29-301.03</cite>(d) shall not be liable in damages to the shareholder for the consequences of the acceptance or rejection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Corporate action based on the acceptance or rejection of a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment under this section shall be valid unless the Superior Court determines otherwise.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(c)(13), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-305.22">29-305.22</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “§ <cite path="§29-301.03">29-301.03</cite>(d)” for “§ <cite path="§29-305.22">29-305.22</cite>(b)” in (d).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
