<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-406.43</num>
  <heading>Resignation and removal of officers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An officer may resign at any time by delivering notice to the nonprofit corporation. A resignation shall be effective when the notice is delivered unless the notice specifies a later effective time. If a resignation is made effective at a later time and the board of directors or the appointing officer accepts the future effective time, the board or the appointing officer may designate a successor before the effective time if the board or the appointing officer provides that the successor does not take office until the effective time.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation or bylaws, an officer may be removed at any time with or without cause by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The board of directors;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The officer who appointed the officer being removed, unless the board provides otherwise; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any other officer authorized by the articles, the bylaws, or the board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “appointing officer” means the officer, including any successor to that officer, who appointed the officer resigning or being removed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-401.50">29-401.50</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
