<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-401.05</num>
  <heading>Restrictions and required approvals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a domestic or foreign nonprofit corporation or eligible entity may not be a party to a merger or sale of its assets without the approval of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, the Mayor (or as may be formerly referred to as the Commissioner of the District of Columbia), the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking or the Public Service Commission, the corporation or eligible entity shall not be a party to a transaction under Chapter 2 of this title without the prior approval of that officer or agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Property held in trust by an entity or otherwise dedicated to a charitable purpose shall not be diverted from its purpose by any transaction under Chapter 2 of this title unless the entity obtains an appropriate order of the Superior Court specifying the disposition of the property to the extent required by and pursuant to the law of the District on cy pres or otherwise dealing with the nondiversion of charitable assets.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless an entity that is a party to a transaction under Chapter 2 of this title obtains an appropriate order of Superior Court under the law of the District on cy pres or otherwise dealing with the nondiversion of charitable assets, the transaction shall not affect:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any restriction imposed upon the entity by its organic records that may not be amended by its board of directors, governors, members, or interest holders or by a designated body;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any restriction imposed upon property held by the entity by virtue of any trust under which it holds that property; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The existing rights of persons other than members, shareholders, or interest holders of the entity.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person that is a member, interest holder, or otherwise affiliated with a charitable corporation or an unincorporated entity with a charitable purpose shall not receive a direct or indirect financial benefit in connection with a transaction under Chapter 2 of this title to which the charitable corporation or unincorporated entity is a party unless the person is itself a charitable corporation or unincorporated entity with a charitable purpose. This subsection shall not apply to the receipt of reasonable compensation for services rendered.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A devise, bequest, gift, grant, or promise contained in a will or other instrument, in trust or otherwise, made before or after a transaction under Chapter 2 of this title to or for the entity that is the subject of the transaction, shall inure to the entity as it continues in existence after the transaction, subject to the express terms of the will or other instrument.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(d)(5), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “Chapter 2 of this title” for “this chapter” in (a) through (e).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
