<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-409.07</num>
  <heading>Effect of merger or membership exchange.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to § <cite path="§29-409.01">29-409.01</cite>(b), (c), and (d), when a merger becomes effective:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The domestic or foreign nonprofit corporation or eligible entity that is designated in the plan of merger as the survivor shall continue or come into existence, as the case may be;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The separate existence of every domestic or foreign nonprofit corporation or eligible entity that is merged into the survivor shall cease;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All property owned by, and every contract and other right possessed by, each domestic or foreign nonprofit corporation or eligible entity that merges into the survivor shall be vested in the survivor without reversion or impairment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>All liabilities of each domestic or foreign nonprofit corporation or eligible entity that is merged into the survivor shall be vested in the survivor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The name of the survivor may, but need not be, substituted in any pending proceeding for the name of any party to the merger whose separate existence ceased in the merger;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The articles of incorporation and bylaws or organic records of the survivor shall be amended to the extent provided in the plan of merger;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The articles of incorporation and bylaws or organic records of a survivor that is created by the merger shall become effective; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The memberships of each corporation that is a party to the merger, and the eligible interests in an eligible entity that is a party to a merger, that are to be converted under the plan of merger into memberships, eligible interests, securities, or obligations; rights to acquire memberships, eligible interests, securities, or obligations; cash; other property or other consideration; or any combination of the foregoing are converted.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to § <cite path="§29-409.01">29-409.01</cite>(b), (c), and (d), when a membership exchange becomes effective:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The memberships or eligible interests in the exchanging entity that are to be exchanged under the plan of membership exchange into memberships, eligible interests, securities, or obligations; rights to acquire memberships, eligible interests, securities, or obligations; cash; other property or other consideration; or any combination of the foregoing are exchanged; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The articles of incorporation and bylaws or organic records of the exchanging entity shall be amended to the extent provided in the plan of membership exchange.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person that becomes subject to owner liability for some or all of the debts, obligations, or liabilities of any entity as a result of a merger or membership exchange has owner liability only to the extent provided in the organic law of the entity and only for those debts, obligations, and liabilities that arise after the effective time of the articles of merger or membership exchange.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The effect of a merger or membership exchange on the owner liability of a person that had owner liability for some or all of the debts, obligations, or liabilities of a party to the merger or membership exchange shall be as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The merger or membership exchange shall not discharge any owner liability under the organic law of the entity in which the person was a member, shareholder, or interest holder to the extent any such owner liability arose before the effective time of the articles of merger or membership exchange.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person shall not have owner liability under the organic law of the entity in which the person was a member, shareholder, or interest holder prior to the merger or membership exchange for any debt, obligation, or liability that arises after the effective time of the articles of merger or membership exchange.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The organic law of any entity for which the person had owner liability before the merger or membership exchange shall continue to apply to the collection or discharge of any owner liability preserved by paragraph (1) of this subsection, as if the merger or membership exchange had not occurred.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The person has whatever rights of contribution from other persons are provided by the organic law of the entity for which the person had owner liability with respect to any owner liability preserved by paragraph (1) of this subsection, as if the merger or membership exchange had not occurred.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A devise, bequest, gift, grant, or promise contained in a will or other instrument, in trust or otherwise, made before or after a merger, to or for any of the parties to the merger, shall inure to the survivor, subject to the express terms of the will or other instrument.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-406.58">29-406.58</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
