<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-412.08</num>
  <heading>Court proceedings.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A dissolved nonprofit corporation that has published a notice under § <cite path="§29-412.07">29-412.07</cite> may file an application with the Superior Court for a determination of the amount and form of security to be provided for payment of claims that are contingent or have not been made known to the dissolved corporation or that are based on an event occurring after the effective date of dissolution but that, based on the facts known to the dissolved corporation, are reasonably estimated to arise after the effective date of dissolution. Provision need not be made for any claim that is or is reasonably anticipated to be barred under § <cite path="§29-412.07">29-412.07</cite>(c).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 10 days after the filing of the application, notice of the proceeding must be given by the dissolved nonprofit corporation to each claimant holding a contingent claim whose contingent claim is shown on the records of the dissolved corporation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court may appoint a guardian ad litem to represent all claimants whose identities are unknown in any proceeding brought under this section. The reasonable fees and expenses of the guardian, including all reasonable expert witness fees, shall be paid by the dissolved nonprofit corporation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Provision by the dissolved nonprofit corporation for security in the amount and the form ordered by the Superior Court under subsection (a) of this section shall satisfy the dissolved corporation’s obligations with respect to claims that are contingent, have not been made known to the dissolved corporation, or are based on an event occurring after the effective date of dissolution, and such claims shall not be enforced against a person that received assets in liquidation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(d)(19), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-412.07">29-412.07</cite> and § <cite path="§29-412.09">29-412.09</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “Court” for “Judicial” in the section heading.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
