<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-405.09</num>
  <heading>Action by ballot.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise restricted by the articles of incorporation or bylaws, any action that may be taken at any annual, regular, or special meeting of members may be taken without a meeting if the membership corporation delivers a ballot to every member entitled to vote on the matter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A ballot shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be in the form of a record;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Set forth each proposed action;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide an opportunity to vote for, or withhold a vote for, each candidate for election as a director; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide an opportunity to vote for or against each other proposed action.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Approval by ballot pursuant to this section of action other than election of directors shall be valid only when the number of votes cast by ballot equals or exceeds the quorum required to be present at a meeting authorizing the action, and the number of approvals equals or exceeds the number of votes that would be required to approve the matter at a meeting at which the total number of votes cast was the same as the number of votes cast by ballot.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All solicitations for votes by ballot shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Indicate the number of responses needed to meet the quorum requirements;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>State the percentage of approvals necessary to approve each matter other than election of directors; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Specify the time by which a ballot must be received by the membership corporation in order to be counted.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation or bylaws, a ballot shall not be revoked.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in ยง <cite path="ยง29-401.50">29-401.50</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
