<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-406.58</num>
  <heading>Variation of indemnification.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation may, by a provision in its articles of incorporation or bylaws or in a resolution adopted or a contract approved by its board of directors or members, obligate itself in advance of the act or omission giving rise to a proceeding to provide indemnification as permitted by § <cite path="§29-406.51">29-406.51</cite> or advance funds to pay for or reimburse expenses as permitted by § <cite path="§29-406.53">29-406.53</cite>. An obligatory provision satisfies the requirements for authorization referred to in §§ <cite path="§29-406.53">29-406.53</cite>(c) and <cite path="§29-406.55">29-406.55</cite>(c). Any such provision that obligates the corporation to provide indemnification to the fullest extent permitted by law shall obligate the corporation to advance funds to pay for or reimburse expenses in accordance with § <cite path="§29-406.53">29-406.53</cite> to the fullest extent permitted by law, unless the provision specifically provides otherwise.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any provision pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall not obligate the nonprofit corporation to indemnify or advance expenses to a director of a predecessor of the corporation, pertaining to conduct with respect to the predecessor, unless otherwise specifically provided. Any provision for indemnification or advance for expenses in the organic records, articles of incorporation, bylaws, or a resolution of the governors, board of directors, members or interest holders of a predecessor of the corporation in a fundamental transaction, or in a contract to which the predecessor is a party, existing at the time the fundamental transaction takes effect, shall be governed by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Section 29-407.05(a)(2) in the case of a domestication;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Section 29-204.06(a)(3) in the case of a for-profit conversion;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Section 29-204.06(a)(3) in the case of a foreign for-profit domestication and conversion;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Section 29-204.06(a)(3) in the case of an entity conversion; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Section 29-409.07(a)(4) in the case of a merger involving only nonprofit corporations, or § <cite path="§29-202.06">29-202.06</cite>(a)(4) in the case of a merger involving another type of entity.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation may, by a provision in its articles of incorporation or bylaws, limit any of the rights to indemnification or advance for expenses created by or pursuant to this part.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This part shall not limit a nonprofit corporation’s power to pay or reimburse expenses incurred by a director or an officer in connection with appearance as a witness in a proceeding at a time when the director or officer is not a party.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation may indemnify, advance expenses to, or provide or maintain insurance on behalf of an employee, agent, or volunteer.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-406.54">29-406.54</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
