<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-408.04</num>
  <heading>Voting on amendments by voting groups.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation or bylaws, if a nonprofit corporation has more than one class of members, the members of each class shall be entitled to vote as a separate voting group, if member voting is otherwise required by this chapter, on a proposed amendment to the articles of incorporation if the amendment would:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Effect an exchange or reclassification of all or part of the memberships of the class into memberships of another class;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Effect an exchange or reclassification, or create the right of exchange, of all or part of the memberships of another class into memberships of the class;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Change the rights, preferences, or limitations of all or part of the memberships of the class in a manner different than the amendment would affect another class;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Change the rights, preferences, or limitations of all or part of the memberships of the class by changing the rights, preferences, or limitations of another class;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Increase or decrease the number of memberships authorized for that class;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Increase the number of memberships authorized for another class; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Authorize a new class of memberships.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a class of members will be divided into 2 or more classes by an amendment to the articles of incorporation, the amendment shall be approved by a majority of the members of each class that will be created.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-407.03">§ 29-407.03</cite>, <cite path="§29-408.07">§ 29-408.07</cite>, <cite path="§29-408.22">§ 29-408.22</cite>, and <cite path="§29-409.04">§ 29-409.04</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
