<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-405.03</num>
  <heading>Court-ordered meeting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court may summarily order a meeting to be held on application of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any member entitled to participate in an annual or regular meeting if an annual meeting was not held within the earlier of 6 months after the end of the corporation’s fiscal year or 15 months after its last annual meeting; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A member who signed a demand for a special meeting under § <cite path="§29-405.02">29-405.02</cite>, if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Notice of the special meeting was not given within 30 days after the date the demand was delivered to the corporation’s secretary; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The special meeting was not held in accordance with the notice.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court may fix the time and place of the meeting, determine the members entitled to participate in the meeting, specify a record date for determining members entitled to notice of and to vote at the meeting, prescribe the form and content of the meeting notice, fix the quorum required for specific matters to be considered at the meeting, or direct that the votes represented at the meeting constitute a quorum for action on those matters, and enter other orders necessary to accomplish the purpose of the meeting.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-405.02">29-405.02</cite>, § <cite path="§29-405.04">29-405.04</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-405.05">29-405.05</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
