<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-405.20</num>
  <heading>Members list for meeting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After fixing a record date for a meeting, a membership corporation shall prepare an alphabetical list of the names of all its members that are entitled to notice of that meeting of the members. The list shall show the address of and number of votes each member is entitled to cast at the meeting.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The list of members shall be available for inspection by any member, beginning 2 business days after notice of the meeting is given for which the list was prepared and continuing through the meeting, at the membership corporation’s principal office or at a place identified in the meeting notice in the city where the meeting will be held. A member or the member’s agent shall be entitled on demand in the form of a record to inspect and, subject to the requirements of § <cite path="§29-413.02">29-413.02</cite>(c), to copy the list, during regular business hours and at the member’s expense, during the period it is available for inspection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The membership corporation shall make the list of members available at the meeting, and a member or the member’s agent is entitled to inspect the list at any time during the meeting or any adjournment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a membership corporation refuses to allow a member or the member’s agent to inspect the list of members before or at the meeting, or copy the list as permitted by subsection (b) of this section, the Superior Court on application of the member, may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Summarily order the inspection or copying at the corporation’s expense;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Postpone the meeting for which the list was prepared until the inspection or copying is complete;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Order the corporation to pay the member’s costs, including reasonable attorney’s fees, incurred to obtain the order; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Order other appropriate relief.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Refusal or failure to prepare or make available the list of members shall not affect the validity of action taken at the meeting.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Instead of making the list of members available as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a membership corporation may state in a notice of meeting that the corporation has elected to proceed under this subsection. A member of a corporation that has elected to proceed under this subsection shall state in the member’s demand for inspection a proper purpose for which inspection is demanded. Within 10 business days after receiving a demand under this subsection, the corporation shall deliver to the member making the demand an offer of a reasonable alternative method of achieving the purpose identified in the demand without providing access to or a copy of the list of members. An alternative method that reasonably and in a timely manner accomplishes the proper purpose set forth in the demand relieves the corporation from making the list of members available under subsection (b) of this section, unless within a reasonable time after acceptance of the offer the corporation fails to do the things it offered to do. Any rejection of the corporation’s offer shall be in the form of a record and shall indicate the reasons the alternative proposed by the corporation does not meet the proper purpose of the demand.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-413.02">29-413.02</cite> and § <cite path="§29-413.07">29-413.07</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
