<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-406.70</num>
  <heading>Conflicting interest transactions; voidability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A contract or transaction between a nonprofit corporation and one or more of its members, directors, members of a designated body, or officers or between a nonprofit corporation and any other entity in which one or more of its directors, members of a designated body, or officers are directors or officers, hold a similar position, or have a financial interest, shall not be void or voidable solely for that reason, or solely because the member, director, member of a designated body, or officer is present at or participates in the meeting of the board of directors that authorizes the contract or transaction, or solely because his or their votes are counted for that purpose, if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The material facts as to the relationship or interest and as to the contract or transaction are disclosed or are known to the board of directors and the board in good faith authorizes the contract or transaction by the affirmative votes of a majority of the disinterested directors even though the disinterested directors are less than a quorum;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The material facts as to the relationship or interest of the member, director, or officer and as to the contract or transaction are disclosed or are known to the members entitled to vote thereon, if any, and the contract or transaction is specifically approved in good faith by vote of those members; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The contract or transaction is fair as to the corporation as of the time it is authorized, approved, or ratified by the board of directors or the members.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Common or interested directors may be counted in determining the presence of a quorum at a meeting of the board that authorizes a contract or transaction specified in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall be applicable except as otherwise restricted in the articles of incorporation or bylaws.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-404.40">29-404.40</cite>, § <cite path="§29-406.31">29-406.31</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-406.80">29-406.80</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
