<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-602.04</num>
  <heading>When property is partnership property.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Property shall be partnership property if acquired in the name of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The partnership; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One or more partners with an indication in the instrument transferring title to the property of the person’s capacity as a partner or of the existence of a partnership but without an indication of the name of the partnership.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Property shall be acquired in the name of the partnership by a transfer to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The partnership in its name; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One or more partners in their capacity as partners in the partnership, if the name of the partnership is indicated in the instrument transferring title to the property.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Property shall be presumed to be partnership property if purchased with partnership assets, even if not acquired in the name of the partnership or of one or more partners with an indication in the instrument transferring title to the property of the person’s capacity as a partner or of the existence of a partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Property acquired in the name of one or more of the partners, without an indication in the instrument transferring title to the property of the person’s capacity as a partner or of the existence of a partnership and without use of partnership assets, shall be presumed to be separate property, even if used for partnership purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§33-102.04">33-102.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 41-152.4.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 204 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
