<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-608.07</num>
  <heading>Settlement of accounts and contributions among partners.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In winding up a partnership’s activities and affairs, the assets of the partnership, including the contributions of the partners required by this section, shall be applied to discharge its obligations to creditors, including, to the extent permitted by law, partners who are creditors. Any surplus shall be applied to pay in cash the net amount distributable to partners in accordance with their right to distributions under subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each partner shall be entitled to a settlement of all partnership accounts upon winding up the partnership activities and affairs. In settling accounts among the partners, profits and losses that result from the liquidation of the partnership assets shall be credited and charged to the partners’ accounts. The partnership shall make a distribution to a partner in an amount equal to any excess of the credits over the charges in the partner’s account. A partner shall contribute to the partnership an amount equal to any excess of the charges over the credits in the partner’s account but excluding from the calculation charges attributable to an obligation for which the partner is not personally liable under § <cite path="§29-603.06">29-603.06</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a partner fails to contribute the full amount required under subsection (b) of this section, all of the other partners shall contribute, in the proportions in which those partners share partnership losses, the additional amount necessary to satisfy the partnership obligations for which they are personally liable under § <cite path="§29-603.06">29-603.06</cite>. A partner or partner’s legal representative may recover from the other partners any contributions the partner makes to the extent the amount contributed exceeds that partner’s share of the partnership obligations for which the partner is personally liable under § <cite path="§29-603.06">29-603.06</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>After the settlement of accounts, each partner shall contribute, in the proportion in which the partner shares partnership losses, the amount necessary to satisfy partnership obligations that were not known at the time of the settlement and for which the partner is personally liable under § <cite path="§29-603.06">29-603.06</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The estate of a deceased partner shall be liable for the partner’s obligation to contribute to the partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An assignee for the benefit of creditors of a partnership or a partner, or a person appointed by a court to represent creditors of a partnership or a partner, may enforce a partner’s obligation to contribute to the partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(f)(8)(H), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-607.01">29-607.01</cite>, § <cite path="§29-608.03">29-608.03</cite>, § <cite path="§29-609.03">29-609.03</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-610.02">29-610.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 41-158.7.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§33-108.07">33-108.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “activities and affairs” for “business” in (a) and (b).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 807 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
