<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-608.01</num>
  <heading>Events causing dissolution and winding up of partnership business.</heading>
  <text>A partnership is dissolved, and its activities and affairs shall be wound up, only upon the occurrence of any of the following events:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>In a partnership at will, the partnership’s having notice from a partner, other than a partner that is dissociated under § <cite path="§29-606.01">29-606.01</cite>(2) through (10), of that partner’s express will to withdraw as a partner, or on a later date specified by the partner;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>In a partnership for a definite term or particular undertaking:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Within 90 days after a partner’s dissociation by death or otherwise under § <cite path="§29-606.01">29-606.01</cite>(6) through (10) or wrongful dissociation under § <cite path="§29-606.02">29-606.02</cite>(b), the express will of at least half of the remaining partners to wind up the partnership’s activities and affairs, for which purpose a partner’s rightful dissociation pursuant to § <cite path="§29-606.02">29-606.02</cite>(b)(2)(A) constitutes the expression of that partner’s will to wind up the partnership’s activities and affairs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The express will of all of the partners to wind up the partnership’s activities and affairs; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The expiration of the term or the completion of the undertaking;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>An event agreed to in the partnership agreement resulting in the winding up of the partnership activities and affairs;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>An event that makes it unlawful for all or substantially all of the business of the partnership to be continued, but a cure of illegality within 90 days after notice to the partnership of the event shall be effective retroactively to the date of the event for purposes of this section;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>On application by a partner, a judicial determination that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The economic purpose of the partnership is likely to be unreasonably frustrated;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Another partner has engaged in conduct relating to the partnership activities and affairs which makes it not reasonably practicable to carry on the activities and affairs in partnership with that partner; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>It is not otherwise reasonably practicable to carry on the partnership activities and affairs in conformity with the partnership agreement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>On application by a transferee of a partner’s transferable interest, a judicial determination that it is equitable to wind up the partnership activities and affairs:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>After the expiration of the term or completion of the undertaking, if the partnership was for a definite term or particular undertaking at the time of the transfer or entry of the charging order that gave rise to the transfer; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>At any time, if the partnership was a partnership at will at the time of the transfer or entry of the charging order that gave rise to the transfer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The passage of 90 consecutive days during which the partnership does not have at least 2 partners.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(f)(8)(B), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-601.04">29-601.04</cite>, § <cite path="§29-604.08">29-604.08</cite>, § <cite path="§29-605.03">29-605.03</cite>, § <cite path="§29-607.01">29-607.01</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-608.12">29-608.12</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 41-158.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§33-108.01">33-108.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “activities and affairs” or variants thereof for “business”; made related stylistic changes; and added (7).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 801 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2(f)(8)(A) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “Dissolution and Winding Up” for “Winding up Partnership Business” in the subchapter heading.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
