<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-603.02</num>
  <heading>Transfer of partnership property.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Partnership property may be transferred as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Subject to the effect of a statement of partnership authority under <cite path="§29-603.03">§ 29-603.03</cite>, partnership property held in the name of the partnership may be transferred by an instrument of transfer executed by a partner in the partnership name.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Partnership property held in the name of one or more partners with an indication in the instrument transferring the property to them in their capacity as partners or of the existence of a partnership, but without an indication of the name of the partnership, may be transferred by an instrument of transfer executed by the persons in whose name the property is held.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Partnership property held in the name of one or more persons other than the partnership, without an indication in the instrument transferring the property to them in their capacity as partners or of the existence of a partnership, may be transferred by an instrument of transfer executed by the persons in whose name the property is held.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A partnership may recover partnership property from a transferee only if it proves that execution of the instrument of initial transfer did not bind the partnership under <cite path="§29-603.01">§ 29-603.01</cite> and:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As to a subsequent transferee who gave value for property transferred under subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section, proves that the subsequent transferee knew or had received a notification that the person that executed the instrument of initial transfer lacked authority to bind the partnership; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>As to a transferee who gave value for property transferred under subsection (a)(3) of this section, proves that the transferee knew or had received a notification that the property was partnership property and that the person that executed the instrument of initial transfer lacked authority to bind the partnership.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A partnership shall not recover partnership property from a subsequent transferee if the partnership would not have been entitled to recover the property, under subsection (b) of this section, from any earlier transferee of the property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a person holds all of the partners’ interests in the partnership, all of the partnership property shall vest in that person. The person may execute a document in the name of the partnership to evidence vesting of the property in that person and may file or record the document.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 302 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 41-153.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § 33-103.02.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-609.04">§ 29-609.04</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
