<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-610.01</num>
  <heading>Statement of qualification.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A partnership may become a limited liability partnership pursuant to this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The terms and conditions on which a partnership becomes a limited liability partnership shall be approved by the vote necessary to amend the partnership agreement except, in the case of a partnership agreement that expressly considers obligations to contribute, the vote necessary to amend those provisions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>After the approval required by subsection (b) of this section, a partnership may become a limited liability partnership by delivering to the Mayor for filing a statement of qualification. The statement shall contain:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the partnership, which shall satisfy the requirements of §§ <cite path="§29-103.01">29-103.01</cite> and <cite path="§29-103.02">29-103.02</cite>(e);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The street address of the partnership’s principal office and, if different, the street address of an office in District, if any;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the partnership does not have an office in District, the information required by § <cite path="§29-104.04">29-104.04</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A statement that the partnership elects to be a limited liability partnership; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A deferred effective date, if any.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The agent of a limited liability partnership for service of process shall be an individual who is a resident of the District or other person authorized to do business in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The status of a partnership as a limited liability partnership shall be effective on the later of the filing of the statement or a date specified in the statement. The status shall remain effective, regardless of changes in the partnership, until it is canceled pursuant to § <cite path="§29-601.05">29-601.05</cite>(d) or revoked pursuant to § <cite path="§29-106.01">29-106.01</cite>(3).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The status of a partnership as a limited liability partnership and the liability of its partners shall not be affected by errors or later changes in the information required to be contained in the statement of qualification under subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The filing of a statement of qualification establishes that a partnership has satisfied all conditions precedent to the qualification of the partnership as a limited liability partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>An amendment or cancellation of a statement of qualification shall be effective when it is filed or on a deferred effective date specified in the amendment or cancellation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-601.02">29-601.02</cite>, § <cite path="§29-601.11">29-601.11</cite>, § <cite path="§29-602.01">29-602.01</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-603.06">29-603.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 41-160.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§33-110.01">33-110.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1001 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
