<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-602.02</num>
  <heading>Formation of partnership.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) of this section, the association of 2 or more persons to carry on as co-owners of a business for profit shall form a partnership, whether or not the persons intend to form a partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An association formed under a statute other than this chapter, a predecessor statute, or a comparable statute of another jurisdiction shall not be a partnership under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In determining whether a partnership is formed, the following rules shall apply:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Joint tenancy, tenancy in common, tenancy by the entireties, joint property, common property, or part ownership shall not by itself establish a partnership, even if the co-owners share profits made by the use of the property.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The sharing of gross returns shall not by itself establish a partnership, even if the persons sharing them have a joint or common right or interest in property from which the returns are derived.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A person that receives a share of the profits of a business shall be presumed to be a partner in the business, unless the profits were received in payment:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Of a debt by installments or otherwise;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For services as an independent contractor or of wages or other compensation to an employee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Of rent;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Of an annuity or other retirement or health benefit to a beneficiary, representative, or designee of a deceased or retired partner;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Of interest or other charge on a loan, even if the amount of payment varies with the profits of the business, including a direct or indirect present or future ownership of the collateral, or rights to income, proceeds, or increase in value derived from the collateral; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>For the sale of the goodwill of a business or other property by installments or otherwise.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="29-101.02">29-101.02</cite>, § <cite root="29-601.02">29-601.02</cite>, § <cite root="29-604.02">29-604.02</cite>, and § <cite root="47-2855.01">47-2855.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>2001 Ed., § <cite root="33-102.02">33-102.02</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 41-152.2.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 202 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
