<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-608.02</num>
  <heading>Partnership continues after dissolution.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, a partnership shall continue after dissolution only for the purpose of winding up its activities and affairs. The partnership shall be terminated when the winding up of its activities and affairs is completed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>At any time after the dissolution of a partnership and before the winding up of its activities and affairs is completed, all of the partners, including any dissociating partner other than a wrongfully dissociating partner, may waive the right to have the partnership’s activities and affairs wound up and the partnership terminated. In that event:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The partnership shall resume carrying on its activities and affairs as if dissolution had never occurred, and any liability incurred by the partnership or a partner after the dissolution and before the waiver shall be determined as if dissolution had never occurred; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The rights of a third party accruing under § <cite path="§29-608.04">29-608.04</cite>(1) or arising out of conduct in reliance on the dissolution before the third party knew or received a notification of the waiver shall not be adversely affected.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(f)(8)(C), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-601.03">29-601.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 41-158.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§33-108.02">33-108.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</law-cite> substituted “activities and affairs” for “business” throughout (a) and (b).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 802 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
