<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-710.06</num>
  <heading>Restrictions on approval of mergers and on relinquishing limited liability limited partnership status.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a partner of a constituent limited partnership will have personal liability with respect to any organization as a result of a merger, approval and amendment of a plan of merger shall be ineffective without the consent of that partner, unless:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The limited partnership’s partnership agreement provides for the approval of the merger with the consent of less than all the partners; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The partner has consented to the provision of the partnership agreement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An amendment to a certificate of limited partnership which deletes a statement that the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership shall be ineffective without the consent of each general partner unless:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The limited partnership’s partnership agreement provides for the amendment with the consent of less than all the general partners; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each general partner that does not consent to the amendment has consented to the provision of the partnership agreement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A partner shall not give the consent required by subsection (a) or (b) of this section merely by consenting to a provision of the partnership agreement which permits the partnership agreement to be amended with the consent of fewer than all the partners.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-701.07">29-701.07</cite>, § <cite path="§29-704.06">29-704.06</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-710.03">29-710.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1110 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
