<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-709.01</num>
  <heading>Direct action by partner.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, a partner may maintain a direct action in the Superior Court against the limited partnership or another partner for legal or equitable relief, with or without an accounting as to the partnership’s activities and affairs, to enforce the rights and otherwise protect the interests of the partner, including rights and interests under the partnership agreement or this chapter or arising independently of the partnership relationship.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A partner commencing a direct action under this section shall be required to plead and prove an actual or threatened injury that is not solely the result of an injury suffered or threatened to be suffered by the limited partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The accrual of, and any time limitation on, a right of action for a remedy under this section shall be governed by other law. A right to an accounting upon a dissolution and winding up shall not revive a claim barred by law.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(g)(10)(A), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-706.04">29-706.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “activities and affairs” for “activities” in (a).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1001 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
