<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-706.01</num>
  <heading>Dissociation as limited partner.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person shall not have a right to dissociate as a limited partner before the completion of the winding up of the limited partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person shall be dissociated from a limited partnership as a limited partner upon the occurrence of any of the following events:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The limited partnership’s having notice of the person’s express will to withdraw as a limited partner or on a later date specified by the person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An event agreed to in the partnership agreement as causing the person’s dissociation as a limited partner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The person’s expulsion as a limited partner pursuant to the partnership agreement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The person’s expulsion as a limited partner by the unanimous consent of the other partners if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>It is unlawful to carry on the limited partnership’s activities with the person as a limited partner;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>There has been a transfer of all of the person’s transferable interest in the limited partnership, other than a transfer for security purposes, or a court order charging the person’s interest, which has not been foreclosed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The person is a corporation and, within 90 days after the limited partnership notifies the person that it will be expelled as a limited partner because it has filed a certificate of dissolution or the equivalent, its charter has been revoked, or its right to conduct business has been suspended by the jurisdiction of its incorporation, there is no revocation of the certificate of dissolution or no reinstatement of its charter or its right to conduct business; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The person is a limited liability company or partnership that has been dissolved and whose business is being wound up;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>On application by the limited partnership, the person’s expulsion as a limited partner by judicial order because:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The person engaged in wrongful conduct that adversely and materially affected the limited partnership’s activities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The person willfully or persistently committed a material breach of the partnership agreement or of the obligation of good faith and fair dealing under <cite path="§29-703.05|(b)">§ 29-703.05(b)</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The person engaged in conduct relating to the limited partnership’s activities which makes it not reasonably practicable to carry on the activities with the person as limited partner;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>In the case of a person who is an individual, the person’s death;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>In the case of a person that is a trust or is acting as a limited partner by virtue of being a trustee of a trust, distribution of the trust’s entire transferable interest in the limited partnership, but not merely by reason of the substitution of a successor trustee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>In the case of a person that is an estate or is acting as a limited partner by virtue of being a personal representative of an estate, distribution of the estate’s entire transferable interest in the limited partnership, but not merely by reason of the substitution of a successor personal representative;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Termination of a limited partner that is not an individual, partnership, limited liability company, corporation, trust, or estate;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The limited partnership’s participation in a merger under <cite path="29|7|X">subchapter X of this chapter</cite>, if the limited partnership is;</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Not the surviving entity; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The surviving entity but, as a result of the merger, the person ceases to be a limited partner;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>The limited partnership’s participation in a transaction under <cite path="29|2">Chapter 2 of this title</cite> if the limited partnership shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Not survive the transaction; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Survive the transaction, but as a result of the transaction, the person ceases to be a limited partner.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(g)(7)(A), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 601 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “completion of the winding up” for “termination” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-711.01">§ 29-711.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
