<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-704.08</num>
  <heading>General standards of general partner’s conduct.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The only fiduciary duties that a general partner shall have to the limited partnership and the other partners are the duties of loyalty and care under subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A general partner’s duty of loyalty to the limited partnership and the other partners shall be limited to the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To account to the limited partnership and hold as trustee for it any property, profit, or benefit derived by the general partner in the conduct and winding up of the limited partnership’s activities or derived from a use by the general partner of limited partnership property, including the appropriation of a limited partnership opportunity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To refrain from dealing with the limited partnership in the conduct or winding up of the limited partnership’s activities as or on behalf of a party having an interest adverse to the limited partnership; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To refrain from competing with the limited partnership in the conduct or winding up of the limited partnership’s activities.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A general partner’s duty of care to the limited partnership and the other partners in the conduct and winding up of the limited partnership’s activities shall be limited to refraining from engaging in grossly negligent or reckless conduct, intentional misconduct, or a knowing violation of law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A general partner shall discharge the duties to the partnership and the other partners under this chapter or under the partnership agreement and exercise any rights consistently with the obligation of good faith and fair dealing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A general partner shall not violate a duty or obligation under this chapter or under the partnership agreement merely because the general partner’s conduct furthers the general partner’s own interest.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>All the partners of a limited partnership may authorize or ratify, after full disclosure of all material facts, a specific act or transaction by a general partner that otherwise would violate the duty of loyalty.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>It is a defense to a claim under subsection (b)(2) of this section and any comparable claim in equity or at common law that the transaction was fair to the limited partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>If, as permitted by subsection (f) of this section or the partnership agreement, a general partner enters into a transaction with the limited partnership which otherwise would be prohibited by subsection (b)(2) of this section, the general partner’s rights and obligations arising from the transaction are the same as those of a person that is not a general partner.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(g)(4)(F), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-701.07">29-701.07</cite>, § <cite path="§29-704.09">29-704.09</cite>, § <cite path="§29-705.09">29-705.09</cite>, § <cite path="§29-706.03">29-706.03</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-706.05">29-706.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> added (f), (g), and (h).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 408 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
