<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-702.04</num>
  <heading>Signing of records.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each record delivered to the Mayor for filing pursuant to this chapter shall be signed in the following manner:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An initial certificate of limited partnership shall be signed by all general partners listed in the certificate.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An amendment adding or deleting a statement that the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership shall be signed by all general partners listed in the certificate.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An amendment designating as general partner a person admitted under § <cite path="§29-708.01">29-708.01</cite>(3)(B) following the dissociation of a limited partnership’s last general partner shall be signed by that person.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An amendment required by § <cite path="§29-708.03">29-708.03</cite>(c) following the appointment of a person to wind up the dissolved limited partnership’s activities or affairs shall be signed by that person.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Any other amendment shall be signed by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>At least one general partner listed in the certificate;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Each other person designated in the amendment as a new general partner; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Each person that the amendment indicates has dissociated as a general partner, unless:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The person is deceased or a guardian or general conservator has been appointed for the person and the amendment so states; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The person has previously delivered to the Mayor for filing a statement of dissociation.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A restated certificate of limited partnership shall be signed by at least one general partner listed in the certificate, and, to the extent the restated certificate effects a change under any other paragraph of this subsection, the certificate shall be signed in a manner that satisfies that paragraph.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A statement of termination shall be signed by all general partners listed in the certificate or, if the certificate of a dissolved limited partnership lists no general partners, by the person appointed pursuant to § <cite path="§29-708.03">29-708.03</cite>(c) or (d) to wind up the dissolved limited partnership’s activities or affairs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Articles of merger shall be signed as provided in § <cite path="§29-710.04">29-710.04</cite>(a).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Any other record delivered on behalf of a limited partnership to the Mayor for filing shall be signed by at least one general partner listed in the certificate.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>A statement by a person pursuant to § <cite path="§29-706.05">29-706.05</cite>(a)(4) stating that the person has dissociated as a general partner shall be signed by that person.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>A statement of withdrawal by a person pursuant to § <cite path="§29-703.06">29-703.06</cite> shall be signed by that person.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>A record delivered on behalf of a foreign limited partnership to the Mayor for filing shall be signed by at least one general partner of the foreign limited partnership.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Any other record delivered on behalf of any person to the Mayor for filing shall be signed by that person.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any person may sign by an attorney in fact any record to be filed pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each record delivered to the Mayor for filing pursuant to Chapter 2 of this title shall be signed by each general partner listed in the certificate of limited partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(g)(3)(C), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-701.07">29-701.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “activities or affairs” for “activities” in (a)(4) and (a)(7).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 204 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
