<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-711.01</num>
  <heading>Application to existing relationships.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before one year after the applicability date of this chapter, this chapter shall govern only:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A limited partnership formed on or after the applicability date of this chapter; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, a limited partnership formed before the applicability date of this chapter which elects, in the manner provided in its partnership agreement or by law for amending the partnership agreement, to be subject to this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c) of this section, on and after one year after applicability date of this chapter, this chapter shall govern all limited partnerships.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>With respect to a limited partnership formed before the applicability date of this chapter, the following rules apply except as the partners otherwise elect in the manner provided in the partnership agreement or by law for amending the partnership agreement:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Section 29-701.04(c) shall not apply and the limited partnership has whatever duration it had under the law applicable immediately before the applicability date of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The limited partnership shall not be required to amend its certificate of limited partnership to comply with § <cite path="§29-702.01">29-702.01</cite>(a)(4).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sections 29-706.01 and 29-706.02 shall not apply and a limited partner has the same right and power to dissociate from the limited partnership, with the same consequences, as existed immediately before the applicability date of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Section 29-706.03(4) shall not apply.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Section 29-706.03(5) shall not apply and a court shall have the same power to expel a general partner as the court had immediately before the applicability date of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Section 29-708.01(3) shall not apply and the connection between a person’s dissociation as a general partner and the dissolution of the limited partnership shall be the same as existed immediately before the applicability date of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>With respect to a limited partnership that elects pursuant to subsection (a)(2) of this section to be subject to this chapter, after the election takes effect, the provisions of this chapter relating to the liability of the limited partnership’s general partners to third parties shall apply:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Before one year after the applicability date of this chapter, to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A third party that had not done business with the limited partnership in the year before the election took effect; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A third party that had done business with the limited partnership in the year before the election took effect only if the third party knows or has received a notification of the election; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On and after one year after applicability date of this chapter, to all third parties, but those provisions shall remain inapplicable to any obligation incurred while those provisions were inapplicable under paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-701.02">29-701.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
