<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-804.01</num>
  <heading>Becoming member.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a limited liability company is to have only one member upon formation, the person shall become a member as agreed by that person and the organizer of the company. That person and the organizer may be, but need not be, different persons. If different, the organizer shall act on behalf of the initial member.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a limited liability company is to have more than one member upon formation, those persons shall become members as agreed by the persons before the formation of the company. The organizer [sic] act on behalf of the persons in forming the company and may be, but need not be, one of the persons.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>After formation of a limited liability company, a person becomes a member:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As provided in the operating agreement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>As the result of a transaction effective under subchapter IX of this chapter or Chapter 2 of this title;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>With the consent of all the members; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>As provided in § <cite path="§29-807.01">29-807.01</cite>(a)(3).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person may become a member without acquiring a transferable interest and without making or being obligated to make a contribution to the limited liability company.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(h)(5)(A), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-801.02">29-801.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> rewrote (c)(4).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 401 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
