<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-801.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Certificate of organization”, except when referring to a right of contribution, means the certificate required by § <cite path="§29-802.01">29-802.01</cite>. The term “certificate of organization” shall include the certificate as amended or restated.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Contribution” means any benefit provided by a person to a limited liability company:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>To become a member upon formation of the company and in accordance with an agreement between or among the persons that have agreed to become the initial members of the company;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>To become a member after formation of the company and in accordance with an agreement between the person and the company; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>In the person’s capacity as a member and in accordance with the operating agreement or an agreement between the member and the company.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Distribution” means a transfer of money or other property from a limited liability company to another person on account of a transferable interest or in the person’s capacity as a member.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The term includes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>A redemption or other purchase by a limited liability company of a transferable interest; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>A transfer to a member in return for the member’s relinquishment of any right to participate as a member in the management or conduct of the company’s activities and affairs or to have access to records or other information concerning the company’s activities and affairs.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The term does not include amounts constituting reasonable compensation for present or past services or payments made in the ordinary course of business under a bona fide retirement plan or other bona fide benefits program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Effective”, with respect to a record required or permitted to be delivered to the Mayor for filing under this chapter, means effective under § <cite path="§29-102.03">29-102.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Foreign limited liability company” means an unincorporated entity formed under the law of a jurisdiction other than the District which would be a limited liability company if formed under the law of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Manager” means a person that under the operating agreement of a manager-managed limited liability company is responsible, alone or in concert with others, for performing the management functions stated in § <cite path="§29-804.07">29-804.07</cite>(c).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Manager-managed limited liability company” means a limited liability company that qualifies under § <cite path="§29-804.07">29-804.07</cite>(a).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Member” means a person that has become a member of a limited liability company under § <cite path="§29-804.01">29-804.01</cite>, or was a member in a limited liability company when the company became subject to this chapter under § <cite path="§29-810.01">29-810.01</cite>, and has not dissociated under § <cite path="§29-806.02">29-806.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Member-managed limited liability company” means a limited liability company that is not a manager-managed limited liability company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Operating agreement” means the agreement, whether or not referred to as an operating agreement and whether oral, in a record, implied, or in any combination thereof, of all the members of a limited liability company, including a sole member, concerning the matters described in § <cite path="§29-801.07">29-801.07</cite>. The term includes the agreement as amended or restated.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Organizer” means a person that acts under § <cite path="§29-802.01">29-802.01</cite> to form a limited liability company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Transferable interest” means the right, as initially owned by a person in the person’s capacity as a member, to receive distributions from a limited liability company in accordance with the operating agreement, whether or not the person remains a member or continues to own any part of the right. The term applies to any fraction of the interest, by whomever owned.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Transferee” means a person to which all or part of a transferable interest has been transferred, whether or not the transferor is a member.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(h)(2)(A), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-804.05">29-804.05</cite> and § <cite path="§29-810.01">29-810.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 102 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act).</text>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
