<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-807.04</num>
  <heading>Other claims against dissolved limited liability company.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A dissolved limited liability company may publish notice of its dissolution and request persons having claims against the company to present them in accordance with the notice.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The notice authorized by subsection (a) of this section shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be published at least once in a newspaper of general circulation in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Describe the information required to be contained in a claim and provide a mailing address to which the claim is to be sent; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>State that a claim against the company is barred unless an action to enforce the claim is commenced within 3 years after publication of the notice.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a dissolved limited liability company publishes a notice in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, unless the claimant commences an action to enforce the claim against the company within 3 years after the publication date of the notice, the claim of each of the following claimants shall be barred:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A claimant that did not receive notice in a record under § <cite path="§29-807.03">29-807.03</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A claimant whose claim was timely sent to the company but not acted on; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A claimant whose claim is contingent at, or based on an event occurring after, the effective date of dissolution.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A claim not barred under this section or § <cite path="§29-807.03">29-807.03</cite> may be enforced:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Against a dissolved limited liability company, to the extent of its undistributed assets; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If assets of the company have been distributed after dissolution, against a member or transferee to the extent of that person’s proportionate share of the claim or of the assets distributed to the member or transferee after dissolution, whichever is less, but a person’s total liability for all claims under this paragraph shall not exceed the total amount of assets distributed to the person after dissolution.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(h)(8)(C), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-804.05">29-804.05</cite> and § <cite path="§29-807.07">29-807.07</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “this section or § <cite path="§29-807.03">29-807.03</cite>” for “this section” in (d).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 704 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act).</text>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
