<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-807.01</num>
  <heading>Events causing dissolution.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A limited liability company is dissolved, and its activities and affairs shall be wound up, upon the occurrence of any of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An event or circumstance that the operating agreement states causes dissolution;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The consent of all the members;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The passage of 90 consecutive days during which the company has no members, unless:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Consent to admit at least one specified person as a member is given by transferees owning the rights to receive a majority of distributions as transferees at the time the consent is to be effective; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>At least one person becomes a member in accordance with the consent;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>On application by a member, the entry by Superior Court of an order dissolving the company on the grounds that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The conduct of all or substantially all of the company’s activities and affairs is unlawful; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>It is not reasonably practicable to carry on the company’s activities and affairs in conformity with the certificate of organization and the operating agreement.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>On application by a member, the entry by Superior Court of an order dissolving the company on the grounds that the managers or those members in control of the company:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Have acted, are acting, or will act in a manner that is illegal or fraudulent; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Have acted or are acting in a manner that is oppressive and was, is, or will be directly harmful to the applicant.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The signing and filing of a statement of administrative dissolution by the Mayor under § <cite path="§29-106.02">29-106.02</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In a proceeding brought under subsection (a)(5) of this section, the Superior Court may order a remedy other than dissolution.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(h)(8)(A), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-801.07">29-801.07</cite>, § <cite path="§29-802.06">29-802.06</cite>, § <cite path="§29-804.01">29-804.01</cite>, § <cite path="§29-807.02">29-807.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-807.06">29-807.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “activities and affairs” for “activities” in the introductory language of (a) and twice in (a)(4); rewrote (a)(3); added (a)(6); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 701 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
