<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-801.09</num>
  <heading>Operating agreement; effect on third parties and relationship to records effective on behalf of limited liability company.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An operating agreement may specify that its amendment requires the approval of a person that is not a party to the operating agreement or the satisfaction of a condition. An amendment shall be ineffective if its adoption does not include the required approval or satisfy the specified condition.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The obligations of a limited liability company and its members to a person in the person’s capacity as a transferee or dissociated member shall be governed by the operating agreement. Subject only to any court order issued under § <cite path="§29-805.03">29-805.03</cite>(b)(2) to effectuate a charging order, an amendment to the operating agreement made after a person becomes a transferee or dissociated member shall be effective with regard to any debt, obligation, or other liability of the limited liability company or its members to the person in the person’s capacity as a transferee or dissociated member and is not effective to the extent the amendment imposes a new debt, obligation, or other liability on the transferee or person dissociated as a member.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a record that has been delivered by a limited liability company to the Mayor for filing and has become effective under this chapter contains a provision that would be ineffective under § <cite path="§29-801.07">29-801.07</cite>(c) or (d)(3) if contained in the operating agreement, the provision shall likewise be ineffective in the record.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (c) of this section, if a record that has been delivered by a limited liability company to the Mayor for filing and has become effective under this chapter conflicts with a provision of the operating agreement:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The operating agreement shall prevail as to members, dissociated members, transferees, and managers; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The record shall prevail as to other persons to the extent they reasonably rely on the record.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(h)(2)(F), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 112 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> added “and is not effective to the extent the amendment imposes a new debt, obligation, or other liability on the transferee or person dissociated as a member” at the end of (b); and substituted “§ <cite path="§29-801.07">29-801.07</cite>(c) or (d)(3)” for “§ <cite path="§29-801.07">29-801.07</cite>(c)” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-801.07">29-801.07</cite>, § <cite path="§29-802.01">29-802.01</cite>, and § <cite path="§29-810.01">29-810.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
