<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-931</num>
  <heading>Allocation and distribution of net savings.</heading>
  <text>At least once a year the members or the directors, or both, as the articles or bylaws may provide, shall apportion the net savings of the association in the following order:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Not less than 10% shall be placed in a reserve fund until such time as the fund equals at least 50% of the paid-up capital. The fund may be used in the general conduct of the business. The amounts apportioned to the reserve fund shall be allocated on the books of the association on a patronage basis or, in lieu thereof, the books and records of the association shall afford a means for doing so, in order that upon dissolution or earlier, if deemed advisable, the reserves may be returned to the patrons who have contributed the same, subject to the limitations of § <cite path="§29-934">29-934</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A return upon capital, within the limitations of § <cite path="§29-922">29-922</cite>, may be paid upon share capital, or, if the bylaws so provide, upon the membership capital certificates of a nonshare association, but the return upon capital may be paid only out of the surplus of the aggregate of the assets over the aggregate of the liabilities, including in the latter the amount of the capital stock, after deducting from the aggregate of the assets the amount by which such aggregate was increased by unrealized appreciation in value or revaluation of fixed assets.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>A portion of the remainder, as determined by the articles or bylaws, shall be allocated to an educational fund to be used in teaching cooperation, and a portion may also be allocated to funds for the general welfare of the members of the association.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The remainder shall be allocated at the same uniform rate to all patrons of the association in proportion to their individual patronage in accordance with the following rules:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>In the case of a member patron, the member’s proportionate amount of savings returns shall be distributed to the member unless the member agrees that the association should credit the amount to the member’s account toward the purchase of an additional share or shares or additional membership capital.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>In the case of a subscriber patron, the patron’s proportionate amount of savings returns may, as the articles or bylaws provide, be distributed to the patron or credited to the patron’s account until the amount of capital subscribed for has been fully paid.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>In the case of a nonmember patron, the patron’s proportionate amount of savings returns shall be set aside in a general fund for such patrons and shall be allocated to individual nonmember patrons only upon request and presentation of evidence of the amount of their patronage. Any savings return so allocated shall be credited to such patron toward payment of the minimum amount of share or membership capital necessary for membership. When a sum equal to this amount has accumulated at any time within a period of time specified in the bylaws, the patron shall be deemed to be, and becomes, a member of the association if the patron so agrees or requests and complies with any provisions in the bylaws for admission to membership. The certificates of shares or membership to which the patron is entitled shall then be issued to the patron.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Sub-subparagraph (ii) of this subparagraph shall apply if within any periods of time specified in the articles or bylaws:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(I)</num>
          <text>Any subscriber has not accumulated and paid in the amount of capital subscribed for;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(II)</num>
          <text>Any nonmember patron has not accumulated in the patron’s individual account the sum necessary for membership; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(III)</num>
          <text>Any nonmember patron has accumulated the sum necessary for membership, but the patron does not request or agree to become a member, or fails to comply with the provisions of the bylaws, if any, for admission to membership.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>If any of the conditions set forth in sub-subparagraph (i) of this subparagraph occur, the amounts so accumulated or paid in and any part of the general fund for nonmember patrons which has not been allocated to individual nonmember patrons shall go to the educational fund and, thereafter, no member or other patron shall have any rights in this paid-in capital or accumulated savings returns as such; provided, that nothing in this section prevents an association:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(I)</num>
          <text>Under this chapter which is engaged in rendering services from disposing of the net savings from the rendering of such services in such manner as to lower the fees charged for services or otherwise to further the common benefit of the members; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(II)</num>
          <text>From adopting a system whereby the payment of savings returns which would otherwise be distributed, shall be deferred for a fixed period of months or years, or from adopting a system whereby the savings returns distributed shall be partly in cash, partly in shares, the shares to be retired at a fixed future date, in the order of their serial number or date of issue.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§29-902">29-902</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§29-931">29-931</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 29-1131.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 29-831.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
