<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-305.40</num>
  <heading>Voting trusts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>One or more shareholders may create a voting trust, conferring on a trustee the right to vote or otherwise act for them, by signing an agreement setting out the provisions of the trust, which may include anything consistent with its purpose, and transferring their shares to the trustee. When a voting trust agreement is signed, the trustee shall prepare a list of the names and addresses of all owners of beneficial interests in the trust, together with the number and class of shares each transferred to the trust, and deliver copies of the list and agreement to the corporation’s principal office.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A voting trust shall be effective on the date the 1st shares subject to the trust are registered in the trustee’s name. A voting trust shall not be valid for not more than 10 years after its effective date unless extended under subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All or some of the parties to a voting trust may extend it for additional terms of not more than 10 years each by signing written consent to the extension. An extension shall be valid for 10 years after the date the 1st shareholder signs the extension agreement. The voting trustee shall deliver copies of the extension agreement and list of beneficial owners to the corporation’s principal office. An extension agreement binds only those parties signing it.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="29-305.41">29-305.41</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
