<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-311.50</num>
  <heading>Other remedies limited.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The legality of a proposed or completed corporate action described in § <cite root="29-311.02">29-311.02</cite>(a) shall not be contested and the corporate action shall not be enjoined, set aside, or rescinded, in a legal or equitable proceeding by a shareholder after the shareholders have approved the corporate action.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Was not authorized and approved in accordance with the applicable provisions of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Subchapter VII, VIII, IX, or X of this chapter;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The articles of incorporation or bylaws; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The resolution of the board of directors authorizing the corporate action;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Was procured as a result of fraud, a material misrepresentation, or an omission of a material fact necessary to make statements made, in light of the circumstances in which they were made, not misleading;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Is an interested transaction, unless it has been recommended by the board of directors in the same manner as is provided in § <cite root="29-306.72">29-306.72</cite> and has been approved by the shareholders in the same manner as is provided in § <cite root="29-306.73">29-306.73</cite> as if the interested transaction were a director’s conflicting interest transaction; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Is approved by less than unanimous consent of the voting shareholders pursuant to § <cite root="29-305.04">29-305.04</cite> if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The challenge to the corporate action is brought by a shareholder that did not consent and as to which notice of the approval of the corporate action was not effective at least 10 days before the corporate action was effected; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The proceeding challenging the corporate action is commenced within 10 days after notice of the approval of the corporate action is effective as to the shareholder bringing the proceeding.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to a corporate action that:</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
