<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-412.04</num>
  <heading>Revocation of dissolution.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation may revoke its dissolution within 120 days of its effective date.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Revocation of dissolution shall be authorized in the same manner as the dissolution was authorized unless that authorization permitted revocation by action of the board of directors alone, in which event the board of directors may revoke the dissolution without action by the members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>After the revocation of dissolution is authorized, the nonprofit corporation may revoke the dissolution by delivering to the Mayor for filing articles of revocation of dissolution, together with a copy of its articles of dissolution, that set forth:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the corporation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The effective date of the dissolution that was revoked;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The date that the revocation of dissolution was authorized; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>That the revocation of dissolution was approved in the manner required by this chapter and by the articles of incorporation and bylaws.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Revocation of dissolution shall be effective upon the effective date of the articles of revocation of dissolution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>When the revocation of dissolution is effective, it relates back to and takes effect as of the effective date of the dissolution and the nonprofit corporation resumes carrying on its activities as if dissolution had never occurred.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
