<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-609.04</num>
  <heading>Statement of merger.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After a merger, the surviving partnership may file a statement that the parties to the merger have merged into the surviving partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A statement of merger shall contain:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of each partnership that is a party to the merger;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name of the surviving partnership into which the other partnerships were merged; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The street address of the surviving partnership’s principal office and of an office in the District, if any.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, for the purposes of § <cite root="29-603.02">29-603.02</cite>, property of the surviving partnership that before the merger was held in the name of another party to the merger shall be property held in the name of the surviving partnership upon filing a statement of merger.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of § <cite root="29-603.02">29-603.02</cite>, real property of the surviving partnership that before the merger was held in the name of another party to the merger shall be property held in the name of the surviving partnership upon recording a certified copy of the statement of merger in the office for recording transfers of that real property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A filed and, if appropriate, recorded statement of merger, executed and declared to be accurate pursuant to § <cite root="29-601.05">29-601.05</cite>(c), stating the name of a partnership that is a party to the merger in whose name property was held before the merger and the name of the surviving partnership, but not containing all of the other information required by subsection (b) of this section, shall operate with respect to the partnerships named to the extent provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 41-159.7.</annotation>
      <annotation>2001 Ed., § <cite root="33-109.07">33-109.07</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 907 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
