<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-710.04</num>
  <heading>Filings required for merger; effective date.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After each constituent limited partnership has approved a merger, articles of merger shall be signed on behalf of each preexisting:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Domestic limited partnership, by each general partner listed in the certificate of limited partnership; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Foreign limited partnership, by an authorized representative.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The articles of merger shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of each constituent limited partnership and the jurisdiction of its governing statute;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name of the surviving limited partnership, the jurisdiction of its governing statute, and, if the surviving limited partnership is created by the merger, a statement to that effect;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The date the merger is effective under the governing statute of the surviving limited partnership;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the surviving limited partnership is to be created by the merger, its certificate of limited partnership;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>If the surviving limited partnership preexists the merger, any amendments provided for in the plan of merger to its certificate of limited partnership;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A statement as to each constituent limited partnership that the merger was approved as required by the limited partnership’s governing statute;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>If the surviving limited partnership is a foreign limited partnership not authorized to do business in the District, the street and mailing address of an office which the Mayor may use for the purposes of § <cite root="29-710.05">29-710.05</cite>(b); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Any additional information required by the governing statute of any constituent limited partnership.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each constituent limited partnership shall deliver the articles of merger for filing with the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A merger shall be effective under this subchapter upon the later of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Compliance with subsection (c) of this section; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to subchapter II of Chapter 2 of this title, as specified in the articles of merger.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="29-702.04">29-702.04</cite>, § <cite root="29-710.03">29-710.03</cite>, and § <cite root="29-710.05">29-710.05</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1108 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
