<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>29-810.01</num>
  <heading>Application to existing relationships.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This chapter shall apply to a limited liability company formed after the applicability date of this chapter and to a limited liability company that elects, as provided by subsection (c) of this section, to be governed by this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (d) of this section, on and after one year after the applicability date of this chapter, this chapter shall govern all limited liability companies, whenever formed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (d) of this section, after the applicability date of this chapter, a limited liability company voluntarily may elect, in the manner provided in its operating agreement or by law for amending the operating agreement, to be subject to this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes [of] applying this chapter to a limited liability company formed before the applicability date of this chapter:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The company’s articles of organization shall be deemed to be the company’s certificate of organization; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of applying § <cite root="29-801.02">29-801.02</cite>(10) and subject to § <cite root="29-801.09">29-801.09</cite>(d), language in the company’s articles of organization designating the company’s management structure operates as if that language were in the operating agreement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="29-801.02">29-801.02</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1104 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
