<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-193">
  <num type="law">21-193</num>
  <num type="bill">21-455</num>
  <num type="act">21-547</num>
  <heading type="short">International Registration Plan Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the International Registration Plan Agreement Act of 1997 to allow buses used in transportation of chartered parties to participate in the International Registration Plan program.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-02-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/34782/B21-0455-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-193</citation>
      <citation type="register">63 DCR 15010</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2016-10-11" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-11-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2016/11/29</enacted>
      <summary>The International Plan Agreement is a reciprocity agreement between the 48 contiguous U.S. States, the District of Columbia, and ten Canadian provinces. The agreement provides for payment of fees based on distance traveled by apportioned vehicles on the highways of member jurisdictions. Currently, charter and tour buses are excluded from the agreement. Law 21-193 eliminates the exemption for buses used in transportation of chartered parties. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Transportation and the Environment</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "International Registration Plan Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 2(3) of the International Registration Plan Agreement Act of 1997, effective September 5, 1997 (D.C. Law 12-14; D.C. Official Code ยง 50-1507.01(3)), is amended by striking the phrase "vehicles displaying restricted plates, buses used in transportation of chartered parties and government-owned vehicles" and inserting the phrase "vehicles displaying restricted plates, and government-owned vehicles" in its place.</text>
    <codify:find-replace doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง50-1507.01|(3)" count="1">
      <find>vehicles displaying restricted plates, buses used in transportation of chartered parties and government-owned vehicles</find>
      <replace>vehicles displaying restricted plates, and government-owned vehicles</replace>
    </codify:find-replace>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
