<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-202">
  <num type="law">21-202</num>
  <num type="bill">21-742</num>
  <num type="act">21-558</num>
  <heading type="short">Charitable Solicitations Relief Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Charitable Solicitation Act to authorize the Mayor to prescribe the terms and conditions under which a charitable solicitation may be exempted from the certificate of registration requirement, and to increase the maximum exemption amount; and to amend section 1000.6 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations to exempt from the secondhand dealer licensure requirement businesses that sell secondhand puzzles or non-electronic games or game pieces, including game cards.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-02-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/35755/Signed_Act/B21-0742-SignedAct.pdf?Id=105858">D.C. Law 21-202</citation>
      <citation type="register">63 DCR 15043</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B21-0742">
      <vote date="2016-11-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-11-15" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2016-12-06</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-202 authorizes the Mayor to prescribe the terms and conditions under which charitable solicitations may be exempted from the certificate of registration requirement. It also increases the maximum exemption amount from $1500 to $25000. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Business, Consumer, and Regulatory Affairs and Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Charitable Solicitations Relief Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§44-1703|(d)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 4(d) of the District of Columbia Charitable Solicitation Act, approved July 10, 1957 (71 Stat. 279; D.C. Official Code § 44-1703(d)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Strike the phrase "The Commissioners may" and insert the phrase "The Mayor may" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>The Council of the District of Columbia may</find>
        <replace>The Mayor may</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Strike the phrase "$1,500 in money or property" and insert the phrase "$25,000 in money or property, adjusted once a year on October 1, in accordance with the consumer price index for the Washington-Baltimore Metropolitan Statistical Area, or any successor index, as published by the United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics, or any successor agency" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>$1,500 in money or property</find>
        <replace>$25,000 in money or property, adjusted once a year on October 1, in accordance with the consumer price index for the Washington-Baltimore Metropolitan Statistical Area, or any successor index, as published by the United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics, or any successor agency</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <codify:not-funded-anno applicability-path="§3"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:ignore/>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 1000.6 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (16 DCMR § 1000.6) is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (h) is amended by striking the phrase "; or" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (i) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; or" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (j) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(j)</num>
          <text>Puzzles or non-electronic games or game pieces, including game cards.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2 shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 21-202" path="§2" date="pending" history="false"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973, (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
