<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-212">
  <num type="law">21-212</num>
  <num type="bill">21-759</num>
  <num type="act">21-569</num>
  <heading type="short">Specialty License Plate Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937 to require the Mayor to issue a motor vehicle identification tag with an inscription, facsimile, or emblem honoring women veterans, and to require the Mayor to issues a motor vehicle identification tag with a bicycle awareness design that includes an image and wording to educate motorists on the 3-foot passing rule; and to amend the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002 and the Office of Veterans Affairs Establishment Act of 2001 to make conforming amendments.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-02-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/35896/Signed_Act/B21-0759-SignedAct.pdf?Id=105698">D.C. Law 21-212</citation>
      <citation type="register">63 DCR 15326</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B21-0759">
      <vote date="2016-11-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-11-15" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2016-12-07</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-212 requires the Mayor to design and issue two types of motor vehicle identification tags: (1) a tag that bears the inscription women veterans or a facsimile or an emblem honoring women veterans, and (2) a tag with a design to enhance motorist's awareness of bicycles. Application and annual display fees may be established by the Mayor by rule and shall be deposited in the Veterans Affairs Fund and the Vision Zero Pedestrian and Bicycle Safety Fund, respectively. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Transportation and the Environment</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Specialty License Plate Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Title IV of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 679; D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.01 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>New sections 2b and 2c are added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="|50|15|I" after="§50-1501.02a" num-value="50-1501.02b" history-prefix="as added"/>
          <num>2b</num>
          <heading>Issuance of women veterans license plates.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The Mayor shall design and issue motor vehicle identification tags to honor women veterans that shall bear either the inscription "women veterans" or a facsimile or an emblem honoring women veterans. These identification tags shall retain and display the "TAXATION WITHOUT REPRESENTATION" slogan of the current District of Columbia motor vehicle identification tags.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>A resident ordering a motor vehicle identification tag for women veterans shall pay a one-time application fee and a display fee each year thereafter. The application fee shall be $25 and the display fee shall be $20, or other amounts as may be established by the Mayor by rule.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The application fee and annual display fee shall be deposited in the Office of Veterans Affairs Fund, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§49-1004">section 705 of the Office of Veterans Affairs Establishment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 49-1004)</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 75-1-ch690" path="§2b">Aug. 17, 1937, 50 Stat. 680, ch. 690, title IV,§ 2b</annotation>
        </section>
        <section>
          <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="|50|15|I" after="§50-1501.02b" num-value="50-1501.02c" history-prefix="as added"/>
          <num>2c</num>
          <heading>Issuance of bicycle awareness license plates.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The Mayor shall design and issue motor vehicle identification tags with a design to enhance motorists' awareness of bicycles, which shall include an image and wording to educate motorists about section 2202.10 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (18 DCMR § 2202.10).These identification tags shall retain and display the "TAXATION WITHOUT REPRESENTATION" slogan of the current District of Columbia motor vehicle identification tags.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>A resident ordering a bicycle awareness tag shall pay a one-time application fee and a display fee each year thereafter. The application fee shall be $25 and the display fee shall be $20, or other amounts as may be established by the Mayor by rule.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The application fee and annual display fee shall be deposited into the Vision Zero Pedestrian and Bicycle Safety Fund, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.20">section 9l of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective October 22, 2015 (D.C. Law 21-36; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.20</code-cite>).</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 75-1-ch690" path="§2c">Aug. 17, 1937, 50 Stat. 680, ch. 690, title IV,§ 2c</annotation>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 3 (D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.03) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a)(l) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.03|(a)"/>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>There shall be levied, collected, and paid for each registration year for each motor vehicle or trailer required to be registered under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="|50|15|I">this act</code-cite>, the registration fee provided in this section, except that in the event the Council of the District of Columbia prescribes and the Mayor of the District of Columbia issues as the official identification tags for the District of Columbia tags treated with special reflective materials designed to increase the visibility and legibility of such tags, the Council may charge a fee not exceeding $.50 in addition to all other fees which may be required.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Any person ordering a tag with special markings unique to that person shall pay a one-time application fee of $100, and may obtain a replacement if a tag is lost or stolen upon payment of a fee of $25 per tag.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Any person displaying a tag already approved for use by a member of an organization other than Disabled American Veterans shall pay a one-time application fee of $100, and may obtain a replacement if a tag is lost or stolen upon payment of a $25 fee per tag.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>Any person ordering Anacostia River Commemorative License Plates shall pay the fees as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-102.07|(b)">section 8(b) of the Anacostia River Clean Up and Protection Act of 2009, effective September 23, 2009 (D.C. Law 18-55; D.C. Official Code § 8-102.07(b))</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Any person ordering veterans identification tags pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02a">section 2a</code-cite> shall pay the fees as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02a|(b)|(2)">section 2a(b)(2)</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(F)</num>
                <text>Any person ordering a women veterans identification tags pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02b">section 2b</code-cite> shall pay the fees as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02b|(b)|(1)">section 2b(b)(1)</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(G)</num>
                <text>Any person ordering bicycle awareness identification tags shall pay the fees as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02c|(b)|(1)">section 2c(b)(1)</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§50-1501.03|(d)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (d) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(2)">
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>; and</find>
            <replace>;</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(3)">
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the period and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1" position="last">
            <find>.</find>
            <replace>;</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>New paragraphs (4) and (5) are added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(3)"/>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>The fees collected for women veteran identification tags shall be deposited in the Office of Veterans Affairs Fund, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§49-1004">section 705 of the Office of Veterans Affairs Establishment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 49-1004)</code-cite>; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(4)"/>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>The fees collected for bicycle awareness identification tags shall be deposited in the Vision Zero Pedestrian and Bicycle Safety Fund, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.20">section 9l of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective October 22, 2015 (D.C. Law 21-36; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.20)</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 9l(b) of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective October 22, 2015 (D.C. Law 21-36; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.20(b)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.20|(b)"/>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>There shall be deposited in the Fund:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>$500,000 per fiscal year from the fines generated from the automated traffic enforcement system, authorized by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2209.01">section 901 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-198; D.C. Official Code § 50-2209.01)</code-cite>; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Fees received by the Department of Motor Vehicles, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02c|(b)|(1)">section 2c(b)(1) of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, passed on 2nd reading on November 15, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-759)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text>Section 705(a) of the Office of Veterans Affairs Establishment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 49-1004(a)), is amended by striking the phrase "other funds for the Office" and inserting the phrase "other funds for the Office, including fees received by the Department of Motor Vehicles pursuant to section 2b(b)(1) of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, passed on 2nd reading on November 15, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-759),".</text>
    <codify:find-replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§49-1004|(a)" count="1">
      <find>other funds for the Office</find>
      <replace>other funds for the Office, including fees received by the Department of Motor Vehicles pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02b|(b)|(1)">section 2b(b)(1) of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, passed on 2nd reading on November 15, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-759)</code-cite>,</replace>
    </codify:find-replace>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(l) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(l)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
