<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-273">
  <num type="law">21-273</num>
  <num type="bill">21-298</num>
  <num type="act">21-648</num>
  <heading type="short">Active Duty Pay Differential Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to expand the pay differential authorization for agency and independent agency employees who serve in the reserve units of the United States Armed Forces and who are called or ordered to active duty in preparation for or as a result of Operation New Dawn, Operation Odyssey Dawn, or any contingency operation as defined in 10 U.S.C. § 101(a)(13).</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-04-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/34248/B21-0298-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-273</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 949</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2016-12-06" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-12-20" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-01-24</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-273 authorizes the District government to pay full-time District employees the difference between their military salaries and their government salary if they are called or ordered into active duty as a member of a reserve unit. Currently, the District is only authorized to issue pay differential for employees called to active duty for Operation Iraqi Freedom in Iraq and Operation Enduring Freedom in Afghanistan.</summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Active Duty Pay Differential Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 1103(a)(7)(A) of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-611.03(a)(7)(A)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-611.03|(a)|(7)|(A)"/>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any full-time permanent, indefinite, or term employee of a District agency or independent agency, who serves in a reserve component of the United States Armed Forces and who has been or will be called to active duty in preparation for, or as a result of, Operation New Dawn, Operation Odyssey Dawn, or any contingency operation as defined in 10 U.S.C. § 101(a)(13), shall receive, upon application and approval, an amount that equals the difference in compensation between the employee's District government basic pay reduced by the employee's basic military pay.  This amount shall not be considered as basic pay for any purpose and shall be paid for any period following the formal inception of Operation New Dawn in 2010, any period following the formal inception of Operation Odyssey Dawn in 2011, or any period following the formal inception of any contingency operation as defined in 10 U.S.C. § 101(a)(13), during which the employee is carried in a non-pay status from the time the employee is called into active duty, until the employee is released from active duty occasioned by any of these military operations, or, in the case of a term employee, until the date of the end of the term of employment.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
