<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-243">
  <num type="law">21-243</num>
  <num type="bill">21-905</num>
  <num type="act">21-659</num>
  <heading type="short">Downtown Business Improvement District Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996 to provide that a board of directors of a condominium association within the geographical area of the Downtown Business Improvement District may petition to join the Downtown Business Improvement District, and to establish the residential tax rate for the Downtown Business Improvement District.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-04-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/36580/Signed_Act/B21-0905-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106254">D.C. Law 21-243</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 1614</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B21-0905">
      <vote date="2016-12-06" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-12-20" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-02-09</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-243 includes the following Business Improvement Districts (BID) as taxable property: Capitol Riverfront, and Downtown. The tax is to provide additional services and improvements intended to enhance local business climate. Among other things, it also changes the BID tax rate for residential properties within the BID and establishes how the BID tax will be computed for residential units restricted to residents based upon income.</summary>
      <committee>Committee on Finance and Revenue</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Downtown Business Improvement District Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996, effective May 29, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-134; D.C. Official Code § 2-1215.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§2-1215.02|(24)|(B)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 3(24)(B) (D.C. Official Code § 2-1215.02(24)(B)) is amended by striking the phrase "and Capitol Riverfront BIDs," and inserting the phrase "Capitol Riverfront, and Downtown BIDs," in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>and Capitol Riverfront BIDs,</find>
        <replace>Capitol Riverfront, and Downtown BIDs,</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§2-1215.09b|(a)|(1)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 10b(a)(1) (D.C. Official Code § 2-1215.09b(a)(1)) is amended by striking the phrase "the BID;" and inserting the phrase "the BID or the board of directors of any condominium association on behalf of a real property within the geographic boundaries of the Downtown BID petition to join the Downtown BID;" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>the BID;</find>
        <replace>the BID or the board of directors of any condominium association on behalf of a real property within the geographic boundaries of the Downtown BID petition to join the Downtown BID;</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§2-1215.51|(c)|(3)|(A)">
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 201(c)(3)(A) (D.C. Official Code § 2-1215.51(c)(3)(A)) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(ii)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Sub-subparagraph (ii) is amended by striking the word "and" at the end.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1" position="last">
          <find>and</find>
          <replace/>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(iii)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Sub-subparagraph (iii) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1" position="last">
          <find>.</find>
          <replace>; and</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>A new sub-subparagraph (iv) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(iii)"/>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the amount of $120 per unit annually for nonexempt residential properties; provided, that for a residential unit restricted to residents based upon income pursuant to a federal or District affordable housing program, the BID tax due on the unit shall be computed by applying the percentage of area median income that an eligible household must meet to participate in the affordable housing program for the unit to the amount of the BID tax that would otherwise be due.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
