<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-236">
  <num type="law">21-236</num>
  <num type="bill">21-863</num>
  <num type="act">21-643</num>
  <heading type="short">Certified Business Enterprise Bonding Liability Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005 to require that a certified business enterprise that owns a majority interest in a joint venture formed to serve as a general contractor on a project has a minimum bonding capacity of 51% of the total contract amount, to require a joint venture to submit quarterly income and project-end statements to the Department of Small and Local Business Development, and to require the Department of Small and Local Business Development to submit to the chair of the Council committee with oversight of the Department of Small and Local Business Development a semiannual report on joint ventures.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-04-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/36382/B21-0863-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-236</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 937</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/36382/Signed_Act/B21-0863-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106064">
      <vote date="2016-12-06" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-12-20" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-01-25</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-236 requires that certified business enterprises entering into certain certified joint ventures, that own the majority of the interest in the joint venture, would provide the bond for the project, and would be solely liable for at least 51% of each claim asserted under the bond. A bond ensures contract completion in the event of contractor default. The Department of Small and Local Business Development is required to submit to the Council a semiannual report on joint ventures. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Committee of the Whole, Subcommittee on Local Business Development and Utilities</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Certified Business Enterprise Bonding Liability Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-218.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§2-218.39a">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2339a (D.C. Official Code § 2-218.39a) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (h)(1)(A) (D.C. Official Code § 2-218.39a(h)(1)(A)) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para codify:path="(h)|(1)|(A)">
            <codify:replace/>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The certified business enterprise owner with majority interest in the joint venture has bonding capacity equal to at least 51% of the total contract amount;</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new subsection (i) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(h)"/>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>No later than 60 days after the end of each operating quarter of the calendar year, a joint venture shall submit quarterly income statements to the Department showing all income and contract receipts and expenses, including the:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Fees for services and labor;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Salaries of the principals of the joint venture; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Distribution of profits.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>No later than 45 days after the completion of the project, the joint venture shall submit a project-end income statement to the Department with a statement of final profit distribution.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§2-218.54|(c)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 2354(c) (D.C. Official Code § 2-218.54(c)) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(8)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (8) is amended by striking the word "and" at the end.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1" position="last">
          <find>and</find>
          <replace/>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(9)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (9) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1" position="last">
          <find>.</find>
          <replace>; and</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (10) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(9)"/>
            <num>(10)</num>
            <text>A list of joint ventures certified by the Department, including the number of compliance checks completed on the joint ventures and a summary of the results, and a list of joint ventures that met the requirements set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-218.39a|(i)">section 2339a(i)</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
