<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 21-7">
  <num type="law">21-7</num>
  <num type="bill">21-88</num>
  <num type="act">21-43</num>
  <heading type="short">At-Risk Funding Temporary Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula for Public Schools and Public Charter Schools Act of 1998 to modify guidelines for spending at-risk funds within the District of Columbia Public Schools.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2015-06-04</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/33437/Signed_Act/B21-0088-SignedAct.pdf?Id=105584">D.C. Law 21-7</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 4564</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B21-0088">
      <vote date="2015-03-03" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2015-03-17" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-04-01</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "At-Risk Funding Temporary Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 108a(b) of the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula for Public Schools and Public Charter Schools Act of 1998, effective February 22, 2014  (D.C. Law 20-87; D.C. Official Code ยง 38-2907.01(b)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Funds provided to schools pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section shall be available for school utilization at the direction of the Chancellor in consultation with the principal and local school advisory team, for the purpose of improving student achievement among at-risk students. The Chancellor shall make publicly available an annual report that explains the allocation of funds sorted by individual schools.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (2) is repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
