<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 13-259">
  <num type="law">13-259</num>
  <heading type="short">Washington Convention Center Marketing Amendment Act of 2000</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2001-04-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/13-259.pdf">D.C. Law 13-259</citation>
      <citation type="register">48 DCR 772</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B13-0876">
      <narrative>Law 13-259, the “Washington Convention Center Marketing Amendment Act of 2000”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-876, which was referred to the Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 8, 2000, and December 5, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-547 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-259 became effective on April 3, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994 (“Act”) to recognize a proposed merger between 2 entities holding marketing service contracts with the Washington Convention Center Authority under the Act and to clarify and revise the Council approval process for marketing service contracts entered into under the Act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Washington Convention Center Marketing Amendment Act of 2000”. Sec. 2. Section 208a of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994 is amended as follows a) Subsection (d) is amended by adding a new second sentence to read as follows: “All money received from the Authority under a marketing services contract shall be separately accounted for and subject to verification by audit.” b) Subsection (e) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (3) is amended as follows A) Strike the phrase “promote neighborhood and cultural tourism in the District and” B) Strike the phrase “hospitality industry” and insert the phrase “hospitality industry, especially through neighborhood and cultural tourism” in its place C) Strike the phrase “; and” and insert a semi-colon in its place 2) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the period and inserting a semi-colon in its place 3) A new paragraph (5) is added to read as follows: “(5) In the event of a merger between the D.C. Committee to Promote Washington and the Washington Convention and Visitors Association, the surviving corporation shall succeed to the responsibilities of the D.C. Committee to Promote Washington and the Washington Convention and Visitors Association under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection and the contract between the surviving corporation and the Washington Convention Center Authority shall supersede and replace the contracts between the Washington Convention Center Authority and D.C. Committee to Promote Washington or the Washington Convention and Codification District of Columbia Code 2001 Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 Visitors Association. The surviving corporation shall A) Market and sell meetings and conventions for the Washington Convention Center and hotels in the District of Columbia B) Market and promote the District of Columbia as a destination; and C) Increase revenue to the District of Columbia and the Washington Convention Center Authority by maximizing sales of hotel rooms and restaurant meals.” c) Subsection (g) is amended to read as follows: “(g) Before entering into any marketing contract that is a multiyear contract or in excess of $1 million during a 12-month period, the Authority shall submit the contract to the Council for review and approval under section 105a(j) of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602 (c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3 District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
