<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 13-300">
  <num type="law">13-300</num>
  <heading type="short">Distribution of Marijuana Amendment Act of 2000</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2001-06-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/13-300.pdf">D.C. Law 13-300</citation>
      <citation type="register">47 DCR 7037</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B13-0240">
      <narrative>Law 13-300, the “Distribution of Marijuana Amendment Act of 2000”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-240, which was referred to the Committee of the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 26, 2000, and July 11, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 27, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-395 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-300 became effective on June 8, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981 to include marijuana as a Schedule III controlled substance in order to make the manufacture, distribution and possession with intent to distribute marijuana a five-year felony, except for the first conviction for the manufacture, distribution or possession with intent to distribute 1/2 pound or less of marijuana which will remain a misdemeanor if the person has not previously been convicted of the manufacture, distribution or possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance or an attempt to do so; and to amend section 1(g) of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia by amending the definition of dangerous crime to include offenses punishable by imprisonment for less than one year. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Distribution of Marijuana Amendment Act of 2000 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981 is amended as follows a) Section 208(a) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (4)(H) is amended by striking the word "and at the end 2) Paragraph (5)(BB) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase and" in its place 3) A new paragraph (6) is added to read as follows 6) Cannabis b) Section 212(2) is repealed c) Section 401(a)(2)(B) is amended by striking the phrase both and inserting the phrase “both; except that upon conviction of manufacturing, distributing or possessing with intent to distribute 1/2 pound or less of marijuana, a person who has not previously been convicted of manufacturing, distributing or possessing with intent to distribute a controlled substance or attempting to manufacture, distribute, or possess with intent to distribute a controlled substance may be imprisoned for not more than 180 days or fined not more than Codification District of Columbia Code 2001 Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 $1000 or both.” in its place. Sec. 3. Section 1(g) of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes is amended by striking the phrase if the offense is punishable by imprisonment for more than 1 year Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the final impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat.813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in § 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116 D.C. Code § 47.392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
