<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1207.61</num>
  <heading>Qualifications for licensure.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Pharmacy shall license as a cytotechnologist a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least a baccalaureate degree from an accredited institution that incorporates the academic coursework and minimum hours of supervised training required by the regulations adopted by the Board and whose program is accredited by an agency recognized by the U.S. Department of Education, or has qualified as a cytotechnologist under federal regulations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Passed a national certification examination given by the Board or from a body recognized by the Board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board of Pharmacy shall license as a histologic technician a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, has demonstrated, to the satisfaction of the Board, that he or she possesses the medical laboratory education, training, or experience that is appropriate for medical laboratory technicians concentrating in histology.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Board of Pharmacy shall license as a histotechnologist a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>At least a baccalaureate degree in biological sciences and chemistry from an accredited institution recognized by the U.S. Department of Education; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Successfully completed a histotechnology program accredited by an agency recognized by the U.S. Department of Education or one year of full-time laboratory work experience in histology deemed acceptable by the Board of Pharmacy; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Passed a national certification examination given by the Board or from a body recognized by the Board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board of Pharmacy shall license as a medical laboratory technician a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Successfully completed a medical laboratory technician program accredited by an agency recognized by the U.S. Department of Education or a military medical laboratory specialists program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Obtained an associate degree or has at least 60 semester hours or 90 quarter hours from an accredited institution recognized by the U.S. Department of Education, including a minimum of 6 semester hours or 9 quarter hours of biological science and 6 semester hours or 9 quarter hours of chemical science, and has 3 years of full-time acceptable medical laboratory work experience within the last 5 years; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Been previously qualified as a medical laboratory technologist under federal regulations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Passed a national certification examination given by the Board or from a body recognized by the Board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Board of Pharmacy shall license as a medical technologist a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, has:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>At least a baccalaureate degree from an accredited institution that includes courses in biological science, chemistry, and mathematics, and has successfully completed a medical technology program accredited by an agency recognized by the U.S. Department of Education;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A baccalaureate degree from a regionally accredited institution recognized by the U.S. Department of Education, including a minimum of 16 semester hours or 24 quarter hours of biological science, 16 semester hours or 24 quarter hours of chemical science, including one semester or one quarter in organic chemistry or biochemistry, one semester or one quarter of mathematics, and 3 years of full-time, clinical laboratory work experience in the major disciplines of laboratory practice deemed acceptable by the Board of Pharmacy, within the last 5 years and one of the following:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Certification as a medical laboratory technologist by a national certifying organization acceptable to the Board;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Successful completion of a medical laboratory technology program accredited by an agency recognized by the U.S. Department of Education; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Successful completion of an advanced military medical laboratory specialist program;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A baccalaureate degree from an accredited institution, including a minimum of 16 semester hours or 24 quarter hours of biological science, 16 semester hours or 24 quarter hours of chemical science, including one semester or one quarter in organic chemistry or biochemistry, one semester or one quarter of mathematics, and 5 years of full- time clinical laboratory work experience in the major disciplines of laboratory practice deemed acceptable by the Board of Pharmacy, within the last 10 years; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Been previously qualified as a medical technologist under federal regulations, or has a baccalaureate degree and training or experience as the Board determines is appropriate for medical technologists concentrating in categories such as blood banking, chemistry, hematology, immunology, microbiology, and virology; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Passed a national certification examination given by the Board or from a body recognized by the Board.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term “major disciplines of laboratory practice” includes blood banking, chemistry, immunology, and microbiology.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§761">March 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 761</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-272" type="History">as added May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-272, § 2(f), 62 DCR 1911</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
