<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1201.04</num>
  <heading>Persons licensed under prior law.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as expressly provided to the contrary in this chapter, any person licensed, registered, or certified by any agency of the District established or continued by any statute amended, repealed, or superseded by this chapter is considered for all purposes to be licensed, registered, or certified by the appropriate health occupations board established under this chapter for the duration of the term for which the license, registration, or certification was issued, and may renew that authorization in accordance with the appropriate renewal provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided to the contrary in this chapter, an individual who was originally licensed, registered, or certified under a provision of law that has been deleted by this chapter continues to meet the education and experience requirements as if that provision had not been deleted.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each employee of the Commission on Mental Health Services who was employed at St. Elizabeths Hospital prior to October 1, 1987, and who accepted employment with the District government on October 1, 1987, without a break in service, shall, within 27 months of appointment by the District government, meet all licensure requirements. If the employee does not meet all licensure requirements, the employee shall be issued a limited license subject to the provisions, limitations, conditions, or restrictions that shall be determined by the appropriate board or commission. The limited license shall not exceed the term of employment with the Commission on Mental Health Services.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§104">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 104, 33 DCR 729</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-40" type="History">Oct. 18, 1989, D.C. Law 8-40, § 3, 36 DCR 5756</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“This Act,” referred to near the middle of subsections (a) and (b), is <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-99">D.C. Law 6-99</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3301.4.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§24-261.02b">§ 24-261.02b</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Nomination and approval of agency heads, see <cite path="§1-523.01">§ 1-523.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Transfer from District government employment to private employment, see <cite path="§24-261.02b">§ 24-261.02b</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
