<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>21-1205</num>
  <heading>Rules and regulations for implementation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 90 days of the effective date of this chapter, the Mayor shall issue proposed rules and regulations to implement this chapter. The rules and regulations issued shall include procedures for:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Obtaining and filing written instructions and notification required by this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Periodic review of written instructions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Storage of medication;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Record keeping;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Initial and ongoing training for certification and recertification for all program employees to administer medication;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The administration of medication in emergency or life-threatening circumstances;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The provision of general supervision by registered nurses of trained employees;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The provision for the successful completion of training for program employees pursuant to this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The monitoring of trained employees who may administer medication to program participants; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The development of assessment tools.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Training programs for all program employees who may be authorized to administer medication in accordance with this chapter shall be approved by the Mayor or shall be medication administration programs approved by the State of Maryland or the Commonwealth of Virginia. The Mayor may enter into agreements of reciprocity with other jurisdictions, under which training programs approved in such jurisdictions shall also be accepted in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 601(b), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175" type="History">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1002(d), 45 DCR 7193</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-38" type="History">Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-38, § 1202(d), 46 DCR 6373</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§21-1203">21-1203</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-1205.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-38">D.C. Law 13-38</cite> rewrote par. (a)(1), which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“Obtaining and filing written instructions and consent required by this chapter;”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(d) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-32">D.C. Law 13-32</cite> substituted “notification” for “consent” in (a)(1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4 (b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-32">D.C. Law 13-32</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 602(d) of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-401, July 13, 1998,  45 DCR 4794), § 602(d) of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-564, January 12, 1999,  46 DCR 669), and § 602(d) of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-41, March 31, 1999,  46 DCR 3446).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2(d) of the Use of Trained Employees to Administer Medication Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-73, May 26, 1999,  46 DCR 5166).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 1202(d) of the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-110, July 28, 1999,  46 DCR 6320).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to the Use of Trained Employees to Administer Medication to Persons with Mental Retardation or Other Disabilities Act of 1995, see Mayor’s Order 2000-56, April 12, 2000 ( 47 DCR 4736).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
