<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>21-1115</num>
  <heading>Inquiry under this chapter if person convicted of offense.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>On the conviction by a court of record of competent jurisdiction of a person of an offense, or of a violation of an ordinance which is in whole or in part a violation of a statute of the District of Columbia, the court when satisfied on the testimony of a physician or a psychologist or other psychologist or other evidence that the person has at least a moderate intellectual disability as defined in the Citizens with Intellectual Disabilities Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act (D.C. Official Code <cite path="§7-1301.01">§ 7-1301.01</cite> et seq.), may suspend sentence, or suspend the entering of an order sending the person to a jail, prison, or reformatory, or to a training or industrial school, and direct that a parent or guardian appointed by the court file a petition under that act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>When the court directs a petition to be filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, it may order that, pending the preparation, filing and hearing of the petition, the person be detained in a place of safety, or be placed under the guardianship of a suitable person, if that person enters into a recognizance for his appearance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Where, upon the hearing of a petition filed pursuant to this section or pursuant to a subsequent hearing under this chapter, the person is found not to have at least a moderate intellectual disability, the court shall impose sentence.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-183" type="History">Sept. 14, 1965, 79 Stat. 771, Pub. L. 89-183, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 568, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 150(g)(1)(A)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-490" type="History">Oct. 22, 1970, 84 Stat. 1087, Pub. L. 91-490, § 2(a)(1)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 604(a)(3), (4), 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 14(o), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 21(e)(9), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act, referred to in subsection (a) of this section, is codified in <cite path="§7-1301.01">§ 7-1301.01</cite> et seq. in the 2001 Edition of the D.C. Official Code.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite>, in (a), substituted “person has at least a moderate intellectual disability” for “person is at least moderately mentally retarded” and “Citizens with Intellectual Disabilities” for “Mentally Retarded Citizens”; and substituted “have at least a moderate intellectual disability” for “be at least moderately mentally retarded” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 21-1115.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-1115.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
