<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>21-2403.01</num>
  <heading>Transfer of guardianship or conservatorship to another state.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A guardian or conservator appointed in the District of Columbia may petition the Superior Court to transfer the guardianship or conservatorship to another state.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notice of a petition under subsection (a) of this section shall be given to the persons that would be entitled to notice of a petition in the District of Columbia for the appointment of a guardian or conservator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>On the Superior Court’s own motion or on request of the guardian or conservator, the incapacitated or protected person, or other person required to be notified of the petition, the Superior Court shall hold a hearing on a petition filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court shall issue a provisional order granting a petition to transfer a guardianship and shall direct the guardian to petition for guardianship in the other state if the Superior Court is satisfied that the guardianship will be accepted by the court in the other state and the Superior Court finds that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The incapacitated person is physically present in or is reasonably expected to move permanently to the other state;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An objection to the transfer has not been made or, if an objection has been made, the objector has not established that the transfer would be contrary to the interests of the incapacitated person; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Plans for care and services for the incapacitated person in the other state are reasonable and sufficient.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court shall issue a provisional order granting a petition to transfer a conservatorship and shall direct the conservator to petition for conservatorship in the other state if the Superior Court is satisfied that the conservatorship will be accepted by the court of the other state and the Superior Court finds that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The protected person is physically present in or is reasonably expected to move permanently to the other state, or the protected person has a significant connection to the other state, considering the factors in § <cite path="§21-2402.01">21-2402.01</cite>(b);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An objection to the transfer has not been made or, if an objection has been made, the objector has not established that the transfer would be contrary to the interests of the protected person; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Adequate arrangements will be made for management of the protected person’s property.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court shall issue a final order confirming the transfer and terminating the guardianship or conservatorship upon its receipt of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A provisional order accepting the proceeding from the court to which the proceeding is to be transferred which is issued under provisions similar to § <cite path="§21-2403.02">21-2403.02</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The documents required to terminate a guardianship or conservatorship in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-270" type="History">Nov. 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-270, § 2(b), 55 DCR 11018</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§21-2402.01">21-2402.01</cite>, § <cite path="§21-2402.04">21-2402.04</cite>, and § <cite path="§21-2403.02">21-2403.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 301 of the Uniform Adult Guardianship and Protective Proceedings Jurisdiction Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
