<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>21-2204</num>
  <heading>Certification of incapacity.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Mental incapacity to make a health-care decision shall be certified by 2 professionals who are licensed to practice in the District and qualified to make a determination of mental incapacity. One of the 2 certifying professionals shall be a physician and one shall be a qualified psychologist or psychiatrist. At least 1 of the 2 certifying professionals shall examine the individual in question within 1 day preceding certification. Both certifying professionals shall give an opinion regarding the cause and nature of the mental incapacity as well as its extent and probable duration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All professional findings and opinions forming the basis of certification under subsection (a) of this section shall be expressed in writing, included in the patient-care records of the individual, and provide clear evidence that the person is incapable of understanding the health-care choice, making a decision concerning the particular treatment or services in question, or communicating a decision even if capable of making it.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Certification of incapacity under this section shall be limited in its effect to the capacity to make health-care decisions and shall not be construed as a finding of incompetency for any other purpose.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-189" type="History">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-189, § 5, 35 DCR 8653</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-68" type="History">Feb. 5, 1994, D.C. Law 10-68, § 23(e), 40 DCR 6311</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-249" type="History">Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-249, § 3(b), 55 DCR 9206</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Presumption of capacity, health care decisions, see § <cite path="§21-2203">21-2203</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Substituted consent, health care decisions, see § <cite path="§21-2210">21-2210</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1203.03">7-1203.03</cite>, § <cite path="§7-1231.07">7-1231.07</cite>, § <cite path="§7-1231.08">7-1231.08</cite>, § <cite path="§7-1305.06a">7-1305.06a</cite>, § <cite path="§7-1305.07a">7-1305.07a</cite>, § <cite path="§21-2002">21-2002</cite>, § <cite path="§21-2041">21-2041</cite>, § <cite path="§21-2046">21-2046</cite>, § <cite path="§21-2047.02">21-2047.02</cite>, § <cite path="§21-2203">21-2203</cite>, § <cite path="§21-2210">21-2210</cite>, and § <cite path="§21-2212">21-2212</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-2204.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-249">D.C. Law 17-249</cite> rewrote subsec. (a), which had read as follows: “(a) Mental incapacity to make a health-care decision shall be certified by 2 physicians who are licensed to practice in the District and qualified to make a determination of mental incapacity. One of the 2 certifying physicians shall be a psychiatrist. At least 1 of the 2 certifying physicians shall examine the individual in question within 1 day preceding certification. Both certifying physicians shall give an opinion regarding the cause and nature of the mental incapacity as well as its extent and probable duration.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-46">D.C. Law 16-46</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “professionals” for “physicians” wherever it appears and substituted “One of the 2 certifying professionals shall be a physician and one shall be a qualified psychologist or psychiatrist.” for “One of the 2 certifying physicians shall be a psychiatrist.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 6(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-46">D.C. Law 16-46</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-194">D.C. Law 16-194</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “professionals” for “physicians” throughout, and substituted “One of the 2 certifying professionals shall be a physician and one shall be a qualified psychologist or psychiatrist.” for the second sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 6(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-194">D.C. Law 16-194</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-100">D.C. Law 17-100</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “professionals” for “physicians” throughout and “One of the 2 certifying professionals shall be a physician and one shall be a qualified psychologist or psychiatrist.” for the second sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 6(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-100">D.C. Law 17-100</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Health-Care Decisions for Persons with Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-190, October 28, 2005,  52 DCR 10021).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Health-Care Decisions for Persons with Mental Retardation and Development Disabilities Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-262, January 26, 2006,  53 DCR 795).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Health-Care Decisions for Persons with Developmental Disabilities Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-480, September 25, 2006,  53 DCR 7940).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Health-Care Decisions for Persons with Developmental Disabilities Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-566, December 19, 2006,  53 DCR 10272).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Health-Care Decisions for Persons with Developmental Disabilities Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-161, October 18, 2007,  54 DCR 10932).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Health-Care Decisions for Persons with Developmental Disabilities Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-245, January 23, 2008,  55 DCR 1230).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment, see § 3(b) of Health-Care Decisions for Persons with Developmental Disabilities Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-492, August 4, 2008,  55 DCR 9167).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
