<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>21-2105</num>
  <heading>Construction of power relating to tangible personal property transactions.</heading>
  <text>In a statutory power of attorney the language granting power with respect to tangible personal property transactions empowers the agent to:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Accept as a gift or as security for a loan, reject, demand, buy, receive, or otherwise acquire ownership or possession of tangible personal property or an interest in tangible personal property;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Sell, exchange, convey with or without covenants, release, surrender, mortgage, encumber, pledge, hypothecate, create a security interest in, pawn, grant options concerning, lease, sublease to others, or otherwise dispose of tangible personal property or an interest in tangible personal property;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Release, assign, satisfy, or enforce by litigation or otherwise, a mortgage, security interest, encumbrance, lien, or other claim on behalf of the principal with respect to tangible personal property or an interest in tangible personal property; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Do an act of management or conservation with respect to tangible personal property or an interest in tangible personal property on behalf of the principal, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Insuring against casualty, liability, or loss;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Obtaining or regaining possession, or protecting the property or interest, by litigation or otherwise;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Paying, compromising, or contesting taxes or assessments or applying for and receiving refunds in connection with taxes or assessments;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Moving from place to place;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Storing for hire or on a gratuitous bailment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Using, altering, and making repairs or alterations.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-147" type="History">Sept. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-147, § 2, 45 DCR 3853</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-2105.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 5 of the Uniform Statutory Form Power of Attorney Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
