<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>21-2111</num>
  <heading>Construction of power relating to estate, trust, and other beneficiary transactions.</heading>
  <text>In a statutory power of attorney the language granting power with respect to estate, trust, and other beneficiary transactions empowers the agent to act for the principal in all matters that affect a trust, probate estate, guardianship, conservatorship, escrow, custodianship, or other fund from which the principal is, may become, or claims to be entitled, as a beneficiary, to a share or payment, including to:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Accept, reject, disclaim, receive, receipt for, sell, assign, release, pledge, exchange, or consent to a reduction in or modification of a share in or payment from the fund;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Demand or obtain by litigation or otherwise money or other thing of value to which the principal is, may become, or claims to be entitled by reason of the fund;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Initiate, participate in, and oppose litigation to ascertain the meaning, validity, or effect of a deed, will, declaration of trust, or other instrument or transaction affecting the interest of the principal;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Initiate, participate in, and oppose litigation to remove, substitute, or surcharge a fiduciary;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Conserve, invest, disburse, and use anything received for an authorized purpose; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Transfer an interest of the principal in stocks, bonds, accounts with financial institutions, insurance, and other property, to the trustee of a revocable trust created by the principal as settlor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-147" type="History">Sept. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-147, § 2, 45 DCR 3853</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-2111.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 11 of the Uniform Statutory Form Power of Attorney Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
