<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>21-2206</num>
  <heading>Rights and duties of attorney in fact.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to any express limitations in the durable power of attorney for health care, an attorney in fact shall have all the rights, powers and authority related to health-care decisions that the principal would have under District and federal law. This authority shall include, at a minimum:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The authority to grant, refuse or withdraw consent to the provision of any health-care service, treatment, or procedure;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The right to review the health care records of the principal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The right to be provided with all information necessary to make informed health-care decisions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The authority to select and discharge health-care professionals; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The authority to make decisions regarding admission to or discharge from health-care facilities and to take any lawful actions that may be necessary to carry out these decisions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and unless a durable power of attorney for health care provides otherwise, the designated attorney in fact, if known to a health-care provider to be available and willing to make a particular health-care decision, shall have priority over any other person to act for the principal in all matters regarding health care.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A designated attorney in fact shall not have the authority to make a particular health-care decision, if the principal is able to give or withhold informed consent with respect to that decision.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In exercising authority under a durable power of attorney for health care, the attorney in fact shall have a duty to act in accordance with:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The wishes of the principal as expressed in the durable power of attorney for health care; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The good faith belief of the attorney in fact as to the best interests of the principal, if the wishes of the principal are unknown and cannot be ascertained.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this subchapter shall affect any right that an attorney in fact may have, independent of the designation in a durable power of attorney for health care, to make or otherwise participate in health-care decisions on behalf of the principal.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-189" type="History">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-189, § 7, 35 DCR 8653</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-68" type="History">Feb. 5, 1994, D.C. Law 10-68, § 23(g), 40 DCR 6311</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-72" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-72, § 2(c)(4), 63 DCR 208</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Patient or client records, obtaining from health care providers, see § <cite path="§3-1210.11">3-1210.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1231.06">7-1231.06</cite> and § <cite path="§7-1231.07">7-1231.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-2206.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72">D.C. Law 21-72</law-cite> substituted “subchapter” for “chapter” in (d).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
