<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>21-2056</num>
  <heading>Protective arrangements and single transactions authorized.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If it is established in a proper proceeding that a basis exists as described in section 21-2051 for affecting the property and business affairs of an individual, the court, without appointing a conservator, may authorize, direct, or ratify any transaction necessary or desirable to achieve any security, service, or care arrangement meeting the foreseeable needs of the protected individual. Protective arrangements include payment, delivery, deposit, or retention of funds or property; sale, mortgage, lease, or other transfer of property; entry into an annuity contract, a contract for life care, a deposit contract, or a contract for training and education; or addition to or establishment of a suitable trust.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If it is established in a proper proceeding that a basis exists as described in section 21-2051 for affecting the property and business affairs of an individual, the court, without appointing a conservator, may authorize, direct, or ratify any contract, trust, or other transaction relating to the protected individual’s property and business affairs if the court determines that the transaction is in the best interest of the protected individual.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before approving a protective arrangement or other transaction under this section, the court shall consider the interests of creditors and dependents of the protected individual and, in view of the incapacity, disappearance, or detention by a foreign power, whether the protected individual needs the continuing protection of a conservator. The court may appoint a special conservator to assist in the accomplishment of any protective arrangement or other transaction authorized under this section who shall have the authority conferred by the order and serve until discharged by order after report to the court of all matters done pursuant to the order of appointment.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-204" type="History">Feb. 28, 1987, D.C. Law 6-204, § 2(a), 34 DCR 632</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§21-2011">21-2011</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-2056.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § <cite path="§2-308">2-308</cite> of the Uniform Guardianship and Protective Proceedings Act (1982 Act).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
