<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>21-501.01</num>
  <heading>Qualified psychologists.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Qualified psychologists are subject to the restrictions and qualifications for practice contained in the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 6-99">D.C. Law 6-99</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§3-1201.01">3-1201.01</cite> et seq.).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Whenever a qualified psychologist has the responsibility for the voluntary, nonprotesting, emergency, or court-ordered admission or hospitalization of a person who is mentally ill, that qualified psychologist or the provider shall, prior to or at the time of admission or commitment, identify a psychiatrist or other appropriate physician who shall be responsible for the medical evaluation and medical management of the person who is mentally ill during the period in which the person is receiving treatment from that provider. The qualified psychologist may be responsible for all other evaluation and management of the mental health services or mental health services or supports for the person who is mentally ill.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-48" type="History">Feb. 24, 1984, D.C. Law 5-48, § 11(c), 30 DCR 5778</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104" type="History">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 6(d), 35 DCR 147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-283" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-283, § 2(c), 50 DCR 917</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-501.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-283">D.C. Law 14-283</cite> rewrote subsec. (b) which had read as follows: “(b) Whenever a qualified psychologist may have the responsibility for the voluntary, nonprotesting, emergency, or court-ordered hospitalization of a mentally ill patient, that qualified psychologist or the hospital shall, prior to or at the time of hospital admission, identify a psychiatrist or other appropriate physician with admitting privileges at the hospital who shall be responsible for the medical evaluation and medical management of the patient for the duration of the patient’s hospitalization. The qualified psychologist shall be responsible for all other evaluation and management of the patient.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-131">D.C. Law 14-131</cite> amended subsec. (b) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) Whenever a qualified psychologist may have the responsibility for the voluntary, nonprotesting, emergency, or court-ordered admission or hospitalization of a person who is mentally ill, that qualified psychologist or the provider shall, prior to or at the time of admission or commitment, identify a psychiatrist or other appropriate physician who shall be responsible for the medical evaluation and medical management of the person who is mentally ill during the period in which the person is receiving treatment from that provider. The qualified psychologist shall be responsible for all other evaluation and management of the mental health services or mental health supports for the person who is mentally ill.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-131">D.C. Law 14-131</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Mental Health Commitment Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-265, January 30, 2002,  49 DCR 1450).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Mental Health Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-350, April 24, 2002,  49 DCR 4417).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-546, December 12, 2002,  50 DCR 199).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-41, March 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2784).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 33(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> provided that the section designation of § <cite path="§21-501.1">21-501.1</cite> of the District of Columbia Official Code is redesignated as § <cite path="§21-501.01">21-501.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
