<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>21-523</num>
  <heading>Court order requirement for hospital detention beyond 48 hours; maximum period for observation.</heading>
  <text>A person admitted to a hospital or the Department under section 21-522   may not be detained in the hospital or by the Department for a period in excess of 48 hours from the time of the person’s admission, unless the administrator of the hospital, the chief clinical officer of the Department, or the administrator’s or chief clinical officer’s designee has, within that period, filed a written petition with the court for an order authorizing the continued detention of the person for emergency observation and diagnosis for a period not to exceed 7 days from the time the order is entered.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-183" type="History">Sept. 14, 1965, 79 Stat. 753, Pub. L. 89-183, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-283" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-283, § 2(j), 50 DCR 917</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§21-522">21-522</cite>, § <cite path="§21-524">21-524</cite>, and § <cite path="§21-526">21-526</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-523.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 21-523.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-283">D.C. Law 14-283</cite> rewrote the section which had read as follows: “§ <cite path="§21-523">21-523</cite>. Court order requirement for hospital detention beyond 48 hours; maximum period for observation.” “A person admitted to a hospital under  section 21-522 may not be detained in the hospital for a period in excess of 48 hours from the time of his admission, unless the administrator of the hospital has, within that period, filed a written petition with the court for an order authorizing the continued hospitalization of the person for emergency observation and diagnosis for a period not to exceed 7 days from the time the order is entered.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(i) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-131">D.C. Law 14-131</cite> amended this section to read as follows: “A person admitted to a hospital or the Department under  section 21-522 may not be detained in the hospital or by the Department for a period in excess of 48 hours from the time of the person’s admission, unless the administrator of the hospital, the chief clinical officer of the Department, or the administrator’s or chief clinical officer’s designee has, within that period, filed a written petition with the court for an order authorizing the continued hospitalization of the person for emergency observation and diagnosis for a period not to exceed 7 days from the time the order is entered.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-131">D.C. Law 14-131</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(i) of Mental Health Commitment Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-265, January 30, 2002,  49 DCR 1450).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(i) of Mental Health Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-350, April 24, 2002,  49 DCR 4417).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(j) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-546, December 12, 2002,  50 DCR 199).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(j) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-41, March 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2784).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
