<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>21-503</num>
  <heading>Examinations and hearings; subpoenas; witnesses; place.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall examine alleged mentally ill persons, inquire into their affairs and the affairs of persons who may be legally liable for their support, and make reports and recommendations to the court.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided by this chapter, the Commission may conduct its examinations and hearings either at the courthouse or elsewhere at its discretion. The court may issue subpoenas at the request of the Commission returnable before the Commission, for the appearance of the alleged mentally ill person, witnesses, and persons who may be liable for his support. Commission members who are psychiatrists or qualified psychologists, are competent and compellable witnesses at any trial, hearing or other proceeding conducted pursuant to this chapter and the physician- or psychologist-patient privilege is not applicable.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-183" type="History">Sept. 14, 1965, 79 Stat. 752, Pub. L. 89-183, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-48" type="History">Feb. 24, 1984, D.C. Law 5-48, § 11(a)(5), 30 DCR 5778</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104" type="History">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 6(e), 35 DCR 147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-283" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-283, § 2(e), 50 DCR 917</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 108-450" type="History">Dec. 10, 2004, 118 Stat. 3473, Pub. L. 108-450, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-503.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 21-503.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 108-450, in subsec. (b), substituted “Commission members who are psychiatrists or qualified psychologists” for “The Commission, or any of the members thereof,”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section applicable upon enactment of certain legislation by the United States Congress, see §§ 2(e) and 3 of Mental Health Civil Commitment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-546, December 12, 2002,  50 DCR 199).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-41, March 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2784).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of §§ 2(d), (e), (l)(2), (n), (r)(3) and (4), (t), and (u) of Law 14-283: Section 3 of Law 14-283 provided that section 2(d), (e), (l)(2), (n), (r)(3) and (4), (t), and (u) shall apply upon the enactment of legislation by the United States Congress that states the following: “Notwithstanding any other law, section 2(d), (e), (l)(2), (r)(3) and (4), (t), and (u) of the Mental Health Civil Commitment Act of 2002, adopted by the Council of the District of Columbia, is enacted into law.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
