<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>21-501</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>As used in the chapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Administrator” means a person in charge of a public or private hospital or his delegate;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1A)</num>
    <text>“Chief clinical officer” means the psychiatrist or qualified psychologist for the Department who is responsible for coordinating the treatment of persons receiving mental health supports or mental health services from the Department;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Chief of service” means the physician or qualified psychologist charged with overall responsibility for the professional program of care and treatment in the particular administrative unit of the hospital to which the patient has been admitted or such other member of the medical staff as the chief of service designates;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Commission” means the Commission on Mental Health;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3A)</num>
    <text>“Core services agency” means a community-based provider of mental health services and mental health supports that is certified by the Department and that acts as a clinical home for consumers of mental health services by providing a single point of access and accountability for diagnostic assessment, medication-somatic treatment, counseling and psychotherapy, community support services, and access to other needed services;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Court” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4A)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the Department of Mental Health;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4A-i)</num>
    <text>“Domestic partner” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§32-701">32-701</cite>(3).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4B)</num>
    <text>“Mental health services” means the services funded or regulated by the Department for the purpose of addressing mental illness or mental health problems;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4C)</num>
    <text>“Mental health supports” means the supports funded or regulated by the Department for the purpose of addressing mental illness or mental health problems;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Mental illness” means a psychosis or other disease which substantially impairs the mental health of a person;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Physician” means a person licensed under the laws of the District of Columbia to practice medicine, or a person who practices medicine in the employment of the Government of the United States or of the District of Columbia;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Private hospital” means a nongovernmental hospital or institution, or part thereof, in the District of Columbia, equipped and qualified to provide inpatient care and treatment for a person with a physical or mental illness;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8A)</num>
    <text>“Provider” means an individual or entity that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is duly licensed or certified by the Department to provide mental health services or mental health supports; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Has entered into an agreement with the Department to provide mental health services or mental health supports;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8B)</num>
    <text>“Psychiatrist” means a physician who is licensed to practice medicine in the District of Columbia, or is employed by the federal government, and has completed a residency in psychiatry;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Public hospital” means a hospital or institution, or part thereof, in the District of Columbia, owned and operated by the Government of the United States or of the District of Columbia, equipped and qualified to provide inpatient care and treatment for persons with from physical or mental illness;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9A)</num>
    <text>“Qualified physician” means a person licensed under the laws of the District of Columbia to practice medicine who is board-certified in emergency medicine and certified by the Department to examine persons and prepare admission certificates pursuant to section 21-522; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Qualified psychologist” means a person who is licensed pursuant to section 501 of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 6-99">D.C. Law 6-99</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§3-1205.01">3-1205.01</cite>), and has (1) one year of formal training within a hospital setting; or (2) two years of supervised clinical experience in an organized health care setting, one of which must be post-doctoral.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-183" type="History">Sept. 14, 1965, 79 Stat. 751, Pub. L. 89-183, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 567, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 150(c)(1)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-48" type="History">Feb. 24, 1984, D.C. Law 5-48,§ 11(a)(4), (b), 30 DCR 5778</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104" type="History">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 6(c), 35 DCR 147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 20(b), 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-283" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-283, § 2(b), 50 DCR 917</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 35(a)(1), 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 22(a), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 21(c)(2), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Interstate Compact on Mental Health, see § <cite path="§7-1101">7-1101</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Jurisdiction of Family Division of Superior Court, see § <cite path="§11-1101">11-1101</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mentally ill persons, see, also, §§ <cite path="§21-901">21-901</cite> et seq., 21-2001 et seq., 24-501 et seq., 44-901 et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Presumption of capacity, see § <cite path="§21-2203">21-2203</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Representation of indigents, see § <cite path="§11-2601">11-2601</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1345.01">4-1345.01</cite>, § <cite path="§20-303">20-303</cite>, § <cite path="§21-502">21-502</cite>, § <cite path="§21-901">21-901</cite>, and § <cite path="§21-2203">21-2203</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-501.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 21-501.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-283">D.C. Law 14-283</cite> added pars. (1A), (3A), (4A), (4B), (4C), (8A), (8B), and (9A); and repealed par. (6) which had read as follows: “(6) ‘Mentally ill person’ means a person who has a mental illness, but does not include a person committed to a private or public hospital in the District of Columbia by order of the court in a criminal proceeding;”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, in par. (8), substituted “with” for “suffering from”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite> added par. (4A-i).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “with” for “suffering from” in (9).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b)(1) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-131">D.C. Law 14-131</cite> added pars. (1A), (3A), (4A), (4B), (4C), (8A), (8B), and (9A) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1A) ‘Chief clinical officer’ means the psychiatrist or qualified psychologist for the Department who is responsible for coordinating the treatment of persons receiving mental health supports or mental health services from the Department;”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3A) ‘Core services agency’ means a community-based provider of mental health services and mental health supports that is certified by the Department and that acts as a clinical home for consumers of mental health services by providing a single point of access and accountability for diagnostic assessment, medication-somatic treatment, counseling and psychotherapy, community support services, and access to other needed services;”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4A) ‘Department’ means the Department of Mental Health;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4B) ‘Mental health services’ means the services funded or regulated by the Department for the purpose of addressing mental illness or mental health problems;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4C) ‘Mental health supports’ means the supports funded or regulated by the Department for the purpose of addressing mental illness or mental health problems;”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8A) ‘Provider’ means an individual or entity that:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) Is duly licensed or certified by the Department to provide mental health services or mental health supports; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Has entered into an agreement with the Department to provide mental health services or mental health supports;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8B) ‘Psychiatrist’ means a physician who is licensed to practice medicine in the District of Columbia and has completed a residency in psychiatry; and”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9A) ‘Qualified physician’ means a person licensed under the laws of the District of Columbia to practice medicine who is board-certified in emergency medicine and certified by the Department to examine persons and prepare admission certificates pursuant to  section 21-522.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b)(2) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-131">D.C. Law 14-131</cite> repealed par. (6).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-131">D.C. Law 14-131</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Mental Health Commitment Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-265, January 30, 2002,  49 DCR 1450).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Mental Health Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-350, April 24, 2002,  49 DCR 4417).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-546, December 12, 2002,  50 DCR 199).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-41, March 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2784).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 21(c)(1) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “Persons with Mental Illness” for ”the Mentally Ill” in the chapter heading.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
