<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>21-522</num>
  <heading>Examination and admission to hospital; notice.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to the provisions of section 21-523, the administrator of a private hospital may, and the administrator of a public hospital or the chief clinical officer of the Department or his designee shall, admit and detain for purposes of emergency observation and diagnosis a person with respect to whom application is made under section 21-521, if the application is accompanied by a certificate of a psychiatrist, qualified physician, or qualified psychologist on duty at the hospital or the Department stating that he or she:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has examined the person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is of the opinion that the person has symptoms of a mental illness and, because of the mental illness, is likely to injure himself or others unless the person is immediately detained; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Is of the opinion that hospitalization is the least restrictive form of treatment available to prevent the person from injuring himself or others.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to the provisions of section 21-523, the chief clinical officer of the Department shall admit and detain, for purposes of emergency observation and diagnosis at a facility certified by the Department for emergency detention, a person with respect to whom application is made under section 21-521, if the application is accompanied by a certificate of a psychiatrist, qualified physician, or qualified psychologist on duty at the Department stating that he or she:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has examined the person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is of the opinion that the person has symptoms of a mental illness and, because of the mental illness, is likely to injure himself or others unless the person is immediately detained;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Is of the opinion that hospitalization is not the least restrictive form of treatment available to ensure that the person will not injure himself or others; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Is of the opinion that detention in a certified facility for observation and diagnosis is the least restrictive treatment alternative to prevent the person from injuring himself or others.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the psychiatrist, qualified physician, or qualified psychologist determines, after examining the person who has been presented for emergency observation and diagnosis, that the person is not mentally ill, not likely to injure himself or others unless immediately detained, or that hospitalization or detention in a facility certified for emergency observation and diagnosis is not the least restrictive form of treatment, the psychiatrist, qualified physician, or qualified psychologist shall not admit the person to the hospital or facility as an inpatient and shall facilitate the person’s outpatient treatment through the Department or a provider, as appropriate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Immediately upon the admission of a mentally ill person to a hospital pursuant to this subchapter, the administrator of the hospital shall notify the chief clinical officer of the Department of the admission by telephone, telefax, or electronically. Not later than 24 hours after the admission pursuant to this subchapter, the administrator of the hospital or the chief clinical officer of the Department shall serve notice of the admission to the Commission, the parent or legal guardian of a person under 18 years of age who was admitted pursuant to this subchapter, and, if authorized by the person who was admitted to the hospital or the Department consistent with the provisions of the District of Columbia Mental Health Information Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 2-136">D.C. Law 2-136</cite>; D.C. Official  Code § <cite path="§7-1201.01">7-1201.01</cite> et seq.), to the spouse or domestic partner, parent of an admitted person who is 18 years of age or older, or legal guardian of the person.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-183" type="History">Sept. 14, 1965, 79 Stat. 753, Pub. L. 89-183, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-48" type="History">Feb. 24, 1984, D.C. Law 5-48, § 11(a)(9), 30 DCR 5778</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-283" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-283, § 2(i), 50 DCR 917</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 22(c), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§21-501">21-501</cite>, § <cite path="§21-523">21-523</cite>, and § <cite path="§21-524">21-524</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-522.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 21-522.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-283">D.C. Law 14-283</cite> rewrote the section which had read as follows: “§ <cite path="§21-522">21-522</cite>. Examination and admission to hospital; notice.” “Subject to the provisions of  section 21-523, the administrator of a private hospital, may, and the administrator of a public hospital shall, admit and detain for purposes of emergency observation and diagnosis a person with respect to whom application is made under  section 21-521, if the application is accompanied by a certificate of a psychiatrist or qualified psychologist on duty at the hospital stating that he has examined the person and is of the opinion that he has symptoms of a mental illness and, as a result thereof, is likely to injure himself or others unless he is immediately hospitalized. Not later than 24 hours after the admission pursuant to this subchapter of a person to a hospital, the administrator of the hospital shall serve notice of the admission, by registered mail, to the spouse, parent, or legal guardian of the person and to the Commission on Mental Health.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite>, in subsec. (d), substituted “spouse or domestic partner” for “spouse”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>Section 2(h) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-131">D.C. Law 14-131</cite> amended this section to read as follows:</text>
      <text>“(a) Subject to the provisions of  section 21-523, the administrator of a private hospital may, and the administrator of a public hospital or the chief clinical officer of the Department or his designee shall, admit and detain for purposes of emergency observation and diagnosis a person with respect to whom application is made under  section 21-521, if the application is accompanied by a certificate of a psychiatrist, qualified physician, or qualified psychologist on duty at the hospital or the Department stating that he:</text>
      <text>“(1) Has examined the person;</text>
      <text>“(2) Is of the opinion that the person has symptoms of a mental illness and, because of the mental illness, is likely to injure himself or others unless the person is immediately hospitalized; and</text>
      <text>“(3) Is of the opinion that hospitalization is the least restrictive form of treatment available to prevent the person from injuring himself or others.</text>
      <text>“(b) Subject to the provisions of  section 21-523, the chief clinical officer of the Department shall admit and detain, for purposes of emergency observation and diagnosis at a facility certified by the Department for emergency detention, a person with respect to whom application is made under  section 21-521, if the application is accompanied by a certificate of a psychiatrist, qualified physician, or qualified psychologist on duty at the Department stating that he:</text>
      <text>“(1) Has examined the person;</text>
      <text>“(2) Is of the opinion that the person has symptoms of a mental illness and, because of the mental illness, is likely to injure himself or others unless the person is immediately detained;</text>
      <text>“(3) Is of the opinion that hospitalization is not the least restrictive form of treatment available to ensure that the person will not injure himself or others; and</text>
      <text>“(4) Is of the opinion that detention in a certified facility for observation and diagnosis is the least restrictive treatment alternative to prevent the person from injuring himself or others.</text>
      <text>“(c) If the psychiatrist, qualified physician, or qualified psychologist determines, after examining the person who has been presented for emergency observation and diagnosis, that the person is not mentally ill, not likely to injure himself or others unless immediately detained, or that hospitalization or detention in a facility certified for emergency observation and diagnosis is not the least restrictive form of treatment, the psychiatrist, qualified physician, or qualified psychologist shall not admit the person to the hospital or facility as an inpatient and shall facilitate the person’s outpatient treatment through the Department or a provider, as appropriate.</text>
      <text>“(d) Immediately upon the admission of a mentally ill person to a hospital pursuant to this subchapter, the administrator of the hospital shall notify the chief clinical officer of the Department of the admission by telephone, telefax, or electronically. Not later than 24 hours after the admission pursuant to this subchapter, the administrator of the hospital or the chief clinical officer of the Department shall serve notice of the admission to the spouse, parent, or legal guardian of the person and to the Commission on Mental Health, if authorized by the person who was admitted to the hospital or the Department consistent with the provisions of the District of Columbia Mental Health Information Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 2-136">D.C. Law 2-136</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§7-1201.01">7-1201.01</cite> et seq.).”</text>
      <text>Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-131">D.C. Law 14-131</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(h) of Mental Health Commitment Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-265, January 30, 2002,  49 DCR 1450).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(h) of Mental Health Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-350, April 24, 2002,  49 DCR 4417).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(i) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-546, December 12, 2002,  50 DCR 199).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(i) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-41, March 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2784).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
