<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>21-906</num>
  <heading>Examinations; adjudications; laws applicable; expense of care and treatment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Superintendent of Saint Elizabeths Hospital shall promptly examine a person committed as provided by sections 21-902 and 21-903, and, if not found to have a mental illness, shall forthwith discharge him, or, if found to have a mental illness, shall return him to the State of his residence or to his relatives, if practicable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Proceedings for the adjudication of a person referred to by subsection (a) of this section, or of a person admitted to the hospital pursuant to section 21-904, as a person with a mental illness, and for the appointment of a committee of his person or property, may be instituted in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Secretary of Health and Human Services or by a party interest. The laws of the District of Columbia apply to the proceedings. This chapter does not impose upon the District of Columbia the expense of care and treatment of a person apprehended, detained, or committed under this chapter, unless the person is a resident of the District of Columbia as defined by subsection (b) of section 21-551.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-183" type="History">Sept. 14, 1965, 79 Stat. 765, Pub. L. 89-183, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 568, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 150(f)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104" type="History">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 6(i), 35 DCR 147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 21(d)(6), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§21-904">21-904</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-906.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 21-906.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</law-cite> substituted “found to have a mental illness” for “found to be mentally ill” in (a); and substituted “person with mental illness” for “mentally ill person” in the first sentence of (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</law-cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
