<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1061.07</num>
  <heading>Methods of applying for military-overseas ballot.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A covered voter who is registered to vote in the District may apply for a military-overseas ballot using either the regular absentee ballot application on the form prescribed by the Board or the federal postcard application or the application’s electronic equivalent.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A covered voter who is not registered to vote in the District may use a federal postcard application or the application’s electronic equivalent to apply to register to vote under § <cite path="§1-1061.06">1-1061.06</cite> and for a military-overseas ballot.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Board shall ensure that the electronic transmission system described in § <cite path="§1-1061.04">1-1061.04</cite>(c) is capable of accepting the submission of both a federal postcard application and any other approved electronic military-overseas ballot application sent to the Board. The voter may use the electronic transmission system or any other method approved under federal law to apply for a military-overseas ballot.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A covered voter may use the declaration accompanying a federal write-in absentee ballot as an application for a military-overseas ballot simultaneously with the submission of the federal write-in absentee ballot, if the declaration is received by the Board by the 7th day before the election.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>To receive the benefits of this subchapter, a covered voter must inform the Board that the voter is a covered voter. Methods of informing the Board that a voter is a covered voter include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The use of a federal postcard application or federal write-in absentee ballot;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The use of an overseas address on an approved voter registration application or ballot application; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The inclusion on an approved voter registration application or ballot application of other information sufficient to identify the voter as a covered voter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>This subchapter does not preclude a covered voter from voting with a regular absentee ballot as authorized by the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-137" type="History">June 5, 2012, D.C. Law 19-137, § 107, 59 DCR 2542</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 7 of the Uniform Military and Overseas Voters Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
