<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1001.06a</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Election Reform Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Election Reform Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Board and shall be used for the purpose of implementing the Omnibus Election Reform Amendment Act of 2009 [<cite doc="D.C. Law 18-103">D.C. Law 18-103</cite>]. On or about October 1, 2009, the Chief Financial Officer shall deposit $300,000 into the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (a) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 12, 1955, 69 Stat. 700, ch. 862, § 6a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">as added Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 1051, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-103" type="History">Feb. 4, 2010, D.C. Law 18-103, § 2(d), 56 DCR 9169</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-103">D.C. Law 18-103</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “and shall be used for the purpose of implementing the Omnibus Election Reform Amendment Act of 2009 <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-255">D.C. Law 18-255</cite>” for “and shall be used solely to implement election reform initiatives to be enacted by the Council”; and repealed subsec. (c), which had read as follows: “(c) Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, no funds in the Fund shall be expended until the Council approves, by resolution, a September 2010 primary election preparation plan submitted to the Council by March 31, 2010.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1051 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1051 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1050 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle F of title I of the act may be cited as the “Election Reform Fund Establishment Amendment Act of 2009”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
