<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1061.16</num>
  <heading>Publication of election notice.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>At least 60 days before a regularly scheduled election and as soon as practicable before an election not regularly scheduled, the Board shall prepare an election notice, to be used in conjunction with a federal write-in absentee ballot. The election notice must contain a list of all of the ballot measures and federal and District offices that as of that date the Board expects to be on the ballot on the date of the election. The notice also must contain specific instructions for how a voter is to indicate on the federal write-in absentee ballot the voter’s choice for each office to be filled and for each ballot measure to be contested.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A covered voter may request a copy of an election notice. The Board shall send the election notice to the voter by facsimile, electronic mail, or regular mail, as the voter requests.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No later than 45 days before an election, the Board shall update the election notice described in subsection (a) of this section with the certified candidates for each office and ballot measure questions and make the updated notice publicly available.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board shall make the election notice prepared under subsection (a) of this section and updated versions of the election notice regularly available on the Board’s Internet website.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-137" type="History">June 5, 2012, D.C. Law 19-137, § 116, 59 DCR 2542</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-273" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-273, § 4(f), 62 DCR 1938</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-273">D.C. Law 20-273</cite> substituted “60 days” for “100 days” in (a).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-273">D.C. Law 20-273</cite>, § 5, see § 21 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-76">D.C. Law 21-76</cite>, Feb. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 264).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 16 of the Uniform Military and Overseas Voters Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-273">D.C. Law 20-273</cite>: Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-273">D.C. Law 20-273</cite> provided (a) that the act shall apply upon the date of inclusions of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan; (b) that the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification; and (c) that the Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register and that the date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">The Budget Director of the Council of the District of Columbia has determined that the fiscal effect of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-273">D.C. Law 20-273</cite> has been included in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
