<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1163.13</num>
  <heading>Additional identifications and certifications.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Every political action committee and every independent expenditure committee shall certify, in each report filed with the Director of Campaign Finance, that the contributions it has received and the expenditures it has made have not been controlled or directed by any public official or candidate, by any political committee, or by any political party.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Every independent expenditure committee shall further certify, in each report filed with the Director of Campaign Finance, that it has made no contributions or transfer of funds to any public official or candidate, any political committee, or any political action committee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A business contributor to a political committee, political action committee, or independent expenditure committee shall provide the committee with the identities of the contributor's affiliated entities that have also contributed to the committee.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A business contributor shall comply with all requests from the Office of Campaign Finance to provide information about its individual owners, the identity of affiliated entities, the individual owners of affiliated entities, the contributions or expenditures made by such entities, and any other information the deemed relevant to enforcing the provisions of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any person other than a political committee, political action committee, or independent expenditure committee that makes one or more independent expenditures in an aggregate amount of $50 or more within a calendar year, other than by contribution to a committee or candidate, shall, in a report filed with the Director of Campaign Finance, identify the name and address of the person, identify the person's affiliated entities that have also made an independent expenditure, the amount and object of the expenditures, and the names of any candidates, initiatives, referenda, or recalls in support of or opposition to which the expenditures are directed. The report shall be filed on the dates which reports by committees are filed, unless the value of the independent expenditure totals $1000 or more in a 2-week period, in which case the report shall be filed within 14 days of the independent expenditure.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Statements required by this section shall be filed on the dates on which reports by committees are filed, but the content of the filings need not be cumulative.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Every person who files statements with the Director of Campaign Finance has a continuing obligation to provide the Director with correct and up-to-date information.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History" path="ยง313">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, ยง 313, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-79" type="History">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-79, ยง 2(k), 61 DCR 153</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the latest of: (1) The inclusion of the fiscal effect of the act in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register; or (2) January 31, 2015.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">A certification dated February 4, 2015, that the fiscal effect of the Campaign Finance Reform and Transparency Amendment Act of 2013, <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite>, has been included in an approved budget and financial plan was published in the D.C. Register on March 13, 2015 (62 DCR 2988).</text>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite> rewrote this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
