<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1162.31</num>
  <heading>Prohibited activities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No registrant or anyone acting on behalf of a registrant shall offer, give, or cause to be given a gift or service to an official in the legislative or executive branch or a member of his or her staff that exceeds $100 in value in the aggregate in any calendar year. This section shall not be construed to restrict in any manner contributions authorized in §§ <cite path="§1-1163.33">1-1163.33</cite>, <cite path="§1-1163.34">1-1163.34</cite>, and <cite path="§1-1163.38">1-1163.38</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No official in the legislative or executive branch or a member of his or her staff shall solicit or accept anything of value in violation of subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No person shall knowingly or willfully make or cause to be made any false or misleading statement or misrepresentation of the facts relating to pending administrative decisions or legislative actions to any official in the legislative or executive branch;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No person shall, knowing a document to contain a false statement relating to pending administrative decisions or legislative actions, cause a copy of the document to be transmitted to an official in the legislative or executive branch without notifying the official in writing of the truth.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>No information copied from registration forms and activity reports required by this part or from lists compiled from such forms and reports shall be sold or utilized by any person for the purpose of soliciting campaign contributions or selling tickets to a testimonial or similar fundraising affair or for any commercial purpose.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>No public official shall be employed as a lobbyist while acting as a public official, except as provided in § <cite path="§1-1162.28">1-1162.28</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No lobbyist or registrant or person acting on behalf of the lobbyist or registrant, shall provide legal representation, or other professional services, to an official in the legislative or executive branch, or to a member of his or her staff, at no cost or at a rate that is less than the lobbyist or registrant would routinely bill for the representation or service in the marketplace.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this section, a nonprofit organization that routinely provides legal representation or other services to clients at no cost may provide such representation or services to such client when doing so serves the purposes for which such services are routinely provided.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 231, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-79" type="History">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-79, § 2(c), 61 DCR 153</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite> deleted “and the representation and services are not provided by a lobbyist or registrant” from the end of (g)(2).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the latest of: (1) The inclusion of the fiscal effect of the act in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register; or (2) January 31, 2015.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">A certification dated February 4, 2015, that the fiscal effect of the Campaign Finance Reform and Transparency Amendment Act of 2013, <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite>, has been included in an approved budget and financial plan was published in the D.C. Register on March 13, 2015 (62 DCR 2988).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
