<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1163.36</num>
  <heading>Prohibition on the use of District government resources for campaign-related activities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No resources of the District of Columbia government, including the expenditure of funds, the personal services of employees during their hours of work, and nonpersonal services, including supplies, materials, equipment, office space, facilities, and telephones and other utilities, shall be used to support or oppose any candidate for elected office, whether partisan or nonpartisan, or to support or oppose any initiative, referendum, or recall measure, including a charter amendment referendum conducted in accordance with § <cite path="§1-203.03">1-203.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>This section shall not prohibit the Chairman and members of the Council, the Mayor, the Attorney General, or the President and members of the State Board of Education from expressing their views on a District of Columbia election as part of their official duties.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall not be construed to authorize any member of the staff of the Chairman and members of the Council, the Mayor, the Attorney General, or the President and members of the State Board of Education, or any other employee of the executive or legislative branch to engage in any activity to support or oppose any candidate for elected office, whether partisan or nonpartisan, an initiative, referendum, or recall measure during their hours of work, or the use of any nonpersonal services, including supplies, materials, equipment, office space, facilities, telephones and other utilities, to support or oppose an initiative, referendum, or recall matter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 336, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-60">Dec. 13, 2013, D.C. Law 20-60, § 302(e), 60 DCR 15487</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-60">D.C. Law 20-60</cite> substituted “the Chairman and members of the Council, the Mayor, the Attorney General” for “the Mayor, the Chairman and members of the Council” in (b)(1); and substituted “the Mayor, the Chairman and members of the Council” for “the Chairman and members of the Council, the Mayor, the Attorney General in (b)(2).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3(e) of the Election Code Conforming Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-143, July 31, 2013,  60 DCR 11799, 20 DCSTAT 1990).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-60">D.C. Law 20-60</cite>: Section 401(b) of 20-60 provided that § 302 of the act shall apply as of December 13, 2013.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
