<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1162.02</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the District of Columbia Board of Ethics and Government Accountability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a District of Columbia Board of Ethics and Government Accountability, whose purpose shall be to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Administer and enforce the Code of Conduct;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Appoint a Director of the Open Government Office;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Appoint a Director of the Ethics Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Receive, investigate, and adjudicate violations of the Code of Conduct;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Conduct mandatory training on the Code of Conduct;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Produce ethics training materials, including summary guidelines for all applicable laws and regulations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Produce a plain-language ethics guide;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Issue rules and regulations governing the ethical conduct of employees and public officials; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Establish an anonymous and confidential telephone hotline for the purpose of receiving information related to violations of the Code of Conduct or other information with regard to the administration or enforcement of the Code of Conduct.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Ethics Board shall conduct a detailed assessment of ethical guidelines and requirements for employees and public officials to include a review of national best practices of government ethics law, and produce, within 240 days of April 27, 2012, recommendations for amending the Code of Conduct. Thereafter, the Ethics Board shall submit recommendations on December 31 of each year. The recommendations shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Whether to adopt local laws that are similar in nature to federal ethics laws;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Whether to adopt post-employment restrictions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Whether to adopt ethics laws pertaining to contracting and procurement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Whether to adopt nepotism and cronyism prohibitions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Whether to criminalize violations of ethics laws;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Whether to expel a member of the Council for certain violations of the Code of Conduct;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Whether to regulate campaign contributions from affiliated or subsidiary corporations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Any other matter as determined by the Ethics Board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History" path="§202">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 202, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-1161.01">1-1161.01</cite>, § <cite path="§1-1162.21">1-1162.21</cite>, and § <cite path="§1-1171.01">1-1171.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 1073 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 1073 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 1073 of Law 19-168 provided that any matter arising after January 29, 2012, from a violation of Title I, Subtitle C of the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2012, effective January 29, 2012 (D.C. Act 19-298;  59 DCR 683), or Title II, Subtitle C of the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Amendment Act of 2012, effective April 27, 2012 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-124">D.C. Law 19-124</law-cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§1-1161.01">1-1161.01</cite> et seq.), may be enforced by the Elections Board until October 1, 2012, after which pending matters shall be transferred to the Ethics Board for enforcement.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
