<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1164.01</num>
  <heading>Transition provisions; applicability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subchapter II, parts A and B, of this chapter shall apply as of April 27, 2012, except that neither the Ethics Board or the Director of Government Ethics shall receive, investigate, or adjudicate violations of the Code of Conduct, or issue advisory opinions, conduct ethics training, or issue ethics manuals until October 1, 2012.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subchapter II, part C, of this chapter shall apply as of April 27, 2012, except that the delivery of statements required by § <cite path="§1-1162.23">1-1162.23</cite>(c)(2)(C) shall be delivered to the Elections Board until October 1, 2012. The Elections Board shall enforce subchapter II, part C, of this chapter until October 1, 2012, after which pending matters shall be transferred to the Ethics Board for enforcement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subchapter II, part D, of this chapter shall apply as of October 1, 2012, except that the Office of Campaign Finance shall administer and enforce the subchapter, including receiving and reviewing the necessary disclosures, until January 1, 2013.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subchapter II, part E, of this chapter shall apply as of April 27, 2012, except that the enforcement of the provisions of part E shall be enforced by the Office of Campaign Finance until October 1, 2012.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subchapter III, parts A and B, of this chapter shall apply as of April 27, 2012.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Subchapter III, part C, of this chapter shall apply as of October 1, 2012.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Subchapter III, part D, of this chapter shall apply as of April 27, 2012.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Subchapter III, part E, of this chapter shall apply as of April 27, 2012.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>Subchapter III, part F, of this chapter shall apply as of April 27, 2012.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>Reserved.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>Reserved.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>This subchapter shall apply as of April 27, 2012.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(m)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History" path="§601">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 601, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 1072(d), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 7010, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added the second sentence in (b); and added “except that the Office of Campaign Finance shall administer and enforce the subchapter, including receiving and reviewing the necessary disclosures, until January 1, 2013” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> repealed (m).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7010e, see § 2(j) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-179">D.C. Law 20-179</cite>, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-371, May 16, 2012,  59 DCR 5711).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 3 of Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-371, May 16, 2012,  59 DCR 5711).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1072(d) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1072(d) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (225 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7010e, see § 2(j) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-179">D.C. Law 20-179</cite>, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7010e of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7010e, and amendment of this section, see § 2(k) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014, 61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7010e of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7010e, and amendment of this section, see § 2(k) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7016(m) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
