<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1162.13</num>
  <heading>Formal investigation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A formal investigation shall be initiated upon:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Receipt of a written complaint transmitted to the Ethics Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A finding by the Office of the Inspector General or District of Columbia Auditor of waste, fraud, abuse of government resources, or a violation of the Code of Conduct; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A finding by a court of competent jurisdiction of liability in a civil proceeding, indictment, or information in a criminal proceeding with respect to acts or offenses that may constitute violations of the Code of Conduct or of this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A written complaint shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The full name and address of the complainant and the respondent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A clear and concise statement of facts that are alleged to constitute a violation of the Code of Conduct or of this subchapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The complainant’s signature;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A verification of the complaint under oath; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Supporting documentation, if any.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No complaint may be made under this subchapter later than 5 years after the discovery of the alleged violation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An individual making a complaint shall be afforded all available protections from adverse employment action or retaliation in accordance with Chapter 6 of  this title and subchapter XII of Chapter 2 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-223.01">2-223.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Within 30 business days of the initiation of a formal investigation, the Director of Government Ethics shall cause evidence concerning the complaint to be presented to the Ethics Board, with the potential for a 15-business-day extension to be granted by the Ethics Board. If the Ethics Board decides that there is reasonable belief that a violation has occurred, the Ethics Board may authorize the issuance of subpoenas.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 213, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-122" type="History">July 15, 2014, D.C. Law 20-122, § 2(e), 61 DCR 5688</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-1162.14">1-1162.14</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-122">D.C. Law 20-122</cite>, in (e), substituted “30 business days” for “15 business days” and added “with the potential for a 15-business-day extension to be granted by the Ethics Board.”</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  2(e) of the Comprehensive Code of Conduct and BEGA Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-323, Apr. 28, 2014, 61 DCR 4681).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
