<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1162.25</num>
  <heading>Confidential disclosure of financial interest.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any employee, other than a public official, who advises, makes decisions or participates substantially in areas of contracting, procurement, administration of grants or subsidies, developing policies, land use planning, inspecting, licensing, policy-making, regulating, or auditing, or acts in areas of responsibility that may create a conflict of interest or appearance of a conflict of interest, as determined by the appropriate agency head, shall file, before May 15th of each year, with that agency head a report containing a full and complete statement of the information required by § <cite path="§1-1162.24">1-1162.24</cite>. Members of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Board of Directors appointed pursuant to § <cite path="§9-1107.01">9-1107.01</cite> shall file the report required by this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon review of the confidential report, any violation of the Code of Conduct found by the agency head shall be forwarded immediately to the Ethics Board for review.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>On or before April 15th of each year, each agency head shall designate the persons in the agency required to submit a confidential report by name, position, and grade level, and shall supply this list to the Ethics Board and the D.C. Ethics Counselor on or before May 1st of each year.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History" path="§225">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 225, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 1072(b), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-286" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-286, § 3(c), 60 DCR 2319</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 1152(b), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-618.01">1-618.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> substituted “May 15th” for “October 2nd” in the first sentence of (a); and in (c), substituted “April 15th” for “September 1st” and “May 1st” for “September 15th.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-286">D.C. Law 19-286</cite> added “and members of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Board of Directors appointed pursuant to § <cite path="§9-1107.01">9-1107.01</cite>” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> substituted “members of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Board of Directors” for “Advisory Neighborhood Commissioners and members of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Board of Directors” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-57">D.C. Law 20-57</cite>, December 13, 2013,  60 DCR 15168).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1072(b) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 1074 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1072(b) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 1074 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-364, June 23, 2014, 61 DCR 6765).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1152(b) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1152(b) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1152(b) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 1074 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> provided that § 1072(a) and (b) of the act [which amended §§ <cite path="§1-1162.24">1-1162.24</cite>(c) and <cite path="§1-1162.25">1-1162.25</cite>] shall apply as of January 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
