<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1163.15</num>
  <heading>Identification of campaign literature.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All newspaper or magazine advertising, posters, circulars, billboards, handbills, bumper stickers, sample ballots, initiative, referendum, or recall petitions, and other printed matter with reference to or intended for the support or defeat of a candidate or group of candidates for nomination or election to any public office, or for the support or defeat of any initiative, referendum, or recall measure, shall be identified by the words “paid for by” followed by the name and address of the payer or the committee or other person and its treasurer on whose behalf the material appears.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each committee and candidate shall include on the face or front page of all literature and advertisement soliciting funds the following notice:</text>
    <text>“A copy of our report is filed with the Director of Campaign Finance of the District of Columbia Board of Elections.”.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any advertisement supporting or opposing a candidate, initiative, referendum, or recall that is disseminated to the public by a political committee, political action committee, or independent expenditure committee or any other person shall disclose, in the advertisement, the identity of the advertisement's sponsor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 315, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-79" type="History">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-79, § 2(l), 61 DCR 153</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite> added (c).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the latest of: (1) The inclusion of the fiscal effect of the act in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register; or (2) January 31, 2015.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">A certification dated February 4, 2015, that the fiscal effect of the Campaign Finance Reform and Transparency Amendment Act of 2013, <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite>, has been included in an approved budget and financial plan was published in the D.C. Register on March 13, 2015 (62 DCR 2988).</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
