<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1321</num>
  <heading>Examination of subdivision dimensions; recording of subdivision.</heading>
  <text>At the request of the proprietor the Surveyor shall examine whether the lots or parcels into which any square or lot may be subdivided as provided in § <cite path="§1-1320">1-1320</cite> agree in dimensions with the whole of the square or lot so intended to be subdivided, and whether the dimensions expressed on the plat of subdivision be the true dimensions of the parts so expressed; and whether said lots or parcels conform to the general orders of the Council of the District of Columbia made under existing law or under authority of § <cite path="§1-1313">1-1313</cite>; and if upon such examination he shall find the plat correct he shall certify the same under his hand and seal to the Mayor with such remarks as appear to him necessary; but no such plat or subdivision shall be admitted to record in the Office of the Surveyor without an order to that effect, indorsed thereon by said Mayor.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 56-2-ch854" path="§1582">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1425, ch. 854, § 1582</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 30, 1902, 32 Stat. 544, ch. 1329</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-621.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-921.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
