<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-141</num>
  <heading>Findings.</heading>
  <text>The Council of the District of Columbia finds that:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Section 2 of a joint resolution to codify and emphasize existing rules and customs pertaining to the display and use of the flag of the United States of America (36 U.S.C. § 174) [revised; now see 4 U.S.C. § 6] addresses the method, time, and places for the display of the United States flag:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The flag should be hoisted briskly and lowered ceremoniously.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>It is the universal custom to display the flag only from sunrise to sunset on buildings and stationary flagstaffs in the open. When a patriotic effect is desired, however, the flag may be displayed 24 hours a day if properly illuminated during the hours of darkness.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The flag should not be displayed on days when the weather is inclement, except when an all-weather flag is displayed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>The flag should be displayed on all days, especially on those days designated as federal and state holidays.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>The flag should be displayed daily on or near the main administration building of every public institution.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>The flag should be displayed in or near every polling place on election days.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>The flag should be displayed during school days in or near every schoolhouse.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The display of the District of Columbia flag will inculcate a spirit of patriotism in our citizens.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-121" type="History" path="§2">July 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-121, § 2, 29 DCR 2072</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-121.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) establishment of advisory commission, see § 2 of Flag Design Advisory Commission Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-424, July 17, 2002,  49 DCR 7627).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) establishment of a Flag Design Advisory Commission, see § 2 of Flag Design Advisory Commission Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-538, December 2, 2002,  49 DCR 11653).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) establishment of the Flag Design Advisory Commission, see § 2 of Flag Design Advisory Commission Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-6, January 27, 2003,  50 DCR 1455).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
