<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1402</num>
  <heading>Purpose.</heading>
  <text>The purpose of the Office is to centralize responsibility for the District government’s investments in information technology and telecommunications systems to help District departments and agencies provide services more efficiently and effectively.  The Office will develop and enforce policy directives and standards regarding information technology and telecommunications systems throughout the District government.  The Office will also serve as a source of expertise for District departments and agencies seeking to use information technology and telecommunications systems to improve services. In addition, the Office may work to ensure that reasonable, affordable access to high-speed Internet services is available to District residents and businesses.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175" type="History" path="§1813">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1813, 45 DCR 7193</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 1042(a), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-1406">1-1406</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1195.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</law-cite> added the last sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of §§ 1-1195.1 to 1-1195.5 1981 Ed., see note to § 1-1401.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of Chapter 11B 1981 Ed., see notes following § 1-1401.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1042(a) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1041 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</law-cite> provided that subtitle E of title I of the act may be cited as the “Technology Services Amendment Act of 2010”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Establishment of Geographic Information System Steering Committee, see Mayor’s Order 2002-27, February 15, 2002 ( 49 DCR 1298).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
