<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1403</num>
  <heading>Functions.</heading>
  <text>The functions assigned to the Office shall be to:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Issue regulations governing the acquisition, use, and management of information technology and telecommunications systems and resources throughout the District government, including hardware, software, and contract services in the areas of data and word processing, telecommunications, printing and copying;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Review and approve all agency proposals, purchase orders, and contracts for the acquisition of information technology and telecommunications systems, resources, and services, and recommend approval or disapproval to the Chief Procurement Officer;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Review and approve the information technology and telecommunications budgets for District government department and agencies;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Coordinate the development of information management plans, standards, systems, and procedures throughout the District government, including the development of an information technology strategic plan for the District;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Assess new or emerging technologies and advise District department and agencies on the potential applications of these technologies to their programs and services;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Implement information technology solutions and systems throughout the District government;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Promote the compatibility of information technology and telecommunications systems throughout the District government;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Serve as a resource and provide advice to District departments and agencies about how to use information technology and telecommunications systems to improve services, including assistance to departments and agencies in developing information technology strategic plans;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Maintain and oversee all District data centers, including, but not limited to, the SHARE, Department of Human Services, Department of Employment Services, University of the District of Columbia, Metropolitan Police Department, Public Benefits Corporation, Saint Elizabeths, Department of Health, and District of Columbia Public Schools data centers; provided, that this paragraph shall not apply to the Department of Motor Vehicles;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Review the use of landlines, wireless phone lines, and data for which the District pays for telecommunication services and decertify and disconnect such services whenever not in active use; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Require District agencies to annually re-certify all inventory in the fixed cost management system of active landlines, wireless phone lines, and data circuits.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The Office may:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Disconnect landlines in favor of wireless devices and vice versa based on usage analysis and in consultation with agency directors; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Review and reject any requests for telecommunication services that do not comply with the technology standards of the Office.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The Office shall not impose any requirement, determination, or decision concerning, or otherwise interfere with, the telecommunications inventory of the Council unless the Council specifically consents;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>Developing and implementing solutions designed to ensure that residents and businesses in all areas of the District have reasonable, affordable access to high-speed Internet services; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>In furtherance of paragraph (10) of this section, obtaining and expending federal grant funds for digital inclusion efforts and awarding sub-grants to nonprofit entities established in the District for the purpose of supporting digital inclusion efforts by such entities, including the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Providing computer literacy training;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Providing free or low-cost computers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Developing new online content;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Conducting public outreach concerning the use, availability, and benefits of computers and the Internet; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Similar efforts to enhance the accessibility, usability, affordability, and perceived value of computers and the Internet among under-served populations of the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175" type="History" path="§1814">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1814, 45 DCR 7193</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 2103(a), 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 632, 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 117, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 177, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 1031, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 1042(b), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 1012, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1042(b) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1031 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1031 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 632 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 632 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2103(a) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2103(a) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 4 of the Chief Technology Officer Year 2000 Remediation Procurement Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-106, July 9, 1999,  46 DCR 6028).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of Chapter 11B 1981 Ed., see notes following <cite path="§1-1401">§ 1-1401</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 4 of the Chief Technology Officer Year 2000 Remediation Procurement Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-38, March 22, 1999,  46 DCR 3015).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of §§ <cite path="§1-1195.1" proof="true">1-1195.1</cite> to <cite path="§1-1195.5" proof="true">1-1195.5</cite> 1981 Ed., see note to <cite path="§1-1401">§ 1-1401</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of the Chief Technology Officer Year 2000 Remediation Procurement Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-17">D.C. Law 13-17</cite>, July 17, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 6314).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>, in par. (10)(C), deleted “and” from the end; in par. (11), substituted “; and” for a period; and added par. (12).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in par. (9), deleted “and” from the end; substituted “; and” for a period at the end of par. (10), and added par. (11).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> deleted “; and” from the end of par. (8); substituted “; and” for a period at the end of par. (9); and added par. (10).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in par. (8).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in par. (8), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite>, in par. (9), inserted “; provided, that this paragraph shall not apply to the Department of Motor Vehicles” before the period.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite> deleted “and” from the end of par. (7), substituted a semicolon for a period at the end of subsec. (8), and added par. (9).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1195.3.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-1406">§ 1-1406</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1011 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle B of title I of the act may be cited as “Digital Inclusion Grant-making Amendment Act of 2011”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1030 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle D of title I of the act may be cited as the “Telecommunication Accountability Amendment Act of 2009”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle D of title VI of Law 15-39: Section 631 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite> provided that subtitle D of title VI of the act may be cited as the Department of Motor Vehicles Destiny Staffing Amendment Act of 2003.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
