<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" enacted="false">
  <num>1-1506.01</num>
  <heading>Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1983</heading>
  <text>(Effective March 31, 1983).
Statute text</text>
  <text>Prepared by the Mayor and transmitted to the Council of the District of Columbia on January 3, 1983, pursuant to the provisions of Section 422 (12) of the District Charter. 
DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEPARTMENT 
OF CONSUMER AND REGULATORY 
AFFAIRS</text>
  <text class="centered">
    <span style="font-style: italic; ">I. Establishment</span>
  </text>
  <text>There is hereby established, in the Executive Branch of the Government of the District of Columbia, under the supervision of a Director, a Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Director of the existing Department of Licenses, Investigations and Inspections, or if confirmation of said Director by the Council is still pending, the Acting Director of the existing Department of Licenses, Investigations and Inspections, shall be the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs upon the effective date of this plan (or the Acting Director if the confirmation process is still pending), and shall serve without the necessity of a new Council confirmation process.</text>
  <text class="centered">
    <span style="font-style: italic; ">II. Purpose</span>
  </text>
  <text>The mission of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs is to protect the health, safety and welfare of the citizens of the District of Columbia by regulation of business activities, land and building use, professional conduct and standards, rental housing and condominiums, health and social service care facilities, and the physical environment of the District of Columbia.</text>
  <text class="centered">
    <span style="font-style: italic; ">III. Functions</span>
  </text>
  <text>A. The functions of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs shall be:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Regulation of certain professional and occupational practices by individuals designated for licensing in the District, by means of registration, examination, approval of qualification, and complaint investigation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Maintenance of a fair and equitable insurance market for citizens of the District through financial surveillance of companies, licensing, rate regulation, and complaint investigation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Protection of the public from illegal, unfair or dangerous commercial practices by means of registration and licensing of businesses and/or individuals and assuring their compliance with all applicable legal requirements.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Assurance that the physical environment and structure of all buildings in the District of Columbia meet all applicable regulations and codes for preservation or the use to which the space or structure is to be put; assurance that public and private land and structures meet adequate health, safety and environmental standards.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Protection of the public through the regulation of rental housing, condominium and cooperative conversions and sales, and assurance of compliance with legislated housing standards and health, safety and sanitation standards for neighborhoods.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Assurance of public and private health and social services standards of safety and care for clients and consumers, by means of registration, licensing and certification of facilities and investigation of complaints.</text>
  </para>
  <text>B. The following functions are hereby transferred to the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to the Department of Licenses, Investigations and Inspections, as established pursuant to Commissioner's Order No. 69-96, dated March 7, 1969, as amended by Mayor's Order 78-42, dated February 17, 1978, and Reorganization Order No. 1 of 1982, dated July 6, 1982.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to the Office of Consumer Protection, established pursuant to D.C. Code, sec. 28-3902 (2001 Ed.).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to the Rental Accommodations Office, established pursuant to D.C. Code, sec. 45-1514 (1981 Ed.).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to the Department of Insurance, established pursuant to Reorganization Order No. 43, dated June 23, 1953, as amended.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to the Office of Licensing and Certification, as identified in Departmental Organization Order No. 50, dated October 1, 1982, (superseding Departmental Organization Order No. 5, dated February 21, 1980) of the Department of Human Services, established pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, dated June 20, 1980.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to the Housing Regulation Division of the Neighborhood Improvement Administration as identified in Departmental Order No. 76-5, dated February 20, 1970, including the functional statement related to the Housing Regulation Division attached thereto, approved February 20, 1976, as amended by Departmental Order No. 76-5A, dated January 6, 1977, Departmental Order No. 76-5B, dated January 19, 1978, Departmental Order No. 76-5C, dated August 18, 1978, and the functions of the Neighborhood Improvement Administration contained in Departmental Organization Order No. 77-25, dated October 18, 1977, without restriction, notwithstanding the provisions of Part II of said Order, other than the function of approving rehabilitation loans and grants and deferred payment loans, of the Department of Housing and Community Development, established pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1975, dated March 8, 1975.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to condominium and cooperative conversion and sales conducted by the Department of Housing and Community Development including the functions identified in Departmental Order No. 76-5, dated February 20, 1970, and Departmental Order No. 79-5, dated March 9, 1979, of the Department of Housing and Community Development, established pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1975, dated March 8, 1975.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>All of the functions of the Office of Policy and Planning related to historic preservation, as identified in the functional statement dated March 24, 1976, attached to Departmental Order No. 76-13, dated April 26, 1976, of the Department of Housing and Community Development, established pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1975, dated March 8, 1975.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to the Bureau of Environmental Health of the Office of Environmental Standards and Quality Assurance, as identified in Departmental Order No. 10-12-10, dated August 25, 1982, of the Department of Environmental Services, established pursuant to Commissioner's Order No. 71-255, dated July 27, 1971.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to the Bureau of Community Hygiene as identified in Departmental Order No. 10-12-09 (Revised), dated July 21, 1976, of the Department of Environmental Services, established pursuant to Commissioner's Order No. 71-255, dated July 27, 1971.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to flooding, erosion and sediment control, as identified in Mayor's Order No. 76-139, dated July 23, 1976, as amended by Mayor's Order No. 76-220, dated November 3, 1976, and Departmental Order No. 10-12-30 (Revised), dated March 3, 1982, of the Department of Environmental Services established pursuant to Commissioner's Order No. 71-255, dated July 27, 1971.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>All of the functions related to partnerships and corporations of the Office of the Recorder of Deeds, identified in Paragraphs B, D, E, and G of Part I and, Paragraphs C and D of Part IV of Organization Order No. 101 - Replacement, Commissioners' Order 63-197, dated January 24, 1963, as amended.</text>
  </para>
  <text class="centered">
    <span style="font-style: italic; ">IV. Transfers</span>
  </text>
  <text>All positions, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the duties and functions assigned herein, are hereby transferred to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  <text class="centered">
    <span style="font-style: italic; ">V. Organization</span>
  </text>
  <text>The Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs is authorized to organize the personnel and property transferred herein within any organizational unit of the Department as the Director deems appropriate.</text>
  <text class="centered">
    <span style="font-style: italic; ">VI. Abolishment</span>
  </text>
  <text>The following agencies of the District of Columbia government are hereby abolished:</text>
  <text>The Department of Licenses, Investigations and Inspections</text>
  <text>The Rental Accommodations Office</text>
  <text>The Department of Insurance</text>
  <text>The Office of Consumer Protection</text>
  <text class="centered">
    <span style="font-style: italic; ">VII. Effective Date</span>
  </text>
  <text>This Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1983 shall become effective in accordance with Section 422 (12) of Public Law 93-198, or on a date thereafter to be designated pursuant to executive order of the Mayor.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>2001 Ed., Title 1, Chapter 15, Subchapter VI, Part A.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
