<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1514.01</num>
  <heading>Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1996</heading>
  <text>(Effective July 17, 1996).
Statute text</text>
  <text>Prepared by the Mayor and transmitted to the Council of the District of Columbia on May 24, 1996, pursuant to section 422(12) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act of 1973, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 770; D.C. Code, sec. 1-242(12) [ยง 1-204.22]); the Governmental Reorganization Procedures Act of 1981, effective October 17, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-42; D.C. Code sec. 1-299.1 [ยง 1-315.01] et seq.) and the Department of Public Health Establishment Act of 1992, effective March 13, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-182; D.C. Code, sec. 6-131 [ยง 7-151] et seq.).</text>
  <text class="centered">I. ESTABLISHMENT</text>
  <text>There is hereby established, in the Executive Branch of the government of the District of Columbia ("District"), under the supervision of the Director, a Department of Health ("Department"). The Director shall have full authority over the Department and all functions and personnel assigned thereto, including the power to re-delegate to other employees and officials of the Department such powers and authority as, in the Director's judgment, are warranted in the interests of efficiency and sound administration.</text>
  <text class="centered">II. PURPOSE</text>
  <text>The mission of the Department is to ensure the provision of high quality health services by establishing District-wide health policy and standards and guidelines for safe and quality health service delivery; foster and promote health education and disease prevention; structure an efficient and cost-effective health care financing system; implement, monitor and evaluate the Department's strategic health plan and the District-wide health plan; and undertake activities that will support the highest quality of life achievable for District residents and visitors.</text>
  <text class="centered">III. ORGANIZATION</text>
  <text>There are hereby established in the Department: (1) the Office of the Director, with such subordinate staff offices as are required to carry out overall management responsibility for the Department; (2) the Finance and Administration Offices, with such subordinate staff offices as are required to coordinate and manage the financial and administrative functions for the Department; (3) the Health Regulation Administration, to develop the District-wide health plan, assure quality management and compliance with applicable federal and District rules that govern public health systems, license health care and social service professionals; regulate occupational and professional conduct and standards, health care and social service facilities and ensure compliance with applicable federal and District rules that govern uses and practices that affect the physical environment; (4) the State Health Affairs Administration, to fulfill state agency functions in the areas of maternal and child health, ambulatory, long term and preventive health care; (5) the Health Care Finance Administration, to administer the Medicaid program, Medical Charities Program and develop service coverage, service delivery and reimbursement policies for the District government's health care financing programs; (6) the Addiction, Prevention and Recovery Administration, to coordinate the administer drug and substance abuse prevention and treatment programs and services; and (7) the HIV/Aids Administration, to coordinate programs and support services for Human Immuno-deficiency Virus (HIV) and Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS).</text>
  <text class="centered">IV. ACTIONS</text>
  <text>A. The functions of the major organizational components of the Department shall be to:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Plan and evaluate the delivery of comprehensive health care services for District residents and visitors;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Provide services to promote good health, reduce morbidity and mortality resulting from major preventable hazards and diseases;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Provide treatment, rehabilitation and substance abuse prevention services to residents of the District and services to identify substance abusers;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Provide nutritious foods and nutrition education to eligible infants, children, mothers and the elderly;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Develop a District-wide health plan and issue certificates of need for new facilities and services in accordance with the health plan;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Provide educational services and oversee the delivery of medical services to combat the spread of AIDS;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Administer the District government's Medicaid and Medical Charities programs;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Regulate occupational and professional conduct, health care and social services facilities, and ensure compliance with applicable federal and District rules that govern uses and practices that affect the physical environment;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Administer the school health program in elementary and secondary schools;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>Administer the provision of long term care services;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>Determine the level of care for placement of individuals in nursing home and community residential facilities;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>Administer the District government's Nurse Aide Program and Personal Care Aide Training, Competency, Evaluation and Certificate Programs;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>Provide information on sexually-transmitted diseases and prevention services;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>Coordinate the development and implementation of health care policies and procedures and oversee the establishment of health care and quality assurance standards;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>Advocate and communicate broad health policy on behalf of the Executive for inclusion in legislation and to serve as a guide for resource allocation determinations and service delivery decisions by private sector providers;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>Establish and promote public/private sector partnerships and consumer participation that fosters the systematic and integrated delivery of comprehensive health services;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>Monitor and evaluate operations to ensure management accountability within the Department; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(18)</num>
    <text>Develop, coordinate and monitor the delivery of quality medical services to clients of the Department of Human Development.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The functions of the office of the Director shall be to provide direction and ensure the coordination of operating Administration, review policy developed by the Department's administration and oversee compliance with statutes and rules that pertain to the operations of the Department and programs administered by the Department. The Office of the Director shall supervise the following staff offices:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Office of the General Counsel, which shall review legal matters pertaining to the Department and its programs, analyze existing or proposed federal or local legislation and rules, manage the development of new legislation and rules and coordinate legal services to the Department and the representation of the Department with the Office of the Corporation Counsel [now Attorney General for the District of Columbia].</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Office of the Medical Examiner, which shall conduct investigations of homicides, suicides, accidental and drug-related deaths to determine the cause of death.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The State Center for Health Policy and Statistics, which shall administer the District's government vital records system, provide comprehensive health needs assessment, policy development and implementation, and program research and evaluation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>The Office of Emergency Health and Medical Services, which shall oversee the development and delivery of emergency health care by coordinating government and community resources.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The functions of the Finance and Administration Offices are to coordinate and manage the financial and administrative function of the Department under the supervision of the Director. The Office of the Director also shall supervise the following three offices:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Office of the Controller, which shall coordinate the analysis, development, and presentation of the Department's budget, monitor expenditures and enter all financial transactions into the financial management system.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Office of Contracts, Procurement and Grants, which shall coordinate and effect the purchases of goods and services of the Department, by reviewing and processing contracts, procurements and grants.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Office of Facilities Management, which shall assure that the Department has adequate, efficient and cost-effective facilities, administrative, printing and graphic services.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <text class="centered">V. TRANSFER OF FUNCTIONS</text>
  <para>
    <num>(A)</num>
    <text>The following functions are hereby transferred to the Department of Health:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each of the functions assigned, and authorities delegated to the Director of the Department of Human Services as set forth in Sections III.(K), (L), and (P), of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986, dated January 3, 1987; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The administrative and management support functions in the Department of Human Services as set forth in Sections III.(A), (B), (C), (D), (E), and (F), of Reorganization Plan no. 3 of 1986, dated January 3, 1987, that relate to the functions set forth in Section V.(A)(I) above. [(A)(I) of this section.]</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <text class="centered">VI. OTHER TRANSFERS</text>
  <text>All positions, personnel, property, records and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available that relate to the functions set forth under Section V. above, are hereby transferred to the Department.</text>
  <text class="centered">VII. REORGANIZATION</text>
  <text>The Director of the Department is authorized to organize the personnel and property transferred herein within any organizational unit of the Department as the Director deems appropriate. Until such establishment, existing Orders establishing the components of the Commission of Public Health remain in force, where they do not conflict with this Plan.</text>
  <text class="centered">VIII. EFFECTIVE DATE</text>
  <text>This Reorganization Plan No. 4 in all its parts shall become effective pursuant to the promulgation of an executive order of the Mayor establishing the same, which shall be issued no later than thirty (30) calendar days after this plan has been approved in accordance with the requirements of Section 422(12) of the Home Rule Act (D.C. Code, sec. 1-242(12) [ยง 1-204.22(12)].</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>2001 Ed., Title 1, Chapter 15, Subchapter XIV, Part A.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
