<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1501.01</num>
  <heading>Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1975</heading>
  <text>(21 DCR 3198; 22 DCR 961; Effective July 25, 1975).Statute text</text>
  <text>Prepared by the Mayor and transmitted to the Council of the District of Columbia April 29, 1975, pursuant to the provisions of Section 422(12) of the District Charter.</text>
  <text class="centered">
    <em>Department of Transportation</em>
  </text>
  <text class="centered">i. establishment</text>
  <text>There is established, under the direction and control of the Mayor, a Department of Transportation headed by a Director. The Director shall have full authority over such Department and all functions and personnel assigned thereto, including the power to redelegate to other employees and officials of the Department such powers as in the Director's judgment are warranted in the interest of efficiency and good administration. All authority vested in the Director shall be exercised in accordance with applicable laws, rules and regulations.</text>
  <para>
    <num>ii.</num>
    <heading>purpose</heading>
    <text>The Department of Transportation is charged with assisting the Mayor to assure the provision of a safe and adequate transportation system for residents and visitors to the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>iii.</num>
    <heading>functions</heading>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Transportation shall:</text>
    <text>A. Plan, program, construct, operate and maintain public transportation facilities and systems to meet transportation needs within the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>B. Identify financial resources to be applied to transportation programs, and develop a plan for allocation of those resources among those programs.</text>
    <text>C. Develop policies relating to transportation facilities not owned by the District of Columbia, e.g., mass transit, taxicab, aviation, transportation terminals; and coordinate those policies with agencies, public and private, which operate and regulate those facilities.</text>
    <text>D. Analyze transportation programs for their impact on the social and physical environment, including land use and development; develop ways and means to mitigate undesirable impact and implement environmental programs.</text>
    <text>E. Promulgate safety standards relating to the licensing and inspection of vehicles, including aircraft and watercraft, and licensing, testing and training of vehicle operators, to the extent those matters fall within the jurisdiction of the District of Columbia; and the operation of programs for the administration of those standards.</text>
    <text>F. Develop highway safety standards, including those relating to bicyclists and pedestrians, and implement safety standards in the District of Columbia streets and highways program.</text>
    <text>G. Cooperatively with the Municipal Planning Office, coordinate District of Columbia transportation plans and programs and maintain liaison with metropolitan area governments, the Council of Government, the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, Federal agencies, and appropriate public and private groups involved in transportation.</text>
    <text>H. Cooperatively with the Municipal Planning Office, coordinate transportation plans and programs with the programs of other District of Columbia departments and agencies to assure consistency with all appropriate goals and objectives of the government.</text>
    <text>I. Develop parking policies and the operation of parking programs assigned to the department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>iv.</num>
    <heading>transfer of functions</heading>
    <text>The following are hereby transferred to the Department of Transportation:</text>
    <text>A. The functions related to the Department of Motor Vehicles as set forth in C.O. 73-238, Replacement of Organizational Order No. 105, dated October 12, 1973.</text>
    <text>B. The functions related to the Department of Motor Vehicles as set forth in C.O. 73-144, Delegation of Authority Regarding Regulation Providing Special Parking Privileges for Handicapped Drivers, dated June 15, 1973.</text>
    <text>C. The functions related to the Department of Motor Vehicles as set forth in C.O. 74-77, Delegation of Authority Regarding Development of a Plan to Implement the Provisions of Highway Safety Standard 316, Debris Hazard Control and Cleanup, dated May 10, 1974.</text>
    <text>D. The functions related to the Department of Motor Vehicles as set forth in C.O. 74-172, Delegation of Authority Regarding the Regulation of Slow-Moving Vehicles, dated August 1, 1974.</text>
    <text>E. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in Order No. 59-33. Department of Highways and Traffic Organization Order No. 122 (Reorganization), dated January 8, 1959, as Amended.</text>
    <text>F. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in Order of the Commissioner 68-236, Delegation of Authority to Establish Flat Rate Charges for Street Repairs, dated March 20, 1968.</text>
    <text>G. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in Order of the Commissioner 68-554, Delegation of Authority to Establish and Administer Traffic Rules and Regulations, dated August 16, 1968.</text>
    <text>H. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in Order of the Commissioner 69-615, Organization Order No. 9, as Amended, Contracting Officer, dated November 4, 1969.</text>
    <text>I. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 70-151, Delegation of Authority for Final Approval of License Bonds, dated April 22, 1970.</text>
    <text>J. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 71-75, Annual Hauling Permit Fee for a Self-Unloading, Single Unit Motor Vehicle by Weight Class with three or more Axles, dated March 18, 1971.</text>
    <text>K. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 71-354, Delegation of Authority to Administer City Council Regulation 71-25 Prohibiting Left Turns into Parking Lots and Garages, dated September 10, 1971.</text>
    <text>L. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 72-11, General Purpose Transportation, dated January 13, 1972.</text>
    <text>M. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 72-107, Implementation of City Council Regulation 71-26 Governing Bicycles, dated May 4, 1972.</text>
    <text>N. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 72-182, Delegation of Authority to Enter into Interstate Agreement with the State of Maryland and the Commonwealth of Virginia, dated July 17, 1972.</text>
    <text>O. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 73-76, Delegation of Authority to Execute Downtown Bus Service Capital Grant Project No. DC-VTG-2, dated March 28, 1973.</text>
    <text>P. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 72-79, Delegation of Authority to Execute Downtown Bus Service Demonstration Grant Project No. DC-06-0069, as Amended and dated March 28, 1973.</text>
    <text>Q. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 73-168, Delegation of Authority Under the District of Columbia Public Space Utilization Act, dated July 13, 1973.</text>
    <text>R. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 74-207, Delegation of Authority to Apply for and Execute an Urban Mass Transportation Capital Improvement Grant for the National Visitors Center, dated September 30, 1974.</text>
    <text>S. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in C.O. 74-54, Designation of Department of Highways and Traffic as the District Agency Responsible for Administration of Programs Under Sec. 230 Safe Roads Program - Highway Safety Act of 1973, dated March 29, 1974.</text>
    <text>T. The functions related to the Department of Motor Vehicles as set forth in Organization Order No. 21, Order of the Commissioner 69-235, Traffic Coordinating Committee, dated May 26, 1969.</text>
    <text>U. The functions related to the Department of Highways and Traffic as set forth in Organization Order No. 23, Order of the Commissioner 69-502, D.C. Public Space Committee, as Amended and dated September 3, 1969.</text>
    <text>V. The functions related to the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles in C.O. 69-234, Highway Safety Program Coordinator, dated May 26, 1969.</text>
    <text>W. Any other functions not specifically mentioned above which are now delegated to, or vested in, the Director of the Department of Highways and Traffic and the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles and the Transportation Systems Coordinator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>v.</num>
    <heading>delegations and redelegations of authority</heading>
    <text>A. The Director of the Department of Transportation is the successor to all authority delegated to the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles, the Director of the Department of Highways and Traffic, and the Transportation Systems Coordinator, and is authorized to act, either personally or through a designated representative, as a member of whatever committees, commissions, boards, or other bodies which presently include as a member the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles, the Director of the Department of Highways and Traffic, and the Transportation Systems Coordinator.</text>
    <text>B. The Director of the Department of Transportation is designated as the Governor's Highway Safety Representative and the Department of Transportation is designated State agency for administration of the Highway Safety Program in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>vi.</num>
    <heading>other transfers</heading>
    <text>All positions, personnel, property, records and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the above functions, other than those resources and functions to be transferred to the Public Service Commission, are hereby transferred to the Director of the Department of Transportation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>vii.</num>
    <heading>organization</heading>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Transportation, in the performance of his duties and functions, is authorized to establish such organizational components thereunder with such specified functions, as he deems appropriate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>viii.</num>
    <heading>rescission</heading>
    <text>A. All Orders and parts of Orders in conflict with any of the provisions of this plan are, to the extent of such conflict, hereby repealed except that any municipal regulation adopted or promulgated by virtue of the authority granted by such orders shall remain in force until otherwise amended or repealed.</text>
    <text>B. The positions of Director, Department of Motor Vehicles, Director, Department of Highways and Traffic and the Transportation Systems Coordinator are hereby abolished.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>ix.</num>
    <heading>effective date</heading>
    <text>The provisions of this plan shall become effective pursuant to the requirements of Section 422(12) of Public Law 93-198.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Statement">
      <text class="centered">
        <em>present problems</em>
      </text>
      <text>District of Columbia activities and functions relating to transportation are presently fragmented among several District agencies and departments.</text>
      <text>The Department of Highways and Traffic is responsible for planning, constructing and maintaining the District's highway system as well as for planning and controlling traffic flow. In addition, this Department maintains the District's public and metered parking facilities.</text>
      <text>The Department of Motor Vehicles is responsible for testing and licensing operators of all powered wheeled vehicles, as well as for inspecting and registering these vehicles.</text>
      <text>The Transportation Systems Coordinator, lodged in the Executive office of the Mayor, provides liaison to the Metro operations, evaluates transportation proposals, and advises the Mayor on transportation policy.</text>
      <text>Each of the above entities provides specific services to the District based on valid and appropriate objectives. Taken collectively, however, these goals are not sufficiently broad to encompass the entire spectrum of District transportation needs. No single authority now exists which can perform an overview of city transportation needs and costs, balancing one mode against another or relating those needs and costs to non-transportation factors such as environmental impact and the broad economic situation.</text>
      <text class="centered">
        <em>plan to establish a district of columbia department of transportation</em>
      </text>
      <text>In order to deal more effectively with the broader issues relating to the overall transportation needs of District citizens and visitors, it is planned to combine into one organizational entity all related activities and functions now dispersed among the several offices cited above.</text>
      <text>The reorganization presented in Reorganization Plan 2, with associated charts and tables, has been prepared with three objectives in mind:</text>
      <text><em>Objective One: Capability for Broad Over-View:</em> A Department of Transportation will be the key mechanism for addressing issues, needs and programs that extend to all transportation modes. The new department will identify rail service needs; perform analyses of the adequacy of the bus system and develop ways to improve it; develop plans and programs to integrate various methods of transportation to expedite passenger movement; promote the development of aviation facilities and their safe use; determine the need for new and perhaps larger transportation terminal facilities; develop the means for a more efficient distribution of goods; and develop a system of bikeways and pedestrianways. In summary, it will broaden the transportation objectives of the city.        
        </text>
      <text><em>Objective Two: More Rational Allocation of Resources:</em> The new realignment of facilities and services should reflect a more balanced approach to the transportation system. At the same time, the realignment should permit the department to obtain a better assessment of the resources needed to operate a total system.        
        </text>
      <text><em>Objective Three: Active Coordination with Independent Transportation Modes and with other Jurisdictions:</em> While the city does not operate the METRO system or taxi companies, the city does have a responsibility to require that these transportation services be adequate, safe and economical. A Department of Transportation will provide the focal point for the city to interact with the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA), the Civil Aeronautics Board (CAB), the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB), the taxi industry, and other owners and regulators of transportation services.        
        </text>
      <text class="centered">
        <em>structure and functions of the new department</em>
      </text>
      <text>The Functional Chart of the planned Department carries out these objectives in structural form. Eight subunits are planned; three at the staff level, four at the operating level, and an Office of the Director. Notes on each of the eight units follow:</text>
      <text><em>Office of the Director:</em> In addition to a Director and Deputy Director, a staff for community relations is being established. The great importance of two-way communication with the community (both residents and visitors to the Nation's Capital) has led to the decision to give this function direct access to the Head of the agency by placing it in his immediate Office.        
        </text>
      <text><em>Office of Administration:</em> The Administrative functions of the two existing departments are consolidated in this Unit. In addition to the present functions, financial resources management and regulations/legislation have been added here. The goal of financial resources management is to inventory and control all department resources within the context of one overall plan and budget. In order to permit analysis of departmental regulations, Federal requirements, and staff-level review of departmental hearing processes, a unit of regulations and legislation is also proposed.        
        </text>
      <text><em>Office of Transportation Policy and Plans:</em> Overall program priorities will be developed here for recommendation to the Director and, through the Director, to the Mayor and Council. The economic impact of transportation decisions has long been neglected, but will find a home in this Office. Systems planning for all modes of transportation will be established to reflect general policy objectives. Traditional project oriented planning such as is now performed in the Highways and Traffic Department will take its cue and direction from the systems planning staff. Finally, establishment of a social program analytical capability will provide a planning link to community transportation needs.        
        </text>
      <text><em>Office of Safety and Environment:</em> The existing highway safety coordination and safety education functions currently in the DMV form the nucleus for this new Office. This organization will allow for a new emphasis on safety standards for additional transport modes and for expansion of the environmental programs, including social impact and interagency cooperation.        
        </text>
      <text>The four operating bureaus, now identified as the Bureaus of Design, Engineering and Research, Construction and Maintenance, Traffic Engineering and Operations, and Motor Vehicle Services, are based on the present operating responsibilities of the Highways and Traffic and Motor Vehicle Departments. A side benefit to be gained, however, is that better resource utilization can be made possible through implementation of intermodal transportation projects at the operating level.</text>
      <text class="centered">
        <em>expected benefits of the creation of the department of transportation</em>
      </text>
      <text>
        <em>Short-range:</em>
      </text>
      <text><strong>1.</strong> Provides a central focal point within the District to deal with issues affecting overall municipal, area, and regional transportation planning.
        </text>
      <text><strong>2.</strong> Provides unified direction over all related activities in setting and achieving District-wide transportation goals, through closer coordination of the various facets of operations and programs.
        </text>
      <text><strong>3.</strong> Permits the expansion of technical and professional planning capability at the operating level without added expense to the District.
        </text>
      <text><strong>4.</strong> Permits greater flexibility for applying available resources appropriately to meet program and project priority needs.
        </text>
      <text><strong>5.</strong> Creates a more effective use of available professional, technical, and administrative staff skills through the expanded planning and resource flexibility capability.
        </text>
      <text>
        <em>Long-range:</em>
      </text>
      <text><strong>1.</strong> Permits acquisition of additional and more suitable skills needed, through the normal process of employee turnover, for dealing with present day long-range transportation issues.
        </text>
      <text><strong>2.</strong> Permits anticipated administrative efficiencies and economies, particularly in the areas of personnel, budget, office services, procurement, and administrative management, through the consolidation of existing administrative staffs and elimination of hierarchical structures now necessary for each of the existing independent agencies.
        </text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., Title 1, Chapter 15, Subchapter I, Part A.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
