<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1512.02</num>
  <heading>Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1993</heading>
  <text>(Approved October 7, 1993)</text>
  <text>TRANSFER OF THE WEATHERIZATION ASSISTANCE PROGRAM FROM THE DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT TO BE CONSOLIDATED WITH THE ENERGY ASSISTANCE PROGRAM UNDER THE D.C. ENERGY OFFICE WITHIN THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS</text>
  <text>Prepared by the Mayor and transmitted to the Council of the District of Columbia pursuant to the provisions of Section 422(12) of the D.C. Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198; 87 Stat. 790, codified at D.C. Code ยง 1-242 (1992 Repl. Vol.) and Section 1-299.3(1) of D.C. Law 4-42, the Government Reorganization Procedures Act of 1981.</text>
  <text class="centered">DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT</text>
  <para>
    <num>I.</num>
    <heading>Transfer</heading>
    <text>The Weatherization Assistance Program (WAP) in the Department of Housing and Community Development (DHCD) is hereby transferred to the D.C. Energy Office (DCEO) under the Department of Public Works.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>II.</num>
    <heading>Purpose</heading>
    <text>The purpose of this plan is to consolidate functions being performed at both DHCD and DCEO. This transfer will eliminate overlapping and duplication of effort and will allow for a more efficient operation of the District Government's weatherization programs.</text>
    <text>The weatherization services provided by DHCD are consistent with those provided by DCEO. DHCD provides grants to eligible District residents for the purpose of weatherizing their homes (both owners and tenants). The funds for DHCD's operation of the programs are provided annually by the U.S. Department of Energy. Costs for the administration of the program are a part of the grant.</text>
    <text>The DCEO operates programs which provide weatherization services and energy assistance in the form of monthly payments for household energy costs to eligible, low-income District residents. DCEO also provides energy efficiency education and promotional activities for residential, commercial, governmental, and institutional entities in the District. In addition, DCEO provides intervention for energy efficiency in utility regulatory proceedings and legislative matters. DCEO is authorized by law (D.C. Law 3-132) to serve as the lead agency to develop and implement the District's responses to energy related problems.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>III.</num>
    <heading>Organization</heading>
    <text>The transfer of the WAP will include the reassignment of one (1) staff position (term), four (4) automobiles, all equipment and records associated with the program, and any unexpended grant funds. The U.S. Department of Energy will redirect the WAP grant to the DCEO.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>IV.</num>
    <heading>Functions</heading>
    <text>The WAP is operated in accordance with the Federal regulations (10 CFR Part 400) promulgated by the U.S. Department of Energy and will not change.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>V.</num>
    <heading>Effective Date</heading>
    <text>This Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1933, becomes effective in accordance with Section 422(12) of Public Law 93-198, or on a date thereafter to be designated pursuant to Executive Order of the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., Title 1, Chapter 15, Subchapter XII, Part B.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Statement">
      <text>In a continuing effort to make the District Government a more effective and efficient vehicle for the residents of the District of Columbia, this Administration proposes that the Weatherization Assistance Program (WAP) at the Department of Housing and Community Development (DHCD) be transferred to the D.C. Energy Office under the Department of Public Works (DPW).</text>
      <text>This transfer would consolidate functions already provided by DCEO, reduce the duplication of services and allow the District to more effectively operate its various energy related programs. This consolidation would also increase efficiency to the fullest extent practicable as it relates to the weatherization of housing units.</text>
      <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development receives funding for the Weatherization Assistance Program for low-income persons from the U.S. Department of Energy. These funds can be redirected to DCEO. The D.C. Energy Office is authorized under D.C. Law 3-132 to serve as the lead agency to develop and implement the District's responses to energy-related problems. Therefore, the transfer of WAP to DCEO would serve to fully implement the law.</text>
      <text>This action will result in the redirection of the WAP grant, the transfer of one (1) staff position, four (4) automobiles, equipment, records and unexpended grant funds.</text>
      <text>I urge the Council to join me in our continuing effort to improve city services for the residents of the District of Columbia by approving this Reorganization Plan.</text>
    </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
