<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1512.03</num>
  <heading>Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1993</heading>
  <text>(Approved October 7, 1993)</text>
  <para>
    <num>I.</num>
    <heading>Purpose</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>To transfer certain functions of Office of Business and Economic Development (OBED) and the Office of International Business (OIB) to the jurisdiction and control of the Office of Economic Development (OED).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>To change the position title from Deputy Mayor for Economic Development to Assistant City Administrator for Economic Development.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>II.</num>
    <heading>Functions</heading>
    <text>All functions associated with the positions transferred from OBED and OIB are hereby transferred to OED.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>III.</num>
    <heading>Transfers</heading>
    <text>Two (2) OIB positions and five (5) OBED positions, associated property, records and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds, if any, that relate to the positions and functions assigned herein, shall be transferred to OED. All authority for administering activities previously authorized or delegated to OIB and OBED is hereby transferred to OED.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>IV.</num>
    <heading>Organization</heading>
    <text>The deputy Mayor for Economic Development, in the performance of the duties and functions assigned by this plan, is authorized to establish such organizational components with specified subcomponents as deemed appropriate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>V.</num>
    <heading>Rescission</heading>
    <text>All orders and parts of orders in conflict with any of the provisions of this plan and the Council mandate are, to the extent of such conflict, hereby repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>VI.</num>
    <heading>Effective Date</heading>
    <text>This Reorganization Plan 4 of 1993 shall become effective in accordance with Section 422(12) of Public Law 93-198, D.C. Code, 1-242(12) [1-204.22] update, and Section 5(c) of Public Law 4-42, D.C. Code 1-299.4(c) [ยง 1-315.04].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>2001 Ed., Title 1, Chapter 15, Subchapter XII, Part C.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Mayor's Statement</heading>
      <text class="centered">POSITION TITLE CHANGE</text>
      <annotation>
        <text>For more than five years, the Office of Economic Development, headed by a Deputy Mayor, has operated under the direction and control of the City Administrator. The position title has created ambiguities regarding the management level of the position and the reporting hierarchy therein. Changing the position title from Deputy Mayor for Economic Development to Assistant City Administrator for Economic Development will more accurately reflect the organizational structure and provide clarity to the Office.</text>
        <text>The authority and responsibilities of the Assistant City Administrator will remain the same as under the Deputy Mayor for Economic Development. The functions of the Office of Economic Development (OED) remains the same as in prior years. Although most economic development cluster agency activities will not change, some will undergo restructuring to optimize investment and development opportunities and to improve regulatory oversight responsibilities.</text>
        <text>This restructuring of cluster agencies, coupled with the change in name of the position to the Assistant City Administrator for Economic Development will provide a more structured and centralized agency operation and will define clearly, the role of the Assistant City Administrator.</text>
        <text class="centered">CONSOLIDATION OF FUNCTIONS</text>
        <text>In early 1991, after an Executive Branch review of the activities being performed by the Office of Business and Economic Development (OBED) and the Office of International Business (OIB), it was determined that a substantial degree of overlap and duplication of functions and responsibilities existed between the two agencies. In addition, the Council of the District of Columbia, in its consideration of the FY 1994 Appropriated Budget, abolished both agencies and transferred certain responsibilities and positions to the Office of Economic Development (OED).</text>
        <text>Based on the review, the need to economize on efforts and dollars, the need to centralize economic development activities in the District government, the legislative action taken by the Council, and in keeping with my pledge to streamline government, I have authorized the reorganization of the two offices, as cited herein.</text>
        <text>In accordance with D.C. Law 4-42, the "Governmental Reorganization Procedures Act of 1981," this reorganization will be accomplished by the transfer of certain staff and functions of OBED and OIB to the administrative control of the Assistant City Administrator for Economic Development in OED. I have determined that both offices have so similar operational responsibilities that the District would be best served by a unified administration. Not only will this change clarify administrative roles and responsibilities, but it will also provide a sharper focus to the District's economic development efforts with the private business sector.</text>
        <text>In summary, economic development and related activities currently being performed separately by the OBED and OIB, both of which promote the District in a local, national, and international arenas, should be merged. The centralization of these activities will diminish fragmented, disjointed, and duplicated service delivery and thus, allow the District to promote its marketing campaign and business services more efficiently and cost-effectively.</text>
      </annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
