<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1508.02</num>
  <heading>Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1987</heading>
  <text>(Effective July 3, 1987)</text>
  <para>
    <num>I.</num>
    <heading>Purpose</heading>
    <text>The purpose of this reorganization is to extend the Mayor's authority to issue grants under Section 13 of the Water Pollution Control Act of 1984, effective March 16, 1985 (D.C. Law 5-188; D.C. Code Sec. 6-932 (1986 Supp.)) (hereinafter the "Water Act") to the Director of the Department of Public Works. This authority is in addition to similar authority granted to the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>II.</num>
    <heading>Functions</heading>
    <text>The following function shall be vested in both the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs and the Department of Public Works:</text>
    <text>Under Section 13 of the Water Act, the function of issuing grants to universities and institutions for research concerning the quality of District waters.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>III.</num>
    <heading>Transfers</heading>
    <text>There is no transfers of positions, property, records or unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations and other funds available or to be made available relating to the duties and functions assigned herein.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>IV.</num>
    <heading>Effective Date</heading>
    <text>The provisions of this Plan shall become effective pursuant to the promulgation of an executive order of the Mayor establishing the same no later than thirty (30) calendar days after this Plan has been approved in accordance with the requirements of Section 422(12) of District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, Public Law 93-198, effective December 24, 1973 (D.C. Code Sec. 1-242(12) [1-204.22]).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., Title 1, Chapter 15, Subchapter VIII, Part B.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Statement">
      <text>This Reorganization is a reallocation of delegated authority. The Departments of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs and Public Works are to share the authority to issue grants pursuant to the Water Pollution Control Act of 1984 ("the Act"), D.C. Code ยง 6-921 [8-103.01] et seq. By Mayor's Order 85-152, dated September 12, 1985, I delegated my authority to administer the Act to the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. Since I issued that Order, however, it has become clear that it should be modified to coincide more clearly with the respective functions of, and projects managed by, the Departments of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs and Public Works.</text>
      <text>In particular, I believe a reorganization to permit Public Works to issue grants for projects related to, or affecting, the Blue Plains Wastewater Treatment Plant and the improvement of water quality in the Potomac and Anacostia Rivers will result in a more efficient utilization of departmental resources and staff. While the missions and responsibilities of the two departments are related, often closely, Public Works is most knowledgeable of the time, program requirements, technical support and other constraints associated with projects such as the combined sewer abatement program and the Anacostia River cleanup effort. These and similar programs impact upon the operation and plant processes of Blue Plains and the requirements imposed upon the District under the National Pollution Discharge Elimination System permit issued by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
      <text>The federal government contributes 55 percent (and in the past contributed 75 percent) of the cost of various construction and water quality projects. The application process often entails a series of deadlines and submittal requirements uniquely and readily within the Public Works' purview. Therefore, in order to maximize the District's responsiveness to both federal grant application requirements and the subsequent release of such funds to District's grantees, I am proposing a reorganization to permit Public Works and Consumer and Regulatory Affairs to share the grant making authority set forth in Section 13 (D.C. Code ยง 6-932 [8-103.12]) of the Act.</text>
      <text>Under this proposed change, Consumer and Regulatory Affairs will still have authority to issue grants for projects which fall under its responsibilities as the state regulatory agency for the District of Columbia. Public Works will have authority to issue grants for research related to the construction and monitoring of public facilities designed to improve water quality. Apart from the sharing of authority, no other changes are necessitated by this reorganization. Both departments will continue to obtain federal grants within their existing office structures and will issue grants to local recipients. Consequently, while no reduction in expenditures is contemplated, neither will expenditures increase, because both departments will utilized current staff to administer grant fund.</text>
      <text>The assignment of these duties jointly to the two departments administering the District's environmental programs and responsibilities ultimately will ensure the public health and safety and the quality of District and regional waters; and there will be no additional burden upon District resources.</text>
    </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
