<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section 
  xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1512.01</num>
  <heading>Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1993</heading>
  <text>(Approved July 21, 1993)</text>
  <text>Prepared by the Mayor and transmitted to the Council of the District of Columbia pursuant to the provisions of Section 422(12) of the District Charter.</text>
  <text class="centered">OFFICE OF THE ASSISTANT CITY ADMINISTRATOR FOR HUMAN RESOURCES DEVELOPMENT</text>
  <para>
    <num>I.</num>
    <heading>Establishment</heading>
    <text>There is hereby established in the Executive Office of the Mayor, the "Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development" under the direction and control of an Assistant City Administrator who shall be appointed by the Mayor to a position in the Executive Service pursuant to Title X of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, D.C. Law 2-139, effective March 3, 1979, (D.C. Code former sections 1-611.1 to 1-611.2) [§§ 1-610.01 to 1-610.02].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>II.</num>
    <heading>Purpose</heading>
    <text>The purpose of the Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development is to coordinate the activities of the Human Resources Development Cluster to provide training and employment services for both District Government employees and residents to meet the technological demands of today's and tomorrow's workplace.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>III.</num>
    <heading>Functions</heading>
    <text>The functions of the Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development shall be to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Establish a Human Resources Development Cluster of District government agencies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide oversight for and coordinate the activities of the Human Resources Development Cluster;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Plan and coordinate training and employment services to be provided by the Human Resources Development Cluster to District Government employees and residents;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Plan and coordinate effective human resource management programs through the Office of Personnel;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Review the negotiation of compensation and working condition agreements affecting District government employees through the Office of Labor Relations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Develop and coordinate job training and development programs; job placement programs; workers' compensation programs for injured workers; an unemployment compensation program; a wage-hour program; an occupational safety and health program; and compensation to crime victims through the Department of Employment Services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Serve as the liaison to the education community and to administer the Office of Education licensing functions through the Office of Education and the Educational Licensure Commission; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Coordinate the Human Rights functions of the Department of Human Rights and Minority Business Development.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>IV.</num>
    <heading>Transfers</heading>
    <text>All positions, personnel, records, unexpended balances of appropriation and functions of the Office of Human Resources Development in the Office of Personnel are hereby transferred to the Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources development.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>V.</num>
    <heading>Organization</heading>
    <text>The Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development is authorized to organize personnel and property within the Office of the Assistant City Administrator as is deemed appropriate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>VI.</num>
    <heading>Effective Date</heading>
    <text>The provisions of this plan shall become effective pursuant to the requirements of Section 422(12) of Public Law 93-198, or on a date thereafter to be designated pursuant to Executive Order of the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>2001 Ed., Title 1, Chapter 15, Subchapter XII, Part A.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Mayor's Statement</heading>
      <annotation>
        <text>The Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development, to be created in 1993, will have oversight of all Human Resources Development Cluster agencies and their functions. Funding for the Office of the Assistant City Administrator was proposed in the revised FY 1993 and FY 1994 budget submissions and transmitted to the City Council in February, 1993.</text>
        <text>The overall mission of the Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development is to coordinate training and development services provided to both Government employees and residents of the District to meet the technological demands of today's and tomorrow's workplace. The people of this city are its most precious commodity and they have a much greater capacity for productivity than has been realized. The greatest missing factor is investment in their potential to make them more competitive. Quality results begin with a quality investment in our human resources which is key to addressing many of our complex social and economic problems in the District. Presently, there is a mismatch between the technical demands of the marketplace and the skills and abilities of our government employees, as well as our citizens. The Human Resources Development Cluster agencies would educate, train, and retrain our workforce to confidently meet the demands of our highly technological environment. Local government sets the tone for economic development and our commitment to a well trained government and local workforce will be a tremendous marketing asset.</text>
        <text>Many large organizations, both private and public, periodically undergo system change based on a change in mission; financial constraints; market and service needs; or in response to technology. The Assistant City Administrator's Office and the cluster would be established at a time that our local government will be undergoing a Reduction In Force. The proposed RIF is due to our financial condition and the need to streamline the size and structure of the workforce. A Reduction In Force is painful, however, something positive will result from this pain. It will change how our government provides services, and provide us with an opportunity to utilize employees more effectively.</text>
        <text>The Human Resources Development Cluster will consist of the following entities: The Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development; the Office of Personnel; the Office of Labor Relations and Collective Bargaining; the Department of Employment Services; the Office of Education; the Human Rights component of the Department of Human Rights and Minority Business Development; and the Office of Government Workforce Training and Development.</text>
      </annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>