<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-152</num>
  <heading>Inclusion of “DC” and “No Taxation Without Representation” within District of Columbia flag.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After the design adopted under subsection (b) of this section becomes effective, the flag of the District of Columbia shall temporarily contain the language “DC” and “No Taxation Without Representation”.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The placement and design of the language prescribed in subsection (a) of this section shall be established by act of the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The flag adopted pursuant to § <cite path="§1-151">1-151</cite> and subsection (b) of this section shall be flown officially as of 90 days following the effective date of the act specified in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The language prescribed in subsection (a) of this section shall be removed from the flag when District of Columbia registered voters are able to vote for 2 Senators and one Representative with full rights and privileges in the Congress of the United States.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The language prescribed in subsection (a) of this section shall not be required in instances where a reproduction of the flag is placed as a symbol on motor vehicles, District of Columbia government letterhead, or other objects.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the District government and any person may officially display a District of Columbia flag that contains the language “DC” and “No Taxation Without Representation” on June 14 of each year, known as Flag Day, until a design is officially adopted by the Council pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-237" type="History" path="§3">Mar. 25, 2003, D.C. Law 14-237, § 3, 49 DCR 10485</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-239" type="History">Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-239, § 2, 59 DCR 14788</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-154">1-154</cite> and § <cite path="§1-172">1-172</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§1-172">1-172</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-239">D.C. Law 19-239</cite> added (f).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
