<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-201.02</num>
  <heading>Purposes.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to the retention by Congress of the ultimate legislative authority over the nation’s capital granted by article I, § 8, of the Constitution, the intent of Congress is to delegate certain legislative powers to the government of the District of Columbia; authorize the election of certain local officials by the registered qualified electors in the District of Columbia; grant to the inhabitants of the District of Columbia powers of local self-government; modernize, reorganize, and otherwise improve the governmental structure of the District of Columbia; and, to the greatest extent possible, consistent with the constitutional mandate, relieve Congress of the burden of legislating upon essentially local District matters.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Congress further intends to implement certain recommendations of the Commission on the Organization of the Government of the District of Columbia and take certain other actions irrespective of whether the charter for greater self-government provided for in subchapter IV of this chapter is accepted or rejected by the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-198">Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 777, Pub. L. 93-198, title I, § 102</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Downtown sports and entertainment arena, financing, see § <cite path="§47-2752">47-2752</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Mayor, subpoena power, see § <cite path="§1-301.21">1-301.21</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>United States Congress, reservation of authority, see §§ <cite path="§1-206.01">1-206.01</cite>, <cite path="§1-206.02">1-206.02</cite>, <cite path="§1-206.03">1-206.03</cite>, and <cite path="§1-206.04">1-206.04</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Water and sewer authority, general powers and purpose, see §§ <cite path="§34-2202.02">34-2202.02</cite> and <cite path="§34-2202.03">34-2202.03</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-201.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 1-121.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 11717(b) of Title XI of Pub. L. 105-33, 111 Stat. 786, the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, provided as follows:</text>
      <text>“(b) References In Law—Any reference in law or regulation to the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act shall be deemed to be a reference to the District of Columbia Home Rule Act.”</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
