<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-207.17</num>
  <heading>Status of the District.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All of the territory constituting the permanent seat of the Government of the United States shall continue to be designated as the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia shall remain and continue a body corporate, as provided in § <cite path="§1-102">1-102</cite>. Said Corporation shall continue to be charged with all the duties, obligations, responsibilities, and liabilities, and to be vested with all of the powers, rights, privileges, immunities, and assets, respectively, imposed upon and vested in said Corporation or the Commissioner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No law or regulation which is in force on January 2, 1975 shall be deemed amended or repealed by this chapter except to the extent specifically provided herein or to the extent that such law or regulation is inconsistent with this chapter, but any such law or regulation may be amended or repealed by act or resolution as authorized in this chapter, or by Act of Congress, except that, notwithstanding the provisions of § <cite path="§1-207.52">1-207.52</cite>, such authority to repeal shall not be construed as authorizing the Council to repeal or otherwise alter, by amendment or otherwise, any provision of subchapter III of chapter 73 of title 5, United States Code in whole or in part.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this section shall affect the boundary line between the District of Columbia and the Commonwealth of Virginia as the same was established or may be subsequently established under the provisions of title I of the Act of October 31, 1945 (59 Stat. 552).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-198" type="History">Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 779, Pub. L. 93-198, title VII, § 717</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-207.71">1-207.71</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., §§ 1-101(b), 1-102(b).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
