<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-204.13</num>
  <heading>Investigations by the Council.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council, or any committee or person authorized by it, shall have power to investigate any matter relating to the affairs of the District, and for that purpose may require the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, papers, and other evidence. For such purpose any member of the Council (if the Council is conducting the inquiry) or any member of the committee may issue subpoenas, and administer oaths upon resolution adopted by the Council or committee, as appropriate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to, any person, the Council by resolution may refer the matter to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, which may by order require such person to appear and give or produce testimony or books, papers, or other evidence, bearing upon the matter under investigation. Any failure to obey such order may be punished by such Court as a contempt thereof as in the case of failure to obey a subpoena issued, or to testify, in a case pending before such Court.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-198" type="History">Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 789, Pub. L. 93-198, title IV, § 413</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Council investigations, penalty for obstructing, see § <cite path="§1-301.43">1-301.43</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Oaths, administration by Mayor, chairman of Council, and members of Council, see § <cite path="§1-301.22">1-301.22</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Procurement, debarment or suspension of businesses, see § <cite path="§2-308.04">2-308.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-218.63">2-218.63</cite> and § <cite path="§2-359.07">2-359.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-234.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-148.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
