<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-204.87</num>
  <heading>Water pollution.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall annually estimate the amount of the District’s principal and interest expense which is required to service District obligations attributable to the Maryland and Virginia pro rata share of District sanitary sewage water works and other water pollution projects which provide service to the local jurisdictions in those states. Such amounts as determined by the Mayor pursuant to the agreements described in subsection (b) of this section shall be used to exclude the Maryland and Virginia share of pollution projects cost from the limitation on the District’s capital project obligations as provided in § <cite root="1-206.03">1-206.03</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall enter into agreements with the states and local jurisdictions concerned for annual payments to the District of rates and charges for waste treatment services in accordance with the use and benefits made and derived from the operation of the said waste treatment facilities. Each such agreement shall require that the estimated amount of such rates and charges will be paid in advance, subject to adjustment after each year. Such rates and charges shall be sufficient to cover the cost of construction, interest on capital, operation and maintenance, and the necessary replacement of equipment during the useful life of the facility.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-198">Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 808, Pub. L. 93-198, title IV, § 487</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="34-2202.16">34-2202.16</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 43-1615.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 43-1619.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) additions, see § 2 of Blue Plains Intermunicipal Agreement of 2012 Congressional Approval Emergency Request Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-422, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9365).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Restriction on use of funds: Section 136 of Pub. L. 102-382, 106 Stat. 1435, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1993, provided that none of the funds made available in this Act may be used by the District of Columbia to impose, implement, collect, administer, transfer, or enforce a payment in lieu of taxes on the Water and Sewer Utility Administration that would increase payments required of suburban jurisdictions in Maryland or Virginia under the Blue Plains Intermunicipal Agreement of 1985.</text>
      <text>Definitions applicable: The definitions in § <cite root="1-201.03">1-201.03</cite> apply to this section.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
