<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-204.42</num>
  <heading>Submission of annual budget.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>At such time as the Council may direct, the Mayor shall prepare and submit to the Council each year, and make available to the public, an annual budget for the District of Columbia government which shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The budget for the forthcoming fiscal year in such detail as the Mayor determines necessary to reflect the actual financial condition of the District government for such fiscal year, and specify the agencies and purposes for which funds are being requested; and which shall be prepared on the assumption that proposed expenditures resulting from financial transactions undertaken on either an obligation or cash outlay basis, for such fiscal year shall not exceed estimated resources from existing sources and proposed resources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An annual budget message which shall include supporting financial and statistical information on the budget for the forthcoming fiscal year and information on the approved budgets and expenditures for the immediately preceding 3 fiscal years;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A multiyear plan for all agencies of the District government as required under § <cite path="§1-204.43">1-204.43</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A multiyear capital improvements plan for all agencies of the District government as required under § <cite path="§1-204.44">1-204.44</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A program performance report comparing actual performance of as many programs as is practicable for the last completed fiscal year against proposed goals for such programs for such year, and, in addition, presenting as many qualitative or quantitative measures of program effectiveness as possible (including results of statistical sampling or other special analyses), and indicating the status of efforts to comply with the reports of the District of Columbia Auditor and the Comptroller General of the United States;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>An issue analysis statement consisting of a reasonable number of issues, identified by the Council in its action on the budget in the preceding fiscal year, having significant revenue or budgetary implications, and other similar issues selected by the Mayor, which shall consider the cost and benefits of alternatives and the rationale behind action recommended or adopted; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A summary of the budget for the forthcoming fiscal year designed for distribution to the general public.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The budget prepared and submitted by the Mayor shall include, but not be limited to, recommended expenditures at a reasonable level for the forthcoming fiscal year for the Council, the District of Columbia Auditor, the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics, the District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission, the Zoning Commission of the District of Columbia, the Public Service Commission, the Armory Board, the Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure, and the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor from time to time may prepare and submit to the Council such proposed supplemental or deficiency budget recommendations as in his judgment are necessary on account of laws enacted after transmission of the budget or are otherwise in the public interest. The Mayor shall submit with such proposals a statement of justifications, including reasons for their omission from the annual budget. Whenever such proposed supplemental or deficiency budget recommendations are in an amount which would result in expenditures in excess of estimated resources, the Mayor shall make such recommendations as are necessary to increase resources to meet such increased expenditures.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall prepare and submit to the Council a proposed supplemental or deficiency budget recommendation under subsection (c) of this section if the Council by resolution requests the Mayor to submit such a recommendation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-198" type="History" path="§442">Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 798, Pub. L. 93-198, title IV, § 442</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-376" type="History">Aug. 14, 1974, 88 Stat. 458, Pub. L. 93-376, title III, § 306(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 104-8" type="History">Apr. 17, 1995, 109 Stat. 142, Pub. L. 104-8, § 301(c)</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 6, 1996, 110 Stat. 1698, Pub. L. 104-184, § 4(c)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Board of education, annual report and budget revision, see § <cite path="§38-154">38-154</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">D.C. retirement board, budget preparation, see § <cite path="§1-711">1-711</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District government, financial plan and annual District budget, process for submission and approval, see § <cite path="§47-392.02">47-392.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Financing of retirement benefits, calculation of District payment, see § <cite path="§1-907.03">1-907.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Financing of retirement benefits, federal and district payments, determination, certification, see § <cite path="§1-722">1-722</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Fund accounting, duties of Mayor, see § <cite path="§47-375">47-375</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public parking authority, budget submission, see § <cite path="§50-2511">50-2511</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Sports and entertainment commission, public or private bond sale, budget submission, see § <cite path="§3-1413">3-1413</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">University of the District of Columbia, budget, see § <cite path="§38-1202.06">38-1202.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-325.11">1-325.11</cite>, § <cite path="§1-711">1-711</cite>, § <cite path="§1-722">1-722</cite>, § <cite path="§1-907.03">1-907.03</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1225.21">2-1225.21</cite>, § <cite path="§7-771.07">7-771.07</cite>, § <cite path="§9-111.01">9-111.01</cite>, § <cite path="§34-1253.02">34-1253.02</cite>, § <cite path="§38-173">38-173</cite>, § <cite path="§47-318.01">47-318.01</cite>, § <cite path="§47-318.05a">47-318.05a</cite>, § <cite path="§47-375">47-375</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-392.02">47-392.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-301.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-221.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Sections 2 and 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-157">D.C. Law 18-157</law-cite> added sections to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. The Mayor shall submit a budget gap-closing plan for the District government for the current fiscal year to the Council not later than February 10, 2010. The Mayor shall make the plan available to the public.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 3. The Mayor shall submit to the Council by the 10th of each month a report, which is certified by the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, on the progress for controlling overspending in fiscal year 2010. The Mayor shall make the reports available to the public.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-157">D.C. Law 18-157</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3102 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3102 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) provisions on limits on local spending increases, see § 4002 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) submission of the budget with local spending increase limitations, see § 1202 of the Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) submission of the budget with local spending increase limitations, see § 1202 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) Department of Employment Services budget and FTE authority provisions, see § 1092 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) Department of Employment Services budget and FTE authority provisions, see § 1092 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2, 3 of Fiscal Year 2010 Balanced Budget and Spending Pressure Control Plan Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-322, March 2, 2010,  57 DCR 1847).</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of title XLI of Law 14-190: Section 4101 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</law-cite> provided that title XLI of the act may be cited as the Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Submission Amendment Act of 2002.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle I of title I of Law 15-205: Section 1091 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</law-cite> provided that subtitle I of title I of the act may be cited as the Department of Employment Services Budget and FTE Authority Act of 2004.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Submission date for budget request for fiscal year 1992: Pursuant to Resolution 8-312, the “Submission Date for the Fiscal Year 1992 Budget Approval Resolution of 1990,” effective December 21, 1990, the Council established the date by which the Mayor shall submit to the Council the proposed budget for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1992, and identified information and documentation to be submitted to the Council with the proposed budget for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1992.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Submission Date for the Fiscal Year 1993 Budget Approval Resolution of 1991: Pursuant to Resolution 9-151, effective December 27, 1991, the Council established the date by which the Mayor shall submit to the Council the proposed budget for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1993, and to identify information and documentation to be submitted to the Council with the proposed budget for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1993.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Submission Date for the Fiscal Year 1995 Budget Approval Resolution of 1993: Pursuant to Resolution 10-206, effective December 24, 1993, the Council established the date by which the Mayor shall submit to the Council the proposed budget for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1995, and to identify information and documentation to be submitted to the Council with the proposed budget for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1995.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Fiscal Year 1996 Budget Submission Date Extension Emergency Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Resolution 11-16, effective February 7, 1995, the Council extended, on an emergency basis, the date of submission by the Mayor of the Fiscal Year 1996 budget to the Council.</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Amendment of Mayor’s Order 83-19 January 3, 1983, Establishment of Office of Financial Management: See Mayor’s Order 88-13, January 22, 1988.</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Agency Budget and Resource Utilization Advisory Committees established: See Mayor’s Order 88-239, October 26, 1988.</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment of Mayor’s Advisory Committee on Resources and Budget: See Mayor’s Order 89-207, September 12, 1989.</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment of District of Columbia Commission on Budget and Financial Priorities: See Mayor’s Order 89-224, October 5, 1989.</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Amendment of Mayor’s Order 89-224: Establishment—D.C. Commission on Budget and Financial Priorities: See Mayor’s Order 90-198, December 13, 1990.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Enactment upon adoption of federal legislation: Section 4 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 11-254">D.C. Law 11-254</law-cite> provided that “§§ <cite path="§47-101">47-101</cite>, <cite path="§47-117">47-117</cite>, <cite path="§47-130">47-130</cite>, <cite path="§47-301">47-301</cite>, <cite path="§47-302">47-302</cite>, <cite path="§47-303">47-303</cite>, <cite path="§47-304">47-304</cite>, <cite path="§47-304.1">47-304.1</cite>, <cite path="§47-305">47-305</cite>, <cite path="§47-310">47-310</cite>, <cite path="§47-312">47-312</cite>, <cite path="§47-317.1">47-317.1</cite> through <cite path="§47-317.6">47-317.6</cite>, <cite path="§47-321">47-321</cite> through <cite path="§47-325">47-325</cite>, <cite path="§47-327">47-327</cite> through <cite path="§47-331">47-331</cite>, and <cite path="§47-332">47-332</cite> through 47-334 of Title 47 §§ <cite path="§1-204.41">1-204.41</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.55">1-204.55</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.50">1-204.50</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.42">1-204.42</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.43">1-204.43</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.44">1-204.44</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.46">1-204.46</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.53">1-204.53</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.47">1-204.47</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.48">1-204.48</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.49">1-204.49</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.24a">1-204.24a</cite> through <cite path="§1-204.24e">1-204.24e</cite>, <cite path="§47-317.06">47-317.06</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.61">1-204.61</cite> through <cite path="§1-204.65">1-204.65</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.71">1-204.71</cite> through <cite path="§1-204.75">1-204.75</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.81">1-204.81</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.85">1-204.85</cite>, <cite path="§1-204.86">1-204.86</cite> and <cite path="§1-204.90">1-204.90</cite>, 2001 Ed. of the District of Columbia Code shall be enacted as part of Title 47 upon the adoption by Congress of legislation so enacting these sections.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3102 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</law-cite> amended Section 2102 of the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Act of 1999 to read as follows:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“In submitting fiscal year budgets to the Council for fiscal years beginning with fiscal year 2001, there should be a guide for calculating the increase in annual expenditures of local funds. This guide should be an increase of no more than 3% over the prior fiscal year’s expenditures of local funds.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Definitions applicable: The definitions in § <cite path="§1-202">1-202</cite> apply to this subchapter.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4102 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</law-cite> provided: “Sec. 4102. Limit on increase in spending. For fiscal year 2004 the Mayor shall not submit a budget to the Council that increases spending by more than 4% of the fiscal year 2003 budget approved by the Council.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 1202 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</law-cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) For fiscal year 2005, the Mayor shall submit a budget to the Council that increases local funds spending by no more than 3.5% of the fiscal year 2004 budget approved by the Council. Any spending transferred from local funds in fiscal year 2004 to non-local funds in Fiscal year 2005 shall be included in any calculation to determine whether the proposed spending for fiscal year 2005 is more than 3.5% greater than local spending in fiscal year 2004.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) By July 1, 2003, the Chief Financial Officer and the Mayor shall identify by contract or subagency, the areas where contract savings identified by the Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Request Act, passed on May 6, 2003 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-214) shall occur and submit the information to Council.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) The budget submission pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall provide that not less than ½ of the personnel costs for Public Safety Communications Center services in fiscal year 2004 shall instead be paid by local funds in fiscal year 2005.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 1092 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</law-cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“For fiscal year 2005, the Department of Employment Services (‘DOES’) shall have:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) No more than 513 full time equivalent (‘FTE’) employees; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) A total budget of $88,846,102, to be allocated as follows:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(A)(i) Personal services budget not to exceed $32,314,000;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(ii) Nonpersonal services budget not to exceed $56,532,000, including not less than $29,965,000 for Subsidies and Transfers;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(B) From the funds identified herein, no less than $764,000 shall be made available for the Office of Apprenticeship and Information Training; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(C) From the funds identified herein, no more than $686,000 shall be made available for security costs.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The budget allocations set forth in paragraph (2)(A) of subsection (a) shall apply to budgeted funds only and exclude any additional grant funds or special purpose funds not included in the fiscal year 2005 budget. The allocations are subject to the following adjustments if there are grant fund or special purpose fund budget modifications approved by the Council: 36% of any budget modifications shall be allocated to personal services and 64% shall be allocated to nonpersonal services.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Deadline for submission of revised revenue estimate: Section 124 of Pub. L. 102-382, 106 Stat. 1433, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1993, provided that no later than 30 days after the end of the first quarter of the fiscal year ending September 30, 1993, the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall submit to the Council of the District of Columbia the new fiscal year 1993 revenue estimates as of the end of the first quarter of fiscal year 1993. These estimates shall be used in the budget request for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1994. The officially revised estimates at midyear shall be used for the midyear report.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 123 of the Joint Resolution Making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2015, and for other purposes, approved September 19, 2014 (Pub. L. 113-164; 128 Stat. 1871) provided: “Notwithstanding any other provision of this joint resolution, except section 106, the District of Columbia may expend local funds under the heading ‘District of Columbia Funds’ for such programs and activities under title IV of H.R. 5016 (113th Congress), as passed by the House of Representatives on July 16, 2014, at the rate set forth under ‘District of Columbia Funds—Summary of Expenses’ as included in the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Request Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-370), as modified as of the date of the enactment of this joint resolution.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Title IV of Division E of Pub. L. 113-235, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2015, approved December 16, 2014 (Pub. L. 113-235; 128 Stat. 2130 at 2342) provided: “Title IV—District of Columbia; Federal Funds; Federal Payment for Resident Tuition Support.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia, to be deposited into a dedicated account, for a nationwide program to be administered by the Mayor, for District of Columbia resident tuition support, $30,000,000, to remain available until expended: Provided, That such funds, including any interest accrued thereon, may be used on behalf of eligible District of Columbia residents to pay an amount based upon the difference between in-State and out-of-State tuition at public institutions of higher education, or to pay up to $2,500 each year at eligible private institutions of higher education: Provided further, That the awarding of such funds may be prioritized on the basis of a resident's academic merit, the income and need of eligible students and such other factors as may be authorized: Provided further, That the District of Columbia government shall maintain a dedicated account for the Resident Tuition Support Program that shall consist of the Federal funds appropriated to the Program in this Act and any subsequent appropriations, any unobligated balances from prior fiscal years, and any interest earned in this or any fiscal year: Provided further, That the account shall be under the control of the District of Columbia Chief Financial Officer, who shall use those funds solely for the purposes of carrying out the Resident Tuition Support Program: Provided further, That the Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall provide a quarterly financial report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate for these funds showing, by object class, the expenditures made and the purpose therefor.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia. For a Federal payment of necessary expenses, as determined by the Mayor of the District of Columbia in written consultation with the elected county or city officials of surrounding jurisdictions, $12,500,000, to remain available until expended, for the costs of providing public safety at events related to the presence of the National Capital in the District of Columbia, including support requested by the Director of the United States Secret Service in carrying out protective duties under the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for the costs of providing support to respond to immediate and specific terrorist threats or attacks in the District of Columbia or surrounding jurisdictions.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment to the District of Columbia Courts. For salaries and expenses for the District of Columbia Courts, $245,110,000 to be allocated as follows: for the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, $13,622,000, of which not to exceed $2,500 is for official reception and representation expenses; for the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, $116,443,000, of which not to exceed $2,500 is for official reception and representation expenses; for the District of Columbia Court System, $71,155,000, of which not to exceed $2,500 is for official reception and representation expenses; and $43,890,000, to remain available until September 30, 2016, for capital improvements for District of Columbia courthouse facilities: Provided, That funds made available for capital improvements shall be expended consistent with the District of Columbia Courts master plan study and facilities condition assessment: Provided further, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, all amounts under this heading shall be apportioned quarterly by the Office of Management and Budget and obligated and expended in the same manner as funds appropriated for salaries and expenses of other Federal agencies: Provided further, That 30 days after providing written notice to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the District of Columbia Courts may reallocate not more than $6,000,000 of the funds provided under this heading among the items and entities funded under this heading: Provided further, That the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration in the District of Columbia may, by regulation, establish a program substantially similar to the program set forth in subchapter II of chapter 35 of title 5, United States Code, for employees of the District of Columbia Courts.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment for Defender Services in District of Columbia Courts. For payments authorized under  section 11-2604 and  section 11-2605, D.C. Official Code (relating to representation provided under the District of Columbia Criminal Justice Act), payments for counsel appointed in proceedings in the Family Court of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia under chapter 23 of title 16, D.C. Official Code, or pursuant to contractual agreements to provide guardian ad litem representation, training, technical assistance, and such other services as are necessary to improve the quality of guardian ad litem representation, payments for counsel appointed in adoption proceedings under chapter 3 of title 16, D.C. Official Code, and payments authorized under section 21–2060, D.C. Official Code (relating to services provided under the District of Columbia Guardianship, Protective Proceedings, and Durable Power of Attorney Act of 1986), $49,890,000, to remain available until expended: Provided, That funds provided under this heading shall be administered by the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration in the District of Columbia: Provided further, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, this appropriation shall be apportioned quarterly by the Office of Management and Budget and obligated and expended in the same manner as funds appropriated for expenses of other Federal agencies.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment to the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia. For salaries and expenses, including the transfer and hire of motor vehicles, of the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia, as authorized by the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, $234,000,000, of which not to exceed $2,000 is for official reception and representation expenses related to Community Supervision and Pretrial Services Agency programs, of which not to exceed $25,000 is for dues and assessments relating to the implementation of the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency Interstate Supervision Act of 2002; of which $173,155,000 shall be for necessary expenses of Community Supervision and Sex Offender Registration, to include expenses relating to the supervision of adults subject to protection orders or the provision of services for or related to such persons, of which up to $9,000,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2017, for the relocation of offender supervision field offices; and of which $60,845,000 shall be available to the Pretrial Services Agency: Provided, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, all amounts under this heading shall be apportioned quarterly by the Office of Management and Budget and obligated and expended in the same manner as funds appropriated for salaries and expenses of other Federal agencies: Provided further, That amounts under this heading may be used for programmatic incentives for offenders and defendants successfully meeting terms of supervision: Provided further, That the Director is authorized to accept and use gifts in the form of in-kind contributions of the following: space and hospitality to support offender and defendant programs; equipment, supplies, and vocational training services necessary to sustain, educate, and train offenders and defendants, including their dependent children; and programmatic incentives for offenders and defendants meeting terms of supervision: Provided further, That the Director shall keep accurate and detailed records of the acceptance and use of any gift under the previous proviso, and shall make such records available for audit and public inspection: Provided further, That the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency Director is authorized to accept and use reimbursement from the District of Columbia Government for space and services provided on a cost reimbursable basis.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment to the District of Columbia Public Defender Service. For salaries and expenses, including the transfer and hire of motor vehicles, of the District of Columbia Public Defender Service, as authorized by the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, $41,231,000, of which $1,150,000, to remain available until September 30, 2017, is for relocation of satellite offices: Provided, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, all amounts under this heading shall be apportioned quarterly by the Office of Management and Budget and obligated and expended in the same manner as funds appropriated for salaries and expenses of Federal agencies: Provided further, That, notwithstanding  section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, and in addition to the authority provided by the  District of Columbia Code Section 2-1607(b), upon approval of the Board of Trustees, the District of Columbia Public Defender Service may accept and use voluntary and uncompensated services for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the District of Columbia Public Defender Service: Provided further, That, notwithstanding  District of Columbia Code section 2-1603(d), for the purpose of any action brought against the Board of the Trustees of the District of Columbia Public Defender Service, the trustees shall be deemed to be employees of the Public Defender Service.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment to the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority. For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, $14,000,000, to remain available until expended, to continue implementation of the Combined Sewer Overflow Long-Term Plan: Provided, That the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority provides a 100 percent match for this payment.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council. For a Federal payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, $1,900,000, to remain available until expended, to support initiatives related to the coordination of Federal and local criminal justice resources in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions. For a Federal payment, to remain available until September 30, 2016, to the Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure, $295,000, and for the Judicial Nomination Commission, $270,000.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment for School Improvement. For a Federal payment for a school improvement program in the District of Columbia, $45,000,000, to remain available until expended, for payments authorized under the Scholarship for Opportunity and Results Act (division C of Public Law 112-10): Provided, That within funds provided for opportunity scholarships $3,000,000 shall be for the activities specified in sections 3007(b) through 3007(d) and 3009 of the Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment for the District of Columbia National Guard. For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia National Guard, $435,000, to remain available until expended for the Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Program.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Federal Payment for Testing and Treatment of HIV/AIDS. For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia for the testing of individuals for, and the treatment of individuals with, human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immunodeficiency syndrome in the District of Columbia, $5,000,000.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“District of Columbia Funds. Local funds are appropriated for the District of Columbia for the current fiscal year out of the General Fund of the District of Columbia (“General Fund”) for programs and activities set forth under the heading “District of Columbia Funds Summary of Expenses” and at the rate set forth under such heading, as included in the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Request Act of 2014 submitted to the Congress by the District of Columbia as amended as of the date of enactment of this Act: Provided, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in section 450A of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act ( section 1-204.50a, D.C. Official Code), sections 816 and 817 of the Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2009 ( secs. 47-369.01 and  47-369.02, D.C. Official Code), and provisions of this Act, the total amount appropriated in this Act for operating expenses for the District of Columbia for fiscal year 2015 under this heading shall not exceed the estimates included in the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Request Act of 2014 submitted to Congress by the District of Columbia as amended as of the date of enactment of this Act or the sum of the total revenues of the District of Columbia for such fiscal year: Provided further, That the amount appropriated may be increased by proceeds of one-time transactions, which are expended for emergency or unanticipated operating or capital needs: Provided further, That such increases shall be approved by enactment of local District law and shall comply with all reserve requirements contained in the District of Columbia Home Rule Act: Provided further, That the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia shall take such steps as are necessary to assure that the District of Columbia meets these requirements, including the apportioning by the Chief Financial Officer of the appropriations and funds made available to the District during fiscal year 2015, except that the Chief Financial Officer may not reprogram for operating expenses any funds derived from bonds, notes, or other obligations issued for capital projects.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“This title may be cited as the ‘District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2015’.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Title VIII of Division E of Pub. L. 113-235 (Pub. L. 113-235; 128 Stat. 2130 at 2393) provides the following: “General Provisions—District of Columbia (Including Transfers of Funds).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 801. There are appropriated from the applicable funds of the District of Columbia such sums as may be necessary for making refunds and for the payment of legal settlements or judgments that have been entered against the District of Columbia government.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 802. None of the Federal funds provided in this Act shall be used for publicity or propaganda purposes or implementation of any policy including boycott designed to support or defeat legislation pending before Congress or any State legislature.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 803. (a) None of the Federal funds provided under this Act to the agencies funded by this Act, both Federal and District government agencies, that remain available for obligation or expenditure in fiscal year 2015, or provided from any accounts in the Treasury of the United States derived by the collection of fees available to the agencies funded by this Act, shall be available for obligation or expenditures for an agency through a reprogramming of funds which—</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) creates new programs;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) eliminates a program, project, or responsibility center;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(3) establishes or changes allocations specifically denied, limited or increased under this Act;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(4) increases funds or personnel by any means for any program, project, or responsibility center for which funds have been denied or restricted;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(5) re-establishes any program or project previously deferred through reprogramming;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(6) augments any existing program, project, or responsibility center through a reprogramming of funds in excess of $3,000,000 or 10 percent, whichever is less; or</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(7) increases by 20 percent or more personnel assigned to a specific program, project or responsibility center, unless prior approval is received from the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The District of Columbia government is authorized to approve and execute reprogramming and transfer requests of local funds under this title through November 7, 2015.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 804. None of the Federal funds provided in this Act may be used by the District of Columbia to provide for salaries, expenses, or other costs associated with the offices of United States Senator or United States Representative under section 4(d) of the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiatives of 1979 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 3-171">D.C. Law 3-171</law-cite>; D.C. Official Code,  sec. 1-123).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 805. Except as otherwise provided in this section, none of the funds made available by this Act or by any other Act may be used to provide any officer or employee of the District of Columbia with an official vehicle unless the officer or employee uses the vehicle only in the performance of the officer's or employee's official duties. For purposes of this section, the term “official duties” does not include travel between the officer's or employee's residence and workplace, except in the case of—</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) an officer or employee of the Metropolitan Police Department who resides in the District of Columbia or is otherwise designated by the Chief of the Department;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) at the discretion of the Fire Chief, an officer or employee of the District of Columbia Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department who resides in the District of Columbia and is on call 24 hours a day;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(3) at the discretion of the Director of the Department of Corrections, an officer or employee of the District of Columbia Department of Corrections who resides in the District of Columbia and is on call 24 hours a day;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(4) at the discretion of the Chief Medical Examiner, an officer or employee of the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner who resides in the District of Columbia and is on call 24 hours a day;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(5) at the discretion of the Director of the Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency, an officer or employee of the Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency who resides in the District of Columbia and is on call 24 hours a day;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(6) the Mayor of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(7) the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 806. (a) None of the Federal funds contained in this Act may be used by the District of Columbia Attorney General or any other officer or entity of the District government to provide assistance for any petition drive or civil action which seeks to require Congress to provide for voting representation in Congress for the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 807. None of the Federal funds contained in this Act may be used to distribute any needle or syringe for the purpose of preventing the spread of blood borne pathogens in any location that has been determined by the local public health or local law enforcement authorities to be inappropriate for such distribution.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 808. Nothing in this Act may be construed to prevent the Council or Mayor of the District of Columbia from addressing the issue of the provision of contraceptive coverage by health insurance plans, but it is the intent of Congress that any legislation enacted on such issue should include a ‘conscience clause’ which provides exceptions for religious beliefs and moral convictions.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 809. (a) None of the Federal funds contained in this Act may be used to enact or carry out any law, rule, or regulation to legalize or otherwise reduce penalties associated with the possession, use, or distribution of any schedule I substance under the Controlled Substances Act ( 21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.) or any tetrahydrocannabinols derivative.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“ (b) None of the funds contained in this Act may be used to enact any law, rule, or regulation to legalize or otherwise reduce penalties associated with the possession, use, or distribution of any schedule I substance under the Controlled Substances Act ( 21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.) or any tetrahydrocannabinols derivative for recreational purposes.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 810. None of the funds appropriated under this Act shall be expended for any abortion except where the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term or where the pregnancy is the result of an act of rape or incest.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 811. (a) No later than 30 calendar days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, the Mayor, and the Council of the District of Columbia, a revised appropriated funds operating budget in the format of the budget that the District of Columbia government submitted pursuant to section 442 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (D.C. Official Code,  sec. 1-204.42), for all agencies of the District of Columbia government for fiscal year 2015 that is in the total amount of the approved appropriation and that realigns all budgeted data for personal services and other-than-personal services, respectively, with anticipated actual expenditures.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) This section shall apply only to an agency for which the Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia certifies that a reallocation is required to address unanticipated changes in program requirements.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 812. No later than 30 calendar days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, the Mayor, and the Council for the District of Columbia, a revised appropriated funds operating budget for the District of Columbia Public Schools that aligns schools budgets to actual enrollment. The revised appropriated funds budget shall be in the format of the budget that the District of Columbia government submitted pursuant to section 442 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (D.C. Official Code,  Sec. 1-204.42).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 813. (a) Amounts appropriated in this Act as operating funds may be transferred to the District of Columbia's enterprise and capital funds and such amounts, once transferred, shall retain appropriation authority consistent with the provisions of this Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The District of Columbia government is authorized to reprogram or transfer for operating expenses any local funds transferred or reprogrammed in this or the four prior fiscal years from operating funds to capital funds, and such amounts, once transferred or reprogrammed, shall retain appropriation authority consistent with the provisions of this Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) The District of Columbia government may not transfer or reprogram for operating expenses any funds derived from bonds, notes, or other obligations issued for capital projects.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 814. None of the Federal funds appropriated in this Act shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year, nor may any be transferred to other appropriations, unless expressly so provided herein.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 815. Except as otherwise specifically provided by law or under this Act, not to exceed 50 percent of unobligated balances remaining available at the end of fiscal year 2015 from appropriations of Federal funds made available for salaries and expenses for fiscal year 2015 in this Act, shall remain available through September 30, 2016, for each such account for the purposes authorized: Provided, That a request shall be submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate for approval prior to the expenditure of such funds: Provided further, That these requests shall be made in compliance with reprogramming guidelines outlined in section 803 of this Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 816. (a) During fiscal year 2016, during a period in which neither a District of Columbia continuing resolution or a regular District of Columbia appropriation bill is in effect, local funds are appropriated in the amount provided for any project or activity for which local funds are provided in the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Request Act of 2015 as submitted to Congress (subject to any modifications enacted by the District of Columbia as of the beginning of the period during which this subsection is in effect) at the rate set forth by such Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) Appropriations made by subsection (a) shall cease to be available—</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) during any period in which a District of Columbia continuing resolution for fiscal year 2016 is in effect; or</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) upon the enactment into law of the regular District of Columbia appropriation bill for fiscal year 2016.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) An appropriation made by subsection (a) is provided under the authority and conditions as provided under this Act and shall be available to the extent and in the manner that would be provided by this Act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(d) An appropriation made by subsection (a) shall cover all obligations or expenditures incurred for such project or activity during the portion of fiscal year 2016 for which this section applies to such project or activity.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(e) This section shall not apply to a project or activity during any period of fiscal year 2016 if any other provision of law (other than an authorization of appropriations)—</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) makes an appropriation, makes funds available, or grants authority for such project or activity to continue for such period; or</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) specifically provides that no appropriation shall be made, no funds shall be made available, or no authority shall be granted for such project or activity to continue for such period.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(f) Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect obligations of the government of the District of Columbia mandated by other law.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 817. Except as expressly provided otherwise, any reference to ‘this Act’ contained in this title or in title IV shall be treated as referring only to the provisions of this title or of title IV.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“This division may be cited as the ‘Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2015’.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
