<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-204.03</num>
  <heading>Compensation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each member of the Council shall receive compensation, payable in periodic installments, at a rate equal to the maximum rate as may be established from time to time for grade 12 of the General Schedule under § 5332 of Title 5 of the United States Code. On and after the end of the 2-year period beginning on the day the members of the Council first elected under this chapter take office, the Council may, by act, increase or decrease such rate of compensation. Such change in compensation, upon enactment by the Council in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, shall apply with respect to the term of members of the Council beginning after the date of enactment of such change.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All members of the Council shall receive additional allowances for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties of office as may be approved by the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Chairman shall not engage in any employment (whether as an employee or as a self-employed individual) or hold any position (other than his position as Chairman), for which he is compensated in an amount in excess of his actual expenses in connection therewith.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), as of December 21, 2001, the Chairman shall receive compensation, payable in equal installments, at a rate equal to $10,000 less than the annual compensation of the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-198" type="History">Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 787, Pub. L. 93-198, title IV, § 403</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 107-96" type="History">Dec. 21, 2001, 107 Stat. 957, Pub. L. 107-96, § 136</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Campaign finance, see § <cite path="§1-1101.01">1-1101.01</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Compensation of Mayor and councilmembers, see § <cite path="§1-611.09">1-611.09</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, coverage and limitations, see § <cite path="§1-602.02">1-602.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-123">1-123</cite>, § <cite path="§1-204.02">1-204.02</cite>, § <cite path="§1-301.85">1-301.85</cite>, § <cite path="§1-602.02">1-602.02</cite>, § <cite path="§1-611.09">1-611.09</cite>, and § <cite path="§1-611.54">1-611.54</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-226.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-143.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 107-96, in subsec. (c), deleted “shall receive, in addition to the compensation to which he is entitled as a member of the Council, $10,000 per annum, payable in equal installments, for each year he serves as Chairman, but the Chairman” preceding “shall not engage”; and added subsec. (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Request for Congressional action: Pursuant to § 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-168">D.C. Law 10-168</cite> and § 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-225">D.C. Law 10-225</cite> the Council requested that the United States Congress enact legislation to repeal subsection (c) of this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
