<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-303.43</num>
  <heading>Regulations relative to firearms, explosives, and weapons.</heading>
  <text>The Council of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and empowered to make, and the Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and empowered to enforce, all such usual and reasonable police regulations, in addition to those already made under §§ <cite path="§1-303.01">1-303.01</cite> to 1-303.03 as the Council may deem necessary for the regulation of firearms, projectiles, explosives, or weapons of any kind in the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 30, 1906, 34 Stat. 809, ch. 3932, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Dangerous weapons, criminal provisions, see § <cite path="§22-4501">22-4501</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Dangerous weapons, licensing, regulation and supervision of dealers, see § <cite path="§47-2838">47-2838</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Firearms, fireworks, or loud noises, prohibition on Capitol grounds, see § <cite path="§10-503.16">10-503.16</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-321.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-227.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(4) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
