<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-306.04</num>
  <heading>Preserving and ensuring community input.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Continuous community input into every phase of development of titles I through XII of section 3 (the “Comprehensive Plan”), from conception to adoption to implementation, is essential to assure that the Comprehensive Plan in all its elements is the valid expression of District residents, property owners, commercial interests, and other groups and individuals in the District. A variety of means to secure community input should be utilized, including advisory and technical committees, community workshops, review of draft texts, public forums and hearings, and other means of discussion and communication. The District government, through its executive and legislative branches, will strive to ensure that the Comprehensive Plan, in all its elements, is both responsive and responsible.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Community input into the implementation of the District elements of the Comprehensive Plan will be assured by the requirement of a periodic review. Not less frequently than once every 4 years, beginning March 31, 2000, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a report, accompanied by a proposed resolution, on the progress made by the government of the District of Columbia in implementing the District elements of the Comprehensive Plan. The Council shall schedule a public hearing on the progress report and, following each review period, submit to the Mayor the findings of the Council and a copy of the public testimony on the progress report.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each progress report shall indicate the progress made in implementing Comprehensive Plan Actions during the reporting period and the key projected implementation activities by land use policy for the next 5 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit periodically to the Council for its consideration proposed amendments to the Comprehensive Plan. Such amendments shall be submitted not less frequently than once every 4 years, beginning March 31, 2002, and shall be accompanied by an environmental assessment of the proposed amendments. Proposed amendments may also be submitted by the Mayor to the Council at any other time that the Mayor determines to be necessary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The process for executive branch consideration of proposed amendments to the Comprehensive Plan initiated by District agencies or the public shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Standards for appropriateness;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A format and deadline for submission of amendments;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Public meetings to be held by the executive;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A mechanism for public review of all proposed amendment submissions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A mechanism for public review of the Mayor’s proposed amendments; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Submission by the Mayor to the Council of proposed amendments to the Comprehensive Plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-76" type="History" path="§9">Apr. 10, 1984, D.C. Law 5-76, § 8 [9]</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-129" type="History">as added May 23, 1990, D.C. Law 8-129, § 3(a)(2), 37 DCR 55</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-193" type="History">Oct. 6, 1994, D.C. Law 10-193, § 3(a)(2), 41 DCR 5536</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-275" type="History">Apr. 27, 1999, D.C. Law 12-275, § 2(c), 46 DCR 1441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-300" type="History">Mar. 8, 2007, D.C. Law 16-300, § 2(c), 54 DCR 924</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§1-301.65">1-301.65</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-248.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-300">D.C. Law 16-300</law-cite> rewrote subsec. (c) which had read as follows: “(c) Each progress report shall indicate the progress made in implementing the Land Use Element of the Comprehensive Plan by land use policy during the reporting period and the key projected implementation activities by land use policy for the next five years.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">For effective date of District elements of Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§1-306.02">1-306.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“Titles I through XII of section 3 (the ‘Comprehensive Plan’)” referred to in the first sentence of (a), refers to § 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 5-76">D.C. Law 5-76</law-cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-558, the “Progress Report on Implementing the Comprehensive Plan Findings Resolution of 2004”, was approved effective June 1, 2004.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Pursuant to Resolution 9-267, effective July 10, 1992, the Council resolved to submit to the Mayor the findings of the Council on the Mayor’s 4th biennial progress report on implementing the District of Columbia Elements of the Comprehensive Plan.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
