<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-301.81</num>
  <heading>Duties of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia (“Attorney General”) shall have charge and conduct of all law business of the said District and all suits instituted by and against the government thereof, and shall possess all powers afforded the Attorney General by the common and statutory law of the District and shall be responsible for upholding the public interest. The Attorney General shall have the power to control litigation and appeals, as well as the power to intervene in legal proceedings on behalf of this public interest.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General shall furnish opinions in writing to the Mayor and the Council whenever requested to do so. All requests for opinions from agencies subordinate to the Mayor shall be transmitted through the Mayor. The Attorney General shall keep a record of requests, together with the opinions. Those opinions of the Attorney General issued pursuant to Reorganization Order No. 50 shall be compiled and published by the Attorney General on an annual basis.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The authority provided under this section shall not be construed to deny or limit the duty and authority of the Attorney General as heretofore authorized, either by statute or under common law.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-160" type="History" path="§101">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-160, § 101, 57 DCR 3012</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-1001.02">1-1001.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
