<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-301.182</num>
  <heading>Powers of the Unit.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In analyzing compliance for the relevant projects under the purview of the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, the Unit is authorized to look at:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All contracts for completed projects;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All contracts for projects currently being developed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All contracts for projects developed after June 13, 2008;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>All relevant statutes and regulations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>All procurement documents, including requests for proposals, requests for expressions of interest, requests for qualifications, and responses;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>All relevant budget documents;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>All documents related to payment of contractors;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>All staffing schemes and position descriptions related to the project under review; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Any other relevant books, accounts, records, reports, findings, and all other papers, things, or property belonging to or in use by the District government and contractor necessary to analyzing compliance.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To carry out its duties, the Unit is authorized to make site visits and meet with government and private-sector project staff members to evaluate whether each project was completed, or is being completed, in accordance with the documents referenced in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In reviewing the annual report required by §§ <cite path="§2-218.50">2-218.50</cite> and <cite path="§2-218.53">2-218.53</cite>, and the annual report, the Unit is authorized to look at any contracts, accounts, records, reports, findings, and all other papers, things, or property belonging to or in use by the District government and contractor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-176" type="History" path="§3">June 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-176, § 3, 55 DCR 5390</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2221(b), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2221(b) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2221(b) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
