<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-307.03</num>
  <heading>Medical assistance expansion program establishment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish a program to expand medical assistance to adult District residents with an annual family income up to 200% of the federal poverty level.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may provide medical assistance to eligible residents by making arrangements with managed care providers either on a fee-for-service or capitated basis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Enrollees of the program shall select a health maintenance organization with a current contract with the District to provide managed care services.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall assign any enrollee who does not choose a provider within a reasonable period of time to the District of Columbia Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In fiscal year 2000, the Mayor may establish a pilot project to expand Medicaid coverage to not more than 2,400 adult District residents.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The funding for the pilot shall be derived by amending the Disproportionate Share adjustment paid to hospitals.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>To implement any expansion for adult District residents with an annual family income up to 200% of the federal poverty level the Mayor shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Seek and obtain all necessary waivers of federal Medicaid statutes, rules, and regulations; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Amend the District State Medicaid plan.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish a program to provide medical assistance to undocumented children not eligible for coverage under Medicaid who reside in the District and have an annual family income up to 200% of the federal poverty level.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may provide medical assistance to eligible residents by making arrangements with managed care providers either on a fee-for-service or capitated basis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Enrollees of the program shall select a health maintenance organization with a current contract with the District to provide managed care services.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall assign any enrollee who does not choose a provider within a reasonable period of time to the District of Columbia Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>In fiscal year 2000, the Mayor shall establish a pilot program to provide medical assistance to not more than 500 immigrant children not eligible to be covered under Medicaid.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Beginning with fiscal year 2001, the Mayor may increase enrollment contingent upon the certification by the Chief Financial Officer of the availability of funding and subject to the District’s financial plan and budget.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may provide financial support to providers to register the uninsured in conformity with the financial plan and budget.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section, § <cite path="§1-307.05">1-307.05</cite>, or § <cite path="§1-307.06">1-307.06</cite> shall be deemed to create or constitute an entitlement or right to medical coverage.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-38" type="History" path="§2202">Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-38, § 2202, 46 DCR 6373</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 4802(a), 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 7009, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-307.06">1-307.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-360.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite>, in subsec. (b)(4), substituted “immigrant” for “undocumented”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Sections 3902 and 3903 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite> provided:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“Sec. 3902. The Medical Assistance Administration (‘MAA’) shall work closely with all District agencies and the Budget Director of the Council of the District of Columbia, in establishing Medicaid rates and Medicaid waiver programs to maximize Federal dollars as a means of reimbursement for services provided by District of Columbia agencies.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“Sec. 3903. MAA shall submit to the Council no later than 15 days after the end of each quarter a report that identifies new District agency programs that are participating in the Medicaid program and the potential savings in local funds associated with their participation.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, in subsec. (e), deleted the first sentence which read: “This section, § <cite path="§1-307.05">1-307.05</cite>, and § <cite path="§1-307.06">1-307.06</cite> are subject to the availability of appropriations.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of section, see § 902 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-41, March 31, 1999,  46 DCR 3446).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) directive to Medical Assistance Administration to work with District agencies and the Council Budget Director to establish rates and programs to maximize Federal reimbursement dollars and to report to the Council on new agency programs participating in Medicaid, see §§ 3902 and 3903 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 3902, 3903, and 4802 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7009 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7009 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 2201 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-38">D.C. Law 13-38</cite> provided: “This title may be cited as the ‘Medical Assistance Expansion Program Act of 1999’.”</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Short title: Section 5051 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> provided that subtitle T of title V of the act may be cited as the “Medicaid Fee-For-Service State Plan Amendment Act of 2008”.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 5052 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> provided: “By October 1, 2008, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a Medicaid state plan amendment that will increase the specialty physician and primary care physician reimbursement rates under the District Medicaid fee-for-service program to match the specialty physician and primary care physician reimbursement rates under the federal Medicare program.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
