<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-307.85</num>
  <heading>Advisory Council to the Agency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Advisory Council to the Agency to assist and advise the Risk Officer regarding the Agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Advisory Council shall consist of 7 members appointed by the Risk Officer. One member shall represent the District of Columbia Primary Care Association, 2 members shall represent District health centers, 2 members shall have expertise in general property insurance and re-insurance, and 2 members shall have general insurance expertise, whether medical malpractice or general property insurance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Risk Officer and the captive manager shall serve as ex officio members of the Advisory Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Risk Officer shall serve as chairperson of the Advisory Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, Advisory Council members shall serve terms of 3 years. An Advisory Council member’s term shall continue until his or her successor is appointed. The Advisory Council members may be reappointed for additional terms.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Risk Officer shall determine the terms the initial Advisory Council members shall serve. Three of the Advisory Council members shall serve terms of 2 years, 2 shall serve terms of 4 years, and 2 shall serve terms of 6 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Vacancies in the Advisory Council shall be filled by the Risk Officer. Advisory Council members may be removed by the Risk Officer for cause.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Advisory Council members shall not be compensated in their capacity as Advisory Council members, but shall be reimbursed for reasonable expenses incurred in the necessary performance of their duties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Advisory Council shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Advise the Risk Officer in the general oversight of the Agency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Assess the needs and interests of the health centers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2A)</num>
      <text>Assess the needs and interests of the District with respect to obtaining property insurance through the Agency; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Meet at least on an annual basis, at meetings announced by the Risk Officer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-196">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-196, § 6, 55 DCR 6261</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 239, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1032(d), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="1-307.81">1-307.81</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in subsec. (e).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> rewrote (b); and added (i)(2A) and made a related change.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1032(d) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1032(d) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <annotation>Section 1031 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle D of Title I of the act may be cited as the “Captive Insurance Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
