<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-319.03</num>
  <heading>Conflicts of interest; ineligibility for employee benefits; liability of District for torts of volunteers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Volunteer citizens may not assist governmental programs until regulations have been properly promulgated under the authority of §§ <cite path="§1-319.01">1-319.01</cite> to 1-319.05. No volunteer may be placed in any position likely to constitute a conflict of interest or the appearance of a conflict of interest in violation of the provisions of Chapter 29 of Title 18, United States Code, or Parts C and D of subchapter II of Chapter 11A of this title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Persons engaged as volunteers by the District of Columbia government as authorized by this section shall not be eligible for benefits provided to employees of the District of Columbia government under Chapters 81, 83, 85, 87, and 89 of Title 5, United States Code.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All volunteers shall be considered employees of the District of Columbia government for the purposes of §§ <cite path="§2-411">2-411</cite> to 2-416.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia shall be liable to third parties for tortious injury caused by volunteers under its supervision and control.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-12" type="History" path="§4">June 28, 1977, D.C. Law 2-12, § 4, 24 DCR 1442</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 501(i), 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">In addition to the references to Title 5 of the United States Code found in (b), there is now a Chapter 84, Retirement.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 401(i) of Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-298, January 29, 2012,  59 DCR 683).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-124">D.C. Law 19-124</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “parts C and D of subchapter II of Chapter 11A of this title” for “part F of subchapter I of Chapter 11 of this title”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-215c.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-306.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
