<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-315.06</num>
  <heading>Transmittal of District of Columbia government organization chart.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor shall annually submit to the Council, on or before February 1st for a 45-day period of review, a revised chart detailing the organization and structure of the District government that shall reflect any reorganization plans or legislative changes relating to the structure of the District government. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the chart, by resolution, within a 45-day review period, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days of Council recess, the chart shall be deemed approved.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-42" type="History" path="§7">Oct. 17, 1981, D.C. Law 4-42, § 7, 28 DCR 3425</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-201" type="History">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-201, § 4(b), 36 DCR 248</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-299.6.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment — Historical Records Advisory Board, see Mayor’s Order 2002-150, September 13, 2002 ( 49 DCR 8615).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Official organizational structure of District government: Pursuant to this section, the organizational structure set forth below is the official organizational structure of the District of Columbia government as enacted by <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-139">D.C. Law 7-139</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Commission on Cooperative Economic Development abolished: Section 401(k) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-86">D.C. Law 12-86</cite>, effective April 29, 1998, provided that the Commission on Cooperative Economic Development, established by Mayor’s Order 80-168, issued May 29, 1980 ( 27 DCR 2596), is abolished. Community Advisory Board on the Deinstitutionalization of Forest Haven abolished: Section 401(m) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-86">D.C. Law 12-86</cite>, effective April 29, 1998 provided that the community Advisory Board on the Deinstitutionalization of Forest Haven, established by Mayor’s Order 86-177, issued October 1, 1986 ( 33 DCR 6963), is abolished. History Records Advisory Board abolished: Section 401(q) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-86">D.C. Law 12-86</cite>, effective April 29, 1998, provided that the Historical Records Advisory Board, established by Mayor’s Order 84-35, issued February 10, 1984 ( 31 DCR 799), is abolished. Traffic Safety Advisory Committee abolished: Section 401(cc) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-86">D.C. Law 12-86</cite>, effective April 29, 1998, provided that the Traffic Safety Advisory Committee, established by Mayor’s Order 84-228, issued December 13, 1984 ( 32 DCR 226), is abolished. Mayor’s Policy Advisory Committee for Weatherization of Low-Income Homes abolished: Section 401(ee) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-86">D.C. Law 12-86</cite>, effective April 29, 1998, provided that the Mayor’s Policy Advisory Committee for Weatherization of Low-Income Homes, established by Mayor’s Order 89-12, issued January 6, 1989 ( 36 DCR 1260), is abolished.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
