<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-325.173</num>
  <heading>H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area business development.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall publish no later than 120 days after April 8, 2011, and no less than annually after that date, a notice of funding availability to make grants to assist retail development projects which generate new jobs in new or improved existing retail space in the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Eligible development projects shall include businesses engaged in the sale of home furnishings, apparel, books, art, groceries, and general merchandise to specialized customers or service-oriented businesses providing a direct service to specialized customers or artistic endeavors, such as art galleries, theaters, or performing arts centers. Special consideration shall be given to businesses that include entrepreneurial and innovative retail elements.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Eligible retail development projects shall not include liquor stores, restaurants whose annual alcohol sales exceed 20%, nightclubs, phone stores, or businesses with 20 or more locations in the United States.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Eligibility for retail development projects shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Site control of the property either through fee simple ownership of the site or through an executed contract or lease with the property owner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Direct frontage on the H Street, N.E., corridor from 3rd Street, N.E., to 15th Street, N.E.;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Execution of a First Source Agreement with the District’s Department of Employment Services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Adherence to design, construction, and rehabilitation requirements as defined by DMPED.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-354" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-354, § 4, 58 DCR 754</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2162(b), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-262" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-262, § 4, 62 DCR 15116</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-325.172">1-325.172</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> rewrote (b); and repealed (c)(3), which read: “Total retail space which is not less than 1,200 square feet.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-262">D.C. Law 20-262</cite> added “whose annual alcohol sales exceed 20%” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Incentive Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-170">D.C. Law 20-170</cite>, March 7, 2015, 61 DCR 12121).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 4 and 5 of the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-1">D.C. Law 21-1</cite>, June 4, 2015,  62 DCR 4550).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2162(b) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2162(b) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Incentive Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-460, Oct. 24, 2014, 61 DCR 11377, 20 STAT 4367).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 4 and 5 of the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-6, Feb. 23, 2015,  62 DCR 2474, 21 STAT 805).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3 of the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-65, May 22, 2015,  62 DCR 6865, 21 DCSTAT 1444).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
