<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-325.211</num>
  <heading>Neighborhood Parade and Festival Fund established.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Neighborhood Parade and Festival Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Commission on Arts and Humanities, to be used for the purposes set forth in subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Deposits into the Fund shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Federal funds, if any;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Gifts, grants, and donations; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>An annual appropriation of $107,000.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (c) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used for parades, festivals, and any other celebrations sponsored by a neighborhood or civic association.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commission on Arts and Humanities is authorized to make grants for the purposes described in this section. Grants made under this section shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of this chapter [§ <cite path="§1-328.11">1-328.11</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2033, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 2002(b), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§39-204">39-204</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> substituted “Commission on Arts and Humanities” for “Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development” in (a); added (b)(1)(C) and made related changes; and added (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see § 2033 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see § 2035 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2002(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2002(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 2001 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title II of the act may be cited as the “Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development Limited Grant-Making Authority Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite>: Section 11001 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
