<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-325.222</num>
  <heading>Innovation Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Innovation Fund (“Fund”) to provide subgrants to nonprofit organizations in education, job training, health, services for seniors, arts, public safety, and the environment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall make a grant to a single grant-managing entity of which at least 94% shall be used to make subgrants for the purpose of promoting a growing economy, educational improvement, increasing sustainability, and improving the quality of life for all residents. The remaining 6% shall be utilized for administrative expenses and evaluation of the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund is designed to provide subgrants to nonprofits in education, job training, health, services for seniors, arts, public safety, and the environment. The funds shall be available for conveyance to a grant-managing entity for the purposes identified in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subgrants shall be awarded, subject to the availability of funding, as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All subgrants shall be awarded on a competitive basis;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The subgrants shall not exceed $100,000 per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Capacity-building subgrants are one-time and can be carried over for a maximum of 3 years;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Program-development subgrants are limited to a maximum of 3 years and contingent on first-year grant outcomes;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The subgrant funds shall be used exclusively to serve District of Columbia residents;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Independent review panels shall be used as part of the subgrant selection process; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>All subgrants shall be subject to District transparency requirements, such as Freedom of Information Act requests.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of this chapter [§ <cite path="§1-328.11">1-328.11</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1013, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-325.221">1-325.221</cite> and § <cite path="§1-325.223">1-325.223</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 1013 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 1013 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
