<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-328.11</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this part, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Candidate” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§1-1161.01">1-1161.01</cite>(6).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Contribution” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§1-1161.01">1-1161.01</cite>(10).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Covered recipient” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>An elected District official who is or could be involved in influencing or approving the award of a grant;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A candidate for elective District office who is or could be involved in influencing or approving the award of a grant;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A political committee affiliated with a District candidate or elected District official described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>A constituent-service program or fund, or substantially similar entity, controlled, operated, or managed by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>An elected District official who is or could be involved in influencing or approving the award of a grant; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>A person under the supervision, direction, or control of an elected District official who is or could be involved in influencing or approving the award of a grant;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>A political party; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>An entity or organization:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>That a candidate or elected District official described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph, or a member of his or her immediate family, controls; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>In which a candidate or elected District official described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph has an ownership interest of 10% or more.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Election” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§1-1161.01">1-1161.01</cite>(15).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Grant” means financial assistance to a person to support or stimulate the accomplishment of a public purpose as defined by the law that authorizes the grant; provided, that the organization, not the District, defines the specific services, the service levels, and the program approach for carrying out the grant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Grant program” means the management or administration by a grantor of grant-making or grant-issuing authority as covered by this part.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Grantee” means a person that receives funds under a grant program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Grantor” means a District agency, board, commission, instrumentality, or program designated by law as the grant-managing entity for a grant program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Immediate family” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§1-1161.01">1-1161.01</cite>(26).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Person” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§1-1161.01">1-1161.01</cite>(42).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Political committee” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§1-1161.01">1-1161.01</cite>(44).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Political party” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§1-1161.01">1-1161.01</cite>(45).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1092, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 1053(a), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-325.162">1-325.162</cite>, § <cite path="§1-325.211">1-325.211</cite>, § <cite path="§1-325.222">1-325.222</cite>, § <cite path="§1-328.04">1-328.04</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1313">2-1313</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1373">2-1373</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1392">2-1392</cite>, § <cite path="§7-736.01">7-736.01</cite>, § <cite path="§7-1141.06">7-1141.06</cite>, and § <cite path="§32-1603">32-1603</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 1092 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 1092 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1053(a) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 1091 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle J of Title I of the act may be cited as the “Grant Administration Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
