<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-325.155</num>
  <heading>Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority project.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § <cite path="§1-325.156">1-325.156</cite> and notwithstanding any other provision of this part, the budget authority for an approved capital project shall be reprogrammed, pursuant to Chapter 3 of Title 47 [§  47-301 et seq.], for use pursuant to subchapter IV-A of Chapter 11 of Title 9 [§ <cite path="§9-1108.01">9-1108.01</cite> et seq.]; provided, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The capital project has been completed or the funds no longer considered necessary and budget authority remain available;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a capital project with a balance of more than $250,000, no funds have been expended or encumbered for 3 consecutive years, and the agency has not notified the Chief Financial Officer within 30 days of the end of the 3-year period that the agency intends to use the funds to implement the project within 18 months; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For a capital project with a remaining budget authority of $250,000 or less, the capital project has not been funded for 3 consecutive years.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If at any time the Chief Financial Officer determines that certain funds are not needed to meet the requirements of the WMATA project, those funds may be reprogrammed, pursuant to Chapter 3 of Title 47, to any capital project that the Chief Financial Officer certifies a funding need.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 1265, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 8042(f), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</law-cite> added “Except as provided in § <cite path="§1-325.155">1-325.155</cite> and” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1045 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-187, August 26, 2009,  56 DCR 7374).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1265 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1265 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 603 of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 8042(f) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
