<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-328.15</num>
  <heading>Eligibility requirements for receiving grants.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to any other eligibility requirements provided under the enabling statute of the grant program, to be eligible to receive funds under a grant program covered by this part, an individual or entity must be current on all taxes and liabilities owed to the District, or have a plan to resolve such taxes and liabilities that is satisfactory to the grantor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Before a person may receive a grant under this part, that person shall provide the District with a sworn statement, under penalty of perjury, that to the best of the person’s knowledge, after due diligence, the person is in compliance with subsections (c) and (d) of this section and is therefore eligible to receive a grant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person that makes a contribution or solicitation for contribution to a covered recipient shall be ineligible to receive a grant from the District valued at $100,000 or more during the time period set forth in subsection (d) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The District shall not award a grant valued at $100,000 or more to a person that is ineligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1) of this subsection during the time period set forth in subsection (d) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For contributions made to persons described under §  1-328.11(3)(A), (B), or (C), a person is ineligible to receive a grant under this part beginning on the date the contribution or solicitation for contribution was made and continuing for one year after the general election for which the contribution or solicitation for contribution was made, whether or not the contribution was made before the primary election.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For contributions made to persons described under §  1-328.11(3)(D), (E), or (F), a person is ineligible to receive a grant under this part beginning on the date the contribution or solicitation for contribution was made and continuing for 18 months after that date.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1096, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 1053(e), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> designated the existing text as (a); and added (b) to (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 1096 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 1096 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1053(e) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 1091 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle J of Title I of the act may be cited as the “Grant Administration Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
