<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-325.281</num>
  <heading>Department of Behavioral Health Enterprise Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Department of Behavioral Health Enterprise Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Department of Behavioral Health (“Department”) in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall consist of revenue from the following fees, proceeds, and revenues collected from the following activities and operations:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Proceeds from the cafeteria managed and operated by the Department on the St. Elizabeths Hospital Campus;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Fees charged for trainings and Continuing Education Units by the Department’s Organizational Development- DMH Training Institute; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Recoupment and collection of housing bridge subsidy payments from individual consumers, representative payees, and landlords by the Department’s Adult Services Supported Housing program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used for the management and operation of the food cafeteria, DMH Training Institute, and Supported Housing programs managed and operated by the Department.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History" path="§5042">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 5042, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this part, see §  5042 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this part, see §  5042 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this part, see §  5042 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
