<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-325.311</num>
  <heading>WMATA Momentum Support Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the WMATA Momentum Support Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Chief Financial Officer in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon approval of the settlement by the District of Columbia Court of Appeals in District of Columbia v. Expedia, Inc., et al., Nos. 14-CV-308, 14-CV-309, the full amount the District obtained from the settlement, minus the amounts designated for other purposes in §§ <cite path="§1-325.291">1-325.291</cite> and <cite path="§1-325.301">1-325.301</cite>, shall be deposited in the Fund.</text>
    <text>
      <em>District of Columbia v. Expedia, Inc., et al., Nos. 14-CV-308, 14-CV-309</em>
    </text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>Upon settlement of litigation in United States ex rel. Mills v. Compass Group North America et al., 2013 CAB SLD 004624, any and all recoveries by the District from the settlement not otherwise encumbered pursuant to the settlement agreement shall be deposited into the Fund.</text>
    <text>
      <em>United States ex rel. Mills v. Compass Group North America et al.</em>
    </text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon execution of an inter-jurisdiction funding agreement for implementation of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Momentum Strategic Plan (“Momentum”), any monies in the Fund shall be made available to finance the District’s share of the implementation costs of Momentum.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interest earned, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7154, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-36" type="History">Oct. 22. 2015, D.C. Law 20-36, §§  7024(d), 7242(b), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “the full amount the District obtained from the settlement, minus the amounts designated for other purposes in §§ <cite path="§1-325.291">1-325.291</cite> and <cite path="§1-325.301">1-325.301</cite>” for “$ 55.9 million from the $ 60.9 million settlement the District obtained” in (b); and added (b-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2(b) and 4 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-76">D.C. Law 21-76</cite>, Feb. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 264).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this part, see §  7164 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this part, see §  7154 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this part, see §  7154 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 7016(z)(4) and 7212(b) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite>, § 7024(d), see § 2(c) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-164, Oct. 16, 2015,  62 DCR 13734).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  2(e) and 6 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-164, Oct. 16, 2015,  62 DCR 13734).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of emergency D.C. Act 21-127, § 7016(z)(4), see § 3(a) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-164, Oct. 16, 2015,  62 DCR 13734).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite>, § 7024(d), see § 2 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-292, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1211).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-292, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1211).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
