<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-329.01</num>
  <heading>Acceptance of gifts and donations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An entity of the District of Columbia government may accept and use a gift or donation during fiscal year 2003 and any subsequent fiscal year if—</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>the Mayor approves the acceptance and use of the gift or donation (except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection); and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>the entity uses the gift or donation to carry out its authorized functions or duties.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Council of the District of Columbia and the District of Columbia courts may accept and use gifts without prior approval by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each entity of the District of Columbia government shall keep accurate and detailed records of the acceptance and use of any gift or donation under subsection (a) of this section, and shall make such records available for audit and public inspection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “entity of the District of Columbia government” includes an independent agency of the District of Columbia and the District of Columbia Public Libraries.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-1)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to the Public Charter School Board, which may accept and use gifts to the Public Charter School Board without prior approval by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to the Board of Library Trustees, which may, pursuant to the laws and regulations of the District of Columbia, accept and use gifts to the District of Columbia Public Library without prior approval by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 108-7" type="History">Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 123, Pub. L. 108-7, Div. C, title III, § 115</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 109-356" type="History">Oct. 16, 2006, 120 Stat. 2029, Pub. L. 109-356, § 125</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-268" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-268, § 6, 54 DCR 833</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 4092, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-2671">38-2671</cite> and § <cite path="§44-951.06">44-951.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-369.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 109-356, in subsec. (c), inserted “and the District of Columbia Public Libraries”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-268">D.C. Law 16-268</cite> added subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> repealed (d); and added (d-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4602 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 6, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  4092 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  4092 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  4092 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority Pursuant to D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§1-204.22">1-204.22</cite> (6) (2001) &amp; 1-329.01 (2001) Concerning Gifts and Donations to Support the Citizen Summit II, see Mayor’s Order 2001-137, September 14, 2001 ( 48 DCR 9001).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority to Accept Donations, see Mayor’s Order 2001-141, September 18, 2001 ( 48 DCR 9008).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Duty to Administer Public Awareness Campaign for Protections from Predatory Lending and Mortgage Foreclosure Improvements Act of 2000, see Mayor’s Order 2001-159, October 12, 2001 ( 48 DCR 9891).</annotation>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 18-344, the “Secretary to the Council Authorization to Accept and Use Donations on Behalf of the Council Delegation Authorization Resolution of 2009”, was approved effective December 15, 2009.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Establishment—Office of Partnership and Grant Services, see Mayor’s Order 2008-33, February 26, 2008 ( 55 DCR 5291).</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Establishment—Office of Partnerships and Grants Services—Revised, see Mayor’s Order 2010-60, April 23, 2010 ( 57 DCR 3509).</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Donations and Gifts to the District Government, see Mayor’s Order 2010-167, October 22, 2010 ( 57 DCR 10006).</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Establishment—Office of Partnerships and Grant Services, see Mayor’s Order 2011-170, October 5, 2011 ( 58 DCR 8847).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment—Office of Partnership and Grant Services, see Mayor’s Order 2008-33, February 26, 2008 ( 55 DCR 5291).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment—Office of Partnerships and Grants Services—Revised, see Mayor’s Order 2010-60, April 23, 2010 ( 57 DCR 3509).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Donations and Gifts to the District Government, see Mayor’s Order 2010-167, October 22, 2010 ( 57 DCR 10006).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment—Office of Partnerships and Grant Services, see Mayor’s Order 2011-170, October 5, 2011 ( 58 DCR 8847).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite>, § 4602, Oct. 19, 2000,  47 DCR 6308, provided similar language:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) An entity of the District of Columbia government may accept and use a gift or donation during fiscal year 2001, or any subsequent fiscal year, if:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) The Mayor approves the acceptance and use of the gift or donation; provided, that the Council of the District of Columbia may accept and use gifts without prior approval by the Mayor; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) The entity uses the gift or donation to carry out its authorized functions or duties.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) Each entity of the District of Columbia government shall keep accurate and detailed records of the acceptance and use of any gift or donation under subsection (a) of this section, and shall make such records available for audit and public inspection.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) For the purposes of this section, the term ‘entity of the District of Columbia government’ includes an independent agency of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(d) This section shall not apply to the District of Columbia Board of Education, which may, pursuant to the laws and regulations of the District of Columbia, accept and use gifts to the public schools without prior approval by the Mayor.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
