<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-325.261</num>
  <heading>End Homelessness Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the End Homelessness Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Department of Human Services in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall consist of 50% of the revenue from the automated traffic enforcement program, to the extent that the revenue is offset by revenue from a tax imposed by Chapter 39A of Title 47 [§ <cite path="§47-3931">47-3931</cite> et seq.] on sales made via the Internet, and interest earned on that revenue, but not to exceed $50 million in a fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used to end homelessness in the District, as set forth in a plan and legislation prepared by the Director to End Homelessness and the Interagency Council on Homelessness and transmitted to the Council for enactment. No moneys may be used from the Fund to supplant existing funding for programs already in existence.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interest earned, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization by Congress, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History" path="§5192">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5192, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5192 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5192 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 5191 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle R of Title V of the act may be cited as the “End Homelessness Fund Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
