<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-333.10</num>
  <heading>Discretionary funds.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia, the Chairman and members of the Council of the District of Columbia, the Chief Judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, the Chief Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, the Executive Officer of the District of Columbia Court System, the Superintendent of Schools, the City Administrator, the Director of the District of Columbia Public Library, and the Chief Executive Officer of the University of the District of Columbia are authorized to provide for the expenditure, within the limits of specified annual appropriation, of funds for appropriate purposes related to their official capacity as they may respectively deem necessary. Their determination thereof shall be final and conclusive, and their certificate shall be sufficient voucher for the expenditure of appropriations made pursuant to this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>At the end of each fiscal year, each official authorized to expend appropriations under this section shall provide an itemized accounting of these appropriations, which shall include the purposes for which all expenditures are made, in the form of an annual report, for presentation to the Mayor and the Council, and which shall be made available for public inspection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section may be cited as the “Discretionary Funds Act of 1973”.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-140" type="History">Oct. 26, 1973, 87 Stat. 509, Pub. L. 93-140, § 26</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-111" type="History">Sept. 23, 1978, D.C. Law 2-111, § 2, 25 DCR 1462</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-46" type="History">Oct. 24, 1981, D.C. Law 4-46, § 2, 28 DCR 4271</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-61" type="History">Jan. 26, 1982, D.C. Law 4-61, § 7, 28 DCR 4771</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-80" type="History">Feb. 20, 1988, D.C. Law 7-80, § 3, 34 DCR 7960</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1102, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-356.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-262a.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> added (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1102 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1102 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 1101 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that Subtitle K of Title I of the act may be cited as the “Discretionary Fund Renaming Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite>: Section 11001 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
