<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-333.09</num>
  <heading>Reception of eminent persons; appropriation authorized.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is authorized to be appropriated an amount not to exceed $100,000 in any fiscal year for expenses as the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall deem to be necessary, including personal services, for the reception and entertainment (including ceremonial gifts) of officials of foreign, state, local, or federal governments and other dignitaries and eminent persons visiting in or returning to the District of Columbia, or for the reception or entertainment of officials of foreign, state, local, or federal governments when the Mayor is visiting any other jurisdiction in his or her official capacity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>There is authorized to be appropriated an amount not to exceed $100,000 in any fiscal year for expenses as the Council of the District of Columbia shall deem to be necessary, including personal services, for the reception and entertainment (including ceremonial gifts) of officials of foreign, state, local, or federal governments and other dignitaries and eminent persons visiting in or returning to the District of Columbia, or for the reception or entertainment of officials of foreign, state, local, or federal governments when any Councilmember is visiting any other jurisdiction in his or her official capacity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>The Mayor and Council may accept, administer, and use gifts or donations for the purpose of aiding, facilitating, and promoting the conduct of ceremonies in the District, including personal services, for the reception and entertainment, including ceremonial gifts, of officials of foreign, state, local, or federal governments and other dignitaries and eminent persons visiting or returning to the District, or for the reception or entertainment of officials of foreign, state, local, or federal governments when the Mayor is visiting any other jurisdiction in his or her official capacity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term “dignitary” or “eminent person” means a person other than a government official, who is of high rank or attainment in his or her occupation or who has performed extraordinary service to, or has significantly contributed to the welfare of, the citizens of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any amounts appropriated for expenses under this section shall be subject to audit and accounted for in the same manner as any other District of Columbia government funds used for governmental purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Secretary of the District of Columbia and the Secretary to the Council of the District of Columbia shall issue annual reports, which shall be made available to the public and which shall include an itemization of each disbursement under this section by the Mayor of the District of Columbia and by the Council of the District of Columbia, respectively. Records of disbursements under this section shall be retained for not less than 5 years.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>July 11, 1947, 61 Stat. 314, ch. 231, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 3205(b), 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-58">Dec. 16, 1987, D.C. Law 7-58, § 2, 34 DCR 7083</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-80">Feb. 20, 1988, D.C. Law 7-80, § 2, 34 DCR 7960</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-258">Mar. 17, 2005, D.C. Law 15-258, § 2, 52 DCR 1176</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Merit system, effective date provisions, see § <cite path="§1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-355.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 1-262.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-258">D.C. Law 15-258</cite>, in subsecs. (a) and (b), substituted “100,000” for “25,000”; and added subsec. (b-1).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
