<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-507</num>
  <heading>Wages, salaries, annuities, retirement, disability benefits, and other remuneration based on District employment subject to attachment garnishment, and assignment for child support, maintenance, alimony payments, and other obligations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After July 25, 1977, wages, salaries, annuities, retirement and disability benefits, and other remuneration based upon employment, or other income owed by, due from, and payable by the government of the District of Columbia to any individual shall be subject to attachment, garnishment, assignment, or withholding under the District of Columbia Child Support Enforcement Amendment Act of 1985, provided the levy is predicated upon the entry of a judgment, order, or decree determining the individual’s legal obligation to provide child support or to make maintenance or alimony payments. Whenever wages, salaries, annuities, retirement and disability benefits, or other remuneration based upon employment is sought to be levied pursuant to this section, the legal process shall be such as is usual in other cases of attachment, garnishment, assignment, or withholding under the District of Columbia Child Support Enforcement Amendment Act of 1985. The government of the District of Columbia shall be subject to process in the same manner and to the same extent as if it were a private person, except that no writ or similar process served under the authority of this section shall be honored by the government of the District of Columbia unless a certified copy of the judgment, order, or decree upon which the levy is predicated has been provided to the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his duly authorized designee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After October 1, 1997, wages salaries, annuities, retirement and disability benefits, and other remuneration based upon employment, or other income owed by, due from, and payable by the government of the District of Columbia to any individual shall be subject to attachment, garnishment, assignment, or withholding in accordance with subchapter III of Chapter 5 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code in the same manner and to the same extent as if the government of the District of Columbia were a private person.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-14" type="History">July 26, 1977, D.C. Law 2-14, § 2, 24 DCR 1774</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-166" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-166, § 33(d), 33 DCR 6710</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 784, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11713</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Attachment and garnishment of wages, see § <cite path="§16-571">16-571</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Child Support Enforcement Amendment Act of 1985, see § <cite path="§46-201">46-201</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-516.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-323.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “District of Columbia Child Support Enforcement Amendment Act of 1985,” referred to in the first and second sentences of (a), is <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-166">D.C. Law 6-166</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
