<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-604.07</num>
  <heading>Transfer of personnel functions to Office of Personnel; exception; property and funds transferred; separation and reassignment of transferred employee.</heading>
  <text>All positions and employees of the District who spent 50 percent or more of their regular duty hours on January 1, 1976, or at any time since that date performing personnel functions, are transferred to the Office of Personnel unless properly reclassified by the District of Columbia Office of Personnel, except as provided herein. The provisions of this section shall not apply to employees in positions within the independent agencies. All property and funds associated with those positions and employees transferred to the Office of Personnel are transferred thereto as provided in subchapter XXXVI of this chapter unless prohibited by statute. Any employee found to be superfluous to the needs of the Office of Personnel shall be separated from his or her position in accordance with appropriate reduction-in-force procedures as provided in subchapter XXIV of this chapter. The Mayor may authorize the reassignment of such employees as is appropriate.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 407, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-604.7.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-334.7.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disability Compensation Program Transfer Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-202">D.C. Law 14-202</cite>, October 17, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 12020).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1102 of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) transfer of powers, duties, and functions to the Office of Risk Management, see § 2 of Disability Compensation Program Transfer Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-400, June 26, 2002,  49 DCR 6526).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) transfer of property, records, and unexpended funds to the Office of Risk Management, see § 2 of Disability Compensation Program Transfer Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-476, October 3, 2002,  49 DCR 9568).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary transfer, due to Congressional review, of the operation of the Disability Compensation Program from the Office of Personnel to the Office of the City Administrator, see § 2 of Disability Compensation Program Transfer and Risk Management Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-128, July 29, 2003,  50 DCR 6836).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary transfer, due to Congressional review, of the operation of the Disability Compensation Program from the Office of Personnel to the Office of the City Administrator, see § 2 of Disability Compensation Program Transfer and Risk Management Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-172, October 6, 2003,  50 DCR 9173).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title of title XX of Law 15-39: Section 2001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite> provided that title XX of the act may be cited as the Disability Compensation Program Transfer and Risk Management Amendment Act of 2003.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Government Employees Disability Compensation Reorganization: Section 1202 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) All of the powers, duties and functions authorized by Title XXIII of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 2-139">D.C. Law 2-139</cite>; D.C. Official Code 1-623.01 et seq.), as set forth in Part C, section III of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1980, effective January 10, 1981, except for the disability compensation formal hearing and administrative appeal functions which shall remain in the Labor Standards Bureau of the Department of Employment Services, are hereby transferred to the Office of Personnel, established pursuant to Mayor’s Order 79-84, effective May 10, 1979.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) All property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available to the Department of Employment Services for the administration and operation of the disability compensation program for District government employees authorized by Title XXIII of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 2-139">D.C. Law 2-139</cite>; D.C. Official Code 1-623.01 et seq.), and set forth in Part C, section III of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1980, effective January 10, 1981, except for the disability compensation formal hearing and administrative appeal functions, which shall remain in the Labor Standards Bureau of the Department of Employment Services, are hereby transferred to the Office of Personnel, established pursuant to Mayor’s Order 79-84, effective May 10, 1979.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) The Office of Personnel shall pay the Department of Employment Services for the cost of disability compensation hearing and administrative appeal functions, pursuant to an assessment by the Department of Employment Services.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2002 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) All of the powers, duties, and functions transferred to the Office of Personnel under section 1202 of the District of Columbia Government Employees Disability Compensation Reorganization and Amendment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite>;  48 DCR 6891), are hereby transferred to the Office of the City Administrator.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) All property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available to the Office of Personnel under section 1202 of the District of Columbia Government Employees Disability Compensation Reorganization and Amendment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite>;  48 DCR 6891), are hereby transferred to the Office of the City Administrator.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
