<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-608.81</num>
  <heading>Certificate of Good Standing filing requirement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided by the rules for temporary waiver of this requirement, each attorney, hearing officer, or administrative law judge who is required to be a member of the D.C. Bar as a prerequisite of employment, employed by the Mayor, the Office of the Corporation Counsel, the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, the Board of Education, and by any independent agency, shall file with the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability, a Certificate of Good Standing from the District of Columbia Bar Committee on Admissions, District of Columbia Court of Appeals, by December 15 of each year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director of Personnel shall publish, on an annual basis, a list of attorneys who have not met the filing requirements of subsection (a) of this section in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Director of Personnel shall promulgate rules and regulations concerning:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The timing for filing the Certificate of Good Standing and associated procedures;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The standards governing when a temporary waiver of the filing requirement may be granted by the personnel authority for the agency; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The procedures by which attorneys shall be notified of the filing requirement and whether they are in compliance with the requirement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The rules and regulations promulgated pursuant to this part shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the rules and regulations within the 45-day review period, the rules and regulations shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The failure of an attorney covered by this subchapter to comply with the requirement of this part shall result in the forfeiture of employment.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-182" type="History">as added July 25, 2002, D.C. Law 14-182, § 2(c), 49 DCR 5129</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 32, 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-241" type="History">Mar. 13, 2015, D.C. Law 20-241, § 2, 62 DCR 1335</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Elections, disclosure of interests, see § <cite path="§1-1106.02">1-1106.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Lobbying, “official in the executive branch” defined, see 1-1105.01.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, educational employees, coverage, see § <cite path="§1-602.03">1-602.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, organization for personnel management, rules and regulations, see § <cite path="§1-604.04">1-604.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in subsecs. (d) and (e), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-241">D.C. Law 20-241</cite>, in (a), substituted “each attorney, hearing officer, or administrative law judge” for “each attorney employed at the level of DS-13 or above,” inserted “employed” preceding “by the Mayor,” and substituted “by December 15 of each year” for “on an annual basis.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see §  2 of the District Government Certificate of Good Standing Filing Requirement Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-175">D.C. Law 20-175</cite>, March 7, 2015, 61 DCR 12713).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Certificate of Good Standing Filing Requirement Temporary Amendment Act of 2016 <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-99"> D.C. Law 21-99</cite>, April 6, 2016, 63 DCR 2215, 20 DCSTAT 3138).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  2 of the District Government Certificate of Good Standing Filing Requirement Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-480, Nov. 10, 2014, 61 DCR 12131, 20 STAT 4404).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Certificate of Good Standing Filing Requirement Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-289, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1202).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
