<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-603.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purpose of this chapter unless otherwise required by the context:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term “agency” means any unit of the District of Columbia government required by law, by the Mayor of the District of Columbia, or by the Council of the District to administer any law, rule, or any regulation adopted under authority of law. The term “agency” shall also include any unit of the District of Columbia government created by the reorganization of 1 or more of the units of an agency and any unit of the District of Columbia government created or organized by the Council of the District of Columbia as an agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1A)</num>
    <text>The term “Attorney General” means the Attorney General for the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term “boards and commissions” means bodies established by law or by order of the Mayor of the District of Columbia consisting of appointed members to perform a trust or execute official functions on behalf of the District of Columbia government. Compensation or reimbursement of expenses, if any, to such members shall be provided according to § <cite path="§1-611.08">1-611.08</cite>; provided, however, that full-time employees shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of § <cite path="§1-611.04">1-611.04</cite> or § <cite path="§1-611.11">1-611.11</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “Career Service” means positions in the District of Columbia government as provided for in subchapter VIII of this chapter and § <cite path="§1-602.04">1-602.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term “Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia, created pursuant to § <cite path="§1-204.01">1-204.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The term “District” means the District of Columbia government (§ <cite path="§1-102">1-102</cite>).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5A)</num>
    <text>The term “domestic partner” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§32-701">32-701</cite>(3).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5B)</num>
    <text>The term “domestic partnership” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§32-701">32-701</cite>(4).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5C)</num>
    <text>The term “domicile” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Physical presence in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>An intent to abandon any and all former domiciles and remain in the District of Columbia during the duration of the appointment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The term “educational employee” means an employee of the District of Columbia Board of Education or of the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia, except persons employed in any of the following types of positions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Clerical, stenographic, or secretarial positions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Custodial, building maintenance, building engineer, general maintenance, or general engineering positions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Bus drivers and other drivers involved in the transportation of persons, equipment, materials or inventory;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Cooks, dieticians, and other positions involved in direct planning, preparation, service, and conditions of preparation and service of food;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Technicians involved in the operation or maintenance of machinery, vehicles, equipment or the processing of materials and inventory; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Positions the major duties in which consist of the supervision of employees covered in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of this definition: provided, however, that this subparagraph shall not be deemed to include heads of academic units at the School of Law or the University of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The term “employee” means, except when specifically modified in this chapter, an individual who performs a function of the District government and who receives compensation for the performance of such services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>The term “Excepted Service” means positions in the District of Columbia government as provided for in subchapter IX of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8A)</num>
    <text>The term “exceptional circumstances” means conditions or facts that are uncommon, deviate from or do not conform to the norm, or are beyond willful control, which are presented to the personnel authority by an agency hiring an individual to fill a position in the Excepted and Executive Services, and which shall be considered by the personnel authority in determining the reasonableness of granting a waiver of the domicile requirement pursuant to §§ <cite path="§1-609.06">1-609.06</cite> and <cite path="§1-610.59">1-610.59</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>The term “Executive Service” means any subordinate agency head whom the Mayor is authorized to appoint in accordance with subchapter X-A of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9A)</num>
    <text>“Gender identity or expression” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§2-1401.02">2-1401.02</cite>(12A).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>The term “grievance” means any matter under the control of the District government which impairs or adversely affects the interest, concern, or welfare of employees, but does not include adverse actions resulting in removals, suspension of 10 days or more, or reductions in grade, reductions in force or classification matters. This definition applies to matters which are subject to procedures established pursuant to section § <cite path="§1-616.53">1-616.53</cite> and is not intended to restrict matters that may be subject to a negotiated grievance and arbitration procedure in a collective bargaining agreement between the District and a labor organization representing employees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10A)</num>
    <text>The term “hard to fill position” means a position so designated by the personnel authority on the basis of demonstrated recruitment and retention problems inherent in the position due to the uniqueness of the duties and responsibilities and the unusual combination of highly specialized qualification requirements for the position.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>The term “head” means the highest ranking executive official of an agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>The term “holidays” means any day established as a legal holiday pursuant to subchapter XII of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>The term “independent agency” means any board or commission of the District of Columbia government not subject to the administrative control of the Mayor, including, the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia, the Board of Library Trustees, the Armory Board, the Board of Elections and Ethics, the Public Service Commission, the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia, the Public Employee Relations Board, the District of Columbia Retirement Board, and the Office of Employee Appeals. For the purposes of this chapter, the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia shall be considered independent agencies of the District of Columbia. For the purposes of subchapter XXVIII of this chapter, the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission shall be considered an independent agency of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13A)</num>
    <text>The term “Legal Service” means positions in the District of Columbia government as provided for in subchapter VIII-B of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13B)</num>
    <text>The term “Management Supervisory Service” means positions in the District of Columbia government as provided for in subchapter IX-A of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13C)</num>
    <text>The term “nonschool-based personnel” means any employee of the District of Columbia Public Schools who is not based at a local school or who does not provide direct services to individual students.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>The term “personnel authority” means an individual with the authority to administer all or part of a personnel management program as provided in subchapter IV of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14A)</num>
    <text>“Public official” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A candidate for nomination for election, or election, to public office;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, Chairman, and each member of the Council of the District of Columbia holding office under Chapter 2 of this title [§ <cite path="§1-201.01">1-201.01</cite> et seq.];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>A Representative or Senator elected pursuant to § <cite path="§1-123">1-123</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>An Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>A member of the State Board of Education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>A person serving as a subordinate agency head in a position designated as within the Executive Service;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(H)</num>
      <text>A member of a board or commission listed in § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>(e); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(I)</num>
      <text>A District of Columbia Excepted Service employee paid at a rate of Excepted Service 9 or above, or its equivalent, who makes decisions or participates substantially in areas of contracting, procurement, administration of grants or subsidies, developing policies, land use planning, inspecting, licensing, regulating, or auditing, or acts in areas of responsibility that may create a conflict of interest or the appearance of a conflict of interest; and any additional employees designated by rule by the Ethics Board who make decisions or participate substantially in areas of contracting, procurement, administration of grants or subsidies, developing policies, land use planning, inspecting, licensing, regulating, or auditing, or act in areas of responsibility that may create a conflict of interest or the appearance of a conflict of interest.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>The term “resident” means any person who is a domiciliary of the District of Columbia and who throughout his or her employment by the District maintains a place of abode in the District of Columbia as his or her actual, regular, and principal place of occupancy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15A)</num>
    <text>The term “school administrators” means principals, assistant principals, school program directors, coordinators, instructional supervisors, and support personnel of the District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>The term “standard” means any criterion, guideline, or measure established by appropriate authority for the purpose of making objective comparisons or determinations for such purposes, including, but not limited to, the classification of positions, establishment of pay, evaluation of qualifications, and appraisal of work performance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>The term “subordinate agency” means any agency under the direct administrative control of the Mayor, including, but not limited to, the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Office of Operations (Mayor’s Order 83-17);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Office of Economic Development (Mayor’s Order 83-18);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Office of Financial Management (Mayor’s Order 83-19);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Department of Corrections (Organization Order 7);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Department of Public Works (Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1983);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>Department of Finance and Revenue (Commissioner’s Order 69-96);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(H)</num>
      <text>Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department (Reorganization Order 6);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(I)</num>
      <text>Department of Administrative Services (Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1983);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(J)</num>
      <text>Department of Housing and Community Development (Reorganization Plan 3 of 1975);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(K)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(L)</num>
      <text>Metropolitan Police force (§ <cite path="§5-105.05">5-105.05</cite>);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(M)</num>
      <text>Department of Parks and Recreation (Organization Order 10);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(N)</num>
      <text>Department of Human Services (Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979 and Mayor’s Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986), including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The Commission on Social Services;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Repealed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Repealed; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>Repealed;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(O)</num>
      <text>Department of Employment Services (Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1980);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(P)</num>
      <text>Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs (Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1983);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(Q)</num>
      <text>Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency (Commissioner’s Order 74-261);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(R)</num>
      <text>Office of Human Rights;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(S)</num>
      <text>Office of Personnel (§ <cite path="§1-604.02">1-604.02</cite>);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(T)</num>
      <text>Office on Latino Affairs (§ <cite path="§2-1311">2-1311</cite>);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(U)</num>
      <text>Office on Aging (§ <cite path="§7-503.01">7-503.01</cite>);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(V)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(W)</num>
      <text>Board of Parole (Organization Order 6);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(X)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(Y)</num>
      <text>Office of Business and Economic Development (§ <cite path="§2-1201.02">2-1201.02</cite>);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(Z)</num>
      <text>Office of the Secretary of the District of Columbia (Mayor’s Order 84-77);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(AA)</num>
      <text>Office of Inspector General (§ <cite path="§1-301.115a">1-301.115a</cite>);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(BB)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(CC)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(DD)</num>
      <text>Office of Cable Television and Telecommunications;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(EE)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(FF)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(GG)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(HH)</num>
      <text>Office of the Budget (Mayor’s Order 79-5);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(II)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(JJ)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(KK)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(LL)</num>
      <text>Commission on the Arts and Humanities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(MM)</num>
      <text>Department of Health;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(NN)</num>
      <text>Office of Contracting and Procurement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(OO)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(PP)</num>
      <text>Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(QQ)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(QQ-i)</num>
      <text>Department of General Services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(RR)</num>
      <text>Office of the Chief Technology Officer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(SS)</num>
      <text>Department of Motor Vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(TT)</num>
      <text>Office of Planning (Mayor’s Order 83-25);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(UU)</num>
      <text>Office of Local Business Development;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(VV)</num>
      <text>Office of Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(WW)</num>
      <text>Office of the Chief Medical Examiner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(XX)</num>
      <text>Child and Family Services Agency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(YY)</num>
      <text>Department of Mental Health;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(ZZ)</num>
      <text>District Department of Transportation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(AAA)</num>
      <text>Office of Unified Communications;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(BBB)</num>
      <text>Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(CCC)</num>
      <text>The Office of Risk Management, established by Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 2003;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(DDD)</num>
      <text>Department on Disability Services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(EEE)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 301, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-81" type="History">Aug. 7, 1980, D.C. Law 3-81, § 2(c), 27 DCR 2632</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-177" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-177, § 3(d), 33 DCR 7241</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-201" type="History">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-201, § 2, 36 DCR 248</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-97" type="History">Mar. 24, 1990, D.C. Law 8-97, § 3(a), 37 DCR 1046</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 801(a), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-98" type="History">Mar. 5, 1996, D.C. Law 11-98, § 301(a), 43 DCR 5</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-78" type="History">Jan. 26, 1996, D.C. Law 11-78, § 501(a), 42 DCR 6181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52,§ 1001(a), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 104-134" type="History">Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 215, Pub. L. 104-134, § 145(1)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-152" type="History">Aug. 1, 1996, D.C. Law 11-152, § 302(c), 43 DCR 2978</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 104-194" type="History">Sept. 9, 1996, 110 Stat. 2372, Pub. L. 104-194, § 138(1)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255,§ 4(a), 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 760, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11261(b)(2)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-124" type="History">June 10, 1998, D.C. Law 12-124, § 101(a), 45 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175" type="History">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, §§ 1807, 1817, 1828, 45 DCR 7193</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, §§ 5(a), 53, 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-285" type="History">June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-285, § 3, 46 DCR 1355</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-38" type="History">Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-38, §§ 208 and 225, 46 DCR 6373</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000, D.C. Law 13-91, § 103(b), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, §§ 1902 and 2919(a), 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-277" type="History">Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-277,§ 3(b)(1), 48 DCR 2043</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-313" type="History">June 19, 2001, D.C. Law 13-313, § 2(a) 48 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-56" type="History">Dec. 18, 2001, D.C. Law 14-56, § 116(a)(1), 48 DCR 7674</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 10, 49 DCR 3444</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-185" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-185, § 2(a), 49 DCR 6073</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 3(a), 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, §§ 2(a), 19(a), 20(d), 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-166" type="History">June 11, 2004, D.C. Law 15-166, § 4(a), 51 DCR 2817</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 3221, 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-335" type="History">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-335, § 201, 52 DCR 2025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 5(a), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91" type="History">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, §§ 113, 117, 118(a), 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191,§ 116, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-262" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-262, § 401, 54 DCR 794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-264" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 201, 54 DCR 818</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-9" type="History">June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 1001, 54 DCR 4102</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-177" type="History">June 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-177, § 3(b), 55 DCR 3696</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 3(a), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, §§ 157(e), 176, 203(c), 248, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 1032(a), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 501(c)(1), 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 9(a), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 1033(b), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Business improvements districts, additional authority and duties, see § <cite path="§2-1215.16">2-1215.16</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Construction codes, see § <cite path="§6-1401">6-1401</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Employees retirement program management, establishment of retirement board and retirement funds, see § <cite path="§1-711">1-711</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Spouse equity, “employee” defined, see § <cite path="§1-529.02">1-529.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-515.01">1-515.01</cite>, § <cite path="§1-529.02">1-529.02</cite>, § <cite path="§1-608.01a">1-608.01a</cite>, § <cite path="§1-609.06">1-609.06</cite>, § <cite path="§1-612.04">1-612.04</cite>, § <cite path="§1-612.31">1-612.31</cite>, § <cite path="§1-711">1-711</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.16">2-1215.16</cite>, § <cite path="§3-101">3-101</cite>, and § <cite path="§22-4231">22-4231</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-603.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-333.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-38">D.C. Law 13-38</cite>, in subsec. (17), deleted “(Commissioner’s Order 71-224)” from the end of par. (R), and added par. (UU) to read “Office of Local Business Development”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, in subsec. (9), substituted “subchapter XI-A” for “subchapter XI”; in subsec. (10), in the second sentence, substituted “1-617.53” for “1-617.3”; redesignated former subsec. (13A) as subsec. (13B); and inserted new subsec. (13A) defining “Legal Service”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite>, in subsec. (17), added par. (VV) to read “Office of Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development”, and par. (WW) to read “Office of the Chief Medical Examiner”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-277">D.C. Law 13-277</cite>, in subsec. (17), added par. (XX).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-313">D.C. Law 13-313</cite>, in subsec. (17), par. (Q), substituted “Emergency Management Agency” for “Office of Emergency Preparedness”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-56">D.C. Law 14-56</cite>, in subsec. (17), repealed par. (N)(iii), which had read: “The Commission on Mental Health; and”, struck “and” at the end of par. (WW), substituted “; and” for a period at the end of par. (XX), and added par. (YY).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-137">D.C. Law 14-137</cite>, in par. (17)(WW), made a nonsubstantive change; in par. (17)(YY), substituted “Child and Family Services; and” for “Child and Family Services.”; and added par. (17)(ZZ).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-185">D.C. Law 14-185</cite> added pars. (5A), (8A), and (10A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite> redesignated par. (13B) as (13C); added a new par. (13B); and in par. (19)(M), substituted “Department of Parks and Recreation” for “Department of Recreation and Parks”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in subpar. (T) of par. (17), substituted “Office on Latino Affairs” for “Office of Latino Affairs”; and, in pars. (8A), (10A), (50), (51), and (52), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-166">D.C. Law 15-166</cite>, in par. (17), repealed subpar. (JJ), and rewrote subpar. (PP).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, in par. (17), made nonsubstantive changes in subpars. (YY) and (ZZ), and added subpar. (AAA).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-335">D.C. Law 15-335</cite>, in par. (17), substituted a semicolon for “and” at the end of subpar. (ZZ), substituted a period for “; and” at the end of subpar. (AAA), and added subpar. (BBB).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite>, in par. (17), repealed subpar. (v) which had read as follows: “(V) Board of Appeals and Review (Organization Order 112);”, validated a previously made correction at the end of subpar. (YY), inserted “District” and “; and” in subpar. (ZZ), and added subpar. (CCC).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-91">D.C. Law 16-91</cite>, in par. (17), validated previously made technical corrections in subpars. (ZZ), (AAA), (BBB), (CCC), and repealed subpars. (N)(iv) and (OO).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in subpars. (AAA) and (BBB) of par. (17), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-262">D.C. Law 16-262</cite>, in par. (17), subpar. (Q), substituted “Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency” for “Emergency Management Agency”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-264">D.C. Law 16-264</cite>, in par. (17), added subpar. (DDD).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-9">D.C. Law 17-9</cite>, in par. (13), deleted “but not limited to, the District of Columbia Board of Education” following “including,”; and, in par. (17), added subpar. (EEE).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-177">D.C. Law 17-177</cite> added subsec. (9A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite> redesignated par. (5A) as par. (5C); and added pars. (5A) and (5B).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite>, in par. (17), subpar. (Q), inserted “(Commissioner’s Order 74-261)”, rewrote subpar. (DD), which had read as follows: “(DD) Office of Cable Television (D.C. Official Code, § <cite path="§34-1205">34-1205</cite>);”, and validated previously made technical corrections in subpars. (AAA), (BBB), (CCC), (DDD), and (EEE).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> repealed subsec. (17)(QQ), which had read as follows: “(QQ) Office of Property Management”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-124">D.C. Law 19-124</cite> added par. (14A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> added (17)(QQ-i).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> added (1A); rewrote the second sentence in (13); and repealed (17)(D).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 5 of Human Services Spending Reduction Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-29">D.C. Law 11-29</cite>, July 25, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 4002).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 16(a)(1) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-51">D.C. Law 14-51</cite>, October 30, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 10807).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see §§ 1407, 1417, and 1428 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-401, July 13, 1998,  45 DCR 4794), and §§ 1407, 1417, and 1428 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-564, January 12, 1999,  46 DCR 669).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3 of the Confirmation Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-25, March 15, 1999,  46 DCR 2971).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see §§ 1407, 1417, and 1428 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-41, March 31, 1999,  46 DCR 3446).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3 of the Confirmation Act Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-92, June 4, 1999,  46 DCR 5330).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see §§ 208 and 225 of the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-110, July 28, 1999,  46 DCR 6320).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Legal Services Clarification and Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-203, December 8, 1999,  46 DCR 10456).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Legal Services Clarification and Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-293, March 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2063).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of section, see §§ 1902 and 2919(a) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 1902, 1903, and 2919(a) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 16(a)(1) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-55, May 2, 2001,  48 DCR 4390).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 16(a)(1) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-101, July 23, 2001,  48 DCR 7123).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 116(a)(1) of Mental Health Service Delivery Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-144, October 23, 2001,  48 DCR 9947).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(a) of Consolidation of Financial Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-381, February 27, 2004,  51 DCR 2652).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3221 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3221 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 201 of Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services Establishment Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-657, December 29, 2004,  52 DCR 481).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 201 of Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-58, March 17, 2005,  52 DCR 3182).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 201 of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1155).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 401(c)(1) of Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-298, January 29, 2012,  59 DCR 683).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  1033(d) and 3032 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">Pursuant to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer’s “Notice of Public Interest” published in the April 18, 1997, issue of the District of Columbia Register ( 44 DCR 2345) the Office of Tax and Revenue assumed all of the duties and functions previously performed by the Department of Finance and Revenue, as set forth in Commissioner’s Order 69-96, dated March 7, 1969. This action was made effective January 22, 1997, nunc pro tunc.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">Pursuant to Mayor’s Order 98-198 ( 46 DCR 240) pub. January 8, 1999, the name of the Office of Emergency Preparedness has been changed to the D.C. Emergency Management Agency.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">Pursuant to Mayor’s Order 2000-20, the agency formerly known as the Department of Recreation and Parks shall be known as the Department of Parks and Recreation.</text>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Orders">Amendment of Organization Order No. 112, establishing Board of Appeals and Review: See Mayor’s Order 84-31, February 9, 1984.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 3 of Law 6-177: Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> provided that the provisions of § 3 are repealed on the 1st day following the 36-month period after February 24, 1987.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 4(b) of Law 6-177: Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-74">D.C. Law 8-74</cite>, effective March 15, 1990, provided that § 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> is repealed.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability: Section 1011 of Law 17-9 provided that this title shall apply upon Congressional enactment of Title IX. Congress enacted the provisions of Title IX in Pub. L. 110-33, approved June 1, 2007.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> purported to substitute “Department of General Services” for “Office of Property Management” in (17)(QQ); however, because (17)(QQ) had previously been repealed, (17)(QQ-i) has been added instead.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
