<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-609.05</num>
  <heading>Lack of job protection; procedural protection.</heading>
  <text>Employees in the Excepted Service (other than those appointed under the authority of § <cite path="§1-609.04">1-609.04</cite>) do not have any job tenure or protection. After 1 year of average or above average performance as determined under subchapter XIII-A of this chapter, persons appointed under the authority of this subchapter shall be entitled to a notice of at least 15 days when termination is contemplated, which may state the reason therefor. The employee does not have any right to appeal the termination. All other provisions of this chapter apply to Excepted Service employees: Except, that persons employed by the Council of the District of Columbia by personnel authorities identified in § <cite path="§1-604.06">1-604.06</cite>(b)(3)(B) may have their employment relationship terminated by the member or chairperson of a committee of the Council of the District of Columbia employing them without further review by way of grievance or adverse action administrative appeals.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 905, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-7" type="History">June 11, 1981, D.C. Law 4-7, § 4, 28 DCR 1672</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000. D.C. Law 13-91, § 103(k), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 3(c), 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-608.56">1-608.56</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-610.5.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-339.5.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, in the second sentence, substituted “subchapter XIV-A” for “subchapter XV”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite> substituted “termination is contemplated, which may state the reason therefor” for “termination of service prior to the expiration date of appointment is contemplated, explaining the reason therefor”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
