<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-608.59</num>
  <heading>Residency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The provisions of § <cite path="§1-608.01">1-608.01</cite>(e) shall apply to employment in the Legal Service other than the Senior Executive Service Attorney Service and attorneys employed by the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of §§ <cite path="§1-608.01">1-608.01</cite>(e) and <cite path="§2-1401.01">2-1401.01</cite> et seq., any attorney appointed to the Senior Executive Service Attorney Service and attorneys employed by the Council of the District of Columbia shall become a bona fide resident of the District within 180 days of the effective date of the appointment, and shall remain a District resident for the duration of the employment.  Failure to become a District resident or to maintain District residency shall result in forfeiture of the position to which the person has been appointed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Director of Personnel may waive the residency requirement in subsection (b) of this section for any individual appointed to a hard-to-fill position pursuant to § <cite path="§1-608.53">1-608.53</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 859</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-260" type="History">as added Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-260, § 2(j), 46 DCR 1318</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000. D.C. Law 13-91, § 110(e), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1831.08">2-1831.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-609.59.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, in subsecs. (a) and (b), substituted “the Senior Executive Service Attorney Service and attorneys employed by the Council of the District of Columbia” for “the Senior Executive Attorney Service”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of subchapter, see note to § <cite path="§1-608.51">1-608.51</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of the Legal Services Clarification and Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-203, December 8, 1999,  46 DCR 10456).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of the Legal Services Clarification and Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-293, March 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2063).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
