<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-602.03</num>
  <heading>Educational employees of the District of Columbia Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Educational employees of the District of Columbia Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall be governed by the provisions of this chapter with the exception of subchapters VIII, IX (except to the extent provided therein), and X-A of this chapter. Subchapter VIII-A of this chapter shall only apply to such educational employees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Educational employees of the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall not be governed by the provisions of § <cite path="§1-609.01">1-609.01</cite> relating to the development of job descriptions in consultation with the Mayor. The Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall develop policies on classification, appointment, promotion, retention, and tenure of employees consistent with the educational missions of their respective schools and in accordance with the sound policies and practices of the American Bar Association in the case of the School of Law, and of land-grant universities that meet the standards established by the College and Universities Personnel Association in the case of the University of the District of Columbia. Additionally, educational employees shall not be covered by subchapters VIII, X, XI (except as it provides for pay setting), XIII, XIII-A, XIX, and XXIV of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2, each qualified District resident applicant shall receive an additional 10-point preference over a qualified non-District resident applicant to fill all positions as non-educational employees of the District of Columbia Board of Education and Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia unless the applicant declines the preference. This 10-point preference shall be in addition to, and not instead of, qualifications established for the position. All persons hired after February 6, 2008, shall submit proof of residency upon employment in a manner determined by the respective Boards. An applicant claiming the hiring preference under this section shall agree in writing to maintain bona fide District residency for a period of 7 consecutive years from the effective date of hire and shall provide proof of residency annually to the Director of Personnel for the first 7 years of employment. Failure to maintain District residency for the consecutive 7-year period shall result in forfeiture of employment. The District of Columbia Board of Education and Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall submit to the Mayor and Council annual reports detailing the names of all new employees and their pay schedules, titles, and place of residence.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 203, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-177" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-177, § 3(c), 33 DCR 7241</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-152" type="History">Aug. 1, 1996, D.C. Law 11-152, § 302(b), 43 DCR 2978</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 2(a), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000. D.C. Law 13-91, § 103(a), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-108" type="History">Feb. 6, 2008, D.C. Law 17-108, § 203(a), 54 DCR 10993</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-602.02">1-602.02</cite>, § <cite path="§1-604.04">1-604.04</cite>, § <cite path="§1-604.06">1-604.06</cite>, and § <cite path="§1-608.01a">1-608.01a</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-602.3.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-332.3.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, in subsec. (a), in the first sentence, substituted “XI-A” for “XI”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-108">D.C. Law 17-108</cite> added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Repeal of § 3 of Law 6-177: Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> provided that the provisions of § 3 are repealed on the 1st day following the 36-month period after February 24, 1987.</text>
      <text>Repeal of § 4(b) of Law 6-177: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§1-602.02">1-602.02</cite>.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
