<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-604.06</num>
  <heading>Personnel authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The implementation of the rules and regulations shall be undertaken by the appropriate personnel authority for employees of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of subsection (a) of this section, the personnel authority for District of Columbia government means the Mayor for all employees, except as provided in <cite path="§1-602.03">§ 1-602.03</cite> and as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For noneducational employees of the District of Columbia Board of Education, the personnel authority is the District of Columbia Board of Education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For noneducational employees of the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia, the personnel authority is the Board of Trustee of the University of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For employees of the Council of the District of Columbia, the personnel authority is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The Chairman of the Council for all central staff of the Council and the employees in the Legal Services employed by the Council of the District of Columbia. For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “central staff of the Council” refers to those employees described in <cite path="§1-609.03|(a)|(3)">§ 1-609.03(a)(3)</cite> except those assigned to an individual member of the Council; provided, however, that the Secretary, General Counsel, and Budget Director to the Council to the Council shall be appointed by the Council of the District of Columbia according to its rules of procedure and organization; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>For employees of the Council, the Chairman of the Council shall exercise the authority possessed by the Director of the Department of Human Resources and may adopt personnel procedures applicable to those employees; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>each member of the Council for his or her personal and committee staff; provided, however, that the respective committees of the Council shall approve the appointment of each committee staffperson. The Chairman and each member of the Council shall utilize the Secretary to the Council for the actual transaction of all personnel matters for employees of the Council;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3A)</num>
      <text>For the Executive Director of the Office of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, the personnel authority is the Chairman of the Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For employees of the Board of Elections, the personnel authority is the Board of Elections; provided, however, that this authority shall not apply to the Director of Campaign Finance (<cite path="§1-1163.02">§ 1-1163.02</cite>). For employees in the Office of Director of Campaign Finance, the personnel authority is the Director of Campaign Finance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>For employees of the Public Service Commission, the personnel authority is the Public Service Commission; provided, however, that the People’s Counsel (<cite path="§34-804">§ 34-804</cite>) shall be appointed according to law and for employees under the direct administrative control of the People’s Counsel, the personnel authority is the People’s Counsel;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>For the Executive Director of the Public Employee Relations Board, created by <cite path="1|6|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, the personnel authority is the Public Employee Relations Board; and for all other employees of the Board, the personnel authority is the Executive Director of the Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>For the Executive Director of the Office of Employee Appeals and the General Counsel of the Office of Employee Appeals created by <cite path="1|6|VI">subchapter VI of this chapter</cite>, the personnel authority is the Office of Employee Appeals; and for all other employees of the Office, the personnel authority is the Executive Director;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>For employees of the Office of District of Columbia Auditor (<cite path="§1-204.55">§ 1-204.55</cite>), the personnel authority is the Auditor of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>For employees of the District of Columbia Armory Board (<cite path="§3-302">§ 3-302</cite>), the personnel authority is the Armory Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>For employees of the District of Columbia Law Revision Commission, the personnel authority is the Chairman of the Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>For employees of the District of Columbia Board of Library Trustees, the personnel authority is the Board of Library Trustees;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>For the Executive Director and Deputy Director of the District of Columbia Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board (“Board”), the personnel authority is the Board, and for all other employees of the Board the personnel authority is the Executive Director of the Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>For employees of the District of Columbia Retirement Board, the personnel authority is the District of Columbia Retirement Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>For the Director of the Office of Zoning, the personnel authority shall be the District members of the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia, and for any other employee of the Office of Zoning the personnel authority shall be the Director of the Office of Zoning;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>For employees of the Child and Family Services Agency, the personnel authority is the Director of the Child and Family Services Agency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(18)</num>
      <text>For employees of the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, the personnel authority is the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(19)</num>
      <text>For employees of the District of Columbia Sentencing and Criminal Code Revision Commission, the personnel authority is the District of Columbia Sentencing and Criminal Code Revision Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(20)</num>
      <text>For employees of the Department of Mental Health, the personnel authority is the Director of the Department of Mental Health;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(21)</num>
      <text>For the Director of the Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration, the personnel authority shall be the members of the Alcoholic Beverage Control Board for the District of Columbia, and for any other employee of the Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration, the personnel authority shall be the Director of the Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(22)</num>
      <text>For employees of the State Board of Education, the personnel authority is the State Board of Education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(23)</num>
      <text>For the Executive Director of the Office of the Statehood Delegation, the personnel authority is the Statehood Delegation as defined in <cite path="§1-209.01|(3)" proof="true">§ 1-209.01(3)</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(24)</num>
      <text>For employees of the Office of the Attorney General, the personnel authority is the Attorney General.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§406">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 406, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-119" type="History">Feb. 26, 1981, D.C. Law 3-119, § 5, 27 DCR 5641</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-24" type="History">Aug. 2, 1983, D.C. Law 5-24, § 12(a), 30 DCR 3341</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-177" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-177, § 3(g), 33 DCR 7241</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-205" type="History">Feb. 28, 1987, D.C. Law 6-205, § 2(a), 34 DCR 670</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-228" type="History">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-228, § 2(b), 36 DCR 754</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-97" type="History">Mar. 24, 1990, D.C. Law 8-97, § 3(b), 37 DCR 1046</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-127" type="History">May 15, 1990, D.C. Law 8-127, § 2(a), 37 DCR 2093</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-163" type="History">Sept. 20, 1990, D.C. Law 8-163, § 6, 37 DCR 4676</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-152" type="History">Aug. 1, 1996, D.C. Law 11-152, § 302(f), 43 DCR 2978</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-124" type="History">June 10, 1998, D.C. Law 12-124, § 101(c), 45 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000. D.C. Law 13-91, § 103(e), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-277" type="History">Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-277, § 3(b)(2), 48 DCR 2043</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, §§ 1507(a)(1), 3803(a), 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-56" type="History">Dec. 18, 2001, D.C. Law 14-56, § 116(a)(2), 48 DCR 7674</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-80" type="History">Mar. 6, 2002, D.C. Law 14-80, § 3, 48 DCR 11268</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, §§ 21, 22(a), 23, 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 102(a), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-190" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-190, § 3(a), 51 DCR 6737</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91" type="History">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, §§ 110(a), 119, 120(a), 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-126" type="History">June 16, 2006, D.C. Law 16-126, § 3(a), 53 DCR 4709</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 1103, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 501(c)(2), 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-284" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-284, § 2(a), 60 DCR 2312</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-271" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-271, §§  104, 221, 62 DCR 1884</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 1033(c), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 3 of Law 6-177: Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> provided that the provisions of § 3 are repealed on the 1st day following the 36-month period after February 24, 1987.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 4(b) of Law 6-177: Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-74">D.C. Law 8-74</cite>, effective March 15, 1990, provided that § 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> is repealed.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Drug Free Workplace Policy: See Mayor’s Order 90-27, January 31, 1990.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Powers of Chief Financial Officer: Section 152 of Pub. L. 104-134, 110 Stat. 1321 220 provided that:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for the fiscal years ending September 30, 1996 and September 30, 1997 —</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) the heads and all other personnel of the following offices, together with all other District of Columbia executive branch accounting, budget, and financial management personnel, shall be appointed by, shall serve at the pleasure of, and shall act under the direction and control of the Chief Financial Officer:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“The Office of the Treasurer.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“The Controller of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“The Office of the Budget.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“The Office of Financial Information Services.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“The Department of Finance and Revenue.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“The District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority established pursuant to Public Law 104-8, approved April 17, 1995, may remove such individuals from office for cause, after consultation with the Mayor and the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) the Chief Financial Officer shall prepare and submit to the Mayor, for inclusion in the annual budget of the District of Columbia under part D of title IV of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act of 1993, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 774; Public Law 93-198), as amended, for fiscal years 1996, 1997 and 1998, annual estimates of the expenditures and appropriations necessary for the operation of the Office of the Chief Financial Officer for the year. All such estimates shall be forwarded by the Mayor to the Council of the District of Columbia for its action pursuant to sections 446 and 603(c) of such Act, without revision but subject to recommendations. Notwithstanding any other provisions of such Act, the Council may comment or make recommendations concerning such estimates, but shall have no authority to revise such estimates.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-126">D.C. Law 16-126</cite> provided: “This act shall apply as of January 1, 2007.”</text>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Orders">Delegation of Personnel Authority in the Metropolitan Police Department to the Chief of Police: See Mayor’s Order 97-88, May 9, 1997 ( 44 DCR 2959).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Personnel Authority to Identify and Designate Positions Subject to, and to Conduct, Criminal Background Investigations for Employees in Subordinate Agencies, see Mayor’s Order 2011-183, November 2, 2011 ( 58 DCR 9652).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Personnel Authority in the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, see Mayor’s Order 2007-237, November 2, 2007 ( 55 DCR 173).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority to Conduct Background Investigations for Potential and Current Information Technology Employees in Subordinate Agencies, see Mayor’s Order 2003-136, September 25, 2003 ( 50 DCR 9955).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Joint Delegation of Personnel Authority in the Department of Human Services, see Mayor’s Order 2002-104, June 28, 2002 ( 49 DCR 6001).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegations and sub-delegations of authority—Director of Personnel, Chief of Police, and Agency Heads—Rescission of Mayor’s Orders 80-78, 92-114, 99-79 and Deletion of Part I of Mayor’s Order 97-88, see Mayor’s Order 2000-83, May 30, 2000 ( 47 DCR 4956).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1033(c) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 104 and 221 of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-7, Feb. 26, 2015,  62 DCR 2646, 21 STAT 807).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  104 and 221 of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-481, Nov. 18, 2014, 61 DCR 12133, 20 STAT 4405).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the State Board of Education Personnel Authority Amendment of this section Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-46, March 27, 2013,  60 DCR 5453, 20 DCSTAT 545).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 401(c)(2) of Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-298, January 29, 2012,  59 DCR 683).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1103 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1103 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of Advisory Commission on Sentencing Structured Sentencing System Pilot Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-510, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8967).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of Advisory Commission on Sentencing Structured Sentencing System Pilot Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-437, May 21, 2004,  51 DCR 5957).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary transfer, due to Congressional review, of the operation of the Disability Compensation Program from the Office of Personnel to the Office of the City Administrator, see § 2 of Disability Compensation Program Transfer and Risk Management Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-172, October 6, 2003,  50 DCR 9173).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary transfer, due to Congressional review, of the operation of the Disability Compensation Program from the Office of Personnel to the Office of the City Administrator, see § 2 of Disability Compensation Program Transfer and Risk Management Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-128, July 29, 2003,  50 DCR 6836).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 116(a)(2) of Mental Health Service Delivery Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-144, October 23, 2001,  48 DCR 9947).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 1407(a)(1) and 3403(a) of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Advisory Neighborhood Commission Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-104, July 23, 2001,  48 DCR 7149).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 16(a)(2) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-101, July 23, 2001,  48 DCR 7123).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Advisory Neighborhood Commission Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-56, May 2, 2001,  48 DCR 4410).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 16(a)(2) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-55, May 2, 2001,  48 DCR 4390).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 16(a)(2) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-51">D.C. Law 14-51</cite>, October 30, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 10807).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Advisory Neighborhood Commission Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-21">D.C. Law 14-21</cite>, September 6, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 9091).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> added the subsection designated herein as (b)(24) and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-271">D.C. Law 20-271</cite> substituted “the personnel authority is the Chairman of the Council” for “the personnel authority is the District of Columbia Law Revision Commission” in (b)(11); and added (b)(23) and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-284">D.C. Law 19-284</cite> added (b)(22); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-124">D.C. Law 19-124</cite>, in subsec. (b)(4), substituted “Board of Elections” for “District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics” both times it appears, and substituted “<cite path="§1-1163.02">§ 1-1163.02</cite>” for “D.C. Official Code, <cite path="§1-1103.01">§ 1-1103.01</cite>”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, in subsec. (b)(3)(A), designated the existing text as sub-sub par. (i) and added sub-sub par. (ii).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-126">D.C. Law 16-126</cite>, in subsec. (b)(19), substituted “Sentencing and Criminal Code Revision Commission” for “Sentencing Commission” in two places.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-91">D.C. Law 16-91</cite>, in subsec. (b)(3)(A), inserted “Council and the employees in the Legal Services employed by the Council of the District of Columbia; and, in subsecs. (b)(19), (20), and (21), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-190">D.C. Law 15-190</cite>, in par. (19) of subsec. (b), substituted “District of Columbia Sentencing Commission” for “Advisory Commission on Sentencing” in two places.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-187">D.C. Law 15-187</cite> added a new par. (17) (21) of subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in subsec. (a), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-80">D.C. Law 14-80</cite>, in subsec. (b), added par. (3A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-56">D.C. Law 14-56</cite>, in subsec. (b), added par. (20).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite>, in subsec. (b), added pars. (18) and (19).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-277">D.C. Law 13-277</cite> added par. (17).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite> validated a previously made technical amendment in par. (13) of subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-334.6.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-604.6.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-606.11">§ 1-606.11</cite>, <cite path="§1-609.05">§ 1-609.05</cite>, and <cite path="§50-305" proof="true">§ 50-305</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Taxicab commission, membership, see <cite path="§50-305" proof="true">§ 50-305</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
