<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-602.02</num>
  <heading>Limited application of chapter.</heading>
  <text>The provisions of this chapter shall apply to the following employees of the District of Columbia government only to the following extent:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, each member of the Council of the District of Columbia, and the Attorney General are entitled to pay, as provided in § <cite path="§1-611.09">1-611.09</cite>, in accordance with the provisions of §§ <cite path="§1-204.21">1-204.21</cite>(d) and <cite path="§1-204.03">1-204.03</cite>(a), and § <cite path="§1-301.85">1-301.85</cite>. The Mayor, each member of the Council of the District of Columbia, and the Attorney General may participate in personnel benefit programs authorized in subchapters XXI, XXII, XXIII, and XXVI of this chapter, and are covered by the provisions of subchapters XVIII, XXV, XXIX, XXX, and XXXI of this chapter, and § <cite path="§1-604.08">1-604.08</cite>;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The President and each member of the District of Columbia Board of Education are entitled to pay, as provided in § <cite path="§1-611.10">1-611.10</cite>, and may participate in personnel benefit programs authorized in subchapters XXI, XXII, XXIII, and XXVI of this chapter. The President and each member of the District of Columbia Board of Education are covered by the provisions of subchapters XXV, XXVIII, XXIX, XXX, and XXXI of this chapter, and § <cite path="§1-604.08">1-604.08</cite>;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, each member of a board or commission appointed to perform part-time, temporary or intermittent duties is entitled to pay as provided in § <cite path="§1-611.08">1-611.08</cite>. Full-time employees who serve on boards and commissions shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of § <cite path="§1-611.04">1-611.04</cite> or § <cite path="§1-611.11">1-611.11</cite>. Individuals serving as employees of boards and commissions shall be covered by the provisions of § <cite path="§1-608.01">1-608.01</cite>(e). Members of boards and commissions are covered by the provisions of subchapters XVIII, XIII, XV, XXIX, XXX, and XXXI and §§ <cite path="§1-604.08">1-604.08</cite> and <cite path="§1-608.01">1-608.01</cite>(e) and shall, if eligible under the terms of an agreement entered into by the Mayor and a federal agency under the provisions of subchapter XXVIII of this chapter, be covered by the provisions of subchapters XXI, XXII, and XXVI of this chapter. This section shall not apply to compensation received by the Board of Education as provided in § <cite path="§1-611.10">1-611.10</cite>;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Each person employed as an educational employee of the District of Columbia Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall be governed by the provisions of § <cite path="§1-602.03">1-602.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Each person employed by an Advisory Neighborhood Commission shall be governed by the provisions of subchapters XXI and XXII of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of District law, subchapter XV-A shall apply to all District employees.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§202">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 202, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-81" type="History">Aug. 7, 1980, D.C. Law 3-81, § 2(a), 27 DCR 2632</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-177" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-177, § 3(b), 33 DCR 7241</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 101-518" type="History">Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 2237, Pub. L. 101-518, § 136(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-203" type="History">Mar. 6, 1991, D.C. Law 8-203, § 4, 37 DCR 8420</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-152" type="History">Aug. 1, 1996, D.C. Law 11-152, § 302(a), 43 DCR 2978</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-160" type="History">Oct. 7, 1998, D.C. Law 12-160, § 102(a)(2), 45 DCR 5147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-310" type="History">June 12, 2003, D.C. Law 14-310, § 4(b), 50 DCR 1092</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 1033(a), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 3 of Law 6-177: Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> provided that the provisions of § 3 are repealed on the 1st day following the 36-month period after February 24, 1987.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 4(b) of Law 6-177: Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-74">D.C. Law 8-74</cite>, effective March 15, 1990, provided that § 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> is repealed.</text>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 136(b) of Public Law 101-518, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1991, provided that the amendments made by § 136(a) shall take effect as if included in the enactment of the Residency Preference Amendment Act of 1988 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 7-203">D.C. Law 7-203</cite>, March</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1033(a) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 102(a)(2) of the Whistleblower Reinforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-400, July 13, 1998,  45 DCR 5158) and § 102(a)(2) of the Whistleblower Reinforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-464, October 28, 1998,  45 DCR 7821).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite>, in (1), substituted “Mayor, each member of the Council of the District of Columbia, and the Attorney General” for “Mayor and each member of the Council of the District of Columbia” twice, and substituted “in accordance with the provisions of §§ <cite path="§1-204.21">1-204.21</cite>(d) and <cite path="§1-204.03">1-204.03</cite>(a), and § <cite path="§1-301.85">1-301.85</cite>” for “in accordance with the provisions of §§ <cite path="§1-204.21">1-204.21</cite>(d) and <cite path="§1-204.03">1-204.03</cite>(a)” in the first sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-310">D.C. Law 14-310</cite>, in subsec. (c), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-332.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-602.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-604.04">1-604.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, applicability to Washington Convention Center employees, see § <cite path="§10-1202.16">10-1202.16</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, applicability to national capital revitalization corporation, see § <cite path="§2-1219.05">2-1219.05</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
