<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-612.38</num>
  <heading>Voluntary Transfer of Leave Program Report.</heading>
  <text>On or before February 1 of each year, the Office of Personnel shall provide a Voluntary Transfer of Leave Program Report to the Council. The report shall include:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A comprehensive list of all voluntary leave bank contributors;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A comprehensive list of all transfer of leave recipients;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Documentation demonstrating that proper deductions have been taken from the contributor’s leave accrual;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Documentation demonstrating the actual transfer of leave to the recipient; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>If the head of an agency excludes an employee or group of employees from the program under § <cite path="§1-612.32">1-612.32</cite>(d) because an organization or program within the agency would be substantially disrupted in carrying out its functions or would incur additional costs:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The manner in which the organization or program within the agency would be substantially disrupted in carrying out its functions; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The amount of additional costs which will be incurred and the reasons that they will be incurred.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1238</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-68" type="History">as added Feb. 6, 2004, D.C. Law 15-68, § 2, 50 DCR 9819</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mayor and Council members, coverage, see § <cite path="§1-602.02">1-602.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, continuation of existing laws, see § <cite path="§1-632.06">1-632.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, effective date provisions, see § <cite path="§1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, life insurance, withholdings from employees and annuitants, see § <cite path="§1-622.10">1-622.10</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public assistance, workers’ compensation, recipients of Temporary Assistance for Needy Families, see § <cite path="§4-205.19k">4-205.19k</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Workers’ compensation, “employee” defined, see § <cite path="§32-1501">32-1501</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-612.32">1-612.32</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
