<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-611.06</num>
  <heading>Compensation system for Career and Excepted Services — Review by the Council of the District of Columbia.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Council by resolution approves, without revision, the new compensation system or systems, or any later changes in such system or systems or in the salary or pay schedules under the system or systems proposed in accordance with § <cite path="§1-611.04">1-611.04</cite> or § <cite path="§1-611.05">1-611.05</cite>, the schedules shall become effective on the dates specified in the schedule submitted by the Mayor as provided in subsection (d) of § <cite path="§1-611.05">1-611.05</cite>. If the Council takes no action on the Mayor’s proposed change within 60 calendar days of the submission thereof, such change shall be deemed to have been approved by the Council on the day next following the expiration of this 60-day period. The 60 calendar days for Council review shall not include days that pass during a recess of the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the Council revises the proposal, it shall return the proposal with its revisions to the Mayor. If the Mayor concurs in the revisions, the provisions of the compensation plan as revised shall become effective on the dates specified by the Council in the resolution revising the compensation plan, as provided in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor does not concur in any 1 or more of the revisions recommended by the Council, including the Council’s recommendation as to the dates on which the pay changes shall become effective, the Mayor shall return the revisions within 10 days to the Council, with a statement of the Mayor’s reasons for not concurring. If the Council, by a two-thirds vote of the members present and voting, adopts a resolution insisting upon any 1 or more of the original revisions, the Council shall return the proposal and the revisions upon which the Council insists to the Mayor within 10 days of the Council’s receipt of the Mayor’s statement of reasons for not concurring in the revisions recommended by the Council. If any revisions insisted upon by the Council, including the Council’s recommendation as to the dates on which the pay changes should become effective, shall result in a greater cost to the District government than the Mayor’s original proposal, the Council shall adopt an act to provide a source of funding to cover the increased cost. The pay provisions of the compensation plan so adopted shall become effective on the dates specified by the Council in the resolution revising the new compensation system. If the two-thirds vote does not prevail, or the Council does not act within 10 days of the Council’s receipt of the Mayor’s statement of reasons for not concurring in the revisions recommended by the Council, the Mayor’s original proposal, with the revisions proposed by the Council in which the Mayor has concurred, shall become effective. The 10 days for Council review shall not include Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Retroactive pay is payable by reason of an increase in the salary or pay schedules under this section only where:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The individual is in the service of the District of Columbia government on the date of final action by the Council on the increase; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The individual retired or died during the period beginning on the effective date of the increase and ending on the date of final action by the Council on the increase, and only for the services performed during that period.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Persons newly hired by the District government may receive an initial rate of pay at any amount up to the midpoint of the grade or pay level for the position.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The District government may pay new hires above the midpoint of the grade or pay level for that position only if the agency director or other appointing official explains the reasons justifying the salary in a memorandum that shall be filed in the employee’s official personnel folder.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1106, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-130" type="History">Mar. 4, 1981, D.C. Law 3-130, § 2(e), 28 DCR 277</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-15" type="History">Aug. 1, 1985, D.C. Law 6-15, § 7(c), 32 DCR 3570</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-94" type="History">Mar. 15, 1990, D.C. Law 8-94, § 2(c), 37 DCR 782</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-115" type="History">Mar. 14, 2012, D.C. Law 19-115, § 2(h), 59 DCR 461</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-608.58">1-608.58</cite>, § <cite path="§1-609.03">1-609.03</cite>, § <cite path="§1-611.04">1-611.04</cite>, § <cite path="§1-611.05">1-611.05</cite>, and § <cite path="§1-623.41">1-623.41</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-612.6.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-341.6.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-115">D.C. Law 19-115</cite> added subsec. (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-134">D.C. Law 17-134</cite> provided as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Easy out retirement incentive.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Notwithstanding section 1106 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 2-139">D.C. Law 2-139</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§1-611.06">1-611.06</cite>) (‘CMPA’), the Council of the District of Columbia adopts changes to the compensation system for the Career, Excepted, Legal, and Management Supervisory Services under section 1104 of the CMPA, that authorize the Mayor to establish a retirement incentive program for certain District employees.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The changes to the compensation system are as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) The Mayor is authorized to establish an easy out retirement incentive program (‘Easy Out Program’) for eligible District of Columbia Public Library (‘DCPL’) employees under its independent personnel authority and the pay authority of the Mayor. The Easy Out Program may be implemented by DCPL’s personnel authority during fiscal year 2008.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The Easy Out Program shall be limited to employees who are:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) Retiring under the optional retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(a), (b), or (f); and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Who are eligible to retire with Social Security (minimum age 62).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The Easy Out Program shall offer a retirement incentive of $500 for each full year of creditable service towards retirement. The retirement incentive will be paid in a lump sum to be paid within fiscal year 2008.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) Retirement incentive payments shall not be considered basic pay for computing retirement entitlement, insurance entitlement, any category of premium pay entitlement, lump-sum leave, or any other entitlement that is computed on basic pay.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) No incentive pay shall be paid to:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) An employee who retires under the discontinued service/involuntary retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(d)(1) of the Civil Service Retirement System, or the disability retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8337;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) A person employed as a reemployed annuitant under the provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8344 who separates from District service, whether or not he or she applies for a re-computation of his or her annuity;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) An employee who is receiving disability compensation under Title XXIII of the CMPA who retires and who elects to remain on disability compensation in lieu of retirement annuity;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) An employee serving under a time-limited appointment;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) An employee who receives a proposal or a final decision notice of removal for cause;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F)(i) An employee who is under indictment or who is charged by information with or who has been convicted of a felony or who has been convicted after pleas of nolo contendere to a felony related to his or her employment duties; provided, that any employee who ultimately is acquitted or cleared of any charge that caused his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been indicted for or charged by information with a felony;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii) For the purposes of sub-subparagraph (i) of this sub-subparagraph, the term ‘felony’ means an offense that is punishable by a term of imprisonment that exceeds one year or a fine of at least $1,000;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(G) An employee who, based on conduct related to his or her employment duties, has been convicted of a misdemeanor or who has pled guilty or had been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a misdemeanor; provided, that any employee who is ultimately acquitted or cleared of any charge which caused his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been charged with a misdemeanor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(H) An employee who retires after the designated period for retirement, as applicable; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(I) An employee who has received written notice that his or her services are essential and are required by the agency until a specific date and who retires before the date cited in the notice.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) An employee who receives an incentive payment under the Easy Out Program shall not be eligible for reemployment with the District government for 5 years from the date of retirement, or hired or retained as a sole source consultant or personal services contractor for 5 years from the date of retirement, unless he or she repays the incentive received if reemployed or hired or retained as a sole source consultant or personal services contractor before the end of the 5-year period.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-134">D.C. Law 17-134</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) additions, see §§ 2, 3 of Retirement Incentive Temporary Act of 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-162">D.C. Law 13-162</cite>, October 4, 2000, law notification  47 DCR 8609).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) additions, see § 2 of Unemployment Compensation Services Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-109">D.C. Law 14-109</cite>, April 13, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 4057).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) additions, see § 2 of Unemployment Compensation Services Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-279">D.C. Law 14-279</cite>, April 2, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 3378).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Sections 2 to 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-171">D.C. Law 17-171</cite> added sections to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Easy out retirement incentive.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Notwithstanding section 1106 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 2-139">D.C. Law 2-139</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§1-611.06">1-611.06</cite>) (‘CMPA’), the Council adopts changes to the compensation system for the Career, Excepted, Legal, and Management Supervisory Services under section 1104 of the CMPA, that authorize the Mayor to establish a retirement incentive program for certain District employees.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The changes to the compensation system are as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) The Mayor is authorized to establish an easy out retirement incentive program (‘Easy Out Program’) which may apply to eligible employees under the personnel authority of the Mayor, and employees of any other personnel authority that is under the pay authority of the Mayor if the personnel authority chooses to participate in the Easy Out Program.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The Easy Out Program may be implemented by the appropriate personnel authority at any time during calendar year 2008 after the effective date of this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The Easy Out Program shall be limited to employees retiring under the retirement provisions of the Civil Service Retirement System (Chapter 83 of Title 5 of the U.S. Code), except an employee retiring under the discontinued service/involuntary retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(d)(1) or under the disability retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8337.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) The Easy Out Program shall offer a retirement incentive of 50% of an employee’s annual rate of basic pay from the employee’s salary or pay schedule which was in effect on October 14, 2007, not to exceed $25,000.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) Retirement incentive payments shall be prorated in the case of a part-time employee.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) Retirement incentive payments shall not be considered basic pay for computing retirement entitlement, insurance entitlement, any category of premium pay entitlement, lump-sum leave, or any other entitlement that is computed on basic pay.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) No incentive pay shall be paid to:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) An employee retiring under the discontinued service/involuntary retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(d)(1) or the disability retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8337;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) An employee who is a reemployed annuitant under the provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8344;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) An employee who is in a critical position as defined by regulations promulgated by the Mayor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) An employee who is under indictment or who is charged by information with or who has been convicted of a felony or who has been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a felony related to his or her employment duties; provided, that any employee who ultimately is acquitted or cleared of any charge that caused his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been indicted for or charged by information with a felony;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) An employee who, based on conduct related to his or her employment duties, has been convicted of a misdemeanor or who has plead guilty or has been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a misdemeanor; provided, that any employee who is ultimately acquitted or cleared of any charge which caused his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been charged with a misdemeanor; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F) An employee who is a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) For the purposes of paragraph (7)(D) of this subsection, the term ‘felony’ means an offense that is punishable by a term of imprisonment that exceeds one year or a fine of at least $1,000.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9) An employee who receives an incentive payment under the Easy Out Program shall not be eligible for reemployment with the District government for 5 years from the date of retirement, or hired or retained as a sole source consultant or personal services contractor for 5 years from the date of retirement, unless he or she repays the incentive received if reemployed or hired or retained as a sole source consultant or personal services contractor before the end of the 5-year period.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(10) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (9) of this subsection, and on a case-by-case basis, the Director of the D.C. Department of Human Resources or independent personnel authority may waive repayment of the incentive; provided, that in the case of an emergency situation involving a direct threat to life or property, the person has knowledge, skills, or abilities directly related to resolving the emergency situation and will serve on a temporary basis not to exceed 60 days.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 3. Early out retirement incentive.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Notwithstanding section 1106 of the CMPA, the Council adopts changes to the compensation system for the Career, Excepted, Legal, and Management Supervisory Services under section 1104 of the CMPA that authorize the Mayor to establish a retirement incentive program for certain District employees.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The changes to the compensation system are as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) The Mayor is authorized to establish an early out retirement incentive program (’Early Out Program’) which may apply to eligible employees under the personnel authority of the Mayor and employees of any other personnel authority that is under the pay authority of the Mayor if the personnel authority chooses to participate in the Early Out Program.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The Early Out Program may be implemented by the appropriate personnel authority at any time during calendar year 2008 after the effective date of this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The Early Out Program shall be limited to employees retiring under the early retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8414(b)(1)(B).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) The Early Out Program shall offer a retirement incentive of 50% of an employee’s annual rate of basic pay from the employee’s salary or pay schedule which was in effect on October 14, 2007, not to exceed $25,000.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) Retirement incentive payments shall be prorated in the case of a part-time employee.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) Retirement incentive payments shall not be considered basic pay for computing retirement entitlement, insurance entitlement, any category of premium pay entitlement, lump-sum leave, or any other entitlement that is computed on basic pay.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) No retirement incentive pay shall be paid under this section to:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) An employee retiring under the law enforcement or firefighter provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(c), the discontinued service/involuntary retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336 (d)(1), or the disability retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8337;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) An employee who is a reemployed annuitant under the provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8344;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) An employee who is in a critical position as defined by regulations promulgated by the Mayor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) An employee who is under the indictment or who is charged by information with or who has been convicted of a felony or who has been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a felony related to his or her employment duties; provided, that any employee who ultimately is acquitted or cleared of any charge that cause his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been indicted for or charged by information with a felony;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) An employee who, based on conduct related to his or her employment duties, has been convicted of a misdemeanor or who has plead guilty or has been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a misdemeanor; provided, that any employee who is ultimately acquitted or cleared of any charge which caused his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been charged with a misdemeanor; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F) An employee who is a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) For the purposes of paragraph (7)(D) of this subsection, the term ‘felony’ means an offense that is punishable by a term of imprisonment that exceeds one year or a fine of at least $1,000.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9) An employee who receives an incentive payment under the Early Out Program shall not be eligible for reemployment with the District government for 5 years from the date of retirement, or hired or retained as a sole source consultant or personal services contractor for 5 years from the date of retirement, unless he or she repays the incentive if reemployed or rehired or retained as a sole source consultant or personal services contractor before the end of the 5-year period.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(10) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (9) of this subsection, and on a case-by-case basis, the Director of the D.C. Department of Human Resources or independent personnel authority may waive repayment of the incentive; provided, that in the case of an emergency situation involving a direct threat to life or property, the person has knowledge, skills, or abilities directly related to the resolving the emergency situation and will serve on a temporary basis not to exceed 60 days.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 4. Retirement incentives for employees covered under other retirement systems.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Notwithstanding section 1106 of the CMPA (D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§1-611.06">1-611.06</cite>), the Council of the District of Columbia adopts changes to the compensation system for the Career, Excepted, Legal, and Management Supervisory Services under section 1104 of the CMPA that authorize the Mayor to establish a retirement incentive program for the following employees:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Employees first employed by the District government after September 30, 1987 who have completed at least 5 years of creditable service with the District government, have vested under the Defined Contribution Plan as provided in section 2610 of the CMPA, and are separating from District government service after becoming entitled to retirement benefits under the Social Security Act; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Employees retiring under any of the other District government retirement systems.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) Retirement incentives under this section may be implemented by the appropriate personnel authority at any time during calendar year 2008 after the effective date of this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Retirement incentives under this section shall consist of 50% of an employee’s annual rate of basic pay from the employee’s salary or pay schedule which was in effect on October 14, 2007, not to exceed $25,000.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) Retirement incentive payments shall be prorated in the case of a part-time employee.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) Retirement incentive payments shall not be considered basic pay for computing retirement entitlement, insurance entitlement, any category of premium pay entitlement, lump-sum leave, or any other entitlement that is computed on basic pay.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(f) No retirement incentive under this section shall be paid to:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) An employee who is in a critical position as defined by regulations promulgated by the Mayor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) An employee who is under the indictment or who is charged by information with or who has been convicted of a felony or who has been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a felony related to his or her employment duties; provided, that any employee who ultimately is acquitted or cleared of any charge that cause his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been indicted for or charged by information with a felony;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) An employee who, based on conduct related to his or her employment duties, has been convicted of a misdemeanor or who has plead guilty or has been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a misdemeanor; provided, that any employee who is ultimately acquitted or cleared of any charge which caused his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been charged with a misdemeanor; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) An employee who is a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(g) For the purposes of paragraph (f)(2) of this section, the term ‘felony’ means an offense that is punishable by a term of imprisonment that exceeds one year or a fine of at least $1,000.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(h) An employee who receives an incentive payment under this section shall not be eligible for reemployment with the District government for 5 years from the date of retirement, or hired or retained as a sole source consultant or personal services contractor for 5 years from the date of retirement, unless he or she repays the incentive if reemployed or rehired or retained as a sole source consultant or personal services contractor before the end of the 5-year period.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (h) of this section, and on a case-by-case basis, the Director of the D.C. Department of Human Resources or independent personnel authority may waive repayment of the incentive; provided, that in the case of an emergency situation involving a direct threat to life or property, the person has knowledge, skills, or abilities directly related to the resolving the emergency situation and will serve on a temporary basis not to exceed 60 days.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 5. Retention award. The Mayor shall issue rules to create and implement a Retention Award for Sustained Superior Performance for up to $25,000 for the remainder of the calendar year 2008.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 6. Not an entitlement or private right of action. No provision of this act shall be construed to create an entitlement or private right of action on the part of any District government employee with respect to the easy out retirement incentive or early out retirement incentive.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 7. Rules. The Mayor shall issue rules to implement the provisions of sections 2, 3, 4, and 5.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 9(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-171">D.C. Law 17-171</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary authority of the Mayor to establish retirement incentive programs for certain employees subject to transfer to the Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation, see § 403 of the Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-487, January 2, 1997,  44 DCR 634).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary authority of the Mayor to establish a voluntary severance incentive program for certain employees subject to transfer to the Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation, see § 404 of the Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-487, January 2, 1997,  44 DCR 634).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary approval of proposed changes to the Career and Excepted Service compensation system and temporary authority of the Mayor to establish retirement incentive programs for certain employees, see § 403 of the Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-39, March 31, 1997,  44 DCR 2044).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary approval of proposed changes to the Career and Excepted Service compensation system and temporary authorization of the Mayor to establish a voluntary severance incentive program for certain employees, see § 404 of the Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-39, March 31, 1997,  44 DCR 2044).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary prohibition on re-employment with the District government, see § 405 of the Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-487, January 2, 1997,  44 DCR 634), and § 405 of the Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-39, March 31, 1997,  44 DCR 2044).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see §§ 302 and 303 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 302, 303, and 305 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) authorization of the retention of a former employee, who received a retirement incentive, under a personal services contract as an unemployment compensation claims examiner, see § 2 of Unemployment Compensation Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-216, December 21, 2001,  49 DCR 388).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) authorization of the retention of a former employee, who received a retirement incentive, under a personal services contract as an unemployment compensation claims examiner, see § 2 of Unemployment Compensation Services Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-299, March 25, 2002,  49 DCR 3382).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) authorization of the retention of a former employee who received a retirement incentive under a personal services contract as an unemployment claims examiner, see § 2 of Unemployment Compensation Services Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-566, December 23, 2002,  50 DCR 290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) authorization of the retention of a former employee who received a retirement incentive under a personal services contract as an unemployment claims examiner, see § 2 of the Unemployment Compensation Program Services Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-34, March 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2566).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of District of Columbia Public Library Retirement Incentive Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-240, January 11, 2008,  55 DCR 2209).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 2 to 7 of Retirement Incentive Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-321, March 20, 2008,  55 DCR 3439).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Resolutions">Resolution 16-219, the “Excepted Service Employees Compensation System Changes Approval Resolution of 2005”, was approved effective July 6, 2005.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Fiscal Year 1995 Spending Reduction Conditional Approval Emergency Resolution of 1994: Pursuant to Resolution 10-423, effective August 5, 1994, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the proposed Easy Out and Early Out Retirement Incentive Programs for Career and Excepted Service Employees under the Mayor’s personnel authority and the District of Columbia General Hospital Operational and Financial Viability Plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Fiscal Year 1995 Spending Reduction Amendment Approval Emergency Resolution of 1994: Pursuant to Resolution 10-455, effective November 1, 1994, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, changes to the Career and Excepted Service compensation system to authorize the Mayor to extend the retirement incentive program for certain District government employees.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District Government Voluntary Severance Incentive Program Approval Emergency Resolution of 1994: Pursuant to Resolution 10-490, effective December 6, 1994, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the proposed Voluntary Severance Incentive Program for Career and Excepted Service Employees.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Metropolitan Police Department pay and benefit performance: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§1-611.05">1-611.05</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Optical and dental benefits: Section 401(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-52">D.C. Law 11-52</cite> provided that the optical and dental benefits for Career and Excepted Services employees not covered by collective bargaining, approved pursuant to Resolution 6-305, are reduced to a level that will allow maximum benefits to continue within available appropriations.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 401(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-52">D.C. Law 11-52</cite> provided that the Mayor shall renegotiate the optical and dental benefits contract to implement subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Fiscal Year 1995 Spending Reduction Approval Emergency Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Resolution 11-21, effective February 7, 1995, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, changes to the Career and Excepted Service compensation system to authorize the Mayor to extend the retirement incentive program for certain District government employees.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Contract Appeals Board Career and Excepted Service Compensation Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-396, effective March 3, 1998, the Council approved the compensation for the Contract Appeals Board Career and Excepted Services.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Office of Emergency Preparedness Executive Service Compensation Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-397, effective March 3, 1998, the Council approved the proposed compensation submitted by the Mayor for the Director of the Office of Emergency Preparedness.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Career and Excepted Service Employees Compensation System Changes for Fire Fighters Approval Emergency Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-434, effective March 3, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the proposed compensation system changes for uniformed members of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department not covered by collective bargaining.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department Salary Adjustment Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-471, effective April 21, 1998, the Council approved a salary adjustment for the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Career, Educational, and Excepted Service Nonunion Employee Emergency Compensation System Change Emergency Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-487, effective June 2, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, a compensation system change for Career, Educational, and Excepted Service nonunion employees.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Career and Excepted Services Compensation System Changes for Nonunion Officers and Members of the Metropolitan Police Department Emergency Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-506, effective May 19, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the proposed Career and Excepted Services compensation system changes for nonunion officers and members of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Contract Appeals Board Career and Excepted Service Compensation Changes Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-583, effective July 7, 1998, the Council approved the proposed compensation submitted by the Mayor for Judge Jonathan D. Zischkau, Administrative Judge of the Contract Appeals Board.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Career and Expected Service Employees Compensation System Changes for Metropolitan Police Officers Emergency Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-558, effective June 16, 1998, the Council approved the Career and Expected Service Employees compensation system changes for the Metropolitan Police Officers.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Metropolitan Police Department Civilian Communications Supervisors Pay Increase Emergency Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-766, effective November 10, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the proposed compensation changes for civilian employees of the District of Columbia Metropolitan Police Department Communications Division not covered by collective bargaining.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Career and Excepted Service Employees Compensation System Changes for Firefighters Emergency Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-778, effective November 10, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the proposed compensation system changes for uniformed members of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department not covered by collective bargaining.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Career and Expected Services Compensation System Changes for Nonunion Employees of the Commission on Mental Health Services Emergency Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-840, effective December 15, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the proposed compensation system changes for nonunion employees of the Commission on Mental Health Services.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Attorney Retention Allowance Compensation System Change for Attorneys in the Office of the Corporation Counsel Emergency Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-859, effective December 15, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, a compensation system change that authorizes the Mayor to establish and to pay an attorney retention allowance of up to 20% for series DS-905 attorneys in the Office of the Corporation Counsel.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Career and Expected Service Employees Compensation System Changes for DS-699 (Emergency Medical Technician, Intermediate Technician, and Paramedic) Employees Emergency Approval Resolution of Fiscal Year 1999: Pursuant to Resolution 12-846, effective December 15, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the proposed compensation system changes for civilian employees in series DS-699 (Emergency Medical Technician, Intermediate Technician, and Paramedic) of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department not covered by collective bargaining.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Sections 302, 303, and 305 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 302. Easy out retirement incentive.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) Notwithstanding section 1106 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 (‘CMPA’) the Council adopts changes to the Career and Excepted Service compensation system under section 1104 of the CMPA, that authorize the Mayor to establish a retirement incentive program for certain District employees.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The changes to the compensation system are as follows:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) The Mayor is authorized to establish an easy out retirement incentive program (‘Easy Out Program’) which shall apply to eligible employees under the personnel authority of the Mayor, and employees of any other personnel authority that is under the pay authority of the Mayor if the personnel authority chooses to participate in the Easy Out Program.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) The Easy Out Program may be implemented by the appropriate personnel authority at any time after the effective date of this act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(3) The Easy Out Program shall be limited to employees retiring under the optional retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(a), (b), or (f).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(4) The Easy Out Program shall offer a retirement incentive of not more than 50% of an employee’s annual rate of basic pay from the employee’s salary or pay schedule which was in effect on April 9, 2000, not to exceed $25,000, to be paid within one year of the employee’s retirement.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(5) Retirement incentive payments shall be prorated in the case of a part- time employee.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(6) Retirement incentive payments shall not be considered basic pay for computing retirement entitlement, insurance entitlement, any category of premium pay entitlement, lump-sum leave, or any other entitlement that is computed on basic pay.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(7) No incentive payment shall be paid to:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(A) An employee retiring under the law enforcement or firefighter provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(c), the discontinued service/involuntary retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(d)(1), or the disability retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8337;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(B) An employee who is a reemployed annuitant under the provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8344;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(C) An employee who is in a critical position as defined by regulations promulgated by the Mayor;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(D) An employee who is a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(E) An employee who is under indictment or who is charged by information with or who has been convicted of a felony or who has been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a felony related to his or her employment duties; provided, that any employee who is ultimately acquitted or cleared of any charge that caused his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been indicted for or charged by information with a felony; or</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(F) An employee who, based on conduct related to his or her employment duties, has been convicted of a misdemeanor or who has plead guilty or has been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a misdemeanor; provided, that any employee who is ultimately acquitted or cleared of any charge that caused his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been charged with a misdemeanor.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(8) For the purposes of paragraph (7)(E) of this subsection, the term ‘felony’ means an offense that is punishable by a term of imprisonment that exceeds one year or a fine of at least $1,000.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(9) An employee who receives an incentive payment under the Easy Out Program shall not be eligible for reemployment with the District government for 5 years from the date of retirement, or hired or retained as a sole source consultant or personal services contractor for 5 years from the date of retirement.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 303. Early out retirement incentive.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) Notwithstanding section 1106 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 (‘CMPA’), the Council adopts changes to the Career and Excepted Service compensation system under section 1104 of the CMPA, that authorize the Mayor to establish a retirement incentive program for certain District employees.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The changes to the compensation system are as follows:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) The Mayor is authorized to establish an early out retirement incentive program (‘Early Out Program’) which shall apply to eligible employees under the personnel authority of the Mayor, and employees of any other personnel authority that is under the pay authority of the Mayor, if the personnel authority chooses to participate in the Early Out Program.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) The Early Out Program may be implemented by the appropriate personnel authority at any time after the effective date of this act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(3) The Early Out Program shall be limited to employees retiring under the voluntary early out retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(d)(2).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(4) The Early Out Program shall offer a retirement incentive of not more than 50% of an employee’s annual rate of basic pay from the employee’s salary or pay schedule which was in effect on April 9, 2000, not to exceed $25,000, to be paid within one year of the employee’s retirement.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(5) Retirement incentive payments shall be prorated in the case of a part- time employee.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(6) Retirement incentive payments shall not be considered basic pay for computing retirement entitlement, insurance entitlement, any category of premium pay entitlement, lump-sum leave, or any other entitlement that is computed on basic pay.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(7) No incentive payment shall be paid to:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(A) An employee retiring under the law enforcement or firefighter provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(c), the discontinued service/involuntary retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8336(d)(1), or the disability retirement provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8337;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(B) An employee who is a reemployed annuitant under the provisions of  5 U.S.C. § 8344;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(C) An employee who is in a critical position as defined by regulations promulgated by the Mayor;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(D) An employee who is a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(E) An employee who is under indictment or who is charged by information with or who has been convicted of a felony or who has been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a felony related to his or her employment duties; provided, that any employee who is ultimately acquitted or cleared of any charge that caused his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been indicted for or charged by information with a felony; or</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(F) An employee who, based on conduct related to his or her employment duties, has been convicted of a misdemeanor or who has plead guilty or has been convicted after a plea of nolo contendere to a misdemeanor; provided, that any employee who is ultimately acquitted or cleared of any charge that caused his or her ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee had never been charged with a misdemeanor.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(8) For the purposes of paragraph (7)(E) of this subsection, the term ‘felony’ means an offense that is punishable by a term of imprisonment that exceeds one year or a fine of a least $1,000.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(9) An employee who receives an incentive payment under the Early Out Program shall not be eligible for reemployment with the District government for 5 years from the date of retirement, or hired or retained as a sole source consultant or personal services contractor for 5 years from the date of retirement.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 305. Sunset provision. This title shall expire on December 31, 2000.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
