<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-612.01</num>
  <heading>Hours of work.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A basic administrative workweek of 40 hours is established for each full-time employee and the hours of work within that workweek shall be performed within a period of not more than 6 of any 7 consecutive days; except, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The basic workweek for uniformed members of the Firefighting Division of the District of Columbia Fire Department shall not exceed 48 hours and the Division shall operate under a 2-shift system with all hours of duty of either shift being consecutive; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The basic workweek, hours of work, and tour of duty for all employees of the Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall be established under rules and regulations issued by the respective Boards; provided, that the basic work scheduling for all employees in recognized collective bargaining units to these established tours of duty shall be subject to collective bargaining, and collective bargaining provisions related to scheduling shall take precedence over conflicting provisions of this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except when the Mayor determines that an organization would be seriously handicapped in carrying out its functions or that costs would be substantially increased, tours of duty shall be established to provide, with respect to each employee in an organization, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assignments to tours of duty are scheduled in advance over periods of not less than 1 week;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The basic 40 hour workweek is scheduled on 5 days, Monday through Friday when practicable, and the 2 days outside the basic workweek are consecutive;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The working hours in each day in the basic workweek are the same;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Overtime shall be paid in accordance with Title XVII and the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, approved June 25, 1938 (52 Stat. 1060; 29 U.S.C. § 201 et seq.);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The occurrence of holidays may not affect the designation of the basic workweek; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Breaks in working hours of more than 1 hour may not be scheduled in a basic workday except under rules and regulations on flexible work schedules as provided in subsection (e) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Special tours of duty, of not less than 40 hours, may be established to enable employees to take courses in nearby colleges, universities or other educational institutions that will equip them for more effective work in the District government. Premium pay may not be paid to an employee solely because his or her special tour of duty results in his or her working on a day or at a time of day for which premium pay is otherwise authorized.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>To the maximum extent practicable, time to be spent by an employee in a travel status away from his or her official duty station shall be scheduled within the regularly scheduled workweek of the employee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall issue rules and regulations governing hours of work. Such rules and regulations shall provide for the use of flexible work schedules within the 40 hour workweek when such schedules are considered both practicable and feasible.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1201, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-177" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-177, § 3(p), 33 DCR 7241</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-152" type="History">Aug. 1, 1996, D.C. Law 11-152, § 302(o), 43 DCR 2978</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-124" type="History">June 10, 1998, D.C. Law 12-124, § 101(o)(1), 45 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-334" type="History">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-334, § 2(a), 52 DCR 2012</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 1032(a), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Retirement of public school teachers, annuities, computation, years of service, see § <cite path="§38-2021.08">38-2021.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-623.47">1-623.47</cite> and § <cite path="§38-2021.08">38-2021.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-613.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-342.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-334">D.C. Law 15-334</cite> rewrote subsec. (a)(2) which had read as follows: “(2) The basic workweek and hours of work for all employees of the Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall be established under rules and regulations issued by the respective Boards; provided, however, that the basic work scheduling for all employees in recognized collective bargaining units shall be subject to collective bargaining, and collective bargaining agreements shall take precedence over the provisions of this subchapter.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> rewrote subsec. (b)(4), which had read as follows: “(4) The basic nonovertime workday may not exceed 8 hours;”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">Sections 2 to 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-1">D.C. Law 19-1</cite> added sections to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“Sec. 2. Furloughing of employees.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(a)(1) Notwithstanding any other District law or regulation, and except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and section 3, the personnel authority of each subordinate and independent agency and instrumentality of the District of Columbia government shall furlough each of its full-time employees for 4 legal public holidays without pay during the fiscal year ending September 30, 2011, and each of its part-time employees with a scheduled tour of duty for the appropriate pro-rated amount of furlough hours for the 4 furlough days.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(2) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the unpaid furlough days required by this act shall be scheduled on the following legal public holidays, as that term is described in section 1202 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 2-139">D.C. Law 2-139</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§1-612.02">1-612.02</cite>):</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(A) Washington’s Birthday, Monday, February 21, 2011;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(B) District of Columbia Emancipation Day, Friday, April 15, 2011;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(C) Memorial Day, Monday, May 30, 2011; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(D) Independence Day, Monday, July 4, 2011.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(b)(1) Each agency and instrumentality shall furlough each covered employee on the designated legal public holidays, unless doing so:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(A) Would impair the ability of the agency or instrumentality to fulfill its essential or emergency public health or public safety functions;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(B) Would impair the ability of the agency or instrumentality to fulfill its mission;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(C) Is not possible because the holiday is not part of an employee’s pay period; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(D) Is not legally permissible.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(2) If a covered employee cannot be furloughed on any of the legal public holidays listed in subsection (a)(2) of this section due to any of the reasons listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection, as determined by the Mayor, the employing agency or instrumentality, in consultation with the applicable personnel authority, shall schedule the furlough day on an alternate date in the same pay period that does not impair the ability of the agency or instrumentality to fulfill its mission, as determined by the Mayor. The District of Columbia Public Schools shall not furlough a classroom teacher on a date when there is classroom instruction during an instructional period.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(3)(A) Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, the 4 furlough days required under subsection (a) of this section may be scheduled on alternate dates in the same or subsequent pay periods for covered employees, including correctional officers, working in an agency listed in this paragraph; provided, that each of the covered employees is furloughed the required 4 days by July 31, 2011. This paragraph shall apply to the:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(i) Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services employees at the Youth Services Center and at New Beginnings;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(ii) Department of Corrections correctional personnel at the Central Detention Facility;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(iii) Office of Unified Communications employees; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(iv) Office of the Chief Medical Examiner employees.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(B) The Mayor shall have discretion in the application of the furlough provided under this paragraph.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(c) To the extent possible, employees who are newly hired after any of the 4 legal public holidays designated as furlough days shall be furloughed during the same pay period of the legal public holiday.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(d) Unless a subordinate or independent agency or instrumentality has authority to adopt rules governing furloughs and has adopted such rules, each agency and instrumentality is subject to the furlough rules published at 6 DCMR B §§ 2438 through 2446 and 2499, or emergency rules published by the District of Columbia Department of Human Resources to implement the provisions of this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(e)(1) Notwithstanding any other District law or regulation, each employee shall be provided not less than 15 days written notice before the employee’s first furlough date and the provision of 15 days written notice shall be sufficient notice to permit the furloughing of the employee on that first furlough date.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(2) If an employing agency or instrumentality is unable to give notice in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection for the unpaid furlough day specified by subsection (a)(2)(A) of this section, or schedule the furlough day as required by this act, the employing agency or instrumentality, in consultation with the applicable personnel authority, shall schedule the furlough day on an alternate date in any subsequent pay period on or before July 31, 2011.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“Sec. 3. Scope of coverage.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(a) This act shall apply to all subordinate and independent agencies and instrumentalities, except the following agencies or instrumentalities:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(1) Not-for-Profit Hospital Corporation;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(2) District of Columbia Housing Authority;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(3) District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(4) Washington Convention and Sports Authority; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(5) District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(b) The following positions shall be exempt from the coverage of this act:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(1) Positions in an agency that is the subject of a court order specifically excluding the positions from furlough actions; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(2) Certain essential or emergency positions, as determined by the Mayor by executive order, within the Metropolitan Police Department and the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“Sec. 4. Transfer of funds. All furlough cost savings associated with special purpose revenue or dedicated taxes shall be transferred to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">Section 6(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-1">D.C. Law 19-1</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1032(a) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of sections, see §§ 2 to 4 of Balanced Budget Holiday Furlough Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-3, February 2, 2011,  58 DCR 1241).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of § 2 of D.C. Act 19-3, see § 2 of Public Safety Civilian Emergency Personnel Furlough Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-28, March 1, 2011,  58 DCR 2587.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of sections, see §§ 2 to 4 of Balanced Budget Holiday Furlough Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-50, April 27, 2011,  58 DCR 3874).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 5 of Fiscal Year 2012 Second Revised Budget Request Emergency Adjustment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-382, June 20, 2012,  59 DCR 7760).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 5 of Fiscal Year 2012 Second Revised Budget Request Congressional Review Emergency Adjustment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-406, July 20, 2012,  59 DCR 9124).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1031 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle D of title I of the act may be cited as the “Overtime Work Hours Amendment Act of 2010”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 3 of Law 6-177: Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> provided that the provisions of § 3 are repealed on the 1st day following the 36-month period after February 24, 1987.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 4(b) of Law 6-177: Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-74">D.C. Law 8-74</cite>, effective March 15, 1990, provided that § 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> is repealed.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of § 101(l)(1) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-124">D.C. Law 12-124</cite>: Section 401(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-124">D.C. Law 12-124</cite>, as amended by § 60 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-264">D.C. Law 12-264</cite>, provided that § 101(o)(1) of the act shall apply upon the enactment by the United States Congress of an amendment to  29 U.S.C. § 207 of the Fair Labor Standards Act to exempt the District of Columbia government from the applicability of the overtime provisions when employees are on a compressed work schedule up to 80 hours per pay period. Since Congress has not, as of date, enacted such an amendment, the amendments made by section 101(o)(1) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-210">D.C. Law 11-210</cite> have not been implemented.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Since Congress has not, as of date, enacted such an amendment, the amendments made by section 101(o)(1) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-124">D.C. Law 12-124</cite> have not been implemented.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
