<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-611.01</num>
  <heading>Classification policy; grade levels; publication required; public hearing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The classification of all positions in the Career, Educational, Legal, Excepted, and the Management Supervisory Services will be accomplished in accordance with the following policy:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Individual positions will be grouped and identified by classes and grades, in accordance with their duties, responsibilities, and qualification requirements and shall be indexed and cross referenced in the incumbent classification and compensation system; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The principle of equal pay for substantially equal work will be supported.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The grade levels of all positions in the Career, Educational, Legal, Excepted, and the Management Supervisory Services shall be based on the consideration of applicable factors, such as knowledge and skills required by the positions; supervisory controls exercised over the work; guidelines used; complexity of the work; scope and effect of the work; personal contacts; purpose of contacts; physical demands of the positions; and work environment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Classification systems or proposals developed under the authority of this subchapter shall be published in the District of Columbia Register at least 60 days prior to their proposed effective date. The Mayor or the Board of Education or the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall hold, as provided in this subchapter, a public hearing on all such proposals he, she, or it has published in the District of Columbia Register prior to his, her, or its adoption of a classification system or amendment to such system; provided, that the classification system or systems in effect on December 31, 1979, shall remain in effect until the adoption of a classification system or systems pursuant to <cite path="§1-611.02">§ 1-611.02</cite> or <cite path="§1-611.11">§ 1-611.11</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§1101">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1101, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-130" type="History">Mar. 4, 1981, D.C. Law 3-130, § 2(a), 28 DCR 277</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-177" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-177, § 3(k), 33 DCR 7241</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-152" type="History">Aug. 1, 1996, D.C. Law 11-152, § 302(j), 43 DCR 2978</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000. D.C. Law 13-91, § 103(m), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 3(e), (f), 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 3 of Law 6-177: Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> provided that the provisions of § 3 are repealed on the 1st day following the 36-month period after February 24, 1987.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 4(b) of Law 6-177: Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-74">D.C. Law 8-74</cite>, effective March 15, 1990, provided that § 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> is repealed.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Compensation for District employees: Section 120 of Pub. L. 104-194, 110 Stat. 2366, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1997, provided that notwithstanding any other provisions of law, the provisions of <cite path="§1-601.01">§ 1-601.01</cite> et seq., enacted pursuant to <cite path="§1-204.22|(3)">§ 1-204.22(3)</cite>, shall apply with respect to the compensation of District of Columbia employees and provided that, for pay purposes, employees of the District of Columbia government shall not be subject to the provisions of title 5 of the United States Code.</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) response by the government of the District of Columbia’s to the federal shutdown, or lapse in appropriations, by designating personnel as essential, authorizing the District to employ personal services, and providing for the compensation of personnel, see §§ 2 to 6 of the Federal Shutdown Response Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-182, October 4, 2013,  60 DCR 14955).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Financial Stability Measures Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-593, November 3, 2010,  57 DCR 10475).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of sections, see §§ 2 to 5 of Financial Stability Measures Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-588, October 19, 2010,  57 DCR 10140).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 1142 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 1022 to 1027 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of Freeze of Within-Grade Salary Increases provisions of Title I of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-51), Title I of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-97), and Title I of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Temporary Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-92), see §§ 2 and 3 of the Freeze of Within-Grade Salary Increase Repeal Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-122, July 29, 2003,  50 DCR 6619).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) Freeze of Within-Grade Salary Increases provisions, see §§ 102 and 103 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-97, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5472).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) Freeze of Within-Grade Salary Increases provisions, see §§ 102 and 103 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-51, March 31, 2003,  50 DCR 2954).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of the Legal Services Clarification and Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-293, March 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2063).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of the Legal Services Clarification and Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-203, December 8, 1999,  46 DCR 10456).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-25">D.C. Law 15-25</cite>, see § 2 of Freeze of Within-Grade Salary Increase Repeal Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-49">D.C. Law 15-49</cite>, December 9, 2003, law notification  51 DCR 1784).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) additions, see §§ 101 to 104 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-25">D.C. Law 15-25</cite>, July 22, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 6095).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “Excepted, and the Management Supervisory Services” for “and the Excepted Services”; and in subsec. (b), substituted “Excepted, and the Management Supervisory Services” for “and Excepted Services”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, in the introductory portion of subsec. (a) and in subsec. (b), inserted “Legal,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-341.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-612.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-611.02">§ 1-611.02</cite>, <cite path="§1-611.11">§ 1-611.11</cite>, <cite path="§1-1161.01">§ 1-1161.01</cite>, <cite path="§1-1163.02">§ 1-1163.02</cite>, <cite path="§42-3502.03b">§ 42-3502.03b</cite>, and <cite path="§42-3502.04a">§ 42-3502.04a</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Rental housing commission members, compensation, see <cite path="§42-3502.01">§ 42-3502.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Rent administrator, compensation, see <cite path="§42-3502.03">§ 42-3502.03</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
