<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-617.11</num>
  <heading>Rights accompanying exclusive recognition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The labor organization which has been certified to be the exclusive representative of all employees in the unit shall have the right to act for and negotiate agreements covering all employees in the unit and shall be responsible for representing the interests of all such employees without discrimination and without regard to membership in the labor organization: Provided, however, that the employee pays dues or service fees consistent with law. Agency shop and other labor organization security provisions should be an appropriate issue for collective bargaining.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Bargaining units established at the time this chapter becomes effective shall continue to be recognized as appropriate units subject to § <cite path="§1-617.09">1-617.09</cite>(c), and labor organizations which have exclusive recognition in bargaining units existing at the time this chapter becomes effective shall continue to enjoy exclusive recognition in these units subject to § <cite path="§1-617.10">1-617.10</cite>(b)(2).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1711, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 3832(d), 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-617.06">1-617.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-618.11.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-347.11.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “consistent with law” for “in an amount equal to the dues of the employees’ organizations”.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3732(d) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
