<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-612.03c</num>
  <heading>Family leave.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An eligible employee shall receive leave with pay for family leave of not more than 8 workweeks within a 12-month period for a single qualifying event.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Leave authorized by this section for a single qualifying event:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>May be exercised by an eligible employee only within the 12-month period following the qualifying event;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>May be used in no less than one-day increments, either consecutively or intermittently; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Shall count against the 16 workweeks of family leave provided under § <cite path="§32-502">32-502</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If an employee using leave under this section is serving in a probationary capacity, the employee’s probationary period shall be extended by the duration of the leave used.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An eligible employee using leave under this section shall enjoy the same employment and benefit protections afforded to an employee under § <cite path="§32-505">32-505</cite>; provided, that § <cite path="§32-505">32-505</cite>(f) shall not apply under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An agency may require that a request for leave under this section be supported by appropriate certification or other supporting documentation. An agency shall keep any information regarding the family relationship confidential.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Each agency shall maintain an accounting of leave used under this section and any records related to its use.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Child” means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A person under 21 years of age;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A person, regardless of age, who is substantially dependent upon the employee by reason of physical or mental disability; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A person who is under 23 years of age who is a full-time student at an accredited college or university.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Eligible employee” means a District government employee; provided, that the term “eligible employee” does not include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A short-term employee appointed for less than 90 days; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An employee with intermittent employment.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Family member” means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A person to whom the employee is related by blood, legal custody, domestic partnership, or marriage;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A foster child;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A child who lives with the employee and for whom the employee permanently assumes and discharges parental responsibility; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A person with whom the employee shares or has shared, within the last year, a mutual residence and with whom the employee maintains a committed relationship.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Qualifying event” means one of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The birth of a child of the employee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The legal placement of a child with the employee (such as through adoption, guardianship, or foster care);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The placement with the employee of a child for whom the employee permanently assumes and discharges parental responsibilities; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The care of a family member of the employee who has a serious health condition.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§1203c">March 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, §  1203c</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">as added Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 1052(b), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 7026, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 1053 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> provided that an employee may exercise leave under § <cite path="§1-612.03c">1-612.03c</cite> for a qualifying event that occurred before Feb. 26, 2015; provided, that the employee otherwise meets the requirements of § <cite path="§1-612.03c">1-612.03c</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 1053 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite>, § 7024(a).</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 1053, see § 7016(3) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7016(b) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 1053, see § 2(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 2-139">D.C. Law 2-139</cite>, § 1203c, concerning family leave, see §§ 1052(b) and  1053 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 1053, see § 2(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014, 61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as enacted by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 1052(b), see § 2(b) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014, 61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 2-139">D.C. Law 2-139</cite>, § 1203c, concerning family leave, see §§ 1052(b) and  1053 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 2-139">D.C. Law 2-139</cite>, § 1203c, concerning family leave, see §§ 1052(b) and  1053 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 1053, see § 2(f)( 1) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-179">D.C. Law 20-179</cite>, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-179">D.C. Law 20-179</cite>, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> rewrote (g)(2).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
