<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-611.08</num>
  <heading>Compensation — Members of boards and commissions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each member of any board or commission who receives compensation or reimbursement of expenses on January 1, 1980, shall receive such rates of compensation or reimbursement of expenses as are provided in existing law, rule, regulation, or order, or in this chapter, except as may be modified from time to time by rules and regulations published pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, members of boards and commissions shall not be compensated for time expended in the performance of official duties except as authorized by subsections (b), (c), (c-1), (c-2), and (c-3) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to establish by rule and regulation the rates of compensation or reimbursement of expenses for members of any board or commission, including any board or commission established after January 1, 1980. Any such rules and regulations proposed by the Mayor shall be transmitted to the Council of the District of Columbia for a 30-day (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days on which the Council of the District of Columbia is on recess) review period. Such rules and regulations shall become effective only if the Council of the District of Columbia does not adopt, within 30 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days on which the Council of the District of Columbia is on recess) from the date of the Mayor’s submission, a resolution disapproving such rules and regulations in whole or in part. Notwithstanding the provisions of § <cite path="§1-604.05">1-604.05</cite>, rules and regulations published under this subsection shall be effective no earlier than 30 days after their publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Members of the following boards and commissions shall be entitled to compensation in the form of a salary as currently authorized by law:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Public Service Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Contract Appeals Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Rental Housing Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Chairperson of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Board of Ethics and Government Accountability; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Full-time members of the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <text>Members of the following boards and commissions shall be entitled to compensation in the form of an hourly rate of pay as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Board of Zoning Adjustment members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $12,000 for each board member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Office of Employee Appeals members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $3,000 for each member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Retirement Board Members shall be entitled to compensation as provided in § <cite path="§1-711">1-711</cite>(c);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Police and Firefighters Retirement and Relief Board members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $8,000 for each board member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Public Employee Relations Board members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $3,000 for each board member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Zoning Commission members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $12,000 for each commission member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Historic Preservation Review Board members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $3,000 for each board member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Alcoholic Beverage Control Board members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $40 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $18,000 for each board member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Part-time members of the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $50 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Board of Elections members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $40 while actually in the service of the board, not to exceed the $12,500 for each member per year and $26,500 for the Chairman per year.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-2)</num>
    <text>Members of the following boards and commissions shall be entitled to compensation in the form of stipend as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each Commissioner, other than the ex officio Commissioner and the Chairperson, of the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia Housing Authority shall be entitled to a stipend of $4,000 per year for their service on the board; the Chairperson shall be entitled to a stipend of $6,000 per year. Each Commissioner also shall be entitled to reimbursement of actual travel and other expenses reasonably related to attendance at board meetings and fulfillment of official duties. Stipends and reimbursements shall be made at least quarterly; provided, that all stipends shall be paid from non-District funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each member of the Higher Education Licensure Commission shall be entitled to a stipend of $8,000 per year for their service on the commission. Each member also shall be entitled to reimbursement of actual travel and other expenses reasonably related to the performance of the duties of the commission while away from their homes or regular places of business; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Public and industry members of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission shall be entitled to compensation of $25 per meeting or work session, not to exceed $1,350 for each public or industry member per year.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Total compensation for all Commission members shall not exceed $10,800, for all meetings and work sessions.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-3)</num>
    <text>Chairpersons of the boards and commissions specified in subsections (c-1) and (c-2) of this section who are public members shall be entitled to an additional compensation of 20% above the annual maximum.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Members of boards and commissions shall not be entitled to reimbursement for expenses unless specifically authorized by law; except, that transportation, parking, or mileage expenses incurred in the performance of official duties may be reimbursed, not to exceed $15 per meeting or currently authorized amounts, whichever is less.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall conduct a comprehensive study of the compensation and stipend levels of the District’s boards and commissions, recognizing the different characteristics of these entities, and examining the best practices in the compensation and stipend policies of surrounding and comparable jurisdictions. Based on this study, the Mayor shall provide a report to the Council by December 31, 2002, with recommendations for a rational compensation and stipend policy applicable to boards and commissions, including any recommendations for changes in specific compensation and stipend levels that could be addressed in the FY 2004 budget and financial plan.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1108, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-81" type="History">Aug. 7, 1980, D.C. Law 3-81, § 2(k), 27 DCR 2632</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 801(b), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-60" type="History">Mar. 20, 1998, D.C. Law 12-60, § 101, 44 DCR 7378</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 106-113" type="History">Nov. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 1515, Pub. L. 106-113, § 119(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-38" type="History">Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-38,§ 302, 46 DCR 6373</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 201, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, §§ 2403, 2502, 2603, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 102(b), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1212, 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 5(b), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91" type="History">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, § 120(b), 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-159" type="History">Sept. 19, 2006, D.C. Law 16-159, § 3, 53 DCR 5385</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-361" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-361, § 3, 56 DCR 1204</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-363" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-363, § 3(b), 58 DCR 963</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 1132, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-198" type="History">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-198, § 2(b), 61 DCR 12450</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-271" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-271, § 241, 62 DCR 1884</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 2202, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-74" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-74, § 3, 63 DCR 252</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Board of consumer claims arbitration, compensation, see § <cite path="§50-503">50-503</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Board of elections and ethics, compensation, see § <cite path="§1-1001.04">1-1001.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Board of library trustees, compensation, see § <cite path="§39-104">39-104</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Board of real property assessments and appeals, compensation, see § <cite path="§47-825.01">47-825.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Board of veterinary examiners, compensation, see § <cite path="§3-505">3-505</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Boxing and wrestling commission, member compensation, see § <cite path="§3-604">3-604</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Education licensure commission, compensation, see § <cite path="§38-1304">38-1304</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Employee deferred compensation program, employee eligibility, treatment of benefits, authorization of program, see § <cite path="§47-3601">47-3601</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Health occupations, members of health occupation boards and advisory committees, compensation, see § <cite path="§3-1204.06">3-1204.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Law revision commission, compensation, see § <cite path="§45-301">45-301</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mayor’s authority to determine honorariums, “honorariums” defined, see § <cite path="§1-321.01">1-321.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Occupational safety and health commission, compensation, see § <cite path="§32-1106">32-1106</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public fund for drug prevention and children at risk, compensation, see § <cite path="§47-4003">47-4003</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Statewide health coordinating council, reimbursement of certain member expenses, see § <cite path="§44-403">44-403</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Taxation, non-health related occupations and professions licensure, establishment of boards, compensation, see § <cite path="§47-2853.09">47-2853.09</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Taxicab commission, compensation, see § <cite path="§50-305">50-305</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Tax revision commission, reimbursement of certain member expenses, see § <cite path="§47-463">47-463</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Workers’ compensation insurance study commission, establishment, see § <cite path="§32-1542.01">32-1542.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-137.02">1-137.02</cite>, § <cite path="§1-321.01">1-321.01</cite>, § <cite path="§1-602.02">1-602.02</cite>, § <cite path="§1-603.01">1-603.01</cite>, § <cite path="§1-606.01">1-606.01</cite>, § <cite path="§1-611.12">1-611.12</cite>, § <cite path="§1-611.52">1-611.52</cite>, § <cite path="§1-612.03">1-612.03</cite>, § <cite path="§1-1001.04">1-1001.04</cite>, § <cite path="§1-1162.05">1-1162.05</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1404.03">2-1404.03</cite>, § <cite path="§3-604">3-604</cite>, § <cite path="§3-1204.06">3-1204.06</cite>, § <cite path="§3-1442">3-1442</cite>, § <cite path="§32-1106">32-1106</cite>, § <cite path="§32-1542.01">32-1542.01</cite>, § <cite path="§38-827.02">38-827.02</cite>, § <cite path="§38-1304">38-1304</cite>, § <cite path="§39-104">39-104</cite>, § <cite path="§44-403">44-403</cite>, § <cite path="§45-301">45-301</cite>, § <cite path="§47-463">47-463</cite>, § <cite path="§47-2853.09">47-2853.09</cite>, § <cite path="§47-3601">47-3601</cite>, § <cite path="§50-305">50-305</cite>, and § <cite path="§50-503">50-503</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-612.8.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-341.8.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Public Law 106-113 rewrote subpar. (c)(2)(F), which previously read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“Redevelopment Land Agency members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 per meeting, not to exceed $1,200 for each member per year.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-38">D.C. Law 13-38</cite>, in subpars. (c)(2)(A) and (c)(2)(G), substituted “$6,000” for “$3,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-298">D.C. Law 13-298</cite>, in subpar. (c)(2)(I), substituted “$6,000” for “$2,500”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite>, in subpars. (c)(2)(A) and (c)(2)(G), substituted “$12,000” for “$6,000”; in subpar. (c)(1)(E), substituted “Chairperson, and public and industry members” for “Chairperson”; added subpar. (c)(2)(K); and added subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-187">D.C. Law 15-187</cite>, in subpar. (c)(2)(I), substituted “$12,000” for “$6,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, in subpar. (H) of par. (2) of subsec. (c), substituted “3,000” for “1,800”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite>, in subsec. (c)(1)(E), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-91">D.C. Law 16-91</cite>, in subpar. (c)((2)(I), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-159">D.C. Law 16-159</cite> repealed subsec. (c)(2)(E) which had read as follows: “(E) Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of 25 per meeting.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-361">D.C. Law 17-361</cite>, in subsec. (c)(2)(I), substituted “$40” for “$25” and substituted “$15, 000” for “$12,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-363">D.C. Law 18-363</cite>, in subsec. (c)(2)(J), substituted “Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia” for “Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added (c)(2)(L).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-198">D.C. Law 20-198</cite> substituted “Police and Firefighters Retirement and Relief Board” for “Police and Firemen's Retirement and Relief Board” in (c)(2)(C).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-271">D.C. Law 20-271</cite> rewrote (c) and (d); and added (a-1), (c-1), (c-2), and (c-3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite>, in (c-2)(1), substituted “$ 4,000” for “$ 3,000,” substituted “$ 6,000” for “$ 5,000,” and added “provided, that all stipends shall be paid from non-District funds.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-74">D.C. Law 21-74</cite>, in (c-2)(2), substituted “Higher Education Licensure Commission” for “Education Licensure Commission” and substituted “$8,000” for “$4,000.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 801 of Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Temporary Act of 1995 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-253">D.C. Law 10-253</cite>, March 23, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 1652).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Real Property Tax Reassessment Temporary Act of 1996 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-207">D.C. Law 11-207</cite>, April 9, 1994, law notification  44 DCR 2402).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 101 of Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Temporary Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-59">D.C. Law 12-59</cite>, March 20, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 2094).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Real Property Tax Reassessment Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-125">D.C. Law 12-125</cite>, June 10, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 5883).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Real Property Tax Reassessment and Cold Weather Eviction Temporary Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-1">D.C. Law 13-1</cite>, May 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 5301).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 3 of the Higher Education Licensure Commission Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-51">D.C. Law 21-51</cite>, Jan. 9, 2016,  62 DCR 13983).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 101 of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-152, October 17, 1997,  44 DCR 6196), and § 101 of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-239, January 13, 1998,  45 DCR 508).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3 of the Real Property Tax Reassessment Congressional Adjournment Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-11, March 3, 1997,  44 DCR 1741), and see § 3 of the Real Property Tax Reassessment Second Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-244, January 13, 1998,  45 DCR 652).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3 of the Real Property Tax Reassessment Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-293, February 27, 1998,  45 DCR 1758).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3 of the Real Property Tax Reassessment and Cold Weather Eviction Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-18, February 17, 1999,  46 DCR 2354).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 302 of the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-110, July 28, 1999,  46 DCR 6320).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2303, 2402, and 2503 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1212 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1212 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  241 of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-481, Nov. 18, 2014, 61 DCR 12133, 20 STAT 4405).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 241 of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-7, Feb. 26, 2015,  62 DCR 2646, 21 STAT 807).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2202 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3 of the Higher Education Licensure Commission Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-158, Oct. 16, 2015,  62 DCR 13715).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3 of the Higher Education Licensure Commission Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-284, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1188).</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of title XXV of Law 14-190: Section 2501 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite> provided that title XXV of the act may be cited as the Boards and Commissions Compensation Study Amendment Act of 2002.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle T of title I of Law 15-205: Section 1211 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> provided that subtitle T of title I of the act may be cited as Historic Preservation Review Board Stipends Amendment Act of 2004.</text>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 12-60: Section 2002 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-60">D.C. Law 12-60</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 1997.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
