<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-614.13</num>
  <heading>Performance report.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Not later than January 1, 1997, and on January 15th in subsequent years, each agency of the District of Columbia government shall develop and submit to the Council of the District of Columbia a performance report covering all major programs of the agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The performance report shall indicate, for each performance measure stated in the previous fiscal year’s performance plan, the actual level of performance as compared to the stated goal or objective for performance. The performance report shall also state the name and position of the management employee or employees most directly responsible for the achievement of each performance measure, and the immediate supervisor or superior of the management employee or employees.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1413</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-16" type="History">as added May 16, 1995, D.C. Law 11-16, § 2(b), 42 DCR 1394</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 1802(b), 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-308.02">47-308.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-615.13.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “on January 15th in subsequent years” for “coincident with annual agency budget submissions in subsequent years”; and rewrote subsec. (b), which previously read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“The performance report shall, for each performance measure stated in the previous fiscal year’s performance plan, indicate the actual level of performance achieved as compared to the stated goal or objective for an acceptable level of performance and the goal or objective for a superior level of performance. The performance report shall also state the position and the immediate supervisor or superior of the District of Columbia management employee most directly responsible for the achievement of each performance measure, as well as the names of the nonmanagement personnel responsible for the accomplishment of the performance measure under management’s supervision.”</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 1802(b) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1802(b) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
