<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-617.15</num>
  <heading>Collective bargaining agreements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An agreement with a labor organization is subject to the approval of the Mayor or his or her designee; provided, that an agreement with a labor organization of employees of the Office of the Attorney General is subject to the approval of the Attorney General, and an agreement with a labor organization of employees of the District of Columbia Board of Education or the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia is subject to the approval of the respective Boards. An agreement shall be approved within 45 days from the date of its execution by the parties, if it conforms to applicable law. If disapproved because certain provisions are asserted to be contrary to law, the agreement shall either be returned to the parties for renegotiation of the offensive provisions or such provisions shall be deleted from the agreement. An agreement which has not been approved or disapproved within the prescribed period of 45 days shall go into effect on the 46th day and shall be binding on the parties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor and each appropriate personnel authority shall submit the collective bargaining agreement to the Council for its information.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1715, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-177" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-177, § 3(v), 33 DCR 7241</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-152" type="History">Aug. 1, 1996, D.C. Law 11-152, § 302(u), 43 DCR 2978</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 1033(f), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-618.15.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-347.15.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “provided, that an agreement with a labor organization of employees of the Office of the Attorney General is subject to the approval of the Attorney General, and an agreement with a labor organization of employees of the District of Columbia Board of Education or The Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia is subject to the approval of the respective Boards” for “or in the case of employees of the District of Columbia Board of Education or the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia, by the respective Boards” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1033(f) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 3 of Law 6-177: Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> provided that the provisions of § 3 are repealed on the 1st day following the 36-month period after February 24, 1987.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 4(b) of Law 6-177: Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-74">D.C. Law 8-74</cite>, effective March 15, 1990, provided that § 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> is repealed.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
