<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-612.03a</num>
  <heading>Universal leave program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall develop a universal leave system for Career and Excepted Service employees who were first employed by the District of Columbia government on or after October 1, 1987, excluding police officers, firefighters, and employees excluded from earning leave pursuant to § <cite path="§1-612.03">1-612.03</cite>(a)(1) through (a)(5).  The universal leave system shall include disability income protection for non work-related illness and injury.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 90 days of the effective date of this section, the Mayor shall submit the universal leave system to the Council for a 60-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays and days of Council recess.  If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed universal leave system by resolution within the 60-day review period, the proposed universal leave system shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The submission to the Council shall at a minimum include the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The rate at which universal leave shall be accrued;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of universal leave days that may be carried forward from one leave year to the next;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A provision for employees who are denied the opportunity to use their universal leave;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The percentage of income to be received under any disability insurance program and its tax status;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The definition of “disability” and a method for dispute resolution;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The stipulated waiting period before disability insurance income would commence;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The period of disability income protection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Transition provisions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The effective date of the universal leave system; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Fiscal impact.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1203a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-124" type="History">as added June 10, 1998, D.C. Law 12-124, § 101(o)(3), 45 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-613.3a.</annotation>
    <text type="Construction of Law">Construction of Law 12-124</text>
    <text type="Construction of Law">Section 301 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-124">D.C. Law 12-124</cite> provided that nothing in the act shall be construed as superseding the provisions of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, approved August 5, 1997 (Public Law 105-33; 111 Stat. 712), except that § <cite path="§47-395.04">47-395.04</cite>(b)(3) is expressly superseded. Further, nothing in the act shall be construed as superseding the provisions of § <cite path="§47-391.01">47-391.01</cite> et seq. or of § 164 of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1998, approved November 19, 1997 (Public Law 105-100; 111 Stat. 2160).</text>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of § 101(o)(3) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-124">D.C. Law 12-124</cite>: Section 401(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-124">D.C. Law 12-124</cite>, as amended by § 60 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-264">D.C. Law 12-264</cite>, provided that § 101(h), (l), (m), (n), (o)(2) through (5), (q), (r), (t), (u), (w), and (y) of the act shall apply as of October 21, 1998.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
