<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-616.52</num>
  <heading>Disciplinary grievances and appeals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An official reprimand or a suspension of less than 10 days may be contested as a grievance pursuant to § <cite path="§1-616.53">1-616.53</cite> except that the grievance must be filed within 10 days of receipt of the final decision on the reprimand or suspension.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An appeal from a removal, a reduction in grade, or suspension of 10 days or more may be made to the Office of Employee Appeals.  When, upon appeal, the action or decision by an agency is found to be unwarranted by the Office of Employee Appeals, the corrective or remedial action directed by the Office of Employee Appeals shall be taken in accordance with the provisions of subchapter VI of this chapter within 30 days of the OEA decision.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A grievance pursuant to subsection (a) of this section or an appeal pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall not serve to delay the effective date of a decision by the agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any system of grievance resolution or review of adverse actions negotiated between the District and a labor organization shall take precedence over the procedures of this subchapter for employees in a bargaining unit represented by a labor organization.  If an employee does not pay dues or a service fee to the labor organization, he or she shall pay all reasonable costs to the labor organization incurred in representing such employee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Matters covered under this subchapter that also fall within the coverage of a negotiated grievance procedure may, in the discretion of the aggrieved employee, be raised either pursuant to § <cite path="§1-606.03">1-606.03</cite>, or the negotiated grievance procedure, but not both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An employee shall be deemed to have exercised their option pursuant to subsection (e) of this section to raise a matter either under the applicable statutory procedures or under the negotiated grievance procedure at such time as the employee timely files an appeal under this section or timely files a grievance in writing in accordance with the provision of the negotiated grievance procedure applicable to the parties, whichever event occurs first.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§1652">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1652</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-124" type="History">as added June 10, 1998, D.C. Law 12-124, § 101(s), 45 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000, D.C. Law 13-91, § 108(b), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of § 101(s) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-124">D.C. Law 12-124</cite>: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§1-616.51">1-616.51</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite> validated previously made technical amendments in subsecs. (d) and (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-617.52.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-617.52.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-606.07">1-606.07</cite>, § <cite path="§1-616.53">1-616.53</cite>, and § <cite path="§1-616.54">1-616.54</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
