<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-623.14</num>
  <heading>Computation of pay.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this section:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The term “overtime pay” means pay for hours of service in excess of a statutory or other basic workweek or other basic unit of work time, as observed by the employing establishment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The term “year” means a period of 12 calendar months, or the equivalent thereof as specified by rules and regulations prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In computing monetary compensation for disability or death on the basis of monthly pay, that pay is determined under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The monthly pay at the time of injury is deemed one-twelfth of the average annual earnings of the employee at that time. When compensation is paid on a weekly basis, the weekly equivalent of the monthly pay is deemed one-fifty-second of the average annual earning. For so much of a period of total disability as does not exceed 90 calendar days from the date of the beginning of compensable disability, the compensation, at the discretion of the Mayor, may be computed on the basis of the actual daily wage of the employee at the time of injury, in which event he or she may receive compensation for the days he or she would have worked but for the injury.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Average annual earnings are determined as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the employee worked in the position in which he or she was employed at the time of his or her injury during substantially the whole year immediately preceding the injury and the employment was in a position for which an annual rate of pay:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Was fixed, the average annual earnings are the annual rate of pay; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Was not fixed, the average annual earnings are the product obtained by multiplying his or her daily wage for the particular employment or the average thereof, if the daily wage has fluctuated; by 300, if he or she was employed on the basis of a 6 day workweek; 280, if employed on the basis of a 5 1/2 day workweek; and 260, if employed on the basis of a 5 day workweek;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the employee did not work in the position in which he or she was employed at the time of his or her injury during substantially the whole year immediately preceding the injury, but the position was one which would have afforded employment for substantially a whole year, the average annual earnings are a sum equal to the average annual earnings of an employee of the same class working substantially the whole immediately preceding year in the same or similar employment with the District government, as determined under paragraph (1) of this subsection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If either of the foregoing methods of determining the average annual earnings cannot be applied reasonably and fairly, the average annual earnings are a sum that reasonably represents the annual earning capacity of the injured employee in the employment in which he or she was working at the time of the injury having regard to the previous earnings of the employee in District of Columbia government employment, and of other employees of the District of Columbia government in the same or most similar class working in the same or most similar employment in the same or neighboring location, other previous employment of the employee or other relevant factors. The average annual earnings may not be less than 150 times the average daily wage the employee earned in the employment during the days employed within 1 year immediately preceding his or her injury; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the employee served without pay or a nominal pay, paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of this subsection apply, as far as practicable, but the average earnings of the employee may not exceed the minimum rate of basic pay for GS-15 as provided in § 5332 of Title 5 of the United States Code or its equivalent as provided in subchapter XI of this chapter; provided that the average earnings of the employee may not exceed the minimum rate of basic pay for DS-12, Step 10 or its equivalent in the collective bargaining unit for those employees hired after December 31, 1979, who make a claim for compensation for disability after December 29, 1994. If the average annual earnings cannot be determined reasonably and fairly in the manner otherwise provided by this section, the average annual earnings shall be determined at the reasonable value of the service performed but not in excess of $3,600 a year.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The value of subsistence and quarters, and of any other form of remuneration in kind for services if its value can be estimated in money and premium pay under § 5545(c)(1) of Title 5 of the United States Code, are included as part of the pay, but account is not taken of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Overtime pay;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Additional pay or allowance authorized outside the District of Columbia government because of differential in cost of living or other special circumstances; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Bonus or premium pay for extraordinary service including bonus or pay for particularly hazardous service.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 2314, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 810(f), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-623.15">1-623.15</cite> and § <cite path="§1-623.33">1-623.33</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-624.14.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-353.14.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
