<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-621.09f</num>
  <heading>Annual report; prohibition on reprogramming.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By April 1st of each year, the Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall publish an annual report regarding the Fund.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The annual report published pursuant to this subsection shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Along with the assumptions for the Fund used by the enrolled actuary pursuant to §  1-621.09b, a side-by-side comparison with the assumptions currently used by the District of Columbia Retirement Board;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A side-by-side comparison of the Fund’s asset allocation and the District of Columbia Retirement Board’s asset allocation for the prior fiscal year;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The most recent recommendations transmitted by the Other Post- Employment Benefits Fund Advisory Committee pursuant to §  1-621.53; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A description of actions taken by the Chief Financial Officer in response to the recommendations described in paragraph (2)(C) of this subsection, including an explanation of why no action was taken on a recommendation, if applicable.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding §  47-363(b)-(d), upon receipt of a reprogramming request of monies in the Fund, the Chairman of the Council shall cause a notice of the request to be published in the District of Columbia Register, together with a statement that the request shall be deemed disapproved 10 days from the date of publication in the District of Columbia Register, unless a proposed approval resolution is filed before that time by a Councilmember, and that if a proposed approval resolution is filed, the request shall be deemed disapproved 30 days (excluding weekends, holidays, and days of Council recess) from the date of the receipt of the reprogramming request, unless before the end of the 30-day review period the Council adopts a resolution of disapproval or approval.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The publication of a notice of a reprogramming request shall satisfy the public notice requirements of this section and the rules of the Council and no further notice shall be necessary for the Council to adopt a resolution affecting the request.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Council shall consider the reprogramming request according to its rules. No reprogramming request may be submitted to the Chairman of the Council under this subsection during such time as the Council is on recess, according to its rules, nor shall any time period provided in this subsection or in the Council’s rules with respect to the request continue to run during such time as the Council is on recess.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If no proposed approval resolution of a reprogramming request is filed with the Secretary to the Council (“Secretary”) within 10 days of the publication of the request from the Mayor in the District of Columbia Register, the request shall be deemed disapproved.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If a proposed approval resolution is filed with the Secretary to the Council within 10 days of publication of the reprogramming request from the Mayor in the District of Columbia Register, the Council may approve or disapprove the reprogramming request by resolution within 30 days (excluding weekends, holidays, and days of Council recess) of the receipt of the request from the Mayor. If the Council neither affirmatively approves or disapproves the request within 30 days (excluding weekends, holidays, and days of Council recess) of the receipt of the request, the request shall be deemed disapproved.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>At any time before final action by the Council on a reprogramming request, including deemed disapproval, the Mayor may withdraw the reprogramming request.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§2109f">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, §  2109f</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-151" type="History">as added Dec. 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-151, § 2(c), 61 DCR 8893</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
