<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-623.42</num>
  <heading>Employees’ Compensation Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “administrative expenses” means, except as provided by subsection (b) of this section, any cost of administration or operation, whether executive, clerical, or otherwise, discretionary or non- discretionary, that is not a payment directed to medical care, vocational rehabilitation, or employee compensation and benefits; provided, that the term “administrative expenses” shall not include expenses for legal service performed by or for the Mayor under §§ <cite path="§1-623.31">1-623.31</cite> and <cite path="§1-623.32">1-623.32</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>There is established in the District of Columbia government the Employees’ Compensation Fund (“Fund”), which shall consists of sums that the Council of the District of Columbia government or Congress, from time to time, may appropriate for or transfer to it and amounts that otherwise accrue to it under this chapter  or other statute. The Fund is available without time limit for the payment of compensation and other benefits and expenses, except administrative expenses, authorized by this chapter  or any extension or application thereof, except as otherwise provided by this subchapter or other statute.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, for fiscal year 2009 only, an amount not to exceed $904,000 may be expended for the administrative expenses of the Fund.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The costs and expenses of the representation of the Mayor or his or her designee by the Corporation Counsel in proceedings under §§ <cite path="§1-623.24">1-623.24</cite> and <cite path="§1-623.28">1-623.28</cite> shall be paid out of the Employees’ Compensation Fund established by this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 2342, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175" type="History">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 2102(h), 45 DCR 7193</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 5(e), 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-219" type="History">Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 1013, 55 DCR 7598</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-624.42.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-353.42.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> rewrote subsec. (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Disability Compensation Administrative Financing Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-239">D.C. Law 12-239</cite>, April 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 4152).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Employees' Compensation Fund Clarification TemporaryAmendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-86">D.C. Law 21-86</cite>, Mar. 9, 2016,  63 DCR 790).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 1702(h) of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-401, July 13, 1998,  45 DCR 4794), and § 1702(h) of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-564, January 12, 1999,  46 DCR 669).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Disability Compensation Administrative Financing Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-445, September 8, 1998,  45 DCR 6663), and § 2 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Disability Compensation Administrative Financing Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-572, January 12, 1999,  46 DCR 903).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Employees' Compensation Fund Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-225, Dec. 17, 2015,  62 DCR 16245).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1012 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> provided that subtitle F of title I of the act may be cited as the “Employee Compensation Fund Allowance and Clarification Amendment Act of 2008”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
