<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-626.04</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purpose of §§ <cite path="§1-626.05">1-626.05</cite> through <cite path="§1-626.12">1-626.12</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>“Creditable service” means the period of employment to be recognized for purposes of eligibility for retirement benefits, which shall be set forth in rules promulgated by the Mayor pursuant to § <cite path="§1-626.08">1-626.08</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For purposes of vesting pursuant to § <cite path="§1-626.10">1-626.10</cite>(b), creditable service for employees whose participation in the District Defined Contribution Plan ceases as a result of the implementation of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, approved August 5, 1997 (Pub.L. No. 105-33), shall also include continuous service performed by nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia courts after September 30, 1997, or service performed for a successor employer that provides the services previously performed by the District government toward the vesting requirement of the Defined Contribution Plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Detention officer” means an employee who is not covered by the Police and Fire Retirement System, whose duties are primarily the investigation, apprehension, or detention of individuals suspected or convicted of offenses against, or violation of, the laws of the United States or the District and whose duties may require frequent contact, supervision, inspection, training, employment, care, transportation, or rehabilitation of individuals in detention. The term “detention officer” includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Employees engaged in the activities listed above who are transferred to a supervisory or administrative position;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Employees of the District of Columbia Department of Corrections, its industries, and utilities who are engaged in the activities listed above;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Employees of the Department of Human Services who are engaged in the activities listed above; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Members of the Board of Parole, parole officers, and probation officers who are engaged in the activities listed above.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Employee” means an individual first employed by the government of the District after September 30, 1987, who would have been covered by the Civil Service Retirement System pursuant to 5 U.S.C. § 8331 had the employee been first employed prior to October 1, 1987.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Internal Revenue Code” means the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 22, 1986 (100 Stat. 2085; 26 U.S.C. § 1 et seq.).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>“Fiduciary” means, except as otherwise provided in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, any individual who, with respect to the District retirement benefits program:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Exercises any discretionary authority or discretionary control respecting management of the Section 401(a) Trust established by § <cite path="§1-626.11">1-626.11</cite> or exercises any discretionary authority or discretionary control respecting management of the Trust’s assets;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Renders investment advice for a fee or other compensation, direct or indirect, with respect to any monies or other property of the Trust, or has any authority or responsibility to do so; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Has any discretionary authority or discretionary responsibility in the administration of the Trust.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>If any money or other property of the Trust is invested in securities issued by an investment company registered under An Act to provide for the registration and regulation of investment companies and investment advisers, and for other purposes (15 U.S.C. § 80a-1 et seq.), that investment shall not by itself cause the investment company or the investment company’s adviser or principal underwriter to be deemed a fiduciary or a party in interest as those terms are defined in this chapter. Nothing contained in this subparagraph shall limit the duties imposed on that investment company, investment adviser, or principal underwriter by any other law.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The term “party in interest” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any person having fiduciary responsibilities to the Trust;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Any person providing services to the Trust;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The government of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>An employee organization recognized as an exclusive representative of any participants in the Trust for purposes of collective bargaining pursuant to § <cite path="§1-617.10">1-617.10</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>A spouse or domestic partner, ancestor, lineal descendant, or spouse or domestic partner of a lineal descendant of any individual described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of this paragraph.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The term “Trust” shall mean the Section 401(a) Trust established by § <cite path="§1-626.11">1-626.11</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§2604">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 2604</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-27" type="History">as added Oct. 1, 1987, D.C. Law 7-27, § 2(g), 34 DCR 5079</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-231" type="History">May 10, 1989, D.C. Law 7-231, § 3(3), 36 DCR 492</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-97" type="History">Mar. 24, 1990, D.C. Law 8-97, § 3(e), 37 DCR 1046</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-68" type="History">Feb. 5, 1994, D.C. Law 10-68, § 6, 40 DCR 6311</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-92" type="History">Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-92, § 2, 45 DCR 1314</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 3(k), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Charter school employees, retirement benefits, determination of period of creditable service, see §§ <cite path="§38-1702.08">38-1702.08</cite> and <cite path="§38-1802.07">38-1802.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-1802.07">38-1802.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-627.4.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite>, in par. (6)(E), substituted “spouse or domestic partner” for “spouse”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Defined Contribution Transition Vesting Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-57">D.C. Law 12-57</cite>, March 18, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 1894).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Defined Contribution Transition Vesting Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-154, September 29, 1997,  44 DCR 5793), and see § 2 of the Defined Contribution Transition Vesting Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-215, December 5, 1997,  44 DCR 7618).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-57">D.C. Law 12-57</cite>, see § 3 of the Defined Contribution Transition Vesting Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-215, December 5, 1997,  44 DCR 7618).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
