<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-629.05</num>
  <heading>Authority to collect infraction fines from responsible District employees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a notice of infraction is issued pursuant to § <cite path="§50-2303.03">50-2303.03</cite> or § <cite path="§50-2209.02">50-2209.02</cite> for an infraction committed by a vehicle owned or leased by the District of Columbia government, the responsible individual shall be required to pay any fine or fee imposed as a result of that notice of infraction.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The responsible individual may challenge any notice of infraction issued for a moving violation as provided in subchapter II of Chapter 23 of Title 50 (§ <cite path="§50-2302.01">50-2302.01</cite> et seq.), or any notice of infraction issued for a parking, standing, or stopping infraction as provided in subchapter III of Chapter 23 of Title 50 (§ <cite path="§50-2303.01">50-2303.01</cite> et seq.).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a responsible individual fails to pay a fine or fee imposed, the period for challenging the issuance of the notice of infraction has expired, and there is no final order dismissing the charges that led to the issuance of the notice of infraction, the Mayor may collect the amount owed, as provided for in § <cite path="§1-629.04">1-629.04</cite>, or by any other means authorized by law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “responsible individual” means the District government employee, contractor, or volunteer who had registered, or signed, to use the vehicle that was the subject of the notice of infraction, or who had been assigned to drive the vehicle that was the subject of the notice of infraction, at the time when the notice of infraction was issued.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§2906">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 2906</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">as added Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 1055, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see § 1055 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</law-cite> added this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
