<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-621.17</num>
  <heading>Post-employment benefits.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An annuitant may be eligible for the post-employment health benefits as set forth in § <cite path="§1-621.05">1-621.05</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To be eligible for post-employment health benefits, the annuitant must:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Retire with at least:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>10 years of creditable District service if the annuitant retired under the District Retirement Benefit Program, the Teachers’ Retirement System, the Judges’ Retirement System, or the Teachers’ Insurance and Annuity Association programs; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>10 years of creditable District service if the annuitant retired under the Police and Fire Retirement System and the annuitant was hired on or after November 10, 1996; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>5 years of creditable District service if the annuitant retired under the Police and Fire Retirement System and the annuitant was hired before November 10, 1996;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be enrolled in a health benefit plan under § <cite path="§1-621.05">1-621.05</cite> at the time of retirement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Have been continuously enrolled in a health benefit plan under § <cite path="§1-621.05">1-621.05</cite> for a period of at least 5 years preceding the annuitant’s retirement date; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Remain continuously covered under a health benefit plan under § <cite path="§1-621.05">1-621.05</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>In addition to annuitants eligible under this section for the post-employment health benefits as set forth in § <cite path="§1-621.05">1-621.05</cite>, individuals described in § <cite path="§1-621.09">1-621.09</cite>(k) shall also be eligible for such benefits and those individuals shall be considered annuitants for the purposes of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If an annuitant’s coverage in a health benefit plan under § <cite path="§1-621.05">1-621.05</cite> ends, for any reason, the annuitant shall cease to be eligible for post-employment health benefits and shall not re-enroll, as an annuitant, in a health benefit plan under § <cite path="§1-621.05">1-621.05</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Upon the death of an annuitant who is enrolled in a health benefit plan under § <cite path="§1-621.05">1-621.05</cite> with family coverage, the annuitant’s surviving spouse and dependent children who are covered under the health benefit plan at the time of death may continue enrollment in a health benefit plan under § <cite path="§1-621.05">1-621.05</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§2117">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 2117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">as added Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 1201(d), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 1092(c), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">National Capital Revitalization Corporation, health, life and retirement benefit plans for officers and employees, see § <cite path="§2-1219.05">2-1219.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> rewrote subsec. (b)(1); and added subsec. (b-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1201(d) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1201(d) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 1093 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided: “Sec. 1093. Applicability. (a) Section 1092(a) and (c) shall apply as of October 1, 2011. (b) This subtitle shall apply subject to its inclusion in an approved budget and financial plan.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
