<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-623.18</num>
  <heading>Continuation of pay; election to use annual or sick leave.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia government shall authorize the continuation of pay of an employee, as defined in paragraph (1) of § <cite path="§1-623.01">1-623.01</cite>, who has filed a claim for a period of wage loss due to a traumatic injury with his or her immediate superior on a form approved by the Mayor within the time specified in paragraph (2) of subsection (a) of § <cite path="§1-623.22">1-623.22</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Continuation of pay under this subchapter shall be furnished:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Unless controverted under rules and regulations of the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a period not to exceed 45 days for employees hired before January 1, 1980, or for employees who have a claim for compensation for disability pending on December 29, 1994, provided that the period of continuation of pay shall not exceed 21 days for all other employees, beginning 2 years after December 29, 1994; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Under accounting procedures and such other rules and regulations as the Mayor may require.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a claim under subsection (a) of this section is denied by the Mayor, payments under this section, at the option of the employee, shall be charged to sick or annual leave or shall be deemed overpayments of pay within the meaning of § 5584 of Title 5 of the United States Code or equivalent provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Payments under this section shall not be considered compensation as defined by paragraph (12) of § <cite path="§1-623.01">1-623.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 2318, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-81" type="History">Aug. 7, 1980, D.C. Law 3-81, § 2(w), 27 DCR 2632</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 810(g), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-623.17">1-623.17</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-624.18.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-353.18.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
