<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-623.34</num>
  <heading>Funeral expenses; transportation of body.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If death results from an injury sustained in the performance of duty, the District of Columbia government shall pay, to the personal representative of the deceased or otherwise, funeral and burial expenses not to exceed $5,000, at the discretion of the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The body of an employee whose home was in the United States, at the discretion of the Mayor, may be embalmed and transported in a hermetically sealed casket to his or her home or last place of residence at the expense of the Employees’ Compensation Fund if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The employee dies from:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The injury while away from his or her home or official station or outside the United States; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Other causes while away from his or her home or official station for the purposes of receiving medical or other services, appliances, supplies, or examination under this subchapter; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The relatives of the employee request the return of the body.</text>
    </para>
    <aftertext>If the relatives do not request the return of the body of the employee, the Mayor may provide for its disposition and incur and pay from the Employees’ Compensation Fund the necessary and reasonable transportation, funeral and burial expenses.</aftertext>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 2334, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-198">Mar. 6, 1991, D.C. Law 8-198, § 3(f), 37 DCR 6890</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-623.09">1-623.09</cite> and § <cite path="§1-623.33">1-623.33</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-624.34.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 1-353.34.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Mayor authorized to issue rules: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§1-623.01">1-623.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
