<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-636.03</num>
  <heading>Implementation Task Force.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is hereby established a Task Force on the Implementation of the Merit Personnel Act (hereinafter referred to in this section as the “Task Force”) which shall be composed of the following members: (1) Two members appointed by the Mayor; (2) 2 members appointed by the Greater Washington Central Labor Council; (3) 2 members appointed by the Committee on Government Operations of the Council; and (4) 1 member appointed by the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia. The members shall elect 1 of their members as Chairperson.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each member of the Task Force shall receive payment of $100 for each 8 hours actually worked per diem or $12.50 per hour, whichever provides less, while in the service of the Task Force. The members shall also receive reimbursement for the payment of actual expenses incurred in the service of the Task Force.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall study and review the implementation of this chapter giving special attention to the implementation timetable set forth in this subchapter. The Task Force shall advise the Mayor and the Council of the District of Columbia within 90 days of the date of their appointment under subsection (d) of this section as to the need for any adjustments in the timetables set forth in this subchapter and the Council may, by act, modify such timetables. The Task Force may engage in other activities as provided in this subsection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Members of the Task Force shall be appointed from constituencies as provided in subsection (a) of this section within 30 days of March 3, 1979. Any vacancies which occur in the membership of the Task Force shall be replaced from the same constituency represented by the member creating a vacancy. No person otherwise in the employ of the District government appointed to the Task Force may receive the per diem or hourly payment provided in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall be disbanded no later than December 1, 1979.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§3603">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 3603, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-366.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-637.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan, “Retirement Reform Act” defined, see § <cite path="§1-901.02">1-901.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Police and fire departments, disability retirement, use of medical resources and expertise by Boards, see § <cite path="§5-710">5-710</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District of Columbia judges, retirement, payment of annuity to survivors, see § <cite path="§11-1569">11-1569</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District of Columbia judges, retirement, “lump-sum credit for retirement” defined, see § <cite path="§11-1561">11-1561</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District of Columbia judges, retirement, computation of retirement salary, see § <cite path="§11-1564">11-1564</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Administration, procurement, authority of Retirement Board unaffected, see § <cite path="§2-352.01">2-352.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
