<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-631.05</num>
  <heading>Employee access to official personnel record.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The official personnel record of a District employee shall be disclosed to the employee or any representative of his or her choice. All such disclosure shall be made in the presence of a representative of the agency having custody of the records.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The following information which may be in an official personnel record shall not be disclosed to any employee:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Information which has been received on a confidential basis from a person under an agreement that the identity of the source of the information will not be disclosed: Provided, however, that such information may be disclosed if all information identifying the source of the information is deleted in such a manner to positively preclude identity of the source;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Medical information, which, in the judgment of the employee’s physician would be injurious to the health of the employee, if disclosed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Criminal investigative reports;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Suitability inquiries and confidential questionnaires undertaken in accordance with rights afforded under this chapter; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Test and examination materials which may continue to be used for selection and promotion purposes: Provided, however, that the description of test and general results thereof shall be disclosed.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each employee shall have the right to present information immediately germane to any information contained in his or her official personnel record and seek to have irrelevant, immaterial, or untimely information removed from the record.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this subchapter, information other than a record of official personnel action is untimely if it concerns an event more than 3 years in the past upon which an action adverse to an employee may be based. Immaterial, irrelevant, or untimely information shall be removed from the official record upon the finding by the agency head that the information is of such a nature. Prior to the removal of any information in the file, the employer shall notify the employee and give him or her an opportunity to be heard.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 3105, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-632.5.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-361.5.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
