<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-714</num>
  <heading>District of Columbia Judges’ Retirement Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a fund to be known as the District of Columbia Judges’ Retirement Fund into which shall be deposited the following (except as provided in § <cite path="§11-1570">11-1570</cite>), which shall constitute the assets of the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any amount deposited pursuant to subchapter III of Chapter 15 of Title 11;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any asset transferred to such Fund under subsection (b) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any amount appropriated for such Fund under subchapter III of this chapter; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any return on investment of the assets of such Fund.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any asset held in the District of Columbia Judicial Retirement and Survivors Annuity Fund may be transferred to the District of Columbia Judges’ Retirement Fund established by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or the amendments made by this chapter, upon the date the assets of the Retirement Fund described in subtitle A of title XI of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 [Pub. L. 105-33] are transferred, the assets of the District of Columbia Judges’ Retirement Fund established under subsection (a) shall be transferred to the District of Columbia Judicial Retirement and Survivors Annuity Fund under § <cite path="§11-1570">11-1570</cite>, and no amounts shall be deposited into the District of Columbia Judges’ Retirement Fund after the date on which the assets are so transferred.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In accordance with the direction of the Secretary, the District of Columbia Judges’ Retirement Fund established under subsection (a) shall be continued at the Board and used for the purposes provided in this chapter until such time as all amounts in such Fund have been expended or transferred to the District of Columbia Judicial Retirement and Survivors Annuity Fund pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection. Thereafter any payments of retirement pay, annuities, refunds, and allowances for judicial personnel of the District of Columbia shall be paid from the District of Columbia Judicial Retirement and Survivors Annuity Fund in accordance with subchapter III of Chapter 15 of Title 11.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 96-122" type="History">Nov. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 866, Pub. L. 96-122, § 124(a), (c)</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 758, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11252(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 105-274" type="History">Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2419, Pub. L. 105-274, § 2(c)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 105-277" type="History">Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681-536, Pub. L. 105-277,§ 804(c)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District of Columbia judges, retirement, computation of retirement salary, see § <cite path="§11-1564">11-1564</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Judges’ Retirement Fund, allocation of retirement benefits, see § <cite path="§1-611.03">1-611.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Judges’ Retirement Fund, transition from District of Columbia administration, see § <cite path="§1-821.01">1-821.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Judicial Retirement and Survivors Annuity Fund, transfer of assets, see § <cite path="§1-807.03">1-807.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan, “judges’ retirement fund” and “retirement program” defined, see § <cite path="§1-901.02">1-901.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-611.03">1-611.03</cite>, § <cite path="§1-702">1-702</cite>, § <cite path="§1-752">1-752</cite>, § <cite path="§1-807.03">1-807.03</cite>, § <cite path="§1-821.01">1-821.01</cite>, § <cite path="§1-901.02">1-901.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§11-1564">11-1564</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-714.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1814.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Annuity Offset Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-123, August 1, 1997,  44 DCR 4652), and see § 2 of the Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Annuity Offset Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-183, October 30, 1997,  44 DCR 6958).</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Subtitle A of title XI of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, referred to in (c)(1), is subtitle A of title XI of Pub. L. 105-33, codified at Chapter 8 of Title 1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Federal contribution to retirement funds: Public Law 104-194, 110 Stat. 2356, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1997, provided for the federal contribution to the Police Officers’ and Fire Fighters’, Teachers’, and Judges’ Retirement Funds, as authorized by the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Stat. 866; Public Law 96-122), $52,070,000.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
