<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-744</num>
  <heading>Prohibition against certain persons holding certain positions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No person who has been convicted of, or has been imprisoned as a result of his conviction of, robbery, bribery, extortion, embezzlement, fraud, grand larceny, burglary, arson, a felony violation of federal or state law involving substances defined in § 102(6) of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (21 U.S.C. § 802(6)), murder, rape, kidnapping, perjury, assault with intent to kill, any crime described in § 9(a)(1) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (15 U.S.C. § 80a-9(a)(1)), a violation of any provision of this chapter, a violation of § 302 of the Labor-Management Relations Act, 1947 (29 U.S.C. § 186), a violation of Chapter 63 of Title 18, United States Code, a violation of § 874, 1027, 1503, 1505, 1506, 1510, 1951, or 1954 of Title 18, United States Code, a violation of the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (29 U.S.C. § 401), or conspiracy to commit any such crime or attempt to commit any such crime, or a crime in which any of the foregoing crimes is an element, shall serve or be permitted to serve: (1) As a fiduciary, investment counsel, agent, or employee of any Fund established by this chapter; or (2) as a consultant to any Fund established by this chapter; during or for 5 years after such conviction or after the end of such imprisonment, whichever is the later, unless prior to the end of such 5-year period, in the case of a person so convicted or imprisoned, his citizenship rights, having been revoked as a result of such conviction, have been fully restored, or the Board of Parole of the United States Department of Justice determines that such person’s service in any capacity referred to in clause (1) or (2) of this subsection would not be contrary to the purposes of this chapter. Prior to making any such determination the Board of Parole shall hold an administrative hearing and shall give notice of such proceeding by certified mail to the state, county, and federal prosecuting officials in the jurisdiction or jurisdictions in which such person was convicted. The Board of Parole’s determination in any such proceeding shall be final. No person shall knowingly permit any other person to serve in any capacity referred to in clause (1) or (2) of this subsection in violation of this subsection. Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this subsection, no corporation or partnership will be precluded from acting as an administrator, fiduciary, officer, trustee, custodian, counsel, agent, or employee, of any Fund established by this chapter, or as a consultant to any Fund established by this chapter, without a notice, hearing, and determination by such Board of Parole that such service would be inconsistent with the intention of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Whoever willfully violates this section shall be fined not more than $10,000, or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person shall be deemed to have been “convicted” and to be under the disability of “conviction” from the date of entry of the judgment of the trial court or the date of the final sustaining of such judgment on appeal, whichever is the later event.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The term “consultant” means any person who, for compensation, advises or represents a Fund or who provides other assistance to such Fund concerning the operation of such Fund.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A period of parole shall not be considered as part of a period of imprisonment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 96-122" type="History">Nov. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 866, Pub. L. 96-122, § 184</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-711">1-711</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-744.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1844.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
