<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-809.01</num>
  <heading>Interim administration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Administration of benefits until appointment of trustee. —</heading>
    <text>Notwithstanding subchapter II of this chapter, after the enactment of this chapter the District Government shall continue to discharge its duties and responsibilities under the District Retirement Program and the District Retirement Fund (as such duties and responsibilities are modified by this chapter), including the responsibility for Federal benefit payments, until such time as the Secretary notifies the District Government that the Secretary has directed the Trustee to carry out the duties and responsibilities required under the contract.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Reimbursement. —</heading>
    <text>The Secretary or the Trustee shall, at such times during or after the period of interim administration described in subsection (a) of this section as are deemed appropriate by the Secretary or the Trustee, reimburse the District Government for any administrative expenses incurred by the District Government in carrying out subsection (a) of this section:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the Secretary or the Trustee finds such expenses to be reasonable and necessary; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To the extent that the District Government is not reimbursed for such expenses from other sources.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Making District Retirement Fund whole. —</heading>
    <text>The District Government shall reimburse the District Retirement Fund for any benefits paid inconsistent with this chapter from the District Retirement Fund between the freeze date and such time as the Secretary notifies the District government that the Secretary has directed the Trustee to carry out the duties and responsibilities required under the contract.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 725, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11041</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 105-277">Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681-531, Pub. L. 105-277, § 801(e)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91">Apr. 12, 2000, D.C. Law 13-91,§ 112, 47 DCR 520</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 108-489">Dec. 23, 2004, 118 Stat. 3969, Pub. L. 108-489, § 2(d)</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Retirement program management, District of Columbia Retirement Board, see § <cite path="§1-711">1-711</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-711">1-711</cite>, § <cite path="§1-807.02">1-807.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§1-821.01">1-821.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-765.1.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite> validated a previously made technical amendment in subsec. (b).</annotation>
      <annotation>Pub. L. 108-489, in subsec. (b), deleted “from Trust Fund” from the heading.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
