<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-805.04</num>
  <heading>Federal information sharing for verification of benefit determinations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>In general. —</heading>
    <text>Except with respect to taxpayer returns and return information subject to § 6103 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the Secretary may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Secure directly from any department or agency of the United States information necessary to enable the Secretary to verify or confirm benefit determinations under this chapter; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By regulation authorize the Trustee to review such information for purposes of administering this chapter and the contract.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Omitted.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Confidentiality. —</heading>
    <text>The Secretary may issue regulations governing the confidentiality of the information obtained pursuant to subsection (a) of this section and the provisions of law amended by § 11024(b) of the District of Columbia Retirement Protection Act of 1997.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Pub. L. 105-33" path="§11024">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 721, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11024</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Amendments to Internal Revenue Code: For amendments to the Internal Revenue Code related to District of Columbia Retirement Programs, see § 11024(b) of Title XI of Pub. L. 105-33, 111 Stat. 721, the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-763.4.</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">Section 11024(b) of the District of Columbia Retirement Protection Act of 1997, referred to in (c), is § 11024(b) of subtitle A of Title XI of Pub. L. 105-33, 111 Stat. 715.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">Section 6103 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in the introductory paragraph of (a), is  26 U.S.C § 6103.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
