<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-907.05</num>
  <heading>Information about retirement programs.</heading>
  <text>Upon a request of the Retirement Board, he Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer, the Chairman of the District of Columbia Public Charter School Board, the President of the Board of Education, or their successors, shall furnish to the Retirement Board information with respect to retirement programs and post employment benefit programs to which this chapter applies as the Retirement Board considers necessary to enable it to carry out its responsibilities under this chapter and to enable the enrolled actuary engaged pursuant to § <cite path="§1-907.03">1-907.03</cite>(a) to carry out the responsibilities of the enrolled actuary under this chapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-152" type="History">Sept. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-152, § 135, 45 DCR 4045</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1013(b), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-784.5.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> substituted “the Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer, the Chairman of the District of Columbia Public Charter School Board, the President of the Board of Education, or their successors, shall furnish to the Retirement Board information with respect to retirement programs and post employment benefit programs” for “the Mayor shall furnish to the Retirement Board information with respect to retirement programs”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 12-152: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§1-901.01">1-901.01</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">For conditional applicability of subtitle B of Title I of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, see notes under § <cite path="§1-911.04a">1-911.04a</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
