<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-911.04a</num>
  <heading>Continuative administration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding § <cite path="§1-711">1-711</cite>(a), the Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer, the District of Columbia Public Charter School Board, and the Board of Education, or their successors, shall continue to discharge their respective duties under the retirement programs until the Retirement Board notifies the Mayor and the Council of the District of Columbia in writing that the Retirement Board is prepared to carry out the duties and responsibilities established under this chapter; provided, that the notification shall occur no later than 12 months after December 7, 2004.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer, the District of Columbia Public Charter School Board, and the President of the Board of Education, or their successors, shall cooperate with the Retirement Board in developing and periodically updating operating procedures for all District personnel offices providing retirement and survivor benefit services to participants and, if applicable, to individuals eligible for benefits under post employment benefit programs.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-152" type="History">Sept. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-152, § 204a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">as added Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1013(c), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91" type="History">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, § 125(b)(2), 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-91">D.C. Law 16-91</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Conditional applicability of subtitle B of Title I of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>: Section 1015 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> provided:</text>
      <text>“This subtitle shall not apply until the enactment by Congress of section 139 of the fiscal year 2005 Budget Request Act, passed on 1st reading on May 14, 2004 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-765) or until enactment of other Congressional legislation that authorizes the Council of the District of Columbia to transfer authority of the administration of the retirement plans of the District of Columbia, whichever occurs first.”</text>
      <text>Section 4(a) of Pub. L. 108-489 provided: “(a) In general. — Section 424(c)(21) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act ( sec. 1-204.24c(21), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking ‘systems’ and inserting the following: ‘systems (other than the retirement system for police officers, fire fighters, and teachers)’.”</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
