<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1001.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term “District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term “qualified elector” means a person who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is at least 17 years of age and who will be 18 years of age on or before the next general election;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is a citizen of the United States;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Has maintained a residence in the District for at least 30 days preceding the next election and does not claim voting residence or right to vote in any state or territory;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Is not incarcerated for a crime that is a felony in the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Has not been found by a court of law to be legally incompetent to vote.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “Board” means the District of Columbia Board of Elections provided for by § <cite root="1-1001.03">1-1001.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term “ward” means an election ward established by the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The term “State Board of Education” means the State Board of Education established by § <cite root="38-2651">38-2651</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The term “Delegate” means the Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The term “felony” includes any crime committed in the District of Columbia referred to in §§ <cite root="1-1001.14">1-1001.14</cite>, <cite root="1-1162.32">1-1162.32</cite>, and <cite root="1-1163.35">1-1163.35</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>The term “Council” or “Council of the District of Columbia” means the Council of the District of Columbia established pursuant to the District of Columbia Home Rule Act [§ 1-201.01 et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>The term “Mayor” means the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia established pursuant to the District of Columbia Home Rule Act [§ 1-202.01 et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9A)</num>
    <text>The term “Attorney General” or “Attorney General for the District of Columbia” means the Attorney General for the District of Columbia provided for by part D-i of subchapter I of Chapter 3 [§ <cite root="1-301.81">1-301.81</cite> et seq.] and § <cite root="1-204.35">1-204.35</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>The term “initiative” means the process by which the electors of the District of Columbia may propose laws (except laws appropriating funds) and present such proposed laws directly to the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia for their approval or disapproval.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>The term “referendum” means the process by which the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia may suspend acts, or some part or parts of acts, of the Council of the District of Columbia (except emergency acts, acts levying taxes, or acts appropriating funds for the general operating budget) until such acts or part or parts of acts have been presented to the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia for their approval or rejection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>The term “recall” means the process by which the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia may call for the holding of an election to remove or retain an elected official of the District of Columbia (except the Delegate to Congress for the District of Columbia) prior to the expiration of his or her term.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>The term “elected official” means the Mayor, the Chairman and members of the Council, the Attorney General, members of the State Board of Education, the Delegate to Congress for the District of Columbia, United States Senator and Representative, and advisory neighborhood commissioners of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>The term “printed” shall include any document produced by letterpress, offset press, photo reproduction, multilith, or other mass reproduction means.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>The term “proposer” means one or more of the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia, including any entity, the primary purpose of which is the success or defeat of a political party or principle, or any question submitted to vote at a public election by means of an initiative, referendum or recall as authorized in amendments numbered 1 and 2 to Title IV of the Home Rule Act (§§ 1-204.101 to 1-204.115). Such entities shall be treated as a political committee as defined in § 1-1161.01(44) for purposes of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The term “residence,” for purposes of voting, means the principal or primary home or place of abode of a person. Principal or primary home or place of abode is that home or place in which the person’s habitation is fixed and to which a person, whenever he or she is absent, has the present intention of returning after a departure or absence therefrom, regardless of the duration of the absence.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>In determining what is a principal or primary place of abode of a person the following circumstances relating to the person may be taken into account:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Business pursuits;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Employment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Income sources;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>Residence for income or other tax purposes;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>Residence of parents, spouse, and children;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(vi)</num>
        <text>Leaseholds;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(vii)</num>
        <text>Situs of personal and real property; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(viii)</num>
        <text>Motor vehicle registration.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A qualified elector who has left his or her home and gone into another state or territory for a temporary purpose only shall not be considered to have lost his or her residence in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>If a qualified elector moves to another state or territory with the intention of making it his or her permanent home, he or she shall notify the Board, in writing, and shall be considered to have lost residence in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>No person shall be deemed to have gained or lost a residence by reason of absence while employed in the service of the District or the United States governments, while a student at any institution of learning, while kept at any institution at public expense, or while absent from the District with the intent to have the District remain his or her residence. If a person is absent from the District, but intends to maintain residence in the District for voting purposes, he or she shall not register to vote in any other state or territory during his or her absence.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>The term “voter registration agency” means an office designated under § <cite root="1-1001.07">1-1001.07</cite>(d)(1) and the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to perform voter registration activities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(18)</num>
    <text>The term “application distribution agency” means an agency designated under § <cite root="1-1001.07">1-1001.07</cite>(d)(14) in whose office or offices mail voter registration applications are made available for general distribution to the public.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(19)</num>
    <text>The term “duly registered voter” means a registered voter who resides at the address listed on the Board’s records.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(20)</num>
    <text>The term “registered qualified elector” means a registered voter who resides at the address listed on the Board’s records.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(21)</num>
    <text>The term “qualified registered elector” means a registered voter who resides at the address listed on the Board’s records.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(22)</num>
    <text>The term “voting system” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The combination of mechanical, electromechanical, or electronic equipment, including the software, firmware, and documentation required to program, control, and support the equipment used to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Define ballots;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Cast and count votes;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Report or display elections results; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>Maintain and produce a permanent record; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The practices and documentation used to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Identify system components and versions of components;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Test the system during its development and maintenance;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Maintain records of system errors and defects;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>Determine necessary system changes after the initial qualification of the system; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>Provide voters with notices, instructions, forms, paper ballots, or other materials.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(23)</num>
    <text>The term “Help America Vote Act of 2002” means the Help America Vote Act of 2002, approved October 29, 2002 (116 Stat. 1666; 42 U.S.C. § 15301 et seq.).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(24)</num>
    <text>The term “gender identity or expression” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite root="2-1401.02">2-1401.02</cite>(12A).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(25)</num>
    <text>“Election observers” means persons who witness the administration of elections, including individuals representing nonpartisan domestic and international organizations, including voting rights organizations, civil rights organizations, and civic organizations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(26)</num>
    <text>“Qualified petition circulator” means an individual who is 18 years of age or older and either:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A District resident; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A resident of another jurisdiction who has registered with the Board as a petition circulator and consented to being subject to the subpoena power of the Board and the jurisdiction of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the enforcement of subpoenas without respect to the individual’s place of residence.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(27)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(28)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Aug. 12, 1955, 69 Stat. 699, ch. 862, § 2</annotation>
      <annotation>Oct. 4, 1961, 75 Stat. 820, Pub. L. 87-389, § 1(26)</annotation>
      <annotation>Apr. 22, 1968, 82 Stat. 103, Pub. L. 90-292, § 4(2)</annotation>
      <annotation>Sept. 22, 1970, 84 Stat. 849, Pub. L. 91-405, title II, §§ 203(a), 205(a)</annotation>
      <annotation>Dec. 23, 1971, 85 Stat. 788, Pub. L. 92-220, § 1(2)-(4)</annotation>
      <annotation>Aug. 14, 1973, 87 Stat. 311, Pub. L. 93-92, § 1(1)</annotation>
      <annotation>Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 832, Pub. L. 93-198, title VII, § 751(2)</annotation>
      <annotation>Aug. 14, 1974, 88 Stat. 458, Pub. L. 93-376, title III, § 306(a)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-79">Sept. 2, 1976, D.C. Law 1-79, title I, § 102(1), title VI, § 602, 23 DCR 2050</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-126">Apr. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 1-126, title III, § 301(a), (b), 24 DCR 2372</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-1">June 7, 1979, D.C. Law 3-1, § 2(a), 25 DCR 9454</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-88">Mar. 16, 1982, D.C. Law 4-88, § 2(b), 29 DCR 458</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-17">Aug. 2, 1983, D.C. Law 5-17, § 5(a), 30 DCR 3196</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-173">Sept. 22, 1994, D.C. Law 10-173, § 2(a), 41 DCR 5154</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-30">July 25, 1995, D.C. Law 11-30, § 2(a), 42 DCR 1547</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91">Apr. 12, 2000, D.C. Law 13-91, § 123(a), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-218">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-218, § 2(a), 51 DCR 9132</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-177">June 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-177, § 4(a), 55 DCR 3696</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-103">Feb. 4, 2010, D.C. Law 18-103, § 2(a), 56 DCR 9169</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-160">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-160,§ 131(b), 57 DCR 3012</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 501(g)(1), 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-31">Oct. 17, 2013, D.C. Law 20-31, § 2(a), 60 DCR 11535</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-158">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-158, § 2(a), 61 DCR 10730</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-167">Mar. 3, 2015, D.C. Law 20-167, § 2(b), 61 DCR 10738</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, “registered qualified elector” defined, see § <cite root="1-309.09">1-309.09</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Delegate to the House of Representatives, qualifications, see § <cite root="1-401">1-401</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="1-301.83">1-301.83</cite>, § <cite root="1-309.09">1-309.09</cite>, § <cite root="1-401">1-401</cite>, § <cite root="1-1001.07">1-1001.07</cite>, and § <cite root="38-2651">38-2651</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-1302.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 1-1102.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, in par. (13), inserted “United States Senator and Representative,”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-218">D.C. Law 15-218</cite> added pars. (22) and (23).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-177">D.C. Law 17-177</cite> added par. (24).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-103">D.C. Law 18-103</cite> rewrote pars. (2) and (7); and added par. (25).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-160">D.C. Law 18-160</cite> added par. (9A); and, in par. (13), inserted “the Attorney General,”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-124">D.C. Law 19-124</cite>, in par. (3), substituted “Board of Elections” for “Board of Elections and Ethics”; in par. (7), substituted “§ <cite root="1-1162.32">1-1162.32</cite> and 1-1163.35” for “§ <cite root="1-1105.07">1-1105.07</cite> or § <cite root="1-1107.01">1-1107.01</cite>”; and, in par. (15), substituted “§ <cite root="1-1161.01">1-1161.01</cite>(44) for purposes of this subchapter” for “§ <cite root="1-1101.01">1-1101.01</cite> for purposes of this subchapter”.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-31">D.C. Law 20-31</cite> added (26).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-158">D.C. Law 20-158</cite> would have added (27) and (28).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-167">D.C. Law 20-167</cite> rewrote (5); and substituted “members of the State Board of Education” for “the President and members of the Board of Education” in (13).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Help America Vote Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-120">D.C. Law 15-120</cite>, March 30, 2004, law notification 51 DCR 3807).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Help American Vote Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-283, December 18, 2003,  51 DCR 197).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Help America Vote Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-405, March 18, 2004,  51 DCR 3650).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Help America Vote Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-658, December 29, 2004,  52 DCR 492).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Omnibus Election Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-236, November 30, 2009,  56 DCR 9154).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 401(g)(1) of Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-298, January 29, 2012,  59 DCR 683).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2(a) and 3 of the Voter Registration Access and Modernization Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-616, Jan. 28, 2015,  62 DCR 1905, 21 STAT 791).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Special Election Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-617, Jan. 28, 2015,  62 DCR 1908, 21 STAT 794).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>The National Voter Registration Act, referred to in (17), is classified at Pub. L. 103-31, May 20, 1993, 107 Stat. 77.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-158">D.C. Law 20-158</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-158">D.C. Law 20-158</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
