<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1432</num>
  <heading>DC-NET Services Support Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the DC-NET Services Support Fund, which shall be used solely to defray operational costs of the DC-NET program. The DC-NET Services Support Fund shall be funded by payments for telecommunications services furnished by the DC-NET program of the Office of the Chief Technology Officer from independent District government agencies, agencies of the federal government, agencies of state or local governments, nonprofit entities providing services in the District of Columbia, entities outside the District government that may engage the DC-Net program to provide telecommunications services to the District of Columbia Public Schools, District of Columbia public charter schools, the District of Columbia Public Library, any open-access public network established for the purpose of providing Internet access services to underserved residents or neighborhoods in the District, and entities designated by the Mayor as necessary to support economic development initiatives of the District government. All funds collected from these sources shall be deposited into the DC-NET Services Support Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the DC-NET Services Support Fund, and any interest earned thereon, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (a) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 1003, 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 1043, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 1032, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “independent District government agencies, agencies of the federal government, agencies of state or local governments, nonprofit entities providing health care or education services in the District of Columbia, entities outside the District government that may engage the DC-Net program to provide telecommunications services to the District of Columbia Public Schools, District of Columbia public charter schools, the District of Columbia Public Library, and any open-access public network established for the purpose of providing Internet access services to underserved residents or neighborhoods in the District” for “independent District government agencies and entities outside the District government that may engage the DC-Net program to provide telecommunications services to the District of Columbia Public Schools”.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, in (a), substituted “nonprofit entities providing services” for “nonprofit entities providing health care or education services” and substituted “any open-access public network established for the purpose of providing Internet access services to underserved residents or neighborhoods in the District, and entities designated by the Mayor as necessary to support economic development initiatives of the District government” for “and any open-access public network established for the purpose of providing Internet access services to underserved residents or neighborhoods in the District.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1003 of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1043 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  1032 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  1032 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  1032 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
