<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-301.47a</num>
  <heading>Fiscal impact statements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Bills and resolutions. —</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <heading>In general. —</heading>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other law, except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, all permanent bills and resolutions shall be accompanied by a fiscal impact statement before final adoption by the Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <heading>Contents. —</heading>
      <text>The fiscal impact statement shall include the estimate of the costs which will be incurred by the District as a result of the enactment of the measure in the current and each of the first four fiscal years for which the act or resolution is in effect, together with a statement of the basis for such estimate.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Appropriations. —</heading>
    <text>Permanent and emergency acts which are accompanied by fiscal impact statements which reflect unbudgeted costs, shall be subject to appropriations prior to becoming effective.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Applicability. —</heading>
    <text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to emergency declaration, ceremonial, confirmation, and sense of the Council resolutions.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-17">Sept. 23, 1975, D.C. Law 1-17, § 4a</annotation>
      <annotation>as added Oct. 16, 2006, 120 Stat. 2038, Pub. L. 109-356, § 204</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 207, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="1-204.24d">1-204.24d</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite>, in the section credit, validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of section, see § 3 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Second Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-202, Nov. 23, 2015,  62 DCR 15276).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
