<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-301.191</num>
  <heading>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice; establishment; authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to § <cite root="1-204.04">1-204.04</cite>(b), the Council establishes the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice (“Office”), as a separate agency, subordinate to the Mayor, within the executive branch of the District of Columbia government, which shall be headed by the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice shall be appointed to head the Office pursuant to § <cite root="1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>(a).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Office shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be responsible for providing guidance and support to, and coordination of, public safety and of justice agencies within the District of Columbia government;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Ensure accountability through general oversight over public safety and justice agencies, as well as the programs under the jurisdiction of the Office, including those listed in paragraph (5) of this subsection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Promote, coordinate, and oversee collaborative efforts among District government agencies, and between District and federal government agencies, to ensure public safety and enhance the delivery of public-safety and justice services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Serve as a liaison to federal government agencies associated with criminal justice or public-safety issues, in the coordination, planning, and implementation of public-safety and justice matters; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be responsible for providing guidance and support to, and coordination of, the:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Access to Justice Initiative;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Motor Vehicle Theft Prevention Commission;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Corrections Information Council;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Office of Justice Grants Administration; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Office of Victim Services.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Funding for the programs listed in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall be specified by the annual Budget Request Act adopted by the Council. Nothing in this paragraph shall prevent the Office from contributing administrative and other support to further the purpose of these programs.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subsection (b) of this section shall not apply to the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice who is the incumbent head of the Office on September 14, 2011.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 3022, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 3022, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “Be responsible for providing guidance and support to, and coordination of, the” for “Oversee and provide administrative support for” in the introductory language of (c)(5)(A).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3022 the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <annotation>Short title: Section 3021 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle C of title III of the act may be cited as “Office of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice Establishment Act of 2011”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
