<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-303.01</num>
  <heading>Police regulations.</heading>
  <text>The Council of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and empowered to make and modify, and the Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and empowered to enforce, usual and reasonable police regulations in and for said District as follows:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>For causing full inspection to be made, at any reasonable times, of the places where the business of pawnbroking, junk-dealing, or second-hand clothing business may be carried on.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>To regulate the storage of highly inflammable substances in the thickly populated portions of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>To establish and regulate the charges to be made by owners of hacks and hackney carriages of any kind whatsoever.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>To prohibit conducting droves of animals upon such streets and avenues as it may deem needful to public safety and good order.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>To regulate the keeping of dogs and fowls.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>To prohibit the deposit upon the street or sidewalks of fruit, or any part thereof, or other substance or articles that might litter the same, or cause injury to or impede pedestrians.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>To regulate or prohibit loud noises with horns, gongs, or other instruments, or loud cries, upon the streets or public places, and to prohibit the use of any fireworks or explosives within such portions of the District as it may think necessary to public safety.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>To prescribe reasonable penalties, including civil penalties, for the infraction of the regulations mentioned in §§ <cite root="1-303.01">1-303.01</cite> and <cite root="1-303.02">1-303.02</cite>. The penalties may be enforced in any court or administrative tribunal of the District of Columbia having jurisdiction of minor offenses or civil infractions, and in the same manner that minor offenses or civil infractions are by law prosecuted or adjudicated and punished.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Jan. 26, 1887, 24 Stat. 368, ch. 49, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation>Mar. 3, 1925, 43 Stat. 1125, ch. 443, § 16</annotation>
      <annotation>Sept. 13, 1961, 75 Stat. 498, Pub. L. 87-227, § 3</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-42">Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-42, § 483, 32 DCR 4450</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-237">Mar. 8, 1991, D.C. Law 8-237, § 27, 38 DCR 314</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-71">Oct. 22, 2009, D.C. Law 18-71, § 12(a), 56 DCR 6619</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Environmental planning commission, see § <cite root="3-1001">3-1001</cite> et seq.</annotation>
      <annotation>Mayor’s authority, supervision of pawnbrokers and other businesses, see § <cite root="5-117.02">5-117.02</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Removal of snow and ice, public property, see § <cite root="9-602">9-602</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Special licensing provisions, sellers of gasoline, kerosene, oils, fireworks, and explosives, see § <cite root="47-2814">47-2814</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Specific licensing provisions, Council’s authority to regulate, modify, or eliminate licensing agreements, see § <cite root="47-2842">47-2842</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Specific licensing provisions, secondhand dealers, see § <cite root="47-2837">47-2837</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="1-303.02">1-303.02</cite>, § <cite root="1-303.03">1-303.03</cite>, § <cite root="1-303.05">1-303.05</cite>, and § <cite root="1-303.43">1-303.43</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-315.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 1-224.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-71">D.C. Law 18-71</cite> repealed par. (3), which had read as follows: “(3) To locate the places where licensed vendors on streets and public places shall stand, and change them as often as the public interests require, and to make all the necessary regulations governing their conduct upon the streets in relation to such business.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>Section 11(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-172">D.C. Law 17-172</cite> repealed par. (3).</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 13(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-172">D.C. Law 17-172</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 10(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-4">D.C. Law 18-4</cite> repealed par. (3).</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 12(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-4">D.C. Law 18-4</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>New Implementing Regulations</heading>
      <text>Pursuant to this section, the following new regulations were adopted in 1978: The “District of Columbia Noise Control Act of 1977” (<cite doc="D.C. Law 2-53">D.C. Law 2-53</cite>, Mar. 16, 1978,  24 DCR 5293) (as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-135">D.C. Law 9-135</cite>, July 23, 1992,  39 DCR 4079) and the “Vendors Regulation Amendments Act of 1978” (<cite doc="D.C. Law 2-82">D.C. Law 2-82</cite>, June 30, 1978,  24 DCR 9293).</text>
      <text>Pursuant to this section, the following new regulations were adopted in 1979: The “District of Columbia Noise Control Amendments Act of 1979” (<cite doc="D.C. Law 3-17">D.C. Law 3-17</cite>, Sept. 28, 1979,  26 DCR 229).</text>
      <text>Pursuant to this section, the following new regulations were adopted in 1982: The “Taxicab Act of 1981” (<cite doc="D.C. Law 4-89">D.C. Law 4-89</cite>, Mar. 31, 1982,  29 DCR 661).</text>
      <text>Pursuant to this section, the following new regulations were adopted in 1982: The “Vendors Regulation Amendment Act of 1982” (<cite doc="D.C. Law 4-195">D.C. Law 4-195</cite>, Mar.  10, 1983,  30 DCR 55).</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(1) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
