<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-306.01</num>
  <heading>District elements of comprehensive plan prepared; purposes.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It is hereby declared that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia has prepared, through an exhaustive process of research, analysis, and review, including citizen involvement and consultation with affected federal, state and local governments, and planning agencies in the National Capital region, District elements of a 20-year Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital as required by § <cite root="2-1002">2-1002</cite>(a) and by § <cite root="1-204.23">1-204.23</cite>(a).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Ten District elements of the Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital are contained in this part: General Provisions; Economic Development; Housing; Environmental Protection; Transportation; Public Facilities; Urban Design; Preservation and Historic Features; Downtown; and Human Services.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The District elements of the Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital contained in this part do not extend to any federal or international projects and developments, or to the United States Capitol buildings and grounds, or to any buildings and grounds under the care of the Architect of the Capitol.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The purposes of the District elements of the Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital are to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Define the requirements and aspirations of District residents, and accordingly influence social, economic and physical development;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Guide executive and legislative decisions on matters affecting the District and its citizens;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Promote economic growth and jobs for District residents;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Guide private and public development in order to achieve District and community goals;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Maintain and enhance the natural and architectural assets of the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Assist in the conservation, stabilization, and improvement of each neighborhood and community in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-76">Apr. 10, 1984, D.C. Law 5-76, § 2, 31 DCR 1049</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>National capital planning commission, see § <cite root="2-1002">2-1002</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="47-813">47-813</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>2001 Ed., § <cite root="1-301.62">1-301.62</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-245.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan of 1984: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-76">D.C. Law 5-76</cite> sets forth titles I through X adopted by the Council of the District of Columbia entitled “The District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan of 1984,” and was reprinted in its entirety in  31 DCR 1049 and is contained in the 10 DCMR compilation. On April 5, 1984, the National Capital Planning Commission adopted a resolution finding that “the District elements adopted and amended by the Council by D.C. Act 5-112 do not have a negative impact on the interests or functions of the Federal Establishment in the National Capital.”</text>
      <text>Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-129">D.C. Law 8-129</cite>, as amended by § 201 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-132">D.C. Law 8-132</cite>, amended Titles I through VIII, X and XI, and added Title XII to the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan of 1984, adopted by <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-76">D.C. Law 5-76</cite>. <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-129">D.C. Law 8-129</cite> was reprinted in its entirety in  37 DCR 55. Amended Titles I through VII, X, XI, and new Title XII will be codified at Title 10 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-132">D.C. Law 8-132</cite> is found at  38 DCR 2213.</text>
      <text>Review of District elements by National Capital Planning Commission: Section 8(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-76">D.C. Law 5-76</cite>, and § 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-129">D.C. Law 8-129</cite>, provided that no District element of the Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital shall take effect until it has been reviewed by the National Capital Planning Commission as provided in subsection (a) of §§ <cite root="1-2002">1-2002</cite> and <cite root="1-244">1-244</cite>.</text>
      <text>Progress report on Comprehensive Plan findings: Pursuant to Resolution 8-243, the “Progress Report on the Comprehensive Plan Findings Resolution of 1990”, effective August 10, 1990, the Council submitted to the Mayor the findings of the Council on the Mayor’s 3rd biennial progress report on implementing the District of Columbia elements of the Comprehensive Plan.</text>
      <text>Comments on Zoning Commission’s proposed Downtown Development District action: Pursuant to Resolution 8-318, the “Zoning Commission Downtown Development District Comments Resolution of 1990”, effective December 21, 1990, the Council expressed the opinion of the Council to the District of Columbia Zoning Commission concerning the Commission’s proposed action on the Downtown Development District.</text>
      <text>Repeal of § 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-187">D.C. Law 5-187</cite>: Section 3(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-275">D.C. Law 12-275</cite> provided that § 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-187">D.C. Law 5-187</cite> is repealed, effective April 27, 1999. Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-187">D.C. Law 5-187</cite> had added a new title XI to the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan of 1984, adopted by <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-76">D.C. Law 5-76</cite>.</text>
      <text>Sections 301 and 401 of D.C. Law 18-361 provided: “Sec. 301. Notwithstanding section 502, section 308(b) of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, effective March 6, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-153; D.C. Official Code § 2-558(b)), and section 204 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act of 1975, October 8, 1975 (D.C. Law 1-19; D.C. Official Code § 2-602), the text, maps, and graphics of the District elements of the Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital, as amended by this act, need not be published in the District of Columbia Register to become effective.” “Sec. 401. Applicability. “No District element of the Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital shall apply until it has been reviewed by the National Capital Planning Commission as provided in section 2(a) of the National Capital Planning Act of 1952, approved June 6, 1924 (43 Stat. 463; D.C. Official Code § 2-1002(a)), and section 423 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 792; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.23).”</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
