<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-325.322</num>
  <heading>Teen Pregnancy Prevention Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Teen Pregnancy Prevention Fund (“Fund”) to provide subgrants to nonprofit organizations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department of Health shall make a grant to a single grant-managing entity of which at least 90% shall be used to make subgrants for the purpose of teen pregnancy prevention. The remaining 10% shall be utilized for administrative expenses and evaluation of the Fund. The grant-managing entity is limited to spending any funds received from the Fund on administrative costs only, and not any substantive work related to teen pregnancy prevention.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund is designed to provide subgrants to nonprofits in health services for teens, reproductive health education, professional development and training, research and policy development, and public education and awareness. The funds shall be available for conveyance to a grant-managing entity for the purposes identified in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subgrants shall be awarded, subject to the availability of funding, as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All subgrants shall be awarded on a competitive basis;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The subgrants shall not exceed $100,000 per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Subgrants are one-time;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The subgrant funds shall be used exclusively to serve District of Columbia residents; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>All subgrants shall be subject to District transparency requirements, such as Freedom of Information Act requests.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of this chapter [§ <cite root="1-328.11">1-328.11</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  5143, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
