<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-101</num>
  <heading>Covered employees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This chapter shall apply to the following employees, except persons employed less than 15 hours per week and except persons employed in an executive, administrative, or professional capacity as defined by the Secretary of Labor under § 13(a)(1) of the Fair Labor Standards Act (29 U.S.C. § 213(a)(1)) or required by District of Columbia law in effect on April 26, 1994, to possess an occupational license:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Employees hired by a contractor as food service workers in a hotel, restaurant, cafeteria, apartment building, hospital, nursing care facility, or similar establishment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Employees hired by a contractor to perform janitorial or building maintenance services in an office building, institution, or similar establishment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Nonprofessional employees hired by a contractor to perform health care or related support services in a hospital, nursing care facility, or similar establishment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Employees hired by a contractor to perform security services in an office building, institution, or similar establishment; provided, that special police officers who are armed, and employees hired by a contractor to perform security services for the Board of Education or a public charter school shall not be included.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter “contractor” includes a subcontractor and means an individual or company that employs 25 or more persons.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-105">Apr. 26, 1994, D.C. Law 10-105, § 2, 41 DCR 1011</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-118">June 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-118, § 402, 53 DCR 2602</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 114, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 36-1501.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-118">D.C. Law 16-118</cite> added par. (a)(4).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in the punctuation in subsecs. (a)(1), (2), and (3).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-105">D.C. Law 10-105</cite> provided that the Mayor shall promulgate rules to implement this chapter.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
