<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1331.10</num>
  <heading>Retaliation prohibited.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An employer may not discriminate in any manner or take adverse action against any person because the person:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Makes an oral or written complaint with the employer or the Mayor alleging that the employer violated any provision of this subchapter or any rule issue pursuant to this subchapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Brings an action or initiates a proceeding involving a violation of this subchapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Testifies in an action authorized under this subchapter or a proceeding involving a violation of the provisions of this subchapter or any rule issued pursuant to this subchapter; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Assists in an investigation by providing information to a litigant in a civil action, the Mayor, or another agency in proceedings as provided by [this] subchapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person who believes that an employer has discriminated in any manner or taken adverse action against the person in violation of this subchapter may submit to the Mayor a written complaint, signed by the complainant, that alleges the discrimination.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of a complaint, the Mayor shall conduct an investigation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 84-2-ch924" path="§210">Aug. 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 976, ch. 924, § 210</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-300" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-300, § 2(b), 60 DCR 2679</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§32-1331.07">32-1331.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite> added this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
