<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1608</num>
  <heading>Anti-displacement.</heading>
  <text>Participants in training activities funded pursuant to ยง <cite path="ยง32-1607">32-1607</cite> shall not be assigned or placed to work for any employer or worksite where:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Any other individual is laid off from the same or substantially equivalent job;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>An employer has terminated a regular employee and filled the vacancy with a participant;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>An employer has caused an involuntary reduction in the workforce and filled the vacancy with a participant;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>An employer has caused an involuntary reduction below full-time hours of any employee in the same or substantially equivalent job;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>An employer has caused an involuntary reduction in wages or employment benefits;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Placement of a recipient will violate an existing collective bargaining agreement, unless the labor organization and the employer provide a written concurrence;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The job is created in a promotional line that will infringe in any way upon the promotional opportunities of currently employed individuals;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>The placement is the equivalent of filling an established unfilled position vacancy, or is the equivalent of performing a job that is substantially similar to the vacant position, unless the participant is given a bona fide opportunity to apply for the position as an unsubsidized employee after 18 weeks of satisfactory service in the position; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>There is a hiring freeze for positions that are the same or substantially similar to the position performed by the participants.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-150" type="History">July 18, 2000, D.C. Law 13-150, ยง 9, 47 DCR 4644</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-263" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-263, ยง 2(h), 62 DCR 1518</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-263">D.C. Law 20-263</law-cite> rewrote the introductory language.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
