<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1001</num>
  <heading>Findings and declaration of policy.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council of the District of Columbia finds that persons employed in the District of Columbia should be paid at wages sufficient to provide adequate maintenance and to protect health. Any wage that is not sufficient to provide adequate maintenance and to protect health impairs the health, efficiency, and well-being of persons so employed, constitutes unfair competition against other employers and their employees, threatens the stability of industry, reduces the purchasing power of employees, and requires, in many instances, that their wages be supplemented by the payment of public moneys for relief or other public and private assistance. Employment of persons at these insufficient rates of pay threatens the health and well-being of the people of the District of Columbia and injures the overall economy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It is declared the policy of this subchapter to ensure the elimination of the conditions referred to above.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-248" type="History">Mar. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 9-248, § 2, 40 DCR 761</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-220.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-248">D.C. Law 9-248</cite>, the “District of Columbia Minimum Wage Act Revision Act of 1992”, see Mayor’s Order 93-114, July 27, 1993.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 17 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-248">D.C. Law 9-248</cite> provided that the Mayor shall issue rules necessary to carry out the provisions of the act pursuant to (subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, 2001 Ed.).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
