<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1008</num>
  <heading>Duties of employers; open records.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Every employer subject to any provision of this subchapter or of any regulation or order issued under this subchapter shall make, keep, and preserve for a period of not less than 3 years or whatever the prevailing federal standard is, whichever is greater, a record of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The name, address, and occupation of each employee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A record of the date of birth of any employee under 19 years of age;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The rate of pay and the amount paid each pay period to each employee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The precise time worked each day and each workweek by each employee; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Any other records or information as the Mayor shall prescribe by regulation as necessary or appropriate for the enforcement of the provisions of this subchapter or of the regulations issued under this subchapter.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any records shall be open and made available for inspection or transcription by the Mayor or the Mayor’s authorized representative at any reasonable time. Every employer shall furnish the Mayor or to the Mayor’s authorized representative on demand a sworn statement of records and information upon forms prescribed or approved by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Every employer shall furnish to each employee at the time of payment of wages an itemized statement showing the date of the wage payment, gross wages paid, deductions from and additions to wages, net wages paid, hours worked during the pay period, and any other information as the Mayor may prescribe by regulation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Every employer, except as specified in §  32-1008.01, shall furnish to each employee at the time of hiring a written notice, both in English and in the employee’s primary language, containing the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the employer and any “doing business as” names used by the employer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The physical address of the employer’s main office or principal place of business, and a mailing address, if different;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The telephone number of the employer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The employee’s rate of pay and the basis of that rate, including: by the hour, shift, day, week, salary, piece, commission, any allowances claimed as part of the minimum wage, including tip, meal, or lodging allowances, or overtime rate of pay, exemptions from overtime pay, living wage, exemptions from the living wage, and the applicable prevailing wages;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The employee’s regular payday designated by the employer in accordance with § <cite path="§32-1302">32-1302</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any such other information as the Mayor considers material and necessary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 90 days of February 26, 2015, or whenever any of the information required in subsection (c) of this section changes, every employer, except as specified in §  <cite path="§32-1008.01">32-1008.01</cite>, shall furnish each employee with an updated written notice containing the information required under subsection (c) of this section. As proof of compliance, every employer shall retain copies of the written notice furnished to employees that are signed and dated by the employer and by the employee acknowledging receipt of the notice.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If an employer fails to comply with this subsection or subsection (c) of this section, the failure shall constitute evidence weighing against the credibility of the employer’s testimony regarding the rate of pay promised.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The period prescribed in § <cite path="§32-1308">32-1308</cite>(c) shall not begin until the employee is provided all itemized statements and written notice required by subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall make available for employers a sample template of the notice within 60 days of February 26, 2015.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-248" type="History">Mar. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 9-248, § 9, 40 DCR 761</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-157" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-157, § 3(c), 61 DCR 10157</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§32-1010">32-1010</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-220.7.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite> added “or whatever the prevailing federal standard is, whichever is greater” in the introductory paragraph of (a)(1); substituted “precise time worked” for “hours worked” in (a)(1)(D); and added (c)-(e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see §  3(a) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-240">D.C. Law 20-240</cite>, March 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1332).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-240">D.C. Law 20-240</cite>, March 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1332).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Wage Theft Prevention Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-2">D.C. Law 21-2</cite>, June 4, 2015,  62 DCR 4552).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 3(a) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-57">D.C. Law 21-57</cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,  62 DCR 15602).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-57">D.C. Law 21-57</cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,  62 DCR 15602).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of the Wage Theft Prevention Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2016 <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-101"> D.C. Law 21-101</cite>, April 6, 2016, 63 DCR 2220, 20 DCSTAT 3142).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b)(1) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-544, Dec. 29, 2014,  62 DCR 243, 20 STAT 4458).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 2(c) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-544, Dec. 29, 2014,  62 DCR 243, 20 STAT 4458).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Wage Theft Prevention Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-8, Feb. 26, 2015,  62 DCR 2669, 21 STAT 830).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Wage Theft Prevention Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-66, May 22, 2015,  62 DCR 6867, 21 DCSTAT 1446).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-188, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14224).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-188, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14224).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3(a) of the Wage Theft Prevention Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-291, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1207).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3(a) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-293, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1215).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-293, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1215).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014, and that the act shall apply to violations occurring after October 1, 2014.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
