<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1331.05</num>
  <heading>Investigation of complaints.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to a complaint from an employee, a representative of an employee, an interested party, or on his or her own initiative, shall investigate violations of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Enter and inspect the premises or place of business, employment, or work site, and upon demand examine and copy, wholly or partly, any or all books, registers, payrolls, and other records, including those required to be made, kept, and preserved under this subchapter or under any regulation issued pursuant to this subchapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Question an employer, employee, or other person in the premises, place of business or employment, or work site;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Require from any employer full and correct statements in writing, including sworn statements, upon forms prescribed or approved by the Mayor, with respect to the payment of wages, hours, names, addresses, and such other information pertaining to remuneration to employees or independent contractors as the Mayor may determine necessary or appropriate; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Investigate such facts, conditions, or matters as the Mayor may determine necessary or appropriate to determine whether this subchapter or any regulation issued pursuant to this subchapter has been or is being violated.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, in the performance of any duty or the execution of any power prescribed by this subchapter, may administer oaths or affirmations, hold hearings, certify official acts, take and cause to be taken depositions of witnesses, issue subpoenas, and compel the attendance of witnesses and production of books, papers, documents, records, and testimony.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In case of failure of any person to comply with a lawful subpoena or of the refusal of any witness to produce evidence or to testify to any matter about which he or she may be lawfully interrogated, the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, upon the application of the Mayor or the Mayor’s designee, may compel obedience by proceedings for contempt as provided in § <cite path="§2-1831.09">2-1831.09</cite>(e).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An employer that fails to produce to the Mayor the books and records requested in the course of an investigation to determine whether the employer is in compliance with the provisions of this subchapter shall be subject to an administrative penalty not to exceed $500 per day for each day the requested records are not produced.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this subchapter shall be deemed a limitation on any power or authority of the Mayor under any law which may be otherwise applicable to administer or enforce this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 976, ch. 924, § 205</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-300" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-300, § 2(b), 60 DCR 2679</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite>, § 4, see § 7019 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite>, § 4, see 7019 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 7001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite> provided that <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite>, §§ 205, 206, and 212(e) shall apply upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7019 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite>, § 4.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
