<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1522</num>
  <heading>Review of compensation orders.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A compensation order shall become effective when filed with the Mayor as provided in § <cite path="§32-1520">32-1520</cite>, and, unless an application for review has been filed with the Board as provided in subsection (b) of this section, shall become final at the expiration of the 30th day thereafter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2A)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A party aggrieved by a compensation order may file an application for review with the Board within 30 days of the issuance of the compensation order. A party adverse to the review may file an opposition answer within 15 days of the filing of an application for review.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A Memorandum of Points and Authorities, which sets forth the legal and factual basis for the review or the opposition thereto, shall be filed with an application for review and an opposition answer; no further submissions shall be permitted, unless requested by the reviewing panel.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Pursuant to the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), any party in interest who is adversely affected or aggrieved by a final decision rendered after review of a compensation order as provided in paragraph (2A) of this subsection or any party in interest who is adversely affected or aggrieved by a compensation order which has been filed as provided in § <cite path="§32-1520">32-1520</cite> may petition for review of such decision or order by the District of Columbia Court of Appeals. If any party shall apply to the Court for leave to adduce additional evidence and shall show to the satisfaction of the Court that such additional evidence is material and that there were reasonable grounds for failure to adduce such evidence in the hearing before the Mayor, the Court may order such additional evidence to be taken before the Mayor, and to be made part of the record. The Court may remand the case for appropriate action.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If any employer or his officers or agents fail to comply with a compensation order making an award that has become final, any beneficiary of such award, or the Mayor, may apply for the enforcement of the order to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for enforcement of such order and upon showing that such employer or his officers or agents have failed to comply therewith, the Court shall enforce obedience to the order by writ of injunction or by other proper process, mandatory or otherwise, to enjoin upon such person and his officers and agents compliance with the order.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Proceedings for suspending, setting aside, or enforcing a compensation order, whether rejecting a claim or making an award, shall not be instituted otherwise than as provided in this section and § <cite path="§32-1520">32-1520</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-77" type="History" path="§23">July 1, 1980, D.C. Law 3-77, § 23, 27 DCR 2503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1102(b), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 56, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§32-1515">32-1515</cite>, § <cite path="§32-1519">32-1519</cite>, and § <cite path="§32-1524">32-1524</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-322.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “an application for review has been filed with the Board” for “proceedings for the suspension or setting aside of such order are instituted”; in subsec. (b), repealed pars. (1) and (2), added par. (2A), and, in par. (3), substituted “(2A) of this subsection or” for “(2) of this subsection, or, if the Mayor has declined to review the order or does not establish a procedure for such review”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in subsec. (b)(3), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1102(b) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1102(b) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
