<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1331.06</num>
  <heading>Hearings.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 15 days after service of notice of a violation, an alleged violator may submit a written request to the Mayor to hold a hearing on the alleged violation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of a timely request, the Mayor shall conduct a hearing in accordance with the procedures set forth in subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], and issue a decision within 30 days after the hearing.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor, after investigation but before a hearing, has cause to believe that a person is violating any provision of this subchapter and the violation has caused, or may cause, immediate and irreparable harm to the public, the Mayor may issue a stop work order requiring the alleged violator to immediately cease and desist construction-related business activities. The order shall be served by certified mail or delivery in person.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 10 days after service of a stop work order, the alleged violator may submit a written request to the Mayor for an expedited hearing on the alleged violation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of a timely request for an expedited hearing, the Mayor shall conduct a hearing within 10 days after the date of receiving the request and shall deliver to the alleged violator at his or her last known address a written notice of the hearing by any means guaranteed to be received at least 5 days before the hearing date.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall issue a decision within 10 days after an expedited hearing.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any party aggrieved by a final order of the Mayor under subsection (c)(3) of this section may seek judicial review and appeal under § <cite path="§2-510">2-510</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Aug. 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 976, ch. 924, § 206</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-300">as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-300, § 2(b), 60 DCR 2679</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite>, § 4, see § 7019 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite>, § 4, see 7019 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite> provided that <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite>, §§ 205, 206, and 212(e) shall apply upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      <text>Section 7019 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite>, § 4.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <annotation>Section 7001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
