<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1410</num>
  <heading>Apprenticeship agreements — Violations; hearings; determinations; appeals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon the complaint of any interested person or upon his own initiative, the Associate Director of Apprenticeship may investigate to determine if there has been a violation of the terms of an apprenticeship agreement made under this subchapter and may hold hearings, inquiries, and other proceedings necessary to such investigation and determination. The parties to such an agreement shall be given a fair and impartial hearing after reasonable notice thereof. All such hearings, investigations, and determinations shall be made under authority of reasonable rules and procedures prescribed by the Apprenticeship Council, subject to the approval of the Registration Agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The determination of the Associate Director of Apprenticeship shall be filed with the Apprenticeship Council. If no appeal is filed with the Apprenticeship Council within 10 days after the date of filing of the determination of the Associate Director of Apprenticeship, the determination shall become the order of the Apprenticeship Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any person aggrieved by a determination or action of the Associate Director of Apprenticeship may appeal to the Apprenticeship Council, which shall hold a hearing after due notice to the interested parties.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any person aggrieved by the action of the Apprenticeship Council may appeal as provided in subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 21, 1946, 60 Stat. 206, ch. 267, § 10</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1948, 62 Stat. 991, ch. 646, § 32(b)</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 24, 1949, 63 Stat. 107, ch. 139, § 127</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 583, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 163(e)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 2012(j), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-412.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 36-130.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite>, in (a), substituted “Associate Director of Apprenticeship” for “Director,” substituted “Registration Agency” for “Secretary of Labor,” and made stylistic changes; and rewrote (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(j) of the Apprenticeship Modernization Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-256">D.C. Law 20-256</cite>, Apr. 30, 2015,  62 DCR 2259).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(j) of the Apprenticeship Modernization Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-579, Jan. 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1258, 21 STAT 724).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(j) of the Apprenticeship Modernization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-16, Mar. 26, 2015,  62 DCR 3847, 21 DCSTAT 843).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2012(j) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
