<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1331.11</num>
  <heading>Provisions relating to contracts with public bodies.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Where, after investigation, the Mayor determines that an employer who is or has engaged in work on a project funded by District funds is in violation of this subchapter, the Mayor shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Withhold from payment due to the employer an amount that is sufficient to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Pay restitution to each employee according to ยง <cite path="ยง32-1331.09">32-1331.09</cite>, including any applicable prevailing wages; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Pay any benefits, taxes, or other contributions that are required by law to be paid on behalf of the employee.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon a final determination, the Mayor shall release the full amount of the withheld funds if no violation is found, or if a violation is found, the balance of the withheld funds after all obligations are satisfied pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An employer found to be in violation of this section more than twice in a 2-year period shall be subject to debarment. A debarment under this section shall be in effect against any successor corporation or business entity that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has one or more of the same principals or officers as the employer against whom the debarment was imposed; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is engaged in the same or equivalent trade or activity.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 976, ch. 924, ยง 211</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-300" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-300, ยง 2(b), 60 DCR 2679</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite> added this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
