<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1631</num>
  <heading>Limits on funding Individual Training Accounts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning January 1, 2015, or upon the effective date of [<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-263">D.C. Law 20-263</cite>, effective May 2, 2015], whichever occurs first, no eligible training provider shall be eligible to receive funding for more than 5 individual training accounts in a calendar year unless at least 25% of the students participating in the entity’s training programs are funded by sources other than the individual training accounts.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning January 1, 2016, no eligible training provider shall be eligible to receive funding for more than 5 individual training accounts in a calendar year unless at least 50% of the students participating in the entity’s training programs are funded by sources other than the individual training accounts.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>WIC shall establish a procedure by which eligible training providers shall certify as to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The total number of students enrolled in the eligible training provider’s training programs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of students who are funded by sources other than individual training accounts; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The percentage calculated using the number in paragraph (1) of this subsection as the denominator and the number in paragraph (2) of this subsection as the numerator.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Eligible training provider” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§32-1602">32-1602</cite>(1A).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Individual training account” shall have the same meaning as provided § <cite path="§32-1602">32-1602</cite>(1B).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History" path="§1142">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1142, 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-263" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-263, § 3(a), (b)(1), (c), 62 DCR 1518</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-263">D.C. Law 20-263</cite>: Section 3(b)(2) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-263">D.C. Law 20-263</cite> provided that § 3(b)(1) of the act, which amended subsection (c) of this section, shall apply as of October 1, 2014.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle M of title I of Law 15-205: Section 1141 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> provided that subtitle M of title I of the act may be cited as the Workforce Investment Implementation Individual Training Accounts Limitation Amendment Act of 2004.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) workforce investment implementation individual training accounts limitation provisions, see § 1142 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) workforce investment implementation individual training accounts limitation provisions, see § 1142 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-263">D.C. Law 20-263</cite> rewrote (a) to (c); and added (d).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
