<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1661</num>
  <heading>Definitions; Task Force established; member ship; duties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Basic skills program” means a secondary, post-secondary, or alternative education or training program that helps individuals enhance the reading, writing, math, English language, digital literacy, or problem-solving skills that adults need to succeed in a job, occupational training, or postsecondary education.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Career pathways” means an approach to connecting progressive levels of basic skills and postsecondary education, training, and supportive services in specific sectors or cross-sector occupations in a way that optimizes the progress and success of individuals (including those with limited education, English skills, or work experience) in securing marketable credentials, family-supporting employment, and further education and employment opportunities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“High-demand occupations or sectors” means occupations or sectors consistent with the Workforce Investment Council’s current Workforce Investment Act of 1998 Demand Occupation List.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Task Force” means the Adult Career Pathways Task Force established in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning October 1, 2014, the Mayor shall establish an Adult Career Pathways Task Force that shall have as its purpose development of a city-wide strategic plan for connecting adult basic skills programs administered in the District to career pathways.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall be convened by the Workforce Investment Council, and shall consist of the following 14 members:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Chairman of the Council, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chair of the Workforce Investment Council, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Deputy Mayor for Education, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The State Superintendent of Education, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Chair of the Public Charter School Board, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Employment Services, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Human Services, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8A)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department on Disability Services, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The Executive Director of the D.C. Public Library, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>A representative of the University of the District of Columbia Community College, appointed by the President of the University of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Three community representatives, appointed by the Mayor, as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A representative of a District organization engaged in the direct provision of a basic skills program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A representative of a District school engaged in the direct provision of a basic skills program; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A representative of a District job training provider.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No later than September 30, 2015, the Task Force shall submit to the Council and the Mayor the city-wide strategic plan required under this section. The plan shall be developed in concert with the District’s state integrated workforce development plan required under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, approved July 22, 2014 (128 Stat. 1425; 29 U.S.C. § 3101 et seq.). In developing the strategic plan, the Task Force shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Review best practices for improving literacy, numeracy, and technology skills for adults;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Review and analyze adult basic skills programs currently administered by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, the District of Columbia Public Schools, the District of Columbia Public Charter Schools, the University of the District of Columbia Community College, the District of Columbia Public Library, and other agencies identified by the Task Force , with focus provided to the missions and goals of the various programs, the types of credentials offered, the degree of funding levels, the age and educational functioning level of students at time of program entry and the rates of gains upon completion, and the degree to which the program partners with job training providers, postsecondary education programs, or employers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Consult with stakeholders, including the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Organizations with research or policy expertise in adult basic skills programs and career pathways;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Organizations focused on adult education and workforce development research or service provision;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Representatives of the District’s business community in high-demand occupations or sectors that the Task Force has identified for potential career pathways; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Representatives from the philanthropic community;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Perform an analysis of evidence-based approaches for helping adult learners with different needs and skill levels advance in career pathways, with special attention paid to practices for adult learners with basic skills below the 6th grade level;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Develop a city-wide mission statement for ensuring that adult learners have access to career pathways by 2020 and annual benchmarks for measuring progress toward that goal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Analyze the high-demand occupations or sectors in which career pathways can be developed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Develop responsibilities among the Task Force agencies for meeting the citywide goals, including recommendations to better align policies and practices around support services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Develop common performance definitions and measures that adult basic skills programs will use to track progress, including educational gains, secondary school diploma or equivalent credential attainment, employment placement and retention, entrance into postsecondary education or training, and other credential completion; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Analyze existing professional development opportunities for adult educators and develop a strategy for addressing any identified gaps.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Following the completion of the city-wide strategic plan, the Workforce Investment Council shall convene the Task Force on a quarterly basis to track implementation of the strategy.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History" path="§2122">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  2122, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 2112, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “14 members” for “13 members” in the introductory language of (c); added (c)(8A); rewrote the introductory language of (d); and substituted “secondary school diploma or equivalent credential attainment” for “GED or secondary school diploma attainment” in (d)(8).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this subchapter, see § 2122 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this subchapter, see § 2122 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this subchapter, see § 2122 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2112 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
