<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1502</num>
  <heading>Administration; annual report to Council.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall administer the provisions of this chapter, and shall make such rules and regulations, appoint and fix the compensation of such personnel, and make such expenditures as may be necessary. All expenditures of the Mayor in the administration of this chapter shall be allowed and paid as provided in § <cite path="§32-1541">32-1541</cite> upon the presentation of itemized vouchers therefor approved by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall report annually to the Council by February 1st of each year on the status, from the previous fiscal year, of the workers’ compensation program. The report shall include the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The total number of cases, the total number of lost time cases, the number of medical only cases, the number of cases where no compensation was paid, the number of cases that are more than 500 weeks, the number of permanent partial disability scheduled cases, the number of permanent partial disability nonscheduled cases, the number of permanent total disability cases, the number of temporary total disability cases, the total number of lost time cases, the number of medical only cases, the number of cases in which claimant was represented by an attorney, cumulative total attorney fees paid, the number of cases controverted, the number of controverted cases decided in favor of employer and decided in favor of claimant, the growth in the assigned risk plan, the number of cases in and the future liability of the special fund; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The percentage of the total number of cases each year that are: more than 500 weeks; permanent partial disability; permanent partial disability nonscheduled; permanent total disability; and temporary total disability.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-77" type="History" path="§3">July 1, 1980, D.C. Law 3-77, § 3, 27 DCR 2503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-229" type="History">Apr. 16, 1999, D.C. Law 12-229, § 2(b), 46 DCR 891</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-302.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Workers’ Compensation Equity Amendment Act Rulemaking Approval Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Proposed Resolution 11-177, deemed approved October 11, 1995, Council approved proposed rules to implement the Workers’ Compensation Equity Amendment Act of 1990.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
