<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1105</num>
  <heading>District of Columbia Occupational Safety and Health Board.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established within the executive branch of the District, a District of Columbia Occupational Safety and Health Board. The Board shall be composed of 7 members appointed by the Mayor, with the advice and consent of the Council from among those residents of the District who by reason of training, education, or experience are qualified to carry out the functions of the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Promulgate occupational safety and health standards in accordance with § <cite root="32-1108">32-1108</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Determine variances in accordance with §§ <cite root="32-1110">32-1110</cite> and <cite root="32-1111">32-1111</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Adopt rules of procedure to govern its orderly operation and the orderly operation of the Commission in accordance with the subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, each member of the Board shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall designate a Chairperson of the Board to serve for a term of 3 years.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two persons shall be appointed from the private sector to represent management, 1 for an initial term of 3 years and 1 for an initial term of 1 year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Two persons shall be appointed from the private sector to represent labor, 1 for an initial term of 3 years and 1 for an initial term of 1 year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>One person shall be appointed from the public management sector to represent management for an initial term of 2 years.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>One person shall be appointed from the public labor sector to represent labor for an initial term of 2 years.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The composition of the Board shall be representative of the working age population of the District in terms of race, ethnic origin, and sex.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Whenever a vacancy on the Board occurs before the end of a term, the Mayor, with the advice and consent of the Council, shall appoint a person to complete the remainder of that term.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit nominations to the Board to the Council within 60 days of the date of approval of the plan. The Board shall begin operation when a majority of the members are sworn in. A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum. A quorum is necessary to conduct the business of the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A member of the Board may continue to serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor is appointed and sworn into office.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may remove a member of the Board for incompetence, misconduct, or neglect of duty, after notice to the member.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-186">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-186, § 6, 35 DCR 8250</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="32-1101">32-1101</cite>, § <cite root="32-1106">32-1106</cite>, § <cite root="32-1107">32-1107</cite>, and § <cite root="32-1124">32-1124</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 36-1205.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <annotation>Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-186">D.C. Law 7-186</cite>, the “District of Columbia Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1988”, see Mayor’s Order 89-121, May 31, 1989.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Section effective: Section 26 (a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-186">D.C. Law 7-186</cite> (§ <cite root="32-1124">32-1124</cite>(a)) provided that §§ <cite root="36-1202">36-1202</cite>, <cite root="36-1203">36-1203</cite>, <cite root="36-1205">36-1205</cite> to 36-1223 (§§ <cite root="32-1102">32-1102</cite>, <cite root="32-1103">32-1103</cite>, <cite root="32-1105">32-1105</cite> to 32-1123, 2001 Ed.), and the repeal of subchapter II of Chapter 2 of Title 36 (Chapter 8 of Title 32, 2001 Ed.) shall apply 2 years after approval of the plan by the Secretary.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
