<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1603</num>
  <heading>Workforce Investment Council.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is created a Workforce Investment Council that shall serve as the District’s state workforce investment board pursuant to section 111 of the Federal Act, which shall carry out the functions of a local workforce investment board as assigned by the Mayor pursuant to section 117(c)(4) of the Federal Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Council shall have grant-making authority for the purpose of providing competitive grants under the authority granted to the Council by this subchapter; provided, that grants shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1 [§ <cite path="§1-328.11">1-328.11</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Council shall have grant-making authority for the purpose of providing competitive grants based on the recommendations of the Workforce Intermediary Task Force, made pursuant to the Workforce Intermediary Task Force Establishment Temporary Act of 2011, effective December 2, 2011 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 19-55">D.C. Law 19-55</cite>; 58 DCR 8962), and approved by the Council in the Workforce Intermediary Task Force Recommendations Emergency Approval Resolution of 2012, effective June 5, 2012 (Res. 19-454; 59 DCR 7454); provided, that grants shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1 [§ <cite path="§1-328.11">1-328.11</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall appoint members of WIC in a manner consistent with the requirements of section 111(b) and (c) of the Federal Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The WIC shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assist the Mayor in the selection of the WIC Executive Director;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In cooperation with the WIA administrative entity:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Develop the District’s state plan consistent with the requirements of section 112 of the Federal Act;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Negotiate the District’s state performance measures as required under section 136(b) of the Federal Act; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Develop the District’s annual report as required under section 136(d) of the Federal Act;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Establish policies and guidance for the District’s American Job Center system as required under section 134(c) of the Federal Act;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>In coordination with the WIA administrative entity, develop and implement District-wide employment and training activities as required under section 134(a) of the Federal Act;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Develop and implement a workforce intermediary pilot project, as described in § <cite path="§2-219.04b">2-219.04b</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Develop applications for incentive grants pursuant to section 503 of the Federal Act.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall certify WIC as the local workforce investment board for the District of Columbia not less than once every 2 years, consistent with the requirements of section 117(c) of the Federal Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall designate WIC to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Certify American Job Centers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Select and terminate American Job Centers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In coordination with the WIA administrative entity, develop a memorandum of agreement with mandatory partner programs for the administration of American Job Centers, which shall include a resource-sharing agreement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Establish eligibility and performance requirements for training providers to be considered eligible to receive ITA funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Identify demand occupations for which training may be provided and develop a demand occupation list not less than once every 2 years;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Implement a procedure for determining initial and subsequent eligibility of training providers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Establish and implement eligibility and performance requirements for providers of training services other than those provided through ITAs, including on-the-job training and customized training services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Develop and implement a policy for the selection of providers of youth employment and training services consistent with section 123 of the Federal Act;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Establish a youth council consistent with section 117(h) of the Federal Act;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Develop an annual operating budget for WIC;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>In cooperation with the WIA administrative entity, advise the Mayor and the Office of the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia on the annual budget and spending plan for youth activities as described in section 129 of the Federal Act and employment and training activities as described in section 134 of the Federal Act; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Coordinate workforce development activities with economic development strategies and other employer linkages.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The WIC shall direct the WIA administrative entity to disburse funds received pursuant to sections 127 and 132 of the Federal Act to support the activities described in subsections (d) and (e) of this section, consistent with WIC policies.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The WIA administrative entity shall disburse the funds described in paragraph (1) of this subsection immediately upon the direction of the local workforce investment board; provided, that the direction does not violate a provision of the Federal Act or District law.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>The WIC may hire staff to assist it in carrying out its responsibilities, as described in subsections (f) and (h) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-150" type="History">July 18, 2000, D.C. Law 13-150, § 4, 47 DCR 4644</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1155(a), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 129(a), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 2012, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-263" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-263, § 2(b), 62 DCR 1518</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Establishment of a workforce intermediary pilot program, § <cite path="§2-219.04b">2-219.04b</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§32-751">32-751</cite> and § <cite path="§32-1651">32-1651</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “University of the District of Columbia as well as with any institution of higher education accredited by the Middle States Association of Colleges and Schools and located in the District to enhance” for “University of the District of Columbia to enhance” in par. (6), and added par. (9).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite>, in subsecs. (b)(4) and (7), substituted “Council of the District of Columbia” for “Council”; and validated a previously made technical correction by substituting “Council” for “Board”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added (c) and (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-263">D.C. Law 20-263</cite> rewrote (a); repealed (b); and added (e) through (j).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1155(a) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1155(a) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2012 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2012 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 2011 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle B of Title II of the act may be cited as the “Workforce Investment Council and Workforce Intermediary Grant-Making Authority Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
