<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1231.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“DOES” means the Department of Employment Services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Reasonable accommodation” means an accommodation that does not cause undue hardship in the operation of the employer's business that an employer can make for an employee whose ability to perform the functions of the employee's job are affected by pregnancy, childbirth, a related medical condition, or breastfeeding, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>More frequent or longer breaks;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Time off to recover from childbirth;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The acquisition or modification of equipment or seating;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>The temporary transfer to a less strenuous or hazardous position or other job restructuring such as providing light duty or a modified work schedule;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Having the employee refrain from heavy lifting;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Relocating the employee's work area; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>Providing private non-bathroom space for expressing breast milk.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Undue hardship” means any action that requires significant difficulty in the operation of the employer's business or significant expense on the behalf of the employer when considered in relation to factors such as the size of the business, its financial resources, and the nature and structure of its operation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-168">Mar. 3, 2015, D.C. Law 20-168, § 2, 61 DCR 11368</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annoGroup>
        <annotation>For temporary (225 days) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Protecting Pregnant Workers Fairness Temporary Amendment Act of 2016 <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-103"> D.C. Law 21-103</cite>, April 20, 2016, 63 DCR 3654, 20 DCSTAT 3147).</annotation>
      </annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Protecting Pregnant Workers Fairness Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-314, Feb. 18, 2016,  63 DCR 2199).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
