<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1539</num>
  <heading>Failure to secure payment of compensation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any employer required to secure the payment of compensation under this chapter who fails to secure such compensation shall be assessed a civil fine of not less than $1,000 and not more than $10,000; and in any case where such employer is a corporation, the president, secretary, and treasurer thereof shall be also severally liable to such fine as herein provided for the failure of such corporation to secure the payment of compensation; and such president, secretary, and treasurer shall be severally and personally liable, jointly with such corporation, for any compensation or other benefit which may accrue under the chapter in respect to any injury which may occur to any employee or such corporation while it shall so fail to secure the payment of compensation as required by § <cite path="§32-1534">32-1534</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any employer who knowingly transfers, sells, encumbers, assigns, or in any manner disposes of, conceals, secretes, or destroys any property belonging to such employer, after 1 of his employees has been injured within the purview of this chapter, and with intent to avoid the payment of compensation under this chapter to such employee or his dependents, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine of not less than $1,000 and not more than $10,000, or by imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or by both such fine and imprisonment; and in any case where such employer is a corporation, the president, secretary, and treasurer thereof shall be also severally liable to such penalty of imprisonment as well as jointly liable with such corporation for such fine.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall not affect any other liability of the employer under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-77" type="History">July 1, 1980, D.C. Law 3-77, § 40, 27 DCR 2503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-198" type="History">Mar. 6, 1991, D.C. Law 8-198, § 2(g), 37 DCR 6890</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-339.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§32-1501">32-1501</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
