<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1012</num>
  <heading>Civil actions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A civil action may be commenced according to § <cite path="§32-1308">32-1308</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, any employer who pays any employee less than the wage to which that employee is entitled under this subchapter shall be liable to that employee in the amount of the unpaid wages, statutory penalties, and an additional amount as liquidated damages equal to treble the amount of unpaid wages.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The court may award an amount of liquidated damages less than treble the amount of unpaid wages, but not less than the amount of unpaid wages. In any action commenced to recover unpaid wages or liquidated damages, the employer shall demonstrate to the satisfaction of the court that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The act or omission that gave rise to the action was in good faith;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>That the employer had reasonable grounds for the belief that the act or omission was not in violation of this subchapter; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>That the employer promptly paid the full amount of wages claimed to be owed to the employee.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>When the employer is a subcontractor alleged to have failed to pay an employee any wages earned, the subcontractor and the general contractor shall be jointly and severally liable to the subcontractor’s employees for violations of this subchapter. The subcontractor shall indemnify the general contractor for any wages, damages, interest, penalties, or attorneys’ fees owed by the general contractor as a result of the subcontractor’s violations of this subchapter, unless those violations were due to the general contractor’s lack of prompt payment in accordance with the terms of the contract between the general contractor and subcontractor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any agreement between an employer and employee in which the employee agrees to work for less than the wages to which the employee is entitled under this subchapter or any regulation issued under this subchapter shall be no defense to any action to recover unpaid wages or liquidated damages.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to supervise the payment of unpaid wages and liquidated damages owed to any employee under this subchapter or any regulation issued under this subchapter, and the agreement of any employee to accept this payment, shall upon full payment, constitute a waiver by the employee of any right the employee may have under subsection (a) of this section to any unpaid wages, and an additional amount as liquidated damages.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>When a temporary staffing firm employs an employee who performs work on behalf of or to the benefit of another employer pursuant to a temporary staffing arrangement or contract for services, both the temporary staffing firm and the employer shall be jointly and severally liable for violations of this subchapter to the employee and to the District. The District, the employee, or the employer’s representative shall notify the temporary staffing firm and employer of the violations at least 30 days before filing a claim for these violations. Unless otherwise agreed to by the parties, the temporary staffing firm shall indemnify the employer for any wages, damages, interest, penalties, or attorneys’ fees owed by the employer as a result of the temporary staffing firm’s violations of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-248" type="History" path="§13">Mar. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 9-248, § 13, 40 DCR 761</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 2063, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-157" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-157, § 3(i), 61 DCR 10157</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§32-1011">32-1011</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-220.11.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> substituted “wages and liquidated damages owed” for “wages owed” in (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</law-cite> rewrote this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</law-cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-240">D.C. Law 20-240</law-cite>, March 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1332).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 3(d) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-57">D.C. Law 21-57</law-cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,  62 DCR 15602).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</law-cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-57">D.C. Law 21-57</law-cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,  62 DCR 15602).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2063 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2063 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b)(4) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-544, Dec. 29, 2014,  62 DCR 243,  20 STAT 4458).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</law-cite>, § 7, see § 2(c) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-544, Dec. 29, 2014,  62 DCR 243,  20 STAT 4458).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-188, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14224).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</law-cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-188, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14224).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3(d) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-293, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1215).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</law-cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-293, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1215).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 2061 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that Subtitle G of Title II of the act may be cited as the “Wage Theft Prevention Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite>: Section 11001 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</law-cite>: Section 7 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014, and that the act shall apply to violations occurring after October 1, 2014.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
