<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-208</num>
  <heading>Work or vacation permit — Issue by Board of Education; contents; records of applicants.</heading>
  <text>The work or vacation permit required by this subchapter shall be issued by the Board of Education and shall state the name, sex, date, and place of birth, and place of residence of the minor, the grade last completed by said minor, and the kind of evidence of age accepted, and such other details as may be necessary for the identification of the minor. It shall certify that all the requirements for issuing a work or vacation permit under the provisions of this subchapter have been fulfilled and shall be signed by the person issuing it. It shall state the name and address of the employer for whom and the nature of the specific occupation in which the work permit authorizes the minor to be employed, and no permit shall be valid except for the employer so named and for the occupation so designated. It shall bear a number, shall show the date of its issue, and shall be signed by the minor for whom it is issued in the presence of the person issuing it, and shall be mailed or delivered to the employer. The Board shall maintain an office record for each applicant containing the minor’s name, sex, date and place of birth; evidence of age, residence, name and address of the employer; and nature of the specific occupation in which the minor is employed; the grade and school last attended by the minor; the employer’s statement of intention to employ; and the parent’s, guardian’s, or custodian’s written consent if such written consent is required.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 29, 1928, 45 Stat. 1000, ch. 908, § 9</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-68" type="History">renumbered as § 8 and amended June 15, 1976, D.C. Law 1-68, § 2(10), 23 DCR 516</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-2605">38-2605</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-508.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 36-209.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
