<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-931</num>
  <heading>Restriction on pre-employment marijuana testing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An employer may only test a prospective employee for marijuana use after a conditional offer of employment has been extended, unless otherwise required by law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Affect employee compliance with employer workplace drug policies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Require an employer to permit or accommodate the use, consumption, possession, transfer, display, transportation, sale, or growing of marijuana in the workplace or at any time during employment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Interfere with federal employment contracts; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Prevent the employer from denying a position based on a positive test for marijuana.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Employer” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§32-1101">32-1101</cite>(6).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Prospective employee” means any individual applying for employment with an employer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-14" type="History">July 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-14, § 2, 62 DCR 6870</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) addition of this section, see § 2 of the Prohibition of Pre-Employment Marijuana Testing Temporary Act of 2014   (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-250">D.C. Law 20-250</cite>, April 30, 2015,  62 DCR 1876).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2 of the Prohibition of Pre-Employment Marijuana Testing Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-525, Dec. 18, 2014,   61 DCR 13112, 20 STAT 4441).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2 of the Prohibition of Pre-Employment Marijuana Testing Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-31, Mar. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 4536).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
