<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>46-303.10</num>
  <heading>Duties of Mayor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, or the Mayor’s designee, is the state information agency under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The state information agency shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Compile and maintain a current list, including addresses, of the tribunals in the District which have jurisdiction under this chapter and any support enforcement agencies in the District and transmit a copy to the state information agency of every other state;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Maintain a register of the names and addresses of tribunals and support enforcement agencies received from other states;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Forward to the appropriate tribunal in the place in the District in which the obligee who is an individual or the obligor resides, or in which the obligor’s property is believed to be located, all documents concerning a proceeding under this chapter received from an initiating tribunal or the state information agency of the initiating state; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Obtain information concerning the location of the obligor and the obligor’s property within the District not exempt from execution by such means as postal verification and federal or state locator services, examination of telephone directories, requests for the obligor’s address from employers, and examination of governmental records, including, to the extent not prohibited by other law, those relating to real property, vital statistics, law enforcement, taxation, motor vehicles, driver’s licenses, and social security.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-81">Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 309, 42 DCR 6748</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-137">redesignated § 310, June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(c)(10), 53 DCR 3634</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 30-343.9.</annotation>
      <annotation>2001 Ed., § <cite root="46-303.09">46-303.09</cite></annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-137">D.C. Law 16-137</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-137">D.C. Law 16-137</cite> provided: “This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Former § <cite root="46-303.10">46-303.10</cite> has been recodified as § <cite root="46-303.11">46-303.11</cite> by <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-137">D.C. Law 16-137</cite>, § 2(c)(10).</text>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 310 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act).</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
