<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>46-303.17</num>
  <heading>Communications between tribunals.</heading>
  <text>A tribunal of the District may communicate with a tribunal of another state or foreign country or political subdivision in a record, or by telephone or other means, to obtain information concerning the laws, the legal effect of a judgment, decree, or order of that tribunal, and the status of a proceeding in the other state or foreign country or political subdivision. A tribunal of the District may furnish similar information by similar means to a tribunal of another state or foreign country or political subdivision.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-81">Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 316, 42 DCR 6748</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-137">redesignated § 317, June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(c)(17), 53 DCR 3634</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="46-302.10">46-302.10</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 30-343.16.</annotation>
      <annotation>2001 Ed., § <cite root="46-303.16">46-303.16</cite></annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-137">D.C. Law 16-137</cite> rewrote section, which had read as follows: “§ <cite root="46-303.16">46-303.16</cite>. Communications between tribunals. ”A tribunal of the District may communicate with a tribunal of another state in writing, or by telephone or other means, to obtain information concerning the laws of that state, the legal effect of a judgment, decree, or order of that tribunal, and the status of a proceeding in the other state. A tribunal of the District may furnish similar information by similar means to a tribunal of another state.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-137">D.C. Law 16-137</cite> provided: “This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Former § <cite root="46-303.17">46-303.17</cite> has been recodified as § <cite root="46-303.18">46-303.18</cite> by <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-137">D.C. Law 16-137</cite>, § 2(c)(18).</text>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 317 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act).</text>
      <text>This section is based upon § 317 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (1996 Act).</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
