<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>46-210</num>
  <heading>Objections to withholding.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An obligor may object to a withholding commenced pursuant to § <cite path="§46-207.01">46-207.01</cite> by filing a motion to quash the withholding with the Court within 15 days after the earlier of the date the notice of withholding was mailed or the date the first payment was withheld.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Court shall resolve any motion to quash the withholding within 90 days after service of the motion on the opposing party, unless, upon a showing of good cause, the Court finds that additional time is needed to resolve the motion.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The only ground for an objection to a withholding is a mistake of fact, which is defined as:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A mistake in the amount of arrears;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A mistake in the identity of the obligor; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A mistake in the amount of the withholding that causes the amount withheld to exceed the limits specified in § <cite path="§46-208">46-208</cite> or section 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act, approved May 29, 1968 (82 Stat. 163; 15 U.S.C.§ 1673(b)).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Payment of arrearages after the date of issuance of a notice of withholding to the obligor pursuant to § <cite path="§46-209">46-209</cite> is not a defense to the withholding.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Court shall deny the motion in all cases except where the identity of the obligor is mistaken or, if applicable, where arrearages have never equaled one month of support payments, and shall notify the obligor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If the Court determines that the amount to be withheld exceeds the limits of § <cite path="§46-208">46-208</cite> or section 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act [15 U.S.C. § 1673(b)], the Court shall serve or direct the IV-D agency to serve an order to withhold on the holder that complies with those limits.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Court shall deny any request to stay the withholding pending resolution of an objection or appeal.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-166" type="History" path="§11">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-166, § 11, 33 DCR 6710</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-269" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-269, § 108(j), 48 DCR 1270</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 3403(h), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-100" type="History">May 12, 2006, D.C. Law 16-100, § 3(j), 53 DCR 1886</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§46-209">46-209</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 30-510.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-269">D.C. Law 13-269</cite> rewrote the section which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) The Clerk shall issue the notice of withholding pursuant to § <cite path="§46-211">46-211</cite> unless the obligor files an objection to contest the withholding pursuant to this section within 15 days after the notice of intent to withhold is mailed.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b) The notice to the holder pursuant to § <cite path="§46-211">46-211</cite> shall be sent within 45 days of the date that the notice of intent to withhold was sent to the obligor pursuant to subsection (a) and this subsection. Any objections raised by the obligor shall be resolved within 45 days from the date that the notice of intent to withhold was sent.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) The only grounds for objection by an obligor are mistakes of fact which are defined as:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) The amount of arrears;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) The identity of the obligor; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) Whether the amount to be withheld as a periodic payment exceeds the limits of  15 U.S.C. § 1673(b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(d) Payment of arrearages after the date of the application to the Clerk of the Court for the issuance of a notice of intent to withhold pursuant to subsection (b) of this section is not a defense to the withholding.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(e)(1) Objections filed to contest the withholding shall be filed with the Court.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) The Court shall order withholding in all cases except where the identity of the obligor is mistaken or where arrearages have never equaled 30 days of support payments, and shall notify the obligor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) The notice of withholding shall include the time period within which the withholding shall begin, and shall contain the information given to the holder pursuant to § <cite path="§46-211">46-211</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(4) The Court shall not grant any request to stay implementation of withholding pending further objections or appeal.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(5) If the Court determines that the amount to be withheld as a periodic payment exceeds the limits of  15 U.S.C. § 1673(b), then the Court shall issue a notice of withholding to the holder that complies with those limits.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(f) Notice to an obligor sent pursuant to § <cite path="§46-222">46-222</cite> shall comply with this section and provisions in § <cite path="§46-222">46-222</cite>(a)(3).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> rewrote subsec. (d); and, in par. (5) of subsec. (e), deleted “direct the Collection and Disbursement Unit to” following “The court shall”. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) had read as follows: “(d) Payment of arrearages after the date of the application to the Collection and Disbursement Unit for the issuance of a notice of withholding pursuant to subsection (b) of this section is not a defense to the withholding.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-100">D.C. Law 16-100</cite> rewrote the section, which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) For support orders subject to immediate or initiated withholding pursuant to § <cite path="§46-207">46-207</cite>(a-1) or § <cite path="§46-208">46-208</cite>(c), the obligor may contest the withholding by filing with the Court a motion to quash the withholding within 15 days of the date the notice of withholding is mailed. Upon the filing of a motion to quash the withholding, the Collection and Disbursement Unit shall hold in escrow all monies collected pursuant to the withholding until the motion is resolved or the Court orders the release of the escrow.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b) The Court shall resolve any motion to quash the withholding within 90 days of the date the notice of withholding was mailed, unless, upon a showing of good cause, the Court finds that additional time is needed to resolve the motion. If the Court finds that additional time is needed to resolve the motion, the Court may release to the obligee any funds held in escrow pursuant to the withholding and order the release of all further payments to the obligee pending further proceedings.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) The only grounds for objection by an obligor are mistakes of fact which are defined as:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) The amount of arrears;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) The identity of the obligor; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) Whether the amount to be withheld as a periodic payment exceeds the limits of  15 U.S.C. § 1673(b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(d) Payment of arrearages after the date of the issuance of a notice of withholding pursuant to § <cite path="§46-209">46-209</cite> is not a defense to the withholding.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(e)(1) Motions filed to contest the withholding shall be filed with the Court.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) The Court shall deny the motion in all cases except where the identity of the obligor is mistaken or where arrearages have never equaled one month of support payments, and shall notify the obligor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) Repealed.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(4) The Court shall not grant any request to stay implementation of withholding or hold funds in escrow pending further objections or appeal.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(5) If the Court determines that the amount to be withheld as a periodic payment exceeds the limits of  15 U.S.C. § 1673(b), the Court shall issue a notice to withhold to the holder that complies with those limits.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(f) Repealed.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 7(j) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-210">D.C. Law 12-210</cite>, April 13, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 3832).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 107(j) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-57">D.C. Law 13-57</cite>, March 7, 2000, law notification  47 DCR 1979).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 107(j) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-207">D.C. Law 13-207</cite>, March 31, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 3238).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(k) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-42">D.C. Law 16-42</cite> rewrote section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 11. Objections to withholding.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) An obligor may object to a withholding commenced pursuant to section 8a by filing a motion to quash the withholding with the Court within 15 days after the earlier of the date the notice of withholding was mailed or the date the first payment was withheld.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Court shall resolve any motion to quash the withholding within 90 days after service of the motion on the opposing party, unless, upon a showing of good cause, the Court finds that additional time is needed to resolve the motion.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The only ground for an objection to a withholding is a mistake of fact, which is defined as:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) A mistake in the amount of arrears;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) A mistake in the identity of the obligor; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) A mistake in the amount of the withholding that causes the amount withheld to exceed the limits specified in section 9 or section 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act, approved May 29, 1968 (82 Stat. 163;  15 U.S.C. § 1673(b)).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) Payment of arrearages after the date of issuance of a notice of withholding to the obligor pursuant to section 10 is not a defense to the withholding.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The Court shall deny the motion in all cases except where the identity of the obligor is mistaken or, if applicable, where arrearages have never equaled one month of support payments, and shall notify the obligor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(f) If the Court determines that the amount to be withheld exceeds the limits of section 9 or section 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act, the Court shall serve or direct the IV-D agency to serve an order to withhold on the holder that complies with those limits.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(g) The Court shall deny any request to stay the withholding pending resolution of an objection or appeal.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-42">D.C. Law 16-42</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 7(j) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Second Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-309, March 23, 1998,  45 DCR 1923), § 7(j) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Second Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-439, August 12, 1998,  45 DCR 6110), § 7(j) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-503, October 27, 1998,  45 DCR 8495), and § 7(j) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-600, January 20, 1999,  46 DCR 1239).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 107(j) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-126, August 4, 1999,  46 DCR 6606).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 107(j) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-177, November 2, 1999,  46 DCR 9678).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 107(j) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-241, January 11, 2000,  47 DCR 581).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 107(j) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-446, November 7, 2000,  47 DCR 9213).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 108(j) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-5, February 13, 2001,  48 DCR 2440).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3403(h) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3403(h) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(k) of Income Withholding Transfer and Revision Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-167, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7648).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(k) of Income Withholding Transfer and Revision Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-200, November 17, 2005,  52 DCR 10490).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
