<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>46-251.04</num>
  <heading>Duties of the employer.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a medical support notice, an employer shall, within 20 business days after the date of the medical support notice:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Determine whether health insurance coverage is available to the child included in the medical support notice based on the parent’s employment status;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Complete and return to the IV-D agency the applicable portion of the medical support notice if health insurance coverage is unavailable to the child based on the parent’s employment status; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Send the medical support notice, excluding the severable employer withholding notice, to each health insurer that provides health insurance coverage for which the child may be eligible, if health insurance coverage is available to the child based on the parent’s employment status.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the employer determines that the child cannot be enrolled in health insurance coverage because the employee contributions exceed the amount that may be withheld from the parent’s earnings due to federal or District of Columbia withholding limitations or prioritizations, the employer shall promptly complete and send to the IV-D agency the applicable portion of the medical support notice.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the employer receives notice from a health insurer that the parent is subject to a waiting period that expires more than 90 days from the health insurer’s receipt of the medical support notice, or that has a duration determined by a measure other than the passage of time, the employer shall inform the health insurer, when the parent is eligible to enroll in health insurance coverage, that the parent is eligible and that the medical support notice requires the enrollment of the child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Within 10 days after an employer receives notice that a parent subject to a medical support notice will terminate employment, or within 10 days after the termination, whichever occurs earlier, the employer shall notify the IV-D agency of the termination and provide the IV-D agency with the last known address and the name and address of the parent’s new employer, if known.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-130">Mar. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-130, § 104, 51 DCR 1615</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-307.42">1-307.42</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 104 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-238">D.C. Law 14-238</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2751).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 104 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-84">D.C. Law 15-84</cite>, March 10, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 3376).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 104 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-485, October 3, 2002,  49 DCR 9631).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 104 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-600, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 664).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 104 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-208, October 24, 2003,  50 DCR 9856).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 104 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-330, January 28, 2004,  51 DCR 1603).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
