<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>46-219</num>
  <heading>No discrimination in employment for withholding.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No employer shall discharge, refuse to employ, take disciplinary action, or otherwise discriminate against any obligor for the reason that a party has subjected or attempted to subject unpaid earnings of the obligor to withholding or like proceedings for the purposes of paying support.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>There shall be a rebuttable presumption that any employer who engages in conduct described in subsection (a) of this section, within 90 days from the date of receipt of a notice or order to withhold, is in violation of this subchapter and may be subject to the sanctions in subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any employer who engages in conduct described in subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of up to $10,000.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any civil penalty obtained under subsection (c) of this section shall be used to offset the obligor’s duty of support.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-166" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-166, § 20, 33 DCR 6710</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-100" type="History">May 12, 2006, D.C. Law 16-100, § 3(s), 53 DCR 1886</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§46-211">46-211</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 30-519.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-100">D.C. Law 16-100</cite>, in subsec. (a), deleted “employee or” preceding “obligor” and substituted “purposes of paying” for “purposes of paying child”; in subsec. (b), substituted “a notice or order to withhold,” for “the notice to the holder pursuant to § <cite path="§46-211">46-211</cite>,”; and in subsec. (d), substituted “duty of” for “duty of child”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(t) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-42">D.C. Law 16-42</cite>, in subsec. (a), deleted “employee or”, and deleted “child” after “purposes of paying”; in subsec. (b), substituted “a notice or order to withhold,” for “the notice to the holder pursuant to section 12,”; and in subsec. (d) deleted “child” after “duty of”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-42">D.C. Law 16-42</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(t) of Income Withholding Transfer and Revision Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-167, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7648).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(t) of Income Withholding Transfer and Revision Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-200, November 17, 2005,  52 DCR 10490).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
