<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>46-251.02</num>
  <heading>Use of medical support notice; IV-D agency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In cases being enforced pursuant to Part D of Title IV of the Social Security Act, approved January 4, 1975 (88 Stat. 2351; 42 U.S.C. § 651 et seq.), where a parent is required by a support order to provide health insurance coverage for a child, which is available through the parent’s employer, the IV-D agency may apply for the enrollment of the child in the health insurance coverage by submitting a medical support notice to the employer. The IV-D agency shall, where appropriate, submit a medical support notice to the employer when the support order requires the noncustodial parent to provide health insurance coverage for the child and the employer is known to the IV-D agency, unless the support order directs enrollment of the child in alternative coverage.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Where a noncustodial parent is a newly hired employee entered in the District of Columbia Directory of New Hires pursuant to § <cite path="§46-226.06">46-226.06</cite>, and the support order requires the noncustodial parent to provide health insurance coverage for a child, the IV-D agency shall submit the medical support notice to the employer within 2 business days after the entry of the employee in the directory.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The IV-D agency shall promptly notify an employer that has received a medical support notice when there is no longer a support order in effect for which the IV-D agency is responsible that requires a parent to provide health insurance coverage for a child.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-130" type="History" path="§102">Mar. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-130, § 102, 51 DCR 1615</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 102 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-330, January 28, 2004,  51 DCR 1603).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 102 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-208, October 24, 2003,  50 DCR 9856).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 102 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-600, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 664).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 102 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-485, October 3, 2002,  49 DCR 9631).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 102 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-84">D.C. Law 15-84</cite>, March 10, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 3376).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 102 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-238">D.C. Law 14-238</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2751).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-307.42">1-307.42</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
