<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>46-251.06</num>
  <heading>Selection of a health insurance coverage option.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of notice from a health insurer that more than one health insurance coverage option is available for a child included in a medical support notice, the IV-D agency shall select an available option in consultation with the child’s custodian.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In selecting an option in consultation with the child’s custodian pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the IV-D agency shall consider, at a minimum, the cost, comprehensiveness, and accessibility of the health insurance coverage. For the purposes of this section, health insurance coverage shall be considered accessible if, based on the work history of the parent providing the coverage, it will be available for at least one year, and if the child lives within the geographic area covered by the plan or within 30 minutes or 30 miles of primary care services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The IV-D agency shall notify the health insurer of its selection promptly after the health insurer provides the IV-D agency with the information required under § <cite path="§46-251.05">46-251.05</cite>(d).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-130" type="History">Mar. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-130, § 106, 51 DCR 1615</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-128" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-128, § 3(b), 55 DCR 1525</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-128">D.C. Law 17-128</cite> rewrote subsec. (b), which had read as follows: “(b) In selecting an option in consultation with the child’s custodian pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the IV-D agency shall consider, at a minimum, the cost, comprehensiveness, accessibility, and continuing availability of the health insurance coverage.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 106 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-238">D.C. Law 14-238</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2751).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 106 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-84">D.C. Law 15-84</cite>, March 10, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 3376).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 106 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-485, October 3, 2002,  49 DCR 9631).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 106 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-600, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 664).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 106 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-208, October 24, 2003,  50 DCR 9856).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 106 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-330, January 28, 2004,  51 DCR 1603).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
