<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>46-224.02</num>
  <heading>Parent locator service.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The IV-D agency is established as the District’s centralized Parent Locator Service to locate parents of children in need of support.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An officer or employee of the District shall cooperate with the IV-D agency to determine the location of a parent who is not supporting his or her child. The officer or employee shall provide any pertinent information that relates to the location, income, or property of a parent, notwithstanding any District statute, ordinance, or rule that makes the information confidential.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A company, corporation, partnership, association, union, organization, or entity doing business in the District shall provide the IV-D agency with the following available information, if the IV-D agency certifies that the information shall be used to locate a parent of a child in need of support and that the information obtained will be treated as confidential by the IV-D agency unless the parent’s name is published or reported to a consumer credit reporting agency pursuant to § <cite path="§46-225">46-225</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Full name of the parent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Name and address of the parent’s employer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Social security number of the parent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Date of birth of the parent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Home address of the parent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Amount of wages earned by the parent; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Number of dependents claimed by the parent on state and federal income withholding forms.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person may not knowingly refuse to give the IV-D agency information that will assist the IV-D agency in locating the parent of a child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A person who knowingly refuses to provide information or provides false information that has been requested pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, upon conviction, shall be imprisoned for not more than 3 months, fined not more than $1,000, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-166" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-166, § 25b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-150" type="History">as added July 25, 1990, D.C. Law 8-150, § 4(e), 37 DCR 3720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-68" type="History">Feb. 5, 1994, D.C. Law 10-68, § 28(b), 40 DCR 6311</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-100" type="History">May 12, 2006, D.C. Law 16-100, § 3(y), 53 DCR 1886</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 30-524.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-100">D.C. Law 16-100</law-cite> rewrote the section, which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) A Parent Locator Division (’Division’) is established within the Office of Paternity and Child Support Enforcement of the Department of Human Services to maintain a parent locator service to locate a parent of a child in need of child support.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b) Any officer or employee of the District shall cooperate with the Division to determine the location of a parent who is not supporting his or her child. The officer or employee shall provide any pertinent information that relates to the location, income, or property of a parent, notwithstanding any District statute, ordinance, or rule that makes the information confidential.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) Any company, corporation, partnership, association, union, or organization doing business in the District shall provide the Division with the following available information, if the Division certifies that the information shall be used to locate a parent of a child in need of support and that the information obtained will be treated as confidential by the Division unless the parent’s name is published for child support arrearages pursuant to § <cite path="§46-225">46-225</cite>:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) Full name of parent;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) Name and address of parent’s employer;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) Social security number of parent;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(4) Date of birth of parent;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(5) Home address of parent;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(6) Amount of wages earned by parent; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(7) Number of dependents claimed by parent on state and federal income withholding forms.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(d) A person may not knowingly refuse to give the parent locator service information that will assist the parent locator service in locating the parent of a child.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(e) Any person who knowingly refuses to provide information or provides false information that has been requested pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, upon conviction, shall be imprisoned for not more than 3 months, fined not more than $1,000, or both.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(z) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-42">D.C. Law 16-42</law-cite> rewrote section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 25b. Parent locator service.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The IV-D agency is established as the District’s centralized Parent Locator Service to locate parents of children in need of support.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) An officer or employee of the District shall cooperate with the IV-D agency to determine the location of a parent who is not supporting his or her child. The officer or employee shall provide any pertinent information that relates to the location, income, or property of a parent, notwithstanding any District statute, ordinance, or rule that makes the information confidential.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) A company, corporation, partnership, association, union, organization, or entity doing business in the District shall provide the IV-D agency with the following available information, if the IV-D agency certifies that the information shall be used to locate a parent of a child in need of support and that the information obtained will be treated as confidential by the IV-D agency unless the parent’s name is published or reported to a consumer credit reporting agency pursuant to section 26:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Full name of the parent;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Name and address of the parent’s employer;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Social security number of the parent;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) Date of birth of the parent;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) Home address of the parent;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) Amount of wages earned by the parent; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) Number of dependents claimed by the parent on state and federal income withholding forms.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) A person may not knowingly refuse to give the IV-D agency information that will assist the IV-D agency in locating the parent of a child.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) A person who knowingly refuses to provide information or provides false information that has been requested pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, upon conviction, shall be imprisoned for not more than 3 months, fined not more than $1,000, or both.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-42">D.C. Law 16-42</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(z) of Income Withholding Transfer and Revision Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-167, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7648).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(z) of Income Withholding Transfer and Revision Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-200, November 17, 2005,  52 DCR 10490).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
