<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>46-212</num>
  <heading>Holder’s duty to withhold and make payments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a holder that receives a notice or order to withhold issued in accordance with this subchapter shall withhold the specified amount and make payment to the Collection and Disbursement Unit no later than 7 business days after the date the amount would have been paid or credited to the obligor. The holder shall begin withholding no later than the first pay period occurring 10 days after the date the notice or order to withhold was issued.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a holder receives notice of any legal proceeding challenging the withholding or the judgment or order of support on which it is based, the holder shall continue to withhold and submit the payments to the Collection and Disbursement Unit until the holder receives written notice from the Court or the IV-D agency directing the holder to cease the withholding.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any payment made by a holder in conformity with this section shall discharge the liability of the holder to the obligor to the extent of the payment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A holder upon whom a notice or order to withhold has been served may deduct and retain from the obligor’s earnings or other income an additional $2 for each deduction made in accordance with the notice or order to withhold. Where the total amount to be withheld, together with a fee, exceeds the limitations set forth in section 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act, approved May 29, 1968 (82 Stat. 163; 15 U.S.C. § 1673(b)), the holder shall reduce the amount of the withholding to conform with these limitations, but the amount of the fee shall not be reduced by reason of the limitations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, if a holder receives a notice or order to withhold issued by another state, the holder shall apply the income withholding law of the state of the obligor’s principal place of employment in determining:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The holder’s fee for processing the notice or order to withhold;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The maximum amount permitted to be withheld from the obligor’s income;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The time periods within which the holder must implement the withholding and forward the support payment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The priorities for withholding and allocating income withheld for multiple support obligees; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Any withholding terms or conditions not specified in the notice or order to withhold.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-166" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-166, § 13, 33 DCR 6710</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-269" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-269, § 108(l), 48 DCR 1270</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 3403(j), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-100" type="History">May 12, 2006, D.C. Law 16-100, § 3(l), 53 DCR 1886</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§46-211">46-211</cite> and § <cite path="§46-251.08">46-251.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 30-512.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-269">D.C. Law 13-269</cite> rewrote subsec. (a); substituted “Collection and Disbursement Unit” for “Court” in subsec. (b); and added subsec. (e). Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) A holder required to withhold earnings or other income shall withhold and make payment no later than the first pay period that occurs after 14 days following the date the notice was mailed or no later than the date the applicable income becomes due or otherwise available to the obligor. Thereafter, the holder shall send the required withholding to the Court on the same date the obligor is compensated.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “Court” for “Collection and Disbursement Unit”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-100">D.C. Law 16-100</cite> rewrote the section, which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a holder required to withhold income shall withhold and make payment to the Collection and Disbursement Unit no later than 7 business days after the date the amount would have been paid or credited to the obligor. Thereafter, the holder shall send the required withholding to the Collection and Disbursement Unit on the same date that the obligor is compensated.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b) When the holder has received written notice of any legal proceedings challenging the withholding or the judgment or order of support on which it is based, the holder shall continue to withhold the payments from the obligor until receipt of a notice from the Court informing the holder to cease the withholding.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) Any payment made by a holder in conformity with this section shall discharge the liability of the holder to the obligor to the extent of the payment.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(d) The holder, upon whom a notice of withholding as provided by § <cite path="§46-211">46-211</cite> is served, may deduct and retain from the person’s earnings or other income an additional $2 for each deduction made in accordance with the notice. Where the total amount to be withheld, together with a fee, exceeds the limitations set forth in  15 U.S.C. § 1673(b), the amount of withholding shall be reduced by the holder to conform with the limitations, but the amount of the fee shall not be reduced by reason of the limitations.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(e) Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, if an employer receives an income withholding order issued by another state, the employer shall apply the income withholding law of the state of the obligor’s principal place of employment in determining:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) The employer’s fee for processing an income withholding order;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) The maximum amount permitted to be withheld from the obligor’s income;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) The time periods within which the employer must implement the income withholding order and forward the support payment;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(4) The priorities for withholding and allocating income withheld for multiple support obligees; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(5) Any withholding terms or conditions not specified in the order.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 7(l) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-210">D.C. Law 12-210</cite>, April 13, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 3832).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 107(l) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-57">D.C. Law 13-57</cite>, March 7, 2000, law notification  47 DCR 1979).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 107(l) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-207">D.C. Law 13-207</cite>, March 31, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 3238).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(m) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-42">D.C. Law 16-42</cite> rewrote section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 13. Holder’s duty to withhold and make payments.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a holder that receives a notice or order to withhold issued in accordance with this act shall withhold the specified amount and make payment to the Collection and Disbursement Unit no later than 7 business days after the date the amount would have been paid or credited to the obligor. The holder shall begin withholding no later than the first pay period occurring 10 days after the date the notice or order to withhold was issued.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) If a holder receives notice of any legal proceeding challenging the withholding or the judgment or order of support on which it is based, the holder shall continue to withhold and submit the payments to the Collection and Disbursement Unit until the holder receives written notice from the Court or the IV-D agency directing the holder to cease the withholding.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Any payment made by a holder in conformity with this section shall discharge the liability of the holder to the obligor to the extent of the payment.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) A holder upon whom a notice or order to withhold has been served may deduct and retain from the obligor’s earnings or other income an additional $ 2 for each deduction made in accordance with the notice or order to withhold. Where the total amount to be withheld, together with a fee, exceeds the limitations set forth in section 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act, approved May 29, 1968 (82 Stat. 163;  15 U.S.C. § 1673(b)), the holder shall reduce the amount of the withholding to conform with these limitations, but the amount of the fee shall not be reduced by reason of the limitations.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) Notwithstanding any other provision of this act, if a holder receives a notice or order to withhold issued by another state, the holder shall apply the income withholding law of the state of the obligor’s principal place of employment in determining:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) The holder’s fee for processing the notice or order to withhold;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The maximum amount permitted to be withheld from the obligor’s income;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The time periods within which the holder must implement the withholding and forward the support payment;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) The priorities for withholding and allocating income withheld for multiple support obligees; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) Any withholding terms or conditions not specified in the notice or order to withhold.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-42">D.C. Law 16-42</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 7(i) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-222, December 23, 1997,  44 DCR 114).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 7(l) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Second Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-309, March 20, 1998,  45 DCR 1923), § 7(l) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Second Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-439, August 12, 1998,  45 DCR 6110), § 7(l) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-503, October 27, 1998,  45 DCR 8495), and § 7(l) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-600, January</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
