<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>46-251.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Custodian” means the parent, relative, guardian, or other person with whom the dependent child resides.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Health insurance coverage” means benefits consisting of amounts paid for the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease, or amounts paid for the purpose of affecting any structure or function of the body (provided directly, through insurance or reimbursement, or otherwise, and includes items and services) under any hospital or medical service policy or certificate, hospital, or medical service plan contract, or health maintenance organization contract offered by a health insurer that is available to either parent, under which medical services could be provided to a dependent child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Health insurer” means any person that provides one or more health benefit plans or insurance in the District of Columbia, including a group health plan, as defined in section 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved April 7, 1986 (100 Stat. 231; 29 U.S.C. § 1167(1)), a plan administrator as defined in section 3(16) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved September 2, 1974 (88 Stat. 835; 29 U.S.C. § 1002(16)), an insurer, a hospital and medical service corporation, a health maintenance organization, a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or any other person providing a plan of health insurance subject to the authority of the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation [Commissioner of Insurance, Securities, and Banking].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“IV-D agency” means the organizational unit of the District of Columbia government, its contractors or assignees, or a successor organizational unit, that is responsible for administering or supervising the administration of the District of Columbia’s State Plan under Part D of Title IV of the Social Security Act, approved January 4, 1975 (88 Stat. 2351; 42 U.S.C. § 651 et seq.), pertaining to parent locator services, paternity establishment, and the establishment, modification, and enforcement of support orders.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Medical support notice” means a notice issued by the IV-D agency that meets the requirements of a National Medical Support Notice promulgated under section 401(b) of the Child Support Performance and Incentive Act of 1998, approved July 16, 1998 (112 Stat. 660; 42 U.S.C. § 651 note).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Support order” means a judgment, decree, or order, whether temporary or final, or subject to modification, issued by a court or an administrative agency of competent jurisdiction, for the support and maintenance of a child, including a child who has attained the age of majority under the law of the issuing state, or a child and the parent with whom the child is living, which provides for monetary support, health care, arrearages, or reimbursement, and which may include related costs and fees, interest and penalties, income withholding, attorneys’ fees, and other relief.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-130" type="History">Mar. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-130, § 101, 51 DCR 1615</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-128" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-128, § 3(a), 55 DCR 1525</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-128">D.C. Law 17-128</cite>, in par. (2), substituted “health insurer that is available to either parent, under which medical services could be provided to a dependent child” for “health insurer”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 101 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-238">D.C. Law 14-238</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2751).</text>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 101 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-84">D.C. Law 15-84</cite>, March 10, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 3376).</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 101 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-485, October 3, 2002,  49 DCR 9631).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 101 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-600, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 664).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 101 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-208, October 24, 2003,  50 DCR 9856).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 101 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-330, January 28, 2004,  51 DCR 1603).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
