<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>46-251.07</num>
  <heading>Withholding for health insurance coverage.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When an employer receives notice from a health insurer that a child has been enrolled in health insurance coverage pursuant to a medical support notice or a support order requiring a parent to provide health insurance coverage, the employer shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Withhold from the employee’s earnings the employee contributions required to effectuate health insurance coverage for the child in each plan in which the child is enrolled;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Send the amount withheld to the applicable health insurer within 7 business days after the date the amount would have been next paid or credited to the employee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Continue to withhold premiums for health insurance coverage from the employee’s earnings on a regular and consistent basis and pay the premiums to the health insurer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Send each additional payment to the health insurer on the same date that the employee is compensated.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Withholding for health insurance coverage shall not exceed the limitations set forth in § 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act, approved May 29, 1968 (82 Stat. 163; 15 U.S.C. § 1673(b)).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this subchapter shall alter the obligation of an obligor, obligee, employer, or other person or entity to comply with the provisions for the withholding of earnings or other income stated in subchapter I of Chapter 2 of this title.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-130" type="History" path="§107">Mar. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-130, § 107, 51 DCR 1615</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-307.42">1-307.42</cite>, § <cite path="§16-911">16-911</cite>, and § <cite path="§46-251.03">46-251.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 107 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-238">D.C. Law 14-238</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2751).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 107 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-84">D.C. Law 15-84</cite>, March 10, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 3376).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 107 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-485, October 3, 2002,  49 DCR 9631).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 107 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-600, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 664).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 107 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-208, October 24, 2003,  50 DCR 9856).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 107 of Medical Support Establishment and Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-330, January 28, 2004,  51 DCR 1603).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
