<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>46-353.10</num>
  <heading>Duties of Office of the Attorney General as state information agency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Office of the Attorney General is the state information agency under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The state information agency shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Compile and maintain a current list, including addresses, of the tribunals in the District which have jurisdiction under this chapter and any support enforcement agencies in the District and transmit a copy to the state information agency of every other state;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Maintain a register of names and addresses of tribunals and support enforcement agencies received from other states;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Forward to the appropriate tribunal in the District all documents concerning a proceeding under this chapter received from another state or a foreign country; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Obtain information concerning the location of the obligor and the obligor’s property within the District not exempt from execution, by such means as postal verification and federal or state locator services, examination of telephone directories, requests for the obligor’s address from employers, and examination of governmental records, including, to the extent not prohibited by other law, those relating to real property, vital statistics, law enforcement, taxation, motor vehicles, driver’s licenses, and social security.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-73" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-73, § 310, 63 DCR 222</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
