<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>46-357.04</num>
  <heading>Initiation by Office of the Attorney General of support proceeding under Convention.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In a support proceeding under this subchapter, the Office of the Attorney General shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Transmit and receive applications; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Initiate or facilitate the institution of a proceeding regarding an application in a tribunal of the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The following support proceedings are available to an obligee under the Convention:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Recognition or recognition and enforcement of a foreign support order;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Enforcement of a support order issued or recognized in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Establishment of a support order if there is no existing order, including, if necessary, determination of parentage of a child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Establishment of a support order if recognition of a foreign support order is refused under ยง <cite path="ยง46-357.08">46-357.08</cite>(b)(2), (4), or (9);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Modification of a support order of a tribunal of the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Modification of a support order of a tribunal of another state or a foreign country.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The following support proceedings are available under the Convention to an obligor against which there is an existing support order:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Recognition of an order suspending or limiting enforcement of an existing support order of a tribunal of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Modification of a support order of a tribunal of the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Modification of a support order of a tribunal of another state or a foreign country.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A tribunal of the District may not require security, bond, or deposit, however described, to guarantee the payment of costs and expenses in proceedings under the Convention.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-73" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-73, ยง 704, 63 DCR 222</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
