<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>46-353.07</num>
  <heading>Duties of support enforcement agency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In a proceeding under this chapter, a support enforcement agency of the District, upon request:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Shall provide services to a petitioner residing in a state;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shall provide services to a petitioner requesting services through a central authority of a foreign country as described in § <cite path="§46-351.02">46-351.02</cite>(6)(A) or (D); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>May provide services to a petitioner who is an individual not residing in a state.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A support enforcement agency of the District that is providing services to the petitioner shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Take all steps necessary to enable an appropriate tribunal of the District, another state, or a foreign country to obtain jurisdiction over the respondent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Request an appropriate tribunal to set a date, time, and place for a hearing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Make a reasonable effort to obtain all relevant information, including information as to income and property of the parties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Within 2 days, exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, after receipt of notice in a record from an initiating, responding, or registering tribunal, send a copy of the notice to the petitioner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Within 2 days, exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, after receipt of communication in a record from the respondent or the respondent’s attorney, send a copy of the communication to the petitioner; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Notify the petitioner if jurisdiction over the respondent cannot be obtained.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A support enforcement agency of the District that requests registration of a child-support order in the District for enforcement or for modification shall make reasonable efforts:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To ensure that the order to be registered is the controlling order; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If 2 or more child-support orders exist and the identity of the controlling order has not been determined, to ensure that a request for such a determination is made in a tribunal having jurisdiction to do so.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A support enforcement agency of the District that requests registration and enforcement of a support order, arrears, or judgment stated in a foreign currency shall convert the amounts stated in the foreign currency into the equivalent amounts in dollars under the applicable official or market exchange rate as publicly reported.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A support enforcement agency of the District shall issue or request a tribunal of the District to issue a child-support order and an income-withholding order that redirect payment of current support, arrears, and interest if requested to do so by a support enforcement agency of another state pursuant to § <cite path="§46-353.19">46-353.19</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>This chapter does not create or negate a relationship of attorney and client or other fiduciary relationship between a support enforcement agency or the attorney for the agency and the individual being assisted by the agency.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-73" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-73, § 307, 63 DCR 222</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
