<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>46-354.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment of support order.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a support order entitled to recognition under this chapter has not been issued, a responding tribunal of the District with personal jurisdiction over the parties may issue a support order if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The individual seeking the order resides outside the District; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The support enforcement agency seeking the order is located outside the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The tribunal may issue a temporary child-support order if the tribunal determines that such an order is appropriate and the individual ordered to pay is:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A presumed father of the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Petitioning to have his paternity adjudicated;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Identified as the father of the child through genetic testing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An alleged father who has declined to submit to genetic testing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Shown by clear and convincing evidence to be the father of the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>An acknowledged father as provided by §§ <cite root="16-909.01">16-909.01</cite> to 16-909.05;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The mother of the child; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>An individual who has been ordered to pay child support in a previous proceeding and the order has not been reversed or vacated.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon finding, after notice and opportunity to be heard, that an obligor owes a duty of support, the tribunal shall issue a support order directed to the obligor and may issue other orders pursuant to § <cite root="46-353.05">46-353.05</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-73">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-73, § 401, 63 DCR 222</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
