<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>46-357.10</num>
  <heading>Foreign support agreement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, a tribunal of the District shall recognize and enforce a foreign support agreement registered in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An application or direct request for recognition and enforcement of a foreign support agreement must be accompanied by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A complete text of the foreign support agreement; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A record stating that the foreign support agreement is enforceable as an order of support in the issuing country.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A tribunal of the District may vacate the registration of a foreign support agreement only if, acting on its own motion, the tribunal finds that recognition and enforcement would be manifestly incompatible with public policy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In a contest of a foreign support agreement, a tribunal of the District may refuse recognition and enforcement of the agreement if it finds:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Recognition and enforcement of the agreement is manifestly incompatible with public policy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The agreement was obtained by fraud or falsification;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The agreement is incompatible with a support order involving the same parties and having the same purpose in the District, another state, or a foreign country if the support order is entitled to recognition and enforcement under this chapter in the District; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The record submitted under subsection (b) of this section lacks authenticity or integrity.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A proceeding for recognition and enforcement of a foreign support agreement must be suspended during the pendency of a challenge to or appeal of the agreement before a tribunal of another state or a foreign country.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-73" type="History" path="ยง710">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-73, ยง 710, 63 DCR 222</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
