<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>46-356.05</num>
  <heading>Notice of registration of order.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When a support order or income-withholding order issued in another state or a foreign support order is registered, the registering tribunal of the District shall notify the nonregistering party. The notice must be accompanied by a copy of the registered order and the documents and relevant information accompanying the order.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A notice must inform the nonregistering party:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That a registered support order is enforceable as of the date of registration in the same manner as an order issued by a tribunal of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That a hearing to contest the validity or enforcement of the registered order must be requested within 20 days after notice unless the registered order is under § <cite path="§46-357.07">46-357.07</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That failure to contest the validity or enforcement of the registered order in a timely manner will result in confirmation of the order and enforcement of the order and the alleged arrearages; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Of the amount of any alleged arrearages.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the registering party asserts that 2 or more orders are in effect, a notice must also:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Identify the 2 or more orders and the order alleged by the registering party to be the controlling order and the consolidated arrears, if any;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notify the nonregistering party of the right to a determination of which is the controlling order;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>State that the procedures provided in subsection (b) of this section apply to the determination of which is the controlling order; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>State that failure to contest the validity or enforcement of the order alleged to be the controlling order in a timely manner may result in confirmation that the order is the controlling order.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Upon registration of an income-withholding order for enforcement, the support enforcement agency or the registering tribunal shall notify the obligor’s employer pursuant to Chapter 2 of this title [§ <cite path="§46-201">46-201</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-73" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-73, § 605, 63 DCR 222</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
