<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>46-357.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>In this subchapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Application” means a request under the Convention by an obligee or obligor, or on behalf of a child, made through a central authority for assistance from another central authority.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Central authority” means the entity designated by the United States or a foreign country described in § <cite path="§46-351.02">46-351.02</cite>(6)(D) to perform the functions specified in the Convention.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Convention support order” means a support order of a tribunal of a foreign country described in § <cite path="§46-351.02">46-351.02</cite>(6)(D).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Direct request” means a petition filed by an individual in a tribunal of the District in a proceeding involving an obligee, obligor, or child residing outside the United States.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Foreign central authority” means the entity designated by a foreign country described in § <cite path="§46-351.02">46-351.02</cite>(6)(D) to perform the functions specified in the Convention.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Foreign support agreement”:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Means an agreement for support in a record that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Is enforceable as a support order in the country of origin;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Has been:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(I)</num>
          <text>Formally drawn up or registered as an authentic instrument by a foreign tribunal; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(II)</num>
          <text>Authenticated by, or concluded, registered, or filed with a foreign tribunal; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>May be reviewed and modified by a foreign tribunal; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Includes a maintenance arrangement or authentic instrument under the Convention.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“United States central authority” means the Secretary of the United States Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-73">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-73, § 701, 63 DCR 222</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
