<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>46-503</num>
  <heading>Content.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Parties to a premarital agreement may contract with respect to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The rights and obligations of each of the parties in any of the property of either or both of them whenever and wherever acquired or located;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The right to buy, sell, use, transfer, exchange, abandon, lease, consume, expend, assign, create a security interest in, mortgage, encumber, dispose of, or otherwise manage and control property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The disposition of property upon separation, marital dissolution, annulment, termination of a domestic partnership pursuant to § <cite path="§32-702">32-702</cite>(d), death, or the occurrence or nonoccurrence of any other event;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The modification or elimination of spousal or domestic partner support;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The making of a will, trust, or other arrangement to carry out the provisions of the agreement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The ownership rights in, and disposition of, the death benefit from a life insurance policy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The choice of law governing the construction of the agreement; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Any other matter, including their personal rights and obligations, not in violation of public policy or a statute imposing a criminal penalty.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The right of a child to support may not be adversely affected by a premarital agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-82" type="History" path="§4">Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-82, § 4, 42 DCR 6770</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-79" type="History">Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-79, § 8(b), 53 DCR 1035</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 40(a), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 30-143.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-79">D.C. Law 16-79</cite>, in subsec. (a)(3), substituted “annulment, termination of a domestic partnership under § <cite path="§32-702">32-702</cite>,” for “annulment,”; and in subsec. (a)(4), substituted “spousal or domestic partner support” for “spousal support”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite>, in subsec. (a)(3), substituted “pursuant to § <cite path="§32-702">32-702</cite>(d),” for “under § <cite path="§32-702">32-702</cite>,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 3 of the Uniform Premarital Agreement Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
