<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 22-362">
  <num type="bill">22-800</num>
  <num type="act">22-362</num>
  <heading type="short">2018 All-Star Game and World Cup Emergency Amendment Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, section 25-723 of the District of Columbia Official Code to amend the hours of operation, sale, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages for on-premises retailers during the 2018 World Cup, and to amend the hours of operation, sale, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages for on-premises retailers, manufacturers, and temporary license holders during the 2018 All-Star Game.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2018-05-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/40158/Signed_Act/B22-0800-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106565">D.C. Act 22-362</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 5955</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B22-0800">
      <vote date="2018-05-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-05-21</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "2018 All-Star Game and World Cup Emergency Amendment Act of 2018".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 25-723 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding new subsections (g) and (h) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Except as provided in § 25-724, the licensee under an on-premises retailer's license, manufacturer's license, or temporary license, during the 2018 All-Star Game, beginning July 14, 2018, and ending July 18, 2018, may operate, sell, serve, and allow for consumption of alcoholic beverages until 4 a.m. and operate 24 hours a day if the licensee:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Registers with the Board;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Pays a registration fee of $100; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Provides written notification, no later than July 3, 2018, to the Board and the Metropolitan Police Department of its extended hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The fees collected pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited in the Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration Fund established by § 25-210.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>This subsection shall expire on July 19, 2018.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(h)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Except as provided in § 25-724, an on-premises retailer's license, may, during the World Cup Tournament, beginning on June 14, 2018, through July 15, 2018, operate, sell, serve, and allow for consumption of alcoholic beverages beginning at 7:00 a.m. on the first day of the World Cup Tournament through the last day of the World Cup Tournament if the licensee:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Registers with the Board;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Pays a registration fee of $100; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Provides written notification, no later than 7 days before the first day of the World Cup Tournament to the Board and the Metropolitan Police Department of its extended hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The fees collected pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited in the Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration Fund established by § 25-210.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term "World Cup Tournament" means the international soccer tournament that takes place every 4 years and is organized by the Fédération Internationale de Football Association.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>This subsection shall expire on July 16, 2018.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-723"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective fate.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
