<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 22-531">
  <num type="bill">22-1043</num>
  <num type="act">22-531</num>
  <heading type="short">Warehousing and Storage Eminent Domain Authority Emergency Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To authorize, on an emergency basis, the Mayor to exercise eminent domain to acquire certain property located on or near W Street, N.E., Lots 36 and 41 in Square 3942 and Parcel 0143/107, for the purposes of warehousing and storage.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2018-11-16</introduced>
    <effective>2018-12-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/41329/Signed_Act/B22-1043-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106535">D.C. Act 22-531</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 13437</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B22-1043">
      <vote date="2018-11-27" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-12-10</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Warehousing and Storage Eminent Domain Authority Emergency Act of 2018".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Findings.</heading>
    <text>The Council finds that:</text>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The District government has a significant need for warehousing and storage space for equipment, records, property, and supplies maintained by District agencies.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The District government has a need to properly store and maintain government records, equipment of agencies such as the Department of Parks and Recreation and the Department of Public Works, surplus property held by the Office of Contracting and Procurement, and emergency medical supplies for the Department of Health.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The District's need for warehousing and storage is near to exceeding the District's current capacity at its owned facilities and there is a reduction in the supply of, and limited vacancy within, warehouse space available for lease in the District.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>The District has identified a site located on or near W Street, N.E., east of Brentwood Road, N.E. ("W Street Site") as a strong site for these purposes as the site allows for by-right use as a warehouse and storage facility and is large enough to accommodate the warehouse and storage needs of numerous District agencies.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>The W Street Site is currently occupied by a private trash transfer station.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>Acquisition of the W Street Site will allow the District to construct and operate a facility or multiple facilities to warehouse and store the equipment, records, property, and supplies of numerous District agencies in a District-owned facility.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง16-1311" action="authority for the Maryor to exercise eminent domain to acquire Lots 36 and 41 in Square 3942 and Parcel 0143/107 for warehousing and storage purposes"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Exercise of eminent domain.</heading>
    <text>The Mayor may exercise eminent domain in accordance with the procedures set forth in subchapter II of Chapter 13 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code to acquire Lots 36 and 41 in Square 3942 and Parcel 0143/107 for warehousing and storage purposes.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
