<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 22-600">
  <num type="bill">22-842</num>
  <num type="act">22-600</num>
  <heading type="short">District Historical Records Advisory Board Amendment Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Public Records Management Act of 1985 to establish the District Historical Records Advisory Board, and to require the development of a Public Records and Archives Action Plan.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2018-06-05</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2019-04-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/40362/B22-0842-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-600</citation>
      <citation type="register">66 DCR 1446</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0842">
      <vote date="2018-11-27" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-12-18" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2018-12-18" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2019-01-24</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, this bill establishes the Commission on Archives and Records Management to advise and make recommendations to the Mayor, the Council, and the public on the management of public records and for the collection, custody, and preservation of the official records, documents, and publications of the District of Columbia.</summary>
      <committee>Committee on Government Operations</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District Historical Records Advisory Board Amendment Act of 2018".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Public Records Management Act of 1985, effective September 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-19; D.C. Official Code § 2-1701 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§2-1701|(a)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 2-1701) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(1)|num">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (1) is redesignated as paragraph (1A).</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>(1)</find>
          <replace>(1A)</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (1) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert before="(1A)"/>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>"Action plan" means the Public Records and Archives Action Plan.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(6A)|num">
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (6A) is redesignated as paragraph (6B).</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>(6A)</find>
          <replace>(6B)</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (6A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert before="(6B)"/>
            <num>(6A)</num>
            <text>"DHRAB" means the District Historical Records Advisory Board established in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1715">section 16a</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>New sections 16a, 16b, and 16c are added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <codify:insert path="2|17" after="§2-1714" num-value="2-1715" history-prefix="as added"/>
          <num>16a</num>
          <heading>Establishment of the District Historical Records Advisory Board.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The District Historical Records Advisory Board is established to make recommendations to the Mayor on collecting, maintaining, preserving, and conserving public records and archival records of historical value to the District.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>The DHRAB shall assume the functions ascribed to the Historical Records Advisory Board established pursuant to Mayor's Order 2002-150.</text>
          </para>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-19" type="History" path="§16a">Sept. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-19, § 16a</annotation>
        </section>
        <section>
          <codify:insert path="2|17" after="§2-1715" num-value="2-1716" history-prefix="as added"/>
          <num>16b</num>
          <heading>Duties of the DHRAB; Public Records and Archives Action Plan.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The DHRAB shall:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Advise the Mayor on policy and program issues with developing and implementing a comprehensive records management program to store public records and archival records of the District.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Support and promote interest among private and public institutions, community organizations, and neighborhood groups to collect, maintain, preserve, and conserve their public records and archival records of historical value.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Coordinate and monitor all projects funded by the National Historical Publication Records Commission.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Review and make recommendations on all requests submitted to the National Historical Publication Records Commission for funding or assistance.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>Assist in securing funding from the National Historical Publication Records Commission and other sources for the following purposes:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Supporting the mission of the Office of Public Records within the Office of the Secretary in developing a comprehensive archives and records management program for the District;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Sponsoring and conducting information management research projects that assist the Administrator in publishing finding aids, indexes, lists, inventories, cross references, and other guides to the records holdings in the District of Columbia Archives, the Records Center, and the Library of Governmental Information;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Sponsoring and conducting records surveying, scheduling, and documentation projects that will assist agencies of the District with organizing and developing comprehensive agency records management programs, and, with publishing agency histories;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>Sponsoring documentation projects of public records of historical value to the District;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Assisting nonprofit organizations and institutions in the District of Columbia with collecting, maintaining, preserving, and conserving the organizations' and institutions' public records and archival records of historical value, and documenting the organizations' and institutions' histories; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(F)</num>
                <text>Sponsoring a computerized network information management project that computerizes public records and archival records of historical value of the District.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>Sponsor, organize, develop, and host information management seminars, workshops, symposia, meetings, and other forums about managing public records and archival records of historical value to the District.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>Organize, develop, and host seminars, workshops, symposiums, meetings, and other forums to advise and assist community organizations and institutions with preserving, conserving, and documenting community organizations' and institutions' histories.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(8)</num>
              <text>Advise and assist community organizations and institutions in developing plans and procedures to preserve and conserve community organizations' and institutions' public records and archival records of historical value.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>By January 1, 2022, the DHRAB shall prepare and submit to the Mayor and Council a Public Records and Archives Action Plan to provide recommendations for the management, custody, and preservation of public records and archival records of historical value to the District of Columbia. In developing the action plan, the DHRAB shall survey all of the District's archival records and may consult with any District employees it deems necessary for the action plan's development. The DHRAB may use any additional research necessary, including consultations with subject matter experts, to inform the action plan's recommendations.</text>
          </para>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-19" type="History" path="§16b">Sept. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-19, § 16b</annotation>
        </section>
        <section>
          <codify:insert path="2|17" after="§2-1716" num-value="2-1717" history-prefix="as added"/>
          <num>16c</num>
          <heading>DHRAB membership; organization; administration.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The DHRAB shall consist of 13 members who meet the following requirements:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The Administrator shall serve as an ex officio member and as chairperson; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>12 members shall be appointed by the Mayor and confirmed by the Council pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-523.01|(f)">section 2(f) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(f))</code-cite>. Members appointed pursuant to this paragraph shall be representative of public and private archival, cultural heritage, and historical institutions, organizations, or programs throughout the District of Columbia.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>All members of the DHRAB shall be voting members.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>The chairperson of the DHRAB may establish subcommittees of the DHRAB as the chairperson deems necessary.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>The DHRAB shall further define its organizational structure and promulgate its rules of procedures.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(e)</num>
            <text>The DHRAB shall meet at such times as it deems necessary, except that it shall meet at least once annually.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(f)</num>
            <text>Of the members of the DHRAB appointed pursuant to subsection (a)(2) of this section, 6 of the initial members shall be designated to serve terms of 3 years from the date of appointment, and 6 of the initial members shall be designated to serve terms of 2 years from the date of appointment.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(g)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>At the expiration of a term, each member shall continue to serve until a successor is qualified and appointed.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Whenever a vacancy occurs on the DHRAB, an individual may be appointed as a member to fill the unexpired term.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(h)</num>
            <text>Members shall serve without compensation; provided, that expenses of the DHRAB, when authorized in advance by the Secretary, shall become obligations against funds designated for those purposes.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>The Office of Public Records within the Office of the Secretary shall provide administrative and staff support to the DHRAB.</text>
          </para>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-19" type="History" path="§16c">Sept. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-19, § 16c</annotation>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§1-523.01|(f)">
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 2(f) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(f)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="(64)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (64) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>; and</find>
        <replace>;</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="(65)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (65) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace position="last">
        <find>.</find>
        <replace>; and</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (66) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <codify:insert/>
          <num>(66)</num>
          <text>The District Historical Records Advisory Board, established by <span codify:value="["/><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1715">section 17 of the District of Columbia Public Records Management Act of 1985, passed on 2nd reading on December 18, 2018 (Enrolled version of Bill 22-842)</code-cite><span codify:value="]"/>.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
