<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 23-1">
  <num type="law">23-1</num>
  <num type="bill">23-25</num>
  <num type="act">23-7</num>
  <heading type="short">Sports Wagering Procurement Practices Reform Exemption Act of 2019</heading>
  <heading type="long">To exempt the initial procurement contract entered into in connection with the Sports Wagering Lottery Amendment Act of 2018 and the Sports Wagering Lottery Emergency Amendment Act of 2018 from the requirements of the Procurement Practices Reform Act of 2010.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-01-08</introduced>
    <effective>2019-04-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/41614/B23-0025-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 23-1</citation>
      <citation type="register">66 DCR 2451</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0025">
      <vote date="2019-02-05" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2019-02-19" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2019-02-22</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced it exempts the initial procurement contract entered into in connection with the Sports Wagering Lottery Amendment Act of 2018 and the corresponding emergency legislation from the requirements of the Procurement Practices Reform Act of 2010. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Finance and Revenue</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Sports Wagering Procurement Practices Reform Exemption Act of 2019".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The initial procurement contract for the sports wagering, lottery gaming systems and related services entered into in connection with the Sports Wagering Lottery Amendment Act of 2018,  enacted on January 23, 2019 (D.C. Act 22-594; 66 DCR 1402), and the Sports Wagering Lottery Emergency Amendment Act of 2018, effective January 30, 2019 (D.C. Act 22-630; 66 DCR 1745) ("initial contract"), shall be exempt from the Procurement Practices Reform Act of 2010, effective April 8, 2011(D.C. Law 18-371; D.C. Official Code § 2-351.01 <em>et seq.</em>); provided, that the initial contract shall be subject to all certified business enterprise, as that term is defined in section 2302(1D) of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of  2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Law § 2-218.02(1D)), requirements under District law and that the initial contract shall be approved by the Council if required by section 451 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 803; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.51).</text>
    <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§36-621.01" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" codify:applicability="2019-05-04">
    <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-1" path="§2">Section 2 of D.C. Law 23-1</cite> provided that the initial procurement contract for the sports wagering, lottery gaming systems and related services entered into in connection with <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="36|6|II">the Sports Wagering Lottery Amendment Act of 2018,  enacted on January 23, 2019 (D.C. Act 22-594; 66 DCR 1402)</code-cite>, and <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-630">the Sports Wagering Lottery Emergency Amendment Act of 2018, effective January 30, 2019 (D.C. Act 22-630; 66 DCR 1745)</cite> (“initial contract”), shall be exempt from <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|3A">the Procurement Practices Reform Act of 2010, effective April 8, 2011(D.C. Law 18-371; D.C. Official Code § 2-351.01 et seq.)</code-cite>; provided, that the initial contract shall be subject to all certified business enterprise, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-218.02|(1D)">section 2302(1D) of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of  2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Law § 2-218.02(1D))</code-cite>, requirements under District law and that the initial contract shall be approved by the Council if required by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.51">section 451 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 803; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.51)</code-cite>.
    </codify:annotation>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
