<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 23-23">
  <num type="law">23-23</num>
  <num type="bill">23-356</num>
  <num type="act">23-99</num>
  <heading type="short">Department of Health Functions Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2019</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Department of Health Functions Clarification Amendment Act of 2001 to exempt the tobacco bar and retail store located at 1132 19th Street, N.W., from the revenue requirements needed to gain an exemption from the indoor smoking prohibition from the Department of Health.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-06-25</introduced>
    <effective>2019-09-11</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/42878/B23-0356-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 23-23</citation>
      <citation type="register">66 DCR 9730</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0356">
      <vote date="2019-06-25" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2019-07-09" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2019-07-24</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of Health Functions Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2019".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Department of Health Functions Clarification Amendment Act of 2001, effective April 4, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-90; D.C. Official Code § 7-741.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 4915(5) (D.C. Official Code § 7-741.01(5)) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; except, that no total annual revenue requirement shall apply to the establishment located at 1132 19th Street, N.W." in its place.</text>
      <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-741.01"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 4917(a)(1) (D.C. Official Code § 7-741.03(a)(1)) is amended by striking the phrase "other establishment;" and inserting the phrase "other establishment; except, that no total revenue requirement shall apply to the establishment located at 1132 19th Street, N.W." in its place.</text>
      <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-741.03"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Sunset.</heading>
    <text>This act shall expire one year after the effective date of the Department of Health Functions Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2019, passed on emergency basis on June 25, 2019 (Enrolled version of Bill 23-355), or upon the expiration date of this act, whichever comes first.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
