<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 23-236">
  <num type="law">23-236</num>
  <num type="bill">23-706</num>
  <num type="act">23-510</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Champions Extension of Hours Amendment Act of 2020</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend section 25-723 of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide the Alcoholic Beverage Control Board with the authority to extend the hours of operation, sale, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages for on-premises retailers or manufacturers holding an on-site sales and consumption permit that are registered in the extended hours program, and for temporary license holders, during home and away postseason games of any District professional sports team.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2020-03-05</introduced>
    <effective>2021-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/44362/Signed_Act/B23-0706-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Law 23-236</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/44362/Signed_Act/B23-0706-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 23-510</citation>
      <citation type="register">67 DCR 14409</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0706">
      <vote date="2020-10-20" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2020-11-10" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2020-12-07</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 23-706 authorizes the Alcoholic Beverage Control Board (ABC Board) to allow on-premises retailers or manufacturers holding an on-site sales and consumption permit registered with ABRA’s extended hours program, and allows temporary license holders to sell, serve, and allow the consumption of alcoholic beverages until 4 a.m. It also enables them to operate 24 hours a day on those days a District of Columbia professional sports team is playing in a postseason game. </summary>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Champions Extension of Hours Amendment Act of 2020".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 25-723 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new subsection (c-1) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-723" after="(c)"/>
        <num>(c-1)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Except as provided in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-724">§ 25-724</cite>, the Board may extend the hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages during postseason games in which a District professional sports team is a participant for licensees registered with the Board to participate in the extension of hours program under subsection (c) of this section.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>If the Board extends the hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages during a postseason game pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, a licensee registered with the Board in the extension of hours program under subsection (c) of this may sell, serve, and allow the consumption of alcoholic beverages until 4 a.m. and operate 24 hours a day for the postseason game day.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The Board shall provide written notification to the Metropolitan Police Department at least 48 hours before extended hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption under this subsection will take effect.  The written notification shall include the list of establishments eligible to participate in the extended hours under this subsection.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>To the extent feasible, the Board shall provide notice of its decision to extend the hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption pursuant to this subsection in the District of Columbia Register.  The Board shall also post notice of its decision on ABRA's website within 24 hours after its decision.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>"District professional sports team" means a professional baseball, basketball, football, hockey, soccer, or tennis team that plays its home games or matches in the Washington-Arlington-Alexandria, DC-VA-MD-WV Metropolitan Division as defined by the Office of Management and Budget as of January 1, 2020.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>"Postseason game" means a professional baseball, basketball, football, hockey, soccer, or tennis playoff or championship game.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
