<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 26-18">
  <num type="law">26-18</num>
  <num type="act">26-70</num>
  <num type="bill">26-213</num>
  <heading type="short">Department of For-Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Department of For-Hire Vehicles Establishment Act of 1985 to authorize the Department of For-Hire Vehicles to enforce traffic laws against carrier-for-hire vehicles; and to amend the M igrant S ervices and S upports Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 2024 by providing that it shall expire 450 days after taking effect.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-03-31</introduced>
    <effective>2025-07-16</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57488/Signed_Act/B26-0213-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=211777">D.C. Law 26-18</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 6114</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0213">
      <vote date="2025-04-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-05-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-05-19</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of For-Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Department of For-Hire Vehicles Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official Code § 50-301.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 4 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.03) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (3A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(3A)</num>
            <text>"Carrier-for-hire" means a class of transportation service by which a network of private operators, couriers, or carriers provide delivery of parcels, food, or beverages in the District for compensation.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (30B) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "regulations governing public and private vehicle-for-hire service" and insert the phrase "regulations governing public and private vehicle-for-hire and carrier-for-hire service" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "traffic stops of public and private vehicles-for-hire, pursuant to protocol prescribed" and insert the phrase "traffic stops of public and private vehicles-for-hire and carrier-for-hire vehicles, pursuant to protocol prescribed" in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 7(a) (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.06(a)) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (4)(F) is amended by striking the phrase "Performing vehicle-for-hire inspections" and inserting the phrase "Performing public and private vehicle-for-hire and carrier-for-hire inspections" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the phrase "and dispatch services," and inserting the phrase "dispatch services, and carriers-for-hire," in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 8 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.07) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (b-1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <num>(b-1)</num>
            <text>The DFHV shall employ vehicle inspection officers to enforce the laws, rules, and regulations pertaining to vehicles-for-hire and carriers-for-hire. A primary function of vehicle inspection officers shall be to ensure the proper provision of service and to support safety through street enforcement efforts, including traffic stops of public and private vehicles-for-hire and carriers-for-hire, pursuant to protocol prescribed by the DFHV.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (c) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (19) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>A new paragraph (19A) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(19A)</num>
              <text>Establish rules relating to the enforcement of traffic regulations against carrier-for-hire vehicles; and</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Section 20k(a) (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.30(a)) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Strike the phrase "shall undergo training on the rules and regulations governing private and public vehicles-for-hire and undergo" and insert the phrase "shall undergo training on the rules and regulations governing private and public vehicles-for-hire and carrier-for-hire vehicles and undergo" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Strike the phrase "inspection officers shall be prohibited from making traffic stops of on-duty private or public vehicles-for-hire in the act of transporting a fare, unless there is reasonable suspicion of a violation" and insert the phrase "inspection officers shall be prohibited from making traffic stops of on-duty private or public vehicles-for-hire in the act of transporting a fare, or a carrier-for-hire vehicle in the act of transporting a parcel, food, or beverage, unless there is reasonable suspicion of a violation" in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 303(b) of the M igrant S ervices and S upports Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 2024, effective September 18, 2024 (D.C. Law 25-214; 71 DCR 11539), is amended by striking the number "225" and inserting the number "450" in its place.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
