<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 26-20" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">26-20</num>
  <num type="act">26-74</num>
  <num type="bill">26-46</num>
  <heading type="short">Emergency Rental Assistance Program Reform Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend section 8f of the Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005 to require specific documentation from tenants establishing eligibility for Emergency Rental Assistance Funds, to clarify the definition of a qualifying emergency situation, and to require the Mayor to issue regulations implementing the amended provisions of that section; and to amend section 501 of the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to permit a court to enter a stay, rather than require a court to enter a stay, when a tenant submits documentation to the court demonstrating that the tenant has a pending Emergency Rental Assistance Program application, to require housing providers to reschedule evictions in certain circumstances involving approved Emergency Rental Assistance Program applications, and to create an affirmative defense in eviction cases on the basis of housing providers' noncompliance with the Emergency Rental Assistance Program application process.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-01-13</introduced>
    <effective>2025-07-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56915/Signed_Act/B26-0046-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=212565">D.C. Law 26-20</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 6447</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B26-0046">
      <vote date="2025-04-01" reading="AMENDMENT"/>
      <vote date="2025-04-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-05-06" reading="AMENDMENT"/>
      <vote date="2025-05-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-05-28</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 26-46 would clarify the definition of qualifying emergency situation; and would permit a court to enter a stay, rather than require a court to enter a stay, when a tenant submits documentation to the court demonstrating that he or she has a pending Emergency Rental Assistance Program application.</summary>
      <committee>Human Services</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Emergency Rental Assistance Program Reform Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section codify:path="§4-753.08">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 8f of the Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005, effective March 10, 2023 (D.C. Law 24-287; D.C. Official Code § 4-753.08), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="(a)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(2)|(A)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (2)(A) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>The lead-in language is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>To qualify for Emergency Rental Assistance Funds, an applicant unit shall be required to document:</text>
                <codify:find-replace count="1">
                  <find>To qualify for Emergency Rental Assistance Funds, an applicant unit may be required to document or otherwise establish:</find>
                  <replace>To qualify for Emergency Rental Assistance Funds, an applicant unit shall be required to document:</replace>
                </codify:find-replace>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(iv)">
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Sub-subparagraph (iv) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>; and</find>
            <replace>;</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(v)">
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Sub-subparagraph (v) is amended by striking the phrase "for payment." and inserting the phrase "for payment; and" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>for payment.</find>
            <replace>for payment; and</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>A new sub-subparagraph (vi) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="3">
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(v)" num-value="(vi)"/>
              <num>(vi)</num>
              <text>The nature of the emergency situation; provided, that if the nature of the emergency situation precludes documentation, an unsworn declaration made under penalty of perjury explaining both the emergency situation and the reason why the applicant unit does not possess documentation regarding the nature of the emergency situation may be considered sufficient documentation of proof for this element of an application.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (3) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal path="(3)"/>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="(d)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (d) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(3)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (3) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>"Emergency situation" means a situation in which immediate action is necessary to avoid homelessness or eviction, to re-establish a rental home, or otherwise to prevent displacement from a rental home, which is the result of an unforeseen or unusual event, such as the loss of a job or high medical costs, that impacts the applicant unit's ability to pay rent and that cannot be resolved without financial assistance.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (3A) is added to read as follows:</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new subsection (e) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(d)" num-value="(e)"/>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall issue regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>The Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3501.01 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§42-3501.03|(a)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 103 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3501.03) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (12A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(12)" num-value="(12A)"/>
            <num>(12A)</num>
            <text>"ERAP provider" means a vendor that processes applications for Emergency Rental Assistance Funds.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (23A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(23)" num-value="(23A)"/>
            <num>(23A)</num>
            <text>"Payment information" means documents or information that identify the owner or manager of a rental unit, identify the balance of rent owed by a tenant, or facilitate the payment of the owner or manager of a rental unit, and that are necessary to perfect an application for Emergency Rental Assistance Funds, which may include personal identification, a W-9 form, a basic business license, proof of a Social Security Number, a property management agreement, or a rent ledger, but which shall not include the content of, or information associated with, a payment plan.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§42-3505.01">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 501 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3505.01) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(r)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (r) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num>(r)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The court may stay any proceeding adjudicating a claim brought by a housing provider to recover possession of a rental unit for nonpayment of rent if a tenant submits documentation to the court demonstrating that he or she has a pending Emergency Rental Assistance Program ("ERAP") application; provided, that the court may stay a proceeding under this subsection only once during the pendency of the case.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not be construed to limit a court's discretion to extend a stay.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>When an eviction based solely on a claim for nonpayment of rent has been authorized by the court and the tenant notifies the housing provider, no later than 48 hours prior to the scheduled date and time of the eviction, that the tenant has an approved ERAP application that would pay the full amount necessary to redeem the tenancy, the housing provider shall cancel the eviction. If the housing provider then reschedules the eviction, the housing provider shall reschedule the eviction for a date no sooner than 3 weeks from the earlier-scheduled eviction date.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>A housing provider that cancels an eviction under paragraph (3) of this subsection shall have leave to file an alias writ ("writ"), and no further leave of court shall be required for the next-requested issuance of a writ following the cancellation of the originally scheduled eviction. This paragraph shall not apply if a judgment is permanently stayed by a tenant's redemption of a tenancy.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>New subsections (s) and (t) are added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(r)" num-value="(s)"/>
            <num>(s)</num>
            <text>In any matter adjudicating a claim brought by a housing provider to recover possession of a rental unit for nonpayment of rent in which the tenant alleges, at or before an initial hearing, that the housing provider is withholding payment information requested by an ERAP provider, the court may order the housing provider to comply with any pending requests for the payment information from an ERAP provider.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(s)" num-value="(t)"/>
            <num>(t)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>In any matter adjudicating a claim brought by a housing provider to recover possession of a rental unit for nonpayment of rent in which the court finds, at trial or upon the resolution of a dispositive motion resolving the entire matter, that the housing provider failed to provide payment information requested by an ERAP provider for more than 45 days after receiving a request for the payment information from an ERAP provider, the court may order that the amount of rent that would have been redeemed by a successful ERAP application be deemed waived and shall not be recoverable by the housing provider.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The court shall not waive rent under paragraph (1) of this subsection if the housing provider shows that:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Compliance with a request for payment information necessary to perfect an ERAP application was delayed by a third party not under the control of the housing provider;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Good cause otherwise exists for the housing provider's non-compliance; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>The housing provider has, since the date of the relevant request for payment information, received payment from ERAP on behalf of the tenant.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>A waiver of rent under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall apply to any future proceeding in which the housing provider seeks from the tenant:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>The recovery of possession of the rental unit the rent for which was waived under paragraph (1) of this subsection; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>A money judgment for the waived rent.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Nothing in this subsection shall limit a tenant's ability to assert any defense to an outstanding rent balance sought by a housing provider.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in sections 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
