<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 26-39" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">26-39</num>
  <num type="act">26-113</num>
  <num type="bill">26-73</num>
  <heading type="short">Disconnect Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To direct local education agencies to adopt and implement a personal wireless communication device policy that prohibits a student from using a personal wireless communication device during the full school day.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-01-27</introduced>
    <effective>2025-09-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56987/Signed_Act/B26-0073-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=217819">D.C. Law 26-39</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 8159</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B26-0073">
      <vote date="2025-06-03" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-07-21</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 26-73 would direct local education agencies to adopt and implement a personal wireless communication device policy that prohibits a student from using a personal wireless communication device during the full school day.</summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Disconnect Act of 2025".</text>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="38" after="8C" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
      <num>8D</num>
      <heading>Personal Wireless Communication Devices in Primary and Secondary Schools.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="38|8D" num-value="38-851.01"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="38|8D">this act</code-cite>, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>"Full school day" shall have the same meaning as provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-201|(2B)">section 1(2B) of an Act To provide for compulsory school attendance, for the taking of a school census in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved February 4, 1925 (43 Stat. 806; D.C. Code § 38-201(2B))</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>"Health care needs" means specific medical requirements or disability- or health-related supports that are documented by a licensed medical provider with the LEA and that require the use of a personal wireless communication device for monitoring a medical condition, administering medication, receiving health-related alerts, receiving disability-related supports, or communicating with medical personnel or caregivers regarding the student's health during the school day.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>"LEA" means local education agency, which is the District of Columbia Public Schools system or any individual public charter school or group of public charter schools operating under a single charter.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>"Personal wireless communication device" means a cellular phone, tablet computer, laptop computer, or gaming device that is not owned or provided by the school.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>"Possessing" means carrying or holding an item on one's person but does not include carrying or holding an item in a backpack, purse, handbag, or other personal carryall.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="38|8D" after="§38-851.01" num-value="38-851.02"/>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">LEA requirements for a personal wireless communication device policy.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No later than 15 days before the start of the 2026-2027 School Year, each LEA serving students enrolled in grades K-12 shall adopt and implement a personal wireless communication device policy that prohibits K-12 students from, at a minimum, possessing a personal wireless communication device on school premises at any time during the full school day.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An LEA's personal wireless communication device policy may include exemptions for a student possessing a personal wireless communication device for specific educational purposes and to manage a student's health care needs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Each LEA's personal wireless communication device policy shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Establish consequences if a student violates the policy; provided, that the consequences shall be consistent with <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-236.04">section 204 of the Attendance Accountability Amendment Act of 2013, effective August 25, 2018 (D.C. Law 22-157; DC Official Code § 38-236.04)</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Establish a process and timeline for the LEA to assess whether the policy is working and how to refine it;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Be published on the LEA's website no later than 15 days before the start of each school year for which the policy is in effect, and that mid-year modifications shall be published no later than 15 days before being effective;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Be communicated to all enrolled families before the first day of school; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Be communicated to all LEA employees, contractors, and volunteers who have contact with students during school hours.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Each LEA's personal wireless communication device policy shall require each school in the LEA to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Identify how a parent or guardian of an enrolled student should communicate urgent information to their child during the full school day;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Identify how the school will communicate with families in cases of emergency; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Identify appropriate storage for students' personal wireless communication devices during the full school day.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="38|8D" after="§38-851.02" num-value="38-851.03"/>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">State education agency responsibilities.</heading>
    <text>By March 1, 2026, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall develop and share with LEAs a model policy that meets the requirements prescribed in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-851.02">section 3</code-cite>.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
