<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 26-41" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">26-41</num>
  <num type="act">26-128</num>
  <num type="bill">26-53</num>
  <heading type="short">Vacant to Vibrant Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To require the Department of Housing and Community Development to create a tangled title information sheet and to require funeral service providers to give the information sheet to survivors of a deceased District resident; to amend Title 18 of the District of Columbia Official Code to allow for the creation of a will registry and to establish a single family home rehabilitation program; to amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to establish payment plans for the payment of delinquent real property taxes; to amend the Department of Buildings Establishment Act of 2020 to require that certain information regarding vacant and blighted buildings be included in Strategic Enforcement Plans; to amend An Act To provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes to amend definitions, factors for establishing vacancy or blight, and exemptions from registration, to require the submission of vacant building maintenance plans, and to allow the Mayor to petition the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for vacant property receivership actions; to amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to establish procedures governing an appeal of a determination of vacancy; to amend the Abatement and Condemnation of Nuisance Properties Omnibus Amendment Act of 2000 to provide a definition for the term "blighted area"; to amend the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986 to require the Department of Buildings to establish an expedited permit review process for certain construction and building permits for Class 3 and 4 properties; to amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to establish new tax rates for Class 3 and 4 properties, to establish a new process for tax sales of Class 3 and 4 properties, to establish a tax credit for the renovation or rehabilitation of Class 3 or 4 properties, and to establish a tax abatement for the renovation or rehabilitation of Class 3 or 4 properties that are used for commercial purposes.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-01-13</introduced>
    <effective>2025-10-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56922/Signed_Act/B26-0053-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=218452">D.C. Law 26-41</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 8881</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0053">
      <vote date="2025-06-03" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-08-11</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 26-53 would establish an electronic will registry. A single-family home rehabilitation program, allow the establishment of a payment plan for delinquent property taxes, and require that all commercial registered agents to accept service of process by electronic mail. It amends the factors for establishing vacancy and blight and among other things, require the Department of Buildings to establish an expedited permit review process for certain construction and building permits. It also provides tax credits and abatements for certain class 3 and 4 properties. </summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Vacant to Vibrant Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="42" after="16B" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
      <num>16C</num>
      <heading>Tangled Title Disclosure.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>I</num>
    <heading>PREVENTION OF VACANT AND BLIGHTED PROPERTIES.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>A</num>
      <heading>TANGLED TITLE INFORMATION SHEET.</heading>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="42|16C" num-value="42-1681"/>
        <num>101</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <text>For purposes of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="42|16C">this subtitle</code-cite>, the term:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>"Department" means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>"Funeral services establishment" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-402|(11)">section 3(11) of the District of Columbia Funeral Services Regulatory Act of 1984, effective May 22, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-84; D.C. Official Code § 3-402(11))</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>"Heir" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§20-101|(c)">section 101(c) of the District of Columbia Probate Reform Act of 1980, effective June 24, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-72; D.C. Official Code § 20-101(c))</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>"Legatee" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§20-101|(g)">section 101(g) of the District of Columbia Probate Reform Act of 1980, effective June 24, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-72; D.C. Official Code § 20-101(g))</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>"Survivor of the deceased" means any individual with whom funeral services are being arranged.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="42|16C" after="§42-1681" num-value="42-1682"/>
        <num>102</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Tangled title disclosure.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>No later than <span codify:value="[March 30, 2026]">180 days after the effective date of this subtitle</span>, the Department shall, in consultation with the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and legal service providers, create and make publicly available a tangled title information sheet detailing the steps necessary, after the death of a real property owner, to legally transfer the real property to a decedent's heirs or legatees. The information sheet also shall include information on legal service providers who offer low-cost or no-cost representation in estate administration cases.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>No later than 5 days after the final disposition of the deceased, or at the time of providing to survivors of the deceased any death certificate or death certificates ordered by the funeral services establishment from the Department of Health, whichever occurs first, a funeral service establishment shall provide the tangled title information sheet made available by the Department to survivors of the deceased.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>A funeral service establishment that fails to provide a tangled title information sheet pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection may be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $100 for each offense.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </section>
    </container>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="18" after="9" history="false">
      <container>
        <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
        <num>10</num>
        <heading>Will Registry.</heading>
      </container>
    </codify:insert>
    <container>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>B</num>
      <heading>WILL REGISTRY.</heading>
      <section>
        <num>111</num>
        <text>Title 18 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The table of contents is amended by adding a new chapter designation to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>10.</num>
              <text>Will Registry.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>A new chapter 10 is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <container>
              <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
              <num>10</num>
              <heading>Will Registry.</heading>
              <toc>
                <section>
                  <num>18-901</num>
                  <heading>General provisions.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>18-902</num>
                  <heading>Deposit of will in testator's life.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>18-903</num>
                  <heading>Custodian of will upon death of testator.</heading>
                </section>
              </toc>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="18|10" num-value="18-1001"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>18-1001</num>
                <heading proof="needed">General provisions.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <text>The provisions of this section are solely for the purpose of providing a safe and convenient repository for a will. The filing of a will with the registry shall not create any presumption as to the authenticity of the document, its signatures, or its admissibility in probate. A deposited will shall not be treated differently by the Probate Court solely because it has been deposited.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>The Register of Wills shall not be liable for the loss of any document submitted to the registry.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(c)</num>
                  <text>The Register of Wills shall keep an index of all wills deposited under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="18|10">this chapter</cite>.</text>
                </para>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="18|10" after="§18-1001" num-value="18-1002"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>18-1002</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Deposit of will in testator's lifetime.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <text>Beginning January 1, 2028, an original will may be deposited by a domiciliary testator, the testator's agent, or the testator's attorney, with the Register of Wills for safekeeping. The will shall be delivered and shall not be opened, except as provided in this section.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>Upon payment of the required fee, the Register of Wills shall give a receipt.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(c)</num>
                  <text>The will shall be enclosed in a sealed wrapper, which shall have endorsed on it "Will of", followed by:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>The name of the testator;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>The testator's address in the District of Columbia;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>The name of the person or persons whom the testator nominated in the will to serve as a personal representative upon the testator's death<s>.</s>; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(4)</num>
                    <text>The testator's Social Security number, if available.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(d)</num>
                  <text>The Register of Wills shall endorse on the sealed wrapper containing the will:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>The date it was received; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>The name of the person from whom it was received.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(e)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, during the lifetime of the testator, a deposited will may be delivered only to the testator or to a person authorized by the testator in writing to receive it.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>If a testator is adjudicated incapacitated or an investigation or proceeding has been initiated in accordance with <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="22|9A">§ 22-931 <em>et seq.</em></code-cite>, or in accordance with <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="21|5">Chapter 5 of Title 21</cite>, and the will was deposited with the registry less than one year from the adjudication or investigation, a court-appointed guardian, conservator, guardian ad litem, or counsel in the proceedings may be authorized to unseal and examine a deposited will of testator under procedures designed to maintain the confidential character of the document, to the extent possible, and to ensure that it will be resealed and kept on deposit after the examination. If the will of an incapacitated testator has been deposited continuously for more than one year, the will cannot be unsealed without a court order.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="18|10" after="§18-1002" num-value="18-1003"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>18-1003</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Custodian of will upon death of testator.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <text>Upon notification of the testator's death, the Register of Wills shall:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>Unseal the will;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>Deliver the will to the Probate Court for filing in accordance with <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§18-110">§ 18-110</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>If the testator was not a domiciliary of the District of Columbia at the time of death, the Register of Wills, upon order of the Probate Court, shall transfer the registered will to the probate officer or Register of Wills for the county or state where the decedent is alleged to have been domiciled at the time of death.</text>
                </para>
              </section>
            </container>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </section>
    </container>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="42" after="30" history="false">
      <container>
        <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
        <num>30A</num>
        <heading>Single Family Home Rehabilitation Program.</heading>
      </container>
    </codify:insert>
    <container>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>C</num>
      <heading>SINGLE FAMILY HOME REHABILITATION PROGRAM.</heading>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="42|30A" num-value="42-3021"/>
        <num>121</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <text>For purposes of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="42|30A">this subtitle</code-cite>, the term:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>"Area median income" means the area median income of the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the periodic calculation provided by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>"Department" means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>"Eligible homeowner" means an owner or owners who:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Owns a single-family residential property;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Has a household income that is 80% of area median income or less;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>Has resided in the single-family residential property as a primary residence for at least 3 years;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(D)</num>
              <text>Is current on all mortgage payments for the last 3 months;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(E)</num>
              <text>Is current on all District and federal taxes; provided, that an owner who has not defaulted on a real property tax payment plan entered into pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-811.05">D.C. Official Code § 47-811.05</cite> and remains current on real property taxes that come due shall be considered current on District real property taxes for purposes of determining eligibility under this paragraph; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(F)</num>
              <text>Possesses current homeowners insurance.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>"Single-family residential property" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-803|(6)">D.C. Official Code § 47 803(6)</cite>.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§121" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="42|30A" after="§42-3021" num-value="42-3022"/>
        <num>122</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Single-family home rehabilitation program.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The Department may offer single-family home rehabilitation grants to eligible homeowners to pay for:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Accessibility modifications to adjust physical barriers within the property for persons with limited mobility or other physical impairment;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Repairs to, or replacement of, the roof;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Renovations to correct code violations, including lead-based paint hazard reduction and replacing or repairing drywall or damaged flooring;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>Energy-related improvements;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>Repairs to the foundation or to address other significant structural damage; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(6)</num>
            <text>Repairs to, or replacement of, electrical, plumbing, or heating and cooling systems.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The Department shall work with qualifying applicants to develop a scope of work, select a licensed and certified contractor, and manage the construction.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Any payments to contractors shall be made by the Department on behalf of eligible homeowners.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|I">Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq</em>.)</code-cite>, shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
        </para>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§122" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
      </section>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>D</num>
      <heading>REAL PROPERTY TAX PAYMENT PLANS.</heading>
      <section>
        <num>131</num>
        <text>Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>Chapter 8 is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The table of contents is amended by adding a new section designation to read as follows:</text>
            <include>
              <toc>
                <section>
                  <num>47-811.05</num>
                  <heading>Real property tax payment plans.</heading>
                </section>
              </toc>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>A new section 47-811.05 is added to read as follows:</text>
            <include>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|8|II" after="§47-811.04" num-value="47-811.05"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-811.05</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Real property tax payment plans.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <text>For purposes of this section, the term:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>"Eligible homeowner" means an owner or owners who receives the homestead deduction pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-850">§ 47-850</cite> and:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>Can demonstrate hardship;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>Has a household adjusted gross income that is less than $125,000, increased annually, beginning October 1, 2025, by the senior or disabled cost-of-living adjustment; provided, that if the adjustment does not result in a multiple of $50, the adjustment shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $50;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(C)</num>
                      <text>Has been determined to have a permanent and total disability by the Social Security Administration, is receiving Supplemental Security Income or Social Security Disability Insurance, is receiving disability annuities pursuant to the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974, approved October 16, 1974 (88 Stat. 1305; 45 U.S.C. § 231 <em>et seq</em>.), or is receiving federal or District of Columbia government disability payments; or</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(D)</num>
                      <text>Is 65 years of age or older.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>"Tax liabilities" means both real property taxes that are delinquent and real property taxes that are currently due but not yet delinquent. The term "tax liabilities" does not include:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>Business Improvement District ("BID") taxes;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>Tax Increment Financing ("TIF") payments;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(C)</num>
                      <text>Payments In Lieu of Taxes ("PILOTs");</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(D)</num>
                      <text>Southeast Water and Sewer ("SEWS") assessments;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(E)</num>
                      <text>Special Energy Assessment assessments; or</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(F)</num>
                      <text>Amounts certified by external agencies pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1340">§ 47-1340</cite>.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>Real property tax payment plans with eligible homeowners are authorized for all amounts due as real property tax liabilities subject to the following terms and conditions:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>Eligibility for a payment plan shall be based on the criteria set forth in the definition of "eligible homeowner" in subsection (a)(1) of this section;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>Payment plans may be computed on a 12-month, 18-month, or 24-month basis, and tax liabilities are to be paid in equal installments over the period agreed to in writing by the eligible homeowner pursuant to the terms of the payment plan;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>No down payment shall be required;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(4)</num>
                    <text>Payments may be made by direct ACH debit from the eligible homeowner's bank account to the District or by check or money order payable to the "DC Treasurer", and, if there are insufficient funds for the debit or check, the eligible homeowner shall also be liable for a fee imposed by the District for the dishonored payment;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(5)</num>
                    <text>An eligible homeowner cannot have more than one payment plan active at a time;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(6)</num>
                    <text>An eligible homeowner cannot apply for a payment plan for periods covered under a payment plan that he or she previously defaulted on;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(7)</num>
                    <text>If there is a reclassification of a property, a homestead or senior/disabled audit, or the granting of a tax relief application during the term of a payment plan, the existing payment plan shall terminate, and the eligible homeowner can reapply for the same periods covered by the terminated plan;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(8)</num>
                    <text>Property will not be sold at a tax sale during the time a payment plan is active;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(9)</num>
                    <text>While enrolled in a payment plan, an eligible homeowner shall remain current on real property taxes that come due;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(10)</num>
                    <text>The Office of Tax and Revenue may declare an eligible homeowner in material breach of a payment plan if he or she fails to make the required payments; provided, that a material breach may not be declared earlier than the 65th day from the agreed upon due date for a missed payment and the 45th day from the mailing of a notice of risk of material breach;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(11)</num>
                    <text>An eligible homeowner who has been declared in material breach of a payment plan may have his or her payment plan reinstated if he or she pays a lump sum equal to twice the regular monthly payment due, together with the missed payments as well as any payments currently due; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(12)</num>
                    <text>The Office of Tax and Revenue may declare an eligible homeowner in default if he or she has failed to cure a material breach within 45 days of the date the eligible homeowner is declared to be in material breach, and, if an eligible homeowner is declared in default of a payment plan, such plan shall be void.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(c)</num>
                  <text>Requests for real property tax payment plans to be entered into pursuant to this section shall be made online at MyTax.DC.gov. The Office of Tax and Revenue shall provide a payment plan agreement confirmation to the eligible homeowner. The agreement shall contain the following information:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>The monthly payment amount;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>The past-due date;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>The length of the plan, including the number of payments;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(4)</num>
                    <text>The total amount agreed to be due under the plan;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(5)</num>
                    <text>A statement of the delinquent tax periods covered by the plan as well as an itemized statement of the amounts due for each period specifying the amount due for principal, interest, penalties, and any other charges or fees;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(6)</num>
                    <text>A statement that the eligible homeowner is required to remain current on real property taxes during the length of the agreement, as well as an explanation of how current payments should be tendered in order to avoid misapplication of payments to delinquent taxes;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(7)</num>
                    <text>A brief explanation of how payments will be applied to the delinquency;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(8)</num>
                    <text>A brief explanation of the consequences of breach and default on the payment plan; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(9)</num>
                    <text>A statement that payments are to be remitted to the District electronically by direct debit or by check or money order payable to the "DC Treasurer", that payments made electronically will be withdrawn from the eligible homeowner's account on the monthly payment due date, and that, if there are insufficient funds for the debit, the eligible homeowner also shall be liable for a fee imposed by the District for the dishonored payment.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(d)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>If an eligible homeowner fails to make a required payment within 20 days of an agreed-upon payment due date, the Office of Tax and Revenue shall send a notice of risk of material breach to the eligible homeowner. The notice shall include a statement that the eligible homeowner is at risk of material breach, the entire amount required to cure the missed payment or payments as well as any payments currently due, and a brief description of the consequences of a material breach.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>If an eligible homeowner is declared to be in material breach of a payment plan, the Office of Tax and Revenue shall send a notice of material breach to the eligible homeowner that includes a clear statement that he or she has been declared in material breach, the date on which the material breach was declared, the entire amount required to cure the missed payment or payments as well as any payments currently due and lump sum payments that may be required, and a clear statement that failure to make the required payment will result in default.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </section>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
            <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§131|(a)|(2)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="§47-1341">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Section 47-1341 is amended as follows:</text>
          <para codify:path="(a)|(2)">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Subsection (a)(2) is amended to read as follows:</text>
            <include lvl="1">
              <para>
                <codify:replace/>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The notice required pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be in substantively the following form and may include a payment coupon or enclosed bill:</text>
                <text>THIS IS A NOTICE OF DELINQUENCY. FAILURE TO PAY TAXES WILL HAVE SERIOUS CONSEQUENCES WHICH MAY INCLUDE LOSS OF TITLE TO THE PROPERTY.</text>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Subject Property: [Identify by taxation square, suffix, and lot number, or parcel and lot number, and by premises address, the real property to be sold]</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">TO AVOID TAX SALE YOU MUST PAY $ [Amount Subject to Sale] by May 31, 20__.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">The amount that you must pay to avoid the tax sale may be less than the total amount owed on the real property account. This amount may include fees or fines due to other DC agencies that have been certified to the Office of Tax and Revenue to be included in a tax sale pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1340">D.C. Code § 47-1340</cite>.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">According to the Mayor's tax roll, you own or may have an interest in the real property listed above. Notice is given that unless you pay the amount stated above or fall within one of the limited exemptions from the tax sale, the Office of Tax and Revenue may sell this real property at tax sale.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">If the property is sold at tax sale, the purchaser may have the right to file a lawsuit to foreclose on the property. You must act now to avoid additional costs and significant expenses, as well as potential loss of title to the property.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Payment to the "DC Treasurer" may be made online at MyTax.DC.gov or mailed (with payment coupon from tax bill) to the Office of Tax and Revenue, DC Government Real Property Taxes, P.O. Box 718095, Philadelphia, PA 19171-8095 (please write your square, suffix, and lot numbers on the check). You should keep a copy of your proof of payment in case there is a later dispute about the payment.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">If payment is not made before May 31, 20__, the amount listed on this notice may no longer be accurate. In that case, you must contact the Office of Tax and Revenue at ______ to obtain an updated payoff amount.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">YOU MAY BE ELIGIBLE FOR ASSISTANCE, INCLUDING A HARDSHIP FORBEARANCE, A REAL PROPERTY TAX PAYMENT PLAN, OR FREE LEGAL SERVICES. PLEASE SEE THE NEXT PAGE FOR ADDITIONAL INFORMATION.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Should you have additional questions, please call the Customer Service Center for the Office of Tax and Revenue at (202) 727-4TAX (4829).</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">RESOURCES FOR REAL PROPERTY TAXPAYERS IN THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Real Property Tax Ombudsman. Homeowners and other interested parties may be eligible for assistance from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman. If you need assistance with a tax sale or related property tax matters, contact the Real Property Tax Ombudsman at ___________.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Classification Disputes. If your real property is classified as vacant or blighted and you believe this classification is incorrect, contact the Vacant Building Enforcement Unit of the Department of Buildings at ______ for information on how to appeal the property classification.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Hardship Forbearance. You may be eligible to defer, or postpone, payment of the past due amount. For information on how to apply for this deferral, please contact the Office of Tax and Revenue at ___________.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Senior Citizen and Low-Income Tax Relief. Senior citizens and low-income households may have additional rights to defer property taxes. If you think you may be eligible for this tax relief, please contact the Office of Tax and Revenue at _______ for more information.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Additional Legal Services. Free and reduced-cost legal services may be available to low- and moderate-income households. You can get a list of service providers from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (above).</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Housing Counseling Services. The U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development ("HUD") sponsors housing counseling agencies throughout the country that can provide advice on buying a home, renting, defaults, foreclosures, and credit issues. You can get a list of HUD-approved housing counseling agencies from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (above).</aftertext>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <para codify:path="(b-1)|(2)">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Subsection (b-1)(2) is amended to read as follows:</text>
            <include lvl="1">
              <para>
                <codify:replace/>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The notice required pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be in substantively the following form, and may include a payment coupon or enclosed bill:</text>
                <text>THIS IS A NOTICE OF DELINQUENCY. FAILURE TO PAY TAXES IMMEDIATELY MAY HAVE SERIOUS CONSEQUENCES WHICH MAY INCLUDE LOSS OF TITLE TO THE PROPERTY.</text>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Subject Property: [Identify by taxation square, suffix, and lot number, or parcel and lot number, and by premises address, the real property to be sold]</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">TO AVOID TAX SALE YOU MUST PAY $[Amount Subject to Sale] by [Last Business Day before tax sale]</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">The amount that you must pay to avoid the tax sale may be less than the total amount owed on the real property account. This amount may include fees or fines due to other DC agencies that have been certified to the Office of Tax and Revenue to be included in a tax sale pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1340">D.C. Code § 47-1340</cite>.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">According to the Mayor's tax roll, you own or may have an interest in the real property listed above. Notice is given that unless you pay the amount stated above or fall within one of the limited exemptions from the tax sale, the Office of Tax and Revenue may sell this real property at tax sale.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">If the property is sold at tax sale, the purchaser may have the right to file a lawsuit to foreclose on the property. You must act now to avoid additional costs and significant expenses, as well as potential loss of title to the property.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Payment to the "DC Treasurer" may be made online at MyTax.DC.gov or mailed (with payment coupon from tax bill) to the Office of Tax and Revenue, DC Government Real Property Taxes, P.O. Box 718095, Philadelphia, PA 19171-8095 (please write your square, suffix, and lot numbers on the check). You should keep a copy of your proof of payment in case there is a later dispute about the payment.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">If payment is made less than 10 calendar days before [the last business day before tax sale], you must provide a copy of the receipt directly to the Office of Tax and Revenue in order to ensure that your property is removed from the tax sale.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">You may FAX the receipt to (202) 478-5995; EMAIL the receipt to [email address]; or HAND-DELIVER a copy of the paid receipt to a Tax Sale Unit representative in the Customer Service Center located at 1101 4th Street, SW, Suite 270W, Washington, DC 20024.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Do not mail your paid receipt.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">YOU MAY BE ELIGIBLE FOR ASSISTANCE, INCLUDING A HARDSHIP FORBEARANCE, A REAL PROPERTY TAX PAYMENT PLAN, OR FREE LEGAL SERVICES. PLEASE SEE THE NEXT PAGE FOR ADDITIONAL INFORMATION.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Should you have additional questions, please call the Customer Service Center for the Office of Tax and Revenue at (202) 727-4TAX (4829).</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">RESOURCES FOR REAL PROPERTY TAXPAYERS IN THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Real Property Tax Ombudsman. Homeowners and other interested parties may be eligible for assistance from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman. If you need assistance with a tax sale or related property tax matters, contact the Real Property Tax Ombudsman at ___________.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Classification Disputes. If your real property is classified as vacant or blighted and you believe this classification is incorrect, contact the Vacant Building Enforcement Unit of the Department of Buildings at _______ for information on how to appeal the property classification.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Hardship Forbearance. You may be eligible to defer, or postpone, payment of the past due amount. For information on how to apply for this deferral, please contact the Office of Tax and Revenue at ___________.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Senior Citizen and Low-Income Tax Relief. Senior citizens and low-income households may have additional rights to defer property taxes. If you think you may be eligible for this tax relief, please contact the Office of Tax and Revenue at _______ for more information.</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Additional Legal Services. Free and reduced-cost legal services may be available to low- and moderate-income households. You can get a list of service providers from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (above).</aftertext>
                <aftertext proof="needed">Housing Counseling Services. The U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development ("HUD") sponsors housing counseling agencies throughout the country that can provide advice on buying a home, renting, defaults, foreclosures, and credit issues. You can get a list of HUD-approved housing counseling agencies from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (above).</aftertext>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§131|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="amendment to" display-template=""/>
        </para>
      </section>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading>VACANT AND BLIGHTED PROPERTY REGISTRATION REFINEMENTS.</heading>
    <section codify:path="§10-562.02">
      <!-- FY '26 BSA amended this to Section 202, Code Sec. 10-562.02 -->
      <num>201</num>
      <text>Section 201 of the Department of Buildings Establishment Act of 2020, effective April 5, 2021 (D.C. Law 23-269; D.C. Official Code § 10-562.01), is amended by adding new subsections (d) and (e) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(c)" num-value="(d)"/>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>For the January 1, 2026 annual enforcement plan required pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the following information shall be included:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>A description of predictive statistical models that could be used to identify properties at risk of becoming vacant or blighted, as well as the data sources and information technology infrastructure necessary to effectively implement these models;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>A detailed description of proactive measures utilized by other jurisdictions in the United States to enforce vacant and blighted property registration ordinances; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>An analysis and determination of the feasibility of utilizing proactive measures to enforce the District's laws regarding registration and maintenance of vacant and blighted buildings.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(d)" num-value="(e)"/>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>For the January 1, 2027 annual enforcement plan required pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, and for the annual enforcement plans issued every 3 years thereafter, the Director shall include a vacant and blighted property rehabilitation strategic plan. In developing the strategic plan, the Director shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Analyze the extent and nature of interagency collaboration among District agencies with respect to:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Enforcing legal requirements related to vacant and blighted buildings in the District; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Incentivizing the successful redevelopment or rehabilitation of vacant and blighted buildings;</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Review the use and effectiveness of existing incentives in the District that support the redevelopment or rehabilitation of vacant and blighted buildings;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Review best practices for preventing vacancy and blight and best practices for redeveloping or rehabilitating vacant and blighted buildings;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>Develop and refine performance metrics that measure the effectiveness of the District's programs, interventions, and incentives regarding vacant and blighted properties; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>Consult with stakeholders, including the following:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Advisory Neighborhood Commissions;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Organizations with significant experience redeveloping or rehabilitating vacant or blighted buildings; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>Organizations or individuals with policy or research expertise on:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(i)</num>
                <text>Implementing strategic code enforcement programs;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <text>Housing development incentives; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <text>Developing performance measures.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>202</num>
      <text>An Act To provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes, approved April 14, 1906 (34 Stat. 114; D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.01 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.05">
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Section 5 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.05) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num codify:value="42-3131.05">5</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
            <para>
              <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
              <text>For purposes of <span codify:value="§§">sections </span> <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.05" codify:value="42-3131.05">5</code-cite> through <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.21" codify:value="42-3131.21">21</code-cite>, the term:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>"Active construction" means construction activity being performed pursuant to a valid building permit.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>"Advisory Neighborhood Commission certification" means a resolution approved by a majority vote of the Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which a building is located requesting that the Mayor classify the building as vacant or blighted vacant.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>"Blighted vacant building" means a vacant building that is determined by the Mayor to be in such a condition as to pose a danger to the health, safety, or general welfare of the community.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>"Commercial unit" means a building, or a part of a building, zoned for commercial purposes under the zoning regulations of the District of Columbia.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>"Dwelling unit" means a room or group of rooms forming a single unit designed, or intended to be used, for living and sleeping, whether or not designed or intended for the preparation and eating of meals or to be under the exclusive control of the occupant. The term "dwelling unit" shall not include a room or group of rooms forming a single unit in a hotel or motel licensed in the District of Columbia, actively operating as a hotel or motel.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>"Fit for occupancy" means ready for immediate occupancy by a tenant without more than minor cosmetic changes and meeting minimum standards for safety, sanitation, and habitability.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>"Multifamily residential building" means a building containing 3 or more dwelling units.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>"Occupied" means:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>For purposes of a dwelling unit, the use of one's residence in improved real property on a regular or habitual basis. For purposes of a dwelling unit, the term "occupied" excludes incidental or non-residential uses such as storage, occasional visits, social gatherings, or maintenance alone; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>For purposes of a commercial unit, use consistent with zoning regulations, for which there is a current valid certificate of occupancy, and:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>Paid utility receipts for the specified period, executed lease agreements, or sales tax return; or</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>Other evidence of use of the building that the Mayor may require by rule.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(9)</num>
                <text>"Owner" shall mean any person or entity who, alone or jointly or severally with others:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Has legal title to the subject property; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Has charge, care, or control of the subject property, whether as owner or member, in whole or in part, of the legally titled owner, as agent of the legally titled owner, or as a fiduciary of the estate of the legally titled owner or any officer appointed by the court.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(10)</num>
                <text>"Owner of record" means the person or persons named in the public record as the title holder of the property.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(11)</num>
                <text>"Real property" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-802|(1)">D.C. Official Code § 47-802(1)</cite>.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(12)</num>
                <text>"Related owners" or "related ownership" exists when a deduction for a loss from the sale or exchange of properties between taxpayers would be disallowed under 26 U.S.C. § 267; provided, that the exclusion under 26 U.S.C. § 267(a)(1) for a loss in a distribution in a complete liquidation shall not apply.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(13)</num>
                <text>"Relative" means a spouse, domestic partner, sibling, parent, grandparent, child, or grandchild, or a sibling's child, spouse, or domestic partner.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(14)</num>
                <text>"Vacant building" means any real property improved by a building that is not lawfully occupied on a regular or habitual basis by the owner or a tenant or other person having the permission of the owner; provided, that, in the case of residential buildings, the Mayor determines that there is no resident for whom an intent to return and lawfully occupy the building can be shown.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.05a">
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 5a (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.05a) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num codify:value="42-3131.05a">5a</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Notice.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Notice shall be deemed to be served properly on the date when mailed by first-class mail to the owner of record of the vacant building at the owner's mailing address as updated in the real property tax records of the Office of Tax and Revenue, or when effectuated in the manner provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.03">section 3</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>In addition to furnishing notice in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall cause notice to be posted on the premises.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>A courtesy copy of the notice provided pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be mailed or electronically mailed to the Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which the vacant building is located. The courtesy copy required by this subsection shall not be construed to satisfy, nor be construed as necessary to satisfy, the notice requirement of subsection (a) of this section.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>A new section 5b is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="42|31A|II" after="§42-3131.05a" num-value="42-3131.05b" history-prefix="as added"/>
            <num>5b</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Determination of vacancy and blight.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>When making a determination that a building is vacant, the Mayor shall consider the following:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Neighbor complaints;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Advisory Neighborhood Commission certification;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Accumulated mail, fliers, or newspapers;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>Past due utility notices, disconnected utilities, or low utility usage inconsistent with regular and habitual occupancy;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>Presence of overgrown vegetation, dead or diseased trees, or noxious weeds;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>Absence of furnishings or personal items consistent with habitation;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>Building is open to casual entry or trespass; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>Any other criteria the Mayor deems relevant.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>When making a determination that a vacant building is a blighted vacant building, the Mayor shall consider the following:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Incidence of illegal activity, as documented by police reports;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Whether the vacant building is the subject of a condemnation proceeding before the Board for the Condemnation of Insanitary Buildings;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Referrals to the Department of Buildings from other District agencies;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>One or more windows, doors, or other means of entry are missing or boarded up;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>Collapsing, missing, or deteriorating walls, roof, stairs, porches, balconies, chimneys, and other building elements;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>Siding or exterior walls that are seriously damaged, missing, or deteriorating;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>Trash and debris are improperly stored or accumulated on the premises;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>Building shows visible signs of vandalism, such as graffiti;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(9)</num>
                <text>Presence of mold, algae, abandoned or wild animals, or insect or pest infestation; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(10)</num>
                <text>Any other criteria the Mayor deems relevant.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 59-1-ch1626" path="§5b">Apr. 14, 1906, 34 Stat. 115, ch. 1626, § 5b</annotation>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.06">
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>Section 6 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.06) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num codify:value="42-3131.06">6</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Registration of vacant buildings; renewal.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Except as provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06a">section 6a</code-cite>, the owner of a vacant building shall, within 90 days after it becomes vacant, register the building and pay the registration fee. The Mayor may extend the time for good cause.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Each application for the registration of a vacant building shall be in a form prescribed by the Mayor and shall contain the following information:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>The street address of the vacant building;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The date on which the building became vacant;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>The name, street address, telephone number, and electronic mailing address of the owner of record;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>The name, address, telephone number, and electronic mailing address of a person based in the District who is responsible for the security and maintenance of the property, if other than the owner of record; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(E)</num>
                  <text>A signed vacant building maintenance plan required pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.12">section 12</code-cite>.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>If at any time the information provided pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection is no longer valid, the owner shall file a new registration within 10 days containing current information. There shall be no additional fee to provide current information pursuant to this paragraph.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>At the time of application for the initial registration or renewal of registration of a vacant building, the owner shall arrange with the Mayor for the inspection of the building. On receiving an application for the initial registration or renewal of registration of a vacant building, the Mayor shall thereafter inspect the building. The Mayor shall approve the initial registration or the renewal of registration for one year if:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The application for registration contains all of the information required pursuant to subsection (b) of this section;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The building has been maintained in accordance with the requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.12">section 12</code-cite>;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The vacancy of the building will not:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Be detrimental to the public health, safety, and welfare;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Unreasonably interfere with the reasonable and lawful use and enjoyment of the other premises within the neighborhood; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Pose a hazard to police officers or firefighters entering the building in an emergency;</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The building complies with the fire, building, and housing codes of the District of Columbia;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>The continuance of any maintenance work or condition of occupancy is not dangerous to life or property;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>No false statements or misrepresentations have been made upon the registration application;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>Orders on a building have been complied with and the building complies with any applicable occupancy requirements; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>The Mayor is permitted to inspect the building before initial registration, during the registration period, and before a renewal of registration.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>If the owner of a vacant building fails to comply with the provisions of subsection (c) of this section, both initially and throughout the registration period, the Mayor may deny or revoke the owner's registration and may subject the owner to the penalties provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.10">section 10</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>After the initial designation of a property as vacant or blighted vacant, the Mayor shall not be required to perform additional inspections or surveys to sustain that classification.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>After the Mayor has made a final determination that a building is a vacant building or a blighted vacant building, that final determination shall remain in effect until the owner submits information to the Mayor sufficient to warrant a change to that classification.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, no person except the owner of record or an authorized agent of the owner of record, with proof of authorization from the owner of record, may register a building as vacant.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The Mayor, upon a showing that the owner of record is physically unable to register the property, may allow a relative of the owner of record to register the building as vacant; provided, that the relative can show proof of being a relative and, to the satisfaction of the Mayor, that the owner of record is physically unable to register the property.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>This subsection shall not in any way limit the Mayor's authority to register as vacant any property for which the owner failed to register it as required by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="42|31A">this act</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>A new section 6a is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="42|31A|II" after="§42-3131.06" num-value="42-3131.06a" history-prefix="as added"/>
            <num>6a</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Exemptions.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>A vacant building shall not be subject to the registration requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06">section 6</code-cite>, the registration fee pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.09">section 9</code-cite>, or the increased real property tax rates for vacant buildings set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-812|(b-10)">D.C. Official Code § 47-812(b-10)</code-cite>, if it is:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Owned by the government of the United States or its instrumentalities; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Authorized as exempt from real-estate taxes by the United States Department of State's Office of Foreign Missions on the basis of its use for diplomatic or consular purposes or for the official business of an international organization.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>A vacant building shall not be subject to the registration fee pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.09">section 9</code-cite> or the increased real property tax rates for vacant buildings set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-812|(b-10)">D.C. Official Code § 47-812(b-10)</code-cite> if it is:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Exempted by the Mayor in extraordinary circumstances and upon a showing of substantial economic or personal hardship as determined pursuant to subsection (c) of this section;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>In compliance with the requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.12">section 12</code-cite> and applicable property maintenance code standards for the District of Columbia, and, if a rental, properly licensed in accordance with applicable District regulations, and the owner or his or her agent has been actively seeking in good faith to rent or sell the building; provided, that an exemption under this paragraph shall only be available for a period not to exceed:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Half a tax year from the initial listing, offer, or advertisement of rent or sale in the case of a single-family residential building;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Two tax years from the initial listing, offer, or advertisement of rent or sale for a multifamily residential building; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Two tax years from the initial listing, offer, or advertisement of rent or sale for a commercial or mixed-use building;</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>For a period not to exceed 3 tax years, the subject of a probate proceeding or the title is the subject of litigation (not including a foreclosure of the right of redemption action brought under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|13A">Chapter 13A of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code)</code-cite>. The tax year in which the exemption under this paragraph commences is determined by the filing date of the applicable probate proceeding or litigation;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>For a period not to exceed 2 tax years, the subject of a pending application for a necessary approval for development before the Board of Zoning Adjustment, the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia, the Commission on Fine Arts, the Historic Preservation Review Board, the Mayor's Agent for Historic Preservation, the Department of Public Works, or the National Capital Planning Commission;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>For a period not to exceed half a tax year, a building for which the owner of the property or his or her agent has an active building permit application that is being reviewed and processed by the District, and the owner is actively seeking in good faith to obtain a building permit for the purposes of making the building fit for occupancy; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>For a period not to exceed 3 tax years, under active construction or undergoing active rehabilitation, renovation, or repair, and there is a valid active building permit to make the building fit for occupancy. During the period for which the exemption is requested, the building must be under active construction or undergoing active rehabilitation, renovation, or repair under a valid active building permit.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>An owner may qualify for an exemption for substantial economic or personal hardship by presenting evidence of such hardship to the Mayor. In making a determination of hardship, the Mayor may consider, but is not limited to, the following criteria:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>The owner was a debtor in an individual bankruptcy action within the last 12 months;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The owner experienced a significant medical event that prevented him or her from engaging in normal work or business activities for at least a period of 30 days;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>The owner was involuntarily terminated from employment and was unemployed for at least 60 days within the last 12 months;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>The owner is:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>60 years of age or older and is receiving social security disability insurance;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>65 years of age or older and has a household income that does not exceed 120% of the median family income and has experienced medical, personal, or financial hardship in the past 180 days;</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(E)</num>
                  <text>The owner was impacted by a fire at the property that was not the result of criminal activity or negligence as identified by a Fire and Emergency Medical Services investigation; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(F)</num>
                  <text>The owner was impacted by a natural disaster at the property.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>A hardship exemption pursuant to this subsection may be granted for a period not to exceed 2 tax years from the required registration date, subject to annual renewal on the basis of continuing extraordinary circumstances and substantial undue economic hardship. The Mayor may withdraw the exemption at any time.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>After granting a hardship exemption pursuant to this subsection, the Mayor shall publish notice of the hardship exemption in the District of Columbia Register. The notice shall contain the name of the owner, the address of the property, and the tax year in which the exemption applies.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The total cumulative time for exemptions granted under subsection (b) of this section to any property shall not exceed 5 tax years in any 12-year period.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>If a vacant building is owned by the District of Columbia or its instrumentalities, it shall be subject to the registration requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06">section 6</code-cite> and the maintenance requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.12">section 12</code-cite>, but not subject to the fee requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.09">section 9</code-cite>, the fines and penalties collected under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.10">section 10</code-cite>, or the increased real property tax rates for vacant buildings set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-812|(b-10)">D.C. Official Code § 47-812(b-10)</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 59-1-ch1626" path="§6a">Apr. 14, 1906, 34 Stat. 115, ch. 1626, § 6a</annotation>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.07">
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>Section 7 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.07) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.09">
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>Section 9 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.09) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num codify:value="42-3131.09">9</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Fees.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The owner of a vacant building shall register the building and pay registration fees within 90 days after it becomes a vacant building.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Fees for registration and renewal shall be as follows:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The initial registration fee shall be $350; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The renewal registration fee shall be $500.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The Mayor may increase the fees set forth in subsection (b) of this section through rules issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.21">section 21</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.10">
        <num>(h)</num>
        <text>Section 10 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.10) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num codify:value="42-3131.10">10</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Penalties for noncompliance.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The failure of the owner of a vacant building to pay all required fees under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.09">section 9</code-cite> after notice of the designation of the owner's building as vacant, the determination of delinquency of registration or fee payment, the denial or revocation of registration, the filing by an owner of any false or misleading registration-related information, or the refusal of the owner of a vacant building to permit the Mayor to inspect the building shall be subject to a civil penalty of up to $1,000 for the first violation, $2,500 for the second violation, and $5,000 for the third and subsequent violations.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The Director of the Department of Buildings shall provide the Office of the Attorney General with a list of all owners who fail to pay the required fee after notice.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>If the owner of a vacant building fails to maintain the building in compliance with the requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.12">section 12</code-cite> or, having obtained a vacant property registration, subsequently fails to comply with the other registration requirements under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06">section 6</code-cite>, the Mayor, in addition to issuing civil penalties pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, may:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Charge the owner with failure to comply and enforce all applicable penalties under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="42|31A">this act</code-cite>; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Take other action as required by the Construction Codes or Construction Codes Supplement of the District of Columbia to bring the building into compliance with those codes.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as additional sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of <span codify:value="§§">sections</span> <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06" codify:value="42-3131.06">6</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.08" codify:value="42-3131.08">8</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.09" codify:value="42-3131.09">9</code-cite>, or <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.12" codify:value="42-3131.12">12</code-cite>, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|18">the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Official Code § 2-1801.01 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>Criminal prosecutions under <span codify:value="§§">sections</span> <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.05" codify:value="42-3131.05">5</code-cite> through <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.21" codify:value="42-3131.21">21</code-cite> shall be brought in the name of the District of Columbia by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.11|(b)">
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Section 11(b) (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.11(b)) is amended by striking the phrase "Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs" and inserting the phrase "Department of Buildings" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs</find>
          <replace>Department of Buildings</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.12">
        <num>(j)</num>
        <text>Section 12 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.12) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num codify:value="42-3131.12">12</num>
            <heading>Vacant building maintenance standard and plan.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The owner of a vacant building shall comply with the following maintenance requirements:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The exterior of the building shall be maintained free of graffiti, tagging, or similar markings;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Exterior walls shall be free of holes, breaks, and loose or rotting materials;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The interior of the building, and the property on which the building is located, shall be free from debris, rubbish, and garbage;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>Exposed metal and wood surfaces on the exterior of the building and any accessory or appurtenant structures shall be protected from the elements and against decay or rust;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>The cornices, belt courses, corbels, terra cotta trim, wall facings, and similar decorative features shall be safe, anchored, and in good repair;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>All balconies, canopies, marquees, signs, metal awnings, stairways, fire escapes, standpipes, exhaust ducts, and similar features shall be in good repair, anchored, safe, and sound;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>Doors, windows, areaways, and other openings shall be weather-tight and secured against entry by birds, vermin, and trespassers, and missing or broken doors, windows, and other openings shall be covered with 1/2 inch CDX plywood that is painted in accordance with the predominant tone of the building and is weather protected, tightly fitted to the opening, and secured by screws or bolts;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>The roof and flashing shall be sound and tight, not admit moisture, and drained to prevent dampness or deterioration in the walls or interior;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(9)</num>
                <text>The building storm drainage system shall be adequately sized and installed in an approved manner and functional;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(10)</num>
                <text>The structural members shall be free of deterioration and capable of safely bearing imposed dead and live loads;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(11)</num>
                <text>The foundation walls shall be plumb, free from open cracks and breaks, and vermin-resistant;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(12)</num>
                <text>Chimneys, cooling towers, smokestacks, and similar appurtenances shall be structurally safe, sound, and in good repair;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(13)</num>
                <text>Openings in sidewalks shall be safe for pedestrian travel;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(14)</num>
                <text>The property on which the building is located shall be free from excessive vegetation; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(15)</num>
                <text>The property on which the building is located, as well as any accessory or appurtenant structures, shall be free from safety, health, or fire hazards.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The owner of a vacant property or his or her agent shall submit a vacant property maintenance plan with the registration form required pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06">section 6</code-cite>. The plan shall include the following:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The name, address, and contact information (telephone number and electronic mailing address where applicable) of the person submitting the plan;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Contact information for the person designated to manage and maintain the property;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>A copy of a letter or notice to properties abutting or immediately adjacent to the vacant building advising residents of the name and contact information of the person designated to manage and maintain the property;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>A plan for actively monitoring, maintaining, and securing the property for the anticipated or expected period of vacancy that demonstrates how the property will be maintained in accordance with subsection (a) of this section; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>Any other information deemed necessary by the Mayor for purposes of effectuating this section.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§202|(j)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="amendment to" display-template=""/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.15">
        <num>(k)</num>
        <text>Section 15 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.15) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num codify:value="42-3131.15">15</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Administrative review and appeal.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Within 15 days after the designation of an owner's building as a vacant building, the determination of delinquency of registration or fee payment, the denial or revocation of registration, or the designation of a vacant building as a blighted vacant building, the owner may petition the Mayor for reconsideration by filing the form prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Within 60 days after receiving a petition pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall issue a notice of final determination to the owner of the vacant building. The petition shall be deemed denied, and it shall have the same effect of the issuance of a notice of final determination, if the Mayor does not act upon the petition within 60 days.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Within 45 days after the date of the notice of final determination or within 45 days of the expiration of the time period set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection, an owner may file an appeal with the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia ("Real Property Tax Appeals Commission") on the form prescribed by the Mayor; provided, that the issuance of a notice of final determination or the failure of the Mayor to issue a notice of final determination within 60 days shall be a prerequisite to filing an appeal with the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission. The Real Property Tax Appeals Commission may not extend the time to file an appeal.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>After receiving a notice of appeal from an owner as required under subsection (b)(2) of this section, the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission shall provide by mail or electronic mail to the Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which the vacant building is located, at least 15 days before any scheduled hearing on the appeal, the following information related to the building at issue:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The name of the owner of the building, and the address of the building, including square, suffix and lot numbers;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The determination under review; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The date, time, and location of the hearing.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The District, through the Office of the Attorney General, may appeal a decision of the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia within 90 days after the receipt of a written decision.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.16">
        <num>(l)</num>
        <text>Section 16 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.16) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num codify:value="42-3131.16">16</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Transmission of list by Mayor.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>No less than once a week, the Mayor shall transmit to the Office of Tax and Revenue a list of buildings:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Registered or designated as vacant;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Designated as blighted vacant; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>For which the time period to issue a notice of final determination under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.15">section 15</code-cite> has expired or a notice of final determination has been issued under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.15">section 15</code-cite> and administrative appeals have been exhausted or expired.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The list shall be in the form and medium prescribed by the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>Buildings shall remain on the list required by this section until a change in classification is approved.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The Mayor and the Office of Tax and Revenue shall develop a procedure to reconcile any material differences between information retained by the Department of Buildings regarding buildings registered or designated as vacant or designated as blighted vacant, and buildings taxed as Class 3 or 4, on at least a monthly basis.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.17">
        <num>(m)</num>
        <text>Section 17 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.17) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.18">
        <num>(n)</num>
        <text>Section 18 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.18) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num codify:value="42-3131.18">18</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Publication of vacant and blighted vacant building information by the Department of Buildings.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The Department of Buildings shall maintain, on a publicly available website, a database or list of vacant buildings. The database or list shall, at a minimum, contain the following information:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The address of the building, including the square, suffix, and lot number of the property on which the building is located;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The Advisory Neighborhood Commission and Ward in which the building is located;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The date on which the building was designated a vacant building or blighted vacant building or registered as a vacant building pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06">section 6</code-cite>;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The type of exemption the building has received, the date on which the building received an exemption, and the number of half tax years the building has been exempt, if applicable;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>The number of months the building has been registered or designated as vacant or designated as blighted vacant;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>The last date on which the property was inspected by the Department; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>The current tax classification of the property.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§42-3131.19">
        <num>(o)</num>
        <text>Section 19 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.19) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(p)</num>
        <text>New sections 20 and 21 are added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="42|31A|II" after="§42-3131.19" num-value="42-3131.20" history-prefix="as added"/>
            <num>20</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Vacant and blighted vacant building receivership.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The Office of the Attorney General may, in the name of the District of Columbia, petition the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the appointment of a receiver to rehabilitate, demolish, or sell a vacant building, upon the occurrence of any of the following:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The vacant building is a nuisance property as defined in subsection (n) of this section;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>A vacant building is designated as blighted vacant and all appeal rights of this designation have been exhausted by the owner; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The vacant building is subject to a condemnation order by the Board for the Condemnation of Insanitary Buildings pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-903">section 3 of An Act To create a board for the condemnation of insanitary buildings in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved May 1, 1906 (34 Stat. 157; D.C. Official Code § 6-903)</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The Office of the Attorney General shall give notice to the owner of the building, and his or her appointed personal representative if applicable, no less than 90 days prior to the filing of a petition.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The petition for appointment of a receiver shall include:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A copy of the registration form or designation form;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Evidence that the owner failed to comply with the vacant building maintenance requirements under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.12">section 12</code-cite>, if applicable;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>A copy of the final order from the Office of Administrative Hearings, if applicable;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>A copy of the condemnation order issued by the Board for the Condemnation of Insanitary Buildings, if applicable; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>A verified pleading that identifies and states the qualifications of the proposed receiver.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The petition for the appointment of a receiver shall name as respondents:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The owner or owners of the property including, in the event the record owner is deceased and no personal representative of the deceased owner's estate has been appointed, an heir or legatee whose identity is revealed by a search in accordance with generally accepted standards of probate decisions of the Superior Court;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Any lien holder of record; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The plaintiff in a proceeding to foreclose the right of redemption; provided, that failure to name the plaintiff shall not prevent the action from going forward but shall prevent the receiver's lien for expenses incurred from rehabilitating, demolishing, or selling the building from having priority over the plaintiff's lien interest.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>After filing a petition and before a receiver is appointed, the Office of the Attorney General shall give notice of pendency and nature of the proceedings by certified mail to the last known addresses of all judgment creditors and lien holders with a recorded interest in the property. This notice is not required for respondents named under subsection (d) of this section.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Within 30 days after the date on which the notice was mailed, a judgment creditor or lien holder with a recorded interest in the property may apply to intervene in the proceeding and to be appointed a receiver. A creditor or lien holder whose interest is not recorded does not have standing to intervene in the proceeding and is not eligible to be appointed a receiver.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Failure to give notice to any judgment creditors or lien holders as required by this subsection shall not prevent the action from going forward but shall prevent the receiver's lien for expenses incurred from rehabilitating, demolishing, or selling the building from having priority over that person's lien interest.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>After a hearing, instead of appointing a receiver to rehabilitate, demolish, or sell the building, the Court may permit an owner, mortgagee, or other person with an interest in the property to rehabilitate or demolish it, if the person:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Demonstrates the ability and expertise to develop and supervise a viable financial and construction plan for the rehabilitation or demolition of the property within a reasonable time;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Agrees to comply with a specified schedule for rehabilitation or demolition of the building; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Posts bond, in an amount determined by the court, as security for the performance of the required work in compliance with a specified schedule.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>The Office of the Attorney General may apply to the court for immediate revocation of a person's appointment pursuant to this subsection if the person appointed is not proceeding with due diligence or in compliance with the specified schedule.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>In the event that the court revokes the person's appointment and appoints a receiver, the bond posted pursuant to paragraph (1)(C) of this subsection shall be applied to the subsequently appointed receiver's expenses for rehabilitating, demolishing, or selling the building.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(g)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>If no qualified person with an ownership interest requests an appointment to rehabilitate or demolish the property, or if an appointee is dismissed, the court shall appoint a receiver of the property for the purposes of rehabilitating and managing the property, demolishing the property, or selling it to a qualified bidder.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>On the appointment of a receiver to rehabilitate, demolish, or sell the property, all parties are divested from any authority to act in furtherance of those goals and the receiver shall assume all rights to possess and use the building, fixtures, furnishings, records, and other related property and goods that the owner or property manager would have if the receiver had not been appointed.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>A receiver appointed to rehabilitate, demolish, or sell a vacant building has no duty, and is not personally liable for failing, to maintain the property or protect the property from casualty or loss. The receiver shall be personally liable only for his or her acts of gross negligence or intentional wrongdoing in carrying out the receivership.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(h)</num>
              <text>A receiver appointed to rehabilitate or demolish a vacant building, in addition to all necessary and customary powers, has the right of possession with authority to:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Contract for necessary labor and supplies for rehabilitation or demolition.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Borrow money for rehabilitation or demolition from an approved lending institution or through a government agency or program, using the receiver's lien against the property as security;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Receive and accept grants or donations;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>Manage the property for a period of up to 2 years and apply the rent received to current operating expenses and to repayment of outstanding rehabilitation expenses; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>Foreclose on the receiver's lien or accept a deed in lieu of foreclosure.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A receiver may, in addition to all necessary and customary powers, sell the property to the highest bidder at public auction or convey the property to a land bank.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>If the receiver intends to sell the property to the high bidder at public auction, the receiver shall post a notice of a public auction 60 days prior to the date on which the auction will be held. The notice shall contain:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>The address of each building for sale at the public auction;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>A description of each building for sale at the public auction, including the size and type of the building;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>The minimum bid required to purchase each building at the public auction; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>Any other information deemed necessary by the receiver.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Before any sale, applicants to bid in a public auction shall demonstrate that:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>The applicants or proposed buyer have financial resources available to rehabilitate the property;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The applicants or proposed buyer have experience rehabilitating properties or have a contract or agreement with a person or organization that has experience rehabilitating properties; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>The applicants or proposed buyers do not have any outstanding property maintenance violations in the District, if applicable.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The receiver may charge a reasonable fee to applicants in connection with an application to bid at a public auction or in connection with the solicitation of offers for a private sale.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>After deducting the expenses of the sale, the amount of outstanding taxes and other government assessments, and the amount of the receiver's lien, the receiver shall apply the remaining proceeds of the sale, first to the petitioner's costs and expenses, and then to the liens against the property in order of priority.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(j)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Any costs or fees incurred by the receiver for purposes of rehabilitating, demolishing, or selling a building pursuant to this subsection shall be a lien against the property. The receiver's lien shall have priority over all other liens and encumbrances, except taxes or other government assessments. The receiver shall allow the Office of the Attorney General's costs and expenses, including reasonable attorneys' fees, to be paid to the extent that proceeds of a sale permit.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>A receiver may foreclose on the lien by a sale of the building at a public auction. After deducting the expenses of the sale, the receiver must apply the proceeds of the sale to the liens against the building, in order of priority.  In lieu of foreclosure, and only if the receiver has rehabilitated the building, an owner may pay the receiver's costs, fees, including attorneys' fees, and expenses or may transfer all ownership in the property to either the receiver or an agreed-on third party for an amount agreed to by all parties to the receivership as being the property's fair market value.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(k)</num>
              <text>Following court ratification of a sale made pursuant to subsection (i) of this section, the receiver shall sign a deed conveying title to the buyer, free and clear of all liens, judgments and other encumbrances. On court ratification of the sale, any secured interest of a lien or judgment creditor automatically attaches to the proceeds from the sale to the extent that those proceeds are available.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(l)</num>
              <text>Upon sale of the property, the receiver shall:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>File with the court a final accounting; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>At the same time, file a motion with the court to dismiss the action.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(m)</num>
              <text>The Office of the Attorney General may contract with a nonprofit or for-profit organization to act as a receiver pursuant to this section; provided, that any organization acting as a receiver shall:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Not be delinquent on any fees, fines, taxes, or financial penalties owed to the District; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Have:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Demonstrated experience with the management or sale of residential or commercial properties; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>If the receiver will rehabilitate or demolish properties, have demonstrated experience and capacity to develop and supervise a viable financial and construction plan for the rehabilitation or demolition of residential or commercial properties.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(n)</num>
              <text>For purposes of this section, a "nuisance property" means a vacant building that has been registered or designated as vacant for at least 24 months, excluding any building that is exempted from the registration fee and increased real property tax rates for vacant buildings pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06a|(b)">section 6a(b)</code-cite>, and for which either:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The owner has failed to comply with the vacant building maintenance requirements under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.12">section 12</code-cite>; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>A violation of the property maintenance code (12G DCMR § 101G <em>et seq</em>.) remains unabated for at least 30 days after the issuance of a final order by the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 59-1-ch1626" path="§20">Apr. 14, 1906, 34 Stat. 115, ch. 1626, § 20</annotation>
            <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§202|(p)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="42|31A|II" after="§42-3131.20" num-value="42-3131.21" history-prefix="as added"/>
            <num>21</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Rules.</heading>
            <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|I">Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>, may issue rules to implement <span codify:value="§§">sections</span> <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.05" codify:value="42-3131.05">5</code-cite> through <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.20" codify:value="42-3131.20">20</code-cite>. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove of the proposed rules, by resolution, within the 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved.</text>
            <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 59-1-ch1626" path="§21">Apr. 14, 1906, 34 Stat. 115, ch. 1626, § 21</annotation>
            <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§202|(p)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section codify:path="§47-825.01a|(e)|(1)|(B)">
      <num>203</num>
      <text>Section 47-825.01a(e)(1)(B) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="2">
        <para>
          <codify:replace/>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>If an owner is aggrieved by a notice of final determination issued pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.15">§ 42-3131.15</cite> or the time period to issue a notice of final determination under that section has expired, the owner may file an appeal on the determination of vacancy with the Commission within 45 days after the date of the notice or expiration. The Commission may not extend the time to file an appeal. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Commission shall render a decision on the appeal within 120 days after the filing.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>An appeal to the Commission under this subparagraph shall be on the same terms and under the same conditions, to the extent reasonable, as if the appeal were brought under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; except, that no worksheet shall be required to be mailed, the Department of Buildings shall be the responsible agency, and any supplemental filing shall be provided to the Commission and the Department of Buildings.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>A response from the Department of Buildings shall be available for inspection at least 7 days before the scheduled hearing.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>The Department of Buildings shall have the authority, as provided to OTR under subsection (f) of this section, to make redeterminations of vacancy and blight and any reclassifications that may be necessary.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(v)</num>
            <text>The Department of Buildings shall be entitled to a rehearing to establish the proper status, vacant or blight, and tax classification of the real property under the same conditions and to the same extent as under paragraph (6) of this subsection; provided, that paragraph (6)(D) of this subsection shall not apply.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </section>
    <section codify:path="§42-3171.01|(1A)">
      <num>204</num>
      <text>Section 431(1A) of the Abatement and Condemnation of Nuisance Properties Omnibus Amendment Act of 2000, effective April 19, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-114; D.C. Official Code § 42-3171.01(1A)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:replace/>
          <num>(1A)</num>
          <text>"Blighted area" means an area determined by the Mayor:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>To be unsafe or unsanitary;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>To have an excessive presence of abandoned properties or vacant buildings, unimproved lots, or substandard structures; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>By reason of deterioration, faulty planning, inadequate or improper facilities, deleterious land use, or the existence of unsafe structures, or any combination of these factors, to be otherwise detrimental to the public health, safety, or welfare.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>III</num>
    <heading>VACANT AND BLIGHTED PROPERTY INCENTIVES AND TAXES.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>A</num>
      <heading>EXPEDITED PERMIT REVIEW FOR VACANT AND BLIGHTED PROPERTIES.</heading>
      <section codify:path="6|14|I">
        <num>301</num>
        <text>The Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986, effective March 21, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-216; D.C. Official Code § 6-1401 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended by adding a new section 10e to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:insert after="§6-1413" num-value="6-1414" history-prefix="as added"/>
            <num>10e</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Expedited permit review for vacant and blighted vacant properties.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>No later than 180 days after the applicability date of this section, the Department shall establish an expedited permit review process for permits described in subsection (b) of this section; provided, that the expedited permit review process shall only apply to permits for Class 3 and Class 4 properties registered as vacant.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The following permits shall be eligible for an expedited permit review process established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A demolition permit;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>A raze permit;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>An addition, alteration, and repair permit;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>An alteration and repair permit;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>A sheeting and shoring permit;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>A new building permit; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>Trade permits.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The Department shall not charge additional fees beyond the standard permit fees for eligible applicants to utilize the expedited permit review process established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
            </para>
            <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-216" type="History" path="§10e">Mar. 21, 1987, D.C. Law 6-216, § 10e</annotation>
            <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§301" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </section>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>B</num>
      <heading>VACANT AND BLIGHTED PROPERTY TAX RATES.</heading>
      <section>
        <num>302</num>
        <text>Chapter 8 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="§47-812">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>Section 47-812 is amended by adding a new subsection (b-13) to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(b-12)" num-value="(b-13)"/>
              <num>(b-13)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the sum of the real property tax rates and special property tax rates for taxable Class 3 Properties in the District of Columbia for the tax year beginning October 1, 2027, and each tax year thereafter, shall be as follows:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>For the first year in which the property is registered or designated as vacant, the tax rate shall be $2 for each $100 of assessed value.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>For the second year in which the property is registered or designated as vacant, the tax rate shall be $3 for each $100 of assessed value.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>For the third year in which the property is registered or designated as vacant, the tax rate shall be $4 for each $100 of assessed value.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>For the fourth year, and any subsequent years, in which the property is registered or designated as vacant, the tax rate shall be $5 for each $100 of assessed value.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the sum of the real property tax rates and special real property tax rates for taxable Class 4 Properties in the District of Columbia for the tax year beginning October 1, 2027, and each year thereafter, shall be as follows:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>For the first year in which the property is designated as blighted vacant, the tax rate shall be $4 for each $100 of assessed value.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>For the second year in which the property is designated as blighted vacant, the tax rate shall be $6 for each $100 of assessed value.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>For the third year in which the property is designated as blighted vacant, the tax rate shall be $8 for each $100 of assessed value.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>For the fourth year, and any subsequent years, in which the property is designated as blighted vacant, the tax rate shall be $10 for each $100 of assessed value.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The Department of Buildings, when certifying real properties to the Office of Tax and Revenue as vacant or blighted vacant under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.16">§ 42-3131.16</cite>, shall further delineate the applicable tax rate for the applicable half tax year for each real property.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>For purposes of determining the applicable tax rate under paragraphs (1) or (2) of this subsection, an exemption period or period during which real property was not properly classified shall be counted as years during which a property was registered or designated as vacant or designated as blighted vacant, if:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>The real property receives an exemption from the tax rates established by this subsection pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06a|(b)">§ 42-3131.06a(b)</code-cite>, and:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>The Department of Buildings withdraws the exemption; or</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>The applicable exemption period expires and the property remains vacant or blighted vacant; or</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The real property was not properly classified as Class 3 or 4 because the owner of the real property filed false or misleading registration-related information.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§302|(a)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="amendment to" display-template=""/>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="§47-813">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Section 47-813 is amended as follows:</text>
          <para codify:path="(c-9)">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Subsection (c-9) is amended as follows:</text>
            <para codify:path="(2)|(A)">
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Paragraph (2)(A) is amended as follows:</text>
              <include lvl="1">
                <para>
                  <num>(2)</num>
                  <para>
                    <codify:replace/>
                    <num>(A)</num>
                    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph and subject to paragraphs (4) and (5) of this subsection, Class 1A Property shall be comprised of:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(i)</num>
                      <text>Residential real property that is improved and its legal use is for nontransient residential dwelling purposes, and that is not Class 1B Property; provided, that such property may be used to host transient guests pursuant to an unexpired short-term rental license endorsement issued pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§30-201.04">§ 30-201.04</cite>; or</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(ii)</num>
                      <text>Real property or a portion of real property for which a raze permit, a demolition permit, a sheeting and shoring permit, or a building permit has been issued:</text>
                      <para>
                        <num>(I)</num>
                        <text>In order to construct a new improvement for predominantly nontransient residential dwelling purpose; or</text>
                      </para>
                      <para>
                        <num>(II)</num>
                        <text>To substantially rehabilitate that portion or all of an existing improvement for exclusively nontransient residential dwelling purposes.</text>
                      </para>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </include>
              <aftertext>.</aftertext>
            </para>
            <para codify:path="(4)">
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Paragraph (4) is amended to read as follows:</text>
              <include lvl="1">
                <para>
                  <codify:replace/>
                  <num>(4)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(A)</num>
                    <text>Class 3 property shall be comprised of all improved real property that appears as vacant on the list compiled under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.16|(a)|(1)">§ 42-3131.16(a)(1)</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(B)</num>
                    <text>The Office of Tax and Revenue may request the Mayor to inspect improved real property to determine whether the property is correctly registered or designated as vacant on the list compiled under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.16|9(a)|(1)">§ 42-3131.16(a)(1)</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </include>
              <aftertext>.</aftertext>
            </para>
            <para codify:path="(5)">
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>Paragraph (5) is amended to read as follows:</text>
              <include lvl="1">
                <para>
                  <num>(5)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(A)</num>
                    <text>Class 4 Property shall be comprised of all improved real property that appears as blighted vacant on the list compiled under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.16|(a)|(2)">§ 42-3131.16(a)(2)</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(B)</num>
                    <text>The Office of Tax and Revenue may request the Mayor to inspect improved real property to determine whether the property is correctly designated as blighted vacant on the list compiled under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.16|(a)|(2)">§ 42-3131.16(a)(2)</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </include>
              <aftertext>.</aftertext>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para codify:path="(d-1)">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Subsection (d-1) is amended as follows:</text>
            <para codify:path="(4A)">
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Paragraph (4A) is amended by striking the phrase "under § 42-3131.16 or § 42-3131.17" and inserting the phrase "under § 42-3131.16" in its place.</text>
              <codify:find-replace count="1">
                <find>under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.16">§ 42-3131.16</cite> or <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.17">§ 42-3131.17</cite></find>
                <replace>under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.16">§ 42-3131.16</cite></replace>
              </codify:find-replace>
            </para>
            <para codify:path="(5)">
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Paragraph (5)(A-i), (B), and (C) are amended to read follows:</text>
              <include lvl="2">
                <para>
                  <codify:replace path="(A-i)"/>
                  <num>(A-i)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>Whenever the classification of improved real property that appears on a list compiled under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.16">§ 42-3131.16</cite> shall change to Class 3 or Class 4 Property:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(I)</num>
                      <text>The owner shall notify the Department of Buildings within 30 days of the change by making application to register the property as vacant under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06">§ 42-3131.06</cite>, and the change in classification of the real property to Class 3 or 4 Property shall be retroactive to the half tax year during which one of the following first occurred:</text>
                      <para>
                        <num>(aa)</num>
                        <text>The owner of the real property registered the real property as vacant under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06">§ 42-3131.06</cite>; or</text>
                      </para>
                      <para>
                        <num>(bb)</num>
                        <text>The owner of real property received a notice of final determination under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.15">§ 42-3131.15</cite>, or the time period to issue a notice of final determination under that section has expired;</text>
                      </para>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(II)</num>
                      <text>The Office of Tax and Revenue shall re-classify the real property without limitation for each tax year or half tax year after receipt of the list under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.16">§ 42-3131.16</cite>; and</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(III)</num>
                      <text>Penalty and interest as prescribed under § 47-811(c) shall be assessed beginning 30 days after the date of the real property tax bill that issues after any administrative appeals have been exhausted.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>Whenever improved real property that appears on a list compiled under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.16">§ 42-3131.16</cite> shall cease to be Class 3 or Class 4 Property, the owner shall notify the Department of Buildings within 30 days after the change in the manner as may be prescribed by the Mayor. If the request for a change in classification is approved, the change in classification of the real property from Class 3 or Class 4 Property shall be retroactive to the half tax year when the Department of Buildings was so notified. If the request is denied, the owner shall have a right to administrative review of the determination as provided under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.15">§ 42-3131.15</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <codify:replace path="(B)"/>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A-i) of this paragraph, if the real property is transferred and continued to qualify for the classification 30 days or less before the date of execution of the deed of transfer, the grantor shall not be required to notify the applicable agency of the change in classification.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <codify:replace path="(C)"/>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>If the tax is paid within 30 days of the corresponding bill, timely notification of the change in classification shall preclude assessment of penalty and interest.</text>
                </para>
              </include>
              <aftertext>.</aftertext>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para codify:path="(d-2)">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The lead-in language of subsection (d-2) is amended by striking the phrase "Class 3 Property or Class 4 Property," and inserting the phrase "Class 2 Property, Class 3 Property, or Class 4 Property," in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace count="1">
              <find>Class 3 Property or Class 4 Property,</find>
              <replace>Class 2 Property, Class 3 Property, or Class 4 Property,</replace>
            </codify:find-replace>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>A new subsection (d-3) is added to read as follows:</text>
            <include>
              <para>
                <codify:insert after="(d-2)" num-value="(d-3)"/>
                <num>(d-3)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(1)</num>
                  <text>If real property changes classification to Class 1A Property as defined in subsection (c-9)(2)(A)(ii) during the period of:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(A)</num>
                    <text>October 1 through March 31 of the tax year, the newly reclassified Class 1A Property, or the portion thereof used exclusively for residential purposes if already improved or assessed under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-829">§ 47-829</cite>, shall be taxed at the Class 1A Property tax rate for the entire tax year; or</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(B)</num>
                    <text>April 1 through September 30 of the tax year, the newly reclassified Class 1A Property, or the portion thereof used exclusively for residential purposes if already improved or assessed under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-829">§ 47-829</cite>, shall be taxed at the Class 1A Property tax rate for the second installment only.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(2)</num>
                  <text>The owner shall apply for a change of classification to Class 1A Property as defined in subsection (c-9)(2)(A)(ii) of this section and shall promptly provide complete documentation in a manner prescribed by the Chief Financial Officer to substantiate any such classification change before it shall be effective.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(3)</num>
                  <text>A change in classification to Class 1A Property as defined in subsection (c-9)(2)(A)(ii) of this section shall be effective beginning in the half tax year for which application is made under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(4)</num>
                  <text>If change in classification to Class 1A Property as defined in subsection (c-9)(2)(A)(ii) of this section is determined to be erroneous because the real property was not put to predominantly residential use 3 years from issuance of the permit, the Chief Financial Officer shall reclassify and tax the real property without limitation for each tax year or half tax year in which the real property was improperly classified as Class 1A Property, subject only to subsection (d-1)(5)(A-i) of this section, if the property is determined to be Class 3 Property or Class 4 Property, or subsection (d-2) of this section. In the event of such reclassification, penalty and interest shall be added beginning from the day the correct amount of tax should have been due but not paid if the property had been properly classified.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(5)</num>
                  <text>Within 45 days from the date of the notice of denial of Class 1A Property reclassification under this subsection, the owner may petition for an administrative review of the rescission or denial and appeal from a final determination thereof to the same extent as if the appeal were filed under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-825.01a|(d)|(2)">§ 47-825.01a(d)(2)</code-cite>.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(6)</num>
                  <text>Notwithstanding the time limitations in paragraphs (4) and (5) of this subsection, the Chief Financial Officer, in his or her discretion, may grant an extension of time to comply or waive penalty and interest assessed pursuant to paragraph (4) of this subsection to prevent an undue hardship to the owner.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(7)</num>
                  <text>The provisions of this subsection, subsection (c-9)(2)(A)(ii) of this section, and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-829">§ 47-829</cite> shall not supersede the requirement to timely file for mixed-use classification for the upcoming tax year pursuant to subsection (f) of this section, when the annual assessment for such upcoming tax year is made under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-824">§ 47-824</cite> and the certificate of occupancy (final or temporary) was issued.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§302|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="amendment to" display-template=""/>
        </para>
      </section>
    </container>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="47|13A" after="IV" history="false">
      <container>
        <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
        <num>V</num>
        <heading>Foreclosure by the Office of the Attorney General of Class 3 and 4 Properties.</heading>
      </container>
    </codify:insert>
    <container>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>C</num>
      <heading>FORECLOSURE BY THE OFFICE OF THE ATTORNEY GENERAL OF VACANT AND BLIGHTED PROPERTIES.</heading>
      <section>
        <num>303</num>
        <text>Chapter 13A of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The table of contents is amended by adding a new subchapter designation to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <container>
              <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
              <num>V</num>
              <heading>Foreclosure by the Office of the Attorney General of Class 3 and 4 Properties.</heading>
              <toc>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1390</num>
                  <heading>Eligibility to foreclose on a Class 3 or 4 Property.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1391</num>
                  <heading>Pre-complaint notice; publication requirements.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1392</num>
                  <heading>Complaint form.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1393</num>
                  <heading>Parties; service of process.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1394</num>
                  <heading>Notice by publication.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1395</num>
                  <heading>Foreclosure proceedings.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1396</num>
                  <heading>Entry of judgment.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1397</num>
                  <heading>Post-judgment conveyance or sale; excess.</heading>
                </section>
              </toc>
            </container>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="§47-1330">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Section 47-1330 is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>New paragraphs (1A) and (1B) are added to read as follows:</text>
            <include lvl="1">
              <para>
                <codify:insert after="(1)" num-value="(1A)"/>
                <num>(1A)</num>
                <text>"Class 3 property" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-813|(c-9)|(4)|(A)">§ 47-813(c-9)(4)(A)</cite>.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <codify:insert after="(1A)" num-value="(1B)"/>
                <num>(1B)</num>
                <text>"Class 4 property" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-813|(c-9)|(5)|(A)">§ 47-813(c-9)(5)(A)</cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (4A) is redesignated as Paragraph (4B)</text>
            <codify:insert after="(4A)">
              <para>
                <num>(4B)</num>
                <text>“Premises address” means the address, if any, for the square, suffix, and lot numbers, or parcel and lot numbers, of real property as reflected in the records in the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
              </para>
            </codify:insert>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>A new paragraph (4A) is added to read as follows:</text>
            <include lvl="1">
              <para>
                <codify:replace path="(4A)"/>
                <num>(4A)</num>
                <text>"Interested party" means any person having an interest in real property:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Who last appears as owner of the property on the Office of Tax and Revenue's real property records;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Who is a mortgagee of the property or assignee of a mortgage of record;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Who is holder of a beneficial interest in a deed of trust recorded against the property; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>Whose identity and address are:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>Reasonably ascertainable from land records with the Recorder of Deeds;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>Revealed by a full title search going back in time at least 50 years; or</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iii)</num>
                    <text>In the event a record owner is deceased and no personal representative of the deceased owner's estate has been appointed, revealed by a search in accordance with generally accepted standards of probate decisions of the Superior Court.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
            <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="amendment to" display-template=""/>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="§47-1332|(c)">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>Section 47-1332(c) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:replace/>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The Mayor shall not sell any real property if:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A forbearance authorization has been approved in writing by the Mayor for the applicable tax sale;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The owner enters into a payment plan pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-811.05">§ 47-811.05</cite> prior to the date of the tax sale;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>For an improved Class 1A or 1B Property, the tax amount to be sold is less than $4,000;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The real property is a Class 1A or 1B Property that is receiving a homestead deduction, with respect to which there is an outstanding non-void certificate of sale; provided, that no real property shall be excluded from sale solely pursuant to this paragraph if the non-void certificate of sale has been outstanding for 3 years or more; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>For a Class 3 or Class 4 property registered or designated as vacant or designated as blighted vacant, the owner has been delinquent for less than one year and the right to appeal a final determination of vacancy or blight has been exhausted by the owner.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(c)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="amendment to" display-template=""/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>A new subchapter V is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <container>
              <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
              <num>V</num>
              <heading>Foreclosure by the Attorney General of Class 3 and 4 Properties.</heading>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|13A|V" num-value="47-1390"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1390</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Eligibility to foreclose on a Class 3 or 4 Property.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Office of the Attorney General ("Office") shall file a complaint with the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to foreclose the right of redemption for a Class 3 or 4 property for which there is a real property tax delinquency after:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>The expiration of one year from the date of delinquency;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>The right to appeal a final determination of vacancy or blight has been exhausted by the owner; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>The Mayor has provided notice pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1391">§ 47-1391</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>The Office may decline to file a complaint with Superior Court, or may dismiss a pending complaint, if the Office ascertains, through application by an interested party or pursuant to the Office's own review and investigation, that:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>An interested party paid the amount set forth in the pre-complaint notice provided pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1391">§ 47-1391</cite>;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>An interested party proves that the real property identified in the pre-complaint notice provided pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1391">§ 47-1391</cite> meets the definition of occupied in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.05|(8)|(A)">§ 42-3131.05(8)(A)</cite>;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>An interested party proves:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>A failure of the Mayor to mail the notices required by §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1341|(a)">47-1341(a)</cite> or <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1391">47-1391</cite>; or</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>That the mailing address of the person who last appears as the record owner of the real property on the tax roll, as properly updated by the record owner by the filing of a change of address with the Office of Tax and Revenue in accordance with <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-405">§ 42-405</cite>, was not correctly or substantively updated by the Office of Tax and Revenue notwithstanding proper filing;</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(4)</num>
                    <text>The foreclosure would result in substantial personal and economic hardship;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(5)</num>
                    <text>An interested party has the intent and ability to return and occupy, rehabilitate, or sell the property within one year's time; or</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(6)</num>
                    <text>Proceeding with the foreclosure would not be in the best interest of the District, including because it would delay the Office's ability to timely pursue foreclosure litigation on other nuisance properties.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(c)</num>
                  <text>After declining to file a complaint or dismissing a complaint pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, the Office shall publish notice of the action in the District of Columbia Register.  The notice shall contain the name of the owner, the address of the property, and the date on which the exemption from immediate sale was approved or the date on which the pending complaint was dismissed.".</text>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(d)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|13A|V" after="§47-1390" num-value="47-1391"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1391</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Pre-complaint notice; publication requirements.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>No less than 90 days prior to the filing of a complaint with the Court pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1392">§ 47-1392</cite>, the Mayor shall send written notice to the owner or owners of record of the property at such owner's mailing address as updated in the Office of Tax and Revenue's real property records.</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>The notice shall inform the owner or owners of record of the property of the intent to file a complaint to foreclose the right of redemption. The notice shall also contain the amount of real property tax due as of the day of the notice and state that the owner may enter into a real property tax payment plan pursuant to § 47-811.05 or pay the amount due, together with any additional interest and penalties, which may be owed prior to the filing date to halt the filing of a complaint pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1392">§ 47-1392</cite>.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>The written notice pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be sent by first class or certified mail.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>At any time after 60 days from the mailing of the notice required by subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall cause to be advertised once in not fewer than 2 newspapers of general circulation in the District that are published once every 2 weeks, notice that the listed property will be subject to foreclosure proceedings due to delinquent real property taxes.</text>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(d)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|13A|V" after="§47-1391" num-value="47-1392"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1392</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Complaint form.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>A complaint filed to foreclose the right of redemption for a Class 3 or 4 Property based on a real property tax delinquency shall, for each property listed in the complaint, contain:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>A description of the real property, by premises address, taxation square, suffix, and lot number, or parcel and lot number;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>The names and last known addresses of all interested parties with an interest in the property and, if applicable, a statement that the address of a particular interested party is unknown;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(C)</num>
                      <text>A statement that the real property taxes are delinquent at the time of filing and the amount of taxes owed, including interest and penalties;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(D)</num>
                      <text>The fact that the real property has not been redeemed by an interested party; and</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(E)</num>
                      <text>A request that the Court pass a judgment to foreclose the right of redemption of all interested parties with an interest in the real property.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>Proof that the property has been registered or designated as vacant or designated as blighted vacant and taxed as Class 3 or Class 4 shall be attached to the complaint and shall be made part of the complaint.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>A copy of the notice issued pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1391">§ 47-1391</cite> shall be attached to the complaint and shall be made part of the complaint.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>A complaint filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section may be amended to include all delinquent taxes on the real property after the commencement of the foreclosure action.</text>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(d)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|13A|V" after="§47-1392" num-value="47-1393"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1393</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Parties; service of process.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <text>The plaintiff in a complaint filed pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1392">§ 47-1392</cite> shall be the District.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>Each interested party with an interest in the property shall be named as a defendant.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>The title of the complaint shall display the last known address of each defendant, as obtained from:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>Any record examined as part of the title examination for the property;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>The real property records with Office of Tax and Revenue or land records with the Recorder of Deeds; and</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(C)</num>
                      <text>Any other likely address that is known to the District.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>Other than the methods described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the District is not required to conduct any further investigations or to search any additional record to ascertain an address for a defendant prior to filing the complaint and undertaking the publication and notice as specified in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1394">§ 47-1394</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(c)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>Notice to a defendant may be made in any other manner that results in actual notice of the pendency of the action.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>If notice is made pursuant to this subsection, the Office of the Attorney General shall file an affidavit with the Court certifying the notice with a description of the method of service used and the time of service.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(d)</num>
                  <text>When the owner of a real property cannot be reasonably ascertained, the unknown owner to the property may be included as a defendant by the following designation:</text>
                  <text>"Unknown owner of [identify the nature of the interest: fee simple, leasehold, or reversionary] interest in the property [give a description of the property in substantially the same form as the description that appears on the pre-complaint notice], the unknown owner's heirs, devisees, and personal representatives and their or any of their heirs, devisees, executors, administrators, grantees, assigns, or successors in right, title, and interest."</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(e)</num>
                  <text>Any complaint filed pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1392">§ 47-1392</cite> against an unknown owner shall attach to it an affidavit by the person making the search stating at a minimum that:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>The owner of the real property is unknown; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>A complete search of records for at least 50 years immediately before the filing of the action was performed in accordance with generally accepted standards of title examination of the records of the Recorder of Deeds and the probate decisions of the Superior Court.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(d)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|13A|V" after="§47-1393" num-value="47-1394"/>
                <num>47-1394</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Notice by publication.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <text>At the same time the summons (or initial summons) is issued, the Office of the Attorney General shall obtain an order of publication directed to all defendants, naming them as provided in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1393">§ 47-1393</cite>. The order of publication shall:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>Describe the real property in the same manner in which it is described in the complaint;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>Warn any person that has or claims to have an interest in the property:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>To answer the complaint or to redeem the property on or before the date specified in the order of publication; and</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>That, in the case of failure to appear, answer, or redeem the property, a judgment will be entered to foreclose the right of redemption and order ownership of the real property to be vested in the Mayor.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>The date specified in paragraph (2)(A) of this subsection may not be less than 60 days from the issuance of the order of publication.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(4)</num>
                    <text>When the order of publication is issued and published, any person that has any right, title, interest, claim, lien, or equity of redemption in the property is bound by the judgment of the court that may be passed in the case as if the person were personally served with process.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(5)</num>
                    <text>The order of publication shall be in substantially the following form:</text>
                  </para>
                  <aftertext proof="needed">Order of Publication:</aftertext>
                  <aftertext proof="needed">The object of this proceeding is to secure the foreclosure of all rights of redemption in and vest title in the Mayor to the following real property:</aftertext>
                  <aftertext proof="needed">[Insert description of property in substantially the same form as the description that appears in the complaint.]</aftertext>
                  <aftertext proof="needed">The complaint states that the property has been registered or designated as vacant or designated as blighted vacant and taxed as Class 3 or Class 4, taxes are delinquent, and the real property has not been redeemed.</aftertext>
                  <aftertext proof="needed">It is thereupon this ... day of...., 20.., by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, ordered, that notice be given by the insertion of a copy of this order in some newspaper having a general circulation in the District of Columbia, once a week for 3 successive weeks, notifying all persons interested in the real property appear in this Court by the ... day of...., 20.., and redeem the real property by payment of $... or answer the complaint or, thereafter, a final judgment will be entered foreclosing the right of redemption in the real property and vesting in the District a title in fee simple.</aftertext>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>Upon issuance of the order of publication pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Office of the Attorney General shall send a copy of the order to each defendant, at the defendant's last known address, by first class or certified mail, postage prepaid.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>This subsection only applies to instances when the Office of the Attorney General has ascertained a defendant's last known address.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(d)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|13A|V" after="§47-1394" num-value="47-1395"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1395</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Foreclosure proceedings.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>If a hearing is scheduled, any interested party has the right to be heard and contest the delinquency of the taxes or the adequacy of the proceedings.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>The hearing described in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall occur at least 30 days after the filing of the complaint and 60 days from the date of the order of publication.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>A guardian ad litem shall be appointed to serve for all interested parties who are or may be minors, or who have been adjudicated incompetent at the date of filing such a list.</text>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(d)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|13A|V" after="§47-1395" num-value="47-1396"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1396</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Entry of judgment.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>In the event that no interested party provides an answer or, if after a hearing on the pleadings and affidavits, the Court finds that the Office of the Attorney General sent notice and a copy of the complaint to each interested party, service of process and other notice requirements have been met, and the information set forth in the complaint is accurate, the Court shall enter a judgment finding:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>That proper notice has been provided to all interested parties;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>The real property has been registered or designated as vacant or designated as blighted vacant and taxed as Class 3 or Class 4; and</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(C)</num>
                      <text>The real property was not redeemed by an interested party; and</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>Order that the ownership of the real property be transferred to the Mayor in fee simple title.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>The judgment entered pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be final and conclusive on all defendants, their heirs, devisees, and personal representatives and they, or any of their heirs, devisees, executors, administrators, assigns, or successors in right, title, or interest shall be bound by the judgment as if they had been named in the action and personally served with process.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(c)</num>
                  <text>After entry of a judgment pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall record a judgment transferring title to the Mayor in the land records with the Recorder of Deeds.</text>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(d)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|13A|V" after="§47-1396" num-value="47-1397"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1397</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Post-judgment conveyance or sale; excess.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <text>After obtaining and recording a judgment pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1396">§ 47-1396</cite>, the Mayor may:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>Convey the property to a land bank; or</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>Sell the real property at a public auction pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>If the Mayor intends to sell a real property at a public auction, the Mayor shall publicly notice any Class 3 and 4 Properties that will be sold at a public auction as follows:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>In not fewer than 2 newspapers of general circulation in the District that are published once every 2 weeks, the Mayor shall publish a public notice stating the listed real property will be sold at public auction and at the place named in the public notice; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>The Mayor shall include the real property in a list of real property published on the Office of Tax and Revenue's website. The listing shall contain the following:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>A description of the real property, by premises address, taxation square, suffix, and lot number, or parcel and lot number;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>The name of the person who last appears on the Mayor's tax roll as the owner of the real property; and</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(C)</num>
                      <text>The minimum bid required to purchase the property.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>The Mayor may sell the real property at auction for an amount less than that required from the owner to redeem the real property.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(4)</num>
                    <text>Before any sale at a public auction, the potential purchaser shall demonstrate that:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>He or she has the financial resources available to rehabilitate the property;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>He or she has experience rehabilitating properties or has a contract or agreement with a person or organization that has experience rehabilitating properties;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(C)</num>
                      <text>He or she does not have any unresolved notices of infractions related to housing code or property maintenance violations in the District, if applicable; and</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(D)</num>
                      <text>He or she is current on all taxes and liabilities owed to the District.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(5)</num>
                    <text>Before making any bid, a potential purchaser shall have on deposit 20% of the purchase price. The deposit shall guarantee full and final settlement for the purchase. If the required deposit is not sufficient, the real property shall be immediately re-auctioned.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(6)</num>
                    <text>The person making the highest bid shall pay the full bid amount to the District of Columbia within 5 business days after the last day of the sale. If the payment is not received within 5 days after the last day of the sale, 20% of the deposit of the defaulting purchaser shall be forfeited to the District, and the real property shall be deemed to have been bid off to and purchased by the Mayor in the name of the District.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(7)</num>
                    <text>If the highest bid for a property sold pursuant to this subsection exceeds the amount of taxes due on the real property, the excess must be refunded, following payment of any recorded liens, to the owner of the record of the property. In the event that no claim for the excess is received by the Mayor within 3 years after the date of the sale, the Chief Financial Officer shall deposit the excess in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(8)</num>
                    <text>After payment is received, the Mayor shall issue a deed for any property purchased by a bidder at a sale held pursuant to this section. The deed shall be prima facie evidence of a good and perfect title in fee simple to the real property.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(c)</num>
                  <text>Real property conveyed to a Land Bank or sold at a public auction pursuant to this section shall be conveyed or sold:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>"As is." There is no guarantee or warranty of any kind, express or implied, relative to: eligibility to build upon or subdivide the property; zoning classification; size; location; fitness for any use or purpose; or any other feature or condition of a foreclosed property sold pursuant to this section; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>To the highest bidder, if the real property is sold at a public auction.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(d)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
            </container>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </section>
    </container>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="47|18" after="XVIII" history="false">
      <container>
        <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
        <num>XIX</num>
        <heading>Vacant and Blighted Property Rehabilitation Credit.</heading>
      </container>
    </codify:insert>
    <container>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>D</num>
      <heading>VACANT AND BLIGHTED HOME REVITALIZATION TAX CREDIT.</heading>
      <section>
        <num>304</num>
        <text>Chapter 18 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The table of contents is amended by adding a new subchapter designation to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <container>
              <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
              <num>XIX</num>
              <heading>Vacant and Blighted Property Rehabilitation Credit."</heading>
              <toc>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1819.01</num>
                  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1819.02</num>
                  <heading>Credit established.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1819.03</num>
                  <heading>Annual cap.</heading>
                </section>
                <section>
                  <num>47-1819.04</num>
                  <heading>Application and Mayoral certification.</heading>
                </section>
              </toc>
            </container>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>A new subchapter XIX is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <container>
              <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
              <num>XIX</num>
              <heading>Vacant and Blighted Property Rehabilitation Credit.</heading>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|18|XIX" num-value="47-1819.01"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1819.01</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
                  <text>For purposes of §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1819.01">47-1819.01</cite> through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1819.04">47-1819.04</cite>, the term:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>"Area median family income" means the median family income for the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development, adjusted for household size.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>"Class 3 property" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-813|(c-9)|(4)|(A)">§ 47-813(c-9)(4)(A)</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>"Class 4 property" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-813|(c-9)|(5)|(A)">§ 47-813(c-9)(5)(A)</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(4)</num>
                    <text>"Eligible development costs" means amounts paid or incurred by an eligible taxpayer after December 31, 2026, for the acquisition, construction, substantial rehabilitation, demolition of structures located on, or environmental remediation of an eligible property.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(5)</num>
                    <text>"Eligible property" means a Class 3 or 4 property registered or designated as vacant or designated as blighted vacant that is:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>A house comprised of 4 or fewer residential units or a condominium unit; and</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>Located in a qualifying census tract as determined by the Mayor as of the date of the application pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1819.04">§ 47-1819.04</cite>.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(6)</num>
                    <text>"Eligible taxpayer" means a taxpayer certified by the Mayor pursuant <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1819.04|(b)">§ 47-1819.04(b)</cite> as eligible to claim the credit established under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|18|XIX">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(7)</num>
                    <text>"Qualifying census tract" means a census tract which has:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(A)</num>
                      <text>A median family income which does not exceed 80% of the median family income of the District;</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(B)</num>
                      <text>A poverty rate that is not less than 130% of the poverty rate of the District; and</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(C)</num>
                      <text>A median value for owner-occupied homes that does not exceed the median value for all owner-occupied homes in the District.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(8)</num>
                    <text>"Substantial rehabilitation" means amounts paid or incurred for rehabilitation of an eligible property if such amounts exceed $150,000.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§304|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|18|XIX" after="§47-1819.01" num-value="47-1819.02"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1819.02</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Credit established.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <text>For tax years beginning after December 31, 2026, there is established a District of Columbia vacant and blighted home revitalization tax credit that may be claimed against taxes imposed under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|18">this chapter</cite>.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>The amount of the credit shall be 50% of the eligible development costs as certified by the Mayor to the Chief Financial Officer pursuant to § 47-1819.04(b).</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(c)</num>
                  <text>The credit may exceed the tax liability under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|18">this chapter</cite>, including any minimum tax due under §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1807.02|(b)">47-1807.02(b)</cite> or <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1801.03|(b)">47-1808.03(b)</cite>, for that taxable year and shall be refundable to the eligible taxpayer, including an organization exempt under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1802.01|(a)|(3)">§ 47-1802.01(a)(3)</cite> from taxation under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|18">this chapter</cite>.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(d)</num>
                  <text>The credit may only be allowed if it:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>Has been approved and certified by the Mayor to the Chief Financial Officer pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1819.04">§ 47-1819.04</cite>:</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>Is claimed by an eligible taxpayer in the taxable year in which the substantial rehabilitation of the eligible property is completed; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>Is claimed in the manner and form prescribed by the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§304|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|18|XIX" after="§47-1819.02" num-value="47-1819.03"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1819.03</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Annual cap.</heading>
                <text>The Mayor may approve up to $2,000,000 in credits under this subchapter each fiscal year.</text>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§304|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
              <section>
                <codify:insert path="47|18|XIX" after="§47-1819.03" num-value="47-1819.04"/>
                <prefix>§</prefix>
                <num>47-1809.04</num>
                <heading proof="needed">Application and Mayoral certification.</heading>
                <para>
                  <num>(a)</num>
                  <text>Before a taxpayer may claim a credit pursuant <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|18|XIX">this subchapter</cite>, the taxpayer must apply to the Mayor requesting approval.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(b)</num>
                  <text>If a taxpayer's application is approved in accordance with <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|18|XIX">this subchapter</cite>, the Mayor shall certify to the Chief Financial Officer the following on before December 1 of the calendar year following the end of the fiscal year in which the credit was approved:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(1)</num>
                    <text>The name and taxpayer identification number of the eligible taxpayer;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(2)</num>
                    <text>The address of the eligible property (including square and lot);</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(3)</num>
                    <text>That the eligible taxpayer's application in accordance with this section was approved;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(4)</num>
                    <text>The date the substantial rehabilitation was completed;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(5)</num>
                    <text>That the eligible taxpayer sold the property to a qualifying homeowner;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(6)</num>
                    <text>The total amount of the eligible development costs incurred by the eligible taxpayer;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(7)</num>
                    <text>The total amount of the credit approved for the eligible taxpayer; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(8)</num>
                    <text>Any other information requested by the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§304|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
              </section>
            </container>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </section>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>E</num>
      <heading>TAX ABATEMENT FOR THE REDEVELOPMENT OF VACANT AND BLIGHTED COMMERCIAL PROPERTIES.</heading>
      <section>
        <num>305</num>
        <text>Subchapter III of Chapter 8 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The table of contents is amended by adding new section designations to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <toc>
              <section>
                <num>47-861.01</num>
                <heading>Tax abatements for the redevelopment of vacant and blighted commercial properties – Definitions.</heading>
              </section>
              <section>
                <num>47-861.02</num>
                <heading>Tax abatements for the redevelopment of vacant and blighted commercial properties – Requirements.</heading>
              </section>
              <section>
                <num>47-861.03</num>
                <heading>Tax abatements for the redevelopment of vacant and blighted vacant commercial properties – Abatement period, abatement amount, and caps.</heading>
              </section>
              <section>
                <num>47-861.04</num>
                <heading>Tax abatements for the redevelopment of vacant and blighted commercial properties – Rules.</heading>
              </section>
            </toc>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="47|8|III">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>New sections 47-861.01, 47-861.02, 47-861.03, and 47-861.04 are added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <section>
              <codify:insert after="§47-861" num-value="47-861.01"/>
              <prefix>§</prefix>
              <num>47-861.01</num>
              <heading proof="needed">Tax abatements for the redevelopment of vacant and blighted commercial properties – Definitions.</heading>
              <para>
                <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
                <text>For purposes of §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-861.01">47-861.01</cite> through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-861.04">47-861.04</cite>, the term:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(1)</num>
                  <text>"Class 3 property" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-813|(c-9)|(4)|(A)">§ 47-813(c-9)(4)(A)</cite>.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(2)</num>
                  <text>"Class 4 property" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-813|(c-9)|(5)|(A)">§ 47-813(c-9)(5)(A)</cite>.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(3)</num>
                  <text>"Eligible development costs" means amounts paid or incurred for construction, substantial rehabilitation, demolition of structures, or environmental remediation of an eligible property. Eligible development costs shall not include land acquisition costs.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(4)</num>
                  <text>"Eligible property" means a Class 3 or Class 4 property that:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(A)</num>
                    <text>Shall be redeveloped to be used for commercial purposes as defined in paragraph (5) of this section; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(B)</num>
                    <text>Has been registered or designated as vacant or designated blighted vacant for at least 12 months without any exemptions pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3131.06a">§ 42-3131.06a</cite>.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(5)</num>
                  <text>"Used for commercial purposes" means use of real property primarily for conducting any trade, business, or profession, whether for profit or not, including providing goods or services or operating as a hotel or inn.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(6)</num>
                  <text>"OTR" means the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§305|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
            </section>
            <section>
              <codify:insert after="§47-861.01" num-value="47-861.02"/>
              <prefix>§</prefix>
              <num>47-861.02</num>
              <heading proof="needed">Tax abatements for the redevelopment of vacant and blighted commercial properties – Requirements.</heading>
              <para>
                <num>(a)</num>
                <text>Subject to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-861.03">§ 47-861.03</cite>, the Mayor may approve an abatement of the tax otherwise imposed under this chapter, in an amount calculated pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-861.03|(a)">§ 47-861.03(a)</cite>, for an eligible property if:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(1)</num>
                  <text>Eligible development costs exceed $1.5 million;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(2)</num>
                  <text>The property owner, or its designee or assignee, demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Mayor that the abatement shall materially assist the redevelopment project and the redevelopment project would not go forward without the abatement;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(3)</num>
                  <text>The property owner, or its designee or assignee, enters into an agreement with the District that requires the owner, or its designee or assignee, to, at a minimum, contract with certified business enterprises for at least 35% of the contract dollar volume of the construction of the project, in accordance with <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-218.46">§ 2-218.46</cite>;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(4)</num>
                  <text>The property owner, or its designee or assignee, executes a First Source Agreement for the construction and operation of the project;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(5)</num>
                  <text>The property owner, or its designee or assignee, requests a letter from the Mayor stating that the proposed redevelopment project is eligible for the tax abatement, setting forth the expected amount of the abatement, as determined pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-861.03|(a)">§ 47-861.03(a)</cite>, and reserving that amount for the project; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(6)</num>
                  <text>The Mayor transmits to the owner the eligibility and reservation letter requested under paragraph (5) of this subsection, subject to such conditions as may be imposed by the Mayor and subject to the adjustment of the abatement amount based on the certifications provided for in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-860.03|(a)">§ 47-860.03(a)</cite> and the abatement cap set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-861.03|(b)">§ 47-861.03(b)</cite>.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(b)</num>
                <text>The Mayor shall, as nearly as practicable, review requests for eligibility and reservation letters in the order in which each completed request is received.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(c)</num>
                <text>The Mayor shall transmit to the Office of Tax and Revenue ("OTR") a copy of each eligibility and reservation letter transmitted by the Mayor to an owner pursuant to subsection (a)(6) of this section.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(d)</num>
                <text>An abatement of the tax otherwise imposed under this chapter shall not be provided for a property for which an eligibility and reservation letter was transmitted by the Mayor pursuant to subsection (a)(6) of this section if the project that was the basis upon which the eligibility and reservation letter was issued has not received a certificate of occupancy within 24 months after the date the eligibility and reservation letter was transmitted; provided, that the Mayor may extend the 24-month period for up to 8 months as deemed necessary.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(e)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(1)</num>
                  <text>After the completion of a project for which an eligibility and reservation letter was issued, the Mayor shall, if the conditions set forth in this section and the eligibility and reservation letter have been met, and subject to the abatement cap set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-860.03|(b)">§ 47-860.03(b)</cite>, issue the property owner a certification of tax abatement, subject to such conditions as the Mayor may impose. The Mayor shall provide a copy of the certification letter to OTR. The certification shall identify:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(A)</num>
                    <text>The property to which the certification applies by square and lot, or parcel or reservation number;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(B)</num>
                    <text>The full legal name of the property owner, including taxpayer identification number;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(C)</num>
                    <text>The tax to which the certification applies;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(D)</num>
                    <text>The portion of the property that is eligible;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(E)</num>
                    <text>The commencement date of the abatement; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(F)</num>
                    <text>Any other information that OTR shall require to administer the abatement.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(2)</num>
                  <text>The Mayor shall notify the property owner and OTR if any property or owner certified under paragraph (1) of this subsection becomes ineligible for the abatement. The notice shall be written and shall identify the ineligible property, the date that the property became ineligible, and any other information required by OTR to terminate the abatement.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§305|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
            </section>
            <section>
              <codify:insert after="§47-861.02" num-value="47-861.03"/>
              <prefix>§</prefix>
              <num>47-861.03</num>
              <heading proof="needed">Tax abatements for the redevelopment of vacant and blighted vacant commercial properties – Abatement period, abatement amount, and caps.</heading>
              <para>
                <num>(a)</num>
                <text>For each property for which a certification of abatement was issued under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-860.02|(e)">§ 47-860.02(e)</cite>, the real property tax imposed on the property under this chapter shall be abated as follows:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(1)</num>
                  <text>Half of the otherwise applicable tax in each of the first 6 tax years following the tax year during which a certification of tax abatement is issued pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-860.02|(e)">§ 47-860.02(e)</cite>;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(2)</num>
                  <text>Two-thirds of the applicable tax in each of the 7th and 8th tax years following the tax year during which a certification of tax abatement is issued pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-860.02|(e)">§ 47-860.02(e)</cite>; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(3)</num>
                  <text>Three-quarters of the applicable tax in each of the 9th and 10th tax years following the tax year during which a certification of tax abatement is issued pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-860.02|(e)">§ 47-860.02(e)</cite>.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(b)</num>
                <text>The total amount of tax abatements the Mayor may approve or certify under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-860.02">§ 47-860.02</cite> in each fiscal year, including amounts certified in prior years, shall be capped at the following amounts, subject to the availability of funding:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(1)</num>
                  <text>For fiscal years 2027, 2028, and 2029, up to $2,500,000; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(2)</num>
                  <text>For each succeeding fiscal year after Fiscal Year 2029, up to $3 million.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(c)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(1)</num>
                  <text>Prior to the preparation by OTR of tax bills for each half-year installment of tax, the Mayor shall certify to OTR, by a date and in a form and medium prescribed by OTR, each property eligible to receive a real property tax abatement pursuant to a certification issued pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-860.02|(e)">§ 47-860.02(e)</cite>, and the portion of the tax to be abated under subsection (a) of this section for each such property with respect to such half-year installment bill.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(2)</num>
                  <text>The certification required by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be accompanied by a statement from the Mayor specifying the total amount of the tax abatement under subsection (b) of this section for the semiannual period of the certification that is available to abate the taxes of the properties identified pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(d)</num>
                <text>If the amount of tax to be abated for any semiannual billing period for all properties certified under subsection (c)(1) of this section exceeds the total dollar amount of tax abatements available as certified under subsection (c)(2) of this section, the available dollar amount shall be allocated pro rata among all properties certified under subsection (c)(1) of this section.</text>
              </para>
              <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§305|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
            </section>
            <section>
              <codify:insert after="§47-861.03" num-value="47-861.04"/>
              <prefix>§</prefix>
              <num>47-861.04</num>
              <heading proof="needed">Tax abatements for the redevelopment of vacant and blighted commercial properties – Rules.</heading>
              <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|I">§ 2-501 <em>et seq.</em></code-cite>, shall issue rules to implement §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-861.01">47-861.01</cite> through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-861.03">47-861.03</cite>.</text>
              <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§305|(b)" applicability-path="§401|(a)" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
            </section>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </section>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>IV</num>
    <heading>APPLICABILITY; FISCAL IMPACT STATEMENT; EFFECTIVE DATE.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>401</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Sections 104, 105, 106, 202(j), 202(p), 301, 302, 303, 304, and 305 of this act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§121" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§122" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§131" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§202|(j)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§202|(p)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§301" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§302|(a)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§302|(b)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(b)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(c)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§303|(d)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§304|(b)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 26-41" path="§305|(b)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the provisions identified in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>402</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
      <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>403</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973, (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
    </section>
  </container>
</document>
