<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 26-42" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">26-42</num>
  <num type="act">26-129</num>
  <num type="bill">26-61</num>
  <heading type="short">Parity in Workers' Compensation Recovery Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Workers' Compensation Act of 1979 to provide that the payment or award of compensation under the workers' compensation law of any other state shall not bar a claim for compensation under the District's workers' compensation law for the same injury or death; provided, that any such award under the District's workers' compensation law shall be reduced by the amount of compensation received or awarded under the workers' compensation law of any other state.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-01-13</introduced>
    <effective>2025-10-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56931/Signed_Act/B26-0061-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=218453">D.C. Law 26-42</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 8926</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0061">
      <vote date="2025-07-14" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-28" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-08-11</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 26-61 would provide that the payment or award of compensation under the workers’ compensation law of any other state shall not bar a claim for compensation under the District’s workers’ compensation law for the same injury or death.  Any such award by the District shall be reduced by the amount of compensation received or awarded under the workers’ compensation law of any other state.  </summary>
      <committee>Executive Administration and Labor</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Parity in Workers' Compensation Recovery Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section codify:path="§32-1503|(a-1)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 4(a-1) of the District of Columbia Workers' Compensation Act of 1979, effective July 1, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-77; D.C. Official Code § 32-1503(a-1)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:replace/>
        <num>(a-1)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Notwithstanding any other law, the payment or award of compensation under the workers' compensation law of any other state to an employee or his dependent shall not bar a claim for compensation under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="32|15">this act</code-cite> for the same injury or death; provided, that any such award of compensation under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="32|15">this act</code-cite> shall be reduced by the amount of compensation received or awarded under the workers' compensation law of any other state.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>This subsection shall apply to all claims under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="32|15">this act</code-cite> that are pending as of <span codify:value="June 28, 2022">the effective date of the Parity in Workers' Compensation Recovery Emergency Amendment Act of 2022, effective June 28, 2022 (D.C. Act 24-453; 69 DCR 7765) ("emergency act")</span>, and all claims under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="32|15">this act</code-cite> filed after <span codify:value="June 28, 2022">the effective date of the emergency act</span>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
