<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 26-57" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">26-57</num>
  <num type="act">26-158</num>
  <num type="bill">26-119</num>
  <heading type="short">Official Sports Capital of the United States Designation Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To designate the District of Columbia as the Official Sports Capital of the United States; and to amend Title II of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994 to require the Washington Convention and Sports Authority to develop and implement a plan to promote, support, and enhance the District's status as the nation's premier destination for sports events, teams, and activities.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-02-06</introduced>
    <effective>2025-12-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57115/Signed_Act/B26-0119-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=225573">D.C. Law 26-57</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0119">
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-10-07" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-10-23</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 26-119 would designate the District of Columbia as the “Official Sports Capital of the United States” and it would require the Washington Convention and Sports Authority (Events DC) to develop a plan to promote, support, and enhance the District’s status as the nation’s premier destination for sports events, teams, and activities. </summary>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Official Sports Capital of the United States Designation Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>I</num>
    <heading>Designation of the District as the Official Sports Capital of the United States.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>101</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Short title.</heading>
      <text>This title may be cited as the "Sense of the Council on the Designation of the District of Columbia as the Official Sports Capital of the United States Act of 2025".</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <codify:marginalia display="See Notes in § 10-1202.03b"/>
      <!-- codified as annotation to newly created sec. 10-1202.03b -->
      <num>102</num>
      <text>The Council finds that:</text>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The District of Columbia is home to numerous professional, collegiate, and amateur sports teams, including the Washington Wizards, Washington Mystics, Washington Nationals, Washington Capitals, D.C. United, Washington Spirit, D.C. Defenders, Old Glory DC, and DC Breeze.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The District has hosted premier national and international sporting events, including the MLB All-Star Game, NBA All-Star Game, NHL Winter Classic, WNBA All-Star Game, the Mubadala Citi DC Open, World Cup qualifiers, and the Army-Navy Game, showcasing its capacity as a global sports hub.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The District's unique status as the nation's capital, and its accessibility, infrastructure, and sports culture make it the most fitting city to serve as the Official Sports Capital of our nation.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>The District continues to invest in world-class sports venues such as the Capital One Arena, Nationals Park, Audi Field, Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium Campus, and the CareFirst Arena, further enhancing its reputation as a premier sports destination.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>The District plays a critical role in advancing equity and inclusivity in sports, fostering youth participation through programs like the Department of Parks and Recreation's community athletics initiatives, and supporting diversity in sports leadership and opportunities.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Designation of the District as the "Official Sports Capital of the United States" will boost tourism, economic development, and national recognition of the District's rich sports culture and history.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>103</num>
      <heading proof="needed">It is the sense of the Council that the District of Columbia shall be designated as the only "Official Sports Capital of the United States".</heading>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading>Plan to promote the District as the Official Sports Capital of the United States.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>201</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Short title.</heading>
      <text>This title may be cited as the "Sports Incentives and Marketing Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>202</num>
      <text>Title II of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective September 28, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-188; D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Section 203 (D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.03) is amended by adding a new paragraph (10N) to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert path="§10-1202.03" after="(10M)" num-value="(10N)"/>
            <num>(10N)</num>
            <text>To direct no less than $500,000 per fiscal year to support the solicitation and selection of a qualified organization to host marquee sports related events designed to attract sports business professionals, including sports media executives, league commissioners, and sports agency professionals;</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>A new section 203b is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="10|12|I|B" after="§10-1202.03a" num-value="10-1202.03b" history-prefix="as added"/>
            <num>203b</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Plan to promote the District as the Official Sports Capital of the United States.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The Authority shall develop and implement a plan to promote and enhance the District's status as the Official Sports Capital of the United States, which shall include:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Initiatives to attract and retain major sporting events, conferences, conventions, and tournaments;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Strategies to increase investment in youth sports and community athletic programs;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Partnerships with professional, collegiate, and amateur teams to engage residents and visitors;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>Marketing and branding efforts to highlight the District's role as the nation's premier sports hub; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>A dedicated focus on developing the District as the national leader in electronic sports, including support for electronic sports tournaments, career pathway programs into electronic sports, digital infrastructure, and engagement of local youth and emerging talent.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>No later than <span codify:value="[April 10, 2026]">120 days after the effective date of the Official Sports Capital of the United States Designation Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on October 7, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-119)</span>, the Authority shall submit to the Council the plan required pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
            </para>
            <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-188" type="History" path="§203b">Sept. 28, 1994, D.C. Law 10-188, § 203b</annotation>
            <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1202.03b" type="Editor's Notes" history="false">
              <text><cite doc="D.C. Law 26-57" path="§102">Section 102</cite> of D.C. Law 26-57 provides that:</text>
              <include>
                <section>
                  <num>102</num>
                  <text>The Council finds that:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
                    <para>
                      <num>(1)</num>
                      <text>The District of Columbia is home to numerous professional, collegiate, and amateur sports teams, including the Washington Wizards, Washington Mystics, Washington Nationals, Washington Capitals, D.C. United, Washington Spirit, D.C. Defenders, Old Glory DC, and DC Breeze.</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(2)</num>
                      <text>The District has hosted premier national and international sporting events, including the MLB All-Star Game, NBA All-Star Game, NHL Winter Classic, WNBA All-Star Game, the Mubadala Citi DC Open, World Cup qualifiers, and the Army-Navy Game, showcasing its capacity as a global sports hub.</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(3)</num>
                      <text>The District's unique status as the nation's capital, and its accessibility, infrastructure, and sports culture make it the most fitting city to serve as the Official Sports Capital of our nation.</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(4)</num>
                      <text>The District continues to invest in world-class sports venues such as the Capital One Arena, Nationals Park, Audi Field, Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium Campus, and the CareFirst Arena, further enhancing its reputation as a premier sports destination.</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(5)</num>
                      <text>The District plays a critical role in advancing equity and inclusivity in sports, fostering youth participation through programs like the Department of Parks and Recreation's community athletics initiatives, and supporting diversity in sports leadership and opportunities.</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(6)</num>
                      <text>Designation of the District as the "Official Sports Capital of the United States" will boost tourism, economic development, and national recognition of the District's rich sports culture and history.</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                </section>
              </include>
            </codify:annotation>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>III</num>
    <heading>Standard provisions.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>301</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
      <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>302</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-206(c)(1)).</text>
    </section>
  </container>
</document>
