<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 26-54" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">26-54</num>
  <num type="act">26-151</num>
  <num type="bill">26-288</num>
  <heading type="short">Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To authorize bond issuances, to establish special funds, to specify the application of various provisions of law, and to establish conditions on the issuance of bonds and expenditure of bond proceeds to facilitate redevelopment and management of the approximately 180 acres of waterfront property located at the former Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium site.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-06-20</introduced>
    <effective>2025-11-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57983/Signed_Act/B26-0288-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=224328">D.C. Law 26-54</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/58397/Signed_Act/B26-0352-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=223720">D.C. Act 26-150</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 10871</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0288">
      <vote date="2025-08-01" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-08-01" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-08-01" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-08-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-08-01" reading="Committee"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(Mendelson)"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(Mendelson)"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(Felder)"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(Parker)"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(T."/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(R."/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(T."/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(R."/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(R."/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(R."/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(R."/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(R."/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="(Frumin)"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-10-03</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development, Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="10|16" after="IV" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>V</num>
      <heading>Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="10|16|V" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Part</prefix>
      <num>A</num>
      <heading>General.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="10|16|V" after="A" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Part</prefix>
      <num>B</num>
      <heading>RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" num-value="10-1605.01"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of <span codify:value="§§">sections</span> <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.01" codify:value="10-1605.01">2</code-cite> through <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.14" codify:value="10-1605.14">15</code-cite>, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>"Authorized Delegate" means the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, the Chief Financial Officer, the Treasurer, or any officer or employee of the executive office of the Mayor to whom the Mayor has delegated any of the Mayor's functions under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="10|16|V|A">this act</code-cite> pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.22|(6)">section 422(6) of the Home Rule Act (D.C. Official Code § 1-204.22(6))</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>"Bonds" means District revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations (including bonds, notes, and other obligations) in one or more series, authorized to be issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.90">section 490 of the Home Rule Act (D.C. Official Code § 1-204.90)</code-cite> and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="10|16|V|A">this act</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>"Certified business enterprise" shall have the same meaning as provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-218.02|(1D)">section 2302(1D) of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-218.02(1D))</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>"Chief Financial Officer" means the Chief Financial Officer established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.24a|(a)">section 424(a)(1) of the Home Rule Act (D.C. Official Code § 1-204.24a(a))</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>"Closing Documents" means all documents and agreements, other than Financing Documents, that may be necessary and appropriate to issue, sell, and deliver the Bonds, and includes agreements, certificates, letters, opinions, forms, receipts, and other similar instruments.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>"Commercial Development" shall have the same meaning as provided in the Term Sheet.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>"Declaration of Covenants" means the Declaration of Covenants Regarding the Transfer of Jurisdiction of the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium Campus (Reservation 343F), dated as of January 14, 2025, and recorded in the land records of the District of Columbia on February 4, 2025, as Instrument No. 2025012660.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(8)</num>
        <text>"Debt Service" means principal, premium, if any, and interest on the Bonds.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(9)</num>
        <text>"Developer" means Pro-Football LLC, or affiliates or designees of Pro-Football LLC approved by the Mayor.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(10)</num>
        <text>"Development and Financing Agreement" means the agreement governing the terms and conditions of the District's funding for the RFK Campus and the Developer's obligation to construct the Stadium Project.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(11)</num>
        <text>"Development Site" means the portions of the RFK Campus that are the subject of the Term Sheet.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(12)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>"District Event" means any Stadium use for a District-sponsored, non-commercial public or community event, such as a graduation, high school football game, or similar use, even if such event charges fees for attendance; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Any other event agreed to be a District event jointly by the Team and the Mayor.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(13)</num>
        <text>"Financing Documents" means the documents that relate to the financing or refinancing of transactions to be effectuated through the issuance, sale, and delivery of the Bonds, including any offering document, and any required supplements to any such documents.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(14)</num>
        <text>"Home Rule Act" means <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="1|2">the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 774; D.C. Official Code § 1-201.01 <em>et seq</em>.)</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(15)</num>
        <text>"Net Parking Revenues" means all parking revenues collected at the Parking Facilities less 15% for operating costs.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(16)</num>
        <text>"Parking Facilities" means the parking facilities constructed pursuant to the Development and Financing Agreement.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(17)</num>
        <text>"Personal Seat License" means a license, location right, or other similar instrument for seats in the Stadium issued to a person for the right to purchase season tickets to games and tickets to other events at the Stadium.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(18)</num>
        <text>"RFK Campus" means the parcels of land that are the subject of the Transfer of Jurisdiction Plat recorded in the Surveyor's Office of the District of Columbia on February 5, 2025, on page 13 of subdivision book 223, together with any public streets within or adjacent to such parcels that may be closed from time to time.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(19)</num>
        <text>"RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund" means the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.31">section 2052 of the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund Establishment Act of 2025, enacted on September 4, 2025 (D.C. Act 26-148; 72 DCR 9825)</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(20)</num>
        <text>"RFK Campus Infrastructure Project" means:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>The financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of costs incurred in the development, design, and construction of the horizontal improvements and eligible capital costs as defined in the Term Sheet;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>The funding of any required deposit to a debt service reserve fund or capitalized interest for the Bonds issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.11|(a)">section 12(a)</code-cite>; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>The payment of certain costs of issuance of the Bonds issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.11|(a)">section 12(a)</code-cite>, such as fees and premiums for any bond issuance or credit enhancement.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(21)</num>
        <text>"RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund" means the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.09">section 10</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(22)</num>
        <text>"RFK Campus Parking Facilities Project" means:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>The financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of costs incurred in the development, design, and construction of the Parking Facilities and horizontal improvements and eligible capital costs as defined in the Term Sheet;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>The funding of any required deposit to a debt service reserve fund or capitalized interest for the Bonds issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.11|(b)">section 12(b)</code-cite>; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>The payment of certain costs of issuance of the Bonds issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.11|(b)">section 12(b)</code-cite>, such as fees and premiums for any bond issuance or credit enhancement.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(23)</num>
        <text>"Small business enterprise" shall have the same meaning as provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-218.02|(16)">section 2302(16) of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-218.02(16))</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(24)</num>
        <text>"Sportsplex" means a public sports and recreation facility to be developed on the Development Site.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(25)</num>
        <text>"Stadium" means the stadium to be constructed by the Developer and owned by the District on a portion of the Development Site, as described in the Term Sheet.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(26)</num>
        <text>"Stadium Event Day" means the Stadium Event Day Interval on each day on which any Team Event is scheduled to be held at all or any part of the Stadium (including periods after midnight for any such Team Event that extends past that hour).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(27)</num>
        <text>"Stadium Event Day Interval" means the period beginning 10 hours before the scheduled start time for commencement of any Team Event and terminating 4 hours following the conclusion of such Team Event.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(28)</num>
        <text>"Stadium Maintenance Fund" means the special fund established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.10">section 11</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(29)</num>
        <text>"Stadium Project" means the development on a portion of the Development Site to include the construction of the Stadium, the Parking Facilities, administrative offices, and other ancillary improvements by the Developer, as described in the Term Sheet.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(30)</num>
        <text>"Stadium Seat Right" means the right to sell, license, or otherwise transfer certain rights to use and occupy seats in the Stadium, including a Personal Seat License.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(31)</num>
        <text>"Team" means the professional football franchise that is a member club of the National Football League ("NFL") known as the Washington Commanders, or a successor member club.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(32)</num>
        <text>"Team Event" means any Team home game, any NFL sponsored event, and any other event at the Stadium that is not a District Event and that is attended by 5,000 or more visitors, including any unticketed such event.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(33)</num>
        <text>"Term Sheet" means the Term Sheet for the Redevelopment of a Portion of the RFK Stadium Campus between the District and Pro-Football LLC, dated April 28, 2025, that memorializes the terms of the disposition and development of the Development Site.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(34)</num>
        <text>"Transaction Document" means any document entered into under the Term Sheet that implements the terms of the disposition and development of the Development Site, including the Development and Financing Agreement and any leases entered into by the parties.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(35)</num>
        <text>"Transportation Improvement Fund" means the special fund established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.29">section 9u of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-288)</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.01" num-value="10-1605.02"/>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Findings.</heading>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <text>The Council finds that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The RFK Campus consists of approximately 180 acres of waterfront property located in the District within Reservation 343F, as shown on the transfer of jurisdiction plat recorded in the Surveyor's Office on February 5, 2025, on page 13 of subdivision book 223. The District has been unable to redevelop the site over the last decade due to federal restrictions on development at the site, and the site has remained vacant, blighted, and fallow. Over the course of the last decade, the District has worked to gain broader control of the site and to remove the federal development restrictions so that a new, multi-use future for the area could be realized.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>With bipartisan support from Congress, the President signed the D.C. Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium Campus Revitalization Act, approved on January 6, 2025 (Pub. L. No. 118-274; 138 Stat. 3234), into law. Pursuant to this law, the National Park Service transferred administrative jurisdiction over the RFK Campus to the District. The Council approved the transfer of jurisdiction pursuant to the Transfer of Jurisdiction Over the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium Campus Emergency Approval Resolution of 2025, effective February 4, 2025 (Res. 26-16; 72 DCR 1436).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The District now has a once-in-a-generation opportunity to continue to revitalize the Anacostia Waterfront, catalyze growth, and develop a vibrant, mixed-use development featuring community sports, professional sports, public recreation, public park space, and cultural amenities. The development will provide the District with significant economic, cultural, social, and financial benefits.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Since gaining administrative jurisdiction over the RFK Campus, the District government has undertaken a comprehensive public engagement process, considering the specific interests of communities near the RFK Campus, economic development opportunities, the capacity of the campus to generate jobs for District residents and opportunities for District businesses, park, open space, and recreational options, river access options, potential community amenities, opportunities to create new housing units, and environmental and historical factors, among other considerations, to determine the best uses for the site.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Considering the public input received, the existing infrastructure of the campus, and the possibility of a catalytic investment in the District, it was determined that the construction and operation of a new first-class, state-of-the-art, sports stadium with supporting facilities, including parking, and infrastructure, for use by the Team and an adjacent Sportsplex would be of considerable public benefit to the District as the first stage of the redevelopment and revitalization of the entire campus.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>To ensure delivery of the Stadium, supporting facilities, and Sportsplex by 2030, a limited zoning exemption is necessary for portions of the RFK Campus.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>Planning for other residential and commercial development at the RFK Campus, in addition to other uses permitted by the transfer of jurisdiction and the Declaration of Covenants, will continue as the Stadium and Sportsplex projects move forward, and will inform the Comprehensive Plan rewrite (DC 2050).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(8)</num>
        <text>The District intends for the comprehensive redevelopment of the RFK Campus to create a vibrant, multi-use community and destination that will create new jobs, business opportunities, housing, community amenities, and neighborhood-serving retail and achieve the 5 Anacostia Waterfront Framework Plan themes of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>A clean and active river;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Gaining access to, along, and across the river;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>A great riverfront park system;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>A riverfront of distinct places and cultural destinations; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>Building and sustaining strong waterfront neighborhoods.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(9)</num>
        <text>The District and Developer have entered into the Term Sheet for the development of the Stadium and supporting facilities and the redevelopment of a portion of the RFK Campus that sets forth the terms and conditions upon which the parties are willing to undertake the projects.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(10)</num>
        <text>The Team has made additional commitments regarding the redevelopment of the RFK Campus in a July 29, 2025, letter to the Council.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(11)</num>
        <text>The Team has committed to executing a Project Labor Agreement and Labor Peace Agreement for the construction of the Stadium Project and hotels on the Development Site.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(12)</num>
        <text>The construction, development, and revitalization of the RFK Campus and the public ownership of the Stadium, for use for athletic and entertainment events, is a municipal use that is in the interest of, and for the benefit of, District residents because such a publicly-owned Stadium will contribute to the social and economic well-being of District residents and significantly enhance economic development and employment opportunities in the District.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(13)</num>
        <text>To further that interest, it is appropriate for the District to take certain actions with respect to the redevelopment of the RFK Campus, as further set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="10|16|V|A">this act</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.02" num-value="10-1605.03"/>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability of certain laws to Transaction Documents, Development Site, easements over the RFK Campus, and the sale of Stadium Seat Rights.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Neither <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|3A">the Procurement Practices Reform Act of 2010, effective April 8, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-371; D.C. Official Code § 2-351.01 <em>et seq</em>.)</code-cite>, nor <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2A">the Public-Private Partnership Act of 2014, effective March 11, 2015 (D.C. Law 20-228; D.C. Official Code § 2-271.01 <em>et seq</em>.)</code-cite>, shall apply to the Transaction Documents nor any other agreement the Mayor may enter into under the Term Sheet; provided, that the preconditions for the issuance of bonds and the expenditure of bond proceeds set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.05">section 6</code-cite> have been met.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to purport to waive <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.51">section 451 of the Home Rule Act (D.C. Official Code § 1-204.51)</code-cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="10|8|I">An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code § 10-801 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>, the Mayor may:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Dispose of the Development Site by lease pursuant to the terms of the Term Sheet; provided, that the preconditions for the issuance of bonds and the expenditure of bond proceeds set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.05">section 6</code-cite> have been met;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Sell Stadium Seat Rights to the Developer pursuant to the terms of the Term Sheet; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Grant easements over the RFK Campus to such persons as the Mayor determines appropriate in furtherance of the redevelopment of the RFK Campus; provided, that the preconditions for the issuance of bonds and the expenditure of bond proceeds set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.05">section 6</code-cite> have been met.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.04a">Section 104a of the Urban Forest Preservation Act of 2002, effective July 1, 2016 (D.C. Law 21-133; D.C. Official Code § 8-651.04a) ("Urban Forest Preservation Act")</code-cite>, shall not apply to the Development Site; provided, that a fee calculated at the rate applicable for special trees pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.04|(b)|(3)">section 104(b)(3) of the Urban Forest Preservation Act (D.C. Official Code § 8-651.04(b)(3))</code-cite>, shall be paid for each Heritage Tree removed from the Development Site;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The waiver of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.04a">section 104a of the Urban Forest Preservation Act (D.C. Official Code § 8-651.04a)</code-cite> set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to the Anacostia Commons riparian area.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The utility and site preparation work related to the Stadium Project and construction of the Stadium Project shall not be subject to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1108.02">section 9b of the Historic Landmark and Historic District Protection Act of 1978, effective November 16, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-185; D.C. Official Code § 6-1108.02)</code-cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Developer shall provide affordable housing for the Development Site in an amount that equals or exceeds 30% of the residential units, with 1/2 of the affordable units set aside for households earning equal to or less than 60% of the median family income ("MFI") and 1/2 of the affordable units set aside for households earning equal to or less than 30% of the MFI ("Affordable Dwelling Unit Requirement").</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Affordable Dwelling Unit Requirement shall be calculated based on the total number of developed units rather than on a per building basis.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Inclusionary zoning requirements shall not be applicable to the Development Site.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>To provide flexibility to deliver all housing types in an expedited and efficient manner, all other details (such as duration of affordability, lottery, and the certification process for the affordable dwelling units) regarding the implementation of the Affordable Dwelling Unit Requirement shall be as set forth in the Transaction Documents.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.03" num-value="10-1605.04"/>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Local hiring, equity, and subcontracting requirements.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text><span codify:value="§§ ">Sections</span><cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.01" codify:value="2-219.01">2</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03|(a)" codify:value="2-219.03(a)">4(a)</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03|(b)">(b)</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03|(c)">(c)</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03|(e)|(1)">(e)(1)</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03|(e)|(1C)">(1C)</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03|(e)|(2)">(2)</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03|(e)|(3)">(3)</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03|(e)|(4)">(4)</cite>, and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03|(e)|(5)">(5)</cite>, and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03a" codify:value="2-219.03a">4a of the First Source Employment Agreement Act of 1984, effective June 29, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-93; D.C. Official Code §§ 2-219.01, 2-219.03(a), (b), (c), (e)(1), (1C), (2), (3), (4), and (5), and 2-219.03a)</cite>, shall apply to the construction obligations of the Stadium Project and the Commercial Development (collectively "the Project"); provided, that good faith efforts will be required to ensure that 51% of all new hires for the Project are District residents; provided further, that residents of Wards 7 and 8 receive a hiring preference for at least 20% of the new jobs created in connection with the Project.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1431">Section 5 of the Amendments to An Act To Provide for Voluntary Apprenticeship in the District of Columbia Act of 1978, effective March 6, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-156; D.C. Official Code § 32-1431) ("Apprenticeship Act"),</code-cite> shall apply to the construction obligations of the Project; except, that 10%, with a goal of 35%, of all apprenticeship hours performed pursuant to apprenticeship programs required by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1431|(a)">section 5(a) of the Apprenticeship Act</code-cite> shall be performed by District residents and the Department of Employment Services may only impose fines for a failure to achieve the 10% requirement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2|IX-A">The Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-218.01 <em>et seq.</em>),</code-cite> shall apply to the construction obligations of the Project, including professional services rendered in furtherance of the Project; except, that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Developer shall require at least 20% equity, excluding debt financing, mezzanine financing, or other equity contributions by limited or institutional investors, and 20% development participation from certified business enterprises; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Forty percent, with a goal of 50%, of the adjusted development budget, as defined in the CBE Agreement referenced in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.05|(a)">section 6(a)</code-cite>, shall be subcontracted to small business enterprises, with a preference for at least 10% of the small business enterprises to be located in, by order of priority, Wards 7, 8, 5, and 6; or, if there are insufficient qualified small business enterprises to completely fulfill the 40% requirement or the 50% goal, then the subcontracting requirement or goal may be satisfied by subcontracting the 40% requirement or 50% goal of the adjusted development budget to any qualified certified business enterprises, with a preference for at least 10% of the certified business enterprises located in, by order of priority, Wards 7, 8, 5, and 6; provided, that all reasonable efforts shall be made to ensure that qualified small business enterprises are significant participants in the overall subcontracting work.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.04" num-value="10-1605.05"/>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Conditions for the issuance of bonds and the expenditure of bond proceeds.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No bonds may be issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="10|16|V|A">this act</code-cite> or the proceeds of those bonds expended, unless the following conditions have been met:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Transaction Documents shall include terms imposing the following requirements:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Subject to capital reserves described in any capital improvements plan with respect to the Parking Facilities, the District shall have the right to all Net Parking Revenues arising from or related to the use, occupancy, or operation of the Parking Facilities other than during Stadium Event Days;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>The Developer and the District shall enter into at least one parking operations agreement regarding operations of the Parking Facilities, including a capital improvements plan;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>The Developer shall locate a Team sales office, with senior leadership, in the District by a date set forth in the Transaction Documents;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>The Developer shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Construct the Stadium using methods and materials in a manner feasibly consistent with the objective of Version 5 LEED Platinum level for New Construction and Major Renovations ("LEED: BD+C v5"), as defined by the U.S. Green Building Council;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Maintain the Stadium in a manner feasibly consistent with the objective of Version 5 LEED Platinum level for Operations and Maintenance ("LEED: O+M v5"), as defined by the U.S. Green Building Council;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Construct, or cause to be constructed, the Commercial Development, as defined in the Term Sheet, other than any residential development within the Commercial Development, in a manner feasibly consistent with the objective of Version 5 LEED Gold level for New Construction and Major Renovations ("LEED: BD+C v5"), as defined by the U.S. Green Building Council; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>Construct, or cause to be constructed, the residential development within the Commercial Development in a manner feasibly consistent with the objective of Version 5 LEED Silver level for New Construction and Major Renovations ("LEED: BD+C v5"), as defined by the U.S. Green Building Council<u>;</u></text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>The Developer shall enter into CBE, Apprenticeship, and First Source Agreements with the District that reflect the requirements set forth at <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.04">section 5</code-cite>; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(F)</num>
          <text>If the Developer fails to complete construction of the required amount of square footage of a stage of development by the outside completion date, all as set forth in the development milestone chart set forth in subsection (b) of this section, then the year in which the rent payable under the Commercial Development Lease, as defined in the Term Sheet, is reset to the Fair Market Rent Amount, as defined in the Term Sheet, shall be accelerated by one year for each missed outside completion date, unless the missed outside completion date is due to force majeure or federal review delays solely due to the reviewing agency (to be defined in the Transaction Documents); provided, that the amount so accelerated shall be equal to the Fair Market Rent Amount multiplied by a percentage determined by dividing the sum of the square footage that the Developer fails to deliver by the applicable outside completion date by the aggregate square footage to be delivered pursuant to the development milestone chart set forth in subsection (b) of this section; provided further, that the acceleration, under this paragraph, from the rent payable under the Commercial Development Lease to the Fair Market Rent Amount rent shall not exceed 10 years; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Team, or an affiliate thereof, shall enter into a Community Benefits Agreement with the Mayor, or any District instrumentality or authority designated by the Mayor, and the Council, within 90 days after <span codify:value="[September 25, 2025]">the effective date of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025, passed on emergency basis on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-352)</span>, which shall reflect the terms contained in, and be negotiated, executed, and administered consistent with the provisions of, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.08">section 9</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The development milestone chart referred to in subsection (a)(1)(F) of this section is as follows:</text>
      <text>
        <table>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Stage of Development</td>
              <td>Required Square Footage</td>
              <td>Outside Completion Date</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>One</td>
              <td>415,000</td>
              <td>3 years</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Two</td>
              <td>567,000</td>
              <td>5 years</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Three</td>
              <td>342,000</td>
              <td>6 years</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Four</td>
              <td>342,000</td>
              <td>7 years</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Five</td>
              <td>735,000</td>
              <td>8 years</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Six</td>
              <td>885,000</td>
              <td>9 years</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Seven</td>
              <td>735,000</td>
              <td>10 years</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Eight</td>
              <td>735,000</td>
              <td>11 years</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Nine</td>
              <td>960,000</td>
              <td>12 years</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Ten</td>
              <td>735,000</td>
              <td>13 years</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of the development milestone chart set forth in subsection (b) of this section, and except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the outside completion date shall be calculated beginning as of the effective date of the zoning order whereby the Zoning Commission shall have included the Plaza District Commercial Parcel (as defined in the Term Sheet) in the zoning map and regulations for the District. Should the zoning order be judicially challenged, the outside completion date shall be calculated beginning one year after the effective date of the zoning order.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Should the zoning regulation established for the Plaza District Commercial Parcel require design review or further processing by either the Zoning Commission or the Board of Zoning Adjustment, the outside completion date for stage one shall be calculated beginning as of the effective date of the zoning order approving the design review or further processing. Should this zoning order be judicially challenged, the outside completion date for stage one shall be calculated beginning one year after the effective date of this zoning order. In either instance the outside completion date for each subsequent stage of development shall be calculated beginning as of the date applicable to stage one.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.05" num-value="10-1605.06"/>
    <num>7</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Cap on District obligations.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The District's contribution to the Stadium budget and the expenditure of funds for the construction of the Stadium shall not exceed $500 million.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The contribution from the District and its instrumentalities to the purchase of the parking garages and the expenditure of funds for the purchase of the parking garages shall not exceed $175 million from the District and $181 million from EventsDC.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The District's contribution to Stadium maintenance, repairs, and capital expenses shall be limited to the amount of funds available in the Stadium Maintenance Fund.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The District shall not provide additional tax abatements, tax exemptions, or subsidies for development of the remainder of the Development Site; provided, that the foregoing prohibition shall not be deemed to restrict the utilization of tax-exempt bond financing, federal low-income housing tax credits, or housing vouchers for the Development Site.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.06" num-value="10-1605.07"/>
    <num>8</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Assignment and transfer of Stadium, Parking Facilities, and Stadium Seat Rights.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may assign or transfer to an instrumentality or authority of the District:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Ownership of the Stadium and the Parking Facilities; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The authority to sell Stadium Seat Rights to the Developer pursuant to the terms of the Term Sheet.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any revenue received by the District from the sale of the Stadium Seat Rights, including revenue received by an instrumentality or authority of the District pursuant to an assignment or transfer of the authority to sell Stadium Seat Rights pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, shall be dedicated to and expended only for the purposes for which such revenue may be expended under the Term Sheet.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.07" num-value="10-1605.08"/>
    <num>9</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Community benefits and Community Reinvestment Fund.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Community Benefits Agreement ("CBA") required pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.05|(a)|(2)">section 6(a)(2)</code-cite> shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Require the Team, or an affiliate thereof, to invest no less than $50 million over 30 years in community benefits for the District in accordance with its negotiated terms;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Be executed by the Mayor, the Chairman of the Council, and the Team, or their designees, after all 3 signatories to the CBA, or their designees, meet together no fewer than 3 times to negotiate its terms; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Include initiatives that promote the following:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Local economic development and job creation;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Community access and activation of the RFK Campus;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Youth education, including youth sports team support, workforce development, and housing stability;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>Health equity and environmental sustainability; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>Public safety and cultural heritage at and surrounding the RFK Campus in coordination with District agencies and community stakeholders.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>A Community Benefits Oversight Committee ("CBOC") shall monitor the implementation of the CBA.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The CBOC shall consist of 9 members, who shall be appointed within one month of the execution of the CBA, as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>The Councilmember that represents the Ward in which the Stadium is located shall appoint 3 members;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Each Councilmember that represents a Ward contiguous to the Ward in which the Stadium is located shall appoint one member;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>The Chairman of the Council shall appoint one member; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall appoint 2 members.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The CBOC shall be subject to the terms established in the CBA.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>The CBOC shall request, review, and publish timely progress reports, provided by the Team, in accordance with the reporting requirements established in the CBA.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>There is established as a special fund, the Community Reinvestment Fund, which shall be administered by the Mayor, DMPED, or any District instrumentality or authority designated by the Mayor or designated by law, with oversight by the CBOC, in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Community Reinvestment Fund shall consist of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Any monetary donations from the Team to the District, as negotiated in the CBA;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Excess RFK Campus Infrastructure Funds, up to $2 million annually, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.31|(d)|(2)">section 2052(d)(2) of the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund Establishment Act of 2025, enacted on September 4, 2025 (D.C. Act 26-148; 72 DCR 9825)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Any money deposited in the Community Reinvestment Fund pursuant to paragraph (2)(A) of this subsection shall be used to finance the community benefits outlined in the CBA and this section.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Funds deposited in the Community Reinvestment Fund pursuant to paragraph (2)(B) of this subsection shall be disbursed to census tracts within Wards 5, 6, 7, and 8 identified as a low-income community, as that term is defined in 26 U.S.C. § 45D(e), with a priority given to communities most directly impacted by Stadium operations and redevelopment. These funds shall be used for the following purposes:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Displacement prevention, including rental assistance, utility assistance, legal representation in eviction proceedings, property tax relief for long-term homeowners, and homebuyer assistance;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Blight revitalization and housing stabilization, including grants or low-interest loans for the rehabilitation of vacant or blighted properties and stabilization of at-risk housing stock;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Small business and community wealth programs, including micro-grants for minority owned small business, workforce training programs tied to stadium operations, and community based development initiatives; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>Public health programs, including grants to fund neighborhood beautification projects and other emerging health needs.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>The money deposited into the Community Reinvestment Fund but not expended in a given fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Community Reinvestment Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitations.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.08" num-value="10-1605.09"/>
    <num>10</num>
    <heading proof="needed">RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is established as a special fund the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund, which shall be administered by the Mayor pursuant to subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The following revenue shall be deposited into the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>All receipts from the taxes imposed by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002.08|(b)">D.C. Official Code § 47-2002.08(b)</code-cite>, including penalty and interest charges; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>All receipts from the taxes imposed by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002">D.C. Official Code § 47-2002</code-cite> and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2202">§ 47-2202</cite> on the sale of or charges for tickets to public events to be performed at the Stadium, as defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002.08">D.C. Official Code § 47-2002.08</code-cite>, including penalties and interest charges.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Money in the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund shall be used to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Pay the Debt Service, including principal and interest, costs of issuance, and credit enhancements, and any costs of defeasance on the Bonds issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.11|(b)">section 12(b)</code-cite> and making any other payments related to such Bonds; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Fund reserves for the Bonds issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.11|(b)">section 12(b)</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>After issuance of the Bonds described in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.11|(b)">section 12(b)</code-cite>, any funds in excess of the amounts required to be paid from or reserved in the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund pursuant to subsection (c) of this section ("Excess Stadium Revenue Funds"), as determined by the Chief Financial Officer, shall be transferred to the Stadium Maintenance Fund established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.10">section 11</code-cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, or any instrumentality or authority of the District that has been designated by the Mayor, may pledge and create a security interest in the funds in the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund for the payment of the Debt Service on any Bonds issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.11|(b)">section 12(b)</code-cite>, any fees and charges incurred in connection therewith, and any payments owing under any document or instrument entered into in connection with such indebtedness in accordance with the provisions of the documents entered into by the District in connection with the issuance of such Bonds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The money deposited into the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.09" num-value="10-1605.10"/>
    <num>11</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Stadium Maintenance Fund.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is established as a special fund the Stadium Maintenance Fund, which shall be administered by the Mayor, or any District instrumentality or authority designated by the Mayor, in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Excess Stadium Revenue Funds, as provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.09|(d)">section 10(d)</code-cite>, shall be deposited into the Stadium Maintenance Fund.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Money in the Stadium Maintenance Fund shall be used to pay maintenance, repair, and capital expenses of the Stadium. Any maintenance, repair, and capital expenses in excess of available funds in the Stadium Maintenance Fund shall be the responsibility of the Developer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The money deposited into the Stadium Maintenance Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Stadium Maintenance Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall submit to the Council an annual report of the funds deposited in and expended from the Stadium Maintenance Fund.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.10" num-value="10-1605.11"/>
    <num>12</num>
    <heading proof="needed">RFK infrastructure and parking facilities bond authorizations.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Mayor, or any District government instrumentality or authority designated by the Mayor, may issue, no earlier than October 1, 2025, one or more series of Bonds in a total principal amount not to exceed $759 million or such lesser amount as necessary in order to generate net proceeds of $500 million for payment of the costs of the RFK Campus Infrastructure Project. The District hereby declares its intent to issue Bonds in the amount authorized in this subsection and to use the proceeds to pay or reimburse expenditures for the costs of the purposes or improvements described in <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-54" codify:value="the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025">this act</cite>. This subsection is a declaration of intent within the meaning of, and for purposes described in, Treasury Regulation 1.150-2 (26 C.F.R. § 1.150-2).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Mayor, or any District government authority or instrumentality designated by the Mayor, may allocate to the Bonds authorized by paragraph (1) of this subsection the funds in the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Mayor, or any District government instrumentality or authority designated by the Mayor, may issue, no earlier than October 1, 2031, one or more series of Bonds in a total principal amount not to exceed $210 million or such lesser amount as necessary in order to generate net proceeds of $175 million for payment of the costs of the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Project. The District hereby declares its intent to issue Bonds in the amount authorized in this subsection and use the proceeds to pay or reimburse expenditures for the costs of the purposes or improvements described in <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-54" codify:value="the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025">this act</cite>. This subsection is a declaration of intent within the meaning of, and for purposes described in, Treasury Regulation 1.150-2 (26 C.F.R. § 1.150-2).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Mayor, or any District government authority or instrumentality designated by the Mayor, may allocate to the Bonds authorized by paragraph (1) of this subsection the funds in the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Mayor and each Authorized Delegate may take any action necessary or appropriate in accordance with <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-54" codify:value="the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025">this act</cite> in connection with the preparation, execution, issuance, sale, delivery, security for, and payment of the Bonds of each series, including determinations of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The final form, content, designation, and terms of the Bonds, including a determination that the Bonds may be issued in certificated or book entry form;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The principal amount of the Bonds to be issued and the denominations of the Bonds;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The rate or rates of interest on, and the method or methods of determining the rate or rates of interest on, the Bonds;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>The date or dates of issuance, sale, and delivery of the payment of interest on, and the maturity date or dates of, the Bonds;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Whether the Bonds are to be sold at a competitive or negotiated sale and the terms and conditions of the sale;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>The terms under which the Bonds may be paid, optionally or mandatorily redeemed, accelerated, tendered, called or put for redemption, repurchase, or remarketing before their respective stated maturities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>Provisions for the registration, transfer, and exchange of each series of the Bonds and the replacement of mutilated, lost, stolen, or destroyed Bonds;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(8)</num>
        <text>The creation of any reserve fund, sinking fund, or other fund with respect to the Bonds and the determination of the priority thereof;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(9)</num>
        <text>The time and place of payment of the Bonds;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(10)</num>
        <text>Whether the Bonds will be taxable, tax-exempt, or a combination thereof;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(11)</num>
        <text>Procedures for monitoring the use of the proceeds received from the sale of the Bonds to ensure that they are properly applied to the RFK Campus Infrastructure Project or RFK Campus Parking Facilities Project and used to accomplish the purposes of <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-54" codify:value="the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025">this act</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(12)</num>
        <text>Actions necessary to qualify the Bonds under the blue sky laws of any jurisdiction where the Bonds are marketed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(13)</num>
        <text>The terms and types of credit enhancement under which the Bonds may be secured; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(14)</num>
        <text>The selection of the underwriter for the Bonds.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Bonds shall contain a legend, which shall provide that the Bonds are special obligations of the District, are without recourse to the District, are not a pledge of, and do not involve, the faith and credit or the taxing power of the District (other than the payments from the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund or RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund or any other security authorized by <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-54" codify:value="the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025">this act</cite>), do not constitute a debt of the District, and do not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings as prohibited by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-206.02|(a)|(2)">section 602(a)(2) of the Home Rule Act (D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(a)(2))</code-cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Bonds shall be executed in the name of the District and on its behalf by the manual or facsimile signature of the Mayor. The Mayor's execution and delivery of the Bonds and any necessary ancillary documents shall constitute conclusive evidence of the Mayor's approval on behalf of the District of the final form and content of the Bonds and any necessary ancillary documents.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>If required, the official seal of the District, or a facsimile of it, shall be impressed, printed, or otherwise reproduced on the Bonds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The Bonds may be issued at any time or from time to time in one or more issues and one or more series and may be sold at public or private sale. A series of Bonds may be secured by a trust agreement or trust indenture between the District and a corporate trustee having trust powers or other instrument or instruments by means of which the District may:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Make and enter into any and all covenants and agreements with the trustee or the holders of the Bonds that the District may determine to be necessary or desirable relating to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>The application, investment, deposit, use, and disposition of the proceeds of the Bonds and the other funds, securities, and property of the District;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>The assignment by the District of its rights in any agreement;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>The terms and conditions upon which additional Bonds of the District may be issued;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>The appointment of a trustee to act on behalf of bondholders and abrogating or limiting the rights of the bondholders to appoint a trustee; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>The vesting in a trustee for the benefit of the holders of the Bonds, or in the bondholders directly, such rights and remedies as the District shall determine to be necessary or desirable;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Pledge, mortgage or assign monies, agreements, property or other assets of the District, either in hand or to be received in the future, or both;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Provide for bond insurance, letters of credit, interest rate swaps, or other financial derivative products or otherwise enhance the credit of and security for the payment of the Bonds or reduce or otherwise manage the interest costs of the bonds and provide security therefore; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Provide for any other matters of like or different character that in any way affect the security for or payment on the Bonds.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The Bonds are declared to be issued for essential public and governmental purposes. The Bonds, the interest thereon, the income therefrom, and all monies pledged or available to pay or secure the payment of the Bonds shall at all times be exempt from taxation by the District, except for estate, inheritance, and gift taxes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The District hereby pledges and covenants and agrees with the holders of the Bonds that, subject to the provisions of the financing documents, the District will not limit or alter the revenues pledged to secure the Bonds or the basis on which the revenues are collected or allocated, will not impair the contractual obligations of the District to fulfill the terms of any agreement made with the holders of the Bonds, will not in any way impair the rights or remedies of the holders of the Bonds, and will not modify in any way, with respect to the Bonds, the exemptions from taxation provided for in <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-54" codify:value="the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025">this act</cite>, until the Bonds, together with interest thereon, with interest on any unpaid installment of interest and all costs and expenses in connection with any suit, action, or proceeding by or on behalf of the holders of the Bonds, are fully met and discharged. This pledge and agreement for the District may be included as part of the contract with the holders of the Bonds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Consistent with <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.90|(a)|(4)|(B)">section 490(a)(4)(B) of the Home Rule Act (D.C. Official Code § 1-204.90 (a)(4)(B))</code-cite>, and notwithstanding <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|I|9">Article 9 of Subtitle I of Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code</code-cite>:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>A pledge made and security interest created in respect of the Bonds or pursuant to any related financing document shall be valid, binding, and perfected from the time the security interest is created, with or without physical delivery of any funds or any property and with or without any further action;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The lien of the pledge shall be valid, binding, and perfected as against all parties having any claim of any kind in tort, contract, or otherwise against the District, whether or not the party has notice; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The security interest shall be valid, binding, and perfected whether or not any statement, document, or instrument relating to the security interest is recorded or filed.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>If there shall be a default in the payment of the principal of, or interest on, any Bonds of a series after the principal or interest shall become due and payable, whether at maturity or upon call for redemption, or if the District shall fail or refuse to carry out and perform the terms of any agreement with the holders of any of the Bonds, the holders of the Bonds, or the trustee appointed to act on behalf of the holder of the Bonds, may, subject to the provisions of the Financing Documents, do the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>By action, writ, or other proceeding, enforce all rights of the holders of the Bonds, including the right to require the District to carry out and perform the terms of any agreement with the holders of the Bonds or its duties under <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-54" codify:value="the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025">this act</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>By action, require the District to account as if it were the trustee of an express trust;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>By action, petition to enjoin any acts or things that may be unlawful or in violation of the rights of the holders of the Bonds; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Declare all the Bonds to be due and payable, whether or not in advance of or at maturity and, if all defaults be made good, annul the declaration and its consequences.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The elected or appointed officials, officers, employees, or agents of the District shall not be personally liable on the Bonds by reason of their issuance.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-54" codify:value="the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025">this act</cite>, the Bonds shall not be general obligations of the District and shall not be a debt or liability of the District within the meaning of any debt or other limit prescribed by law. The faith and credit or the general taxing power of the District (other than funds in the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund or RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund) shall not be pledged to secure the payment of the Bonds.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.11" num-value="10-1605.12"/>
    <num>13</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Bond Financing and Closing Documents.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may prescribe the final form and content of all Financing Documents and all Closing Documents to which the District is a party that may be necessary or appropriate to issue, sell, and deliver the Bonds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may execute, in the name of the District and on its behalf, the Financing Documents and any Closing Documents to which the District is a party by the Mayor's manual or facsimile signature.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If required, the official seal of the District, or a facsimile of it, shall be impressed, printed, or otherwise reproduced on the Financing Documents and the Closing Documents to which the District is a party.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Mayor's execution and delivery of the Financing Documents and the Closing Documents to which the District is a party shall constitute conclusive evidence of the Mayor's approval, on behalf of the District, of the final form and content of the executed Financing Documents and the executed Closing Documents.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may deliver the executed and sealed Financing Documents and Closing Documents, on behalf of the District, prior to or simultaneously with the issuance, sale, and delivery of the Bonds, and to ensure the due performance of the obligations of the District contained in the executed, sealed, and delivered Financing Documents and Closing Documents.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.12" num-value="10-1605.13"/>
    <num>14</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Traffic Operations and Parking Plan requirement.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The District Department of Transportation ("DDOT"), in collaboration with Advisory Neighborhood Commissions 7F, 7D, 6A, 6B, and 5D, and the Developer, shall develop a Traffic Operations and Parking Plan ("TOPP") for the Stadium Project and surrounding neighborhood blocks.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The TOPP required by subsection (a) of this section shall provide guidance for transit riders, drivers, ride sharers, pedestrians, and cyclists to safely travel to and from the Stadium and surrounding neighborhood, with a particular focus on minimizing negative impacts on the surrounding communities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>DDOT shall issue regulations to ensure that the District enforces parking-meter and residential-parking-permit restrictions within the Stadium Project and surrounding neighborhood, including on Sundays and holidays.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert path="10|16|V|A" after="§10-1605.13" num-value="10-1605.14"/>
    <num>15</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Required reports.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall provide to the Council and post online the following information associated with the RFK Campus Redevelopment:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>All Transaction Documents, within 30 days of execution;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>All modifications to the Transaction Documents for the duration of the lease, within 30 days of execution;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Beginning June 1, 2026, and quarterly thereafter until construction on the Stadium Project is complete, a report regarding the development, design, and construction progress of the Stadium Project, including:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Financial information, detailing hard and soft costs by initial expected budgets, revised budgets, amount expended in the reporting month, and amount expended to date; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>A timeline for completion of the Stadium and any parking facilities;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Beginning October 1, 2026, the Mayor shall transmit, at least quarterly, a report to the Council detailing all First Source compliance information required to be submitted by the Team or the Developer to the Department of Employment Services and all small business enterprise and all certified business enterprise compliance documentation required to be submitted by the Team or the Developer to the Department of Small and Local Business Development, with any personally identifiable information redacted; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Beginning January 1, 2030, a semi-annual report on the activity on the RFK Campus, including:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Event data, as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Number of events hosted at the Stadium, identifying if they are Team Events or non-Team Events;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Number of events hosted on the RFK Campus; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Number of tickets sold and number of attendees per event;</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Commercial space data, as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Total rentable square feet of commercial space, broken down by type (including apartment/multifamily, office, hotel, and retail);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>The vacancy rate of each type of commercial space;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>For each apartment/multifamily space, the number of units with a certificate of occupancy, per building; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>For each hotel, the number of keys and revenue per available room;</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>The total number of employees of the Team, any Team subsidiary, and the Team's corporate parent whose primary worksite is in the District, including:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Number of full-time, part-time, and temporary positions; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>The state of residence of those employees; and</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>The total number of employees working in the Stadium, including:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Number of full-time, part-time, and temporary positions;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>The state of residence of those employees and, for District employees, ward of residence; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Number of vacant positions.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>No sooner than July 1, 2032, the District Department of Transportation, in collaboration with the Team, shall submit a report to the Council analyzing the need for a third parking garage to accommodate traffic associated with the development of the RFK Campus.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Mayor, in collaboration with the Team, no later than January 1, 2028, shall produce a report to the Council that includes a site survey, feasibility study, and financial assessment for the inclusion of a new engine and ladder company within the Development Site and as part of the phased construction plans.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The report shall include an estimate of the District funding needed, potential site locations on the RFK Campus, co-location opportunities with planned development sites, and an assessment of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department's needs for the additional apparatus and full staffing.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>16</num>
    <heading proof="needed">RFK Campus parking facility bonds; Washington Convention and Sports Authority bond authority.</heading>
    <text>Title II of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective September 28, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-188; D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.01 et seq.), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§10-1202.04">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 204 (D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.04) is amended by adding a new subsection (a-2) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(a-1)" num-value="(a-2)"/>
          <num>(a-2)</num>
          <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the Authority may, without submission to the Council, adopt inducement resolutions or resolutions authorizing the issuance of bonds and may issue bonds in a total principal amount not to exceed $284 million or such lesser amount as necessary in order to generate net proceeds of $181 million to finance the construction of the parking facilities approved by the Mayor on the RFK Campus.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§10-1202.10|(a)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 210(a) (D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.10(a)) is amended by striking the phrase "or certain costs of the new convention center hotel or a District sports or entertainment facility hotel." and inserting in the phrase ", certain costs of the new convention center hotel or a District sports or entertainment facility hotel, or parking facilities approved by the Mayor on the RFK Campus." in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find> or certain costs of the new convention center hotel or a District sports or entertainment facility hotel.</find>
        <replace>, certain costs of the new convention center hotel or a District sports or entertainment facility hotel, or parking facilities approved by the Mayor on the RFK Campus.</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>17</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Property, possessory interest, and recordation tax exemptions.</heading>
    <para codify:path="§42-1102">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 302 of the District of Columbia Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 11; D.C. Official Code § 42-1102), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(36)|(B)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (36)(B) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>; and</find>
          <replace>;</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(37)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (37) is amended by striking the phrase "2024." and inserting the phrase "2024; and" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>2024.</find>
          <replace>2024; and</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (38) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(37)" num-value="(38)"/>
            <num>(38)</num>
            <text>Deeds with respect to the real property (and any improvements thereon) on which the stadium, as defined by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002.08|(a)|(2)">§ 47-2002.08(a)(2)</code-cite>, and standalone parking facilities that serve the stadium are constructed or to be constructed, to the extent such deeds convey an interest between the District and Pro-Football LLC, or an affiliate of Pro-Football LLC, pursuant to the leases authorized by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.03|(c)|(1)">section 4(c)(1) of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="§47-1002">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Section 47-1002 is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(34)">
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (34) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>; and</find>
            <replace>;</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(35)">
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (35) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace position="last">
            <find>.</find>
            <replace>; and</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>A new paragraph (36) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(35)" num-value="(36)"/>
              <num>(36)</num>
              <text>Each parcel (and the improvements thereon) on the RFK Campus, as defined by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002.08|(a)|(1)">§ 47-2002.08(a)(1)</cite>, on which the stadium, as defined by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002.08|(a)|(2)">§ 47-2002.08(a)(2)</cite>, and standalone parking facilities that serve the stadium are constructed or to be constructed, so long as the leases authorized by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.03|(c)|(1)">section 4(c)(1) of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025</code-cite> between the District and Pro-Football LLC or an affiliate of Pro-Football LLC for the stadium and standalone parking facilities remain in effect.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§47-1005.01">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Section 47-1005.01 is amended by adding a new subsection (c-3) to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(c-2)" num-value="(c-3)"/>
            <num>(c-3)</num>
            <text>This section shall not apply to the real property (and any improvements thereon) on the RFK Campus, as defined by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002.08|(a)|(1)">§ 47-2002.08(a)(1)</cite>, on which the stadium, as defined by<cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002.08|(a)|(2)"> § 47-2002.08(a)(2)</cite>, and standalone parking facilities that serve the stadium are constructed or to be constructed, for so long as the leases authorized by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.03|(c)|(1)">section 4(c)(1) of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025</code-cite> between the District and Pro-Football LLC, or an affiliate of Pro-Football LLC, for the stadium and the standalone parking facilities remain in effect.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>18</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Football stadium sales taxes.</heading>
    <text>Chapter 20 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The table of contents is amended by adding a new section designation to read as follows:</text>
      <!-- done below -->
      <include>
        <toc>
          <section>
            <num>47-2002.08</num>
            <heading>Football stadium additional sales taxes.</heading>
          </section>
        </toc>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new section 47-2002.08 is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <codify:insert path="47|20" after="§47-2002.07" num-value="47-2002.08"/>
          <prefix>§</prefix>
          <num>47-2002.08</num>
          <heading proof="needed">Football stadium additional sales taxes.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>"RFK Campus" means those parcels of land that are the subject of the Transfer of Jurisdiction Plat recorded in the Surveyor's Office on February 5, 2025, on page 13 of subdivision book 223.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>"Stadium" means the stadium constructed on the RFK Campus after October 1, 2025, to be owned by the District, as described in the Term Sheet.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>"Term Sheet" shall have the meaning set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.01|(33)">section 2(33) of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-288)</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>"Ticket" means any physical, electronic, or other form of a certificate, documents, or token showing that a fare, admission, or license fee for a revocable right to enter the Stadium has been paid.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|20">this chapter</cite>, there is imposed an additional sales tax of 4.25% on the gross receipts of any person from the sale of or charges for tickets to any public event to be performed at the Stadium subject to the gross sales tax under chapter 20 or the compensating-use tax under chapter 22.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|20">this chapter</cite>, there is imposed an additional sales tax of 4.25% on the gross receipts of any person from the sale at the Stadium of tangible personal property or services otherwise taxable under the provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|20">this chapter</cite>, except for the gross receipts from:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The sales of food and beverages subject to the tax imposed by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002|(a)|(3)" codify:value="§ 47-2002[(a)(3)]">§ 47-2002(3)</cite>; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The sale of or charge for the service of parking motor vehicles subject to the tax imposed by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002|(a)|(1)">§ 47-2002(a)(1)</cite>.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall promulgate regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section, including regulations relating to the determination of District gross receipts and electronic filing and payment of sales taxes and fees.</text>
          </para>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§47-2005">
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 47-2005 is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(38)|(B)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (38)(B) is amended by striking the period and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>.</find>
          <replace>;</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(39)|(B)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (39)(B) is amended by striking the period and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>.</find>
          <replace>;</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(40)">
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (40) is amended by striking the period and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace position="last">
          <find>.</find>
          <replace>;</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(41)">
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (41) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>.</find>
          <replace>; and</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (42) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(41)" num-value="(42)"/>
            <num>(42)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Sales of Personal Seat Licenses at the Stadium for the term of the lease between the District and Pro-Football LLC, or an affiliate of Pro-Football LLC, for the Stadium.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(i)</num>
                <text>"Personal Seat License" means a license, location right, or other similar instrument for seats in the Stadium issued to a person for the right to purchase season tickets to games and tickets to other events at the Stadium.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <text>"Stadium" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002.08|(a)|(2)">§ 47-2002.08(a)(2)</cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>19</num>
    <heading proof="needed">RFK Transportation Improvement Fund.</heading>
    <text>The Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective May 21, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-137; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.01 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended by adding a new section 9u to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="50|9A|I" after="§50-921.28" num-value="50-921.29" history-prefix="as added"/>
        <num>9u</num>
        <heading proof="needed">RFK Transportation Improvement Fund.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>There is established as a special fund the Transportation Improvement Fund, which shall be administered by the Mayor pursuant to subsection (c) of this section.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Excess RFK Campus Infrastructure Funds up to $20 million annually, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.31|(d)|(2)">section 2052(d)(2) of the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund Establishment Act of 2025, enacted on September 4, 2025 (D.C. Act 26-148; 72 DCR 9825)</code-cite>, shall be deposited into the Transportation Improvement Fund.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Money in the Transportation Improvement Fund shall be used to support public-transit related improvements for the RFK Campus, including Metrorail and Metrobus, related infrastructure, Metrorail stations and roadways, and investments to improve transportation access to the RFK Campus; provided, that any roadway improvements are directly related to an improvement to public transit access on the RFK Campus.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Expenditures for the purposes set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection may include both operating and capital costs, but may not be expended for the maintenance or construction of new roadways unless the expenditure is directly related to an improvement to public transit access.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The money deposited into the Transportation Improvement Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Transportation Improvement Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>For purposes of this section, the term "RFK Campus" shall have the meaning set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.01|(18)">section 2(18) of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-288)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History" path="§9u">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 9u</annotation>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section codify:path="§1-306.07|(a)">
    <num>20</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Limited zoning exemption.</heading>
    <text>Section 7(a) of the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Element Amendment Act of 1984, effective May 23, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-129; D.C. Official Code § 1-306.07(a)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="(1)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "and (4)" and inserting the phrase "(4), and (5)" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>and (4)</find>
        <replace>(4), and (5)</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (5) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(4)" num-value="(5)"/>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>The uses of government land for a multi-purpose stadium to serve as a venue for a National Football League team in the District, an accessory office building, accessory parking facilities, and a public sports and recreation facility on a portion of the RFK Campus, as defined by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002.08|(a)|(1)">D.C. Official Code § 47-2002.08(a)(1)</code-cite>, shall not be subject to zoning until, with respect to each structure constructed for such uses, after such time as a final certificate of occupancy is issued for the structure.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>21</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Lease of the Development Site.</heading>
    <para codify:path="§10-801|(a)|(1)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 1(a)(1) of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code § 10-801(a)(1)), is amended by striking the phrase "owned in fee simple by the District" and inserting the phrase "owned in fee simple by the District or, in the case of real property disposed of by lease, under the jurisdiction of the District" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>owned in fee simple by the District</find>
        <replace>owned in fee simple by the District or, in the case of real property disposed of by lease, under the jurisdiction of the District</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§1-301.01|(c)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 1(c) of An Act To grant additional powers to the Commissioners of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved December 20, 1944 (58 Stat. 819; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.01(c)), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The existing text is designated as paragraph (1).</text>
        <codify:redesignate-para num-value="(1)"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (2) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(1)" num-value="(2)"/>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The Mayor may not exercise his or her authority under this subsection with respect to the parcels of land that are the subject of the Transfer of Jurisdiction Plat recorded in the Surveyor's Office of the District of Columbia on February 5, 2025, on page 13 of subdivision book 223, together with any public streets within or adjacent to such parcels that may be closed from time to time; except, that the Mayor may lease such parcels, on the condition that the preconditions for the issuance of bonds and the expenditure of bond proceeds set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.05">section 6 of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-288)</code-cite>, have been met.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:marginalia display="DCMR"/>
    <num>22</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Establishment of Stadium District Entertainment Area.</heading>
    <text>Section N101.20 of Title 12A of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (12-A DCMR § N101.20) is amended by adding a new paragraph (g) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Stadium District Entertainment Area. The Stadium District Entertainment Area is the real property comprising the Stadium, Stadium District Parcel, and Plaza District Commercial Parcel portions of the RFK Campus, as identified in the Term Sheet. Designated Entertainment Area Sign Permits may be allowed in the Stadium District Entertainment Area subject to the requirements of this subsection.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term "Term Sheet" shall have the meaning set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.01|(33)">section 2(33) of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-288)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section codify:path="§2-1226.39">
    <num>23</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Anacostia Waterfront environmental standards.</heading>
    <text>Section 459 of the National Capital Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Act of 2008, effective March 26, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-138; D.C. Official Code § 2-1226.39), is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert after="(c)" num-value="(d)"/>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>For any project on the development site, as defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.01|(11)">section 2(11) of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-288)</code-cite>, DDOE may grant an exemption pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section; except, that DDOE shall transmit the exemption to the Council for approval, for a 30-day period of review, excluding days of Council recess.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The Council shall be deemed to have approved the exemption under this subsection if, during the 30-day period, no member introduces a resolution disapproving the exemption. If a member introduces a resolution disapproving the exemption within the 30-day period, the Council shall have an additional 30 days, excluding days of Council recess, to disapprove the exemption by resolution, or it will be deemed approved.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>24</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Washington Convention and Sports Authority compliance monitoring.</heading>
    <text>Title II of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective September 28, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-188; D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.01 et seq.), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <para codify:path="§10-1202.03">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Section 203 (D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.03) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(13)">
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (13) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>; and</find>
            <replace>;</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(14)">
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (14) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>.</find>
            <replace>; and</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>A new paragraph (15) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(14)" num-value="(15)"/>
              <num>(15)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>To retain an independent consultant to monitor the redevelopment of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus, including compliance with all requirements of <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-54" codify:value="the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025">the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-288)</cite>, the terms of the Development and Financing Agreement, and all related Transaction Documents.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Beginning October 1, 2026, the Authority shall submit a quarterly report to the Council on the monitoring activities and the compliance findings.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(i)</num>
                  <text>"Development and Financing Agreement" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.01|(10)">section 2(10) of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-288)</code-cite>.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(ii)</num>
                  <text>"Transaction Document" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.01|(33)">section 2(33) of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-288)</code-cite>.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§10-1202.04|(m)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Section 204(m) (D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.04(m)) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>25</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Excess RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund disbursement.</heading>
    <text>Section 2052(d)(2) of the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund Establishment Act of 2025, enacted on September 4, 2025 (D.C. Act 26-148; 72 DCR 9825), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="1">
      <para>
        <!-- done in Law 26-55 -->
        <!-- <codify:replace doc="D.C. Law 26-55" path="§2052|(d)|(2)"/> -->
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>If the amount of an annual deposit to the RFK Transportation Improvement Fund pursuant to paragraph (1)(C) of this subsection would exceed $20 million, $20 million shall be deposited in the RFK Transportation Improvement Fund, the next $2 million shall be deposited into the Community Reinvestment Fund, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.08|(c)">section 9(c) of the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-288)</code-cite>, and any amount over $22 million shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>26</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>27</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973, (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
