<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 26-84" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">26-84</num>
  <num type="act">26-201</num>
  <num type="bill">26-32</num>
  <heading type="short">Uniform Special Deposits Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code to enact the Uniform Special Deposits Act to establish clear criteria for what constitutes a special deposit, to permit parties to opt-in to the protections of the act by agreement, to establish the conditions under which a bank is obligated to pay a special deposit to a beneficiary, to provide that neither the depositor nor the beneficiary have a property interest in a special deposit, to clarify the applicability of the creditor process on a special deposit, to clarify the legality of a bank's right to exercise a setoff or right to recoupment against a special deposit that its unrelated to the special deposit, to establish a 5-year default term for special deposits, to provide that this act shall be applied and construed in a manner that promotes uniformity among the jurisdictions that adopt it, and to provide for its application to existing and future special deposits.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-01-07</introduced>
    <effective>2026-02-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56889/Signed_Act/B26-0032-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=227783">D.C. Law 26-84</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56889/Signed_Act/B26-0032-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=227783">D.C. Act 26-201</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 13482</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B26-0032">
      <vote date="2025-10-21" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-11-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-11-24</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 26-32 would establish clear criteria for special deposits and clarify the treatment of special deposits in the event of the bankruptcy of a depositor.  It also clarifies the applicability of the creditor process on a special deposit. It is an “opt-in” statute, which is available to banks and depositors to suit their needs for particular purposes.</summary>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Special Deposits Act of 2025".</text>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="28" after="29" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
      <num>29A</num>
      <heading>Uniform Special Deposits.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The table of contents is amended by adding a new chapter designation to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <text>29A. Uniform Special Deposits.</text>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new Chapter 29A is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <container>
          <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
          <num>29</num>
          <heading>A. Uniform Special Deposits.</heading>
          <toc>
            <text>Sec.</text>
            <section>
              <num>28-2951</num>
              <heading>Definitions.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2952</num>
              <heading>Scope; choice of law; forum.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2953</num>
              <heading>Variation by agreement or amendment.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2954</num>
              <heading>Requirements for special deposit.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2955</num>
              <heading>Permissible purpose.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2956</num>
              <heading>Payment to beneficiary by bank.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2957</num>
              <heading>Property interest of depositor or beneficiary</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2958</num>
              <heading>When creditor process enforceable against bank.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2959</num>
              <heading>Injunction or similar relief.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2960</num>
              <heading>Recoupment or setoff.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2961</num>
              <heading>Duties and liability of bank.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2962</num>
              <heading>Term and termination.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2963</num>
              <heading>Principles of law and equity.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2964</num>
              <heading>Uniformity of application and construction.</heading>
            </section>
            <section>
              <num>28-2965</num>
              <heading>Transitional provision.</heading>
            </section>
          </toc>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" num-value="28-2951"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2951</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
            <para>
              <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
              <text>For the purposes of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>"Account agreement" means an agreement that:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Is in a record between a bank and one or more depositors;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>May have one or more beneficiaries as additional parties; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>States the intention of the parties to establish a special deposit governed by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>"Bank" means a person engaged in the business of banking and includes a savings bank, savings and loan association, credit union, and trust company. Each branch or separate office of a bank is a separate bank for the purposes of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>"Beneficiary" means a person that:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Is identified as a beneficiary in an account agreement; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>If not identified as a beneficiary in an account agreement, may be entitled to payment from a special deposit:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>Under the account agreement; or</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>On termination of the special deposit.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>"Contingency" means an event or circumstance stated in an account agreement that is not certain to occur but must occur before the bank is obligated to pay a beneficiary.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>"Creditor process" means attachment, garnishment, levy, notice of lien, sequestration, or similar process issued by or on behalf of a creditor or other claimant.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>"Depositor" means a person that establishes or funds a special deposit.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>"Good faith" means honesty in fact and observance of reasonable commercial standards of fair dealing.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>"Knowledge" of a fact means:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>With respect to a beneficiary, actual knowledge of the fact; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>With respect to a bank holding a special deposit:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>Actual knowledge of the fact by an individual, if the bank:</text>
                    <para>
                      <num>(I)</num>
                      <text>Has established a reasonable routine for communicating material information to the individual to whom the bank has assigned responsibility for the special deposit; and</text>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                      <num>(II)</num>
                      <text>Maintains reasonable compliance with the routine; or</text>
                    </para>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>If the bank has not established and maintained reasonable compliance with a routine described in sub-subparagraph (i) of this subparagraph or otherwise exercised due diligence, implied knowledge of the fact that would have come to the attention of an individual to whom the bank has assigned responsibility for the special deposit.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(9)</num>
                <text>"Obligated to pay a beneficiary" means a beneficiary is entitled under the account agreement to receive from the bank a payment when:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>A contingency has occurred; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The bank has knowledge the contingency has occurred.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(10)</num>
                <text>"Permissible purpose" means a governmental, regulatory, commercial, charitable, or testamentary objective of the parties stated in an account agreement. The term includes an objective to:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Hold funds:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>In escrow, including for a purchase and sale, lease, buyback, or other transaction;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>As a security deposit of a tenant;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iii)</num>
                    <text>That may be distributed to a person as remuneration, retirement or other benefit, or compensation under a judgment, consent decree, court order, or other decision of a tribunal; or</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iv)</num>
                    <text>For distribution to a defined class of persons after identification of the class members and their interest in the funds;</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Provide assurance with respect to an obligation created by contract, such as earnest money to ensure a transaction closes;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Settle an obligation that arises in the operation of a payment system, securities settlement system, or other financial market infrastructure;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>Provide assurance with respect to an obligation that arises in the operation of a payment system, securities settlement system, or other financial market infrastructure; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(E)</num>
                  <text>Hold margin, other cash collateral, or funds that support the orderly functioning of financial market infrastructure or the performance of an obligation with respect to the infrastructure.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(11)</num>
                <text>"Person" means an individual, estate, business or nonprofit entity, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or other legal entity. The term includes a protected series, however denominated, of an entity if the protected series is established under law that limits, or limits if conditions specified under law are satisfied, the ability of a creditor of the entity or of any other protected series of the entity to satisfy a claim from assets of the protected series.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(12)</num>
                <text>"Record" means information:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Inscribed on a tangible medium; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Stored in an electronic or other medium and retrievable in perceivable form.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(13)</num>
                <text>"Special deposit" means a deposit that satisfies the requirements set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2954">§ 28-2954</cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2951" num-value="28-2952"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2952</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Scope; choice of law; forum.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text><cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">This chapter</cite> applies to a special deposit under an account agreement that states the intention of the parties to establish a special deposit governed by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>, regardless of whether a party to the account agreement or a transaction related to the special deposit, or the special deposit itself, has a reasonable relation to the District.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The parties to an account agreement may choose a forum in the District for settling a dispute arising out of the special deposit, regardless of whether a party to the account agreement or a transaction related to the special deposit, or the special deposit itself, has a reasonable relation to the District.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text><cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">This chapter</cite> does not affect:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A right or obligation relating to a deposit other than a special deposit under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The voidability of a deposit or transfer that is fraudulent or voidable under other law.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2952" num-value="28-2953"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2953</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Variation by agreement or amendment.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The effect of §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2951">28-2951</cite> through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2955">28-2955</cite>, §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2957">28-2957</cite> through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2960">28-2960</cite>, and § <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2963">28-2963</cite> may not be varied by agreement, except as provided in those sections. Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the effect of §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2956">28-2956</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2961">28-2961</cite>, and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2962">28-2962</cite> may be varied by agreement.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>A provision in an account agreement or other record that substantially excuses liability or substantially limits remedies for failure to perform an obligation under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite> is not sufficient to vary the effect of a provision of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>If a beneficiary is a party to an account agreement, the bank and the depositor may amend the agreement without the consent of the beneficiary only if the agreement expressly permits the amendment.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>If a beneficiary is not a party to an account agreement and the bank and the depositor know the beneficiary has knowledge of the agreement's terms, the bank and the depositor may amend the agreement without the consent of the beneficiary only if the amendment does not adversely and materially affect a payment right of the beneficiary.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>If a beneficiary is not a party to an account agreement and the bank and the depositor do not know whether the beneficiary has knowledge of the agreement's terms, the bank and the depositor may amend the agreement without the consent of the beneficiary only if the amendment is made in good faith.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2953" num-value="28-2954"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2954</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Requirements for special deposit.</heading>
            <para>
              <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
              <text>A deposit is a special deposit if it is:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A deposit of funds in a bank under an account agreement;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>For the benefit of at least 2 beneficiaries, one or more of which may be a depositor;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Denominated in a medium of exchange that is currently authorized or adopted by a domestic or foreign government;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>For a permissible purpose stated in the account agreement; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>Subject to a contingency.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2954" num-value="28-2955"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2955</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Permissible purpose.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>A special deposit must serve at least one permissible purpose stated in the account agreement from the time the special deposit is created in the account agreement until termination of the special deposit.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>If, before termination of the special deposit, the bank or a court determines the special deposit no longer satisfies subsection (a) of this section, §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2957">28-2957</cite> through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2960">28-2960</cite> shall cease to apply to any funds deposited in the special deposit after the special deposit ceases to satisfy subsection (a) of this section.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>If, before termination of a special deposit, the bank determines the special deposit no longer satisfies subsection (a) of this section, the bank may take action it believes is necessary under the circumstances, including terminating the special deposit.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2955" num-value="28-2956"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2956</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Payment to beneficiary by bank.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Unless the account agreement provides otherwise, the bank is obligated to pay a beneficiary if there are sufficient actually and finally collected funds in the balance of the special deposit.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the obligation to pay the beneficiary is excused if the funds available in the special deposit are insufficient to cover such payment.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>Unless the account agreement provides otherwise, if the funds available in the special deposit are insufficient to cover an obligation to pay a beneficiary, a beneficiary may elect to be paid the funds that are available or, if there is more than one beneficiary, a pro rata share of the funds available. Payment to the beneficiary making the election under this subsection discharges the bank's obligation to pay a beneficiary and does not constitute an accord and satisfaction with respect to another person obligated to the beneficiary.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>Unless the account agreement provides otherwise, the obligation of the bank obligated to pay a beneficiary is immediately due and payable.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>The bank may discharge its obligation under this section by:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Crediting another transaction account of the beneficiary; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Taking other action that:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Is permitted under the account agreement for the bank to obtain a discharge; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Otherwise would constitute a discharge under law.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <text>If the bank obligated to pay a beneficiary has incurred an obligation to discharge the obligation of another person, the obligation of the other person is discharged if action by the bank under subsection (e) of this section would constitute a discharge of the obligation of the other person under law that determines whether an obligation is satisfied.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2956" num-value="28-2957"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2957</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Property interest of depositor or beneficiary.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Neither a depositor nor a beneficiary has a property interest in a special deposit.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Any property interest with respect to a special deposit is only in the right to receive payment if the bank is obligated to pay a beneficiary and not in the special deposit itself. Any property interest under this subsection is determined under other law.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2957" num-value="28-2958"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2958</num>
            <heading proof="needed">When creditor process enforceable against bank.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, creditor process with respect to a special deposit is not enforceable against the bank holding the special deposit.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Creditor process is enforceable against the bank holding a special deposit with respect to an amount the bank is obligated to pay a beneficiary or a depositor if the process:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Is served on the bank;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Provides sufficient information to permit the bank to identify the depositor or the beneficiary from the bank's books and records; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Gives the bank a reasonable opportunity to act on the process.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>Creditor process served on a bank before it is enforceable against the bank under subsection (b) of this section does not create a right of the creditor against the bank or a duty of the bank to the creditor. Other law determines whether creditor process creates a lien enforceable against the beneficiary on a contingent interest of a beneficiary, including a depositor as a beneficiary, even if not enforceable against the bank.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2958" num-value="28-2959"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2959</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Injunction or similar relief.</heading>
            <text>A court may enjoin, or grant similar relief that would have the effect of enjoining, a bank from paying a depositor or beneficiary only if payment would constitute a material fraud or facilitate a material fraud with respect to a special deposit.</text>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2959" num-value="28-2960"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2960</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Recoupment or setoff.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) or (c) of this section, a bank may not exercise a right of recoupment or setoff against a special deposit.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>An account agreement may authorize the bank to debit the special deposit:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>When the bank becomes obligated to pay a beneficiary, in an amount that does not exceed the amount necessary to discharge the obligation;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>For a fee assessed by the bank that relates to an overdraft in the special deposit account;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>For costs incurred by the bank that relate directly to the special deposit; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>To reverse an earlier credit posted by the bank to the balance of the special deposit account, if the reversal occurs under an event or circumstance warranted under other law of the District governing mistake and restitution.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The bank holding a special deposit may exercise a right of recoupment or setoff against an obligation to pay a beneficiary, even if the bank funds payment from the special deposit.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2960" num-value="28-2961"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2961</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Duties and liability of bank.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>A bank does not have a fiduciary duty to any person with respect to a special deposit.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>When the bank holding a special deposit becomes obligated to pay a beneficiary, a debtor-creditor relationship arises between the bank and beneficiary.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The bank holding a special deposit has a duty to a beneficiary to comply with the account agreement and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>If the bank holding a special deposit does not comply with the account agreement or <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>, the bank is liable to a depositor or beneficiary only for damages proximately caused by the noncompliance. Except as provided by other law of the District, the bank is not liable for consequential, special, or punitive damages.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>The bank holding a special deposit may rely on records presented in compliance with the account agreement to determine whether the bank is obligated to pay a beneficiary.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <text>If the account agreement requires payment on presentation of a record, the bank shall determine within a reasonable time whether the record is sufficient to require payment. If the agreement requires action by the bank on presentation of a record, the bank is not liable for relying in good faith on the genuineness of the record if the record appears on its face to be genuine.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(g)</num>
              <text>Unless the account agreement provides otherwise, the bank is not required to determine whether a permissible purpose stated in the agreement continues to exist.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2961" num-value="28-2962"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2962</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Term and termination.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Unless otherwise provided in the account agreement, a special deposit terminates 5 years after the date the special deposit was first funded.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Unless otherwise provided in the account agreement, if the bank cannot identify or locate a beneficiary entitled to payment when the special deposit is terminated, and a balance remains in the special deposit, the bank shall pay the balance to the depositor or depositors as a beneficiary or beneficiaries.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>A bank that pays the remaining balance as provided under subsection (b) of this section has no further obligation with respect to the special deposit.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2962" num-value="28-2963"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2963</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Principles of law and equity.</heading>
            <text><cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|I">Subtitle I of this title</cite>, District consumer protection law, District laws governing deposits generally, District law related to escheat and abandoned or unclaimed property, and the principles of law and equity, including law related to capacity to contract, principal and agent, estoppel, fraud, misrepresentation, duress, coercion, mistake, and bankruptcy, supplement <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite> except to the extent inconsistent with <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2963" num-value="28-2964"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2964</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Uniformity of application and construction.</heading>
            <text>In applying and construing <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>, consideration must be given to the need to promote uniformity of the law among jurisdictions that enact it.</text>
          </section>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="28|29A" after="§28-2964" num-value="28-2965"/>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>28-2965</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Transitional provision.</heading>
            <para>
              <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
              <text><cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">This chapter</cite> applies to:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A special deposit made under an account agreement executed on or after <span codify:value="[February 3, 2026]">the effective date of this chapter</span>; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>A deposit made under an agreement executed before <span codify:value="[February 3, 2026]">the effective date of this chapter</span>, if:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>All parties entitled to amend the agreement agree to make the deposit a special deposit governed by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|29A">this chapter</cite>; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The special deposit referenced in the amended agreement satisfies <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-2954">§ 28-2954</cite>.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </container>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
