<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 26-80">
  <num type="law">26-80</num>
  <num type="act">26-199</num>
  <num type="bill">26-164</num>
  <heading type="short">Rebalancing Expectations for Neighbors, Tenants, and Landlords (RENTAL) Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to provide for expedited review of eviction proceedings stemming from a dangerous crime or crime of violence, to grant courts discretion to determine when equities require the dismissal of a claim by a housing provider, to reduce the pre-filing notice period in cases seeking eviction for nonpayment, and to update procedures for pre-filing notice to tenants in eviction cases; to amend Chapter 15 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code to reduce a pre-eviction-hearing summons period, to provide courts that hear eviction cases with discretion not to dismiss cases for certain deficiencies, and to update processes for the deposit of rental payments into the court registry during eviction cases for nonpayment; to amend the Tenant Opportunity to Purchase Act of 1980 to reorganize various existing provisions, to clarify the applicability of the act in circumstances such as the disposition of intestate decedents' property, to allow for the entry and exit of non-controlling investors in property ownership entities without triggering the act, to exempt new construction for the 15 years after construction and certain covenanted affordable housing projects from the act, to establish a system of certified tenant support providers, to streamline tenant notice provisions and consolidate certain tenant grievance procedures, to establish protections from interference in the act's processes and enforcement mechanisms, to require the Department of Housing and Community Development to develop certain form documents and receive filings of certain processes, to establish permissible consideration for tenant assignment of their rights under the act, and to direct the Department of Housing and Community Development to maintain a public database; to amend Chapter 48 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to clarify the applicability of recent changes to the District low-income housing tax credit program; to amend the Inclusionary Zoning Implementation Amendment Act to facilitate the resale of units; to amend the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999 to revise the structure of the board of the Authority, to modify the schedule for annual financial accountability reports, to provide flexibility for board and executive director training, to update the public housing resident bill of rights, and to add protections for residents whose public housing properties undergo federal subsidy repositioning; to amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to adjust Housing Authority board stipends; and to amend the Confirmation Act of 1978 to conform terminology regarding the Housing Authority board.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-03-03</introduced>
    <effective>2025-12-31</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57311/Signed_Act/B26-0164-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=227055">D.C. Law 26-80</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57311/Signed_Act/B26-0164-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=227055">D.C. Act 26-199</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 12894</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0164">
      <vote date="2025-07-14" reading="Postponed"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-28" reading="Motion"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-28" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-28" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-28" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-28" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-28" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="AMENDMENT"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="Frumin"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="Bonds"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="Bonds"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="MOTION"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="T."/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="T."/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="Reconsideration"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="Nadeau,"/>
      <vote date="2025-09-17" reading="Final"/>
      <vote date="2025-10-21" reading="Motion"/>
      <vote date="2025-10-21" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-10-21" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-10-21" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-11-13</enacted>
      <summary>Please see Referral Memo. COMMITTEE REFERRAL IS AS FOLLOWS:</summary>
      <committee>Housing, Human Services, Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Rebalancing Expectations for Neighbors, Tenants, and Landlords (RENTAL) Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>I</num>
    <heading>PUBLIC SAFETY EVICTIONS.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>101</num>
      <text>Section 501 of the Rental Housing Act of 1985 effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3505.01), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a)(4) is amended by striking the phrase "shall dismiss" and inserting the phrase "may, in its discretion when weighing the prejudice to all parties, dismiss" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a-1) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "at least 30 days" and inserting the phrase "at least 10 days" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A new paragraph (3) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>The notice required by this subsection shall be provided as follows:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>By certified mail or delivery service providing delivery tracking confirmation, return receipt requested; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>By hand delivery to the rental unit or by posting on the front door of the rental unit.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Subsection (c) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>A housing provider may recover possession of a rental unit where a court of competent jurisdiction has determined that the tenant, or a person occupying the premises with or in addition to the tenant, has performed an illegal act within the rental unit or the housing accommodation. Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2)(B) of this subsection, the housing provider shall serve on the tenant a 30-day notice to vacate. If the person who was found to have performed an illegal act is someone occupying the premise other than the tenant, the tenant may be evicted only if the tenant knew or should have known that an illegal act was taking place. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to excuse a housing provider's unlawful retaliatory action or failure to comply with the Violence Against Women Act of 1994, approved September 13, 1994 (108 Stat. 1902; 34 U.S.C. § 12291 <em>et seq.</em>), or successor legislation, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, approved July 26, 1990 (104 Stat. 327; 42 U.S.C. § 12101 <em>et seq</em>.), Titles VIII and IX of the Civil Rights Act of 1968, approved April 11, 1968 (82 Stat. 81; 42 U.S.C. §§ 3601-3619, 3631), the Human Rights Act of 1977, effective December 13, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-38; D.C. Code § 2-1401.01 <em>et seq</em>.), sections 507 and 508 of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-273; D.C. Official Code §§ 42-3505.07, 42-3505.08), or other applicable federal or District law.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>In each case pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection filed after the effective date of the Rebalancing Expectations for Neighbors, Tenants, and Landlords (RENTAL) Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading (reconsideration) on October 21, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-164), in which the alleged illegal act within the rental unit or the housing accommodation would constitute a dangerous crime as defined in D.C. Official Code § 23-1331(3) or a crime of violence as defined in D.C. Official Code § 23-1331(4) and was not committed in self-defense or defense of another:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(i)</num>
                  <text>The housing provider, after considering in good faith all reasonable available means to preserve the housing of non-offending occupants, such as barring the offending individual from the property or assessing whether the lease can be transferred to an eligible occupant, shall serve on the tenant a 10-day notice to vacate; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(ii)</num>
                  <text>The Court shall hold a hearing on an expedited basis within 20 days following the filing of the complaint.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>In addition to the defense listed in subsection (c-1) of this section, it shall be a defense to an action for possession under this subsection based on allegations of a dangerous crime or crime of violence if:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(i)</num>
                  <text>The tenant did not know or did not have reason to know that criminal activity was occurring or would likely occur on the premises; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(ii)</num>
                  <text>The tenant took reasonable steps to prevent the commission of violent criminal activity, such as requesting the housing provider remove the offending household member's name from the lease, reporting prior criminal activity to the police, seeking assistance from social services or counseling agencies, or denying permission, if feasible, for the offending household member to reside in the dwelling unit; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(iii)</num>
                  <text>The tenant was a victim or intended victim of the criminal activity.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>If the Court determines by a preponderance of evidence that the tenant or occupant engaged in a dangerous crime as defined in D.C. Official Code § 23-1331(3) or a crime of violence as defined in D.C. Official Code § 23-1331(4), the Court shall enter a final judgment for possession and issue a writ of restitution that mandates the eviction of the tenant or occupant.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading>COURT EVICTION PROCEDURES.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>201</num>
      <text>Chapter 15 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>The table of contents is amended by adding a new section designation to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <toc>
            <section>
              <num>16-1502a</num>
              <heading>Protective orders and court registry payments.</heading>
            </section>
          </toc>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 16-1501(d) is amended by striking the phrase "shall dismiss the complaint." and inserting the phrase "may, in its discretion when weighing the prejudice to all parties, dismiss the complaint or provide leave for the complainant to correct any deficiencies." in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Section 16-1502(a) is amended by striking the phrase "30 days, excluding Sundays and legal holidays," and inserting the phrase "at least 14 days" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>A new section 16-1502a is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-1502a</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Protective orders and court registry payments.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Any party to a case for restitution of possession based on nonpayment of rent may move for the entry of a protective order that prospectively requires the defendant to deposit the rent payment, in the monthly amount required by the rent ledger, lease, rental agreement, or rental agreement addenda, into the court's registry, in regular monthly intervals, through the conclusion of the case.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Parties may enter into, vacate, or modify protective orders by consent with the approval of the court at any time.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>If a motion for a protective order is made, the court shall address the motion as follows:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The court shall inform the defendant of common protective order defenses that may justify a reduction in protective order monthly amounts, including current violations of the housing code and disputes over the calculation of the monthly rent amount asserted in the complaint. The court shall inform the defendant of the possible consequences of knowingly asserting baseless defenses.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The court shall issue a preliminary protective order for the monthly rent amount required by the rent ledger, lease, rental agreement, or rental agreement addenda after the initial motion and shall schedule a hearing thereafter on any alleged current violations of the housing code or other defenses that may merit an adjustment to the preliminary protective order. In determining the amount of the preliminary protective order, the court is not required to conduct an evidentiary proceeding, but may in its discretion consider evidence that the parties are prepared to present, including whether there is any dispute regarding the plaintiff's assertion of the monthly rent amount.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>III</num>
    <heading>TENANT OPPORTUNITY TO PURCHASE ACT.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>301</num>
      <text>The Tenant Opportunity to Purchase Act of 1980, effective September 10, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-86; D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>A new section 401a is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>401a</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
            <para>
              <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
              <text>For purposes of this title, the term:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>"Department" means the Department of Housing and Community Development, or any successor agency.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>"Owner" means:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Any person, any one of a number of persons, or any entity in whom is vested all or any part of the beneficial ownership, dominion, or title of a housing accommodation; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The committee, conservator, or legal guardian of a person described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph who is non compos mentis, a minor child, or otherwise under a disability.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>"Qualified Purchaser" means any person certified by the Mayor pursuant to section 402d, or an agency or instrumentality of the District.".</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>"Tenant" means any person or persons who, under the terms of a current or expired written lease or other rental agreement, are entitled to occupy the housing accommodation and are liable to the owner for the payment of rent.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit the definition of "tenant" for purposes of any other law.".</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>"Tenant support provider" means:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Any person or organization certified by the Mayor pursuant to section 402c; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The Office of the Tenant Advocate, as established by section 2065 of the Office of the Chief Tenant Advocate Establishment Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 42-3531.05).</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 402 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.02) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The section heading is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <section>
              <num>402</num>
              <heading proof="needed">Tenant opportunity to purchase.</heading>
            </section>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsections (a-2)(1), (b), (c), and (d) are repealed.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>New subsections (e) and (f) are added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Within 5 days after a request by any person, the Mayor shall provide:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Written certifications, including the date of receipt, of any notices received pursuant to titles IV and V of this act, or, if the Mayor has not received notices regarding a property specified by the requestor, certification of such non-receipt; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Copies of the notices.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The certifications may be recorded among the records of the Recorder of Deeds and shall be exempt from filing fees.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <text>A tenant's rights under this title vest at the time of receipt of an offer of sale pursuant to section 403 and shall not apply to a tenant that begins occupying a housing accommodation after the issuance of an offer of sale.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>New sections 402b, 402c, and 402d are added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>402b</num>
            <heading proof="needed">"Sale" defined; excluded properties.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>For the purposes of titles IV and V of this act, the terms "sell" or "sale" shall include:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The execution of any agreement pursuant to which the owner of the housing accommodation agrees to some, but not all, of the following:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Relinquishes possession of the property;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Extends an option to purchase the property for a sum certain at the end of the assignment, lease, or encumbrance and provides that a portion of the payments received pursuant to the agreement is to be applied to the purchase price;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Assigns all rights and interests in all contracts that relate to the property;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>Requires that the costs of all taxes and other government charges assessed and levied against the property during the term of the agreement are to be paid by the lessee either directly or through a surcharge paid to the owner;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(E)</num>
                  <text>Extends an option to purchase an ownership interest in the property, which may be exercised at any time after execution of the agreement but shall be exercised before the expiration of the agreement; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(F)</num>
                  <text>Requires the assignee or lessee to maintain personal injury and property damage liability insurance on the property that names the owner as the additional insured;</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>A master lease which meets some, but not all, of the factors described in paragraph (1) of this subsection or which is similar in effect; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The transfer of an ownership interest in a corporation, partnership, limited liability company, association, trust entity formed under the Uniform Statutory Trust Entity Act of 2010, D.C. Official Code § 29-1201.01 <em>et seq.</em>, or a similar statutory provision of another jurisdiction, or other entity which owns an accommodation as its sole or principal asset, which, in effect, results in the transfer of the majority of the ownership interests in the accommodation pursuant to paragraph (1) of this section. For the purposes of this paragraph, the term:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>"Principal asset" means the value of the accommodation relative to the entity's other holdings; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>"Majority of the ownership interests" means the ownership interests associated with the majority of the value of the capital, profits, and losses of the entity in which the interests are being transferred.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>For the purposes of titles IV and V of this act, and notwithstanding anything to the contrary herein, the term "sell" or "sale" shall not include</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>A transfer, even though for consideration, by a decedent's estate to members of the decedent's family, heir, or a legatee.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term "members of the decedent's family" means:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>The decedent's surviving spouse or domestic partner as defined in section 2(3) of the Health Care Benefits Expansion Act of 1992, effective June 11, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-114; D.C. Official Code § 32-701(3)), lineal descendants of the decedent, or spouses of lineal descendants of the decedent;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>A trust for the primary benefit of the persons referred to in sub-subparagraph (i) of this subparagraph;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iii)</num>
                    <text>A partnership, corporation, or other entity controlled by the individuals referred to in sub-subparagraphs (i) and (ii) of this subparagraph; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iv)</num>
                    <text>Heir as defined in D.C. Official Code § 20-101(c);</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>An inter-vivos transfer, even though for consideration, between spouses, parent and child, siblings, grandparent and grandchild, or domestic partners as defined in section 2(3) of the Health Care Benefits Expansion Act of 1992, effective June 11, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-114; D.C. Official Code § 32-701(3));</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>A transfer of legal title or an interest in an entity holding legal title to a housing accommodation pursuant to a bona fide deed of trust or mortgage, and thereafter any transfer by foreclosure sale or deed in lieu of foreclosure pursuant to a bona fide deed of trust or mortgage;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>A transfer of ownership interests or series of transfers of ownership interests between or among existing owners of a housing accommodation, or within an entity that directly or indirectly owns the housing accommodation, that reallocates ownership interests but does not result in the admission of a new, unrelated third-party owner; provided, that a Notice of Transfer is sent to tenants for this exemption pursuant to section 403a;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>A tax sale or transfer pursuant to a tax foreclosure;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>A bankruptcy sale;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>Any transaction involving accommodations otherwise subject hereto expressly contemplated by a registration statement filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission prior to February 22, 1994;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>Any transfer of a property directly caused by a change in the form of the entity owning the property; provided, that the transfer is without consideration, including a transfer of interests in an entity to an entity under D.C. Official Code § 29-204.06; provided, that a Notice of Transfer is sent to tenants for this exemption pursuant to section 403a;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(9)</num>
                <text>The transfer of ownership interests in a corporation, partnership, limited liability company, association, statutory trust entity formed under the Uniform Statutory Trust Entity Act of 2010, D.C. Official Code § 29-1201.01 <em>et seq.</em>, or a similar provision of another jurisdiction, or other entity that owns a housing accommodation; provided, that the sole purpose of the transfer is to admit one or more limited partners or investor members who individually or combined, if more than one, will have a minority interest in the entity and who, at the time of settlement, each make a capital contribution that has a value equivalent to the percentage interest of the fair market value of the entity or the housing accommodation that the investor is acquiring, or allow for the exit of one or more partners and members, and the new investor shall be prohibited from acquiring any additional interest in the entity within 12 months after the new investor's initial admission; provided further, that a Notice of Transfer is sent to tenants for this exemption pursuant to section 403a, and:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Any new limited partners or investors will receive, and any exiting limited partner or investor members received, tax benefits pursuant to 26 U.S.C. § 42, or a comparable District program; or</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Before and after the transfer, the entity is controlled, directly or indirectly, by the same person or entity;</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(10)</num>
                <text>A transfer of title to the housing accommodation to an entity under D.C. Official Code § 29-204.06;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(11)</num>
                <text>A transfer of bare legal title into a revocable trust, without actual consideration for the transfer, where the transferor is the current beneficiary of the trust pursuant to section 302(17) of the District of Columbia Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 11; D.C. Official Code 42-1102(17));</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(12)</num>
                <text>A transfer of the housing accommodation to a named beneficiary of a revocable trust by reason of the death of the grantor of the revocable trust, pursuant to section 302 of the District of Columbia Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 11; D.C. Official Code § 42-1102);</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(13)</num>
                <text>A transfer of the housing accommodation by the trustee of a revocable trust if the transfer would otherwise be excluded under this act if made by the grantor of the revocable trust, pursuant to section 302(19) of the District of Columbia Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 11; D.C. Official Code 42-1102(19));</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(14)</num>
                <text>A transfer pursuant to a court order or court-approved settlement;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(15)</num>
                <text>A transfer by eminent domain or under threat of eminent domain;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(16)</num>
                <text>A transfer of interest in an entity that owns a housing accommodation or a transfer of title to a housing accommodation, if:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>The credit period, as defined in 26 U.S.C. § 42, for the housing accommodation has ended;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Immediately prior to the transfer, the housing accommodation is subject to:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>An extended low-income housing commitment, as that term is defined in 26 U.S.C. § 42(h)(6)(B); or</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>A comparable restrictive covenant as a result of a federal or District program with occupancy, rent, and income requirements at least as restrictive as under 26 U.S.C. § 42;</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Before and after the transfer, the owner of the housing accommodation is controlled, directly or indirectly, by the same person or entity;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>Immediately following the transfer, the housing accommodation is for a term of not less than 10 years subject to an existing or new extended low-income housing commitment or a comparable restrictive covenant as a result of a federal or District program with occupancy, rent and income requirements at least as restrictive as under 26 U.S.C. § 42; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(E)</num>
                  <text>A Notice of Transfer is sent to tenants for this exemption pursuant to section 403a;</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(17)</num>
                <text>A transfer of interest in an entity that owns a housing accommodation or a transfer of title to a housing accommodation, the sole purpose of which is to qualify for and enter into a new credit period, as defined in 26 U.S.C. § 42, for purposes of the rehabilitation of the housing accommodation; provided, that, before and after the transfer, the owner of the housing accommodation is controlled, directly or indirectly, by the same person or entity; provided further, that a Notice of Transfer is sent to tenants for this exemption pursuant to section 403a;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(18)</num>
                <text>A sale or other transfer of interest in a property owned by the District of Columbia Housing Authority;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(19)</num>
                <text>A sale or other transfer of interest in a property owned by and licensed as a hospital, convent, monastery, skilled nursing home, memory care home, assisted living home, senior personal care independent living home, extended care facility, or convalescent or rehabilitation home, or in a dormitory owned or leased by an educational institution; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(20)</num>
                <text>A sale or other transfer of interest in a new building that has completed construction, as evidenced by a permanent certificate of occupancy for a new multifamily building, within the 15 years before the date of sale; provided, that a Notice of Transfer is sent to tenants for this exemption pursuant to section 403a.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The burden of proof to establish that a property or transfer is exempt from the requirements of titles IV and V of this act shall be on the owner.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Before an individual enters into a lease for a rental unit located in a housing accommodation that is not subject to the tenant opportunity to purchase based on subsection (b)(20) of this section, the owner of the housing accommodation shall provide written notice to the individual regarding such exemption.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The owner of each housing accommodation that becomes subject to subsection (b)(20) of this section on the effective date of the Rebalancing Expectations for Neighbors, Tenants, and Landlords (RENTAL) Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading (reconsideration) on October 21, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-164), shall provide written notice within 90 days after such date to all tenants of the housing accommodation regarding the change in applicability of law.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Failure of the owner of a housing accommodation to provide proper notice under this subsection shall not affect the validity of the exemption from the tenant opportunity to purchase applicable to the housing accommodation.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <num>402c</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Tenant support providers.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The Mayor shall establish a certification process for tenant support providers, which shall be selected based on their expertise and ability to counsel tenants who seek to exercise their rights under this title regarding:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The formation and governance of tenant organization and other legal and collective ownership structures;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Technical support services for first-time homeowners;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Obtaining financing for the purchase of housing accommodations; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>Assisting in the process of closing on property transactions.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The Department shall maintain a list of certified tenant support providers and their contact information on a publicly accessible website.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>Certification as a tenant support provider shall be valid for 4 years.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>A tenant support provider shall not:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Act in a manner that is adverse to the interests of a tenant occupying a property subject to this title; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Serve a tenant occupying a property in which the tenant support provider, or any employee thereof, may have a present or future financial interest.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>The Mayor shall promptly investigate any complaint alleging that a tenant support provider has a conflict of interest or has failed to comply with the requirements of this title. If the Mayor determines that a tenant support provider has a conflict of interest or has failed to comply with the requirements of this title, the Mayor may limit, suspend, or revoke that tenant support provider's certification.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <num>402d</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Qualified purchaser.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>For the first 4-year period after the effective date of this section, a pre-approved developer, as defined in 14 DCMR § 2499.1, shall be granted certification as a qualified purchaser. The Mayor shall establish criteria for the certification of qualified purchasers, which shall be selected based on:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The capacity to acquire, own, manage, and improve or redevelop, either independently or through an agent, housing accommodations and related facilities acquired under this title or title IV-A for the remaining useful life of the housing accommodation;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>For entities that own rental accommodations in the District or are subject to a controlling interest by an entity that also has a controlling interest in rental accommodations in the District, a history of responsible stewardship of rental accommodations without unabated serious violations of the housing code; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Understanding of, and ability to comply with, the requirements of this title.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Certification as a qualified purchaser shall be valid for 4 years.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The Mayor shall solicit and accept new applications for qualified purchasers on a rolling basis.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The Mayor shall recruit and solicit applications from reputable parties that have not previously conducted real estate transactions in the District.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The Department shall maintain a list of qualified purchasers on a publicly accessible website.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A qualified purchaser shall be in compliance with the entity filing requirements as prescribed in D.C. Official Code § 29-102.01.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>A qualified purchaser shall not act in a manner that is adverse to the interests of tenants occupying a property subject to this title. The Mayor shall promptly investigate any complaint alleging that a qualified purchaser has a conflict of interest or has failed to comply with the requirements of this title. If the Mayor determines that a qualified purchaser has a conflict of interest or has failed to comply with the requirements of this title, the Mayor may limit, suspend, or revoke that qualified purchaser's certification.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>Section 403 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.03) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The existing text is designated as subsection (a).</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The lead-in language is amended to read as follows:</text>
            <include>
              <para>
                <num>(a)</num>
                <text>An offer of sale shall include, at minimum:</text>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (2) is amended to read as follows:</text>
            <include lvl="1">
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>A statement that the tenant has the right to purchase the accommodation under this title and a notice that the tenants are entitled to no-cost technical assistance and training on their rights provided by a tenant support provider approved by the Mayor;</text>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrase "floor plan." and inserting the phrase "floor plan; and" in its place.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>A new paragraph (5) is added to read as follows:</text>
            <include lvl="1">
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>The name and contact information of all tenant support providers certified by the Mayor pursuant to section 402c as of the date of issuance of the offer of sale; provided, that if no such organizations have been certified, the owner will be deemed in compliance with this paragraph.</text>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>A new subsection (b) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The owner shall provide each tenant with a written copy of the offer of sale by certified mail, a delivery service providing delivery tracking confirmation, or hand delivery. Notice to tenants shall be sent to their address at the housing accommodation unless a tenant has supplied in writing to the owner a different address for notice.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>On the same date as copies of the offer of sale are sent to tenants, the owner shall provide the Mayor with a written copy of the offer of sale and a signed statement confirming that copies of the offer of sale were provided to each tenant. The offer of sale shall be sent to the Mayor by registered or certified mail, return receipt requested, by commercial overnight delivery service that maintains proof of delivery, by hand delivery, or by any other method designated by the Department. If the owner delivers the notification to the Mayor by hand delivery, the Owner shall obtain a date stamped copy demonstrating the Mayor's receipt.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>If the housing accommodation includes occupied units that are not the subject of a current or expired written lease or rental agreement, then on the same date as copies of the offer of sale are sent to tenants, the owner shall post at each building entrance, or unit entrance if the units do not have a common building entrance, a notice, in a form to be developed by the Mayor, that an offer is being mailed to tenants, as defined in section 401a(4), and that residents who have a right to occupy the accommodation pursuant to an oral lease must notify the owner or a designated representative and provide a rent receipt or other proof of tenancy no more than 15 days after receipt of the offer of sale.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>New sections 403a and 403b are added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>403a</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Notice of transfer.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>If an opportunity to purchase is not provided pursuant to section 402, the owner shall provide the Mayor written notice of a transfer of an interest ("Notice of Transfer") in a housing accommodation or of any ownership interest in a corporation, partnership, limited liability company, association, entity formed under the Uniform Statutory Trust Entity Act of 2010, D.C. Code § 29-1201.01 <em>et. seq.</em>, or similar statutory provision of another jurisdiction, or other entity which owns a housing accommodation.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Tenants shall have 45 days after the date of receipt of the Notice of Transfer to file a petition for relief pursuant to sections 503 or 503a.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>For a transfer that is not a sale pursuant to section 402b(b), but for which a Notice of Transfer is required, the owner shall also provide copies of the Notice of Transfer to each tenant by certified mail or a delivery service providing delivery tracking confirmation. Notice to tenants shall be sent to their address at the housing accommodation unless a tenant has provided the owner with a different address in writing.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The Notice of Transfer shall be substantially in the form prescribed by the Mayor and shall provide at a minimum:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A statement of the rights of the tenant or the tenant organization under this act;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>An accurate description of the transfer, including whether the transfer will result in any changes in management, current rents, or any applicable affordability requirements for the housing accommodation;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The date of the proposed transfer; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The reason, if any, why the owner asserts the transfer may not constitute a sale as defined in section 402b.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>In addition to any other requirements for the form of the Notice of Transfer prescribed by this section, a Notice of Transfer for a housing accommodation to be transferred for the purposes of receiving tax benefits pursuant to 26 U.S.C. § 42, or a comparable District program, shall include a description of the applicable federal or District subsidy, and a description of the steps in the transaction employed by the developer to avail itself of the subsidy.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <text>The owner's failure to provide the Notice of Transfer, or the provision of a notice that is fraudulent or contains material misrepresentations, shall create a rebuttable presumption that the transfer constitutes a sale for purposes of titles IV and V of this act.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(g)</num>
              <text>A tenant or tenant organization shall be precluded from asserting any rights under titles IV and V of this act for a transfer exempt under subsection 402b(b).</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(h)</num>
              <text>Any change in the transfer agreement that would invalidate a claim of exemption shall be reported in writing to the Mayor, substantially in a form prescribed by the Mayor, and proper notice shall be provided to the tenant or tenant organization.".</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <num>403b</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Cooling-off period; interference prohibited.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Within the first 5 business days following receipt of the offer of sale by the Mayor pursuant to section 403, the Mayor shall provide all tenant support providers established under section 402c and qualified purchasers with a copy of the offer of sale.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>A tenant organization of a housing accommodation with 5 or more units may not assign its purchase rights to a third party pursuant to section 406 prior to receiving a valid offer of sale or during the first 45 days following receipt of a valid offer of sale unless the tenant organization has submitted the following materials to the Department before receiving the offer of sale:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The tenant organization's registration application materials, including:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>The name, address, and phone number of tenant officers and legal counsel (if any);</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>A copy of the articles of incorporation;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>A copy of the bylaws; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>Documentation that the organization represents at least a majority of the occupied rental units at the time of registration; and</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Proof of certification that the tenant organization has received training on its rights under this title from an organization or agency approved by the Department or by the Office of the Tenant Advocate, which shall be transmitted to the Department by the training organization or agency directly and include:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>The date and time of the training;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The number of units represented at the training session; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>A statement affirming that a quorum was met under the tenant organization's bylaws.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>For housing accommodations with 2 through 4 units, other than 2-unit single family accommodations, covered by section 410(a), a tenant, either jointly or individually, may not assign their purchase rights to a third party pursuant to section 406 prior to receiving a valid offer for sale or during the first 22 days following the receipt of a valid offer of sale, unless the tenant has received training from an organization or agency approved by the Department or by the Office of the Tenant Advocate on their rights under this title.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>Any person that contacts a tenant organization or individual tenant related to an offer or negotiation subject to this title shall disclose:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The names, residence, and business addresses of each person with direct, indirect, legal, or beneficial ownership of a governance or total distributional interest of the entity as provided for in D.C. Official Code § 29-102.01(a)(6) and (7); and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Any financial connection to the property.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>Neither the owner nor the third-party purchaser or any other agent or party with a financial or other interest in the accommodation shall interfere with a tenant's exercise of their rights under this title. Interference includes:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Attempting to organize the tenants in an effort to persuade the tenants to waive or exercise rights in any particular manner without fully disclosing the interested party's financial or other interest in the outcome; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Failing to disclose that tenants have a right to no-cost training on their rights under this title, as well as the right to a consultation with a tenant support provider.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>Section 404 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.04) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>404</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Third party rights.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The right of a third party to purchase an accommodation is conditional upon exercise of tenant rights under this title. The time periods for negotiation of a contract of sale and for settlement under this title are minimum periods, and the owner may afford the tenants a reasonable extension of such period, without liability under a third-party contract.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Third parties and their agents shall not interfere with the tenants' right to organize or otherwise exercise their rights under this title. Third parties may negotiate with tenants for the assignment or waiver of rights pursuant to section 406; provided, that the third party first discloses:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Their identity and that they are interested in purchasing the accommodation;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>That they are not tenant organizers, as defined in section 506(a)(2) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective September 19, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-160; D.C. Official Code § 42-3505.06(a)(2)), and do not represent the interests of the tenants; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>That the tenants have the right to have a training with a certified tenant support provider before engaging in negotiations.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>Third party purchasers are presumed to act with full knowledge of tenant rights and public policy under this title.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>Section 405 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.05) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "sections 410(4) and 411(4), respectively" both times it appears and inserting the phrase "sections 410(a)(4) and 411(4), respectively" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a-1) is amended by striking the phrase "409(c), 410, and 411" and inserting the phrase "409(c), 410(a), and 411" in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(h)</num>
        <text>A new section 405a is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>405a</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Template agreements and contracts; filing with department.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>No agreement or contract entered into under this title, including development agreements, shall be deemed valid or enforceable unless the information specified in this section is filed with the Department within 30 days after signature by all parties. Information submitted to the Department shall include:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Address and ward;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Unit count;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Sales price;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>Information related to rent-stabilization;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>Information related to income-restricted units and subsidies; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>Other information as determined by the Department.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>No later than 180 days after the applicability date of this section, the Department, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>), shall issue rules to establish:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A standard template for purchase contracts; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Rules governing the minimum information required to be included in a purchase contract.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The use of templates established pursuant to subsection (b) shall not be mandatory for the execution of an agreement governed by this act.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Section 406 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.06) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>406</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Exercise or assignment of rights; secondary assignment.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The tenant may exercise rights under this title in conjunction with a third party or by assigning or selling those rights to any party, whether private or governmental. The exercise, assignment, or sale of tenant rights may be for any consideration which the tenant, in the tenant's sole discretion, finds acceptable. Such an exercise, assignment, or sale may occur at any time in the process set forth in this title; provided, that the cooling-off period in section 403b has elapsed, and may be structured in any way the tenant, in the tenant's sole discretion, finds acceptable.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>If a tenant assigns or sells the tenant's rights under this title, the recipient may only further reassign the rights to a private or nonprofit corporation or a partnership of which the assignee or buyer is an owner, managing member, or officer who can legally bind the entity.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>No consideration shall be allowed in exchange for a secondary assignment.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>A tenant who has assigned or sold rights under this title for consideration is entitled to said consideration regardless of whether the tenant has vacated the housing accommodation prior to receipt.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(j)</num>
        <text>Section 408 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.08) is amended by striking the phrase "sections 409(c)(4), 410(2), and 411(2)" both times it appears and inserting the phrase "409(c)(4), 410(a)(2), or 411(2)" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(k)</num>
        <text>Section 410 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.10) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Designate the existing text as subsection (a).</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The lead-in language of subsection (a) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The following provisions shall apply to accommodations owned in majority by a business corporation, as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 29-101.02(2)(A), with 2 through 4 units, other than 2-unit single-family accommodations:</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>A new subsection (b) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Accommodations with 2 through 4 units, not owned in majority by a business corporation as defined in D.C. Official Code § 29-101.02(2)(A), shall be exempt from this title except that tenants of such accommodations shall be entitled to the notice and rights provided in section 409(b).</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(l)</num>
        <text>Section 412 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.12) is amended by striking the phrase "409(c)(5), 410(3) and (4) and 411(3) and (4)" and inserting the phrase "409(c)(5), 410(a)(3) and (4), and 411(3) and (4)" in its place.".</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(m)</num>
        <text>A new section 415 is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>415</num>
            <heading proof="needed">TOPA transparency portal.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Within one year of the applicability date of this section, the Mayor shall establish and maintain a publicly accessible and searchable database of information pertinent to this title, which shall include the following information:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>As applicable, from the Offer of Sale:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>Address and ward;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>Unit count;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iii)</num>
                    <text>Reason for notice;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iv)</num>
                    <text>Information related to rent-stabilization; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(v)</num>
                    <text>Information related to income-restricted units and subsidies;</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Whether a tenant organization has been registered pursuant to section 402a;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Which purchaser was selected by the tenant organization;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>The total duration of the transaction from offer of sale to final closing;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(E)</num>
                  <text>Outcomes negotiated by the tenant organization, including affordability or building improvements;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(F)</num>
                  <text>The tenant organization's written statement of interest<u>;</u></text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(G)</num>
                  <text>Final sales submitted to the Department pursuant to section 405a; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(H)</num>
                  <text>Notices of transfer received pursuant to section 403a.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The Mayor shall not collect or publish this information prior to the closing of the transaction.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>To the maximum extent practicable, the database established pursuant to this section shall be integrated with the Public Accessible Rent Control Housing Database as established in section 203a of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective October 22, 2015 (D.C. Law 21-36; D.C. Official Code § 42-3502.03c).</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The database established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall publish information received by the Department on or after the date of its establishment. The publishing of historical information and data shall be subject to additional funding.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The publishing of any information pursuant to this section does not guarantee the completeness or accuracy of such information and shall not create liability on the part of the District or by any officer or employee thereof for any damages that result from reliance on the published information.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of District law, unless otherwise prescribed by this section, information submitted to the Department pursuant to this title shall be deemed confidential and shall be exempt from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act of 1976, effective March 29, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-96; D.C. Official Code § 2-531 <em>et seq.</em>) ("FOIA").</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>), may issue rules to govern the sharing or publishing of conclusions and analysis derived from information that is received pursuant to this title.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the public release of any information that would otherwise be exempt from disclosure under District law, including proprietary business information, trade secrets, personal financial data, or other protected material under FOIA<em>.</em></text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(n)</num>
        <text>A new section 416 is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>416</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Unlawful acts.</heading>
            <para>
              <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
              <text>It shall be unlawful for any person to:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Coerce a tenant or tenant organization to waive their rights under this title;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Retaliate against or harass a tenant seeking to exercise their rights under this title; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Make fraudulent or misleading statements or engage in conduct intended to prevent a tenant from exercising their rights under this title.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(o)</num>
        <text>Section 503 is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>503</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Civil cause of action.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>An aggrieved owner, tenant, or tenant organization may seek enforcement of any right or provision under this act through a civil action in law or equity, and, upon prevailing, may seek an award of costs and reasonable attorney fees. In an equitable action, the public policy of this act favors the waiver of bond requirements to the extent permissible under law or court rule.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Any person suffering a loss due to violations of section 416 shall be entitled to recover, in addition to the amount of actual damages, double the amount of any interest collected in violation of this act, plus any reasonable attorneys' fees incurred in the collection of that amount.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(p)</num>
        <text>Section 436 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.36) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>436</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Assignment of District rights.</heading>
            <text>The Mayor may assign the opportunity to purchase provided under this title to a qualified purchaser certified pursuant to section 402d that agrees to obligate itself and any successors in interest to maintain the affordability required by section 433.</text>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>302</num>
      <text>Section 302 of the District of Columbia Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 11; D.C. Official Code 42-1102), is amended by adding a new paragraph (14A) to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(14A)</num>
          <text>Deeds to property transferred to a qualified purchaser, as that term is defined in section 401a(2A) of the Tenant Opportunity to Purchase Act of 1980, passed on 2nd reading (reconsideration) on October 21, 2025 (Enrolled Version of Bill 26-164), to whom tenant or District purchase rights have been assigned pursuant to sections 406 and 503 of that act.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>IV</num>
    <heading>DC LOW-INCOME HOUSING TAX CREDIT.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>401</num>
      <text>Chapter 48 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Section 47-4801(8) is revived and amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(8)</num>
            <text>"Qualified project" means a rental housing development in the District that receives an allocation of federal low-income housing tax credits under 26 U.S.C. § 42(h)(1) or (4) after October 1, 2021, and with respect to which an extended low-income housing commitment pursuant to 26 U.S.C. § 42(h)(6)(B), between the owner of the rental housing development and the Department is executed on or after October 1, 2021, and with respect to which the Department issues an eligibility statement on or before September 30, 2024.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 47-4802(d) is amended by striking the phrase "eligible projects" and inserting the phrase "qualified projects or eligible projects" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Section 47-4803 is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a)(1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>An owner of a qualified project or eligible project may be awarded a District of Columbia low-income housing tax credit with respect to that qualified project or eligible project. The amount of the credit awarded annually shall not exceed 9% of the project's qualified basis, as determined in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (b)is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
            <include>
              <para>
                <num>(b)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(1)</num>
                  <text>If an owner of a project that was awarded or otherwise granted a District of Columbia low-income housing tax credit transfers, sells, or assigns the credit to another taxpayer, pursuant to § 47-4806, the District of Columbia low-income housing tax credit shall not be taken, pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, against taxes imposed under this title unless the owner has filed with the Department, in a form determined by the Department, an affidavit certifying that the value received by the owner of the qualified project or eligible project was used to ensure financial feasibility of the qualified project or eligible project.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase "an eligible project" and inserting the phrase "a qualified project or eligible project" in its place.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Subsection (f)(1) is amended by striking the phrase "to any eligible project" and inserting the phrase "to any qualified project or eligible project" in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>Section 47-4804 is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (b)(2) is amended by striking the date "October 1, 2025" and inserting the date "October 1, 2024" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (c)(2) is amended by striking the date "October 1, 2025" and inserting the date "October 1, 2024" in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>V</num>
    <heading>FACILITATION OF RESALE OF INCLUSIONARY ZONING UNITS.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>501</num>
      <text>Section 107(2) of the Inclusionary Zoning Implementation Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-275; D.C. Official Code § 6-1041.07(2)), is amended by striking the phrase "may purchase an inclusionary unit for the purpose of reselling it to eligible households" and inserting the phrase "may purchase an inclusionary unit, or facilitate the purchase or sale of an inclusionary unit, for the purpose of reselling the inclusionary unit to an eligible household" in its place.</text>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>VI</num>
    <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA HOUSING AUTHORITY BOARD OF DIRECTORS.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>601</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999, effective May 9, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-105; D.C. Official Code § 6-201 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 6-201) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (6) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>"Board" means the Board of Commissioners established by section 4a; provided, that for the purposes of sections 10(h), 12(r), and 21(b), the term "Board" shall include any prior form in which the Board existed since the establishment of the Authority pursuant to this act.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Paragraphs (8), (22), and (33) are repealed.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (10) is amended by striking the phrase "Resident Council Advisory Board" and inserting the phrase "Resident Advisory Board" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (15) is amended by striking the phrase "District of Columbia Housing Authority" and inserting the word "Authority" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>A new paragraph (17A) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(17A)</num>
              <text>"Dwelling unit" means any room or group of rooms located within a residential or mixed-use building and forming a single unit that is used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, and the preparation and eating of meals.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 3(b-1)(1)(A) (D.C. Official Code § 6-202(b-1)(1)(A)) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The lead-in language is amended by striking the phrase "Beginning on December 1, 2022, and monthly thereafter, the Authority shall submit a report" and inserting the phrase "The Authority shall submit a quarterly report" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Sub-subparagraph (iii) is amended by striking the phrase "units have been vacant in the prior year," and inserting the phrase "units have been vacant," in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>A new section 4a is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>4a</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Board of Commissioners.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The Authority shall be governed by a Board of Commissioners ("Board"), which shall consist of 9 members and govern in accordance with this section and section 12.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Residents of Housing Properties shall elect 2 Commissioners in accordance with section 12(k). The Authority shall conduct elections for one such Commissioner to take office no later than December 31, 2025, and every 3 years thereafter, and for the other elected Commissioner to take office no later than December 31, 2026, and every 3 years thereafter.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The Mayor shall appoint 7 Commissioners with the advice and consent of the Council, in accordance with section 2(e) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(e)), as follows:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>No later than October 1, 2025, and every 3 years thereafter, the Mayor shall nominate:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>One member who has professional experience in federal housing laws and regulations; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>One member who has professional experience in homeless services system planning and coordinating;</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>No later than October 1, 2026, and every 3 years thereafter, the Mayor shall nominate:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>One member who has professional experience in affordable housing development, operations, or finance; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>One member who has professional experience providing legal assistance in housing matters to low-income District residents; and</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>No later than October 1, 2027, and every 3 years thereafter, the Mayor shall nominate:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>One member who has experience as the holder of a housing voucher;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>One member who has professional experience in capital project financing; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>One member who has professional experience in accounting and enterprise financial management.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>No person shall be elected, appointed, or reappointed to the Board if the person has served 9 years or longer, either in consecutive or non-consecutive terms, as a member of the Board in any form in which the Board existed since the establishment of the Authority pursuant to this act.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>Section 8a(a)(1) (D.C. Official Code § 6-207.01(a)(1)) is amended by striking the word "February" and inserting the word "June" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>New sections 11a and 11b are added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>11a</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Transition from temporary Stabilization and Reform Board.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Each individual who served as a voting or non-voting member of the temporary Stabilization and Reform Board of the Authority as of the effective date of the Housing Authority Resident Empowerment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025, effective September 4, 2025 (D.C. Act 26-145; 72 DCR 9614), shall serve as a voting interim Commissioner of the Board established by section 4a without need for confirmation or appointment until he or she is replaced or reappointed in accordance with this section. Section 12(d) shall not apply to individuals named in this section for purposes of the special initial terms prescribed in this section.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>No later than October 1, 2025, the Mayor shall nominate an interim Commissioner with the qualifications identified in section 4a(c)(3)(C) for a 2-year term; provided, that notwithstanding section 12(c)(2), the Mayor may nominate the Chief Financial Officer or their designee, who shall be an employee of the Chief Financial Officer, for such initial 2-year term as a non-voting Commissioner; provided, further that Leroy Clay III shall serve as an interim non-voting Commissioner until reconfirmed or replaced in this manner. The 2-year term of the Commissioner appointed pursuant to this subsection shall expire when the first Commissioner identified in section 4a(c)(3)(C) is appointed.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>Rosa Burbridge shall serve as an interim Commissioner until the first Commissioner described under section 4a(b) is elected and takes office.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>No later than October 1, 2025, the Mayor shall nominate 2 interim Commissioners with the qualifications listed in section 4a(c)(2)(A) for one-year terms; provided, that Raymond A. Skinner and James M. Dickerson shall serve as Commissioners until they are reappointed or replaced in this manner; provided, further that Raymond A. Skinner shall be the Chairperson of the Board until the Board selects a Chairperson pursuant to section 12(m). The 2 Commissioners appointed pursuant to this subsection shall serve as Commissioners until the second Commissioner identified under section 4a(b) is elected and takes office and the first Commissioner appointed pursuant to section 4a(c)(2)(A) takes office.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>Christopher Murphy shall serve as an interim Commissioner until he is reappointed as or replaced by the first Commissioner appointed pursuant to section 4a(c)(1)(A).</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <text>No later than October 1, 2025, the Mayor shall nominate one interim Commissioner with the qualifications listed in section 4a(c)(3)(B) for a 2-year term.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(g)</num>
              <text>No later than October 1, 2025, the Mayor shall nominate one interim Commissioner with the qualifications listed in section 4a(c)(3)(A) for a 2-year term; provided, that Denise Blackson shall serve as a Commissioner until she is reappointed to such 2-year term or replaced by the appointee to such 2-year term.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(h)</num>
              <text>No later than October 1, 2025, the Mayor shall nominate one interim Commissioner who has attained homeownership with the assistance of the Authority for a one-year term; provided, that Ronnie Harris shall serve as an interim Commissioner until she is reappointed as or replaced by such homeownership experience Commissioner pursuant to this subsection.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Notwithstanding section 12(c)(2), the Mayor may nominate the Executive Director of the Interagency Council on Homelessness for the initial 3-year term specified in section 4a(c)(1)(B). Theresa Silla shall serve as an interim Commissioner until reappointed or replaced in this manner.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(j)</num>
              <text>Jennifer Reed shall serve as a Commissioner until a quorum of Commissioners confirmed, reconfirmed, or elected pursuant to this section and section 4a take office.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(k)</num>
              <text>Notwithstanding section 1108(c-2)(1) of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-611.08(c-2)(1)):</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Commissioners who are District government employees shall not be entitled to stipends for their service on the Board.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Prior to January 1, 2026, stipends for Board service shall be limited to $4,000 per year and an additional stipend of $2,000 per year for the Chairperson.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(l)</num>
              <text>This section shall sunset upon all Commissioners of the Board established pursuant to section 4a taking office.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <num>11b</num>
            <heading proof="needed">City-Wide Resident Advisory Board training and consultation.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The Authority shall establish and implement a comprehensive training program for members of the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board with the goal of enabling tenant members to participate fully in the oversight of the Authority's operation and capital planning. The Authority shall develop the training program in consultation with public housing residents and public housing industry professional organizations.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The Authority shall provide to the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board training on relevant federal and District laws, leadership development, communication, and negotiations.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The Authority shall provide a copy of resolutions on the agenda for consideration by the Board to the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board at least 24 hours before the scheduled date and time of the Board meeting at which the resolution will be considered.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The Authority shall seek and consider the input of the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board when a policy or program change affects residents.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>At least once a quarter, the Board shall invite the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board to report to the Board on any topics of interest or concerns and respond to the concerns of the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board in writing, no later than 45 days following the quarterly meeting.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>Section 12 (D.C. Official Code § 6-211) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The section heading is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <section>
              <num>12</num>
              <heading proof="needed">Additional Board provisions.</heading>
            </section>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsections (a), (b), (e), (f), (g), (j), (o), and (p) are repealed.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Subsection (c) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>An individual seeking to serve as a Commissioner identified under section 4a(c)(1), (2), and (3)(B) and (C) shall have 5 or more years of professional experience in a relevant leadership role out of the last 10 years.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>No officer or employee of the federal or District government may serve as a Commissioner.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Subsection (h) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
            <include>
              <para>
                <num>(h)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(1)</num>
                  <text>Within 90 days after each Commissioner's appointment or election, the Commissioner shall complete training covering the following topics:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(A)</num>
                    <text>The role of a public housing agency board;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(B)</num>
                    <text>Ethics for public housing agencies and board members or commissioners;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(C)</num>
                    <text>Background on major housing authority programs, including public housing, the Housing Choice Voucher Program, and the rental assistance demonstration;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(D)</num>
                    <text>Fair housing and reasonable accommodations;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(E)</num>
                    <text>Public housing authority budgets, financial oversight, and financial reporting; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(F)</num>
                    <text>Federal procurement requirements.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (2) is repealed.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (3) is amended to read as follows:</text>
            <include lvl="1">
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>In addition to the training required in paragraph (1) of this subsection, each Commissioner shall spend at least 4 hours per quarter in training or educational seminars on corporate governance, public housing and the Housing Choice Voucher Program law and regulations, the Moving to Work program, resident opportunity such as HUD's Section 3 requirements for economic and employment opportunities, HUD reporting requirements, public housing performance monitoring and risk management, federal or local language access guidelines, labor and personnel, real estate and construction, or other subjects related to housing authority operation, and management. The maximum reimbursable cost, if any, of this training shall be established by the Board and paid by the Authority.</text>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (6) is repealed.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Subsection (i) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>The elected Commissioners shall be public housing residents at the time of election; provided, that an elected Commissioner who ceases to reside in public housing may complete their term unless removed pursuant to subsection (t) of this section.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Subsection (k) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
            <include>
              <para>
                <num>(k)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(1)</num>
                  <text>Elections of Commissioners by Housing Property residents shall be conducted in accordance with rules and procedures established by the Board, and shall be held no sooner than 5 months and no later than 2 months prior to the expiration of the then current 3-year term. All elections shall be held under the supervision of an independent expert in election monitoring, to be selected by the Board.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (2) is amended as follows:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>The lead-in language is amended to read as follows:</text>
              <include lvl="1">
                <para>
                  <num>(2)</num>
                  <text>The results of each election shall be retained until the elected Commissioner begins their term pursuant to the next scheduled election. If the elected Commissioner becomes unable to serve or is removed from the Board as hereinafter provided, that Commissioner's seat for the remaining term shall be filled as follows:</text>
                </para>
              </include>
              <aftertext>.</aftertext>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the phrase "City-Wide Resident Council Advisory Board;" and inserting the phrase "City-Wide Resident Advisory Board;" in its place.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Subsection (m) is amended by striking the phrase "The Mayor shall designate one of his or her 4 nominees nominated pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section as Chairperson. The ex officio Commissioner shall not be appointed as Chairperson." and inserting the phrase "The Board shall elect a Chairperson from among its members." in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Subsection (q) is amended by striking the phrase "Other than the ex officio Commissioner and the labor representative who is a Commissioner, no person" and inserting the phrase "No person" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Subsection (u) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(u)</num>
              <text>The Board may, by majority vote, require that any Commissioner or Executive Director resolve actual or potential conflicts of interest by reporting the actual or potential conflict of interest to the general counsel and ethics officer of the Authority for consideration and determination of required steps, which may include public disclosure of the conflict of interest and recusal from the decision-making process involving the conflict, divestiture, or any other manner which complies with federal and District law.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Subsection (w) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(w)</num>
              <text>The Board shall meet regularly at least 10 times each calendar year. Each meeting shall provide for a period for public comments, which shall not be limited in time, except that the time allowed each individual speaker may be reasonably limited. To allow the Board to meet and entertain any proposed action, there must be a quorum present, which shall consist of 5 Commissioners. Meetings of the Board shall be subject to the Open Meetings Act, effective March 31, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-350; D.C. Official Code § 2-571 <em>et seq.</em>).</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>Section 14 (D.C. Official Code § 6-213) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase "direction and supervision" and inserting the word "oversight" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The lead-in language of subsection (d)(1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Within 90 days of the Executive Director's appointment, to the extent directed by the Board, the Executive Director shall complete training covering the following topics:</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>A new subsection (e) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>As part of the process of selecting an Executive Director, the Board shall seek and consider the input of public housing residents, voucher holders, and the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(h)</num>
        <text>Section 26g(b)(2) (D.C. Official Code § 6-232(b)(2)) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subparagraph (E) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="2">
            <para>
              <num>(E)</num>
              <text>To file a complaint that requests an administrative determination of the resident's rights when the resident believes that the resident has been aggrieved or adversely affected by an act or a failure to act by an Authority official, as provided in Authority policy and regulations;</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subparagraphs (G), (H), and (I) are amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="2">
            <para>
              <num>(G)</num>
              <text>To have a lease terminated only for serious or repeated violations of the material terms of the lease, as provided in the relevant provisions of the Authority's public housing regulations, which shall be identified in the Bill of Rights;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(H)</num>
              <text>To 30 days' notice of any action to correct, cure, or vacate for violation of a lease, except where the Authority has determined that the head of household responsible for the dwelling unit under the lease is deceased and there are no remaining household members, as provided in the relevant provisions of the Authority's public housing regulations, which shall be identified in the Bill of Rights;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(I)</num>
              <text>To be relocated away from living conditions that represent an emergency or a threat to life, health, or safety as determined by the Authority, another governmental entity, or as a result of a judicial proceeding; to alleviate threat of attack by criminal elements as verified and documented by the Authority Police Department or any other police department or law enforcement agency authorized to operate in the District; and in certain other circumstances, as provided in the relevant provisions of the Authority's public housing regulations, which shall be identified in the Bill of Rights;</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>A new section 27 is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <num>27</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Public housing subsidy repositioning requirements.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>In any repositioning of a Housing Property's federal subsidy, the Authority shall adhere to the following principles to the extent applicable and practicable:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The Authority shall honor the right of households relocated from the Housing Property in connection with the repositioning, including any household transferred to a housing voucher program at any point after the inclusion of the Housing Property in a repositioning plan submitted to HUD, to return to living on the site of the Housing Property.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The Authority shall engage the residents and resident council of the Housing Property to jointly develop relocation and continued occupancy plans before any relocation, detailing resident relocation plans, if required, and continued occupancy both before, during, and after the subsidy conversion; provided, that the Executive Director may order relocation without a jointly developed plan to the extent necessary to ensure human safety.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The Authority shall establish an advisory team that shall participate in, at minimum, the planning, entitlement, relocation, and return phases of the project. Residents of the Housing Property shall constitute at least 25% of the advisory team.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The Authority shall provide residents of the Housing Property with clearly written plans and schedules for each phase of the project. These plans will be project specific and will be amended as necessary in response to resident input.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>In the design of the improvements or redevelopment, the Authority shall ensure the inclusion of amenities that make a positive contribution to the life of the residents of the Housing Property and shall not include products and services that contribute to the devastating health indicators that impact residents of low-income communities, such as childhood asthma.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>The Authority shall negotiate with any development partners to include in the project and operating budgets a community fund for the benefit of the community of former Housing Property residents. The sources and uses of any fund shall be worked out with the Housing Property residents through their elected resident council, subject to approval by the Board or compliance with regulations adopted by the Board.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>The number of housing units reserved for extremely low-income households following repositioning shall exceed the number of preexisting affordable housing units at the Housing Property.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>The Authority shall not submit applications to federal authorities, or seek Board approval submission of, a Rental Assistance Demonstration or federal Section 18 repositioning, unless the Authority has:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Conducted at least 2 resident meetings with residents of the Housing Property; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Provided details of the proposal to the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board, the Mayor's administration, the chair of the committee of the Council with jurisdiction over the Authority, the Councilmember of the Ward in which the Housing Property is located, and the Attorney General, and allowed 15 days for such authorities to provide comments.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>As part of any request to the Board to approve a contract, HUD application, or other formal action in support of a federal subsidy repositioning, the Executive Director shall provide a written status update for each implicated Housing Property explaining how the Authority is complying with each of the principles listed in subsection (a) of this section or, to the extent any such principle cannot be satisfied, an explanation of any relevant efforts the Authority is pursuing in lieu of adherence to that principle.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>In addition to any summary required under section 202(c) of the Procurement Practices Reform Act of 2010, effective April 8, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-371; D.C. Official Code § 2-352.02(c)), any contract that the Authority submits to the Council in support of a federal subsidy repositioning of a Housing Property shall contain a status update in the form prescribed in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to establish a new private cause of action.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>602</num>
      <text>Section 1108(c-2)(1) of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-611.08(c-2)(1)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Each Commissioner of the Board of the District of Columbia Housing Authority ("Board") shall be entitled to a stipend of $8,000 per year for their service, and the chairperson shall be entitled to an additional stipend of $4,000 per year; provided, that subsection (c-3) of this section shall not apply to the chairperson of such Board. Each such Commissioner also shall be entitled to reimbursement of actual travel and other expenses reasonably related to attendance at Board meetings and fulfillment of official duties. Stipends and reimbursements shall be made at least quarterly and prorated, if necessary, to reflect the dates of actual membership on the Board or dates of service as chairperson of the Board;</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>603</num>
      <text>Section 2(e)(27) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(e)(27)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(27)</num>
          <text>The Board of the District of Columbia Housing Authority, as established by section 4a of the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999, passed on 2nd reading (reconsideration) on October 21, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-164);</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>VII</num>
    <heading>APPLICABILITY; FISCAL IMPACT; EFFECTIVE DATE.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>701</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Amendatory section 401a(5) within section 301(a), amendatory sections 402c and 402d within section 301(c), section 301(m), and section 302 shall apply upon the date of inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the provisions identified in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>702</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
      <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>703</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or, in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review</text>
      <text>as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December</text>
      <text>24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813, D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
    </section>
  </container>
</document>
