<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1804.02</num>
  <heading>Calculation of number of students.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Quarterly reporting requirement. —</heading>
    <text>On June 30, October 15, December 15, and March 30 of each year the District of Columbia public schools and each eligible chartering authority shall submit a report to the Mayor and the Council containing the information described in subsection (b) of this section that is applicable to the schools under their respective authorities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Calculation of number of students. —</heading>
    <text>Not later than 30 days after April 26, 1996, and not later than October 15 of each year thereafter, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall calculate the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of students, including nonresident students and students with special needs, enrolled in each grade from kindergarten through grade 12 of the District of Columbia public schools and in public charter schools, and the number of students whose tuition for enrollment in other schools is paid for with funds available to the District of Columbia public schools;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amount of fees and tuition assessed and collected from the nonresident students described in paragraph (1) of this subsection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The number of students, including nonresident students, enrolled in preschool and prekindergarten in the District of Columbia public schools and in public charter schools;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The amount of fees and tuition assessed and collected from the nonresident students described in paragraph (3) of this subsection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The number of full time equivalent adult students enrolled in adult, community, continuing, and vocational education programs in the District of Columbia public schools and in public charter schools;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The amount of fees and tuition assessed and collected from resident and nonresident adult students described in paragraph (5) of this subsection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The number of students, including nonresident students, enrolled in nongrade level programs in District of Columbia public schools and in public charter schools;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The amount of fees and tuition assessed and collected from nonresident students described in paragraph (7) of this subsection; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The number of enrolled students who have dropped out since the date of the previous report.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Annual reports. —</heading>
    <text>Not later than October 30 of each year the Mayor shall prepare and submit to the Authority (during a control year), the Council, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a summary of the calculations made pursuant to subsection (b) of this subsection, including the 4 immediately prior reporting periods specified in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <heading>Audit of initial calculations. —</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <heading>In general. —</heading>
      <text>The Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall provide for the conduct of an independent audit of the initial calculations described in subsection (b) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <heading>Conduct of audit. —</heading>
      <text>In conducting the audit, the independent auditor:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Shall provide an opinion as to the accuracy of the information contained in the report described in subsection (c) of this subsection; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Shall identify any material weaknesses in the systems, procedures, or methodology used by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>In determining the number of students, including nonresident students, enrolled in the District of Columbia public schools and in public charter schools, and the number of students whose tuition for enrollment in other school systems is paid for by funds available to the District of Columbia public schools; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>In assessing and collecting fees and tuition from nonresident students.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <heading>Submission of audit. —</heading>
      <text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Council receives the initial annual report from the Office of the State Superintendent of Education required under subsection (c) of this subsection, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall submit to the Mayor, the Council, and the appropriate congressional committees, the audit conducted pursuant to this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <heading>Cost of the audit. —</heading>
      <text>The Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall fund the independent audit solely from amounts appropriated to the Office of the State Superintendent of Education for staff, stipends, and non-personal services of the Office of the State Superintendent of Education by an act making appropriations for the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 104-134" type="History" path="§2402">Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 1321 137, Pub. L. 104-134, § 2402</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-176" type="History">Oct. 21, 2000, D.C. Law 13-176, § 8(c), 47 DCR 6835</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-348" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-348,§ 102(b), 52 DCR 1991</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 4092, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4091 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle J of title IV of the act may be cited as the “Per Capita District of Columbia Public School and Public Charter School Funding Amendment Act of 2010”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4092 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Public School Enrollment Integrity Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-519, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8995).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Public School Enrollment Integrity Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-282, December 18, 2003,  51 DCR 191).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Public School Enrollment Integrity Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-174, October 6, 2003,  50 DCR 9181).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Public School Enrollment Integrity Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-192, November 29, 2001,  48 DCR 11239).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Public School Enrollment Integrity Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-86, July 9, 2001,  48 DCR 6373).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of the Public School Enrollment Integrity Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-453, November 7, 2000,  47 DCR 9406).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) provisions governing the hiring of an independent contractor to perform a census of enrolled students and employees in public schools, see § 402 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-41, March 31, 1999,  46 DCR 3446).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 6(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-67">D.C. Law 15-67</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Annual reports. — Not later than October 30 of each year the Mayor shall prepare and submit to the Authority (during a control year), the Council, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a summary of the calculations made pursuant to subsection (b) of this subsection, including the four immediately prior reporting periods specified in subsection (a) of this section.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Quarterly reporting requirement. — On June 30, October 15, December 15, and March 30 of each year the District of Columbia public schools and each eligible chartering authority shall submit a report to the Mayor containing the information described in subsection (b) of this section that is applicable to their schools; provided, however, that in the case of the June 30 report, the information submitted by each eligible chartering authority shall be in the form of estimates of the number of students who will fall into each category on the following October 5.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-67">D.C. Law 15-67</cite> rewrote subsecs. (a) and (c); in subsec. (b), substituted “Information required. — The reports described in subsection (a) of this section shall contain the following information:” for “Calculation of the number of students. — Not later than 30 days after April 26, 1996, and not later than October 15, of each year thereafter, the State Education Office shall calculate the following:”; and repealed subsec. (d). Subsecs. (a) and (c) read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 6(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-38">D.C. Law 14-38</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(b)(4) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-38">D.C. Law 14-38</cite> repealed subsec. (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Annual reports.—Not later than October 30 of each year the Mayor shall prepare and submit to the Authority, the Council, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a summary of the calculations made pursuant to subsection (b) of this subsection, including the four immediately prior reporting periods specified in subsection (a) of this section.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(b)(3) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-38">D.C. Law 14-38</cite> amended subsec. (c) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(b)(2) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-38">D.C. Law 14-38</cite> amended subsec. (b) by striking the phrase following “Calculation of the number of students not later than 30 days after April 26, 1996, and not later than October 15, of each years thereafter, the Board shall calculate the following:” and inserting the phrase “The reports described in subsection (a) of this section shall contain the following information:” in its place.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Quarterly reporting requirement.—On June 30, October 15, December 15, and March 30 of each year the District of Columbia public schools and each eligible chartering authority shall submit a report to the Mayor containing the information described in subsection (b) of this section that is applicable to their schools; provided, however, that in the case of the June 30 report the information submitted by each eligible chartering authority shall be in the form of estimates of the number of students who will fall into each category on the following October 5.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(b)(1) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-38">D.C. Law 14-38</cite> amended subsec. (a) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 6(b) of D.C. Laws 13-199 provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Annual reports.—Not later than October 30 of each year the Mayor shall prepare and submit to the Authority, the Council, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a summary of the calculations made pursuant to subsection (b) of this subsection, including the four immediately prior reporting periods specified in subsection (a) of this section.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Quarterly reporting requirement.—On June 30, October 15, December 15, and March 30 of each year the District of Columbia public schools and each eligible chartering authority shall submit a report to the Mayor containing the information described in subsection (b) of this section that is applicable to their schools; provided, however, that in the case of the June 30 report the information submitted by each eligible chartering authority shall be in the form of estimates of the number of students who will fall into each category on the following October 5.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(b) of D.C. Laws 13-427 rewrote subsecs. (a) and (c); in subsec. (b) substituted “The reports described in subsection (a) of this section shall contain the following information:” for “Calculation of the number of students not later than 30 days after April 26, 1996, and not later than October 15, of each years thereafter, the Board shall calculate the following:”; and repealed subsec. (d). Subsecs (a) and (c), as amended, read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “the Mayor and the Council containing” for “Mayor containing” and substituted “authorities” for “authorities; provided, that in the case of the June 30 report, the information submitted by each eligible chartering authority shall be in the form of estimates of the number of students who will fall into each category on the following October 5”; in subsec. (b), substituted “Office of the State Superintendent of Education” for “State Education Office” in the lead-in language, deleted “and” from the end of par. (7); substituted “; and” for a period at the end of par. (8), and added par. (9); and, in subsec. (d), substituted “Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall” for “State Education Office shall arrange with the Authority to” in par. (1), substituted “Office of the State Superintendent of Education” for “State Education Office” in par. (2)(B), and rewrote pars. (3) and (4) of subsec. (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-348">D.C. Law 15-348</cite> rewrote subsecs. (a) and (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-176">D.C. Law 13-176</cite> provided for substitution of reference to state education office for board of education where appearing.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-2853.42.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§38-159">§ 38-159</cite>, <cite path="§38-1804.01">§ 38-1804.01</cite>, <cite path="§38-2602">§ 38-2602</cite>, <cite path="§38-2604">§ 38-2604</cite>, <cite path="§38-2902">§ 38-2902</cite>, <cite path="§38-2906">§ 38-2906</cite>, and <cite path="§38-2906.02">§ 38-2906.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Applicability of Formula, see <cite path="§38-2902">§ 38-2902</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
