<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-202</num>
  <heading>Establishment of school attendance requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Every parent, guardian, or other person, who resides permanently or temporarily in the District during any school year and who has custody or control of a minor who has reached the age of 5 years or will become 5 years of age on or before September 30th of the current school year shall place the minor in regular attendance in an educational institution during the period of each year when the public schools of the District are in session. This obligation of the parent, guardian, or other person having custody extends until the minor reaches the age of 18 years. For the purpose of this section placement in summer school is not required.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any minor who has satisfactorily completed the senior high school course of study prescribed by the Board and has been granted a diploma that certifies his or her graduation from high school, or who holds a diploma or certificate of graduation from another course of study determined by the Board to be at least equivalent to that required by the Board for graduation from the public senior high schools, shall be excused from further attendance at school.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any minor who has reached the age of 17 years may be allowed flexible school hours by the Superintendent of Schools provided he or she is actually, lawfully, gainfully, and regularly employed, but in no case shall he or she be excused entirely from regular attendance or excused to the extent that his or her timely graduation would be jeopardized or prevented.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board shall, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, issue rules to establish requirements to govern acceptable credit for studies completed at independent or private schools and private instruction, to govern the validity of applications for permission to be absent from school, to govern the selection and appointment of appropriate staff members to carry out the provisions of this chapter under the direction of the Superintendent of Schools, pursuant to <cite path="1|6">Chapter 6 of Title 1</cite>, and in respect to other matters within the scope of authority of the Board that relates to this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 68-2-ch140" path="§1">Feb. 4, 1925, 43 Stat. 806, ch. 140, Art. I, §§ 1, 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-247" type="History">renumbered as Art. II, § 1 and amended, Mar. 8, 1991, D.C. Law 8-247, § 2(a), 38 DCR 376</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-202" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-202, § 604, 55 DCR 6297</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-17" type="History">Sept. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 20-17, § 303(a), 60 DCR 9839</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 303(a) of the Attendance Accountability Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-133, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11531, 20 DCSTAT 1973).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Class Exclusion Standards Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-23, March</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-8">D.C. Law 17-8</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The Mayor shall make resources available to support the programs in subsection (d) of this section within the context of appropriated funds within the budget and financial plan.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The Mayor shall provide for comprehensive inter-agency collaborative support programs, such as programs offered by the Department of Mental Health, the Department of Human Services, the Child and Family Services Agency, and the Department of Parks and Recreation, to assist the student subject to class exclusion at the school, except for those students who may be a danger to the school’s faculty, students, or others, where the student was placed prior to the disciplinary action.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The Board shall require a monthly report of disciplinary measures taken by each school regarding class exclusions and suspensions, including the rationale for the particular choice of discipline.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The standards adopted under subsection (a) of this section shall include a progressive schedule of discipline which promotes the goal of in-class education for students subject to disciplinary action, beginning with in-class intervention strategies and ending with expulsion as the final and most extreme form of discipline, and to the extent consistent with this progressive schedule, it shall be the policy of the District of Columbia to prefer in-school disciplinary action, except for those students who may be a danger to the school’s faculty, students, or others.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) To promote the education of students in the school, except for those students who may be a danger to the school’s faculty, students, or others, where the student was placed prior to disciplinary action, and that prioritize consideration of the student’s academic standing, the educational needs of the students, and the number of previous offenses.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) To determine when class exclusions will be the appropriate disciplinary measure for students;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Board of Education (‘Board’) shall adopt uniform disciplinary standards:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 1a. Establishment of standards for class exclusions and suspensions.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-8">D.C. Law 17-8</cite> added provisions to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-17">D.C. Law 20-17</cite> substituted “an educational institution” for “a public, independent, private, or parochial school, or in private instruction” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-202">D.C. Law 17-202</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “September 30th” for “December 31st”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., §§ <cite path="§31-201">31-201</cite>, <cite path="§31-202">31-202</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-402.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§2-1571">§ 2-1571</cite>, <cite path="§16-2309">§ 16-2309</cite>, <cite path="§38-203">§ 38-203</cite>, <cite path="§38-206">§ 38-206</cite>, <cite path="§38-1800.02">§ 38-1800.02</cite>, and <cite path="§38-2605">§ 38-2605</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Belief that child is of compulsory school age, taking into custody, see <cite path="§16-2309">§ 16-2309</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Additional powers and duties of Superintendent, see <cite path="§38-105">§ 38-105</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
