<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2401.02</num>
  <heading>Property rights.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Property rights described. —</heading>
    <text>Gallaudet University is vested with all the property and the rights of property, and shall have and be entitled to use all authority, privileges, and possessions and all legal rights which it has, or which it had or exercised under any former name, including the right to sue and be sued and to own, acquire, sell, mortgage, or otherwise dispose of property it may own now or hereafter acquire. Gallaudet University shall also be subject to all liabilities and obligations now outstanding against the corporation under any former name.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Disposal of real property. —</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>With the approval of the Secretary, the Board of Trustees of Gallaudet University may convey fee simple title by deed, convey by quitclaim deed, mortgage, or otherwise dispose of any or all real property title to which is vested in Gallaudet University, Gallaudet College, the Columbia Institution for the Deaf, or any predecessor corporation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The proceeds of any such disposition shall be considered a part of the capital structure of the corporation, and may be used solely for the acquisition of real estate for the use of the corporation, for the construction, equipment, or improvement of buildings for such use, or for investment purposes, but, if invested, only the income from the investment may be used for current expenses of the corporation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 99-371" type="History" path="§102">Aug. 4, 1986, 100 Stat. 781, Pub. L. 99-371, § 102</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-73" type="History">Aug. 11, 1993, 107 Stat. 733, Pub. L. 103-73, § 203(b)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-1841.2.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
