<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2902</num>
  <heading>Applicability of Formula.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Formula shall apply to operating budget appropriations for District of Columbia resident students in DCPS and Public Charter Schools of the District of Columbia. The student count to which the Formula is applied shall not include students enrolled in private institutions providing special education services paid by the District of Columbia or to nonresident students subject to the requirement of paying tuition pursuant to <cite path="38|3">Chapter 3 of this title</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Formula shall apply only to operating budget appropriations from the District of Columbia General Fund for DCPS and for Public Charter Schools. It shall not apply to funds from federal or other revenue sources, or to funds appropriated to other agencies and funds of the District government.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Formula shall apply only to Public Charter Schools until the DCPS student enrollment count is verified by an independent contractor who shall perform a census on the student enrollment of the DCPS. The count shall include the information provided in <cite path="§38-1804.02|(b)">§ 38-1804.02(b)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-207" type="History" path="§103">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-207, § 103, 45 DCR 8095</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Uniform Per Student Funding Formula For Public Schools and Public Charter Schools Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-18, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2691).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-485, December 18, 2000,  48 DCR 20).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of chapter, see note to <cite path="§38-2901">§ 38-2901</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§38-2901">§ 38-2901</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-6">D.C. Law 14-6</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-6">D.C. Law 14-6</cite>, in subsec. (a), added the following to the end: “For purposes of adult education only, as defined in section 102(1), the Formula shall apply to the University of the District of Columbia (‘UDC’).”; in subsec. (b), substituted “, for public charter schools, and for the adult education program of UDC” for “and for”; and repealed subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-262">D.C. Law 13-262</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Repealed.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Formula shall apply only to operating budget appropriations from the District of Columbia General Fund for DCPS, for public charter schools, and for the adult education program of UDC Public Charter Schools. It shall not apply to funds from federal or other revenue sources, or to funds appropriated to other agencies and funds of the District government.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Formula shall apply to operating budget appropriations for District of Columbia resident students in DCPS and Public Charter Schools of the District of Columbia. The student count to which the Formula is applied shall not include students enrolled in private institutions providing special education services paid by the District of Columbia or to nonresident students subject to the requirement of paying tuition pursuant to 38-302 through 38-306. For purposes of adult education only, as defined in section 102(1), the Formula shall apply to the University of the District of Columbia (‘UDC’).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-262">D.C. Law 13-262</cite>, rewrote this section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-2902.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
