<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-651.08</num>
  <heading>Maintenance of records.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A school shall keep the medication action plans in the school health suite or other designated, easily accessible location.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A school shall create and maintain a list of students with valid medication action plans, including the emergency contact information for each student. The principal of the school may distribute the list among appropriate employees or agents of the school.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A school shall maintain accurate records of all its employees and agents who are certified to administer medication.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A school shall maintain accurate records of all incidents where medication was administered to a student in an emergency circumstance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-107" type="History" path="§9">Feb. 2, 2008, D.C. Law 17-107, § 9, 54 DCR 12230</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5 of Student Access to Treatment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-140, October 17, 2007,  54 DCR 10736).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5 of Student Access to Treatment Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-82, July 26, 2007,  54 DCR 7999).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 11(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-52">D.C. Law 17-52</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Each school that has a student with a medication action plan for self-administration may schedule a meeting at the beginning of the school year with the school nurse, the principal, the student, the responsible person, and any other appropriate school staff to review the student’s medication action plan. Authorization to possess and self-administer previously approved medication shall not be dependent on having had this meeting.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) A school shall create and maintain a list of students with valid medication action plans, including the emergency contact information for each student. The principal of the school may distribute this list among appropriate school employees.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) A school shall keep the medication action plan in the school health suite, or other designated, easily accessible location.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 5. Maintenance of records.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5 of Law 17-52 added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
