<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>11-1525</num>
  <heading>Operations; personnel; administrative services.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission may make such rules and regulations for its operations as it may deem necessary, and such rules and regulations shall be effective on the date specified by the Commission. The District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Official Code, secs. 2-501 to 2-510) shall be applicable to the Commission only as provided by this subsection. For the purposes of the publication of rules and regulations, judicial notice, and the filing and compilation of rules, sections 5, 7, and 8 of that Act (D.C. Official Code, secs. 2-504, 2-505, and 2-507), insofar as consistent with this subchapter, shall be applicable to the Commission; and for purposes of those sections, the Commission shall be deemed an independent agency as defined in section 3(5) of that Act (D.C. Official Code, sec. 2-502). Nothing contained herein shall be construed to require prior public notice and hearings on the subject of rules adopted by the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission is authorized, without regard to the provisions governing appointment and classification of District of Columbia employees, to appoint and fix the compensation of, or to contract for, such officers, assistants, reporters, counsel, and other persons as may be necessary for the performance of its duties. It is authorized to obtain the services of medical and other experts in accordance with the provisions of section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, but at rates not to exceed the daily equivalent of the rate provided for GS-18 of the General Schedule.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia is authorized to detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of its personnel to assist in carrying out the duties of the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Financial and administrative services (including those related to budgeting and accounting, financial reporting, personnel, and procurement) shall be provided to the Commission by the District of Columbia, for which payment shall be made in advance, or by reimbursement, from funds of the Commission in such amounts as may be agreed upon by the Chair of the Commission and the District of Columbia government. Regulations of the District of Columbia for the administrative control of funds shall apply to funds appropriated to the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 493, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-266">June 13, 1994, Pub. L. 103-266, § 1(b)(30), 108 Stat. 713</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>District Charter provisions relating to rules and regulations of Commission, see § <cite path="§1-204.31">1-204.31</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 11-1525.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 11-1525.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>The General Schedule, referred to at the end of the last sentence of subsection (b) of this section, appears in  5 U.S.C. § 5332.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
