<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-1523</num>
  <heading>Terms of office; vacancy; continuation of service by a member.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the term of office of members and alternate members of the Commission shall be six years.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Of the members and alternate members first appointed to the Commission —</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>one member and alternate member appointed by the President shall be appointed for a term of six years, one member appointed by the President shall be appointed for a term of four years, and one such member shall be appointed for a term of two years, as designated by the President at the time of appointment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>the member and alternate member appointed by the chief judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall be appointed for a term of four years; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>the member and alternate member appointed by the Commissioner [Mayor] of the District of Columbia shall be appointed for a term of two years.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A member or alternate member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term of that member’s predecessor shall serve only for the remainder of that term. Any vacancy on the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If approved by the Commission, a member may serve after the expiration of that member’s term for purposes of participating until conclusion in a matter, relating to the suspension, retirement, or removal of a judge, begun before the expiration of that member’s term. A member’s successor may be appointed without regard to the member’s continuation in service, but that member’s successor may not participate in the matter for which the member’s continuation in service was approved.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 493, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-266" type="History">June 13, 1994, Pub. L. 103-266, §§ 1(b)(28), (29), 108 Stat. 713</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District Charter provisions relating to terms of office and vacancies on Commission, see § <cite path="§1-204.31">1-204.31</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-1523.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-1523.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made, in brackets, in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
