<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>11-1723</num>
  <heading>Fiscal Officer.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There shall be a Fiscal Officer in the District of Columbia court system who shall be responsible for the budget of the court system and for the accounts of the courts, subject to the supervision of the Executive Officer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fiscal Officer shall receive, safeguard, and account for all fees, costs, payments, and deposits of money or other items, and shall be responsible for depositing in the Treasury of the United States all fines, forfeitures, fees, unclaimed deposits, and other moneys.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fiscal Officer shall be responsible for the approval of vouchers and shall arrange for an annual independent audit of the accounts of the courts.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 511, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-266">June 13, 1994, Pub. L. 103-266, § 1(b)(86), 108 Stat. 713</annotation>
      <annotation>Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 752, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11242(b)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 107-96">Dec. 21, 2001, 115 Stat. 928, Pub. L. 107-96, par. 18</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 108-335">Oct. 18, 2004, 118 Stat. 1345, Pub. L. 108-335, § 329</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 109-356">Oct. 16, 2006, 120 Stat. 2027, Pub. L. 109-356, § 116(a)</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 11-1723.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 11-1723.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>Pub. L. 107-96 deleted “and the internal auditing of the accounts of the courts” following “vouchers” in subsec. (a), par. (3).</annotation>
      <annotation>Pub. L. 108-335 repealed subsec. (b) which had read as follows: (b) “The Fiscal Officer shall give bond with two or more sureties, to be approved by the Joint Committee, in an amount prescribed by the Joint Committee, faithfully to discharge the duties of that office.”</annotation>
      <annotation>Pub. L. 109-356 made a technical correction to Pub. L. 108-335 that deleted paragraph designation (1) in subsec. (a) and redesignated pars. (a)(2) and (3) as subsecs. (b) and (c).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
      <annotation>Section 116(c) of Pub. L. 109-356 provided that the amendments made by this section shall take effect as if included in the enactment of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2005 [Pub. L. 108-335].</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
