<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-1912</num>
  <heading>Juror fees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding section 602(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, grand and petit jurors serving in the Superior Court shall receive fees and expenses at rates established by the Board of Judges of the Superior Court, except that such fees and expenses may not exceed the respective rates paid to such jurors in the Federal system.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A petit or grand juror receiving benefits under the laws of employment security of the District of Columbia shall not lose such benefits on account of performance of juror service.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Employees of the United States or of any State or local government who serve as grand or petit jurors and who continue to receive regular compensation during the period of jury service shall not be compensated for jury service. Amounts representing reimbursement of expenses incurred in connection with jury service may be paid to such employees to the extent provided in the jury system plan.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 516, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 99-650" type="History">Nov. 14, 1986, 100 Stat. 3635, Pub. L. 99-650, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 755, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11246(a)</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">Section 602(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, referred to in this section, is § 602(a) of the Act of December 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 813, Pub. L. 93-198, which is codified as § 1-206.02(a).</text>
    <text type="References in Text">Section 11717(b) of title XI of Pub. L. 105-33, 111 Stat. 786, provided that any reference in law or regulation to the “District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act” shall be deemed to be a reference to the “District of Columbia Home Rule Act,” which is set out in Volume 1.</text>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§11-1901">11-1901</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-1906.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-1912.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
