<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-1701</num>
  <heading>Administration of District of Columbia court system.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There shall be a Joint Committee on Judicial Administration in the District of Columbia (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Joint Committee”) consisting of (1) the Chief Judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, who shall serve as Chair, (2) an associate judge of that court elected annually by the judges thereof, (3) the Chief Judge of the Superior Court, and (4) two associate judges of that court elected annually by the judges thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Joint Committee shall have responsibility within the District of Columbia court system for the following matters:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>General personnel policies, including those for recruitment, removal, compensation, and training.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Accounts and auditing.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Procurement and disbursement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Submission of the annual budget requests of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, and the District of Columbia Court System as the integrated budget of the District of Columbia courts, except that such requests may be modified upon the concurrence of four of the five members of the Joint Committee.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Formulation and enforcement of standards for outside activities of and receipt of compensation by the judges of the District of Columbia court system.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Development and coordination of statistical and management information systems and reports supporting the annual report of the District of Columbia court system.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Liaison between the District of Columbia court system and the court systems of other jurisdictions, including the Judicial Conference of the United States, the Judicial Conference of the District of Columbia Circuit, and the Federal Judicial Center.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>With the concurrence of the respective chief judges of the District of Columbia courts, other policies and practices of the District of Columbia court system and resolution of other matters which may be of joint and mutual concern of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals and the Superior Court.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Joint Committee, with the assistance of the Executive Officer of the District of Columbia courts, shall —</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>consider and evaluate the business of the courts and means of improving the administration of justice within the District of Columbia court system and shall report thereon in its annual report;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>prepare and publish an annual report of the District of Columbia court system regarding the work of the courts, the performance of the duties enumerated in this chapter, and of any recommendations relating to the courts;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>recommend from time to time to the Congress changes in the organization, jurisdiction, operation, and procedures of the courts which are appropriate for legislative action, and institute such changes, pursuant to the responsibilities enumerated in subsection (b), in the methods of administering judicial business in the court system as would improve the administration of justice; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>arrange for such training seminars, and other related services, as are desirable and feasible for judges and other court personnel, including services from the Federal Judicial Center on a reimbursable basis.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Joint Committee shall have authority to issue all orders and directives necessary to implement the responsibilities and duties enumerated in this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 508, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-266" type="History">June 13, 1994, Pub. L. 103-266, § 1(b)(80), 108 Stat. 713</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 752, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11242(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 108-335" type="History">Oct. 18, 2004, 118 Stat. 1345, Pub. L. 108-335, § 329</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 109-356" type="History">Oct. 16, 2006, 120 Stat. 2026, Pub. L. 109-356, § 116(a)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Judicial retirement, periodic increases and existing rights, see § <cite path="§11-1571">11-1571</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§11-1571">11-1571</cite>, § <cite path="§11-1702">11-1702</cite>, and § <cite path="§11-1703">11-1703</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-1701.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-1701.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 108-335 repealed subsec. (b)(5) which had read as follows: “(5) Approval of the bonds of fiduciary employees within the District of Columbia court system.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 109-356 made a technical correction to Pub. L. 108-335 that did not change the text of the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 116(c) of Pub. L. 109-356 provided that the amendments made by this section shall take effect as if included in the enactment of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2005 [Pub. L. 108-335].</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Termination of Federal Disclosure Requirements: See Pub. L. 99-573, § 6.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made, in brackets, in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
