<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-1741</num>
  <heading>Court operations and organization.</heading>
  <text>Within the respective District of Columbia courts, and subject to the supervision of the chief judges thereof, the Executive Officer shall —</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>supervise, analyze, and improve case assignments, calendars, and dockets;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>provide improved services and introduce new methods to better utilize the time of and accommodate government and other witnesses;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>supervise, analyze, and improve the management of jurors;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>recommend changes and improvements in court rules and procedures affecting the Executive Officer’s administrative responsibilities;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>report periodically to the appropriate chief judge with respect to case volumes, backlogs, length of time cases have been pending, number and identity of incarcerated defendants awaiting trial, and such other information as the respective chief judges may request;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>mechanize and computerize court operations and services where feasible and desirable and carry on continuing studies and evaluations of increased and innovative uses of mechanization and computerization;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>conduct studies and research with respect to court operations on the Executive Officer’s own initiative or on request of the respective chief judges;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>make recommendations to the chief judge of the Superior Court relating to the arrangement and division of the business of that court and the fixing of the time of sessions of the various divisions and branches of that court; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>perform such other duties as may be assigned to the Executive Officer by a chief judge.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 513, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-266" type="History">June 13, 1994, Pub. L. 103-266, §§ 1(b)(90), (91), 108 Stat. 713</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-1741.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-1741.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
