<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>11-1731</num>
  <heading>Reports of other personnel.</heading>
  <text>The Executive Officer or the chief judge may request such reports as may be necessary to the efficient administration of the courts from —</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia,</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>the Corporation Counsel,</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>the United States Marshal for the District of Columbia,</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>the Commissioner [Mayor] of the District of Columbia,</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>the superintendent of any hospitals or institutions to which persons have been committed by the Superior Court,</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>the District of Columbia Public Defender Service,</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>the District of Columbia Bail Agency [District of Columbia Pre-trial Services Agency],</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>the District of Columbia Department of Corrections,</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department,</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>the District of Columbia Department of Public Health [Department of Health], and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>the District of Columbia Department of Public Welfare [Department of Human Services].</text>
  </para>
  <afterText>These officials, agencies, and departments shall furnish such reports and information as may be requested pursuant to this section.</afterText>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 513, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 11-1731.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 11-1731.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>District of Columbia Bail Agency abolished: The District of Columbia Bail Agency was abolished and replaced by the District of Columbia Pre-trial Services Agency by the Act of September 27, 1978, Pub. L. 95-388.</text>
      <text>Health Department abolished: The Health Department of the District of Columbia, including the office of the head thereof, was abolished and the functions thereof transferred to the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia by Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1952. Reorganization Order No. 57 of the Board of Commissioners, dated June 30, 1953, and Reorganization Order No. 52, dated June 30, 1953, combined and redesignated Organization Order No. 141, dated February 11, 1964, established under the direction and control of a Commissioner, a Department of Public Health headed by a Director, for the purpose of planning, implementing, and directing public health and hospital care programs, and for performing certain other allied medical and paramedical functions. The Anatomical Board was established under the direction and control of the Director of Public Health consisting of members as prescribed in the D. C. Code. The Order prior to redesignation abolished the previously existing Health Department, Gallinger Hospital, Glenn Dale Sanatorium, and the Anatomical Board and transferred their functions and positions to the new Department. The organization of the new Department was set out in the Order. The executive functions of the Board of Commissioners were transferred to the Commissioner of the District of Columbia by § 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967. Functions stated in Organization Order No. 141 were transferred to the Director of the Department of Human Resources by Commissioner’s Order No. 69-96, dated March 7, 1969, as amended by Commissioner’s Order No. 70-83, dated March 6, 1970. The Department of Human Resources was replaced by Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, dated February 21, 1980, which Plan established the Department of Human Services.</text>
      <text>Board of Public Welfare abolished: The Board of Public Welfare was abolished and the functions thereof transferred to the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia by Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1952. The executive functions of the Board of Commissioners were transferred to the Commissioner of the District of Columbia by § 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967. Reorganization Order No. 58 as amended, redesignated as Organization Order No. 140 and amended, established under the direction and control of a Commissioner, a Department of Public Welfare, headed by a Director with the purpose of planning, implementing and directing public welfare programs. Reorganization Order No. 58 provided that the previously existing Board of Public Welfare would be abolished. That Order also transferred specified functions of the former board to the Department of Public Health and the Department of Public Welfare. Functions of the Department of Public Welfare and of the Department of Public Health as set forth in Organization Order Nos. 140 and 141, respectively, were transferred to the Director of the Department of Human Resources by Commissioner’s Order No. 69-96, dated March 7, 1969, as amended by Commissioner’s Order No. 70-83, dated March 6, 1970. The Department of Human Resources was replaced by the Department of Human Services by Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, dated February 21, 1980.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made, in brackets, in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
