<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-1726</num>
  <heading>Compensation and benefits for court personnel.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In the case of nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia courts whose compensation is not otherwise fixed by this title, the Executive Officer shall fix the rates of compensation of such employees without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, United States Code. Any rates so established shall be subject to the limitation on maximum pay in section 5382(a) of such title. In fixing the rates of compensation of nonjudicial employees under this section, the Executive Officer may be guided by the rates of compensation fixed for employees in the executive and judicial branches of the Federal Government or State or local governments occupying the same or similar positions or occupying positions of similar responsibility, duty, and difficulty.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia courts shall be treated as employees of the Federal Government solely for purposes of any of the following provisions of title 5, United States Code:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Subchapter 1 of chapter 81 (relating to compensation for work injuries).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Chapter 83 (relating to retirement).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Chapter 84 (relating to the Federal Employees’ Retirement System).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Chapter 87 (relating to life insurance).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Chapter 89 (relating to health insurance).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Chapter 89A (relating to enhanced dental benefits).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Chapter 89B (relating to enhanced vision benefits).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Chapter 90 (relating to long-term care insurance).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The employing agency shall make contributions under the provisions referred to paragraph (1) [of this subsection] at the same rates applicable to agencies of the Federal Government.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An individual who is a nonjudicial employee of the District of Columbia courts on the date of the enactment of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 [August 5, 1997] may make, within 60 days after such date, an election under section 8351 or section 8432 of title 5, United States Code, to participate in the Thrift Savings Plan for Federal employees.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Judicial employees of the District of Columbia courts shall be treated as employees of the Federal Government for purposes of any of the following provisions of title 5, United States Code:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Subchapter 1 of chapter 81 (relating to compensation for work injuries).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Chapter 87 (relating to life insurance).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Chapter 89 (relating to health insurance).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Chapter 89A (relating to enhanced dental benefits).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Chapter 89B (relating to enhanced vision benefits).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Chapter 90 (relating to long-term care insurance).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The employing agency shall make contributions under the provisions referred to paragraph (1) [of this subsection] at the same rates applicable to agencies of the Federal Government.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For purposes of section 8706(b) and section 8901(3)(B) of title 5, United States Code, benefits paid from the retirement system for judicial employees of the District of Columbia courts or from the system providing benefits to survivors of such employees shall be considered an annuity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For purposes of section 8901(3)(A) of title 5, United States Code, the retirement system for judicial employees of the District of Columbia courts shall be considered a retirement system for employees of the Government.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 511, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 755, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11246(b)(1)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 108-7" type="History">Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 129, Pub. L. 108-7, Div. C, title III, § 138(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 109-356" type="History">Oct. 16, 2006, 120 Stat. 2024, 2027, Pub. L. 109-356, §§ 112(a), 117(b)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-1726.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-1726.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Section 138 of Public Law 108-7 added subsecs. (b)(1)(F) and (c)(1)(D).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 109-356, in the second sentence of subsec. (a), substituted “maximum pay in section 5382(a)” for “pay fixed by administrative action in section 5373”; in subsec. (b)(1), rewrote subpar. (F) and added subpars. (G) and (H); and, in subsec. (c)(1), rewrote subpar. (D) and added subpars. (E) and (F).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 11246(b)(3) of title XI of Pub. L. 105-33, 111 Stat. 755, provided that the amendments made by § 11246(b) shall apply with respect to all months beginning after the Dates on which the Director of the Office of Personnel Management issues regulations to carry out § <cite path="§11-1726">11-1726</cite> (as amended by § 11246(b)(1)).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 112(b) of Pub. L. 109-356 provided that the amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to pay periods beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [October 16, 2006].</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
