<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-2301</num>
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <heading>Medical Examiner; Deputies; appointment, qualifications, and compensation.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 518, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 106-522" type="History">Nov. 22, 2000, 114 Stat. 2440, Pub. L. 106-522, § 148(a)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-2301.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-2301.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-104">D.C. Law 13-104</cite> which enacted the Mandatory Autopsy for Deceased Wards of the District of Columbia and Mandatory Unusual Incident Report Temporary Act of 1999, added definitions of unusual incident and ward.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 7 (b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-104">D.C. Law 13-104</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) requirement of certain autopsies and reports, see §§ 2 to 5 of the Mandatory Autopsy for Deceased Wards of the District of Columbia and Mandatory Unusual Incident Report Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-232, January 11, 2000,  47 DCR 515).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) requirement of certain autopsies and reports, see §§ 2 to 5 of the Mandatory Autopsy for Deceased Wards of the District of Columbia and Mandatory Unusual Incident Report Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-309, April 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2730).</annotation>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">Functions vested in the Department of Public Health were transferred to the Department of Human Resources by Commissioner’s Order No. 70-83, dated March 6, 1970. The Department of Human Resources was replaced by the Department of Human Services by Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, dated February 21, 1980.</text>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">Establishment of Commission on Medical Examiner’s Office: See Mayor’s Order 89-62, March 28, 1989.</text>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made, in brackets, in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
