<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-2604</num>
  <heading>Payment for representation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any attorney appointed pursuant to this chapter shall, at the conclusion of the representation or any segment thereof, be compensated at a fixed rate of $90 per hour. Such attorney shall be reimbursed for expenses reasonably incurred.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The compensation to be paid to an attorney appointed pursuant to this chapter shall not exceed the following maximum amounts:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For representation of a defendant before the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for misdemeanors or felonies, the maximum amount set forth in section 3006A(d)(2) of title 18, United States Code, for representation of a defendant before the United States magistrate judge or the district court for misdemeanors or felonies (as the case may be).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For representation of a defendant before the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, the maximum amount set forth in section 3006A(d)(2) of title 18, United States Code, for representation of a defendant in an appellate court.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For representation of a defendant in post-trial matters for misdemeanors or felonies, the amount applicable under paragraph (1) for misdemeanors or felonies (as the case may be).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Claims for compensation and reimbursement in excess of any maximum amount provided in subsection (b) of this section may be approved for extended or complex representation whenever such payment is necessary to provide fair compensation. Any such request for payment shall be submitted by the attorney for approval by the chief judge of the Superior Court upon recommendation of the presiding judge in the case or, in cases before the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, approval by the chief judge of the Court of Appeals upon recommendation of the presiding judge in the case. A decision shall be made by the appropriate chief judge in the case of every claim filed under this subsection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A separate claim for compensation and reimbursement shall be made to the Superior Court for representation before that court, and to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals for representation before that court. Each claim shall be supported by a sworn written statement specifying the time expended, services rendered, and expenses incurred while the case was pending before the court, and the compensation and reimbursement applied for or received in the same case from any other source. The court shall fix the compensation and reimbursement to be paid to the attorney. In cases where representation is furnished other than before the Superior Court or the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, claims shall be submitted to the Superior Court which shall fix the compensation and reimbursement to be paid.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For purposes of compensation and other payments authorized by this section, an order by a court granting a new trial shall be deemed to initiate a new case.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If a person for whom counsel is appointed under this section appeals to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, such person may do so without prepayment of fees and costs or security therefor and without filing the affidavit required by section 1915(a) of title 28, United States Code.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-412" type="History">Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1091, Pub. L. 93-412, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-44" type="History">Jan. 31, 1984, D.C. Law 5-44, § 2, 30 DCR 5411</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-11" type="History">Aug. 6, 1993, D.C. Law 10-11, § 201, 40 DCR 4007</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-25" type="History">Sept. 30, 1993, D.C. Law 10-25, § 201, 40 DCR 5489</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-266" type="History">June 13, 1994, Pub. L. 103-266, § 1(b)(121), 108 Stat. 713</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 805, 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Dec. 21, 2001, 115 Stat. 928, Pub. L. 107-96, par. 20(a)(1), (c)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 107-117" type="History">Jan. 10, 2002, 115 Stat. 2307, Pub. L. 107-117, § 404</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 110-335" type="History">Oct. 2, 2008, 122 Stat. 3724, Pub. L. 110-335, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 111-8" type="History">Mar. 11, 2009, 123 Stat. 700, Pub. L. 111-8, § 822(a)</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 5-44: Section 4(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-44">D.C. Law 5-44</cite> provided that the act shall apply to services rendered as a result of court appointments made after January 31, 1984.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 10-25: Section 601(b)(5) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-25">D.C. Law 10-25</cite> provided that for services rendered as a result of court appointments made on or after October 1, 1993, section 201 shall apply as of October 1, 1993.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Expiration of § 805 of Law 11-52: Section 1701(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-52">D.C. Law 11-52</cite> provided that § 805 of the act shall expire on October 1, 1995.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 129 of Pub. L. 107-96, Dec. 21, 2001, 115 Stat. 923, and Section 128 of Pub. L. 108-7, Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 127, provided for the prompt payment of appointed counsel.</text>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 822(c) of Pub. L. 111-8 provided: “The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to cases and proceedings initiated on or after the date of enactment of this Act.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 2 of Pub. L. 110-335 provided: “The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to cases and proceedings initiated on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">“The amendments made by this provision shall apply with respect to cases and proceedings initiated on or after March 1, 2002.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Pub. L. 107-96, 115 Stat. 929, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2002, provided in part:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 201 of the Omnibus Budget Support Emergency Act of 1993 (D.C. Act 10-32, June 3, 1993,  40 DCR 3658)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 701(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-11">D.C. Law 10-11</cite> provided that the act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 601(b)(5) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-11">D.C. Law 10-11</cite> provided that for services rendered as a result of court appointments made on or after October 1, 1993, Section 201 shall apply as of October 1, 1993.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 201 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-11">D.C. Law 10-11</cite> substituted “at a fixed rate of $50 per hour” for “at a rate fixed by the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration, not to exceed the rate of $35 per hour” in (a); substituted “$1,300” for “$900” in (b)(1) and (3); and substituted “$2450” for “$1700” in (b)(2) and (3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 111-8, in subsec. (a), substituted “$90 per hour” for “$80 per hour”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 110-335, in subsec. (a), substituted “$80 per hour” for “$65 per hour”; and rewrote subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 107-117 made a nonsubstantive change.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 107-96 substituted “$65” for “$50” in subsec. (a); and, in subsec. (b), substituted “$1900” for “$1300” twice, and substituted “$3600” for “$2450” twice.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-2604.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-2604.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1906">7-1906</cite>, § <cite path="§11-2603">11-2603</cite>, and § <cite path="§16-2326.01">16-2326.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Neglect and termination of parental rights proceedings, compensation of attorneys, see § <cite path="§16-2326.01">16-2326.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Adult protection proceedings, representation of indigents, see § <cite path="§7-1906">7-1906</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
