<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-2601</num>
  <heading>Plan for furnishing representation of indigents in criminal cases.</heading>
  <text>The Joint Committee on Judicial Administration shall place in operation, within ninety days after the effective date of this chapter, in the District of Columbia a plan for furnishing representation to any person in the District of Columbia who is financially unable to obtain adequate representation —</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>who is charged with a felony, or misdemeanor, or other offense for which the sixth amendment to the Constitution requires the appointment of counsel or for whom, in a case in which such person faces loss of liberty, any law of the District of Columbia requires the appointment of counsel;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>who is under arrest, when such representation is required by law;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>who is charged with violating a condition of probation or parole in custody as a material witness, or seeking collateral relief, as provided in —</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Section 23-110 of the District of Columbia Official Code (remedies on motion attacking sentence),</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Chapter 7 of Title 23 of the District of Columbia Official Code (extradition and fugitives from justice),</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Chapter 19 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code (habeas corpus),</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Section 928 of the Act of March 8, 1901 (D.C. Official Code, sec. 24-502) (commitment 04 of mentally ill person while serving sentence);</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>who is subject to proceedings pursuant to Chapter 5 of Title 21 of the District of Columbia Official Code (hospitalization of the mentally ill);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>who is a juvenile and alleged to be delinquent or in need of supervision.</text>
  </para>
  <aftertext>Representation under the plan shall include counsel and investigative, expert, and other services necessary for an adequate defense. The plan shall include a provision for private attorneys, attorneys furnished by the Public Defender Service, and attorneys and qualified students participating in clinical programs.</aftertext>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-412" type="History">Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1090, Pub. L. 93-412, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-266" type="History">June 13, 1994, Pub. L. 103-266, § 1(b)(116), 108 Stat. 713</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Appropriations approved: Public Law 103-334, 108 Stat. 2577, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1995, provided that funds appropriated for expenses under <cite path="§11-2601">§ 11-2601</cite> et seq. for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1995, shall be available for obligations incurred under the Act in each fiscal year since inception in fiscal year 1975.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Appropriations approved: Public Law 104-194, 110 Stat. 2358, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1997, provided that funds appropriated for expenses under <cite path="§11-2601">§ 11-2601</cite> et seq. (the District of Columbia Criminal Justice Act, 88 Stat. 1090; Pub. L. 93-412) for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1997, shall be available for obligations incurred under the Act in each fiscal year since inception in fiscal year 1975.</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">Section 1701(b) of D.C. Act 11-124 provided that § 805 of that act shall expire on October 1, 1995.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">Section 1001(b) of D.C. Act 11-44 provided that § 505 of that act shall expire on October 1, 1995.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 505 of the Omnibus Budget Support Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-44, April 28, 1995,  42 DCR 2217) and § 805 of the Omnibus Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-124, July 27, 1995,  42 DCR 4160).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-2601.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-2601.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§7-1304.12">§ 7-1304.12</cite>, <cite path="§11-2607">§ 11-2607</cite>, and <cite path="§16-2335.01">§ 16-2335.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Representation of indigents by Public Defender Service, see <cite path="§2-1602">§ 2-1602</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Family Division proceedings, right to counsel, see <cite path="§16-2304">§ 16-2304</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
