<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-721</num>
  <heading>Orders and judgments of the Superior Court.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Court of Appeals has jurisdiction of appeals from —</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>all final orders and judgments of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>interlocutory orders of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia —</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>granting, continuing, modifying, refusing, or dissolving or refusing to dissolve or modify injunctions;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>appointing receivers, guardians, or conservators or refusing to wind up receiverships, guardianships, or the administration of conservators or to take steps to accomplish the purpose thereof; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>changing or affecting the possession of property; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>orders or rulings of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia appealed by the United States or the District of Columbia pursuant to section 23-104 or 23-111(d)(2).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a party aggrieved by an order or judgment specified in subsection (a) of this section, may appeal therefrom as of right to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Review of judgments of the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and of judgments in the Criminal Division of that court where the penalty imposed is a fine of less than $50 for an offense punishable by imprisonment of one year or less, or by fine of not more than $1,000, or both, shall be by application for the allowance of an appeal, filed in the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>When a judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in making in a civil case (other than a case in which a child, as defined in section 16-2301, is alleged to be delinquent, neglected, or in need of supervision) a ruling or order not otherwise appealable under this section, shall be of the opinion that the ruling or order involves a controlling question of law as to which there is substantial ground for a difference of opinion and that an immediate appeal from the ruling or order may materially advance the ultimate termination of the litigation or case, the judge shall so state in writing in the ruling or order. The District of Columbia Court of Appeals may thereupon, in its discretion, permit an appeal to be taken from that ruling or order, if application is made to it within ten days after the issuance or entry of the ruling or order. An application for an appeal under this subsection shall not stay proceedings in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia unless the judge of that court who made such ruling or order or the District of Columbia Court of Appeals or a judge thereof shall so order.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>On the hearing of any appeal in any case, the District of Columbia Court of Appeals shall give judgment after an examination of the record without regard to errors or defects which do not affect the substantial rights of the parties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Court of Appeals shall hear an appeal from an order of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia holding an individual in contempt and imposing the sanction of imprisonment on such individual in the course of a case for custody of a minor child not later than 60 days after such individual requests that an appeal be taken from that order.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Any appeal from an order of the Family Court of the District of Columbia terminating parental rights or granting or denying a petition to adopt shall receive expedited review by the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 480, Pub. L. 91-358, Title I, § 111</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 101-97" type="History">Sept. 23, 1989, 103 Stat. 634, Pub. L. 101-97, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-266" type="History">June 13, 1994, Pub. L. 103-266, § 1(b)(7), 108 Stat. 713</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 107-114" type="History">Jan. 8, 2002, 115 Stat. 2112, Pub. L. 107-114, § 4(b)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 5 of Pub. L. 101-97 provided that the amendments made by §§ 2 and 3 shall apply with respect to any individual imprisoned before the expiration of the 18-month period that begins on the Dates of the enactment of this Act for disobedience of an order or for contempt committed in the presence of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia or the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 107-114 added subsec. (g).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-721.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-721.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§17-301">17-301</cite> and § <cite path="§17-307">17-307</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District Charter provisions relating to jurisdiction of Court of Appeals, see § <cite path="§1-204.31">1-204.31</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
