<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-722</num>
  <heading>Administrative orders and decisions.</heading>
  <text>The District of Columbia Court of Appeals has jurisdiction (1) except as provided in clause (2), to review orders and decisions of the Commissioner [Mayor] of the District of Columbia, the District of Columbia Council, any agency of the District of Columbia (including the Board of Zoning Adjustment of the District of Columbia and the Zoning Commission of the District of Columbia), and the District of Columbia Redevelopment Land Agency, in accordance with the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Official Code, secs. 2-501   — 2-510); and (2) to review orders and decisions of the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia in accordance with section 8 of the Act of March 4, 1913 (D.C. Official Code, Chapters 1 through 11, Title 34).</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 481, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District Charter provisions relating to jurisdiction of Court of Appeals, see § <cite path="§1-204.31">1-204.31</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§17-303">17-303</cite> and § <cite path="§17-307">17-307</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-722.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-722.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made, in brackets, in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
