<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-908</num>
  <heading>Designation and assignment of judges.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection 11-908A, the chief judge may designate the number of judges to serve in any division and branch of the Superior Court and may assign and reassign any judge to sit in any division or branch. When making assignments to the Family Division and Tax Division, the chief judge shall consider the qualifications and interest of the judges. Each associate judge shall attend and serve in the division and branch to which assigned.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>When the business of the Superior Court requires, the chief judge may certify to the chief judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals the need for temporary assignment of an additional judge or judges as provided in section 11-707.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon presentation of a certificate of necessity by the chief judge of the Superior Court, the chief judge of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit may designate and assign temporarily a judge or judges as provided in subsection (c) of section 292 of title 28, United States Code.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 483, Pub. L. 91-358, Title I, § 111</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-266" type="History">June 13, 1994, Pub. L. 103-266, § 1(b)(14), 108 Stat. 713</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 107-114" type="History">Jan. 8, 2002, 115 Stat. 2107, Pub. L. 107-114, § 3(e)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§11-908A">11-908A</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-908.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-908.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 107-114, in subsec. (a), substituted “Subject to  section 11-908A, the chief judge” for “The chief judge”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
