<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>11-921</num>
  <heading>Civil jurisdiction.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Superior Court has jurisdiction of any civil action or other matter (at law or in equity) brought in the District of Columbia. Such jurisdiction shall vest in the court as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning on the effective date of the District of Columbia Court Reorganization Act of 1970, the court has jurisdiction of any civil action or other matter begun before such effective date in the District of Columbia Court of General Sessions, the Juvenile Court of the District of Columbia, or the District of Columbia Tax Court.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Beginning on such effective date, the court has jurisdiction of any civil action or other matter, at law or in equity, which is begun in the Superior Court on or after such effective date and in which the amount in controversy does not exceed $50,000.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Beginning on such effective date, the court has jurisdiction (regardless of the amount in controversy) of any civil action or other matter, at law or in equity, which —</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>is brought under —</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>subchapter I of Chapter 11 of Title 16 (relating to ejectment);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>subchapter II or III of Chapter 13 of Title 16 (relating to the condemnation of land on behalf of the District of Columbia);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Chapter 19 of Title 16 (relating to writs of habeas corpus directed to persons other than Federal officers and employees);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Chapter 25 of Title 16 (relating to change of name);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Chapter 33 of Title 16 (relating to quieting title to real property);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>subchapter II of Chapter 35 of Title 16 (relating to writ of quo warranto);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>Chapter 37 of Title 16 (relating to replevin of personal property);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(viii)</num>
          <text>the Hospital Treatment for Drug Addicts Act for the District of Columbia (D.C. Official Code, secs. 24-701 through 24-711) (relating to commitment of narcotics users); or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ix)</num>
          <text>section 2 of the Act of August 3, 1968 (D.C. Official Code, sec. 2-201.02) (relating to contractors bonds).</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>involves an appeal from or petition for review of any assessment of tax (or civil penalty thereon) made by the District of Columbia; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>is brought under Chapter 23 of Title 16.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Immediately following the expiration of the eighteen-month period beginning on such effective date, the court has jurisdiction (regardless of the amount in controversy) of any civil action or other matter, at law or in equity, brought under —</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Chapter 3 of Title 21 (relating to gifts to minors);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Chapter 5 of Title 21 (relating to hospitalization of the mentally ill);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Chapter 7 [repealed] of Title 21 (relating to property of the mentally ill);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Chapter 11 of Title 21 (relating to commitment and maintenance of substantially retarded persons);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Chapter 13 [repealed] of Title 21 (relating to appointment of committees for alcoholics and addicts);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Chapter 15 [repealed] of Title 21 (relating to appointment of conservators); or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Chapter 3, 7 [repealed], 11, 13 [repealed], or 15 [repealed] of Title 21 in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia and not completed in that court before the expiration of such eighteen-month period.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Immediately following the expiration of the thirty-month period beginning on such effective date, the court has jurisdiction (regardless of the amount in controversy) —</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>of any matter (at law or in equity) —</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>brought under Chapter 29 of Title 16 (relating to partition of property and assignment of dower);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>which would have been within the jurisdiction of the Orphans Court of Washington County, District of Columbia before June 21, 1870;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>relating to the execution or validity of wills devising real property within the District of Columbia, and of wills and testaments properly presented for probate in the court, and the admission to probate and recording of those wills;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>relating to the proof of wills of either personal or real property and the revocation of probate of wills for cause;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>involving the granting and revocation for cause of letters testamentary, letters of administration, letters ad colligendum and letters of guardianship, and the appointment of successors to persons whose letters have been revoked;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>involving the hearing, examination, and issuance of decrees upon accounts, claims, and demands existing between executors or administrators and legatees or persons entitled to a distributive share of an intestate estate, or between wards and their guardians;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>involving the enforcement of the rendition of inventories and accounts by executors, administrators, collectors, guardians, and trustees required to account to the court;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(viii)</num>
          <text>involving the enforcement of distribution of estates by executors and administrators and the payment or delivery by guardians of money or property belonging to their wards; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ix)</num>
          <text>otherwise within the probate jurisdiction of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia on the day before such effective date; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>any matter (at law or in equity) described in subparagraph (A) which was begun in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia and not completed in that court before the expiration of such thirty-month period.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Immediately following the expiration of the thirty-month period beginning on such effective date, the court has jurisdiction (regardless of the amount in controversy) of any civil action or other matter, at law or in equity, brought in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court does not have jurisdiction over any civil action or other matter (1) over which exclusive jurisdiction is vested in a Federal court in the District of Columbia, or (2) over which jurisdiction is vested in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia under section 11-501 (relating to civil actions or other matters begun in such court before the expiration of the thirty-month period beginning on the effective date of the District of Columbia Court Reorganization Act of 1970).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 484, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-530" type="History">Dec. 7, 1970, 84 Stat. 1390, Pub. L. 91-530, § 2(a)(1)</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">“The effective date of the District of Columbia Court Reorganization Act of 1970,” referred to throughout this section, means, as set forth in § 199(c) of the Act, the first day of the seventh calendar month which began after the enactment of the Act.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">“Chapter 7 of title 21”, referred to in subsection (a)(4)(C), was repealed by § 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-204">D.C. Law 6-204</cite>, effective February 28, 1987.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">“Chapter 13 of title 21”, referred to in subsection (a)(4)(E), was repealed by § 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-204">D.C. Law 6-204</cite>, effective February 28, 1987.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">“Chapter 15 of title 21”, referred to in subsection (a)(4)(F), was repealed by § 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-204">D.C. Law 6-204</cite>, effective February 28, 1987.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">“Chapters 7, 13, 15 of title 21”, referred to in subsection (a)(4)(G), were repealed by § 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-204">D.C. Law 6-204</cite>, effective February 28, 1987.</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 11-921.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-921.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-411">2-411</cite>, § <cite path="§11-501">11-501</cite>, and § <cite path="§16-601">16-601</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District Charter provisions relating to jurisdiction of Superior Court, see § <cite path="§1-204.31">1-204.31</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Claims against the District, definition of court, see § <cite path="§2-411">2-411</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
