<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>11-1504</num>
  <heading>Services of retired judges.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A judge, retired for reasons other than disability, who has been favorably recommended and appointed as a senior judge, in accordance with subsection (b), may perform such judicial duties as such senior judge is assigned and willing and able to undertake. A senior judge shall be subject to reappointment every four years, unless the Senior Judge has reached his or her seventy-fourth birthday, whereupon review shall be at least every two years, in accordance with subsection (b). Except as provided under this section, retired judges may not perform judicial duties in District of Columbia courts.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At any time prior to or not later than one year after retirement, a judge may request recommendation from the District of Columbia Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Commission”) to be appointed as a senior judge in accordance with this section; except that any retired judge shall have not less than 180 days from the effective date of this Act to file a request for an initial recommendation from the Commission.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A retired judge willing to perform judicial duties may request a recommendation as a senior judge from the Commission. Such judge shall submit to the Commission such information as the Commission considers necessary to a recommendation under this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall submit a written report of its recommendations and findings to the appropriate chief judge and the judge requesting appointment within 180 days of the date of the request for recommendation. The Commission, under such criteria as it considers appropriate, shall make a favorable or unfavorable recommendation to the appropriate chief judge regarding an appointment as senior judge. The recommendation of the Commission shall be final.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The appropriate chief judge shall notify the Commission and the judge requesting appointment of such chief judge’s decision regarding appointment within 30 days after receipt of the Commission’s recommendation and findings. The decision of such chief judge regarding such appointment shall be final.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A judge may continue to perform judicial duties upon retirement, without appointment as a senior judge, until such judge’s successor assumes office.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A retired judge, actively performing judicial duties as of the date of enactment of the District of Columbia Retired Judge Service Act, may continue to perform such judicial duties as he or she may be willing and able to assume, subject to the approval of the appropriate chief judge, for a period not to exceed one year from the date of enactment of such Act, without appointment as a senior judge.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 491, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 111</annotation>
      <annotation>Oct. 30, 1984, 98 Stat. 3142, Pub. L. 98-598, § 2(a)</annotation>
      <annotation>Oct. 28, 1986, 100 Stat. 3228, Pub. L. 99-573, §§ 14(a), (b)</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="1-204.31">1-204.31</cite> and § <cite root="11-908A">11-908A</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 11-1504.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 11-1504.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>“The effective date of this Act,” referred to in subsection (a)(2), is October 28, 1986.</text>
      <text>The “District of Columbia Retired Judge Service Act,” referred to in subsection (d), is Public Law 98-598.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
