<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-190">
  <num type="law">16-190</num>
  <heading type="short">Emerging Technology Opportunity Development Task Force Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2007-03-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-190.pdf">D.C. Law 16-190</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 6791</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0504">
      <narrative>Law 16-190, the “Emerging Technology Opportunity Development Task Force Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-504, which was referred to the Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 20, 2006, and July 11, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 31, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-474 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-190 became effective on March 2, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establish an emerging technology opportunity development task force to identify and assess emerging technologies and their economic development opportunities, and to encourage participation by universities, schools, government, and businesses in a comprehensive strategy to increase emerging technology. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Emerging Technology Opportunity Development Task Force Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. Establishment of Task Force. There is established a Technology Opportunity Development Task Force (“Task Force”) to serve as a collaborative body to identify knowledge-based economic opportunities, including emerging technology fields, that could provide research and economic development opportunities for the District of Columbia and create a comprehensive and coordinated strategy to enhance commercial activity in these fields. Sec. 3. Duties a) The Task Force shall conduct a detailed assessment of the emerging knowledge and technology cluster in the District of Columbia through the following 1) A review of national best practices to develop and attract knowledge-based and technology-based companies 2) Creation of a plan to promote the development of research-driven and innovative firms in the District; and (3) Creation of a way to market and identify the District as a center for creativity and innovation, capitalizing on established institutions such as museums, think tanks, universities, and media and communication industries b) The Task Force shall explore means to increase economic activity within the District through knowledge-based activities, including technology commercialization, by encouraging the following: Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2006 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 1) Development of the technology infrastructure such as fiber optics cable and research and incubator space needed by knowledge-based and technology-based companies 2) The transfer and commercialization of university research 3) Partnerships between businesses and universities to market university products and attract government and private investment for these products 4) Creation of an entrepreneurial environment for new businesses to take advantage of emerging knowledge-based and technology development opportunities, especially in underserved communities and disadvantaged populations 5) Relocation of businesses to the District to take advantage of these initiatives 6) Investment by venture capital firms in emerging knowledge-based and technology-based companies in the District; and (7) Collaboration by universities, public schools, and small businesses to A) Define the jobs that may be created through innovation-led and technology development initiatives and the skills that will be needed for these jobs B) Integrate opportunities for students and employees to work across disciplines to obtain the skills necessary for enhanced job performance; and (C) Help individuals without technical skills to participate in on-the-job training, in conjunction with public schools and local universities. Sec. 4. Composition; compensation, procedure; sunset a) The Task Force shall be selected by the Mayor and the Chairman of the Council and be comprised of no more than 23 representatives from the following entities 1) University research and federal research communities 2) Business leaders including entrepreneurs 3) Real estate development 4) Banking, investment, and venture capital 5) Government and public policy 6) Public education 7) Community organizations; and (8) Washington, D.C.-area grantmakers b) The chairperson shall be appointed by the Mayor from among the members c) The Mayor shall appoint at least 3 members from the Task Force to the Federal Comprehensive Economic Development Strategy (“CEDS”) Committee d) Members shall serve without compensation; except, that members may receive reimbursement for documented expenses incurred in the service of the Task Force e) The Mayor shall provide staff support to the Task Force and the funds necessary to accomplish its duties and the purposes of this act f) The Task Force may meet as necessary to conduct its official business. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 g) The Task Force may conduct hearings, receive testimony, and establish rules of procedure as may be necessary h) The Task Force shall disband no later than one year after its initial meeting. Sec. 5. Findings and recommendations. No later than 30 days prior to disbandment, the Task Force shall submit to the Mayor and the Council its findings and recommendations, including any proposed legislative changes and the estimated cost of the proposed legislation. Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 7. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1221.31"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1221.32"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1221.33"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1221.34"/>
  </section>
</document>
