<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-199">
  <num type="law">16-199</num>
  <heading type="short">Separation Pay, Term of Office and Voluntary Retirement Modifications for Chief of Police Charles H. Ramsey Amendment Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2007-03-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-199.pdf">D.C. Law 16-199</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 8832</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0733">
      <narrative>Law 16-199, the “Separation Pay, Term of Office and Voluntary Retirement Modifications for Chief of Police Charles H. Ramsey Amendment Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-733, which was referred to the Committee on Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 11, 2006, and October 3, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 23, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-494 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-199 became effective on March 2, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to modify the separation pay provisions applicable to the Executive Service in the case of involuntary separation from the District government of Chief of Police Charles H. Ramsey; to amend An Act Relating to the Metropolitan police of the District of Columbia to provide that, effective retroactively to April 21, 2003, Chief Ramsey shall serve in the capacity of Chief of Police for a term not to exceed 5 years, except that the Mayor may terminate him earlier with or without cause; and to amend the District of Columbia Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act to increase the rate of annuity for voluntary retirement for Chief Ramsey to 3.43% effective retroactively to April 21, 1998. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Separation Pay, Term of Office and Voluntary Retirement Modifications for Chief of Police Charles H. Ramsey Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. Section 1058 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective June 10, 1998 (D.C. Law 12-124; D.C. Official Code § 1- 610.58 is amended as follows a) Designate the existing text as subsection (a b) A new subsection (b) is added to read as follows: “(b)(1) Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section and except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, Charles H. Ramsey, Chief of Police, shall be paid separation pay equivalent to up to 6 months of his basic pay upon involuntary separation from the District government by the Mayor if the involuntary separation is without cause. “(2) If Chief Ramsey is involuntarily separated without cause at any time during the last 6 months of his term, as that term is set forth in subsection (c) of paragraph 2 of section 1 of An Act Relating to the Metropolitan police of the District of Columbia, approved February 28, 1901 (31 Stat. 819; D.C. Official Code § 5-105.01 he shall be entitled to separation pay equal to the actual number of days remaining in his term.”. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2006 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 1-610.58 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 3. Paragraph 2 of section 1 of An Act Relating to the Metropolitan police of the District of Columbia, approved February 28, 1901 (31 Stat. 819; D.C. Official Code § 5- 105.01 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows: “(c) Effective April 21, 2003, Charles H. Ramsey, Chief of Police, shall serve in the capacity of Chief of Police for a term of 5 years, except that the Mayor may earlier terminate Chief Ramsey with or without cause.”. Sec. 4. Subsection (h) of the Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act, approved September 1, 1916 (39 Stat. 718; D.C. Official Code § 5-712 is amended by adding a new paragraph (6) to read as follows: “(6) Notwithstanding the first sentence of paragraph (1) of this subsection, Charles H. Ramsey, Chief of Police, may voluntarily retire from the service and, effective April 21, 1998, the date of his appointment as Chief of Police, shall be entitled to an annuity computed at a rate of 3.43% of his average pay times the number of years of his creditable service.”. Sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved Amend § 5-105.01 Amend § 5-712 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
