<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-127">
  <num type="law">16-127</num>
  <heading type="short">Government Facility Security Amendment Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2006-06-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-127.pdf">D.C. Law 16-127</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 4712</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0388">
      <narrative>Law 16-127, the “Government Facility Security Amendment Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-388 which was referred to the Committees on the Judiciary and Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 7, 2006, and April 4, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 21, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-345 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-127 became effective on June 16, 2006.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and ten, and for other purposes to prohibit policemen from serving as watchmen at the Municipal Building; to amend the Office of Property Management Establishment Act of 1998 to re-establish the Protective Services Division within the Office of Property Management; and to repeal the Government Facility Security Amendment Act of 2004. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Government Facility Security Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and ten, and for other purposes, approved March 3, 1909 (Pub. L. No. 60-303; 35 Stat. 689 is amended by adding a new paragraph after the first paragraph under the subheading “FOR CARE OF DISTRICT BUILDING:” to read as follows: “Policemen shall not be detailed for duty as watchmen at the Municipal Building.”. Sec. 3. The Office of Property Management Establishment Act of 1998, effective March 26, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-175; D.C. Official Code § 10-1001 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 1804(a)(3 D.C. Official Code § 10-1003(a)(3 is amended by striking the phrase “custodial services, ” and inserting the phrase “custodial services, security services,” in its place b) Section 1806(a D.C. Official Code § 10-1005(a is amended as follows 1) The lead-in language is amended by striking the word “three” and inserting the word “four” in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the word “and” at the end 3) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place 4) A new paragraph (5) is added to read as follows: Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2006 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 10-1003 Amend § 10-1005 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(5) The Protective Services Division, which will coordinate and manage the security requirements for District government facilities.”. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
