<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-19">
  <num type="law">16-19</num>
  <heading type="short">Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Board Expansion Amendment Act of 2005</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2005-09-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-19.pdf">D.C. Law 16-19</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 6572</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0025">
      <narrative>Law 16-19, the “Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Board Expansion Amendment Act of 2005”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-25, which was referred to the Committee of Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 3, 2005, and June 7, 2005, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 22, 2005, it was assigned Act No. 16-101 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-19 became effective on September 14, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Act of 2004 to ensure that there is an appropriate number of members on the Corporation’s Board of Directors by adding 2 new members to be filled by a recognized labor union organization and a recognized environmental organization. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Board Expansion Amendment Act of 2005”. Sec. 2. The Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Act of 2004, effective December 7, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-219; D.C. Official Code § 2-1223.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 105(a) is amended as follows 1) The lead-in text is amended to read as follows: “The powers of the Corporation shall be vested in a Board of Directors which shall consist of the following 11 voting members, and may include 4 nonvoting members to be selected as follows:” 2) Paragraph (1) is amended as follows A) Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the word “Seven” and inserting the word “Nine” in its place B) New subparagraphs (E) and (F) are added to read as follows: “(E) One public citizen member shall be a representative of a recognized labor union organization. “(F) One public citizen member shall be a representative of a recognized environmental organization.” b) Section 107(a) is amended by striking the phrase “not less than 4 of these voting” and inserting the phrase “not less than 5 of these voting” in its place. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 2-1223.05 Amend § 2-1223.07 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
