<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-167">
  <num type="law">16-167</num>
  <heading type="short">Drug Offense Driving Privileges Revocation and Disqualification Amendment Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2006-09-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-167.pdf">D.C. Law 16-167</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 6194</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0565">
      <narrative>Law 16-167, the “Drug Offense Driving Privileges Revocation and Disqualification Amendment Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-565 which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 20, 2006, and July 11, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 18, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-435 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-167 became effective on September 29, 2006.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925 to require that drug offense conviction information shall be sent electronically by the court to the Mayor within one business day of the conviction or adjudication and shall include the person’s name, address, date of birth, conviction date, driver’s license number, if any, social security number, if any, the offense, and any other necessary information. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Drug Offense Driving Privileges Revocation and Disqualification Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. Section 13a(a) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-222; D.C. Official Code § 50-1403.02(a is amended by striking the sentence “A copy of the conviction or adjudication shall be forwarded by the court to the Mayor.” and inserting the sentence “Notification of the conviction or adjudication shall be sent electronically by the court to the Mayor within one business day of the conviction or adjudication and shall include the person’s name, address, date of birth, conviction date, driver’s license number, if any, social security number, if any, the offense, and any other information required by the Mayor to take the action required by this section.” in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement in the committee report required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1- 206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2006 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 50-1403.02 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
