<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-236">
  <num type="law">16-236</num>
  <heading type="short">Additional Sanctions for Nuisance Abatement and Office of the Tenant Advocate Duties Clarification Amendment Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2007-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-236.pdf">D.C. Law 16-236</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 391</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0786">
      <narrative>Law 16-236, the “Additional Sanctions for Nuisance Abatement and Office of the Tenant Advocate Duties Clarification Amendment Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-786, which was referred to Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 14, 2006, and December 5, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 28 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-592 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-236 became effective on March 8, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend AN ACT to provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes, to provide for civil fines, penalties, and fees to be imposed as additional sanctions for any infraction of certain provisions; and to amend the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to clarify the duties of the Office of the Tenant Advocate to include assistance to tenant organizations. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Additional Sanctions for Nuisance Abatement and Office of the Tenant Advocate Duties Clarification Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. Section 10(c) of AN ACT to provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes, effective April 27, 2001 (D.C. Law 13-281; D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.10(c is amended to read as follows: “(c) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as additional sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of sections 6, 7, 9, or 12, pursuant to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Official Code § 2-1801.01 et seq ”. Sec. 3. Section 2067 of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3531.07 is amended to read as follows: “Sec. 2067. Duties of the Office of the Tenant Advocate. ”The Office shall: ”(1) Provide education and outreach to tenants and the community about laws, rules, and other policy matters involving rental housing, including tenant rights under the petition process and formation of tenant organizations; “(2) Represent the interest of tenants and tenant organizations in legislative, executive, and judicial issues, including advocating changes in laws and rules and reviewing landlord petitions on behalf of tenants; Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2007 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 42-3131.10 Amend § 42-3531.07 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(3) Advise tenants and tenant organizations on filing complaints and petitions, including petitions in response to disputes with landlords; “(4) Advise and assist tenants and tenant organizations at conciliation meetings; “(5) Represent tenants and tenant organizations in court or administrative proceedings; “(6) Organize tenant and tenant organizations participation in building-wide inspections; and “(7) Operate a Tenant Phone Hotline and Tenant Center.”. Sec. 4. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
