<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-219">
  <num type="law">16-219</num>
  <heading type="short">Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology Amendment Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2007-03-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-219.pdf">D.C. Law 16-219</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 10211</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0435">
      <narrative>Law 16-219, the “Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology Amendment Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-435, which was referred to Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 14, 2006, and December 5, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 19, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-548 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-219 became effective on March 6, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 to regulate the practice of audiology and speech-language pathology, to establish a Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology, and to establish the minimum qualifications for licensure of audiologists and speech-language pathologists. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.01 et seq is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended as follows 1) Add the phrase “Sec. 218. Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology.” after the phrase “Sec. 217. Board of Marriage and Family Therapy.” 2) Add the following after “Sec. 832. Transition of licensed marriage and family therapists.”: “TITLE VIII-B “QUALIFICATIONS FOR LICENSURE TO PRACTICE AUDIOLOGY AND SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGY. “Sec. 841. Qualifications For Licensure.” b) Section 101(1 D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.01(1 is amended by adding the phrase “Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology,” after the phrase “ “Board” means the” c) Section 102 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.02) is amended as follows 1) A new paragraph (2B) is added to read as follows: “(2B)(A) “Practice of audiology” means the planning, directing, supervising, and conducting of habilitative or rehabilitative counseling programs for individuals or groups of individuals who have, or are suspected of having, disorders of hearing; any service in audiology, Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2007 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 3-1201.01 Amend § 3-1201.02 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. including prevention, identification, evaluation, consultation, habilitation or rehabilitation, instruction, and research; participating in hearing conservation, hearing aid and assistive listening device evaluation, selection, preparation, dispensing, and orientation; fabricating ear molds; providing auditory training and speech reading; or administering tests of vestibular function and tests for tinnitus. The practice of audiology includes speech and language screening limited to a pass-or-fail determination for the purpose of identification of individuals with disorders of communication. The practice of audiology does not include the practice of medicine or osteopathic medicine, or the performance of a task in the normal practice of medicine or osteopathic medicine by a person to whom the task is delegated by a licensed physician. “(B) Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as preventing or restricting the practice, services, or activities of a school audiologist employed by, and working in accordance with, the regulations of the District of Columbia Board of Education.” 2) A new paragraph (20) is added to read as follows: “(20)(A) “Practice of speech-language pathology” means the application of principles, methods, or procedures related to the development and disorders of human communication, including any condition, whether of organic or non-organic origin, that impedes the normal process of human communication including disorders and related disorders of speech, articulation, fluency, voice, oral, or written language; auditory comprehension and processing; oral, pharyngeal or laryngeal sensorimotor competencies; swallowing; auditory or visual processing; auditory or visual memory or cognition; communication; and assisted augmentative communication treatment and devices. “(B) The term practice of speech-language pathology also includes the planning, directing, supervising, and conducting of a habilitative and rehabilitative counseling program for individuals or groups of individuals who have, or are suspected of having, disorders of communication, and any service in speech-language pathology including prevention, identification, evaluation, consultation, habilitation or rehabilitation, instruction, or research. “(C) The practice of speech-language pathology may include pure-tone air conduction hearing screening, screening tympanometry, and acoustic reflex screening, limited to a pass-or-fail determination for the identification of individuals with other disorders of communication and may also include aural habilitation or rehabilitation, which means the provision of services and procedures for facilitating adequate auditory, speech, and language skills in individuals with hearing impairment. The practice of speech-language pathology does not include the practice of medicine or osteopathic medicine, or the performance of a task in the normal practice of medicine or osteopathic medicine by a person to whom the task is delegated by a licensed physician. “(D) Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as preventing or restricting the practice, services, or activities of a school speech-language pathologist working in accordance with the regulations of the District of Columbia Board of Education.”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 d) A new section 218 is added to read as follows: “Section 218. Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology. “(a) There is established a Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology, which shall consist of 7 members appointed by the Mayor. “(b) The Board shall regulate the practice of audiology and speech-language pathology. “(c) The Board shall administer the examination required for audiology and speech- language pathology licenses. “(d) Of the members of the Board, 2 shall be practicing audiologists, 2 shall be practicing speech-language pathologists, one shall be a practicing Otolaryngologist, and 2 shall be consumer members with no direct affiliation with either the practice of audiology or the practice of speech-language pathology or other health profession. The professional members shall: “(1) For audiology, at least 3 years preceding appointment, have been actively engaged as an audiologist in rendering professional services in audiology or in the education and training of masters, doctoral, or postdoctoral students of audiology in audiology research, and for the 2 years preceding the appointment, have spent the majority of their time devoted to one of the activities listed in this paragraph. “(2) For speech pathology, at least 3 years preceding the appointment, have been actively engaged as a speech-pathologist in rendering professional services in speech pathology or in the education and training of masters, doctoral, or postdoctoral students of speech pathology in speech-pathology research, and for the 2 years preceding the appointment, have spent the majority of their time devoted to one of the activities listed in this paragraph. “(3) For otolaryngology, at least 3 years preceding the appointment, have been actively engaged as an otolaryngologist in rendering professional services in otolaryngology or in the education and training of masters, doctoral, or postdoctoral students of otolaryngology in otolaryngology research, and for the 2 years preceding the appointment have spent the majority of their time devoted to one of the activities listed in this paragraph. “(e) Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, members of the Board shall be appointed for terms of 4 years. No person may be appointed more than once to fill an unexpired term or more than 2 consecutive full terms. “(f) The initial appointees, with the exception of the representatives of the general public and the Otolaryngologist, shall be deemed to be and shall become licensed audiologists and speech-language pathologists immediately upon their qualification and appointment as members of the Board. “(g) Of the members initially appointed, 2 shall be appointed for 2 years, 2 shall be appointed for 3 years, and 3 members, including the chairperson, shall be appointed for 4 years. “(h) The Mayor shall designate one Board member to serve as chairperson during the term of his or her appointment to the Board. No person may serve as chairperson for more than ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 4 years.” e) Section 401(b)(2 D.C. Official Code § 3-1204.01(b)(2 is amended by striking the phrase “Professional Counseling,” and inserting the phrase “Professional Counseling, the audiologist and speech-language pathologist members initially appointed to the Board” in its place f) Section 501 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.01) is amended by striking the phrase “professional counseling,” and inserting the phrase “professional counseling, audiology, speech- language pathology,”in its place g) A new title VIII-B is added to read as follows: “SUBCHAPTER VIII-B “QUALIFICATIONS FOR LICENSURE TO PRACTICE AUDIOLOGY AND "SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGY. “Sec. 841. Qualifications for licensure. “(a) The Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology shall license as an audiologist a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of Title V, has: “(1) Graduated with a Master’s degree or a Doctoral degree in audiology from a recognized educational institution that incorporates the academic course work and minimum hours of supervised training required by the regulations adopted by the Board and whose audiology program is regionally accredited by the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association or an equivalent accrediting body; “(2) Passed a qualifying examination given by the Board or from an accrediting body recognized by the Board; and “(3) Completed a period of supervised postgraduate professional practice in audiology as specified by rulemaking issued by the Board. “(b) The Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology shall license as a speech- language pathologist a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of Title V, has: “(1) Graduated with a Master’s degree or Doctoral degree in speech-language pathology from a recognized educational institution that incorporates the academic course work and minimum hours of supervised training required by the regulations adopted by the Board and whose speech-language pathology program is regionally accredited by the American Speech- Language-Hearing Association or an equivalent accrediting body; “(2) Passed a qualifying examination given by the Board or from an accrediting body recognized by the Board; and “(3) Completed a period of supervised postgraduate professional practice in speech-language pathology as specified by rulemaking issued by the Board.” “(c) An audiology or speech-language pathology license shall be renewable every 2 years by the Board.” h) Section 1003 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1210.03) is amended by adding a new subsection (z) to read as follows: Amend § 3-1204.01 Amend § 3-1205.01 Amend § 3-1210.03 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(z) Unless authorized to practice audiology or speech-language pathology pursuant to this act, a person shall not advertise the performance of audiology or speech-language; use a title or description such as “audiological,” “audiologist,” “audiology,” “hearing clinic,” “hearing clinician,” “hearing or aural rehabilitation,” “hearing specialist,” “communication disorders,” “communicologist,” “language pathologist,” “logopedist,” “speech and language clinician,” “speech and language therapist,” “speech clinic,” “speech clinician,” “speech correction,” “speech correctionist,” “speech pathology,” “speech-language pathology,” “speech therapist,” or “speech therapy,” or any other name, style, or description denoting that the person is an audiologist or speech-language pathologist or practicing audiology or speech-language pathology.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02 (c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02 (c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
