<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-290">
  <num type="law">16-290</num>
  <heading type="short">Film DC Economic Incentive Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2007-03-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-290.pdf">D.C. Law 16-290</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 984</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0935">
      <narrative>Law 16-290, the “Film DC Economic Incentive Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-935, which was referred to Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 14, 2006, and December 5, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 28, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-649 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-290 became effective on March 14, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establish the Film DC Economic Incentive Grant Fund to provide incentives to attract and retain film, television, and multimedia business in the District. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Film DC Economic Incentive Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. Film DC Economic Incentive Grant Fund a) There is hereby established a segregated, nonlapsing fund to be known as the Film DC Economic Incentive Grant Fund (“Fund” The Fund shall appear as a separate program line within the budget of the Office of Motion Picture and Television Development. The Fund shall be funded by annual appropriations. All funds deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this act, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act b)(1) The funds in the Fund shall be used A) To provide incentives through discretionary grants for nationally distributed film and television projects, excluding production of television coverage of news or athletic events, that expend at least $500,000 in qualified expenses in a period of 5 or more days for production activities located in the District of Columbia, in amount not to exceed the lesser of 10% of qualified expenses or 100% of the taxes paid to the District on the qualified expenses; and (B) For administrative costs and monitoring of the Fund 2) For the purposes of this subsection, the term “qualified expenses” means the costs incurred in the District for the production of the film or television project (including all expenses incurred in the District of Columbia from vehicle rentals, camera equipment, lighting, stage equipment, recording equipment, costumes, wardrobe, construction materials, props, scenery materials, film and tape, design materials, special effects materials, fabrication, printing or production of scripts, storyboards, costumes, salaries paid to District residents, hotel expenses, food and alcohol purchases, restaurant expenses, and related supplies and equipment c) The Mayor shall submit an annual report to the Council, on or before December 31 of each year, for the fiscal year concluding September 30 that includes: Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2007 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 1) For each grant, the amount of the grant, the rationale for the grant, and the revenue generated for the District by each project for which a grant was awarded 2) The criteria used in evaluating the grant proposals; and (3) The number of grant applications received and a description of each project for which a grant application was made. Sec. 3. Rulemaking. The Mayor may promulgate rules necessary to implement this act. Sec. 4. Funding from revised revenue certification. The unallocated revenue from the certification of the Chief Financial Officer’s December 2006 and February 2007 revised quarterly revenue estimates for fiscal year 2007, less the amount to be allocated to section 1043 of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, signed by the Mayor on August 8, 2006 (D.C. Act 16-476; 53 DCR 6899 the Washington Stage Guild Exemption Act of 2006, effective September 26, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-172; D.C. Official Code §10- 1074 the Organ and Bone Marrow Donor Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on November 14, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-701 and the Domestic Partnerships Joint Filing Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on December 19, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-958) shall be deposited in the Fund in an amount to not to exceed $1,600,000. Sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect upon its approval by the Mayor (or in the event of a veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1204.11"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1204.11a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2b</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1204.11b"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2c</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1204.11c"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2d</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1204.11d"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2e</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1204.11e"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1204.12"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1204.13"/>
  </section>
</document>
