<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-209">
  <num type="law">16-209</num>
  <heading type="short">ANTI-TAGGING AND ANTI-VANDALISM AMENDMENT ACT OF 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2007-03-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-209.pdf">D.C. Law 16-209</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 9080</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0395"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend AN ACT TO provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes, to authorize the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs to abate graffiti nuisance property in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Anti-Tagging and Anti-Vandalism Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. Section 1(c) of AN ACT TO provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes, approved April 14, 1906 (34 Stat. 114; D.C. Official Code § 42-3131.01(c is amended as follows a) The existing text is re-designated as paragraph (1 b) Newly re-designated paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase “natural causes.” and inserting the phrase “natural causes. The condition may also include the presence of graffiti.” in its place c) New paragraphs (2) and (3) are added to read as follows: “(2) For the purposes of this subsection, the presence of graffiti shall be deemed to be a housing regulation violation. “(3) In the case of graffiti which does not constitute a life-or-health threatening condition, but which constitutes a nuisance, the Mayor may order the removal of the graffiti within a specified time period and, subject to 7 days’ notice to the owner or an authorized agent in the manner provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection and an opportunity for review of the order, the Mayor may remove the graffiti if the owner does not comply.”. Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2006 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 42-3131.01 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
