<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-246">
  <num type="law">16-246</num>
  <heading type="short">Mount Vernon Triangle BID Amendment Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2007-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-246.pdf">D.C. Law 16-246</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 618</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0937">
      <narrative>Law 16-246, the “Mount Vernon Triangle BID Amendment Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-937, which was referred to Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 14, 2006, and December 5, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 28 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-602 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-246 became effective on March 8, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996 to revise the BID taxes for the Mount Vernon Triangle business improvement district. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Mount Vernon Triangle BID Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. Section 205(c) of The Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996, effective May 29, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-134; D.C. Official Code § 2-1215.55 (c is amended to read as follows: “(c)(1) The BID taxes for the nonexempt real properties in the Mount Vernon Triangle BID shall be: “(A) The amount of 35 per square foot of land; “(B) The amount of 15 per rentable square foot of commercial buildings; provided, that any supermarket that is receiving a tax incentive pursuant to § 47-3802 shall not be required to pay the BID tax during the term of the incentive; “(C) The amount of $90 per hotel room annually; and “(D)(i) The amount of $120 per unit annually for nonexempt residential properties. “(ii) If a residential unit is restricted to residents based upon income pursuant to a Federal or District affordable housing program, the BID tax due on the unit shall be computed by applying the percentage of area median income eligible residents must meet to participate in the affordable housing program to the amount of the BID tax which would otherwise be due. “(2) Subject to the requirements of section 8, the BID taxes set forth in this subsection may be increased by 5%.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the attached fiscal impact statement as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2007 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 2-1215.55 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of a veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
