<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-294">
  <num type="law">16-294</num>
  <heading type="short">SECOND TECHNICAL AMENDMENTS ACT OF 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2007-03-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-294.pdf">D.C. Law 16-294</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 1086</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0996">
      <narrative>Law 16-294, the ‘Second Technical Amendments Act of 2006‘, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-996, which was referred to Committee on the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 14, 2006, and December 5, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 28, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-653 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-294 became effective on March 14, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to clarify when a waiver of notice or injury or death shall be allowed and to conform the disability period for retention rights upon return to employment; to amend the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to correct the citation of the year of passage; to repeal sections 47- 1806.08, 47-1806.08a, 47-1806.08b, 47-1808.08c, 47-1808.08d, 47-1808.08e, 47- 1808.08f, and 47-1808.08g of the District of Columbia Official Code, which provided for a targeted historic housing tax credit program that has been replaced by a grant program established by Targeted Historic Preservation Assistance Amendment Act of 2006; to amend the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002 to strike an erroneous clause inadvertently retained in a previous amendment; to amend the Parking Enhancement Amendment Act of 2006 to correct a typographical error; to amend the Parking Amendment Act of 2006 to correct a section citation and to add an inadvertently omitted phrase; to amend the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006 to correctly state an expenditure amount, to strike an erroneous word, and to correct a cross reference; to amend section 5 of the Washington Stage Guild Tax Exemption Act of 2007 to make a conforming amendment; to amend the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund and Tobacco Settlement Financing Amendment Act of 2006 to add an inadvertently omitted parenthesis; to amend section 47-340.23 of the District of Columbia Official Code to correct a typographical error and to correct an address and expenditure amount; to amend the District of Columbia Deed Recordation Tax Act to restore an amendment that was inadvertently omitted during the enrollment process; to amend Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to correct section numbering; to amend section 115(b) of the New Convention Center Hotel Omnibus Financing and Development Act of 2006 to correct a typographical error; to amend the Poverty Lawyers Loan Assistance Repayment Program Act of 2006 to add a paragraph that was inadvertently omitted during enrollment; to amend section 47-1803.02(a)(2) of the District of Columbia Official Code to add a new subparagraph (X) that was inadvertently omitted during enrollment; to amend the School Modernization Financing Act of 2006 to change the date of calculation of the cost-of-construction adjustment applied to the additional revenue allocation to conform to the end of the fiscal year Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2007 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. instead of the calendar year; to repeal section 47-1806.11 of the District of Columbia Official Code; and to amend the Living Wage Act of 2006 to clarify that contracts or other agreements that are subject to higher federal wage level determinations are exempt from the act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Second Technical Amendments Act of 2006 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-623.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2319(b D.C. Official Code §1-623.19(b is amended as follows 1) The lead-in sentence is amended by striking the word "if 2) Paragraph (b)(1) is amended by striking the word "The" and inserting the phrase "If the" in its place 3) Paragraph (b)(2) is amended by striking the word "The" and inserting the phrase "If the" in its place 4) Paragraph (b)(3) is amended by striking the word "Objection" and inserting the phrase "Unless objection" in its place b) Section 2345(b)(1 D.C. Official Code §1-623.45(b)(1 is amended by striking the phrase "one year" and inserting the phrase "two years" in its place c) This section shall apply as of April 5, 2005. Sec. 3. Section 206(a) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3502.06(a is amended by striking the phrase "June 6, 1006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-109 Petitions and voluntary agreements pending as of the effective date of the Rent Control Reform Amendment Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on June 6, 1006" and inserting the phrase "June 6, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-109 Petitions and voluntary agreements pending as of the effective date of the Rent Control Reform Amendment Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on June 6, 2006" in its place. Sec. 4. Sections 47-1806.08, 47-1806.08a, 47-1806.08b, 47-1808.08c, 47-1808.08d, 47- 1808.08e, 47-1808.08f, and 47-1808.08g of the District of Columbia Official Code are repealed. Sec. 5. Section 9b(a)(2) of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.10(a)(2 is amended by striking the phrase "transferred or revert to the fund balance of" and inserting the phrase "transferred to" in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 6. Section 2(a) of the Parking Enhancement Amendment Act of 2006, signed by the Mayor on July 25, 2006 (D.C. Act 16-464; 53 DCR 6719 is amended by striking the section designation "2411.9" and in inserting the section designation "2411.19" in its place. Sec. 7. The Parking Amendment Act of 2006, signed by the Mayor on July 21, 2006 (D.C. Act 16-453; 53 DCR 6499 is amended as follows a) Section 3 is amended by striking the section citation "47-2892(c and inserting the section citation "47-2829(c in its place b) Section 5(a)(3) is amended by striking the phrase "where a wedding" and inserting the phrase "where a non-recurring event such as a wedding" in its place. Sec. 8. The Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, signed by the Mayor on August 8, 2006 (D.C. Act 16- 476; 53 DCR 6899 is amended as follows a) Section 1043 is amended by adding a new paragraph (1A) to read as follows: “(1A) An amount of $5 million to the Office of the City Administrator for the Mayor’s Youth Strategy fund;” b) Section 2102 is amended by striking the phrase "of $950,000 million" and inserting the phrase "of $950,000" in its place c) Section 2055(18) is amended by striking the phrase “subtitle O” and inserting the phrase “subtitle II-L” in its place. Sec. 9. Section 5 of the Washington Stage Guild Tax Exemption Act of 2006, signed by the Mayor on July 18, 2006 (D.C. Act 16-441; 53 DCR 6432 is amended as follows a) Strike the subsection designation a b) Subsection (b) is repealed. Sec.10. Section 3(c)(1)(A) of the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund and Tobacco Settlement Financing Amendment Act of 2006, effective July 25, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-142; 53 DCR 4412 is amended by striking the phrase "District and" and inserting the phrase "District) and" in its place. Sec. 11. Section 47-340.23(c) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1)(A) is amended by striking the phrase “$1 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for the purposes of acquisition and redevelopment of property in the 3300 block of Georgia Avenue, N.W.” and inserting the phrase “$2 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for the purposes of acquisition and redevelopment of property in the 3200 block of Georgia Avenue, N.W for redevelopment of Park Morton under the Great Streets initiative.” in its ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. place b) Paragraph (2) is amended as follows 1) Subparagraph (O) is repealed 2) Subparagraph (Q) is amended by striking the phrase "6500 block of Georgia Avenue" and inserting the phrase "6400 block of Georgia Avenue" in its place. Sec. 12. Section 303(a-3) of the District of Columbia Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 12; D.C. Official Code § 42-1103(a-3 is amended by striking the phrase a)(1 and inserting the phrase a)(1) or (3 in its place. Sec. 13. Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by striking the section designation “47-1074. Far Southeast Community Organization; lots 73, 74, and 75, square 5753.”and inserting the section designation “47-1075. Far Southeast Community Organization; lots 73, 74, and 75, square 5753.” in its place b) Strike the phrase “§ 47-1074. Far Southeast Community Organization; lots 73, 74, and 75 in square 5753.” and insert the phrase“47-1074. Far Southeast Community Organization; lots 73, 74, and 75, square 5753.” in its place. Sec. 14. Section 115(b) of the New Convention Center Hotel Omnibus Financing and Development Act of 2006, effective September 19, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-163; 53 DCR 5438 is amended by striking the phrase “47-4608" and inserting the phrase “47-4609" in its place. Sec. 15. Section 2(6) of the District of Columbia Poverty Lawyer Loan Assistance Repayment Program Act of 2006, signed by the Mayor on October 25, 2006 (D.C. Act 16-503; 53 DCR 9055 is amended to read as follows: “(6) ““Eligible employment” means those areas of legal practice certified by the Attorney General to serve the public interest, including employment with legal organizations that qualify for District of Columbia Bar Foundation funding. The term “eligible employment” shall not include employment with the District of Columbia or federal government or with or as the Administrator.”. Sec. 16. Section 47-1803.02(a)(2) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new subparagraph (X) to read as follows: “(X) Loans awarded and subsequently forgiven under the District of Columbia Poverty Lawyer Loan Assistance Repayment Program Act of 2006, signed by the Mayor on October 25, 2006 (D.C. Act 16-503; 53 DCR 9055).”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 17. Section 121(b) of the School Modernization Financing Act of 2006, effective June 7, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-123; 53 DCR 2843 is amended by striking the phrase “December 31 of such fiscal year.” and inserting the phrase “September 30 of such fiscal year.” in its place. Sec. 18. Chapter 18 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents for Chapter 18 is amended by striking the phrase “§ 47- 1806.11. Tax on residents and nonresidents – Credits energy conservation credit.” and inserting the phrase "§ 47-1806.11. Tax on residents and nonresidents – Credits energy conservation credit. Repealed in its place b) Section 47-1806.11 is amended to read as follows: “§ 47-1806.11. Tax on residents and nonresidents – Credits – energy conservation credit. Repealed Sec. 19. Section 105(1) of the Living Wage Act of 2006, June 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16- 118; D.C. Official Code § 2-220.05(1 is amended by striking the phrase "wage level determinations" and inserting the phrase "higher wage level determinations" in its place. Sec. 20. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 21. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December ENROLLED ORIGINAL 6Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
