<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-35">
  <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="4|7A"/>
  <num type="law">16-35</num>
  <heading type="short">Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2005-10-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-35.pdf">D.C. Law 16-35</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 8113</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0103">
      <narrative>Law 16-35, the “Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-103 which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 7, 2005, and July 6, 2005, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 3, 2005, it was assigned Act No. 16-169 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-35 became effective on October 22, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To reaffirm the District of Columbia=s commitment to addressing the problem of homelessness, to establish the Interagency Council on Homelessness and describe its members, powers, and duties, to describe the Continuum of Care for individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless, to codify the rights and responsibilities of clients of homeless services providers, and the standards by which the District of Columbia and homeless services providers must deliver services to clients, and to revise the procedures for resolving disputes between clients and providers of homeless services. TABLE OF CONTENTS Sec. 2. Definitions. Sec. 3. Application. Sec. 4. Establishment of Interagency Council on Homelessness. Sec. 5. Powers and duties of the Interagency Council. Sec. 6 Operation of the Interagency Council. Sec. 7. Continuum of Care for individuals and families who are homeless. Sec. 8. Eligibility for services within the Continuum of Care. Sec. 9. Client rights. Sec. 10. Additional rights for clients in temporary shelter or supportive housing. Sec. 11. Client responsibilities. Sec. 12. Common standards for providers. Sec. 13. Additional standards for providers of severe weather shelter. Sec. 14. Additional standards for providers of low barrier shelter. Sec. 15. Additional standards for providers of temporary shelter and supportive housing. Sec. 16. Additional standards for providers of transitional housing. Sec. 17. Monitoring and inspections. Sec. 18. Program Rules. Sec. 19. Notice. Sec. 20. Transfer. Sec. 21. Suspension. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 2 Sec. 22. Termination. Sec. 23. Alternative sanctions.Sec. 24. Emergency transfers, suspensions, or terminations. Sec. 25. Mediation. Sec. 26. Fair hearings. Sec. 27. Administrative review. Sec. 28. No entitlement to services. Sec. 29. Limitation on use of District monies. Sec. 30. Contracting authority. Sec. 31. Rulemaking authority. Sec. 32. Conforming amendments. Sec. 33. Fiscal impact statement. Sec. 34. Effective date. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the AHomeless Services Reform Act of 2005@. Sec. 2. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term 1) AAdministrative Procedure Act@ or AAPA@ means the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat 1204; D.C. Official Code 2-501 et seq 2) AAdult@ means any individual who A) Has reached the age of majority under District law as defined in section 2 of the District of Columbia Age of Majority Act, effective July 22, 1976 (D.C. Law 1- 75; D.C. Official Code 46-101 or (B) Qualifies as an emancipated minor under District law 3) AApartment style@ means a housing unit with A) Separate cooking facilities and other basic necessities to enable families to prepare and consume meals B) Separate bathroom facilities for the use of the family; and (C) Separate sleeping quarters for adults and minor children in accordance with the occupancy standards of Title 14 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (Housing 4) AAppropriate permanent housing@ means permanent housing that does not jeopardize the health, safety, or welfare of its occupants, meets the District=s building code requirements, and is affordable for the client 5) AAppropriately trained and qualified@ means having received specialized training designed to teach the skills necessary to successfully perform one=s job and to work compassionately with individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless 6) ABasic necessities@ means a dinette set, refrigerator, stove, exhaust fan or ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 3 window, storage cabinets, cookware, flatware, and tableware 7) AClient@ means an individual or family seeking, receiving, or eligible for services from a program covered by section 3 8) AContinuum of Care@ means the comprehensive system of services for individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless and designed to serve clients based on their individual level of need. The Continuum of Care may include crisis intervention, outreach and assessment services, shelter, transitional housing, permanent supportive housing, and supportive services 9) ACrisis intervention@ means assistance to prevent individuals and families from becoming homeless, which may include, but need not be limited to, cash assistance for security deposits, rent or mortgage payments, credit counseling, mediation with landlords, and supportive services 10) ACulturally competent@ means the ability of a provider to deliver or ensure access to services in a manner that effectively responds to the languages, values, and practices present in the various cultures of its clients so the provider can respond to the individual needs of each client 11) ADay program@ means a facility that provides open access to structured activities during set hours of the day to meet the supportive services needs of individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless 12) ADepartment@ means the Department of Human Services 13) ADistrict@ means the District of Columbia government, its agents, or its designees 14) ADrop-in center@ means a facility that delivers supportive services that may include food, clothing, showers, medical services, and employment services 15) ADrug@ means a controlled substance as defined in section 102(4) of the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, effective August 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-29; D.C. Official Code 48-901.02(4 or the Controlled Substances Act of 1970, approved October 27, 1970 (84 Stat. 1242; 21 U.S.C 801 et seq 16) AFamily@ means A) A group of individuals with at least one minor or dependent child, regardless of blood relationship, age, or marriage, whose history and statements reasonably tend to demonstrate that they intend to remain together as a family unit; or (B) A pregnant woman in her third trimester 17) AGroup home@ means a housing unit with A) Sleeping quarters that may be shared B) Shared cooking and bathroom facilities; and (C) Other basic necessities to enable individuals or families to prepare and consume meals 18) AHomeless@ means A) Lacking a fixed, regular residence that does not jeopardize the health, safety, or welfare of its occupants, and lacking the financial ability to immediately acquire one; or ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 4 (B) Having a primary nighttime residence that is i) A supervised publicly or privately operated shelter or transitional housing facility designed to provide temporary living accommodations; or (ii) A public or private place not designed for, or ordinarily used as, a regular sleeping accommodation for human beings 19) AHousing First@ means a program that provides clients with immediate access to independent permanent housing and supportive services without prerequisites for sobriety or participation in psychiatric treatment. Clients in Housing First programs may choose the frequency and type of supportive services they receive and refusal of services will have no consequence for their access to housing or on continuation of their housing and supportive services 20) AHyperthermia shelter@ means a public or private building that the District shall make available, for the purpose of providing shelter to individuals or families who are homeless and cannot access other shelter, whenever the actual or forecasted temperature or heat index rises above 95 degrees Fahrenheit. The term Ahyperthermia shelter@ does not include overnight shelter 21) AHypothermia shelter@ means a public or private building that the District shall make available, for the purpose of providing shelter to individuals or families who are homeless and cannot access other shelter, whenever the actual or forecasted temperature, including the wind chill factor, falls below 32 degrees Fahrenheit 22) AIndividual with a disability@ means a person with a physical or mental impairment that substantially limits the major life activities of the person 23) AImminent risk of becoming homeless@ means the likelihood that an individual's or family's circumstances will cause the individual or family to become homeless in the absence of prompt government intervention 24) AImminent threat to the health or safety@ means an act or credible threat of violence on the grounds of a shelter or supportive housing facility 25) AInteragency Council@ means the Interagency Council on Homelessness established pursuant to section 4 26) ALow barrier shelter@ means an overnight housing accommodation for individuals who are homeless, provided directly by, or through contract with or grant from, the District, for the purpose of providing shelter to individuals without imposition of identification, time limits, or other program requirements 27) AMember agency@ or Amember agencies@ means the District agencies or divisions thereof represented on the Interagency Council pursuant to section 4(b 28) APermanent supportive housing@ means supportive housing for an unrestricted period of time for individuals and families who were once homeless and continue to be at imminent risk of becoming homeless, including persons with disabilities as defined in 24 C.F.R 582.5, for whom self-sufficient living may be unlikely and whose care can be supported through public funds 29) AProgram Rules@ means the set of provider rules, client rights, and complaint and appeal procedures, including those enumerated in this act, proposed by a ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 5 particular provider for the purpose of governing the behavior and treatment of its clients and approved by the Mayor subject to section 18 30) AProvider@ means an individual or entity within the Continuum of Care that operates a program covered by section 3 31) APublic assistance@ means government-funded payments in or by money, medical care, remedial care, shelter, goods or services to, or for the benefit of, needy persons 32) AResident of the District@ means an individual or family who is living in the District voluntarily and not for a temporary purpose and who has no intention of presently moving from the District. The term "resident of the District" shall be interpreted and applied in accordance with section 503 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Official Code 4-205.03 33) ASanction@ means an adverse action taken by a provider affecting the delivery of services to a client, and may include loss of privileges or denial, reduction, delay, transfer for inappropriate or punitive reasons, suspension, or termination of services 34) AService plan@ means a written plan collaboratively developed and agreed upon by both the provider and the client, consisting of time-specific goals and objectives designed to promote self-sufficiency and attainment of permanent housing and based on the client's individually assessed needs, desires, strengths, resources, and limitations 35) ASevere weather conditions@ means the outdoor conditions whenever the actual or forecasted temperature, including the wind chill factor or heat index, falls below 32 degrees Fahrenheit or rises above 95 degrees Fahrenheit 36) ASevere weather shelter@ means hyperthermia shelter or hypothermia shelter 37) AShelter@ means severe weather shelter, low barrier shelter, and temporary shelter 38) ASupportive housing@ means transitional housing and permanent supportive housing 39) ASupportive services@ means services addressing employment, physical health, mental health, alcohol and other substance abuse recovery, child care, transportation, case management, and other health and social service needs which, if unmet, may be barriers to obtaining or maintaining permanent housing 40) ATemporary shelter@ means A) A housing accommodation for individuals who are homeless that is open either 24 hours or at least 12 hours each day, other than a severe weather shelter or low barrier shelter, provided directly by, or through contract with or grant from, the District, for the purpose of providing shelter and supportive services; or (B) A 24-hour apartment-style housing accommodation for individuals or families who are homeless, other than a severe weather shelter, provided directly by, or through contract with or grant from, the District, for the purpose of providing shelter and supportive services 41) ATransitional housing@ means a 24-hour housing accommodation, provided directly by, or through contract with or grant from, the District, for individuals and families ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 6 who A) Are homeless B) Require a structured program of supportive services for up to 2 years or as long as necessary in order to prepare for self-sufficient living in permanent housing; and (C) Consent to a case management plan developed collaboratively with the provider 42) AWeapon@ means any pistol or other firearm (or imitation thereof or other dangerous or deadly weapon, including a sawed-off shot gun, shot gun, machine gun, rifle, dirk, bowie knife, butcher knife, switch blade knife, razor, black jack, billy club or metallic or other false knuckles, as referenced in section 2 of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Stat. 560; D.C. Official Code 22-4502 and any air gun, air rifle, canon, torpedo, bean shooter, sling, projectile, dart, BB gun, spring gun, blow gun, other dangerous missile or explosive, or other dangerous weapon or ammunition of any character, as referenced in Chapter 23 of Title 24 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Sec. 3. Application a) The provisions in sections 9-27 shall apply to 1) Each program within the Continuum of Care offered by the District of Columbia or by a provider receiving funding for the program from either the District of Columbia or the federal government, if such funds are administered, whether by grant, contract, or other means, by the Department of Human Services or its designee; and (2) Clients of programs covered under paragraph (1) of this subsection b) In multi-program agencies, the provisions in sections 9-27 shall only apply to those programs that meet the criteria in subsection (a) of this section and clients of those programs c) This section shall not be construed to expand or limit the requirements of any other provision of this act. Sec. 4. Establishment of Interagency Council on Homelessness a) There is established in the District the Interagency Council on Homelessness for the purpose of facilitating interagency, cabinet-level leadership in planning, policymaking, program development, provider monitoring, and budgeting for the Continuum of Care of homeless services b) The Interagency Council is composed of 1) The City Administrator, who shall serve as chairperson of the Interagency Council 2) The administrative head of each of the following entities or divisions thereof A) Department of Human Services B) Department of Mental Health C) Child and Family Services Agency D) Department of Housing and Community Development; ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 7 (E) Department of Health F) District of Columbia Housing Authority G) Department of Corrections H) Department of Employment Services I) District of Columbia Public Schools J) District of Columbia Emergency Management Agency K) Office of Property Management; and (L) Metropolitan Police Department 3) A representative of any private entity designated to approve or allocate any grants or contracts, on behalf of the Mayor, for services within the Continuum of Care 4) A representative from a minimum of 4 and a maximum of 10 organizations that are providing services within the Continuum of Care 5) A minimum of 2 and a maximum of 5 homeless or formerly homeless individuals 6) A minimum of 2 and a maximum of 5 advocates for the District of Columbia=s homeless population; and (7) The Chairman of the Council, or his or her designee, and the Chairman of the committee of the Council having purview over homeless services, or his or her designee, both of whom shall be non-voting members c) All non-government members of the Interagency Council described in subsections (b)(4 6) of this section shall be nominated for appointment by the Mayor and approved by the Council. The Mayor shall transmit to the Council, within 90 days of the effective date of this act, nominations of each non-government member of the Interagency Council for a 60-day period of review, excluding days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove a nomination by resolution within the 60-day review period, the nomination shall be deemed approved. Sec. 5. Powers and duties of the Interagency Council a) The Interagency Council shall provide leadership in the development of strategies and policies that guide the implementation of the District=s policies and programs for meeting the needs of individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless b) In fulfilling the responsibility described in subsection (a) of this section, the Interagency Council shall 1) Coordinate an annual, community-wide needs-assessment and planning process to identify, prioritize, and target needs for services within the Continuum of Care. The needs-assessment shall take into account existing data and include input from at least one public hearing, which shall be held at least once each year 2) At least every 5 years, prepare and publish a strategic plan for services within the Continuum of Care that takes into account existing data and community input 3) Prepare an annual plan detailing how the District intends to provide or arrange for services within the Continuum of Care that takes into account existing data and ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 8 community input 4) Review on a regular basis the efforts of each member of the Interagency Council to fulfill the goals and policies of the annual plan prepared pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection, including a review of the number and nature of contracts and grants entered into by each agency to provide services within the Continuum of Care 5) Prepare and submit to the Mayor an annual written report evaluating the efforts of each member agency of the Interagency Council to meet the goals and policies of the annual plan prepared pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection 6) Direct the Office of Property Management to identify vacant public buildings or tax-foreclosed buildings to be used as shelter and supportive housing facilities 7) Provide input into the District=s planning and application for federal funds for services within the Continuum of Care. All applications for federal funds shall take into account the strategic plan developed by the Interagency Council prepared pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection 8) Have access to data collected and generated by a computerized information system as set up by the Mayor pursuant to section 8(d The data may include the number of beds or units available in the District=s shelter and supportive housing facilities, the availability of supportive services in the District, and the current usage of and unmet demand for such beds, units, and services 9) By September 1 of each year, develop a plan, consistent with the right of clients to shelter in severe weather conditions, describing how member agencies will coordinate to provide hypothermia shelter and identifying the specific sites that will be used as hypothermia shelters; and (10) Review reports of the fair hearings and administrative reviews requested or received by clients within the Continuum of Care, which shall include the provider party to the appeal, the subject matter of the appeal, and the final disposition of the appeal c) The Mayor shall, no later than February 1 of each year, make available to all Interagency Council members the District=s proposed budget breakdown of each agency=s appropriations for services within the Continuum of Care. The Interagency Council shall give comments to the Mayor regarding the proposed budget d) Each member agency of the Interagency Council shall 1) Conduct or commission an annual audit of any private entity designated by the agency to approve or allocate any grants or contracts, on behalf of the Mayor, for services within the Continuum of Care, and make available a report of the audit to all Interagency Council members 2) Offer training and technical assistance to its employees who directly provide services within the Continuum of Care and to any providers with which the member agency or its designee contracts to deliver the services; and (3) Report to the Interagency Council on a quarterly basis currently available data on the number of individuals and families that applied for homeless services and the number of homeless individual or families that were served by the agency and its contractors. ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 9 Sec. 6. Operation of the Interagency Council a) The Interagency Council shall meet not less than quarterly. All meetings of the Interagency Council shall comply with the following requirements 1) A quorum of one-third of the appointed representatives of member agencies, one-third of appointed representatives of providers of homeless services, and one-third of the appointed homeless or formerly homeless individuals or advocates must be present in order to conduct the business of the Interagency Council 2) The meetings of the Interagency Council, and the meetings of any committees it shall establish pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, shall be subject to the open meeting provisions of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 831; D.C. Official Code 1-207.42 and (3) The Interagency Council shall provide a reasonable opportunity at the beginning of each meeting during which members of the public may comment on matters relevant to the work of the Interagency Council b) The Interagency Council shall enact rules of procedure or bylaws to guide the regular operation of the Interagency Council. The rules of procedure or bylaws shall be made available to the public upon request c) The Interagency Council may establish committees to aid in conducting its business. No meeting of a committee of the Interagency Council shall qualify as a meeting of the Interagency Council for purposes of fulfilling the requirements in subsection (a) of this section d) The Mayor shall, within 30 days of the effective date of this act, designate an existing department or agency to provide staff assistance and support to the Interagency Council. Sec. 7. Continuum of Care for individuals and families who are homeless a) The District=s provision of homeless services shall be based on a Continuum of Care that offers a comprehensive range of services through various member agencies and is designed to meet the specific, assessed needs of individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless. The District shall respond to the changing needs of individuals and families by ensuring that transfer between and among services within the Continuum of Care is fluid and allows clients to modify the intensity of services they receive to meet their needs, preferences, and changing circumstances b) The Continuum of Care may include the following range of services 1) Crisis intervention for the purpose of preventing homelessness by enabling individuals and families at imminent risk of becoming homeless to remain in or access permanent housing; provided, that the Mayor shall not offer crisis intervention services authorized by this paragraph until the Chief Financial Officer has certified the availability of fiscal year 2006 funding pursuant to section 1016(5) of the Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Act of 2005, passed on 2nd reading on July 6, 2005 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-200 2) Outreach and assessment, including the operation of a hotline, for the purpose of identifying the housing and supportive service needs of individuals and families who ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 10 are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless and linking them to appropriate services 3) Shelter to meet the housing needs of individuals and families who are homeless through the provision of A) Severe weather shelter for the purpose of protecting lives in extreme hot and cold weather B) Low barrier shelter for individuals for the purpose of sheltering and engaging individuals who avoid temporary shelter because of identification, time limit, or other program requirements; and (C) Temporary shelter for individuals and families for the purpose of meeting short-term housing needs and other supportive service needs 4) Supportive housing to meet the longer-term housing needs of individuals and families who are homeless through the provision of A) Transitional housing for the purpose of providing eligible individuals and families who are homeless with long-term housing and supportive services in order to prepare them for self-sufficient living in permanent housing; and (B) Permanent supportive housing for the purpose of providing eligible individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless with housing and supportive services C) Housing First for the purpose of providing eligible individuals and families who are homeless with housing and supportive services 5) Supportive services for the purpose of providing individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless with services that address their housing, employment, physical health, mental health, alcohol and other substance abuse recovery, child care, case management, transportation, and other health and social service needs which, if unmet, may be barriers to obtaining or maintaining permanent housing. These services may, but need not, be delivered through day programs, drop-in centers, shelters, and transitional and permanent supportive housing providers, or through referrals to other appropriate service providers c) Whenever the actual or forecasted temperature, including the wind chill factor, falls below 32 degrees Fahrenheit, or whenever the actual or forecasted temperature or heat index rises above 95 degrees Fahrenheit, the District shall make available appropriate space in District of Columbia public or private buildings and facilities for any person in the District who is homeless and cannot access other shelter. In doing so, the District shall not use District of Columbia Public School buildings currently being used for educational purposes without the prior approval of the Board of Education d) The Mayor shall not place homeless families in non-apartment style shelters. Sec. 8. Eligibility for services within the Continuum of Care a) An individual or family is eligible to receive services within the Continuum of Care if the individual or family 1) Is homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless; ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 11 (2) Is a resident of the District, as defined by section 503 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Official Code 4-205.03 and (3) Meets any additional eligibility requirements that have been established pursuant to section 17 by the provider from whom services are sought b) No individual or family may be deemed ineligible for services solely because the individual or family cannot establish proof of homelessness or residency at the time of the individual or family's application for assistance c)(1) The Mayor shall operate at least one central intake center for families for the purposes of A) Assessing the eligibility of families for services within the Continuum of Care and making appropriate referrals for those services; and (B) Serving as a resource center for families who are seeking information about the availability of services within the Continuum of Care 2) Families who are eligible for services within the Continuum of Care shall receive appropriate referrals to the first available provider based on the chronological order in which they apply for assistance, consistent with any additional eligibility requirements established pursuant to section 18 by the provider from whom services are sought 3) Any family who is determined to be eligible for services pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(A) of this section, but who is not immediately served due to lack of capacity, shall be placed on one or more waiting lists for the services sought and shall be served in the order in which appropriate referrals become available 4) Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, in determining what is an Aappropriate referral,@ the Mayor shall consider relevant factors, including prior receipt of services, disability, family size, affordability of housing and age, and may use these factors to prioritize a family=s placement in shelter or other service 5) The Mayor shall not impose or apply eligibility criteria that exclude or tend to exclude an individual with a disability or any class of individuals with disabilities from fully and equally enjoying any services within the Continuum of Care, unless such criteria are shown to be necessary for the provision of the services d) The Mayor shall operate a computerized information system to collect, maintain, and distribute up-to-date information regarding the number of beds or units available in shelter and supportive housing in the District, the availability of supportive services, and the current usage and unmet demand for such beds, units, and services. Sec. 9. Client rights. Clients served within the Continuum of Care shall have the right to 1) At all times, be treated by providers and the Department with dignity and respect 2) Access services within the Continuum of Care free from discrimination on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, language, culture, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, familial status, family responsibilities, matriculation, ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 12 political affiliation, disability, and source of income, and in accordance with the Human Rights Act of 1977, effective December 13, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-38; D.C. Official Code 2-1401.01 et seq the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, approved July 26, 1990 (104 Stat. 328; 42 U.S.C 12101 et seq the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, approved August 7, 1998 (112 Stat. 1095; 29 U.S.C 701 et seq Title II of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, approved July 2, 1964 (78 Stat. 243; 42 U.S.C 2000a et seq and the Language Access Act of 2004, effective June 19, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-167; D.C. Official Code 2-1931 et seq 3) Receive reasonable modifications to policies, practices, or procedures when the modifications are necessary to avoid discrimination on the basis of disability, unless the client=s provider demonstrates that the modifications would fundamentally alter the nature of the services 4) Access services within the Continuum of Care free from verbal, emotional, sexual, financial, and physical abuse and exploitation 5) Shelter in severe weather conditions 6) At a reasonable time and with reasonable prior notice, view and copy, or have an authorized representative view and copy, all records and information that are related to the client and maintained by the client's provider, including any relevant personal, social, legal, financial, educational, and medical records and information, subject to the provisions of paragraph (7) of this subsection 7) Confidential treatment by the Department and providers of personal, social, legal, financial, educational, and medical records and information related to a client or any member of a client=s family, whether obtained from the client or from any other source, in a manner consistent with the confidentiality requirements of District and federal law 8) Engage in or abstain from the practice of religion, including the religion of a particular provider or other clients 9) Upon request, be told the name and job title of any provider staff member delivering services 10) Provide input and feedback to providers on their delivery of services 11) File complaints with a provider or the Mayor regarding the provider=s delivery of services or treatment of the client 12) Participate actively in development of any service plan for the client, be told of the progress made toward the goals of that service plan, and receive a review of the service plan upon request 13) Be free from testing for drugs or alcohol except when A) Program guidelines prohibit intoxication and a licensed social worker with experience identifying indications of drug or alcohol use or a certified addiction counselor determines that there is reasonable cause to believe that the client is engaging in drug or alcohol use; or (B) A client consents to drug or alcohol testing as part of the client's case management plan developed in accordance with paragraph (12) of this subsection 14) Meet and communicate privately with attorneys, advocates, clergy, physicians, and other professionals; ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 13 (15) Timely notice, where required by section 19, of any decision by the Department or a provider that adversely affects the client=s receipt of services within the Continuum of Care 16) Appeal, where permitted by sections 26 and 27, of any decision by the Department or a provider that adversely affects the client=s receipt of services within the Continuum of Care 17) Be free from retaliation, punishment, or sanction for exercising any rights provided under this act; and (18) Continuation of shelter and supportive housing services without change, other than transfer pursuant to section 20 or emergency transfer, suspension, or termination pursuant to section 24, pending the outcome of any fair hearing requested within 15 calendar days of receipt of written notice of a suspension or termination. Sec. 10. Additional rights for clients in temporary shelter or supportive housing. Clients residing in temporary shelter or supportive housing shall have the right to 1) Receive visitors in designated areas of the shelter or housing premises during reasonable hours and under such reasonable conditions as specified in the provider's Program Rules established pursuant to section 18 2) Leave and return to the shelter or housing premises within reasonable hours as specified by the Program Rules established pursuant to section 18 3) Reasonable prior notice specifying the date and time of any inspections of a client's living quarters and of the provider staff member authorized to perform the inspection, except when, in the opinion of the provider's executive or program director, there is reasonable cause to believe that the client is in possession of a substance or object that poses an imminent threat to the health and safety of the client or any other person on the provider's premises and such reasonable cause is documented in the client's record 4) Be present or have an adult member of the family present at the time of any inspection unless, in the opinion of the provider=s executive or program director, there is reasonable cause to believe that the client is in possession of a substance or object that poses an imminent threat to the health and safety of the client or any other person on the provider=s premises and such reasonable cause is documented in the client=s record 5) Reasonable privacy in caring for personal needs and in maintaining personal living quarters; and (6) Conduct their own financial affairs, subject to the reasonable requirements of Program Rules established pursuant to section 18 or to a service plan pursuant to section 9(12 Sec. 11. Client responsibilities a) Clients receiving services within the Continuum of Care shall 1) Seek appropriate permanent housing or Housing First, except when the client is residing in severe weather and low barrier shelter 2) Seek employment, education, or training when appropriate, except when the ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 14 client is residing in severe weather and low barrier shelter 3) Refrain from the following behaviors while on a provider=s premises A) The use or possession of alcohol or illegal drugs B) The use or possession of weapons C) Assaulting or battering any individual, or threatening to do so; and (D) Any other acts that endanger the health or safety of the client or any other individual on the premises 4) Ensure that children within the client=s family and physical custody are enrolled in school, where required by law 5) Ensure that the client=s minor children receive appropriate supervision while on the provider=s premises 6) Utilize child care services when necessary to enable the adult client to seek employment or housing or to attend school or training, unless the client meets any of the exemptions of section 519g of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-241; D.C. Official Code 4-205.19g or section 5809.4(b e) of Title 29 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, including any subsequent revisions 7) Respect the safety, personal rights, and private property of provider staff members and other clients 8) Maintain clean sleeping and living areas, including bathroom and cooking areas 9) Use communal areas appropriately, with attention to cleanliness and respect for the interests of other clients 10) Be responsible for one=s own personal property; and (11) Follow all Program Rules established by a provider pursuant to section 18 b) Clients residing in temporary shelter and transitional housing shall participate in the provider=s assessment and case management services. Sec. 12. Common standards for all providers. Providers shall 1) Ensure staff members are appropriately trained, qualified, and supervised 2) Maintain safe, clean, and sanitary facilities that meet all applicable District health, sanitation, fire, building, and zoning codes 3) Assist clients to prepare for living in permanent housing, as deemed appropriate by the provider and the client 4) Collaborate and coordinate with other service providers to meet the client=s needs, as deemed appropriate by the provider and the client 5) Receive and utilize client input and feedback for the purpose of evaluating and improving the provider=s services 6) Establish procedures for the provider=s internal complaint procedures 7) Provide clients with copies of printed information describing the range of services within the Continuum of Care 8) In accordance with section 8(c) and as openings occur, inform all clients of ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 15 services for which they may be eligible 9) Deliver or provide access to culturally competent services and language assistance for clients with limited English proficiency 10) Provide services free from discrimination on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, language, culture, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, familial status, family responsibilities, matriculation, political affiliation, disability, and source of income, and in accordance with the Human Rights Act of 1977, effective December 13, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-38; D.C. Official Code 2-1401 et seq the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, approved July 26, 1990 (104 Stat. 328; 42 U.S.C 12101 et seq the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, approved August 7, 1998 (112 Stat. 1095; 29 U.S.C 701 et seq and Title II of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, approved July 2, 1964 (78 Stat. 243; 42 U.S.C 2000a et seq 11) Provide reasonable modifications to policies, practices, and procedures when the modifications are necessary to avoid discrimination on the basis of disability, unless the provider demonstrates that making the modifications would fundamentally alter the nature of the services 12) Ensure confidential treatment of the personal, social, legal, financial, and medical records and information related to a client or any member of a client=s family, whether obtained from the client or from any other source, consistent with the confidentiality requirements of District and federal law 13) Establish Program Rules in accordance with section 18 14) Provide notice of its Program Rules in accordance with section 19 15) Collect, record, and annually report to the Mayor all complaints, including requests for fair hearings or administrative reviews, made against or related to the provider during the year; and (16) Establish procedures to revise practices and policies as may be necessary to ensure that clients may access services free from discrimination on the basis of disability. Sec. 13. Additional standards for providers of severe weather shelter. In addition to the standards in section 12, providers of severe weather shelter shall provide 1) When severe weather conditions continue overnight, a clean bed with clean linens, pad, and blanket for each bed 2) Basic needs, such as food and clothing and other supportive services, or information about where to obtain such basic needs and supportive services 3) 24-hour, properly functioning toilet facilities 4) Cool water, available via water cooler, fountain, or other means; and (5) Properly functioning heating and cooling systems during the appropriate seasons. Sec. 14. Additional standards for providers of low barrier shelter. In addition to the requirements in sections 12 and 13, providers of low barrier shelter ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 16 shall provide 1) Case management services with an appropriately trained, qualified, and supervised case manager, which shall include the development of a service plan 2) Hot shower facilities; and (3) Personal hygiene supplies. Sec. 15. Additional standards for providers of temporary shelter and supportive housing. In addition to the requirements in sections 12, 13, and 14, providers of temporary shelter and supportive housing shall provide 1) Assessment by an appropriately trained, qualified, and supervised case manager in order to identify each client=s service needs 2) Direct provision of, or referral to, appropriate supportive services to enable the client to fulfill the goals and requirements in the client=s service plan 3) Mail and phone services, or procedures for handling mail and phone messages, that enable the client to receive mail and messages without identifying the client as residing in temporary shelter or supportive housing 4) Private, secure space for the temporary storage of personal belongings 5) Access to laundry facilities in the immediate vicinity of the shelter or supportive housing facility when all of the units are in one location 6) Reasonable access to phones during reasonable hours and during emergencies 7) The opportunity to establish a voluntary savings or escrow account; and (8) In supportive housing and temporary shelters for families, access to immediate indoor or outdoor areas equipped with basic facilities for exercise and play for use by minor children. Sec. 16. Additional standards for providers of transitional housing. In addition to the requirements of sections 12, 13, 14, and 15, all providers of transitional housing shall provide 1) Follow-up supportive services, for a minimum of 6 months, for clients who have transferred to permanent housing from their program, unless the client is receiving such supportive services from another provider 2) An apartment-style or group home housing accommodation; and (3) Access to private space and personal time. Sec. 17. Monitoring and inspections a) The Mayor shall monitor and evaluate the services delivered by all programs covered by section 3 b) The Mayor shall inspect the premises of all providers operating programs covered by section 3. Inspections shall be conducted 1) At least once during each calendar year 2) Whenever the Mayor has reason to believe that a provider is not in ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 17 compliance with the applicable standards established in this act or with other requirements or agreements; and (3) In a reasonable manner and during the regular hours of operation of the provider c) During any inspection conducted pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, the provider shall make available for examination any records or other materials related to the delivery of its services, including records relating to clients and to internal complaints, in accordance with the confidentiality requirements of section 9(7 d) The Mayor shall not delegate the responsibilities of this section to any agency or entity that serves as a provider of services covered by section 3. Sec. 18. Program Rules a) Pursuant to the limitations of subsections (b) and (c) of this section, providers may establish Program Rules related to the specific goals of their programs. The Program Rules shall include 1) Any applicable special eligibility requirements for the purpose of limiting entry into the program to individuals or families exhibiting the specific challenges that the program is designed to address, except in severe weather shelter and low barrier shelter 2) Rules regarding client responsibilities, including those listed in section 11 3) A list of client rights, including those listed in section 9, and where appropriate, section 10 4) A description of the internal complaint procedures established by the provider for the purpose of providing the client with an opportunity to promptly resolve complaints 5) A description of the procedures by which an individual with a disability may request a reasonable modification of policies or practices that have the effect of limiting the right to access services free from discrimination on the basis of disability as established by section 9(2 6) A description of the procedures and notice requirements of any internal mediation program established by the provider pursuant to section 25 7) A description of any schedule of sanctions that a provider may apply to clients who are in violation of the Program Rules, as authorized by sections 20 through 24; and (8) A description of a client=s right to appeal any decision or action by the provider that adversely affects the client's receipt of services through fair hearing proceedings pursuant to section 26 and administrative review proceedings pursuant to section 27 b) Any Program Rules established by a provider shall be submitted to the Mayor for approval in accordance with the following requirements 1) Within 90 days of the effective date of this act 2) On a yearly basis thereafter, with any proposed changes clearly identified; and (3) Whenever a provider seeks approval to change its eligibility criteria, the rules of its internal mediation program or complaint procedures, or its schedule of sanctions. ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 18 (c) No provider may enforce any provision within its Program Rules, other than those requirements or protections specifically enumerated by this act, unless 1) The Program Rules were in existence before the effective date of this act and less than 180 days has passed since the effective date of this act; or (2) The Mayor has approved the Program Rules pursuant to subsection (b) of this section. Sec. 19. Notice a)(1) All providers shall give prompt and effective notice of their Program Rules by A) Posting a copy of their Program Rules on the provider's premises in a location easily accessible to clients and visitors; and (B) Giving every new client written notice of the provider=s Program Rules, and reading and explaining the written notice to the client 2) The client and the provider staff member delivering the notice pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection shall both sign a statement acknowledging the client=s receipt of the notice and indicating the client=s awareness, understanding, and acceptance of the Program Rules b) All providers shall give to any client to whom they have denied services oral and written notice of the right to appeal the denial, including information about how to request a fair hearing pursuant to section 26 and administrative review pursuant to section 27 c) All providers shall give written and oral notice to clients of their transfer to another provider or of their suspension or termination from services at least 15 days prior to the effective date of the transfer, suspension, or termination, except 1) When the sanction results from the client=s imminent threat to the health or safety of someone on the premises of the provider in accordance with section 24; or (2) When the sanction is a suspension of supportive services for a period shorter than 10 days d) Any notice issued pursuant to subsection (b) or (c) of this section must be mailed or served upon the client and shall include 1) A clear statement of the sanction or denial 2) A clear and detailed statement of the factual basis for the sanction or denial, including the date or dates on which the basis or bases for the sanction or denial occurred 3) A reference to the statute, regulation, policy, or Program Rule pursuant to which the sanction or denial is being implemented 4) A clear and complete statement of the client=s right to appeal the sanction or denial through fair hearing proceedings pursuant to section 26 and administrative review proceedings pursuant to section 27, including the appropriate deadlines for instituting the appeal; and (5) A statement of the client=s right, if any, to continuation of benefits pending the outcome of any appeal, pursuant to section 9(18 e) Providers shall establish procedures to provide effective notice of rights, rules, sanctions, and denials to clients with special needs, including those who may be mentally ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 19 impaired or mentally ill, or who may have difficulty reading or have limited English proficiency. Sec. 20. Transfer a) A provider may transfer a client to another provider to ensure the client receives the most appropriate services available within the Continuum of Care whenever 1) The client consents to the transfer; or (2) The provider identifies and secures for the client a placement with another provider that more appropriately meets the client=s medical, mental health, behavioral, or rehabilitative service needs in accordance with the client=s service plan b) In addition to the circumstances under which a client may be transferred as described in subsection (a) of this section, a provider may transfer a client when a client fails or refuses to comply with the provider=s Program Rules and the client responsibilities listed in section 11, or engages in any of the behaviors listed in section 22(2 provided, that 1) The client has received proper notice of the Program Rules, client responsibilities, and prohibited behaviors, as required by section 19; and (2) The provider has made a good-faith effort to enable the client to comply with the Program Rules so that the client is able to continue receiving services without a transfer c) Transfers of clients under this section can be made through direct arrangements with other providers within the Continuum of Care or through coordination with the central intake center established pursuant to section 8(c)(1 Such efforts shall be documented by the provider in the client=s records. Sec. 21. Suspension a) If a client fails or refuses to comply with the provider=s Program Rules and the client responsibilities listed in section 11, or engages in any of the behaviors listed in section 22(2 the provider may suspend services to the client for an appropriate period of time in light of the severity of the act or acts leading to the suspension, but in no case for any period longer then 30 days. The suspension may be implemented only when 1) The client has received proper notice of the Program Rules, client responsibilities, and prohibited behaviors, as required by section 19; and (2) The provider has made a good-faith effort to enable the client to comply with the Program Rules so that the client is able to continue receiving services without suspension b) Prior to suspension of services, the provider shall make a reasonable effort, given the severity of the situation, to transfer the client to another provider within the Continuum of Care, in accordance with section 20 c) A provider may not suspend adult individuals or adult family members in a manner that results in minor children or dependent adults being left unattended in a shelter or supportive housing unit. Sec. 22. Termination. ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 20 A provider may terminate its delivery of services to a client only when 1) The provider documents that it has considered suspending the client in accordance with section 21 or has made a reasonable effort, in light of the severity of the act or acts leading to the termination, to transfer the client in accordance with section 20 2) The client A) Possesses a weapon on the provider=s premises B) Possesses or sells illegal drugs on the provider=s premises C) Assaults or batters any person on the provider=s premises D) Endangers the client=s own safety or the safety of others on the provider=s premises E) Intentionally or maliciously vandalizes, destroys, or steals the property of any person on the provider=s premises F) Fails to accept an offer of appropriate permanent housing or supportive housing that better serves the client=s needs after having been offered 2 appropriate permanent or supportive housing opportunities; or (G) Knowingly engages in repeated violations of a provider=s Program Rules; and (3) In the case of terminations pursuant to subparagraphs (2)(F) and (2)(G) of this section, the provider has made reasonable efforts to help the client overcome obstacles to obtaining permanent housing. Sec. 23. Alternative sanctions a) A provider may employ lesser sanctions as alternatives to the transfer, suspension, or termination of services authorized in sections 20 through 22 b) Any alternative sanction applied shall be authorized in the schedule of sanctions included in the provider=s Program Rules and may include loss of special privileges and imposition of additional responsibilities. Sec. 24. Emergency transfers, suspensions, or terminations a) Whenever a client presents an imminent threat to the health or safety of the client or any other person on a provider's premises, the provider, in light of the severity of the act or acts leading to the imminent threat, may immediately transfer, suspend, or terminate the client, without providing prior written notice of the transfer, suspension, or termination as required by section 19(c b) The provider shall endeavor to provide written notice, consistent with the requirements of section 19(d to any client transferred, suspended, or terminated pursuant to subsection (a) of this section at the time that the action is taken. If it is not possible or safe to provide written notice at the time of the action, a subsequent written notice shall be provided to the client within 15 days, or, if the client=s whereabouts are unknown, upon request within 90 days of the transfer, suspension, or termination. The time period during which the client may request fair hearing proceedings to appeal the transfer, suspension, or termination pursuant to section 26 shall not begin until the client has received the subsequent written notice. ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 21 (c) No client transferred, suspended, or terminated pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall have the right to request mediation of the action from the provider pursuant to section 25 or to continue to receive shelter or supportive housing services without change pending appeal pursuant to section 9(18 d) Whenever a provider transfers, suspends, or terminates a client pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the provider shall immediately notify the Department of the action. The notification shall include the following information 1) The identity of the client who was transferred, suspended, or terminated 2) The nature, date, and time of the action taken by the provider 3) The provider staff member authorizing the transfer, suspension, or termination; and (4) The act or acts leading to the transfer, suspension, or termination e) Whenever the Department receives a notification pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, the Department shall issue a written finding of whether the emergency transfer, suspension, or termination order complies with the requirements of this section. The notification shall be issued within 24 hours of receipt of the notification by the Department. If the Department finds that the order was improperly issued, the Department shall reinstate the client=s access to the services received prior to the issuance of the order, pending the outcome of a hearing pursuant to sections 26 and 27. Sec. 25. Mediation a) Providers are strongly encouraged to establish internal mediation programs to resolve disputes with clients b) Any provider who chooses to establish an internal mediation program shall offer mediation services to any client of the provider, or the client=s representative, who requests them c) Upon receiving an oral or written request for mediation, the provider shall provide the client or the client's representative with reasonable written notice of 1) The time and place of any mediation proceedings; and (2) The client=s right to request a fair hearing for formal review of his or her complaint pursuant to section 26 and his or her right to request administrative review pursuant to section 27 d) The provider shall allow the client or the client=s representative to review its records of the client prior to the mediation proceeding e) The provider shall allow the client to be accompanied by a legal or other representative of the client=s choosing in any mediation proceedings f) Upon conclusion of the mediation proceedings, the provider shall notify the client of his or her right to request a fair hearing pursuant to section 26, and the deadline for making such a request, if he or she is not satisfied with the outcome of the mediation g) No member of the provider=s staff who was involved in the incident or incidents at issue in the mediation shall serve as a mediator during the proceedings. ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 22 Sec. 26. Fair hearings a) The Office of Administrative Hearings shall grant a fair hearing to any client or client representative who wishes to appeal a decision listed in subsection (b) of this section and who requests such a hearing, orally or in writing, within 90 days of receiving written notice of the adverse action. A request for a fair hearing shall be made to the client=s provider, the Department, the Mayor, or the Mayor=s designee. If the request is made orally, the individual receiving the request shall promptly acknowledge the request, reduce it to writing, and file the request for a fair hearing with the Office of Administrative Hearings b) A client or client representative may request a fair hearing to 1) Appeal an administrative review decision made pursuant to section 27 2) Review any decision of a provider of services, other than shelter or supportive housing, to A) Transfer the client to another provider B) Suspend provision of services to the client for a period longer than 10 days; or (C) Terminate services to the client; or (3) Obtain any legally available and practicable remedy for any alleged violation of A) The provider standards listed in sections 12-16; or (B) The client rights listed in sections 9 and 10, including the denial of a request by an individual with a disability for a reasonable accommodation or modification of policies or practices c) The Mayor shall treat a fair hearing request made by a client representative in the same manner as it would be treated if it were made directly by the client; provided, that the Mayor subsequently receives written documentation authorizing the client representative to act on behalf of the client in accordance with the requirements of section 1004 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Official Code 4-210.05 d) In accordance with section 9(18 any client who requests a fair hearing within 15 days of receipt of written notice of a suspension or termination of shelter or supportive housing shall continue to receive shelter or supportive housing pending a final decision from the fair hearing proceedings. This right to continuation of shelter or supportive housing pending appeal shall not apply in the case of an emergency suspension or termination pursuant to section 24 e) Upon receipt of a fair hearing request, the Mayor or the Mayor=s designee shall offer the client or client representative an opportunity for an administrative review by the Department of the decision that is the subject of the fair hearing request f) All fair hearings shall be conducted in the following manner 1) In accordance with the requirements for the review of contested cases as provided in the Administrative Procedure Act 2) In accordance with the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001, effective March 6, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-76; D.C. Official Code 2-1831.01 et seq and (3) In accordance with the following additional requirements: ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 23 (A) The hearing shall be held within a reasonably short time following the request, such time not to exceed 15 days following the initial request for hearing B) If a party fails to appear, the Administrative Law Judge designated to conduct the hearing may enter a default decision in favor of the party present. The default may be set aside only for good cause shown, and upon equitable terms and conditions; and (C) The Administrative Law Judge shall issue a final decision within 15 days of the completion of the hearing g) Materials and documents filed with the Office of Administrative Hearings during fair hearing proceedings shall be maintained in compliance with section 16(d) of the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001, effective March 6, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-76; D.C. Official Code 2-1831.13(d the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, approved August 21, 1996 (Pub. L. No. 104-191; 110 Stat. 1936 and any other District or federal law pertaining to confidentiality of records h) The Mayor or the Mayor=s designee shall maintain a file of final fair hearing and administrative review decisions, indexed by issue, with identifying information redacted. The file shall be accessible to clients, their representatives, and other persons upon request to the Mayor or the Mayor=s designee. Sec. 27. Administrative review a) The purpose of the administrative review shall be to enable the Department to ascertain the legal validity of the decision that is the subject of the fair hearing request, and, if possible, achieve an informal resolution of the appeal b) Any administrative review conducted pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be completed within 15 days of the receipt of the administrative review request, except upon showing of good cause as to why such deadline cannot be met. If good cause is shown, a decision shall be rendered as soon as possible thereafter. If an extension of time for review is required for good cause, written notice of the extension shall be provided to the client or client representative prior to the commencement of the extension c) An administrative review must be completed before the Office of Administrative Hearings shall grant a fair hearing to any client or client representative d) All administrative reviews shall be conducted in the following manner 1) In accordance with the administrative review procedures described in section 1007 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Official Code 4-210.07 and (2) In accordance with the following additional requirements A) The client or client representative shall have the right to submit issues and comments in writing to the Department; and (B) The client or the client representative shall have the right to review provider's records regarding the client, or the records of other related service providers regarding the client, prior to the administrative review proceeding C) The administrative review shall be conducted by an employee of the Department; ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24 (D) The administrative review decision shall be issued in writing, in a manner readily understood by the client, and shall include i) A clear and detailed statement of the factual basis supporting the administrative review decision ii) A clear and detailed statement of the actions proposed to be implemented, including any sanctions, probationary periods, or any denial, transfer, suspension, or termination of services to be imposed iii) A reference to the statute, regulation, Program Rule, or policy pursuant to which the administrative review decision is made iv) Notice that the client=s request for a hearing shall be considered formally withdrawn upon submission of a signed statement confirming such withdrawal; and (v) A statement that if the client is not satisfied with the administrative review decision, the fair hearing shall be held. Sec. 28. No entitlement to services a) No provision of this act shall be construed to create an entitlement (either direct or implied) on the part of any individual or family to any services within the Continuum of Care, other than shelter in severe weather conditions as authorized by section 9(5 b) No provision of this act shall be construed to require the District to expend funds for individuals or families who are eligible for services within the Continuum of Care, beyond the level of the District's annual appropriation for services within the Continuum of Care. Sec. 29. Limitation on use of District monies a) No public funds shall be used for payment of goods or services from any vendor or organization that engages in discriminatory practices b) No District funds shall be used to support the delivery of services that are not authorized by this act or by rules issued pursuant to this act c) All District funds appropriated to fund or support services within the Continuum of Care shall be used in accordance with District contract and procurement regulations and District grant regulations. Sec. 30. Contracting authority. The Mayor may execute contracts, grants, and agreements as necessary to implement the provisions of this act. Sec. 31. Rulemaking authority. The Mayor, pursuant to Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code 2-501 et seq may issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 25 Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved. Sec. 32. Conforming amendments a) Section 603 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Official Code 4-206.03 is repealed b) The District of Columbia Right to Overnight Shelter Initiative of 1984, effective March 14, 1985 (D.C. Law 5-146; D.C. Official Code 4-701 et seq is repealed c) The Frigid Temperature Protection Amendment Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-204; D36 DCR 454 is repealed d) The Emergency Shelter Services for Families Reform Amendment Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 7-86; 35 DCR 140 is repealed e) Section 1 of An Act To establish a District of Columbia Armory Board, and for other purposes, approved June 4, 1948 (62 Stat. 339; D.C. Official Code 3-301 is amended by striking the phrase Asuch other activities as may be in the interest of the District of Columbia,@ and inserting the phrase Asuch other activities as may be in the interest of the District of Columbia, including, but not limited to, the provision of emergency protection when the temperature falls below 32 degrees Fahrenheit,@ in its place. Sec. 33. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statements of the Budget Director and the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 34. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Repeal 4-206.03 Repeal 4-701 4-714 Repeal 3-301 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 26 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code '1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-751.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-752.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-752.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-752.02a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-752.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.01a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8b</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8c</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8d</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8e</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.11"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.12"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.13"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>12</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.21"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>12a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.21a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>13</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.22"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>14</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.23"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>15</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.24"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>16</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.25"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>16a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.25a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>17</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.31"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>18</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.32"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>19</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.33"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>20</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.34"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>21</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.35"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>22</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.36"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>22a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.36a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>23</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.37"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>24</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.38"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>25</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.39"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>26</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.41"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>27</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.42"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>27a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.51"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>27b</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.52"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>27c</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.53"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>27d</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.54"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>27e</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.55"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>27f</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.56"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>28</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-755.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>29</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-755.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>30</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-756.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>31</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-756.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>31a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-756.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>31b</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-756.04"/>
  </section>
</document>
