<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-97">
  <num type="law">16-97</num>
  <heading type="short">Residential Energy Conservation Tax Credit Illegal Dumping Enforcement Amendment Act of 2005</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2006-05-12</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-97.pdf">D.C. Law 16-97</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 1663</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0461">
      <narrative>Law 16-97, the “Residential Energy Conservation Tax Credit Illegal Dumping Enforcement Amendment Act of 2005”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-461 which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on January 4, 2006, and February 7, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 27, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-292 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-97 became effective on May 12, 2006.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 18 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to authorize an income tax credit for homeowners and tenants who purchase or install energy conservation devices for their residences and for new home construction. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Residential Energy Conservation Tax Credit Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. Chapter 18 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents for Chapter 18 is amended by a new section designation “§ 47- 1806.11. Tax on residents and nonresidents – Credits energy conservation credit.” after the section designation “§ 47-1806.10. Income averaging–employment discrimination.” b) Chapter 18 is amended by adding a new section 47-1806.11 to read as follows: “§ 47-1806.11. Tax on residents and nonresidents – Credits – energy conservation credit. “(a) For the purposes of this section, the term: “(1) “Energy conservation expenses” means the cost for the purchase and installation of a device in a taxpayer’s residence intended to reduce energy consumption or the cost of the purchase and installation of an alternative energy source, which device or source has been certified by the United States Department of Energy as meeting or exceeding the established energy efficiency standards. “(2) “High energy efficient” means a device or material in a taxpayer’s residence that meets or exceeds the applicable energy savings requirements developed by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency and the U.S. Department of Energy for the ENERGY STAR program. “(3) “Major home appliance” means a refrigerator, stove, clothes washer, dryer, clothes washer/dryer, dishwasher, microwave, freezer, room air conditioner, humidifier, refrigerator, or ventilating fan. “(b)(1) A taxpayer shall be allowed a credit against the tax imposed by § 47-1806.03 in the following amounts: “(A) Twenty-five percent of the taxpayer’s energy conservation expenses Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2006 Spring Supp. West Group Publisher New § 47-1806.11 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. for double pane thermal storm windows, insulation for exterior and interior doors of a residence, and the caulking and weather-stripping of any windows and doors; “(B) Twenty percent of the taxpayer’s energy conservation expenses for the purchase and installation of high energy efficient water, heating, or cooling system, or insulation for existing hot water heaters, or insulation of existing duct work, or piping in non-heated areas; “(C) Twenty percent of the taxpayer’s energy conservation expenses for the purchase and installation of insulation for floors, walls, and ceilings; “(D) Twenty percent of the taxpayer’s energy conservation expenses for the purchase and installation of high energy efficient major home appliances or for ceiling fans; “(E) Fifteen percent of the taxpayer’s energy conservation expenses for the replacement of energy inefficient lighting fixtures with permanent high energy efficient light fixtures; and “(F) Ten percent of the taxpayer’s energy conservation expenses for the purchase and installation of any programmable or set-back thermostat or lighting switch. “(2) The annual credit claimed under this subsection shall not exceed $500. Any unused credit may be carried over, subject to the $500 annual limit, for 4 years tax years.”. “(c) A taxpayer who purchases a new residence shall be allowed a credit against the tax imposed by § 47-1806.03, not to exceed $2,000, equal to 5% of the purchase price of the residence if the residence is certified by an agency or organization approved by the Office of Tax and Revenue to be 50% or more energy efficient than the 1995 model energy code at closing.”. Sec. 3. Section 2 shall apply as of January 1, 2006. Sec. 4. Inclusion in the budget and financial plan. This act shall take effect subject to the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, Note, § 47-1806.11 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
