<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>36-121</num>
  <heading>Filing and publication of container description.</heading>
  <text>All persons, firms, partnerships, or corporations engaged in the bottling, selling, or distributing of milk or cream in bottles, cans, crates, or other containers within the District of Columbia, on which the name, trademark, or other device designating the owner is branded, blown, cut, carved, embossed, or impressed, may file with the Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia a description of the name or names, marks or devices so used by them, the said description to be a statement under oath by the owner of said name, mark, or device. The said owner of said name, mark, or device shall, after filing the description as above required, cause the same to be published at least once a week for 2 consecutive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation in the District of Columbia. The said owner of said name, mark, or device shall thereafter file with the Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia an affidavit made by himself or any other competent person stating that said description has been published as herein provided, and shall file in the office of the Health Department of the District of Columbia a copy of said registration and said affidavit of publication, both duly certified as true copies by the Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia. The registration of any such name, mark, or device shall be complete on the filing of said certified copies in the Health Office of the District of Columbia, and thereafter the name, mark, or device shall be considered as registered in accordance with this subchapter, and any bottle, can, crate, or other container on which said name, mark, or device shall be or shall be placed shall be considered as registered in accordance with this subchapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 69-1-ch737" path="§1">July 3, 1926, 44 Stat. 809, ch. 737, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-493" type="History">July 5, 1966, 80 Stat. 263, Pub. L. 89-493, § 7</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Labeling of milk containers, see § <cite path="§37-201.14">37-201.14</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Milk, cream, and ice cream, see § <cite path="§48-601">48-601</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 48-201.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 48-201.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Health Department abolished: The Health Department of the District of Columbia, including the office of the head thereof, was abolished and the functions thereof transferred to the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia by Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1952. Reorganization Order No. 57 of the Board of Commissioners, dated June 30, 1953, and Reorganization Order No. 52, dated June 30, 1953, combined and redesignated Organization Order No. 141, dated February 11, 1964, established under the direction and control of a Commissioner, a Department of Public Health headed by a Director, for the purpose of planning, implementing, and directing public health and hospital care programs, and for performing certain other allied medical and para-medical functions. The Anatomical Board was established under the direction and control of the Director of Public Health consisting of members as prescribed in the D. C. Code. Prior to redesignation, the Order abolished the previously existing Health Department, Gallinger Hospital, Glenn Dale Sanatorium, and the Anatomical Board, and transferred their functions and positions to the new Department. The organization of the new Department was set out in the Order. The executive functions of the Board of Commissioners were transferred to the Commissioner of the District of Columbia by § 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967. Functions stated in Organization Order No. 141 were transferred to the Director of the Department of Human Resources by Commissioner’s Order No. 69-96, dated March 7, 1969, as amended by Commissioner’s Order No. 70-83, dated March 6, 1970. The Department of Human Resources was replaced by Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, dated February 21, 1980, which Plan established the Department of Human Services.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
