<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>36-131</num>
  <heading>Injunctive relief.</heading>
  <text>Whenever any person who has registered milk bottles, cans, crates, or other containers as herein provided shall have, upon complaint under oath, prosecuted any other person for violation of the provisions of this subchapter in the use, handling, holding, filling, selling, offering for sale, buying, trafficking in, breaking, or destroying of such registered milk bottles, cans, crates, or other containers and said other persons shall have been convicted on 3 occasions at least for the said unlawful use, handling, holding, filling, selling, offering for sale, buying, trafficking in, breaking, or destroying of said registered milk bottles, cans, crates, or other containers, then the said registrant of said milk bottles, cans, crates, or other containers shall be entitled, upon making complaint to a judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, to have issued an injunction directed to said violator enjoining him from further illegal use, handling, holding, filling, selling, offering for sale, buying, trafficking in, breaking, or destroying of said registered milk bottles, cans, crates, or other containers.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>July 3, 1926, 44 Stat. 811, ch. 737, § 11</annotation>
      <annotation>June 25, 1936, 49 Stat. 1921, ch. 804</annotation>
      <annotation>June 25, 1948, 62 Stat. 991, ch. 646, § 32(a), (b)</annotation>
      <annotation>May 24, 1949, 63 Stat. 107, ch. 139, § 127</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 573, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(c)(54)</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 48-211.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 48-211.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
