<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>36-202</num>
  <heading>Unauthorized use of registered label; injunctive relief.</heading>
  <text>No person shall in any way use or display the label, brand, mark, name, or other character adopted by any such union or association as provided in § <cite path="§36-201">36-201</cite> without the consent or authority of such union or association; or counterfeit or imitate any such label, brand, mark, name, or other character, or knowingly sell, dispose of, keep, or have in his possession with intent to sell or dispose of any goods, wares, merchandise, or other products of labor, upon which any such counterfeit or imitation is attached, affixed, printed, stamped, or impressed, or knowingly sell, dispose of, keep, or have in his possession with intent to sell or dispose of any goods, wares, merchandise, or other products of labor contained in any box, case, can, or package, to which or on which any such counterfeit or imitation is attached, affixed, printed, painted, stamped, or impressed. If copies of such device have been filed, the union or association may maintain an action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to enjoin the manufacture, use, display, or sale of counterfeit or colorable imitations of such device, or of goods bearing the same, or the unauthorized use or display of such device or of goods bearing the same, and the Court may restrain such wrongful manufacture, use, display, or sale, and every unauthorized use or display by others of the genuine devices so registered and filed, if such use or display is not authorized by the owner thereof, and may award to the plaintiff such damages resulting from such wrongful manufacture, use, display, or sale as may be proved, together with the profits derived therefrom.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 72-1-ch47" path="§2">Feb. 18, 1932, 47 Stat. 50, ch. 47, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1936, 49 Stat. 1921, ch. 804</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1948, 62 Stat. 991, ch. 646, § 32(b)</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 24, 1949, 63 Stat. 107, ch. 139, § 127</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 573, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(c)(55)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§36-203">36-203</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 48-402.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 48-402.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
