<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-190">
  <num type="act">25-190</num>
  <num type="bill">25-360</num>
  <heading type="short">Marion Barry Avenue Designation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2023</heading>
  <heading type="long">To designate, on an emergency basis due to congressional review, Good Hope Road, SE, between Anacostia Drive, SE, and Alabama Avenue, SE, as Marion Barry Avenue, SE; to symbolically designate Marion Barry Avenue, SE, between the intersection of Naylor Road, SE, and 25th Street, SE, and Alabama Avenue, SE, as Good Hope Way; and to require the District to reissue certain documents to individuals and entities with new addresses on Marion Barry Avenue, SE.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-07-07</introduced>
    <effective>2023-07-31</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53471/Signed_Act/B25-0360-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=166963">D.C. Act 25-190</citation>
      <citation type="register">70 DCR 10721</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B25-0360">
      <vote date="2023-07-11" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-07-31</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Marion Barry Avenue Designation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2023".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Pursuant to section 401 and notwithstanding section 421 of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-201; D.C. Official Code §§ 9-204.01 and 9-204.21), the Council designates Good Hope Road, SE, between Anacostia Drive, SE, and Alabama Avenue, SE, as depicted in the plat in the committee report for the Marion Barry Avenue Designation Act of 2023, enacted on April 26, 2023 (D.C. Act 25-81; 70 DCR 6321), as "Marion Barry Avenue, SE".</text>
        <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-204.01" action="designation of Good Hope Road, SE, between Anacostia Drive, SE, and Alabama Avenue, SE, as &quot;Marion Barry Avenue, SE&quot;"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Pursuant to section 401 and notwithstanding section 423 of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-201; D.C. Official Code §§ 9-204.01 and 9-204.23), the Council symbolically designates the portion of the newly designated Marion Barry Avenue, SE, between the intersection of Naylor Road, SE, and 25th Street, SE, and Alabama Avenue, SE, as "Good Hope Way".</text>
      <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-204.01" action="designation of Marion Barry Avenue, SE, between the intersection of Naylor Road, SE, and 25th Street, SE, and Alabama Avenue, SE, as &quot;Good Hope Way&quot;"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the District shall reissue at no charge the following documents to any individual or entity having an address on Good Hope Road, SE, as of July 1, 2023, to reflect the designation of Marion Barry Avenue, SE:</text>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Business licenses issued by the Department of Licensing and Consumer Protection;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Professional licenses issued by the Department of Licensing and Consumer Protection;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Driver's licenses and identification cards issued by the Department of Motor Vehicles; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Motor vehicle registrations issued by the Department of Motor Vehicles.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text proof="needed">The Deputy Mayor for Operations and Infrastructure, or other official or agency designated by the Mayor, shall timely notify residents and businesses of the name change and any need to apply for reissue of documents.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of July 1, 2023.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
