<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-202">
  <num type="act">25-202</num>
  <num type="bill">25-381</num>
  <heading type="short">Sexual Harassment Investigation Review Emergency Act of 2023</heading>
  <heading type="long">To require, on an emergency basis, the Inspector General to hire outside counsel for the purposes of reviewing previous investigations of sexual harassment complaints against the former Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development and Chief of Staff to the Mayor and to produce a report of findings within 90 days.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-07-10</introduced>
    <effective>2023-07-31</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53514/Signed_Act/B25-0381-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=166990">D.C. Act 25-202</citation>
      <citation type="register">70 DCR 10756</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B25-0381">
      <vote date="2023-07-11" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2023-07-11" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-07-31</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Sexual Harassment Investigation Review Emergency Act of 2023".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2023 and subject to funding availability, the Inspector General shall hire and direct independent counsel to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Review investigations of complaints of sexual harassment and violations of Mayor's Order 2017-313, effective December 18, 2017, against the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development and Chief of Staff to the Mayor as of January 1, 2023;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Investigate other findings and items outside of the scope of prior investigations pursuant to paragraph (1) of this section, including hiring and promotion practices, workplace culture, and allegations of retaliation against complainants; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Review and make recommendations on sexual harassment complaint and investigation procedures of the District government.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Inspector General shall provide findings and recommendations to the Mayor and Council no later than 90 days after the effective date of this act.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Independent counsel hired by the Inspector General pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall have experience in confidentiality and sexual harassment law, including litigation and mediation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any subsequent formal or informal complaints received related to the individual  investigated pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be investigated by independent counsel under the direction of the Inspector General.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Inspector General may limit expenditures required to meet the requirements of this act to $450,000.</text>
    </para>
    <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง1-546.03" type="Editor's Notes" history="false">
      For a temporary (90 days) requirement that the Inspector General hire and direct independent counsel to review investigations of complaints of sexual harassment and violations of Mayor's Order 2017-313, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-202">D.C. Act 25-202</cite>.
    </codify:annotation>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
