<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-215">
  <num type="act">25-215</num>
  <num type="bill">25-383</num>
  <heading type="short">Walter Reed Development Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 2023</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Walter Reed Development Omnibus Act of 2016 to provide that revenues received from the Developer as Initial Consideration Payments under the Walter Reed Land and Disposition Agreement shall, after October 1, 2023, be deposited into the Walter Reed Reinvestment Fund and issued as a grant to the Developer to pay or reimburse certain costs of job creation and economic development of or related to the Walter Reed Redevelopment Site.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-07-10</introduced>
    <effective>2023-08-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act">D.C. Act 25-215</citation>
      <citation type="register">70 DCR 10929</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0383">
      <vote date="2023-07-11" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-08-02</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Walter Reed Development Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 2023".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 6 of the Walter Reed Development Omnibus Act of 2016, effective May 18, 2016 (D.C. Law 21-119; D.C. Official Code § 2-1227.05), is amended by adding a new subsection (b-1) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1227.05" after="(b)"/> -->
        <num>(b-1)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding subsection (b)(2) of this section and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-328.13">section 1094 of the Grant Administration Act of 2013, effective December 24, 2013 (D.C. Law 20-61; D.C. Official Code § 1-328.13)</code-cite>, funds received from the Developer after October 1, 2023, as an installment of Initial Consideration Payment under the Walter Reed Land and Disposition Agreement shall be deposited into the Fund and issued as a grant to the Developer to pay or reimburse costs it has incurred or will incur for the purposes set forth in subsection (c)(1) of this section.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1227.05"/>
      <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1227.05" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
        <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on October 31, 2023. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1227.05(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
      </codify:insert> -->
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
