<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-338" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">25-338</num>
  <num type="bill">25-596</num>
  <heading type="short">CJCC Data Collection Technical Correction Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2023</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, due to congressional review, the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council for the District of Columbia Establishment Act of 2011 to clarify the requirement that the CJCC report aggregate programmatic data on process and outcomes of programs.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-12-04</introduced>
    <effective>2023-12-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/54382/Signed_Act/B25-0596-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=182491">D.C. Act 25-338</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0596">
      <vote date="2023-12-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-12-21</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "CJCC Data Collection Technical Correction Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2023".</text>
  <section codify:path="§22-4234">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 1505 of the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council for the District of Columbia Establishment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 22-4234), is amended by adding new subsections (b-5) and (b-6) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
      <!-- <codify:insert after="(b-4)" num-value="(b-5)"/> -->
        <num>(b-5)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>By December 1, 2023, and on a quarterly basis thereafter, the CJCC shall submit to the Mayor and the Council and post on its website a report that includes, in accordance with existing law, aggregate data on the following with respect to the criminal justice and juvenile justice systems:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Diversion;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Pretrial supervision;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Detention;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Prosecution;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>Sentencing;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(F)</num>
            <text>Commitment;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(G)</num>
            <text>Incarceration;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(H)</num>
            <text>Probation;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>Parole;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(J)</num>
            <text>Supervised release; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(K)</num>
            <text>Deferred prosecution agreements, deferred sentencing agreements, deferred disposition agreements, and consent decrees.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The CJCC shall include in the report information and context to aid the general public in interpretation of the data.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Prior to submitting and posting the aggregate data, the CJCC shall provide each agency that supplies data at least one week to review and comment on the data presentation and any analysis relevant to the agency. The CJCC shall review the feedback provided by the agencies and determine, in its sole discretion, whether to revise the presentation and analysis accordingly.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
      <!-- <codify:insert after="(b-5)" num-value="(b-6)"/> -->
        <num>(b-6)</num>
        <text>The CJCC shall post the following year-to-date data on its website monthly, beginning with the earliest year for which CJCC is able to obtain historical data:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Arrests for violent crimes committed by juveniles and adults, by offense; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Gun violence and homicide counts and rates citywide and by ward, neighborhood, and police service area.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-4234"/>
    <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-4234" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on March 20, 2024. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-4234(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert> -->
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 5 of the Prioritizing Public Safety Temporary Amendment Act of 2023, enacted on October 5, 2023 (D.C. Act 25-229; 70 DCR 13762), is repealed.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
