<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-423" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">25-423</num>
  <num type="bill">25-725</num>
  <heading type="short">Food Delivery Fees Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Fair Meals Delivery Act of 2022 to modify the requirements of third-party meal delivery platforms.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-03-04</introduced>
    <effective>2024-03-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act">D.C. Act 25-423</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 3515</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0725">
      <vote date="2024-03-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-03-25</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Food Delivery Fees Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section codify:path="§48-652">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 3 of the Fair Meals Delivery Act of 2022, effective March 10, 2023 (D.C. Law 24-292; D.C. Official Code § 48-652), is amended by adding new subsections (e), (f), and (g) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert/>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>A third-party meal delivery platform shall not exclude any restaurant with whom the third-party meal delivery platform has an agreement from the relevant search results of a customer within 4 miles of a restaurant.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <codify:insert/>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>A third-party meal delivery platform shall not reduce the delivery radius of any restaurant below 4 miles, based on the level or percentage of commissions paid.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a third-party meal delivery platform from offering a larger delivery radius for a fee.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <codify:insert/>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>A third-party meal delivery platform shall not reduce the number of food delivery workers available to deliver an online order from a restaurant with whom the third-party meal delivery platform has an agreement based solely on the level or percentage of commissions paid. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a third-party meal delivery platform from offering priority delivery services for a fee.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-652"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-652" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
        *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on June 23, 2024. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-652(Perm)">Past Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § l-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
