<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-512" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">25-512</num>
  <num type="bill">25-856</num>
  <heading type="short">Association Meeting Flexibility Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, due to congressional review, the Condominium Act of 1976 to authorize condominium unit owners' associations to conduct virtual meetings and to clarify voting and quorum requirements for such meetings; and to amend section 29-910 of the District of Columbia Official Code to allow cooperatives to conduct remote meetings.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-06-24</introduced>
    <effective>2024-07-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/55774/Signed_Act/B25-0856-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=195802">D.C. Act 25-512</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0856">
      <vote date="2024-06-25" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-07-18</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Association Meeting Flexibility Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section codify:path="§42-1903.03">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 303 of the Condominium Act of 1976, effective March 29, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-89; D.C. Official Code § 42-1903.03), is amended by adding new a subsection (f) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert/>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding any language contained in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="42|19">this act</code-cite> or in the condominium instruments:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The executive board may authorize unit owners to submit votes by electronic transmission up to 7 days before the scheduled date of any meeting of the unit owners, and unit owners who submit votes during such period shall be deemed to be present and voting in person at such meeting.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Meetings of the unit owners' association, board of directors, or committees may be conducted or attended by telephone conference, video conference, or similar electronic means. If a meeting is conducted by telephone conference, video conference, or similar electronic means, the equipment or system used must permit any unit owner in attendance to hear and be heard by, and to comprehend what is said by, all other unit owners participating in the meeting. Any unit owner, board member, or committee member attending such meeting remotely shall be deemed present for quorum purposes.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>A link or instructions on how to access an electronic meeting shall be included in the notice required under subsection (a) of this section.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Any matters requiring a vote of the unit owners' association at an annual or regular meeting may be set by the executive board for a vote, and a ballot may be delivered with the notice required under subsection (a) of this section. The executive board may set a reasonable deadline for a ballot to be returned to the association.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
     <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.03"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.03" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on October 16, 2024. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.03(Perm)">Prior Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section codify:path="§29-910">
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Section 29-910 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase "If authorized by the articles or bylaws" and inserting the phrase "Regardless of whether remote regular and special meetings of members are authorized by the articles or bylaws" in its place.</heading>
    <codify:find-replace count="1">
      <find>If authorized by the articles or bylaws</find>
      <replace>Regardless of whether remote regular and special meetings of members are authorized by the articles or bylaws</replace>
    </codify:find-replace>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§29-910"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§29-910" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire onOctober 16, 2024. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§29-910(Perm)">Prior Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of July 14, 2024.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
