<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-579" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">25-579</num>
  <num type="bill">25-966</num>
  <heading type="short">Buzzard Point Park and Trails National Park Service Grant Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, due to congressional review, the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002 to authorize the Director to make grants of more than $1 million to the National Park Service for certain projects in the Buzzard Point neighborhood.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-09-30</introduced>
    <effective>2024-10-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56239/Signed_Act/B25-0966-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=199691">D.C. Act 25-579</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0966">
      <vote date="2024-10-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-10-18</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Buzzard Point Park and Trails National Park Service Grant Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section codify:path="§50-921.02|(c)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 3(c) of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective May 21, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-137; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.02(c)), is amended by adding a new paragraph (5) to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="1">
      <para>
      <codify:insert after="(4)" num-value="(5)"/>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Director may issue grants, including grants in excess of $1 million, to the National Park Service for the purpose of planning, designing, constructing, making improvements to, or maintaining parks and trails within the Buzzard Point neighborhood.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.02"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.02" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on January 16, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.02(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § l-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
