<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-503" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">25-503</num>
  <num type="bill">25-854</num>
  <heading type="short">2024 Summer Olympics, Paralympic Games, Art All Night, and Dine All Night Emergency Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, section 25-723 of the District of Columbia Official Code to extend the hours of operation, sale, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages for on-premises retailers, manufacturers holding an on-site sales and consumption permit, and temporary license holders for the 2024 Summer Olympic Games, 2024 Paralympic Games, and the All Night and Dine All Night events, to allow and establish indoor and outdoor entertainment hours for businesses that register with the Alcoholic Beverage and Cannabis Board for the Art All Night and Dine All Night events, and to allow non-alcohol licensees that hold a valid certificate of occupancy to register with the Alcoholic Beverage and Cannabis Board to sell, serve, and permit the consumption of alcoholic beverages during the Art All Night and Dine All Night events.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-06-24</introduced>
    <effective>2024-07-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/55772/Signed_Act/B25-0854-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=195769">D.C. Act 25-503</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 8398</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0854">
      <vote date="2024-06-25" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-07-15</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "2024 Summer Olympics, Paralympic Games, Art All Night, and Dine All Night Emergency Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section codify:path="§25-723">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 25-723 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new subsection (g) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert after="(f)" num-value="(g)"/>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Except as provided in § <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-724">25-724</cite>, a licensee under an on-premises retailer's license, manufacturer's license holding an on-site sales and consumption permit, or a temporary license may during the 2024 Summer Olympic Games, 2024 Paralympic Games, and the Art All Night and Dine All Night events operate 24 hours a day and sell, serve, and allow for the consumption of alcoholic beverages between the hours of 6:00 a.m. and 4:00 a.m. if the licensee:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Registers with the Board prior to extending its hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Pays a registration fee of $100; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Provides written notification, no later than July 25, 2024, to the Board and the Metropolitan Police Department of its extended hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption; except, that written notification may be provided no later than September 26, 2024 for the Art All Night or Dine All Night events.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A non-alcohol licensee that holds a valid certificate of occupancy that has registered with the Department of Small and Local Business Development ("DSLBD") to participate in Art All Night or Dine All Night may also register with the Board pursuant to the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Eligible alcohol and non-alcohol licensees that register with the Board that have also registered with DSLBD to participate in Art All Night or Dine All Night may offer outdoor entertainment until 11 p.m. and indoor entertainment until 2 a.m. during those dates that they are registered to participate.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>The fees collected pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited in the Alcoholic Beverage and Cannabis Administration Fund established by § <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-210">25-210</cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>"Art All Night" means an annual arts festival organized by DSLBD that celebrates visual and performing arts that takes place in all 8 wards occurring on the evenings of September 27, 2024 and September 28, 2024.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Dine All Night" means an all-night dining and culinary event organized by DSLBD that involves qualifying restaurants and food establishments occurring from September 19, 2024 through September 29, 2024.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>"2024 Summer Olympic Games" means the international multisport competition occurring from July 26, 2024 through August 11, 2024.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>"2024 Paralympic Games" means the international multisport competition occurring from August 28, 2024 through September 8, 2024.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>This subsection shall expire on September 30, 2024.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-723"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-723" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on October 13, 2024. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-723(Perm)">Past Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
