<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-634" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">25-634</num>
  <num type="bill">25-1022</num>
  <heading type="short">Review of Agency Action Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act to codify agency deference and clarify that a reviewing court or tribunal shall defer to an agency's reasonable interpretation of a statute or regulation it administers so long as that interpretation is not plainly wrong or inconsistent with the statutory or regulatory language or the legislature's intent.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-11-08</introduced>
    <effective>2024-11-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56522/Signed_Act/B25-1022-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=201722">D.C. Act 25-634</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 14466</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-1022">
      <vote date="2024-11-12" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-11-22</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Review of Agency Action Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section codify:path="§2-510">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 110 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1209; D.C. Official Code § 2-510), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="(a)|(1)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a)(1) is amended by striking the phrase "So far as necessary" and inserting the phrase "Subject to subsections (c) and (d) of this section and so far as necessary" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>So far as necessary</find>
        <replace>Subject to subsections (c) and (d) of this section and so far as necessary</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>New subsections (c) and (d) are added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(b)" num-value="(c)"/>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>In reviewing an order or decision of the Mayor or an agency in any court or administrative proceeding, including but not limited to proceedings under subsection (a) of this section, the reviewing tribunal shall defer to the Mayor's or agency's reasonable interpretation of a statute or regulation it administers; provided, that the interpretation is not plainly wrong, or inconsistent with the statutory or regulatory language or the legislature's intent.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(c)" num-value="(d)"/>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>In reviewing a rule adopted by the Mayor or an agency, the reviewing tribunal shall defer to the Mayor's or agency's reasonable interpretation of a statute it administers, provided that the interpretation is not plainly wrong or inconsistent with the statutory language or the legislature's intent.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-510"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-510" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 20, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-510(Perm)">Past Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
