<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-640">
  <num type="act">25-640</num>
  <num type="bill">25-1013</num>
  <heading type="short">Residential Tranquility Temporary Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Residential Tranquility Act of 2010 to prohibit persons targeting a residence for purposes of a demonstration from using sound amplifying devices in a residential zone between 7:00 p.m. and 9:00 a.m., and to prohibit a person from launching or throwing a projectile onto the residential property of another with the intent to cause fear, intimidate, or retaliate against any person living or working at that residence; and to amend the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 to provide that the term expiration date for a Council appointment to the Corrections Information Council shall be December 7th of the year in which the term expires.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-10-28</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2025-05-08</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56452/Signed_Act/B25-1013-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=201707">D.C. Act 25-640</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 14480</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-1013">
      <vote date="2024-10-29" reading="Final"/>
      <vote date="2024-11-12" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-11-22</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Residential Tranquility Temporary Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Residential Tranquility Act of 2010, effective May 26, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-374; D.C. Official Code § 22-2751 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 22-2751) is amended by adding a new paragraph (4) to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>"Sound amplifying device" means any machine, device, or loudspeaker that amplifies sound of the human voice, music, or any other sound. The term "sound amplifying device" shall not include automobile audio systems when used and heard only by the occupants of the vehicle in which the automobile audio system is installed, personal hearing aids, or headphones.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 3 (D.C. Official Code § 22-2752) is amended by adding new subsections (a-1) and (a-2) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(a-1)</num>
          <text>It is unlawful for a person to use a sound amplifying device to target a residence for purposes of a demonstration between 7:00 p.m. and 9:00 a.m. in Residential Zones, Residential Flat Zones, or Residential Apartment Zones, as those terms are defined in the District of Columbia Zoning Regulations.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(a-2)</num>
          <text>It is unlawful to continue or resume targeting a residence in violation of this law after being instructed by a law enforcement officer to cease targeting a residence in violation of this law.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new section 3a is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <num>3a</num>
          <heading proof="needed">Throwing projectiles at residential property.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>It is unlawful for any person to launch or throw a projectile onto the residential property of another with the intent to cause fear, intimidate, or retaliate against any person living or working at that residence.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>A person who violates this section, upon conviction, shall be fined no more than the amount set forth in section 101 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012, effective June 11, 2013 (D.C. Law 19-317; D.C. Official Code § 22-3571.01), or incarcerated for no more than 90 days, or both.</text>
          </para>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 11201a(b)(2) of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, effective October 2, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-233; D.C. Official Code § 24-101.01(b)(2)), is amended by adding a new subparagraph (B-1) to read as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(B-1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the term expiration date for a Council appointment to the Corrections Information Council shall be December 7th of the year in which the term expires.</text>
    </para>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 60-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(2)).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
