<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-624">
  <num type="act">25-624</num>
  <num type="bill">25-987</num>
  <heading type="short">CRIAC Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Public Works Act of 1954 to clarify that an owner or occupant of property in the District shall pay an impervious area charge that the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority d/b/a DC Water ("DC Water") assesses; and to amend the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996 to clarify that DC Water may assess an impervious area charge on any property in the District.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-09-30</introduced>
    <effective>2024-11-13</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56281/Signed_Act/B25-0987-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=201194">D.C. Act 25-624</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0987">
      <vote date="2024-10-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2024-10-15" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-11-13</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "CRIAC Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Public Works Act of 1954, approved May 18, 1954 (68 Stat. 104; D.C. Official Code § 34-2101 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 207 (D.C. Official Code § 34-2107) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a)(1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>A billing methodology that takes into account both the water consumption of, and water service to, a property where water is supplied from the District water supply system.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (c) is repealed.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 208 (D.C. Official Code § 34-2108) is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>The owner or occupant of each property in the District shall pay any impervious area charge that the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority establishes pursuant to section 216(c-1) of the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996, effective April 18, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-111; D.C. Official Code § 34-2202.16(c-1)).</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 216 of the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996, effective April 18, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-111; D.C. Official Code § 34-2202.16), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A new subsection (c-1) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(c-1)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>The Authority shall assess an impervious area charge on any property in the District based on a billing methodology that takes into account the amount of impervious surface on a property that either prevents or retards the entry of water into the ground as occurring under natural conditions, or that causes water to run off the surface in greater quantities or at an increased rate of flow, relative to the flow present under natural conditions.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term "surface" includes rooftops, footprints of patios, driveways, private streets, other paved areas, athletic courts and swimming pools, and any path or walkway that is covered by impervious material.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The impervious area charge shall be the obligation of the property owner. Failure to pay the impervious area charge shall result in a lien being placed upon the property without further notice to the owner. The Mayor may enforce the lien in the same manner as in section 104 of the District of Columbia Public Works Act of 1954, approved May 18, 1954 (68 Stat. 102; D.C. Official Code § 34-2407.02).</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Any owner or occupant of a property that is assessed an impervious area charge may contest an impervious area charge bill according to the same procedures provided to owners or occupants of properties that receive water and sewer service, under section 1805 of the District of Columbia Public Works Act of 1954, approved June 13, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-136; D.C. Official Code § 34-2305).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (e) is amended by striking the phrase "including the" and inserting the phrase "including the impervious area charge and the" in its place.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of March 25, 2009.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved</text>
      <text>December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)),.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
