<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-679" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">25-679</num>
  <num type="bill">25-1054</num>
  <heading type="short">DC Circulator Transition Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, due to congressional review, section 47-362 of the District of Columbia Official Code to require that the Mayor submit all reprogramming requests related to the DC Circulator to the Council for prior approval; and to amend the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002 to require that money from the sale, lease, or transfer of DC Circulator assets be deposited in the DC Circulator Fund and expended to support DC Circulator workers, and to require that the District Department of Transportation coordinate with the Washington Metropolitan  Area Transit Authority to determine the feasibility of assuming control of the DC Circulator, providing alternative or additional bus service, or hiring former DC Circulator workers at their current pay and seniority status.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-12-02</introduced>
    <effective>2025-01-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56648/Signed_Act/B25-1054-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=203466">D.C. Act 25-679</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 25</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-1054">
      <vote date="2024-12-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-01-03</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "DC Circulator Transition Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section codify:path="§47-362">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 47-362 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new subsection (j) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <!-- <codify:insert after="(i)" num-value="(j)"/> -->
        <num>(j)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-361|(14)">§ 47-361(14)</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-363|(a)">§ 47-363(a)</cite> shall apply to any reprogramming request, regardless of dollar value, related to the DC Circulator, as described in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|9A|II">Title III of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective March 5, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-225; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.31 et seq.)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-362"/>
    <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-362" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on April 3, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-362(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert> -->
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Title III of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective March 6, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-225; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.31 et seq.), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 11c (D.C. Official Code § 50-921.33) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section codify:path="§50-921.33">
          <!-- <codify:replace/> -->
          <num codify:value="50-921.33">11c</num>
          <heading proof="needed">DC Circulator Fund establishment.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>There is established as a special fund the DC Circulator Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the District Department of Transportation ("DDOT") in accordance with subsections (c), (d), and (e) of this section.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>All special purpose funds collected from the following sources shall be deposited into the Fund:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>All revenue collected pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.32">section 11b</code-cite> by the District, WMATA, or their agents;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Parking meter revenue from the National Park Service for meters on the Mall;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>All monetary gifts intended to be used to assist in the funding of the DC Circulator; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>All money derived from the sale, lease, or transfer of any property, real or personal, related to the DC Circulator, including any vehicles or equipment.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, money in the Fund shall be used for the following purposes:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>For DDOT to pay for goods, services, property; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Any other authorized purpose.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Money in the Fund deposited pursuant to subsection (b)(4) of this section shall be used to support any workers, contractors, or employees of the DC Circulator or of Department staff associated with the DC Circulator, including the payment of wages, bonuses, severance pay, or workforce development, and administrative costs borne by DDOT in providing this support; except, that expenditures for administrative costs may not exceed 10% of the deposits under this paragraph.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>During any period of time in which a contract with WMATA is in effect, money from the payment of fares, the purchase of tickets, and the sale of advertising space by third parties may be, with the written consent of the Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia and pursuant to the terms of the contract, deposited in a WMATA interest bearing account for the benefit of the District of Columbia and used by WMATA to offset its costs of contract performance, but only to the extent that Congress has appropriated funds to the District to perform or procure those services; provided, that for a period of 8 months following March 2, 2010, no DC Circulator route shall replace more than 20% of the revenue miles or revenue hours of any WMATA route.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(e)</num>
            <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
          </para>
          <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.33"/>
          <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.33" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
            <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on April 3, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.33(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
          </codify:insert> -->
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§50-921.36">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 11f (D.C. Official Code § 50-921.36) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <!-- <codify:replace path="§50-921.36"/> -->
          <num codify:value="50-921.36">11f</num>
          <heading proof="needed">Coordination with WMATA regarding DC Circulator termination.</heading>
          <para>
            <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
            <text>The District Department of Transportation shall coordinate with WMATA to determine the feasibility of WMATA:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Assuming control and management of the DC Circulator, maintaining the DC Circulator workforce, and continuing DC Circulator service;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Providing alternative Metrobus routes or additional Metrobus service for riders impacted by planned termination of the DC Circulator; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Hiring former DC Circulator workers while preserving their rate of pay and seniority.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.36"/>
          <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.36" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
            <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on April 3, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.36(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
          </codify:insert> -->
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
