<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 25-605" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">25-605</num>
  <num type="bill">25-984</num>
  <heading type="short">Hotel Enhanced Cleaning and Notice of Service Disruption Emergency Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, An Act to revise certain laws relating to the liability of hotels, motels, and similar establishments in the District of Columbia to their guests to authorize the Mayor to issue rules to establish requirements for cleaning and maintenance of hotels and motel rooms, with the exception of certain establishments operating on an "extended stay" model, and to establish standards for public notice of lodging establishment service disruptions.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-09-30</introduced>
    <effective>2024-10-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56277/Signed_Act/B25-0984-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=200357">D.C. Act 25-605</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0984">
      <vote date="2024-10-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-10-24</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Hotel Enhanced Cleaning and Notice of Service Disruption Emergency Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section codify:path="30|1">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>An Act to revise certain laws relating to the liability of hotels, motels, and similar establishments in the District of Columbia to their guests, approved December 8, 1970 (84 Stat. 1395; D.C. Official Code § 30-101 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended by adding a new section 3a to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <codify:insert after="§30-103" num-value="30-104" history-prefix="as added"/>
        <num>3a</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Cleaning and maintenance of hotels and motels and public notice of service disruptions.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|I">Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>, may issue rules to establish requirements for the cleaning and maintenance of hotels, motels, and other lodging establishments (collectively "lodging establishments") and to establish standards for public notice of actual or potential disruptions to service at, or use or enjoyment of, lodging establishments.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>A lodging establishment providing guest rooms that contain a kitchen, defined as a cooking facility that includes a permanently affixed cooktop appliance consisting of two or more burners, with or without an oven, with a power supply served by either an electrical connection or a natural gas line, shall not be required to clean those guest rooms on a daily basis, unless specifically requested by a guest.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Civil fines and penalties may be imposed by the Mayor pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|18">the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Official Code § 2-1801.01 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite> ("Civil Infractions Act"), for infraction of the rules.  The adjudication of any such infraction, fine, or penalty shall be pursuant to the Civil Infractions Act.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <annotation type="History" doc="84 Stat. 1395" path="§3a">Dec. 8, 1970, 84 Stat. 1395, Pub. L. 91-537, § 3a</annotation>
    <codify:temporary-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§30-104" interim-path="§30-103" perm-eff="2024-10-24"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§30-104" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on January 22, 2025.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Applicability</text>
    <text>This act shall apply as of the expiration date of the Hotel Enhanced Cleaning and Notice of Service Disruption Second Temporary Amendment Act of 2023, effective March 1, 2024 (D.C. Law 25-129; 71 DCR 857).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
