<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-174">
  <num type="act">24-174</num>
  <num type="bill">24-276</num>
  <heading type="short">Fiscal Year 2022 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To adopt, as a request to Congress for appropriation and authorization, the federal portion of the budget of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2022.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-05-27</introduced>
    <effective>2021-09-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/47280/Signed_Act/B24-0276-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-174</citation>
      <citation type="register">68 DCR 009726</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0276">
      <vote date="2021-08-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2021-09-13</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Fiscal Year 2022 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Adoption of the federal portion of the Fiscal Year 2022 budget.</heading>
    <text>There is adopted, as a request to Congress for appropriation and authorization, the following federal portion of the budget of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2022.</text>
    <container name="district-of-columbia-federal-funds-appropriation-request-federal-payment-to-the-district-of-columbia-courts">
      <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA FEDERAL FUNDS APPROPRIATION REQUEST Federal Payment to the District of Columbia Courts</heading>
      <text>For salaries and expenses for the District of Columbia Courts, $357,804,000 to be allocated as follows: for the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, $14,910,000, of which not to exceed $2,500 is for official reception and representation expenses; for the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, $137,050,000, of which not to exceed $2,500 is for official reception and representation expenses; for the District of Columbia Court System, $85,614,000, of which not to exceed $2,500 is for official reception and representation expenses; and $120,230,000, to remain available until September 30, 2023, for capital improvements for District of Columbia courthouse facilities; Provided, That funds made available for capital improvements shall be expended consistent with the District of Columbia Courts master plan study and facilities condition assessment; Provided further, That, in addition to the amounts appropriated herein, fees received by the District of Columbia Courts for administering bar examinations and processing District of Columbia bar admissions may be retained and credited to this appropriation, to remain available until expended, for salaries and expenses associated with such activities, notwithstanding section 450 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (section 1-204.50, D.C. Official Code); Provided further, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, all amounts under this heading shall be apportioned quarterly by the Office of Management and Budget and obligated and expended in the same manner as funds appropriated for salaries and expenses of Federal agencies; Provided further, That 30 days after providing written notice to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the District of Columbia Courts may reallocate not more than $9,000,000 of the funds provided under this heading among the items and entities funded under this heading; Provided further, That the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration in the District of Columbia may, by regulation, establish a program substantially similar to the program set forth in subchapter II of chapter 35 of title 5, United States Code, for employees of the District of Columbia Courts.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="federal-payment-for-defender-services-in-district-of-columbia-courts">
      <heading>Federal Payment for Defender Services in District of Columbia Courts</heading>
      <text>For payments authorized under section 11-2604 and section 11-2605, D.C. Official Code (relating to representation provided under the District of Columbia Criminal Justice Act), payments for counsel appointed in proceedings in the Family Court of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia under chapter 23 of title 16, D.C. Official Code, or pursuant to contractual agreements to provide guardian ad litem representation, training, technical assistance, and such other services as are necessary to improve the quality of guardian ad litem representation, payments for counsel appointed in adoption proceedings under chapter 3 of title 16, D.C . Official Code, and payments authorized under section 21-2060, D.C. Official Code (relating to services provided under the District of Columbia Guardianship, Protective Proceedings, and Durable Power of Attorney Act of 1986), $46,005,000, to remain available until expended; Provided, That funds provided under this heading shall be administered by the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration in the District of Columbia; Provided further, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, this appropriation shall be apportioned quarterly by the Office of Management and Budget and obligated and expended in the same manner as funds appropriated for expenses of Federal agencies.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="federal-payment-for-resident-tuition-support">
      <heading>Federal Payment for Resident Tuition Support</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia, to be deposited into a dedicated account, for a nationwide program to be administered by the Mayor, for District of Columbia resident tuition support, $40,000,000, to remain available until expended; Provided, That such funds, including any interest accrued thereon, may be used on behalf of eligible District of Columbia residents to pay an amount based upon the difference between in-State and out­of-State tuition at public institutions of higher education, or to pay up to $2,500 each year at eligible private institutions of higher education; Provided further, That the awarding of such funds may be prioritized on the basis of a resident's academic merit, the income and need of eligible students, and such other factors as may be authorized; Provided further, That the District of Columbia government shall maintain a dedicated account for the Resident Tuition Support Program that shall consist of the Federal funds appropriated to the Program in this Act and any subsequent appropriations, any unobligated balances from prior fiscal years, and any interest earned in this or any fiscal year; Provided further, That the account shall be under the control of the District of Columbia Chief Financial Officer, who shall use those funds solely for the purposes of carrying out the Resident Tuition Support Program; Provided further, That the Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall provide a quarterly financial report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate for these funds showing, by object class, the expenditures made, and the purpose therefor.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="federal-payment-for-school-improvement">
      <heading>Federal Payment for School Improvement</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment for a school improvement program in the District of Columbia, $52,500,000, to remain available until expended, for payments authorized under the Scholarship for Opportunity and Results Act (division C of Public Law 112-10), as amended; Provided, That, to the extent that funds are available for opportunity scholarships and following the priorities included in section 3006 of such Act, the Secretary of Education shall make scholarships available to students eligible under section 3013(3) of such Act, including students who were not offered a scholarship during any previous school year; Provided further, That within funds provided for opportunity scholarships up to $1,200,000 shall be for the activities specified in sections 3007(b) through 3007(d) of the Act and up to $500,000 shall be for the activities specified in section 3009 of the Act; Provided further, That none of the funds made available under this heading may be used for an opportunity scholarship for a student to attend a school which does not certify to the Secretary of Education that the student will be provided with the same protections under the Federal laws which are enforced by the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education which are provided to a student of a public elementary or secondary school in the District of Columbia and which does not certify to the Secretary of Education that the student and the student's parents will be provided with the same services, rights, and protections under the Individuals With Disabilities Education Act (20 U.S.C. 1400 <em>et seq</em>.) which are provided to a student and a student's parents of a public elementary or secondary school in the District of Columbia, as enumerated in Table 2 of Government Accountability Office Report 18-94 (entitled "Federal Actions Needed to Ensure Parents Are Notified About Changes in Rights for Students with Disabilities"), issued November 2017.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="federal-payment-to-the-criminal-justice-coordinating-council">
      <heading>Federal Payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, $2,150,000, to remain available until expended, to support initiatives related to the coordination of Federal and local criminal justice resources in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="federal-payment-for-judicial-commissions">
      <heading>Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment, to remain available until September 30, 2023, to the Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure, $330,000, and for the Judicial Nomination Commission,</text>
      <text>$300,000.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="federal-payment-for-the-district-of-columbia-national-guard">
      <heading>Federal Payment for the District of Columbia National Guard</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia National Guard, $600,000, to remain available until expended for the Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Program.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="federal-payment-for-testing-and-treatment-of-hivaids">
      <heading>Federal Payment for Testing and Treatment Of HIV/AIDS</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia for the testing of individuals for, and the treatment of individuals with, human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immunodeficiency syndrome in the District of Columbia, $5,000,000.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="federal-payment-for-emergency-planning-and-security-costs-in-the-district-of-columbia">
      <heading>Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment of necessary expenses, as determined by the Mayor of the District of Columbia in written consultation with the elected county or city officials of surrounding jurisdictions, $25,000,000, to remain available until expended, for the costs of providing public safety at events related to the presence of the National Capital in the District of Columbia, including support requested by the Director of the United States Secret Service in carrying out protective duties under the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for the costs of providing support to respond to immediate and specific terrorist threats or attacks in the District of Columbia or surrounding jurisdictions.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="federal-payment-to-the-district-of-columbia-water-and-sewer-authority">
      <heading>Federal Payment to the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, $8,000,000, to remain available until expended, to continue implementation of the Combined Sewer Overflow Long-Term Control Plan; Provided, that the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority provides a 100 percent match for this payment.</text>
    </container>
    <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.46" type="Budget Legislation" history="false">
            For adoption, as a request to Congress for appropriation and authorization, of the federal portion of the budget of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2022, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-174">the Fiscal Year 2022 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2021, D.C. Act 24-174; July 13, 2022, 68 DCR 9726</cite>). 
          </codify:annotation>
  </section>
  <section>
     <codify:marginalia display="Congressional action needed for codification"/>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Compensation of the Chief Financial Officer.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 424(b)(2)(E) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 142; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.24b(b)(5)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="2">
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>PAY.—The Chief Financial Officer shall be paid at the greater of:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>A rate such that the total amount of compensation paid during any calendar year is equal to the limit on total pay which is applicable during the year under section 5307 of title 5, United States Code, to an employee described in section 5307(d) of such title; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>A rate established in law by the District of Columbia; provided, that any rate established pursuant to this clause which is applicable to any individual serving as the Chief Financial Officer shall not be reduced during any period of that individual's service as Chief Financial Officer.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
     <codify:marginalia display="Congressional action needed for codification"/>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Contingency cash.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No funds in excess of $500,000 shall be obligated or expended from the Contingency Cash Reserve Fund established by section 450A(b) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved November 22, 2000 (114 Stat. 2440; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.50a(b)), unless such expenditures have been approved by the Council by resolution.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Contingency Cash Reserve Transparency Amendment Act of 2008, enacted on January 29, 2008 (D.C. Act 17-278; 55 DCR 1530), is enacted into law.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
     <codify:marginalia display="Congressional action needed for codification"/>
    <num>5</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other law, the following sales shall be subject to the sales and use taxes of the District of Columbia:</text>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Sales at gift shops, souvenir shops, kiosks, convenience stores, food shops, cafeterias, restaurants, and similar establishments in federal buildings, including memorials and museums, in the District of Columbia that make sales to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>The general public, if operated by the federal government, an agent of the federal government, or a contractor; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Other than the general public, if operated by an agent of the federal government or a contractor; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Sales of goods and services by a government-sponsored enterprise or corporation, institution, or organization established by federal statute or regulation ("federal enterprise or organization"), including the Smithsonian Institution, National Gallery of Art, National Building Museum, Federal National Mortgage Association, and Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, if the federal enterprise or organization is otherwise exempt from such taxation, to the extent such sales otherwise would be subject to the sales and use taxes of the District of Columbia if the federal enterprise or organization were organized as a nonprofit corporation established pursuant to Chapter 4 of Title 29 of the District of Columbia Official Code, and exempt from federal income taxation pursuant to section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, approved August 16, 1954 (68A Stat. 163; 26 U.S.C. § 501(c)(3)).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Federal portion of the budget.</heading>
    <text>The federal funds for which appropriation by Congress is requested by this act constitute the federal portion of the Fiscal Year 2022 annual budget for the District of Columbia government under section 446(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 801; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.46(a)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § l-30l.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect as provided in section 446 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 801; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.46).</text>
  </section>
</document>