<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-193">
  <num type="bill">24-391</num>
  <num type="act">24-193</num>
  <heading type="short">Office of Administrative Hearings Unemployment Appeals Extension Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, due to congressional review, section 812 of the Coronavirus Support Temporary Amendment Act of 2021 to extend the tolling of time period to request a hearing from the Office of Administrative Appeals for unemployment compensation appeals.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-10-04</introduced>
    <effective>2021-11-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/47906/Signed_Act/B24-0391-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-193</citation>
      <citation type="register">68 DCR 011599</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0391">
      <vote date="2021-10-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2021-11-01</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Office of Administrative Hearings Unemployment Appeals Extension Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 812 of the Coronavirus Support Temporary Amendment Act of 2021  effective June 24, 2021 (D.C. Law 24-9; 68 DCR 4824), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1831.01"/>
        <num codify:value="2-1831.01">812</num>
        <heading>Administrative hearings deadlines.</heading>
        <text>Notwithstanding any provision of District law, but subject to applicable federal laws and regulations, the time period to request an administrative hearing for an appeal of a determination of benefits eligibility for unemployment compensation pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§51-111|(b)">section 11(b) of An Act to provide for unemployment compensation in the District of Columbia, authorize appropriations, and for other purposes, approved August 28, 1935 (49 Stat 951; D.C. Official Code § 51-111(b)),</code-cite> shall be tolled.</text>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1831.01"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1831.01" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments to temporary legislation by emergency legislation that will expire on January 21, 2022. To view the text of the temporary legislation that created this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-9">Temporary Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of October 23, 2021.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
