<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-203">
  <num type="bill">24-414</num>
  <num type="act">24-203</num>
  <heading type="short">Public Service Commission Member Qualifications Emergency Amendment Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and fourteen and for other purposes to set qualifications for members of the Public Service Commission.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-10-04</introduced>
    <effective>2021-11-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/47952/Signed_Act/B24-0414-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-203</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0414">
      <vote date="2021-10-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2021-11-01</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public Service Commission Member Qualifications Emergency Amendment Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Paragraph 97(a) of Section 8 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and fourteen and for other purposes, approved March 4, 1913 (37 Stat. 995; D.C. Official Code § 34-801), is amended by striking the phrase "1978." and inserting the phrase "1978. Of the 3 members of the Commission, for members nominated after October 1, 2021, one member shall have experience in electric grid modernization and renewable energy integration or technology and, where possible, issues impacting the environment, and one member shall have experience in consumer protection. The first member nominated after October 1, 2021, shall be the member with experience in electric grid modernization and renewable energy integration or technology, and the second member nominated after October 1, 2021, shall be the member with experience in consumer protection." in its place.</text>
    <codify:find-replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-801" count="1">
      <find>1978.</find>
      <replace>1978. Of the 3 members of the Commission, for members nominated after October 1, 2021, one member shall have experience in electric grid modernization and renewable energy integration or technology and, where possible, issues impacting the environment, and one member shall have experience in consumer protection. The first member nominated after October 1, 2021, shall be the member with experience in electric grid modernization and renewable energy integration or technology, and the second member nominated after October 1, 2021, shall be the member with experience in consumer protection.</replace>
    </codify:find-replace>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-801"/>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-801" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
        <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on December 30,2021. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-801(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
      </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of October 1, 2021.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
