<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-248">
  <num type="act">24-248</num>
  <num type="bill">24-532</num>
  <heading type="short">Streatery Program Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend section 25-113 of the District of Columbia Official Code, on an emergency basis, to extend the expiration date of the District of Columbia Streatery Program, and provide clarity to Alcoholic Beverage Control Board license holders and the public with regard to the requirements for operating under the Streatery Program.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-12-06</introduced>
    <effective>2021-12-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/48349/Signed_Act/B24-0532-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-248</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0532">
      <vote date="2021-12-07" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2021-12-22</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Streatery Program Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 25-113(a)(6) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="1">
      <para>
        <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-113|(a)|(6)"/>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>An on-premises retailer's licensee, class C/R, D/R, C/T, D/T, C/H, D/H, C/N, D/N, C/X, or D/X, including a multipurpose facility or private club, or a manufacturer's licensee, class A or B, with an on-site sales and consumption permit, or a Convention Center food and alcohol business may register with the Board at no cost to sell, serve, and permit the consumption of beer, wine, or spirits on new or expanded temporary ground floor or street level outdoor public or private space not listed on its existing license.  Upon registration, Board approval shall not be required; provided, that the licensee:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Registers with the Board and receives written authorization from ABRA prior to selling, serving, or permitting the consumption of beer, wine, or spirits on the proposed outdoor public or private space;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Registers with District Department of Transportation ("DDOT") prior to operating on any proposed outdoor public space or receives written approval from the property owner prior to utilizing any proposed outdoor private space; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Agrees to follow all applicable District laws, regulations, guidance documents, administrative orders, including Mayor's Orders, and permit requirements or conditions, which may contain requirements that supersede provisions contained in this section.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>An on-premises retailer's license [licensee], class C/R, D/R, C/T, D/T, C/H, D/H, C/N, D/N, C/X, or D/X, or a manufacturer's license [licensee], class A or B, with an on-site sales and consumption permit, or a Convention Center food and alcohol business that has registered with the Board to sell, serve, and permit the consumption of beer, wine, and spirits to seated patrons on outdoor public or private space not listed on its existing license in accordance with subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Ensure that the proposed outdoor public or private space is located in a commercial or mixed-use zone as defined in the District's zoning regulations;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Restrict the sale, service, or the consumption of alcoholic beverages outdoors for on-premises consumption to the hours between 6:00 a.m. and midnight, Sunday through Saturday;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Not provide live music or entertainment, except for background or recorded music played at a conversational level that is not heard in the homes of District residents;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>Abide by the terms of their public space permit with regard to the allowable placement of alcohol advertising, if any, in outdoor public space; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(v)</num>
            <text>Have its own clearly delineated outdoor space and not share tables and chairs with another business.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Registration under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall be valid until April 30, 2022.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>The Board may fine, suspend, or revoke an on-premises retailer's licensee, class C/R, D/R, C/T, D/T, C/H, D/H, C/N, D/N, C/X, or D/X, or a manufacturer's licensee, class A or B, with an on-site sales and consumption permit, and shall revoke the registration to sell, serve, or permit the consumption of beer, wine, or spirits on outdoor public or private space not listed on the license, if the licensee fails to comply with subparagraph (A) or (B) of this paragraph.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the Board shall interpret settlement agreement language that restricts sidewalk cafés or summer gardens as applying only to those outdoor spaces that are currently licensed by the Board as sidewalk cafés or summer gardens.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>The Board shall not interpret settlement agreement language that restricts or prohibits sidewalk cafés or summer gardens to apply to new or extended outdoor space, the use of which is now permitted under this paragraph.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>The Board shall not interpret settlement agreement language that restricts or prohibits the operation of permanent outdoor space to mean prohibiting the temporary operation of sidewalk cafés or summer gardens.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>The Board shall require all on-premises retailer licenses [licensees], class C/R, D/R, C/T, D/T, C/H, D/H, C/N, D/N, C/X, or D/X, or manufacturer licenses [licensees], class A or B, with an on-site sales and consumption permit, to delineate or mark currently licensed outdoor space from new or extended outdoor space authorized by the DDOT or the property owner.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(v)</num>
            <text>With regard to existing outdoor public or private space, parties to a settlement agreement shall be permitted to waive provisions of settlement agreements that address currently licensed outdoor space for a period not to exceed 180 days.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(F)</num>
          <text>For purposes of this paragraph, ground floor or street level sidewalk cafés or summer gardens enclosed by awnings or tents having no more than 2 sides shall be considered outdoor space.  Areas enclosed by retractable glass walls and other forms of operable walls shall not be considered outdoor dining.  Temporary unlicensed rooftops and summer gardens not located on the ground floor or street level are not eligible for registration under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
     <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-113"/>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-113" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
        <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on March 22, 2022. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-113(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
      </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
