<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-277">
  <num type="act">24-277</num>
  <num type="bill">24-569</num>
  <heading type="short">Limited Coronavirus Procurement Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Coronavirus Support Temporary Amendment Act of 2021 to authorize certain emergency procurements deemed necessary to respond to changing public health conditions and to protect the health and safety of District residents.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-12-20</introduced>
    <effective>2022-01-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/48458/Signed_Act/B24-0569-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-277</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 000216</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0569">
      <vote date="2021-12-21" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-01-13</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Limited Coronavirus Procurement Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2021".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§7-2304|(b)|(2)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 507(a) of the Coronavirus Support Temporary Amendment Act of 2021, effective June 24, 2021 (D.C. Law 24-9; D.C. Official Code § 7-2304(b)(2)), is amended by striking the phrase "shall expire on November 5, 2021;" and inserting the phrase "shall expire on November 5, 2021, except for procurements that:</text>
    <include lvl="2">
      <para>
        <codify:insert/>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Are necessary to protect public health and safety through:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>COVID-19 testing, including the necessary supports for testing including staffing, equipment, and supplies;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Vaccination against COVID-19, including the necessary supports for vaccination including staffing, equipment, and supplies; or,</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Updating and maintaining information technology systems that support the District's response to COVID-19, including the necessary supports for such updates and maintenance; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <codify:insert/>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Are entered into after a summary of each proposed procurement is provided to the Council and made publicly available online that includes:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A description of the specific goods or services to be procured;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The source selection method, including whether the procurement was competitively sourced;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The contract amount and the source of funds, including whether the source is federal or local;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The name and certified business enterprise status of the proposed awardee; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>An explanation regarding why expedited procurement procedures are necessary to meet the specific need identified.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext> in its place.</aftertext>
    <!-- <codify:find-replace count="1">
      <find>shall expire on November 5, 2021;</find>
      <replace>shall expire on November 5, 2021, except for procurements that:</replace>
    </codify:find-replace> -->
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2304"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2304" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on April 13, 2022. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and emergency legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2304(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a)</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
