<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-215">
  <num type="act">24-215</num>
  <num type="bill">24-494</num>
  <heading type="short">McMillan Townhomes Parcels, Commercial Parcels, and Multifamily Parcels Extension of Disposition Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes to extend the time limit for the disposition of certain District-owned real properties located at 2501 1st Street, N.W., formerly the McMillan Sand Filtration Site, and known for tax and assessment purposes as Lot 0800 in Square 3128.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-10-28</introduced>
    <effective>2021-11-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/48200/Signed_Act/B24-0494-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-215</citation>
      <citation type="register">68 DCR 012371</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0494">
      <vote date="2021-11-02" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2021-11-18</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "McMillan Townhomes Parcels, Commercial Parcels, and Multifamily Parcels Extension of Disposition Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 1 of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code § 10-801), is amended by adding a new subsection (d-9) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-801" after="(d-8)"/> -->
        <num>(d-9)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, the time period within which the Mayor may dispose of the District-owned real property located at 2501 1st Street, N.W., formerly the McMillan Sand Filtration Site, and known for tax and assessment purposes as Lot 0800 in Square 3128, pursuant to the McMillan Residential Townhomes Parcel Disposition Approval Resolution of 2014, effective December 2, 2014 (Res. 20-705; 62 DCR 1091), the McMillan Commercial Parcels Disposition Approval Resolution of 2014, effective December 2,  2014 (Res. 20-707; 62 DCR 1097), and the McMillan Residential Multifamily Parcels Disposition Approval Resolution of 2014, effective December 2, 2014 (Res. 20-706; 62 DCR 1094), and as extended by the McMillan Townhomes Parcel, Commercial Parcel, and Multifamily Parcels Disposition Extension Approval Resolution of 2015, effective November 3, 2015 (Res. 21-0253; 66 DCR 4330), is extended to the expiration date of the McMillan Townhomes Parcels, Commercial Parcels, and Multifamily Parcels Extension of Disposition Authority Temporary Act of 2021, passed on 1st reading on November 2, 2021 (Engrossed version of Bill 24-495).</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-801"/>
    <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-801" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 16, 2022. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-801(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert> -->
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
