<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-329">
  <num type="act">24-329</num>
  <num type="bill">24-627</num>
  <heading type="short">Limited Coronavirus Procurement Second Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the District of Columbia Public Emergency Act of 1980 to authorize certain emergency procurements deemed necessary to respond to changing public health conditions and to protect the health and safety of District residents.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-01-31</introduced>
    <effective>2022-02-04</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/48663/Signed_Act/B24-0627-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-329</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0627">
      <vote date="2022-02-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-02-04</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Limited Coronavirus Procurement Second Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2304|(b)|(2)">
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Implement those provisions of the District of Columbia response plan as issued by the Mayor, without regard to established operating procedures relating to the performance of public works, entering into contracts, incurring obligations, employment of temporary workers, rental of equipment, purchase of supplies and materials, and expenditure of public funds; provided, that this paragraph shall apply only to employees of the District of Columbia government; provided further, that, with respect to any public emergency or public health emergency declared, extended, or otherwise in effect in 2022, the additional authority provided pursuant to this paragraph for entering into contracts and incurring obligations is limited to procurements that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Are necessary to protect public health and safety through:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Coronavirus testing, including the necessary supports for testing such as staffing, equipment, and supplies;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Vaccination against COVID-19, including the necessary supports for vaccination such as staffing, equipment, and supplies;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Updating and maintaining information technology systems that support the District's response to COVID-19, including the necessary supports for such updates and maintenance; or,</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The provision of masks and personal protective equipment; and,</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Are entered into after a summary of each proposed procurement is provided to the Council and made publicly available online that includes:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A description of the specific goods or services to be procured;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The source selection method, including whether the procurement was competitively sourced;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The contract amount and the source of funds, whether federal or local;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The name and certified business enterprise status of the proposed awardee; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>An explanation regarding why expedited procurement procedures are necessary to meet the specific need identified." in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </codify:replace>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 5(b)(2) of the District of Columbia Public Emergency Act of 1980, effective March 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-149; D.C. Official Code § 7-2304(b)(2)), is amended by striking the phrase "District of Columbia government;" and inserting the phrase "District of Columbia government; provided further, that, with respect to any public emergency or public health emergency declared, extended, or otherwise in effect in 2022, the additional authority provided pursuant to this paragraph for entering into contracts and incurring obligations is limited to procurements that:</text>
    <include lvl="1">
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Are necessary to protect public health and safety through:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Coronavirus testing, including the necessary supports for testing such as staffing, equipment, and supplies;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Vaccination against COVID-19, including the necessary supports for vaccination such as staffing, equipment, and supplies;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Updating and maintaining information technology systems that support the District's response to COVID-19, including the necessary supports for such updates and maintenance; or,</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The provision of masks and personal protective equipment; and,</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Are entered into after a summary of each proposed procurement is provided to the Council and made publicly available online that includes:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A description of the specific goods or services to be procured;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The source selection method, including whether the procurement was competitively sourced;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The contract amount and the source of funds, whether federal or local;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The name and certified business enterprise status of the proposed awardee; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>An explanation regarding why expedited procurement procedures are necessary to meet the specific need identified.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2304"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2304" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on May 5, 2022. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2304(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of February 4, 2022.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
