<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-353">
  <num type="act">24-353</num>
  <num type="bill">24-689</num>
  <heading type="short">Research Practice Partnership Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To clarify, on an emergency basis due to congressional review, that the District of Columbia Education Research Practice Partnership may assist its Advisory Committee.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-02-28</introduced>
    <effective>2022-03-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/48883/Signed_Act/B24-0689-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-353</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 002629</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0689">
      <vote date="2022-03-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-03-02</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Research Practice Partnership Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 105 of the District of Columbia Education Research Practice Partnership Establishment and Audit Act of 2018, effective March 28, 2019 (D.C. Law 22-268; D.C. Official Code ยง 38-785.04), is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Partnership and its executive director may provide staff support to the Advisory Committee, including the scheduling of meetings and the drafting of documents.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง38-785.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of March 2, 2022.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
