<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-385">
  <num type="act">24-385</num>
  <num type="bill">24-749</num>
  <heading type="short">Rent Notice and Rent Increase Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to clarify that no lawful rent increase notice issued to a tenant or lawful rent increase implemented between January 1, 2022, and February 28, 2022, shall be deemed null and void.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-04-04</introduced>
    <effective>2022-04-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/49246/Signed_Act/B24-0749-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-385</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0749">
      <vote date="2022-04-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-04-25</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Rent Notice and Rent Increase Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 904 of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3509.04) is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3509.04" after="(b)"/>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>No rent increase notice given to a tenant or rent increase implemented between January 1, 2022, and February 28, 2022, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="42|35">this act</code-cite>, the Rental Accommodations Act of 1975, the Rental Housing Act of 1977, or the Rental Housing Act of 1980 that meets the requirements of District law shall be deemed null and void by operation of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-9" path="§405|(7)">section 405(7) of the Coronavirus Support Temporary Amendment Act of 2021, effective June 24, 2021 (D.C. Law 24-9; 68 DCR 4824)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3509.04"/>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3509.04" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
        <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on July, 24, 2022. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3509.04(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
      </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
