<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-47">
  <num type="bill">24-89</num>
  <num type="act">24-47</num>
  <heading type="short">Public Space Maintenance and Arts Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Public Space Maintenance Temporary Act of 2020 to clarify the authority of the Mayor to enter into an agreement with a Business Improvement District corporation for the maintenance and improvement of a District-owned asset or public space during a public health emergency and for 30 days thereafter; and to amend the Commission on the Arts and Humanities Act to clarify the definition of District funds for purposes of determining the eligibility of a nonprofit corporation to be a member of the National Capital Arts Cohort.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-02-25</introduced>
    <effective>2021-03-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/46583/Signed_Act/B24-0089-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-47</citation>
      <citation type="register">68 DCR 003458</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0089">
      <vote date="2021-03-02" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2021-03-24</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public Space Maintenance and Arts Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 2 of the Public Space Maintenance Temporary Act of 2020, enacted on November 2, 2020 (D.C. Act 23-464; 67 DCR 13238), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "improve public space, including sidewalks, streets, parks, plazas, signage, and public art, within the boundaries of the BID" and inserting the phrase "improve a District-owned asset or public space, including sidewalks, streets, parks, plazas, signage, and public art, within or partially within the boundaries of the BID" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase "improving public space" and inserting the phrase "improving a District-owned asset or public space" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase "in public space" both times it appears and inserting the phrase "on a District-owned asset or public space" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1215.81" action="amendment of this section" applicability="2021-08-05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 3(9)(A)(i) of the Commission on the Arts and Humanities Act, effective October 21, 1975 (D.C. Law 1-22; D.C. Official Code § 39-202(9)(A)(i)), is amended by striking the phrase "exclusive of District funds" and inserting the phrase "exclusive of District funds other than sponsorships provided by Events DC" in its place.</text>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-202"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of March 6, 2021.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
