<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-444">
  <num type="act">24-444</num>
  <num type="bill">24-809</num>
  <heading type="short">Opioid Overdose Prevention Emergency Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Drug Paraphernalia Act of 1982 to permit employees of the District government acting within the scope of their official duties and District contactors acting within the scope of their contract to deliver, or possess with intent to deliver, drug testing equipment.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-05-10</introduced>
    <effective>2022-06-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/49541/Signed_Act/B24-0809-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-444</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 007737</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0809">
      <vote date="2022-06-07" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-06-28</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Opioid Overdose Prevention Emergency Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 4(b) of the Drug Paraphernalia Act of 1982, effective September 17, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-149; D.C. Official Code § 48-1103(b)), is amended by adding a new paragraph (1B) to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="1">
      <para>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-1103|(b)" after="(1A)"/>
        <num>(1B)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, it shall not be unlawful for an employee of the District government acting within the scope of their official duties and contractors or grantees of the District government engaged to combat opioid overdoses acting within the scope of their contract to deliver, or possess with intent to deliver, the testing equipment and other objects described in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-1101|(3)|(D)">section 2(3)(D)</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-1103"/>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-1103" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
        <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on September 26, 2022. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-1103(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
      </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
