<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 24-599">
  <num type="act">24-599</num>
  <num type="bill">24-1017</num>
  <heading type="short">Advisory Neighborhood Commission Allotment Emergency Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1975 to provide that certain amounts in the Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Technical Support and Assistance Fund be used for allotments to Advisory Neighborhood Commissions in Fiscal Year 2023; and to amend the Advisory Neighborhood Commission Boundaries Act of 2022 to require individuals in possession of Advisory Neighborhood Commission physical assets to return the assets to the successor Advisory Neighborhood Commission, unless an individual is a Commissioner for the successor Advisory Neighborhood Commission as of January 2, 2023.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-10-03</introduced>
    <effective>2022-10-31</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/51352/Signed_Act/B24-1017-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-599</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-1017">
      <vote date="2022-10-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-10-31</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Advisory Neighborhood Commission Allotment Emergency Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 13a of the Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1975, effective December 3, 2020 (D.C. Law 23-149; D.C. Official Code § 1-309.13a), is amended by adding a new subsection (c-1) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-309.13a" after="(c)"/>
        <num>(c-1)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding subsection (c) of this section, in Fiscal Year 2023:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>$799,688 in the Fund shall be used to provide quarterly allotments to Advisory Neighborhood Commissions in accordance with <span codify:value="§§"></span> <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-207.38|(e)" codify:value="1-207.38(e)">section 738(e) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 824; D.C. Official Code § 1-207.38(e)),</code-cite> and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-309.51|(c)" codify:value="1-309.51(c)">section 3(c) of the Advisory Neighborhood Commission Boundaries Act of 2022, effective August 10, 2022 (D.C. Law 24-148; D.C. Official Code § 1-309.51(c)) (ANC Boundaries Act of 2022)</code-cite>; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>$25,000 in the Fund shall be allotted on a per capita basis, based on the 2020 census population of each Advisory Neighborhood Commission, to the following Advisory Neighborhood Commissions established by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-148" path="§2">section 2 of the ANC Boundaries Act of 2022</cite>; provided, that the Advisory Neighborhood Commission has fulfilled the requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-309.13">section 16</code-cite>(a) and (c), as determined by the Office of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>ANC 1E;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>ANC 2G;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>ANC 3A;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>ANC 4E;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>ANC 5F; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(F)</num>
            <text>ANC 8F.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-309.13a"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-309.13a" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on January 29, 2023. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-309.13a(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§1-309.51|(a)">
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 3(a) of the Advisory Neighborhood Commission Boundaries Act of 2022, effective August 10, 2022 (D.C. Law 24-148; D.C. Official Code § 1-309.51(a)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Designate the existing text as paragraph (1).</text>
      <codify:redesignate-para num-value="(1)"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Add a new paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <codify:insert/>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>An individual who possesses a physical asset belonging to an ANC shall relinquish the asset to the ANC that is the successor in interest to the asset unless, as of January 2, 2023, the individual is a duly elected Commissioner for the successor ANC.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-309.51"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-309.51" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on January 29, 2023. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-309.51(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
