<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 24-673">
  <num type="act">24-673</num>
  <num type="bill">24-1077</num>
  <heading type="short">Criminal Justice Involvement Reduction Emergency Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council for the District of Columbia Establishment Act of 2001 to require the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council to submit reports to the Mayor and the Council to determine what factors, programs, or interventions effectively prevent District youth from entering the juvenile and criminal justice systems, and to analyze the types of school-based incidents that lead to a law enforcement referral or arrest.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-10-31</introduced>
    <effective>2022-11-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/51568/Signed_Act/B24-1077-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-673</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-1077">
      <vote date="2022-11-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-11-22</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Criminal Justice Involvement Reduction Emergency Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§22-4234">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 1505 of the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council for the District of Columbia Establishment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 22-4234), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="(b-2)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b-2) is amended by striking the phrase "and every 2 years thereafter, the CJCC" and inserting the phrase "the CJCC" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>and every 2 years thereafter, the CJCC</find>
        <replace>the CJCC</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="(b-3)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b-3) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:replace/>
          <num>(b-3)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>On October 1, 2020, the CJCC shall submit a report to the Mayor and the Council analyzing the root causes of youth crime and the prevalence of adverse childhood experiences among justice-involved youth, such as housing instability, childhood abuse, family instability, substance abuse, mental illness, family criminal involvement, or other factors considered relevant by the CJCC that incorporates the results of the survey conducted pursuant to subsection (b-2) of this section.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>By October 1, 2022, the CJCC shall submit a report to the Mayor and the Council that analyzes protective factors that reduce the risk of District youth entering the juvenile and criminal justice systems and includes recommendations, informed by best practices in other jurisdictions, the results of the survey conducted pursuant to subsection (b-2) of this section, and the report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, on factors, programs, or interventions that effectively prevent District youth from entering the juvenile and criminal justice systems, such as access to stable housing, nutrition assistance, healthcare assistance, violence intervention, and educational, recreational, and youth programming.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>By October 1, 2024, the CJCC shall submit a report to the Mayor and the Council that analyzes the types of school-based incidents that lead to law enforcement referral or arrest, and whether factors such as economic resources, race, Individualized Education Program eligibility, mental health conditions, school location, and school resource officer assignment statistically affect the likelihood of law enforcement referrals or arrests.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
     <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-4234"/>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-4234" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
        <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 20, 2023. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-4234(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
      </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
