<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2142</num>
  <heading>Inventory tracking requirements.</heading>
  <text>No later than December 1, 2012, the Mayor shall transmit to the Council an implementation plan that details the budget and resources necessary to begin tracking the Department of Housing and Community Development’s (“DHCD”) affordable housing inventory. The plan shall explicate the process and analyze the budget and resources necessary to begin tracking the number of:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Affordable housing units that remain under affordability restrictions administered by DHCD, including the number of units that are:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Made affordable to low-income households;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Made affordable to very low-income households;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Made affordable to extremely low-income households;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Made available for homeownership;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Made available for rent; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Specifically allocated for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Individuals diagnosed with HIV/AIDS;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Individuals diagnosed with a mental illness;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Individuals diagnosed as deaf or hearing impaired;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>Individuals, and families, who are homeless;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>Individuals who are victims of domestic violence; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(vi)</num>
        <text>Individuals diagnosed with a developmental disability;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Low-income, very low-income, and extremely low-income households and individuals currently residing in the affordable housing units described in paragraph (1) of this section, including those listed in paragraph (1)(F)(i) through (vi) of this section;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Affordable housing units that will exit affordability restrictions within the next 5 years, 10 years, 20 years, 30 years, or 40 years, including a delineation of their affordability levels and whether they are allocated for those individuals listed in paragraph (1)(F)(i) through (vi) of this section; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Affordable housing units in each ward, including a delineation of their affordability levels and whether they are allocated for those individuals listed in paragraph (1)(F)(i) through (vi) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2093, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
