<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2602</num>
  <heading>Deposits to credit of Fund.</heading>
  <text>There shall be deposited to the credit of the Fund such amounts as may be appropriated pursuant to this subchapter; grants and gifts from public and private sources to the Fund or to the District of Columbia for the purposes of the Fund; repayments of principal and any interest on loans provided from the Fund; proceeds realized from the liquidation of any security interests held by the District of Columbia under the terms of any assistance provided from the Fund; interest earned from the deposit or investment of monies of the Fund; repayments of principal and any interest on loans provided under the District of Columbia Government Employer-Assisted Housing Program; and all other revenues, receipts and fees of whatever nature derived from the operation of the Fund.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-103">Sept. 12, 1978, D.C. Law 2-103, § 3, 25 DCR 1977</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-118">June 11, 1992, D.C. Law 9-118, § 8(b), 39 DCR 3189</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-60">Mar. 20, 1998, D.C. Law 12-60, § 1101, 44 DCR 7378</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-96">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-96, § 9(b), 47 DCR 1081</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 45-2202.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 45-1802.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-96">D.C. Law 13-96</cite> inserted “repayments of principal and any interest on loans provided under the District of Columbia Government Employer-Assisted Housing Program;” following “interest earned from the deposit or investment of monies of the Fund;”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 9(b) of the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-188, December 1, 1999,  46 DCR 10407).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 9(b) of the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-258, February 9, 2000,  47 DCR 1124).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Repeal of Law</heading>
      <text>Repeal of Law 9-118</text>
      <text>Section 1101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-60">D.C. Law 12-60</cite> repealed the District of Columbia Employer-Assisted Housing Act of 1992, <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-118">D.C. Law 9-118</cite>.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Because of the enactment of subchapter II of this chapter by <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-266">D.C. Law 12-266</cite>, “subchapter” has been substituted for “chapter”.</text>
      <text>Section 11 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-96">D.C. Law 13-96</cite> provided: “This act shall apply as of October 1, 1997.”</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
