<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3405.01</num>
  <heading>Rule making; publication requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall issue rules for the implementation of this chapter. The Mayor shall issue rules for the holding of elections which shall include, but not be limited to, provisions for secret voting, and the right of any person including the owner to observe the counting of the ballots.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>By November 9, 1980, the Mayor shall publish in the D.C. Register a summary of tenant rights and obligations pursuant to this chapter, and sources of technical assistance, which shall include, but shall not be limited to, information regarding counseling, subsidy programs, relocation services, housing purchase and rehabilitation finance, tax relief programs, formation of tenant organizations, purchase of housing accommodations, rehabilitation, and conversion to cooperative or condominium.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>By March 5, 1996, the Mayor shall issue updated rules for comment, which shall reflect all changes made by the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment Extension and Amendment Act of 1995. Within 180 days after publication of the proposed rules, the Mayor shall adopt final rules. The failure to meet these deadlines shall not prevent the changes in the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment Extension and Amendment Act of 1995 from being effective immediately upon September 6, 1995.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-86">Sept. 10, 1980, D.C. Law 3-86, § 501, 27 DCR 2975</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-31">Sept. 6, 1995, D.C. Law 11-31, § 3(p), 42 DCR 3239</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 47, 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 45-1651.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(p) of Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Temporary Extension Amendment Act of 1994 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-176">D.C. Law 10-176</cite>, September 22, 1994, law notification  41 DCR 6076).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(p) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-285, July 8, 1994,  41 DCR 4904).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(p) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-47, May 4, 1995,  42 DCR 2410) and § 3(p) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Congressional Recess Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-96, July 19, 1995,  42 DCR 3837).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>The Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Act of 1995, referred to in this section, is <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-31">D.C. Law 11-31</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <annotation>Delegation of authority under Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1983, as amended, see Mayor’s Order 84-8, January 12, 1984.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Reenactment of Law 3-86: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite root="42-3401.01">42-3401.01</cite>.</text>
      <text>Amendment of section by Law 10-144: Section 2(p) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-144">D.C. Law 10-144</cite> purported to amend this section by adding (c) to read as follows:</text>
      <text>“(c) Within 180 days after July 23, 1994, the Mayor shall issue updated rules for comment, which shall reflect all changes made by the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Extension and Amendment Act of 1994. Within 180 days after publication of the proposed rules, the Mayor shall adopt final rules. The failure to meet these deadlines shall not prevent the changes in the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Extension and Amendment Act of 1994 from being effective immediately upon July 23,</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
