<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3508.06</num>
  <heading>Incentives for development of single-room-occupancy housing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may provide tax abatements and deferral or forgiveness of water and sewer fees and other indebtedness to the District as incentives for the development of single-room-occupancy housing for low- and moderate-income tenants. These incentives shall be provided pursuant to negotiations and written agreements between the Mayor and housing providers engaged in the development or operation of single-room-occupancy housing accommodations. In these negotiations and written agreements, the Mayor may establish a formula for abating property tax liability for properties developed pursuant to this section for a period of not more than 10 years beginning during the first year that newly-constructed or rehabilitated single-room-occupancy housing becomes available for occupancy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The incentives provided by this section shall be available for new construction, renovation of any vacant rental housing accommodation, or renovation of any non-housing property, whether vacant or not, for single-room-occupancy housing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To qualify for the incentives provided by this section, the housing provider shall demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Mayor that the single-room-occupancy housing meets the following minimum standards:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Rental rates are affordable for low- and moderate-income tenants and reflect costs offset by the tax abatements and deferral or forgiveness of indebtedness to the District provided pursuant to this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The location is in compliance with the Zoning Regulations of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each rental unit includes no less than 95 square feet of space, and a clothing storage unit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Toilet and shower or bathing facilities are provided on each floor where tenants reside, in a reasonable size to meet the needs of the tenants residing on that floor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A common-space day room, kitchen, and laundry facilities sufficient to meet the needs of all tenants at 100% occupancy are provided;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A 24-hour security system, either manual or electronic, is provided; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The housing accommodation has a resident manager who resides on the premises.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Within 180 days from August 25, 1994, the Mayor shall compile, provide to the Council, and publish in the District of Columbia Register an initial list of District-owned and privately-owned properties in the District that are available and suitable for the development of single-room-occupancy housing in accordance with this section. At least annually thereafter, the Mayor shall publish a revised list and provide a written report to the Council regarding the status of single-room-occupancy housing development at these and other sites.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-10">July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, § 806</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-155">as added Aug. 25, 1994, D.C. Law 10-155, § 2(d), 41 DCR 4873</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 45-2586.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Termination of Law: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite root="42-3508.01">42-3508.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
