<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-1118</num>
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <heading>Abatement of taxes due where cost does not warrant collection.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 87-408" type="History">Mar. 2, 1962, 76 Stat. 16, Pub. L. 87-408, title III, § 318</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 9(d), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-938.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 45-738.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">Temporary Repeal of Section For temporary (225 day) repeal of section, see § 10(f) of the Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</law-cite>, Oct. 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">For temporary (225 day) repeal of section, see § 10(f) of the Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2002 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</law-cite>, Mar. 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section, see § 10(f) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section, see § 10(f) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section, see § 10(f) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
