<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-1801</num>
  <heading>Signs on sidewalk or parking prohibited; number of signs; removal; penalties.</heading>
  <text>No sign or advertisement relating to the sale, rent, or lease of land or premises shall be located on the sidewalk or parking of any street, avenue, or road in the District of Columbia. One painted or printed sign or advertisement for the sale, rent, or lease of land or premises may, with the written consent of the owner or legal representative of the owner, be placed, by any 1 of not exceeding 3 real estate agents, on any lot, piece, or parcel of land abutting on a street, avenue, or road in said District, or attached to the exterior of any building fronting thereon. The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to use the police authority vested in him, to require the removal of any sign or advertisement in violation of this provision, and to institute prosecutions, in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, against persons violating the provisions hereof, and every such person, upon conviction of such violation, shall be fined in the sum of not less than $5 nor more than $25. This section shall not apply to the temporary placement of directional signs relating to the sale or lease of real estate which indicate the holding of an open house or a sign attached to the 1 painted or printed sign allowed by this section which indicates that the premises have been sold, leased, or placed under contract.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Mar. 4, 1913, 37 Stat. 974, ch. 150, § 7</annotation>
      <annotation>Apr. 1, 1942, 56 Stat. 190, ch. 207, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation>July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation>July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-189">Mar. 16, 1993, D.C. Law 9-189, § 2, 39 DCR 9001</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-289">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-289, § 7, 60 DCR 2328</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Out-of-door advertising signs, power of Council to regulate and license, see § <cite root="1-303.21">1-303.21</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 45-2001.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 7-1001.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-181">D.C. Law 19-181</cite> repealed this section.</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 8 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-181">D.C. Law 19-181</cite> provided that any order, rule, or regulation in effect under a law replaced by this act shall remain in effect until repealed, amended, or superseded.</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 9 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-181">D.C. Law 19-181</cite> provided that sections 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7 of the act shall apply upon the Mayor’s issuance of a comprehensive final rulemaking governing signs on public space and private property pursuant to section 2 of the act.</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 11(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-181">D.C. Law 19-181</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) repeal of section, see § 7 of the Sign Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-387, July 11, 2012,  59 DCR 8491).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary repeal of section, see § 7 of the Sign Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-499, October 26, 2012,  59 DCR 12749), applicable after the Mayor’s issuance of a comprehensive final rulemaking governing signs on public space and private property, and with the condition that any order, rule, or regulation in effect under a law replaced by this act shall remain in effect until repealed, amended, or superseded.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> would have repealed this section.</text>
      <text>Section 9 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> provided that any order, rule, or regulation in effect under a law replaced by this act shall remain in effect until repealed, amended, or superseded.</text>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite>, § 7: Section 10 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> provided that sections 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, and 8 of the act shall not apply until the Mayor’s issuance of a comprehensive final rulemaking governing signs on public space and private property pursuant to section 2 of the act. Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> rewrote §§ <cite root="1-303.21">1-303.21</cite> and <cite root="1-303.23">1-303.23</cite>, and repealed § <cite root="1-303.22">1-303.22</cite>.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
