<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-1231</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Digitized image” means an electronic document that is created as an electronic copy of a paper document that accurately depicts the information on the paper document and is unalterable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Document” means information that is:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Eligible to be recorded in the land records maintained by the Recorder of Deeds.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Electronic” means relating to technology having electrical, digital, magnetic, wireless, optical, electromagnetic, or similar capabilities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Electronic document” means a document that is received by the Recorder of Deeds in an electronic form.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Electronic signature” means an electronic sound, symbol, or process attached to or logically associated with a document and executed or adopted by a person with the intent to sign the document.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Paper document” means a document that is received by the Recorder of Deeds in a form that is not electronic.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Person” means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership,</text>
    <text>limited liability company, association, joint venture, public corporation, government, or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or any other legal or commercial entity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-25" type="History" path="§2">Oct. 18, 2005, D.C. Law 16-25, § 2, 52 DCR 8084</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 2 of the Uniform Real Property Electronic Recording Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
