<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-1901.04</num>
  <heading>Separate taxation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If there is any unit owner other than the declarant, a tax or assessment shall not be levied on the condominium as a whole or against any common elements, but only on the individual condominium units. A condominium unit shall be carried on the records of the District of Columbia and assessed as a separate and distinct taxable entity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, for real property tax years beginning after September 30, 2011, horizontally or vertically abutting condominium units owned by the identical unit owner that comprise and are used as a single dwelling unit may be combined for assessment and taxation purposes into a separate and distinct taxable entity (“combined tax lot”); provided, that the unit owner applies for combined tax lot treatment pursuant to § <cite path="§47-832">47-832</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Combined tax lot treatment granted pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall take effect for the succeeding real property tax year following the date the application is received.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-89" type="History" path="§104">Mar. 29, 1977, D.C. Law 1-89, title I, § 104, 23 DCR 9532b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-233" type="History">Mar. 8, 1991, D.C. Law 8-233, § 2(d), 38 DCR 261</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-150" type="History">July 13, 2012, D.C. Law 19-150, § 2, 59 DCR 5132</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-1804.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-1204.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-150">D.C. Law 19-150</cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsec. (b).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
