<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-1701</num>
  <heading>Purposes.</heading>
  <text>The purposes of this subchapter are to protect the public against incompetence, fraud and deception in real estate transactions; to establish a Real Estate Guaranty and Educational Fund to compensate victims of unlawful real estate practices; and for other purposes.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-209" type="History" path="§2">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-209, § 2, 30 DCR 390</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-117" type="History">Sept. 26, 1984, D.C. Law 5-117, § 2(a), 31 DCR 4023</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 1233(a), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-321.02">1-321.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-1921.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of chapter to District of Columbia Housing Authority: Section 13 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-243">D.C. Law 10-243</law-cite>, the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1994, provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of chapter to District of Columbia Housing Authority: (a) The provisions of Chapter 17 of Title 42 shall not apply to the property managers of housing properties within the jurisdiction of the Authority. The activities of property managers of housing properties shall be regulated by the applicable statutes, rules, and regulations of the United States in effect on March 21, 1995.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) Execution or other judicial process shall not issue against the real property of the Authority nor shall any judgment against the Authority be a charge or lien upon its real property. This section shall not apply to or limit the right of obligees to foreclose or otherwise enforce any mortgage on property of the Authority or the right of obligees to pursue any remedies for the enforcement of any pledge or lien given by the Authority on its rents, fees, and revenues.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
