<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-1102.02</num>
  <heading>Transfer of economic interest defined.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A transfer of an economic interest in real property occurs upon the conveyance, vesting, granting, bargaining, sale, or assignment, directly or indirectly, of a controlling interest by 1 or more persons or by 1 or more transactions, within any 12-month period, in any corporation, partnership, association, trust, or other entity that, during the 12-month period immediately preceding the transfer of an economic interest in real property:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Derives more than 50% of its gross receipts from the ownership or disposition of real property in the District; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Holds real property in the District that has a value comprising 80% or more of the value of its entire tangible asset holdings.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of subsection (a) of this section, a transfer of a controlling interest includes the aggregate of the transfer of any legal, equitable, beneficial, or other ownership interest in:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any entity described in subsection (a) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any entity that is a partner in, shareholder in, or beneficiary of, an entity described in subsection (a) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any other entity:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>That derives, directly or indirectly, any portion of its receipts from the ownership of any entity described in subsection (a) of this section; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Has asset value that includes, directly or indirectly, any legal, equitable, beneficial, or other ownership interest in any entity described in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, as of October 1, 2009, every transfer of an interest in a cooperative housing association in connection with the grant, transfer, or assignment of a proprietary leasehold or other proprietary interest, in whole or in part, shall be a transfer of an economic interest.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 87-408" type="History">Mar. 2, 1962, 76 Stat. 11, Pub. L. 87-408, title III, § 302b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-128" type="History">as added June 14, 1994, D.C. Law 10-128, § 101(d), 41 DCR 2096</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 7091(a), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 7102(b), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-1101">42-1101</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-922.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> substituted “this section, as of October 1, 2009, every transfer of an interest” for “this chapter, a transfer of shares” in (c); and made a stylistic change.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2(b), 3(b) of Cooperative Housing Association Economic Interest Recordation Tax Temporary Amendment Act of 2009 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 18-109">D.C. Law 18-109</cite>, March 3, 2010, law notification  57 DCR 2828).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-295">D.C. Law 18-295</cite> amended subsec. (c) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">“(c) Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, every transfer of an interest in a cooperative housing association in connection with the grant, transfer, or assignment of proprietary leasehold or other proprietary interest, in whole or in part, shall be a transfer of an economic interest. This subsection shall apply as of October 1, 2009.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-295">D.C. Law 18-295</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-74">D.C. Law 19-74</cite> rewrote subsec. (c) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">“(c) Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, every transfer of an interest in a cooperative housing association in connection with the grant, transfer, or assignment of proprietary leasehold or other proprietary interest, in whole or in part, shall be a transfer of an economic interest. This subsection shall apply as of October 1, 2009.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(t)(2) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-179">D.C. Law 20-179</cite>, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see § 101(d) of the Omnibus Budget Support Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-224, April 14, 1994,  41 DCR 2079).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary repeal of the Omnibus Budget Support Emergency Act of 1994, see § 801 of the Second Omnibus Budget Support Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-226, April 14, 1994,  41 DCR 2113).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see § 101(d) of the Second Omnibus Budget Support Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-226, April 14, 1994,  41 DCR 2113).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7041 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-187, August 26, 2009,  56 DCR 7374).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7091(a) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2(c), 3(c) of Cooperative Housing Association Economic Interest Recordation Tax Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-234, November 20, 2009,  56 DCR 9046).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7091(a) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment  Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Cooperative Housing Association Economic Interest Recordation Tax Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-570, October 20, 2010,  57 DCR 10084).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Cooperative Housing Association Economic Interest Recordation Tax Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-12, February 11, 2011,  58 DCR 1433).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Cooperative Housing Association Economic Interest Recordation Tax Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-194, October 18, 2011,  58 DCR 9160).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7102(b) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7102(b) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 7090 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle G of title VII of the act may be cited as the “Economic Interests in Real Property Clarification Amendment Act of 2009”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 10-128: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-1101">42-1101</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
