<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-1102</num>
  <heading>Deeds exempt from tax.</heading>
  <text>The following deeds shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Repealed;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Deeds to property acquired by the United States of America or the District of Columbia, unless its taxation has been authorized by Congress;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Deeds to real property acquired by an institution, organization, corporation, or government entitled to exemption from real property taxation under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite> (or exempt from recordation taxes under a law of the United States of America or the District of Columbia); provided, that, unless waived by regulation, a copy of a filed real property tax exemption application accompanies the deed at the time of recordation; provided further, that this exemption shall not apply to property which is exempt under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(29) or § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(30);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Deeds to property acquired by an institution, organization, corporation, or association entitled to exemption from real property taxation by special act of Congress, which property was acquired solely for a purpose or purposes for which such special exemption was granted; provided, that a return, under oath, showing the purpose or purposes for which such property was acquired, shall accompany the deed at the time of its offer for recordation;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>A purchase money mortgage or purchase money deed of trust that is recorded simultaneously with the deed conveying the real property for which the purchase money mortgage or purchase money deed of trust was obtained;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Supplemental deeds;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Deeds between spouses, parent and child, grandparent and grandchild, or domestic partners, as defined in § <cite path="§32-701">32-701</cite>(3), without actual consideration therefor;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Tax deeds;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Deeds of release of property which is security for a debt or other obligation;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>Deeds of personal representatives of decedents, acting under the provisions of Title 20, transferring to a distributee, without additional consideration, real property of a decedent or a life estate in the real property;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>When a permanent loan deed of trust or mortgage is submitted for recordation and the tax on the construction loan deed of trust or mortgage has been timely and properly paid, no additional tax liability arises under § <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite>, except where the amount of the obligor’s liability secured by the permanent loan deed of trust or mortgage exceeds the amount of his liability secured by the construction loan deed of trust or mortgage, in which case the tax shall be calculated only on the amount of such difference; provided, however, that such permanent loan deed of trust or mortgage shall contain a reference to the construction loan deed of trust or mortgage and the date and instrument number where it is recorded;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>Deeds to property transferred to a qualifying lower income homeownership household in accordance with § <cite path="§47-3503">47-3503</cite>(a);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>Deeds to property transferred to a qualifying nonprofit housing organization in accordance with § <cite path="§47-3505">47-3505</cite>(c);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>Deeds to property transferred to a cooperative housing association in accordance with § <cite path="§47-3503">47-3503</cite>(a)(2);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>Construction loan deeds of trust or mortgages or permanent loan deeds of trust or mortgages in accordance with § <cite path="§47-3503">47-3503</cite>(a)(3);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>A deed by a transferor that conveys bare legal title to the trustee of a revocable trust, without consideration for the transfer, where the transferor is the beneficiary of the trust;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(18)</num>
    <text>A deed to property transferred to a beneficiary of a revocable trust as the result of the death of the grantor of the revocable trust;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(19)</num>
    <text>A deed to property transferred by the trustee of a revocable trust if the transfer would otherwise be exempt under this section if made by the grantor of the revocable trust;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(20)</num>
    <text>A deed to property transferred to a resident management corporation in accordance with § <cite path="§47-3506.01">47-3506.01</cite>;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(21)</num>
    <text>A security interest instrument in Class 1 Property, as that class of property is established pursuant to § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>(c-4), that contains no more than 5 dwelling units. Each security interest instrument submitted for recordation for which an exemption under this paragraph is claimed shall have affixed thereto an affidavit stating the following:</text>
    <text>“I (we) the owner(s) of the real property described within certify, subject to criminal penalties for making false statements pursuant to § <cite path="§22-2405">22-2405</cite> of the District of Columbia Code    , that the real property described within is Class 1 Property, as that class of property is established pursuant to § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>(c-4), with 5 or fewer units.”;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(22)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A deed to property transferred pursuant to § <cite path="§29-204.06">29-204.06</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>In order for limited liability companies to receive the exemption provided in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the Recorder of Deeds shall be notified, within 30 days, of any change to the members or interests in profits and losses during the 12-month period following the effective date of the conversion so that the applicable recordation tax can be imposed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Violation of the provisions of subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall be punishable pursuant to § <cite path="§42-1120">42-1120</cite> [repealed];</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(23)</num>
    <text>A deed for the improvements known as the District of Columbia Correctional Treatment Facility, located on a portion of Lot 800 of Square 1112E, with a street address of 1901 E Street, S.E.;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(24)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Deeds conveying, vesting, granting, or assigning title to, an interest in, a security interest in, or an economic interest in the real property (and any improvements thereon) described as Square 454, Lots 41, 824, 838, 857, 877, 878; the portion of the public alley that reverted to (i) former Lot 820, (which is currently known as Lot 866), and (ii) former Lot 821 (which is currently known as Lot 867) pursuant to the Plat of Alley Closing filed with the Surveyor of the District of Columbia in Liber 17 at folio 74; and the portions of the public alley that will revert to Lots 41, 824, 838, 857, 877 and 878, all in Square 454, pursuant to the alley closing approved by the Closing of Public Alleys in Square 454 and Square 455, S.O. 98-194 Act of 1999, effective October 22, 1999 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-48">D.C. Law 13-48</law-cite>; 46 DCR 6768);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The amount of all taxes, fees, and deposits exempt, abated, or waived under this paragraph, § <cite path="§2-1217.31">2-1217.31</cite>(b), and §§ <cite path="§47-902">47-902</cite>(17), <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(26), and <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>(32) [(32) repealed], shall not exceed, in the aggregate, $ 7 million;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(25)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Deeds conveying, vesting, granting, or assigning title to, an interest in, a security interest in, or an economic interest in the real property (and any improvements thereon) described as Square 299, Lot 831, in connection with debt or equity financing for the Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project until the Development Sponsor sells the Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project, as evidenced by the recordation of a deed conveying title to Square 299, Lot 831, at which time such amounts shall be due and payable without penalty or interest;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The amount of all taxes, fees, and deposits deferred under this paragraph, and §§ <cite path="§2-1217.32">2-1217.32</cite>(b), <cite path="§47-902">47-902</cite>(19), <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(27), and <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>(34), shall not exceed, in the aggregate, $4 million;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>“Development Sponsor” means Portals Hotel Site, LLC, a Delaware limited liability company, and its successors and assigns;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>“Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project” means the acquisition and initial development, construction, equipping, and furnishing of a Mandarin Oriental hotel within the Portals project, located on Square 299, Lot 831, consisting of a 400-room hotel with approximately 33,000 square feet of associated meeting and banquet space, 2 restaurants, a health spa and fitness center totaling approximately 10,000 square feet, and approximately 90,000 square feet of public parking space for approximately 200 cars;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>“Mandarin TIF Bonds” means the tax increment financing bonds issued in connection with the Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project pursuant to the Tax Increment Revenue Bonds Mandarin Hotel Project Emergency Approval Resolution of 2000, effective March 7, 2000 (Res. 13-510; 47 DCR 2133), and the Mandarin Hotel Project Modification Approval Resolution of 2000, effective December 19, 2000 (Res. 13-745; 48 DCR 83);</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>This paragraph shall apply upon the closing of the sale of the Mandarin TIF Bonds;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(26)</num>
    <text>Deeds executed pursuant to a decree of divorce or of separate maintenance or pursuant to a written instrument incident to such divorce or separation;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(27)</num>
    <text>Deeds to an entity described in paragraph (3) of this section of a lease or ground rent for a term, including renewals, that is at least 30 years; provided, that if the entity were the owner of the real property in which the possessory interest is conveyed, the real property would have been entitled to exemption from real property taxation under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>; provided further, that, unless waived by regulation, a copy of a filed real property tax exemption application accompanies the deed at the time of its offer for recordation;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(28)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A deed to residential real property, without consideration for the transfer, to the trustee of a special needs trust established for the benefit of a trust beneficiary who has a disability, as defined in § 1614(a)(3) of the Social Security Act, approved October 30, 1972 (86 Stat. 1471; 42 U.S.C. § 1382c(a)(3)), or from the trustee of a special needs trust that, by its terms, terminates upon the death of the trust beneficiary with a disability.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, a trust is a special needs trust if the trust instrument:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>States, among its purposes, that the trust assets are not intended to be counted in determining the beneficiary’s eligibility for needs-based governmental benefits; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(I)</num>
          <text>Names the beneficiary with a disability as the sole trust beneficiary during his or her lifetime; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(II)</num>
          <text>Provides that the beneficiary with a disability shall not serve as trustee;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(29)</num>
    <text>A security interest instrument securing a credit enhancement, such as a letter of credit, issued by a for-profit business organization, where such credit enhancement is required in connection with affordable housing financing provided by the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency that is funded in whole or in part through bonds issued pursuant to the U.S. Department of Treasury’s New Issue Bond Program. This paragraph shall apply as of January 1, 2009;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(30)</num>
    <text>Beginning October 1, 2009, a security interest instrument pertaining to a cooperative housing association;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(31)</num>
    <text>Beginning October 1, 2009, a deed of economic interest pertaining to a limited-equity cooperative, as defined under § <cite path="§47-802">47-802</cite>(11);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(32)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A deed to property to which there is a valid certification by the Mayor that both the property and transferee are eligible for exemption from real property taxation pursuant to § <cite path="§47-1005.02">47-1005.02</cite>; provided, that, unless waived by regulation, a copy of the certification shall accompany the deed at the time it is submitted for recordation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term “deed to property” includes a deed of trust encumbering the property;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(33)</num>
    <text>A security interest instrument executed by a borrower in connection with a loan under the Industrial Revenue Bond Forward Commitment Program authorized by subchapter II-B of Chapter 3 of Title 47 [§ 47–340.01 et seq.]; provided, that unless waived by regulation, a certification by the Mayor that the security interest instrument is entitled to this exemption accompanies the security interest instrument at the time it is presented for recordation; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(34)</num>
    <text>Deeds to property transferred to a named beneficiary of a revocable transfer on death deed under subchapter IV of Chapter 6 of Title 19 [§ <cite path="§19-604.01">19-604.01</cite> et seq.], by reason of the death of the grantor of the revocable transfer on death deed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 87-408" type="History">Mar. 2, 1962, 76 Stat. 11, Pub. L. 87-408, title III, § 302</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-72" type="History">June 24, 1980, D.C. Law 3-72, § 206, 27 DCR 2155</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-92" type="History">Sept. 13, 1980, D.C. Law 3-92, § 101(b), 27 DCR 3390</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-72" type="History">Mar. 10, 1982, D.C. Law 4-72, § 3(b), 28 DCR 5273</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-31" type="History">Oct. 8, 1983, D.C. Law 5-31, § 10(b), 30 DCR 3879</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-205" type="History">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-205, § 5, 36 DCR 457</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-20" type="History">Sept. 9, 1989, D.C. Law 8-20, § 2(b), 36 DCR 4564</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-56" type="History">Mar. 7, 1992, D.C. Law 9-56, § 3, 38 DCR 7281</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-120" type="History">June 11, 1992, D.C. Law 9-120, § 4(a), 39 DCR 3195</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-128" type="History">June 14, 1994, D.C. Law 10-128, § 101(b), 41 DCR 2096</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-38" type="History">Sept. 8, 1995, D.C. Law 11-38, § 4(b), 42 DCR 3269</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-276" type="History">June 3, 1997, D.C. Law 11-276, § 7(a), 44 DCR 1416</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-241" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-241, § 3, 48 DCR 610</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 506(b), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 26, 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-232" type="History">Mar. 25, 2003, D.C. Law 14-232, § 3, 49 DCR 9764</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 9(a), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 73, 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-176" type="History">Sept. 8, 2004, D.C. Law 15-176, § 2, 51 DCR 5707</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-293" type="History">Apr. 5, 2005, D.C. Law 15-293, § 12, 52 DCR 1465</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, §§ 1212, 1296, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91" type="History">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, § 114, 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 62, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 59, 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-118" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-118, § 201, 55 DCR 1461</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231,§ 34, 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-60" type="History">Dec. 13, 2011, D.C. Law 19-60, § 2, 58 DCR 9169</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, §§ 7102(a), 7133, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 5, 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 7152(a), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-141" type="History">Dec. 4, 2014, D.C. Law 20-141, § 204, 61 DCR 7763</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §§  7032, 7103(d), 7104, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Exemptions for qualifying lower income homeownership households and cooperative housing associations, see § <cite path="§47-3503">47-3503</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Gallery Place Project tax and fee abatements, see § <cite path="§2-1217.31">2-1217.31</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project fee deferral, see § <cite path="§2-1217.32">2-1217.32</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Resident management corporations, deed tax exemptions, see § <cite path="§47-3506.01">47-3506.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1217.32">2-1217.32</cite>, § <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite>, § <cite path="§42-1108.01">42-1108.01</cite>, § <cite path="§42-3404.02">42-3404.02</cite>, § <cite path="§47-902">47-902</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>, § <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>, § <cite path="§47-3503">47-3503</cite>, § <cite path="§47-3505">47-3505</cite>, § <cite path="§47-3506.01">47-3506.01</cite>, § <cite path="§47-4603">47-4603</cite>, § <cite path="§47-4605">47-4605</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-4634">47-4634</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-922.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 45-722.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-241">D.C. Law 13-241</law-cite> added par. (24).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</law-cite> rewrote par. (10) which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(10) Deeds of personal representatives of decedents, acting under the provisions of Title 20, transferring to a distributee without additional consideration real property of a decedent;”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</law-cite>, in par. (10), validated a previously made technical correction; and in par. (24)(B), substituted “47-2005(32)” for “47-2005(28)”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-232">D.C. Law 14-232</law-cite> added par. (25).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</law-cite> repealed par. (1); in par. (2), substituted “America, unless its taxation has been authorized by Congress;” for “America;”; rewrote par. (3); in par. (21), substituted “, as that class of property is established pursuant to § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>(c-4)” for “or Class 2 Property, as those classes of property are established pursuant to § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>,”; and added pars. (26) and (27).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</law-cite>, in pars. (20), (21), (22), (23), (24), (25), and (26), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-176">D.C. Law 15-176</law-cite>, in par. (7), substituted “parent and child, or domestic partners as defined in § <cite path="§32-701">32-701</cite>(3)” for “or parent and child,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-293">D.C. Law 15-293</law-cite>, in par. (3), substituted “for recordation; provided further, that this exemption shall not apply to property which is exempt under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(29);” for “for recordation;”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</law-cite>, in par. (7), substituted “parent and child, grandparent and grandchild, or domestic partners,” for “or parent and child, or domestic partners”; in par. (26), substituted a semicolon for “; and”; in par. (27), substituted “; and” for a period; and added par. (28).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-91">D.C. Law 16-91</law-cite>, in pars. (26), (27), and (28), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</law-cite>, in par. (3), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</law-cite>, in par. (28), substituted “has a disability” for “is disabled”, “trust beneficiary with a disability” for “disabled trust beneficiary” and “beneficiary with a disability” for “disabled beneficiary”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-118">D.C. Law 17-118</law-cite>, in par. (3), inserted “or § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(30)”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</law-cite>, in par. (7), substituted “spouses” for “husband and wife”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-60">D.C. Law 19-60</law-cite> added par. (29).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</law-cite> repealed (16), which read: “A deed that conveys an economic interest in improved residential real property that is owned by a cooperative housing association”; added (30), (31) and (32); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</law-cite> substituted “§ <cite path="§29-204.06">29-204.06</cite>” for “§ <cite path="§29-1013">29-1013</cite>” in (22)(A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> rewrote (32).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</law-cite>, repealed before its effective date, would have added (33).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</law-cite> added (33) and (34), and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 6(b) of the Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</law-cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of the Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project Tax Deferral Temporary Act of 2002 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-143">D.C. Law 14-143</law-cite>, May 21, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 5060).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 10(a) of the Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</law-cite>, Oct. 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 10(a) of the Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2002 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</law-cite>, Mar. 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of East of the River Hospital Revitalization Tax Exemption Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-76">D.C. Law 17-76</law-cite>, January 23, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 1456).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2(a), 3(a) of Cooperative Housing Association Economic Interest Recordation Tax Temporary Amendment Act of 2009 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-109">D.C. Law 18-109</law-cite>, March 3, 2010, law notification  57 DCR 2828).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(a) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-295">D.C. Law 18-295</law-cite> repealed par. (16) as of October 1, 2009; in par. (27), deleted “and”; in par. (28)(B)(ii)(II), substituted a semicolon for a period; and added pars. (29) and (30), which had read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(29) Beginning October 1, 2009, a security interest instrument pertaining to a cooperative housing association; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(30) Beginning October 1, 2009, a deed of economic interest pertaining to a limited-equity cooperative, as defined under D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§47-802">47-802</cite>(11).”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-295">D.C. Law 18-295</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(a) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-74">D.C. Law 19-74</law-cite> repealed par. (16) as of October 1, 2009; in par. (27), deleted “and” from the end; in par. (28)(B)(ii)(II), substituted a semicolon for a period; and added pars. (29) and (30) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(29) Beginning October 1, 2009, a security interest instrument pertaining to a cooperative housing association; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(30) Beginning October 1, 2009, a deed of economic interest pertaining to a limited-equity cooperative, as defined under D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§47-802">47-802</cite>(11).”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 103 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-226">D.C. Law 19-226</law-cite> amended (32) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(32) A deed to property if the Mayor has certified that the property and purchaser are eligible for exemption from property taxation pursuant to D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§47-1005.02">47-1005.02</cite>.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 402(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-226">D.C. Law 19-226</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(t)(1) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-179">D.C. Law 20-179</law-cite>, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 7(a) of the Correctional Treatment Facility Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-457, December 13, 1996,  44 DCR 156), and § 7(a) of the Correctional Treatment Facility Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-32, March 11, 1997,  44 DCR 1908).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of the Gallery Place Economic Development Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-500, January 5, 2001,  48 DCR 562).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6(b) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project Tax Deferral Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-227, January 8, 2002,  49 DCR 682).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project Tax Deferral Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-563, December 23, 2002,  50 DCR 278).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 3 and 5 of Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project Tax Deferral Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-345, April 24, 2002,  49 DCR 4300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 10(a) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 10(a) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 10(a) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project Tax Deferral Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-36, March 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 1212, 1296, 1298, 1299 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6 of Finance and Revenue Technical Amendments Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-585, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 340).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of East of the River Hospital Revitalization Tax Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-174, November 2, 2007,  54 DCR 11216).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 201 of Arthur Capper/Carrollsburg Public Improvement Revenue Bonds Technical Correction Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-318, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3418).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2(a), 3(a) of Cooperative Housing Association Economic Interest Recordation Tax Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-234, November 20, 2009,  56 DCR 9046).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Cooperative Housing Association Economic Interest Recordation Tax Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-570, October 20, 2010,  57 DCR 10084).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Cooperative Housing Association Economic Interest Recordation Tax Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-12, February 11, 2011,  58 DCR 1433).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Cooperative Housing Association Economic Interest Recordation Tax Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-194, October 18, 2011,  58 DCR 9160).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7102(a) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7102(a) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of (32), see § 103 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-482, October 12, 2012,  59 DCR 12478).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of (32), see § 103 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-604, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1045), applicable as of January 10, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of provisions concerning new issue bond program recordation tax refund, see § 2 of the New Issue Bond Program Recordation Tax Refund Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-141, July 31, 2013,  60 DCR 11794, 20 DCSTAT 1986).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7152 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7152 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 203 of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-342, May 28, 2014,  61 DCR 5691).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 203 of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-409, Aug. 1, 2014,  61 DCR 8281).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 7042 and 7113(d) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 7032 and 7103(d) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</law-cite>, § 7103(d), see § 2(n) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014, 61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 7032 and 7103(d) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</law-cite>, § 7103(d), see § 2(n) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle Z of title I of Law 16-33: Section 1211 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</law-cite> provided that subtitle Z of title I of the act may be cited as the Family Property Recordation and Transfer Tax Exemption Act of 2005.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle KK of title I of Law 16-33: Section 1295 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</law-cite> provided that subtitle KK of title I of the act may be cited as the Disabled Property Owners Tax Reduction Act of 2005.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 7151 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that Subtitle O of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Tax Clarification Amendment Act of 2013”.</text>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 5 of Law 14-232 provided that this act shall take effect subject to the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability and expiration of subtitle KK of title I, §§ 1295 to 1300, of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</law-cite>: Sections 1298 and 1299, as amended by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</law-cite>, § 7068(l), (m) provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 1298. Conditional applicability.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) Sections 1296 and 1297 shall apply for taxable years beginning after September 30, 2005.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) Repealed.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 1299. Repealed.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-60">D.C. Law 19-60</law-cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 8-20: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-1101">42-1101</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 6 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 9-56">D.C. Law 9-56</law-cite> provided that the Mayor shall, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, issue rules to implement the provisions of the act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 5 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 9-120">D.C. Law 9-120</law-cite> provided that the Mayor may, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, issue rules to implement the provisions of the act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 10-128: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-1101">42-1101</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-176">D.C. Law 15-176</law-cite>: Section 7 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-176">D.C. Law 15-176</law-cite> provided: “Sections 2 through 6 shall apply as of October 1, 2003.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-60">D.C. Law 19-60</law-cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 3. Applicability.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">The Budget Director of the Council of the District of Columbia has determined that as of September 20, 2012, the fiscal effect of Law 19-60 has been included in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore, the provisions of this section, enacted by Law 19-60, are in effect.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite>: Section 7152(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that § 7152(a) (which amended § <cite path="§42-1102">42-1102</cite>(32)) shall apply as of September 20, 2012.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</law-cite> became effective on Dec. 4, 2014, but was repealed prior to its effective date by emergency D.C. Act 20-377, § 7114, eff. July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, by emergency D.C. Act 20-449, § 7104, eff. October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, by emergency D.C. Act 20-566, § 7104, eff. January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, and by D.C. Law (Act 20-424), § 7104,  61 DCR 9990.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
