<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-2702.03</num>
  <heading>Executive Director; powers and duties; service as Secretary of Board; other necessary employees; rights and privileges thereof.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Directors shall appoint an Executive Director who shall be an employee of the Agency, but who shall not be a member of the Board, and who shall serve at the pleasure of the Board and receive such compensation as shall be fixed by the Board. The Executive Director shall be appointed by the Board with the advice and consent of the Council. The Executive Director shall administer, manage and direct the affairs and activities of the Agency in accordance with the policies, control and direction of the Board. The Executive Director shall approve all accounts for salaries, allowable expenses of the Agency or of any employee or consultant thereof, and expenses incidental to the operation of the Agency. He shall perform such other duties as may be directed by the Board in carrying out the purposes of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall be a District resident throughout his or her term and failure to maintain District residency shall result in a forfeiture of the position.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall be Secretary to the Board. He shall attend the meetings of the Board, shall keep a record of the proceedings of the Board, and shall maintain and be custodian of all books, documents and papers filed with the Board, of the minutes book or journal of the Board and of its official seal.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Executive Director may employ on a permanent or temporary basis such employees, including, but not limited to, technical advisors, financial advisors, accountants, legal counsel, appraisers, underwriters, and such other officers, agents and employees deemed necessary to operate the Agency efficiently, and shall determine their qualifications, duties, and compensation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2, each qualified District resident applicant shall receive an additional 10-point preference over a qualified non-District resident applicant for all positions within the Agency unless the applicant declines the preference. This 10-point preference shall be in addition to, and not instead of, qualifications established for the position. All persons hired after February 6, 2008, shall submit 8 proofs of residency upon employment in a manner determined by the Board of Directors. An applicant claiming the hiring preference under this section shall agree in writing to maintain bona fide District residency for a period of 7 consecutive years from the effective date of hire and shall provide proof of such residency annually to the director of personnel for the Agency for the first 7 years of employment. Failure to maintain District residency for the consecutive 7-year period shall result in forfeiture of employment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-135" type="History" path="§203">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-135, § 203, 25 DCR 5008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-44" type="History">Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-44, § 2(b), 32 DCR 4487</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-247" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-247, § 2(d), 46 DCR 1100</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-108" type="History">Feb. 6, 2008, D.C. Law 17-108, § 215(a), 54 DCR 10993</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2113.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 45-1905.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-108">D.C. Law 17-108</law-cite> added subsec. (a-1); and, in subsec. (c), designated par. (1) and added par. (2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Act Amendment Temporary Act of 1985 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 6-4">D.C. Law 6-4</law-cite>, May 9, 1985, law notification 32 DCR ]).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Supersedure of Law 6-4: Section 3(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 6-44">D.C. Law 6-44</law-cite> provided that upon October 5, 1985, the act shall supersede the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Amendment Act Temporary Act of 1985, effective May 9, 1985 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 6-4">D.C. Law 6-4</law-cite>).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
