<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-2853.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Administrative costs” means the costs of the Department to administer, manage, and monitor the low-income housing tax credit program, including personnel costs, whether incurred before or after April 8, 2005.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Developer” means a person or entity that proposes to cause the construction affordable housing using tax credits provided under the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Fund” means the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Fund established by § <cite path="§42-2853.02">42-2853.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Program” means the program authorized by section 42 of the Internal Revenue Code [26 U.S.C. § 42].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“User fee” means a fee charged by the Department to a developer in connection with the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Program, including application, reservation, allocation, and monitoring fees.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-299" type="History" path="§2">Apr. 8, 2005, D.C. Law 15-299, § 2, 52 DCR 1502</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Fund Temporary Act of 2004 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-230">D.C. Law 15-230</law-cite>, March 16, 2005, law notification  52 DCR 3556).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) fund provisions, see § 2 of Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Non-Reverting/Non Lapsing Proprietary Fund Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-511, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8969).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) fund provisions, see § 2 of Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Fund Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-730, January 19, 2005,  52 DCR 1958).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) fund provisions, see § 2 of Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Fund Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-39, February 17, 2005,  52 DCR 3037).</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 42 of the Internal Revenue Code, referred to in par. (5), is classified to  26 U.S.C. § 42.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
