<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2013</num>
  <heading>Bylaws — Availability for examination; made part of declaration; amendment; compliance mandatory.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The administration of every project constituted into a horizontal property regime shall be governed by the bylaws as the council of co-owners may from time to time adopt, which said bylaws together with the declaration, including recorded attachments thereto, referred to in § <cite path="§42-2006">42-2006</cite> shall be available for examination by all the co-owners, their duly authorized attorneys or agents, at convenient hours on working days that shall be set and announced for general knowledge.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A true copy of said bylaws shall be annexed to the declaration referred to in § <cite path="§42-2006">42-2006</cite> and made a part thereof. No modification of or amendment to the bylaws shall be valid unless set forth in an amendment to the declaration and such amendment is duly recorded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each unit owner shall comply strictly with the bylaws and with the administrative rules and regulations adopted pursuant thereto, as either of the same may be lawfully amended from time to time. Failure to comply with any of the same shall be ground for an action to recover sums due, for damages or injunctive relief, or both, maintainable by the manager, the administrator, board of directors or of administration, or as specified in the bylaws or in proper case, by an aggrieved unit owner.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-218" type="History">Dec. 21, 1963, 77 Stat. 454, Pub. L. 88-218, § 13</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-3" type="History">May 22, 1975, D.C. Law 1-3, § 2(2), 21 DCR 3945</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-1713.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-913.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Supersedure of chapter: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-2001">42-2001</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
