<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2141</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Affordable housing unit” means a unit of housing that is offered for rent or for sale for residential occupancy and as a result of a federal or District subsidy is made available and affordable to households whose income levels are less than or equal to 120% of the area median income.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Area median income” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>For a household of 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the periodic calculation provided by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For a household of 3 persons, 90% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>For a household of 2 persons, 80% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>For a household of one person, 70% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>For a household of more than 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons, increased by 10% for each household member exceeding 4 persons (for example, the area median income for a family of 5 shall be 110% of the area median income for a family of 4; the area median income for a household of 6 shall be 120% of the area median income for a family of 4).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Extremely low-income” means a household income equal to 30% or less of the area median income.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Homeless” means a person:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Who is lacking a fixed, regular residence that provides safe housing and the financial means to acquire such a residence immediately; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Whose primary night-time residence is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>A supervised publicly or privately operated shelter or transitional housing facility designed to provide temporary living accommodations; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>A public or private place not designed for, or ordinarily used as, a regular sleeping accommodation for human beings.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Low-income” means a household income equal to, or less than, 80% of the area median income and greater than 50% of the area median income.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Very low-income” means a household income equal to, or less than, 50% of the area median income and greater than 30% of the area median income.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2092, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
