<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-2802</num>
  <heading>Housing Production Trust Fund established.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Housing Production Trust Fund as a permanent revolving special revenue fund within the Governmental Funds of the District apart from the General Fund consisting of identifiable, renewable, and segregated capital, which shall be administered by the Department to provide assistance in housing production for targeted populations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used to provide:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Pre-development loans for nonprofit housing developers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Grants for architectural designs for adaptive re-use of previously nonresidential structures;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Loans to develop housing and provide housing services for low- and very low-income elderly persons who have special needs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Bridge loans and gap financing to reduce up-front costs and costs of residential development and to keep a housing project in operation, if circumstances change adversely during development;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Loans for first-effort model projects;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Financing for the construction of new housing, or rehabilitation or preservation of existing housing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Financing for site acquisition, construction loan guarantees, collateral, or operating capital;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Loans or grants to finance on-site child development facilities for proposed housing or commercial development projects;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8A)</num>
      <text>Loans authorized through the Homestead Housing Preservation Program in § <cite path="§42-2107">42-2107</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8B)</num>
      <text>Payments to a person contracted to perform services under § <cite path="§42-2105.01">42-2105.01</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Other loans and grants for housing production determined by the Department to be consistent with the purposes of this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Funds for the administration of the Fund, not to exceed 10% in fiscal year 2009 or earlier, not to exceed 15% in fiscal year 2010, not to exceed 15% in fiscal year 2011, and not to exceed 10% in fiscal year 2012 or later of the funds deposited into the Fund pursuant to subsection (c) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Funds for the New Communities Initiative as that term is defined in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph; provided, that the use of the funds for the initiative is consistent with the provisions and purposes of this section and meets the requirements of § <cite path="§42-2812.03">42-2812.03</cite>(d) and the rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term “New Communities Initiative” means a large scale and comprehensive plan, submitted by the Mayor to the Council for approval, that provides housing infrastructure with a special focus on public housing, provides critical social support services, decreases the concentration of poverty and crime, enhances access to education, and provides training and employment education to neighborhoods where crime, unemployment, and truancy converge to create intractable physical and social conditions.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least 40% of the funds disbursed from the Fund during a fiscal year shall be for the purposes of assisting in the provision of housing opportunities for very low-income households, which includes individuals who have previously been incarcerated for or convicted of a felony under state or federal law and who are otherwise entitled to services and assistance pursuant to this chapter, including maximizing the possibility of home ownership. The Mayor may submit a written request to the Council for a waiver of the 40% requirement if, by the 4th quarter of the fiscal year, the Mayor has not received a sufficient number of viable housing proposals. The Council shall approve or disapprove the waiver by resolution within 30 days, and the resolution shall be deemed disapproved if the Council does not act within this 30-day period.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At least 40% of the funds disbursed from the Fund during a fiscal year shall be for the purposes of assisting in the provision of housing opportunities for extremely low-income households, including maximizing the possibility of home ownership. The Mayor may submit a written request to the Council for a waiver of the 40% requirement if, by the 4th quarter of the fiscal year, the Mayor has not received a sufficient number of viable housing proposals. The Council shall approve or disapprove the waiver by resolution within 30 days, and the resolution shall [be] deemed disapproved if the Council does not act within this 30-day period.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>At least 50% of the funds disbursed from the Fund during a fiscal year shall be for the purposes of assisting in the provision of rental housing. The Mayor may submit a written request to the Council for a waiver of the 50% requirement if, in the 3rd quarter of the fiscal year, the Mayor has not received a sufficient number of viable rental housing proposals. The Council shall approve or disapprove the waiver by resolution within 30 days, and the resolution shall be deemed approved if the Council does not act within the 30-day period.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-2)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An amount not to exceed $16 million of the funds deposited into the Fund may be used by the Mayor to secure bonds issued for the benefit of the New Communities Initiative or other purposes consistent with the Housing Production Trust Fund uses and pursuant to subsection (b)(11) of this section; provided, that securitization above $16 million may only occur upon certification by the Mayor that resources are needed to fulfill the New Communities projects.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Council authorization by act shall be required for any amount above $16 million in the Fund to secure financing for the New Community Initiative or other purposes consistent with the Housing Production Trust Fund uses.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall not apply to the new issuance of bonds after May 1, 2013.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-3)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or any other law to the contrary, $4 million of the funds deposited into the Fund may be made available by the Mayor to the Workforce Housing Land Trust. The uses of the funds shall be governed exclusively by the provisions of the Land Trust Plan and the requirements of subchapter III-A of Chapter 10 of Title 6 [§ <cite path="§6-1061.01">6-1061.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-4)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or any other law, the Mayor may transfer an amount not to exceed $18 million from the Fund to the Rent Supplement Fund established by § <cite path="§6-226">6-226</cite>(d)(1), for the purpose of funding in fiscal year 2012 the assistance programs set forth in §§ <cite path="§6-226">6-226</cite> through <cite path="§6-229">6-229</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>None of the funds transferred to the Rent Supplement Fund pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be used for administrative costs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If, pursuant to the Contingency for Additional Estimated Revenue Act of 2011, effective September 20, 2012 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite>; 59 DCR 8025) [Subtitle P of Title VII of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>], the appropriation for the District of Columbia Housing Authority is increased by an amount by which a revised revenue estimate exceeds the revenue estimate of the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia dated February 28, 2011, the transfer set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be reduced by an equal amount.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-5)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>There shall be deposited in the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fee option contributions made by commercial developers under a commercial linked development policy to be established by statute by the Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Community development program contributions made pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 7 of Title 26, as determined by the Superintendent of Banking and Financial Institutions in consultation with the Department;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Appropriated amounts;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Grants, fees, donations, or gifts from public and private sources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Repayments of principal and interest on loans provided from the Fund;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Proceeds realized from the liquidation of security interests held by the District under terms of assistance provided from the Fund;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Interest earned from the deposit or investment of monies from the Fund;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>All revenues, receipts, and fees of whatever source derived from the operation of the Fund;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Any fee or portion of an application fee that the Zoning Commission, by rule, may require an applicant for a Planned Unit Development to pay when the applicant proposes a housing production option or fee option in connection with a planned unit development application, to the extent that the Zoning Commission designates that the fee or portion of that fee shall be allocable to the Fund;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Available community development block grants;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Repayments of loans, including principal and interest, provided under § <cite path="§42-2107">42-2107</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Proceeds realized from the liquidation of any security interests held by the District under the terms of assistance provided from the fund through the Homestead Housing Preservation Program established in Chapter 21 of this title;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>$5 million on October 1, 2002;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>Beginning October 1, 2003, 15% of the real property transfer tax imposed by § <cite path="§47-903">47-903</cite> and 15% of the deed recordation tax imposed by § <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite>; provided, that if, in any fiscal year, the Chief Financial Officer certifies the proposed budget will not be balanced as required by § <cite path="§1-206.03">1-206.03</cite>(c) if the provisions of this paragraph take effect, the applicable percentage for the fiscal year shall be the amount derived from the available general fund balance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16A)</num>
      <text>[Not funded].</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>All fines collected pursuant to § <cite path="§6-1041.03">6-1041.03</cite>, which shall be used exclusively to fund the Mayor’s purchase of dwelling units for sale or rental to low- and moderate-income households as authorized by § <cite path="§6-1041.04">6-1041.04</cite>(c).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Department shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Periodically review Fund revenue sources to determine what additional revenue sources may be required to assure the continuation of the Fund and its programs and shall request Council action to access revenue sources otherwise unavailable to the Department;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>File with the Chairperson of the Committee on Economic Development quarterly reports on activities and expenditures;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Conduct annual audits, publish annual reports, hold public hearings, and make annual assessments of the continued housing needs of targeted populations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Monitor for compliance written agreements entered into by the Department and commercial developers pursuant to this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Provide outreach and housing production counseling and technical assistance to individuals or groups interested in producing housing for targeted populations as provided in § <cite path="§42-2803">42-2803</cite>(b);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Encourage profit and nonprofit developers to produce housing units of 3 or more bedrooms designed to accommodate large families and to produce child development facilities in a housing development;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Give priority to nonprofit housing developers for receipt of loans from the Fund; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other applicable law, ensure that the provisions of § <cite path="§42-2802.02">42-2802.02</cite> are enforced.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-202" type="History" path="§3">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-202, § 3, 36 DCR 444</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-114" type="History">Apr. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-114, §§ 501(b), 802, 49 DCR 1468</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1102, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-307" type="History">June 5, 2003, D.C. Law 14-307, § 302, 49 DCR 11664</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 222(b), 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105,§§ 74(a)(2), (d), 75(a), 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 2012(b), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-357" type="History">May 24, 2005, D.C. Law 15-357, § 402, 52 DCR 1999</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2172(b), 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, §§ 5(n), 63, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-192" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-192, § 2062(a), 53 DCR 6899</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-275" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-275, § 203, 54 DCR 880</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20" type="History">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 2402(a), 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-219" type="History">Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 2010, 55 DCR 7598</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-285" type="History">Dec. 24, 2008, D.C. Law 17-285, § 3(b), 55 DCR 11986</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-365" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-365, § 2, 56 DCR 1217</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2101, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 2092, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 2033, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2072, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, §§ 2072, 2122(a), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-190" type="History">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-190, § 2(a), 61 DCR 12156</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-208" type="History">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-208, § 2(b), 61 DCR 12725</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle A of title XI of Law 14-190: Section 1101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite> provided that subtitle A of title XI of the act may be cited as the Housing Production Trust Fund Amendment Act of 2002.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2061 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</cite> provided that subtitle E of title II of the act may be cited as the “Housing Production Trust Fund and New Communities Financing Clarification Act of 2006”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite> provided that subtitle S of title II of the act may be cited as the “New Communities Amendment Act of 2007”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2100 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle K of title II of the act may be cited as the “Housing Production Trust Fund Amendment Act of 2009”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2091 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle I of title II of the act may be cited as the “Housing Production Trust Fund and Affordable Housing Production Report Amendment Act of 2010”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 2071 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle H of Title II of the act may be cited as the “Housing Production Trust Fund Revenue Dedication Emergency Amendment Act of 2013”.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">For approval of the Northwest One Redevelopment Plan and authorization of the Mayor to exercise eminent domain authority in the area bounded by North Capitol Street, N.E., K Street, N.E., New Jersey Avenue, N.E., and New York Avenue, N.E., see the Northwest One/Sursum Corda Affordable Housing Protection, Preservation and Production Act of 2006, effective November 16, 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-188">D.C. Law 16-188</cite>;  53 DCR 6750).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-365">D.C. Law 17-365</cite> provided that this act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">The Budget Director of the Council of the District of Columbia has determined, as of February 15, 2012, that the fiscal effect of Law 17-365 has not been included in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore, the provisions of this section, enacted by Law 17-365, are not in effect.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-208">D.C. Law 20-208</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-208">D.C. Law 20-208</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority to Acquire Certain Real Estate in the District of Columbia, see Mayor’s Order 2007-81, April 2, 2007 (54</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2072 and 2122(a) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2072 and 2122(a) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Housing Production Trust Fund Pollin Memorial Community Dedicated Tax Appropriations Authorization Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-62, May 11, 2011,  58 DCR 4242).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2092 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 302 of Fiscal Year 2010 Balanced Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-531, August 6, 2010,  57 DCR 8109).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 302 of Fiscal Year 2010 Balanced Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-450, June 28, 2010,  57 DCR 5635).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2101 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2101 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Workforce Housing Production Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-440, July 16, 2008,  55 DCR 8290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Workforce Housing Production Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-201, November 26, 2007,  54 DCR 11903).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Workforce Housing Production Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-104, July 27, 2007, 54 DCR ).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2402(a) of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2062(a) of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-1, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1165).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of District of Columbia Housing Authority northwest One/Temple Courts Subsidiary Establishment Approval Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-664, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1127).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2062(a) of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-499, October 23, 2006,  53 DCR 8845).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2062(a) of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-477, August 8, 2006,  53 DCR 7068).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2172(b) of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2012(b) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2012(b) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 302 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Housing Production Trust Fund Continuing Basis Definition Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-61, April 16, 2003,  50 DCR 3379).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 302 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1102 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Housing Production Trust Fund Continuing Basis Definition Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-599, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 661).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 302 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Housing Production Trust Fund Affordability Period Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-536, December 2, 2002,  49 DCR 11648).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2002(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-222">D.C. Law 18-222</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) Not to exceed 10% in fiscal year 2012 or later; and”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) Not to exceed 15% in fiscal year 2011; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Not to exceed 15% in fiscal year 2010;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) Not to exceed 10% in fiscal year 2009 or earlier;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(10) Beginning on October 1, 2009, funds for the administration of the Fund deposited into the fund pursuant to subsection (c) of this section:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 302 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-222">D.C. Law 18-222</cite> rewrote subsec. (b)(10) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Workforce Housing Production Program Temporary Amendment Act of 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-244">D.C. Law 17-244</cite>, October 21, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 11707).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Workforce Housing Production Program Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-44">D.C. Law 17-44</cite>, November 24, 2007, law notification  55 DCR 3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Housing Production Trust Fund Continuing Basis Definition Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-304">D.C. Law 14-304</cite>, May 3, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 3778).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Housing Production Trust Fund Affordability Period Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-298">D.C. Law 14-298</cite>, April 11, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 5856).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-208">D.C. Law 20-208</cite> would have added (c-1) to read as follows: “(c-1) There is authorized to be appropriated at least $ 100 million annually, from all sources, to be deposited into, and expended from, the Fund.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment  by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-190">D.C. Law 20-190</cite> rewrote (d)(8).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed (b-5); and added (b-2)(3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added (b-5).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> added subsec. (b-4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in subsec. (b)(10), substituted “not to exceed 10% in fiscal year 2009 or earlier, not to exceed 15% in fiscal year 2010, not to exceed 15% in fiscal year 2011, and not to exceed 10% in fiscal year 2012 or later” for “not to exceed in a fiscal year, beginning in fiscal year 2009, 10%”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, in subsec. (b)(10), substituted “, beginning in fiscal year 2009, 10%” for “5%”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-365">D.C. Law 17-365</cite>, in subsec. (c), deleted “and” from the end of par. (16) and added par. (16A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-285">D.C. Law 17-285</cite> added subsec. (b-3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> repealed subsec. (c)(9), which had read as follows: “(9) Lease payments from loans received under the Land Acquisitions for Housing Development Opportunities Program;”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite>, in subsec. (b-2)(1), substituted “$16 million” for “12 million” in two places, and inserted “; provided, that securitization above $16 million may only occur upon certification by the Mayor that resources are needed to fulfill the New Communities projects”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-275">D.C. Law 16-275</cite> added subsec. (c)(17).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</cite> rewrote subsecs. (a) and (b-2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in subsec. (b)(10), inserted “of this section” and validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite>, in subsecs. (b)(8B) and (b)(9), “and” was deleted from the end of the subsections; in subsec. (b)(10), substituted “fiscal year; and” for “fiscal year.”; and added subsecs. (b)(11) and (b-2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-357">D.C. Law 15-357</cite>, in subsec. (b-1)(A), substituted “very low-income households, which includes individuals who have previously been incarcerated for or convicted of a felony under state or federal law and who are otherwise entitled to services and assistance pursuant to this chapter,” for “very low-income households,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, in par. (10) of subsec. (b), substituted “deposited into the Fund pursuant to subsection (c)” for “expended from the Fund during the fiscal year”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in par. (9) of subsec. (b), and pars. (12) to (16) of subsec. (c), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite>, in subsec. (d)(8), substituted “targeted populations; provided, that the Department shall not be required to assure affordability on a continuing basis where assistance is provided for the rehabilitation of owner-occupied single-family homes or where assistance is provided under Chapter 21 of Title 42 or another statutory program” for “targeted populations”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “$5 million” for “$11.5 million” in par. (15), and validated a previously made technical correction in par. (16).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(13) Proceeds realized from the sale of abandoned or deteriorated properties pursuant to Title VIII of the Housing Act of 2001, unless those properties are sold pursuant to Chapter 21 of this title; and”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(12) Beginning October 1, 2002, 15% of the real property transfer tax imposed by § <cite path="§47-903">47-903</cite> and 15% of the deed recordation tax imposed by § <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite>;”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite>, in subsec. (c), repealed pars. (12) and (13), and added pars. (15) and (16). Prior to repeal, pars. (12) and (13) read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-114">D.C. Law 14-114</cite>, in subsec. (b)(3), substituted “low- and very low-income” for “low- and moderate- income”; in subsec. (b)(8), substituted a semicolon for “; and”; added subsecs. (b)(8A) and (b)(8B); in subsec. (b)(9), substituted “other Loans and grants” for “other loans”, and substituted “; and” for a period at the end; added subsecs. (b)(10) and (b-1); added subsecs. (c)(12), (13), and (14); in subsec. (c)(12), substituted a semicolon for “; and”; in subsec. (c)(13), substituted a semicolon for a period; and, in subsec. (d)(2), deleted “Housing and” following “Committee on”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-3102.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-1054">6-1054</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1061.02">6-1061.02</cite>, § <cite path="§10-801">10-801</cite>, § <cite path="§38-2972.01">38-2972.01</cite>, § <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite>, § <cite path="§42-1122">42-1122</cite>, § <cite path="§42-2801">42-2801</cite>, § <cite path="§42-2812.01">42-2812.01</cite>, § <cite path="§42-2812.02">42-2812.02</cite>, § <cite path="§47-903">47-903</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-919">47-919</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
