<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-2901</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the District of Columbia Department of Public and Assisted Housing Development.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“First-time homebuyer” means a purchaser who has no ownership interest in a principal residence at any time during the 3-year period ending on the date of the application for assistance, but includes an applicant who has divorced or separated during the 3-year period where a formal settlement did not convey an ownership interest in a principal residence which had been jointly owned.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Housing unit” means any room or group of rooms forming a single-family residential unit, including a semi-detached condominium, cooperative, or semi-detached or detached home that is intended to be used or used for living, sleeping, and the preparation and eating of meals by human occupants.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Police officer” means officers of all ranks employed by the District of Columbia Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-70" type="History" path="§2">Feb. 23, 1994, D.C. Law 10-70, § 2, 40 DCR 7575</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2231.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program and Community Safety Temporary Act of 1993 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-63">D.C. Law 10-63</cite>, October 8, 1993, law notification 40 DCR ]).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-70">D.C. Law 10-70</cite> provided that the Mayor shall, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, issue rules within 90 days after February 23, 1994, to implement the provisions of this chapter. The rules shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Report on cost of tax exemption for police substations: Section 6 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-70">D.C. Law 10-70</cite> provided that six months from February 23, 1994, the Department of Finance and Revenue shall submit a report to the Council on the fiscal impact of providing a real property tax exemption to that portion of the real property belonging to any individual, partnership, or corporation that is provided rent free to the District for use solely by the Metropolitan Police Department as a police substation. The exemption shall be applicable only while the property is used as an active police substation.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: (1) An application procedure for the Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program; and.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">(2) A standard of eligibility and selection of Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program applicants. The Mayor may establish priorities for eligibility based on length of residency in the District, geographic location, or other means as deemed appropriate.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Report on fiscal impact: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-70">D.C. Law 10-70</cite> provided that at the end of 1 year from the issuance of regulations to implement this chapter, similar incentives for teachers and firefighters shall be considered, and the Department of Finance and Revenue shall submit a report to the Council on the fiscal impact of these incentives.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
