<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2702.07</num>
  <heading>Agency reports; Council review and approval of proposals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Directors of the Agency shall determine, by enactment of an eligibility resolution that a housing project or homeownership program contemplated to be financed through a bond issuance meets the requirements of this chapter. Subsequent to enactment of an eligibility resolution, the Agency shall send to the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia written notification thereof, describing the nature of the housing project, the benefits designed to result therefrom, as related to the public purposes of the Agency, and the criteria under which funds will be made available.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>Each notification transmitted to the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia shall set forth information pertaining to the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Date of application;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Name and description of the project;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Address and ward location of the project;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Developer of the project;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Amount and type of financing requested;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Amount and type of federal or District funds involved; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The number of units reserved for very-low, low and moderate income persons, income restrictions, and rent levels.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Agency may not adopt an inducement resolution or a resolution authorizing a bond issuance to fund a project nor may the agency implement a proposed housing program submitted in accordance with this section unless the proposal has been submitted to the Council for a 30-day review period, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days of Council recess. During the Council review period, comments of the Council representative from the affected ward shall be considered.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If, during the 30-day review period, the Council does not adopt a resolution disapproving the proposal, the Agency may take action to implement the proposal. The Council may adopt a resolution approving the proposal prior to expiration of the 30-day period in which case the Agency may take immediate action to implement the proposal.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In the event a proposal is disapproved, the resolution shall state the reasons for disapproval. The Agency staff may modify the proposal to address the concerns expressed in the resolution of disapproval and may without further action of the Board resubmit the proposal, as modified, for a 30-day review period, excluding days of Council recess. If, during the 30-day review period the Council does not adopt a resolution disapproving the resubmitted proposal, the Agency may take action to implement the proposal. The Council may adopt a resolution approving the resubmitted proposal prior to the expiration of the 30-day review period in which case the Agency may take immediate action to implement the proposal. For purposes of this section the term “proposal” shall include housing projects and programs.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-135" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-135, § 207</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-44" type="History">as added Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-44, § 2(d), 32 DCR 4487</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-192" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-192, § 12, 33 DCR 7836</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-247" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-247, § 2(g), 46 DCR 1100</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000, D.C. Law 13-91, § 154, 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-209">6-209</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2117.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, validating a previously made technical amendment struck the phrase “(1) Each notification transmitted to the Chairman” and inserted the phrase “(a-1) Each notification transmitted to the Chairman” in its place.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Act Amendment Temporary Act of 1985 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 6-4">D.C. Law 6-4</cite>, May 9, 1985, law notification 32 DCR ]).</annotation>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 13-183, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Stanton Glenn Apartments Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1999”, was approved effective July 6, 1999.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 13-184, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Widrich Court Apartments Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1999”, was approved effective July 6, 1999.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 13-185, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Garfield Park Apartments Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1999”, was approved effective July 6, 1999.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 13-219, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Fort Chaplin Park Apartments Mortgage Revenue Bonds Emergency Approval Resolution of 1999”, was approved effective July 6, 1999.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 13-354, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Randolph Towers Apartments and Aspen Courts Apartments Mortgage Revenue Bonds Emergency Approval Resolution of 1999”, was approved effective November 2, 1999.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 13-356, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Congress Park I Apartments Mortgage Revenue Bonds Emergency Approval Resolution of 1999”, was approved effective November 2, 1999.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Supersedure of Law 6-4: Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-44">D.C. Law 6-44</cite> provided that upon October 5, 1985, the act shall supersede the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Amendment Act Temporary Act of 1985, effective May 9, 1985 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 6-4">D.C. Law 6-4</cite>).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of Mount Vernon Plaza Apartments as eligible project for financing: Pursuant to Resolution 6-769, the “Mount Vernon Plaza Approval Resolution of 1986,” effective July 8, 1986, the Council approved the Mount Vernon Plaza as an eligible project for financing.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of 1986 Single-Family Forward Commitment Mortgage Purchase Program as eligible for financing: Pursuant to Resolution 6-770, the “Housing Finance Agency Single-Family Forward Commitment Mortgage Purchase Resolution of 1986,” effective July 8, 1986, the Council approved the program as eligible for financing.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of Jeffrey Gardens Apartments Project as eligible for financing: Pursuant to Resolution 7-203, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Jeffrey Gardens Apartments Project Approval Resolution of 1988”, effective January 5, 1988, the Council approved the Jeffrey Gardens Apartments as an eligible project for financing.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of Monroe Tower Apartments Project as eligible for financing: Pursuant to Resolution 7-205, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Monroe Towers Apartments Project Approval Resolution of 1988”, effective January 5, 1988, the Council approved the Monroe Towers Apartments as an eligible project for financing.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of Southern Gardens Apartments Project as eligible for financing: Pursuant to Resolution 7-206, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Southern Gardens Apartments Project Approval Resolution of 1988,” effective January 5, 1988, the Council approved the Southern Gardens Apartments as an eligible project for financing.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of Collateralized Single-Family Mortgage Purchase Program: Pursuant to Resolution 7-271, the “Housing Finance Agency Collateralized Single-Family Mortgage Purchase Resolution of 1988”, effective May 31, 1988, the Council approved the Collateralized Single-Family Mortgage Purchase Program.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of Supplemental Collateralized Single-Family Mortgage Purchase Program: Pursuant to Resolution 7-344, the “Housing Finance Agency Supplemental Collateralized Single-Family Mortgage Purchase Resolution of 1988”, effective November 15, 1988, the Council approved the Supplemental Collateralized Single-Family Mortgage Purchase Program.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for Massachusetts Courts Apartments: Pursuant to Resolution 8-70, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Massachusetts Courts Apartments Approval Resolution of 1989”, effective June 27, 1989, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Agency’s proposal for the Massachusetts Courts Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for Parkchester Apartments: Pursuant to Resolution 8-245, the “D.C. Housing Finance Agency Parkchester Apartments Resolution of 1990,” effective July 27, 1990, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the Parkchester Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Chastleton Apartments Refunding Resolution of 1991: Pursuant to Resolution 9-67, effective June 14, 1991, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the Chastleton Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Mount Vernon Plaza Apartments Refunding Resolution of 1991: Pursuant to Resolution 9-68, effective June 14, 1991, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the Mount Vernon Plaza Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Carmel Plaza North Apartments Refunding Resolution of 1991: Pursuant to Resolution 9-69, effective June 14, 1991, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the Carmel Plaza North Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Parkchester Apartments Project Supplemental Financing Emergency Approval Resolution of 1991: Pursuant to Resolution 9-106, effective July 19, 1991, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s supplemental proposal for the Parkchester Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Housing Finance Agency Savannah Park Apartments Approval Resolution of 1992: Pursuant to Resolution 9-322, effective July 24, 1992, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the Savannah Park Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Housing Finance Agency Cloister (a.k.a. “Trinity” Apartments) Refunding Approval Emergency Resolution of 1993: Pursuant to Resolution 10-160, effective October 5, 1993, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s Proposal for the Cloister (a.k.a. “Trinity”) Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Housing Finance Agency New Amsterdam Apartments Refunding Approval Emergency Resolution of 1993: Pursuant to Resolution 10-162, effective October 5, 1993, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the New Amsterdam Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Tyler House Apartments Multi-Family Housing Revenue Bonds Approval Emergency Resolution of 1994: Pursuant to Resolution 10-493, effective December 6, 1994, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the Tyler House Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Single Family Forward Commitment Mortgage Purchase Program Approval Emergency Resolution of 1994: Pursuant to Resolution 10-495, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the 1994 Single Family Forward Commitment Mortgage Purchase Program.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Livingston Manor Apartments Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Proposed Resolution 11-60, deemed approved April 5, 1995, Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the Livingston Manor Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Benning Road Apartments Multi-Family Housing Revenue Bonds Emergency Approval Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Resolution 11-80, effective June 6, 1995, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the Benning Road Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Capitol Hill Towers Apartments Multi-family Mortgage Revenue Refunding Bonds Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Resolution 11-162, effective November 7, 1995, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal to refund the Capitol Hill Towers Apartment Project bonds.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Agency 1995 Single Family Forward Commitment Mortgage Purchase Program Approval Emergency Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Resolution 11-114, effective July 11, 1995, Council approved, on an emergency basis, District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the 1995 Single Family Forward Commitment Mortgage Purchase Program.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Capitol Park Apartments Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Proposed Resolution 11-263, deemed approved, November 2, 1995, Counsel approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the Capitol Park Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing finance Agency Dakotas Apartments Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Proposed Resolution 11-264, deemed approved, November 2, 1995, Counsel approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the Dakotas Apartments.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Rockburne Estates Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1997: Proposed Resolution 12-0422, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Rockburne Estates Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1997” was deemed approved, effective Nov. 7, 1997.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Haven House Cooperative Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1997: Proposed Resolution 12-0422, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Haven House Cooperative Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1997” was deemed approved, effective Nov. 7, 1997.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency 636 Cooperative Association for Tax Exempt Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-(PR12-592), effective April 1, 1998, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the 636 Cooperative Association.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Archbishop Rivera Y. Damas Cooperative, Inc. Tax-Exempt Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-(PR12-791), effective July 16, 1998, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for Archbishop Rivera Y. Damas Cooperative, Inc.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Wheeler Creek Estates Tax-Exempt Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Approval Emergency Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-620, effective July 7, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s Eligibility Resolution for the Wheeler Creek Estates.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Housing Finance Agency Randolph Street Apartments Tax-Exempt Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-747, effective November 10, 1998, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the acquisition and rehabilitation of the Randolph Street Apartments in Ward 4.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Housing Finance Agency Fort Stevens Apartments Tax-Exempt Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-748, effective November 10, 1998, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the acquisition and rehabilitation of the Fort Stevens Apartments in Ward 4.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Housing Finance Agency Burke Park Apartments Tax-Exempt Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-749, effective November 10, 1998, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the acquisition and rehabilitation of the Burke Park Apartments in Ward 2.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Hamlin &amp; 7th Street Apartments Tax-Exempt Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-750, effective November 10, 1998, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the acquisition and rehabilitation of the Hamlin &amp; 7th Street Apartments in Ward 5.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Finance Agency Stewart Glen Apartments Tax-Exempt Multi-Family Mortgage Revenue Bonds Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-751, effective November 10, 1998, the Council approved the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency’s proposal for the acquisition and rehabilitation of the Stewart Glen Apartments in Ward 8.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
