<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-2110</num>
  <heading>Appropriation; reports.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There may be appropriated out of revenues available to the District sufficient funds to administer the Program. Beginning with the budget submission for Fiscal Year 1988, the Mayor shall include in the budget submission to the Council a statement of goals and objectives regarding the number of properties contemplated for inclusion in the Program in the upcoming fiscal year and a projection of the funds that would be necessary to permit transfer and repair of the property under the Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Thirty days after the end of the 1st full calendar quarter after August 9, 1986, and 30 days after the end of each calendar quarter thereafter, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a report on the progress in implementing the Program. The report shall include, but not be limited to, the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The ward location, size, and assessed value of each property transferred under the Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A list of all properties remaining in the Program at the close of the quarter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The individuals or organizations that were transferees under the Program and the sales price and other terms of transfers made under the Program during the preceding quarter; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A description of assistance provided to transferees under the Program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-135" type="History">Aug. 9, 1986, D.C. Law 6-135, § 11, 33 DCR 3771</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-192" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-192, § 5(h), 33 DCR 7836</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-114" type="History">Apr. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-114, § 801(j), 49 DCR 1468</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2710.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-114">D.C. Law 14-114</law-cite> substituted “Mayor” for “Administrator” throughout section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
