<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2604</num>
  <heading>Promulgation of rules and regulations by Mayor; review by Council; contents of loan agreements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to promulgate rules and regulations to govern the operation of the Fund, including but not limited to, rules and regulations establishing standards for determining the eligibility and selection of applicants; procedures for applying for assistance and for notifying applicants (including the development of appropriate forms); and criteria for determining the terms and conditions under which loans or other forms of financial assistance may be made from the Fund which, among things, shall reflect the ability of the recipient to pay and may provide for the deferred payment or forgiveness of loans. The rules and regulations issued by the Mayor for the purpose of implementing the provisions of this subchapter shall be submitted by the Mayor to the Council of the District of Columbia for a 45 calendar day review period, excluding days of Council recess. No such rules or regulations shall take effect until the end of the 45 calendar day period beginning on the day such rules or regulations are transmitted by the Mayor to the Chairman of the Council, and then only if during such period, the Council does not adopt a resolution disapproving such rules and regulations in whole or in part.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any loan agreement entered into pursuant to such rules and regulations shall provide that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All applicants for and recipients of financial assistance from the Funds shall be tenant organizations (as defined in § <cite path="§42-3401.03">42-3401.03</cite>(18) or a first time homebuyer seeking to purchase housing in the District of Columbia as a primary residence including, but not limited to, single family homes, condominium units, or occupancy rights to cooperative housing. For the purposes of this section, the term “first time homebuyer” means a real property purchaser who had no ownership interest in his or her principal residence at any time during the 3 year period ending on the date of his or her application for assistance, but including an applicant who has divorced or separated during the 3 year period where a formal settlement has been made under which the applicant does not receive an ownership interest in a primary residence which had been jointly owned, and who has no other current ownership interest in residential real property.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1A)</num>
      <text>Priority in the allocation of assistance under the Fund shall be given to residents of the District of Columbia and District of Columbia residents who are low income, elderly, displaced applicants, or residents with disabilities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the home purchased ceases to be the primary residence of the recipient of financial assistance from the Fund, the payments to such Fund by the recipient shall be accelerated on terms and conditions prescribed by the Mayor; provided, that such obligation shall not be inconsistent with the applicable law or regulations of any federal home purchase assistance program made available to the recipient.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-103" type="History">Sept. 12, 1978, D.C. Law 2-103, § 5, 25 DCR 1977</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-44" type="History">Oct. 24, 1981, D.C. Law 4-44, § 2(d), 28 DCR 4265</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-151" type="History">Sept. 23, 1986, D.C. Law 6-151, § 2(b), 33 DCR 4783</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-259" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-259, § 2(b), 46 DCR 1316</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 61, 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Lower income homeownership households, qualifications, see § <cite path="§47-3502">47-3502</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-3502">47-3502</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2204.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 45-1804.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, in subsec. (b)(1A), substituted “displaced applicants, or residents with disabilities” for “handicapped, disabled, or displaced applicants”.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Resolutions">Resolution 16-651, the “Home Purchase Assistance Program Approval Resolution of 2006”, was approved effective May 29, 2006.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Resolutions</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Because of the enactment of subchapter II of this chapter by <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-266">D.C. Law 12-266</cite>, “subchapter” has been substituted for “chapter” in the second sentence of (a).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Home Purchase Assistance Program Loan Repayment Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-(PR12-890), effective October 7, 1998, the Council approved the amendment of Chapter 25 of the Home Purchase Assistance Program Regulations to authorize the use of loan repayment funds to pay reasonable administrative costs associated with making loans.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
