<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2131</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Affordable housing development” means any structure or building in the District (whether existing, planned, or under construction) containing one or more affordable housing units and the land appurtenant thereto, including privately owned units, rental properties, public housing, cooperatives, and limited-equity cooperatives.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Affordable Housing Inventory” means a single, unified, searchable, and sortable database of all affordable housing developments that is maintained by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Affordable Housing Locator” means a list of affordable housing developments generated using data in the Affordable Housing Inventory that the Mayor provides to the public in an effort to assist low-income and moderate-income households locate available affordable housing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Affordable housing unit” means a dwelling that is offered for rent or for sale for residential occupancy and is made available to, and affordable to, a household whose income is equal to, or less than, 120% of AMI, as a result of a federal or District subsidy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“AMI” means the periodic Area Median Income calculation provided by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development as a direct calculation without taking into account any adjustments.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Household” means all the persons who would occupy an affordable housing unit, including a single family, one person living alone, 2 or more families living together, or any other group of related or unrelated persons who share living arrangements.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-215" type="History">Aug. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-215, § 2, 55 DCR 7494</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Because of the codification of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite>, §§ 2092 and 2093 as subchapter II of this chapter, the preexisting text, including §§ <cite path="§42-2131">42-2131</cite> through <cite path="§42-2136">42-2136</cite>, has been designated as subchapter I.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
