<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-2603</num>
  <heading>Availability; use prescribed by Mayor.</heading>
  <text>The Fund shall be available without fiscal year limitation for the purpose of providing financial assistance for down payments or interim financing to recipients for the purpose of purchasing or securing housing, including single family homes, condominium units, or occupancy rights to cooperative housing in the District of Columbia as their principal place of residence and of providing financial assistance to District of Columbia government employees eligible under the District of Columbia Employer-Assisted Housing Program to purchase a home in the District of Columbia. Under terms and conditions prescribed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia (“Mayor”), the Fund shall be used for making loans and providing other forms of financial assistance. The assistance provided pursuant to the Fund may be used in conjunction with other available home assistance programs.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-103" type="History" path="§4">Sept. 12, 1978, D.C. Law 2-103, § 4, 25 DCR 1977</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-44" type="History">Oct. 24, 1981, D.C. Law 4-44, § 2(c), 28 DCR 4265</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-118" type="History">June 11, 1992, D.C. Law 9-118, § 8(c), 39 DCR 3189</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-60" type="History">Mar. 20, 1998, D.C. Law 12-60, § 1101, 44 DCR 7378</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-96" type="History">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-96, § 9(c), 47 DCR 1081</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2203.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 45-1803.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-96">D.C. Law 13-96</cite> rewrote the first sentence which formerly provided: “The Fund shall be available without fiscal year limitation for the purpose of providing financial assistance for down payments or interim financing to recipients for the purpose of purchasing or securing housing, including single family homes, condominium units, or occupancy rights to cooperative housing in the District of Columbia as their principal place of residence and of providing financial assistance to District of Columbia government employees eligible under the District of Columbia Employer-Assisted Housing Program to purchase a home in the District of Columbia.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 9(c) of the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-188, December 1, 1999,  46 DCR 10407).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 9(c) of the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-258, February 9, 2000,  47 DCR 1124).</annotation>
    <text type="Repeal of Law">Repeal of Law 9-118</text>
    <text type="Repeal of Law">Section 1101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-60">D.C. Law 12-60</cite> repealed the District of Columbia Employer-Assisted Housing Act of 1992, <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-118">D.C. Law 9-118</cite>.</text>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 11 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-96">D.C. Law 13-96</cite> provided: “This act shall apply as of October 1, 1997.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
