<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3112</num>
  <heading>Violation of injunction or abatement order.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A violation of any court order issued under this chapter is punishable as a contempt of court.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon finding that a defendant has willfully violated an order issued under this chapter, the court may issue any additional orders necessary to abate the drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related nuisance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon motion, the court may vacate an order or judgment of abatement if the owner of the property satisfies the court that the drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related nuisance has been abated for 90 days prior to the motion, corrects all housing code and health code violations on the property, and deposits a bond in an amount to be determined by the court, which shall be in an amount reasonably calculated to ensure continued abatement of the nuisance. Any bond posted under this subsection shall be forfeited immediately if the drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related nuisance recurs during the 2-year period following the date on which an order under this section is entered. At the close of 2 years following the date on which an order under this section is entered, the bond shall be returned.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-194" type="History">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-194, § 13, 45 DCR 7982</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-81" type="History">Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-81, § 3(b), 53 DCR 1050</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-259" type="History">Nov. 6, 2010, D.C. Law 18-259, § 7(b), 57 DCR 5591</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-3312.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-81">D.C. Law 16-81</cite> substituted “drug or prostitution-related” for “drug-related”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-259">D.C. Law 18-259</cite> substituted “drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related” for “drug or prostitution-related”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-3101">42-3101</cite>.</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of chapter, see notes to § <cite path="§42-3101">42-3101</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
