<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3502.23</num>
  <heading>Addition to Comprehensive Housing Strategy report.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor shall include in the reports to the Council pursuant to § <cite path="§6-1054">6-1054</cite>, analyses of the need, means, and methods of further assisting income qualified elderly tenants, disabled tenants, teachers of the District of Columbia Public Schools or a District of Columbia Public Charter School, and low-income tenants to pay their rent. The report shall consider:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The income and any other criteria that shall be used to determine which tenants qualify for the program;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The rent that qualified households shall pay;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The number and the allocation of units to be included in any set-aside;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The extent to which the program should incorporate any District affordable housing program and any federal affordable housing program available in the District;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The reporting requirements which should be imposed on housing providers subject to this subchapter and on qualified tenants to ensure that the program is effective.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-10" type="History">July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, § 223</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-145" type="History">as added Aug. 5, 2006, D.C. Law 16-145, § 2(g), 53 DCR 4889</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Homestead housing preservation, “low-income persons” defined, see § <cite path="§42-2103">42-2103</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Housing Finance Agency, assisted housing projects, eligibility for rent supplements, see § <cite path="§42-2703.08">42-2703.08</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
