<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3651.04</num>
  <heading>Notice and hearing requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>After a petition has been filed under § <cite path="§42-3651.03">42-3651.03</cite>, the Chief Judge of the Superior Court, or the Judge’s designee, shall immediately issue an order requiring the owner, agent, lessor, or manager, as respondent, to show cause why a receiver should not be appointed. The order shall include a notice that the Court will consider, in addition to the grounds for receivership set forth in § <cite path="§42-3651.02">42-3651.02</cite>, a plan submitted by the respondent to abate the conditions alleged in the petition.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The order of the Court, along with the notice and a copy of the petition, shall be served on the owner of record, and the agent, lessor, or manager, at his or her last known address or by such other method as the Court may direct and shall be posted in a conspicuous place upon the rental housing accommodation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If the petition is not filed by the Office of the Corporation Counsel, the order of the Court, along with a copy of the petition, shall be served on the Corporation Counsel.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>No later than 5 days, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, after receiving a copy of the petition under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs shall make available to the petitioner for its use in the proceedings certified copies of all licensure and housing inspection reports in the custody of the District government that document conditions in the rental housing accommodation within the previous 3 years.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If, upon filing of a petition, the Court finds probable cause to believe a condition or practice in the affected rental housing accommodation poses an immediate danger to the health, safety, or security of the tenants, it may, ex parte, issue an order of not more than 14 days duration appointing a receiver and direct that the order be served along with the notice required by this section; provided, that a hearing be commenced before the expiration of the order.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the event of an ex parte appointment under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the petitioner shall ensure that the owner, agent, lessor, or manager of the rental housing accommodation is served with notice and a copy of the petition, any supporting affidavits, and the order of appointment:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>By personal service within 72 hours after the appointment; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>By notice conspicuously posted inside or on the front door of the rental housing accommodation within 96 hours of the appointment, if the petitioner files with the Court a sworn statement setting forth in detail his diligent effort to serve notice under sub-subparagraph (i) of this subparagraph.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In addition, the petitioner shall serve the order of the Court, along with a copy of the petition, on the owner of record at his or her last known address and his or her agent, lessor, or manager at his or her last known address.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A receiver appointed under subsection (b) of this section may immediately collect all rents or payments for use and occupancy of the affected rental housing accommodation and alleviate the conditions cited by the Court in the order appointing the receiver.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-281" type="History">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-281, § 504, 48 DCR 1888</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-3651.03">42-3651.03</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
