<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3531.03</num>
  <heading>Findings.</heading>
  <text>The Council finds that, despite the fact that the District has some of the most comprehensive pro-tenant laws in the United States:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Tenants in the District are under-informed of their rights.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>It is difficult for tenants to obtain information.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Tenants cannot usually afford legal representation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Tenants are under-informed about dispute mediation and adjudication options available to tenants in the District through the courts and through the Office of the Attorney General.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Few tenants have time for self-advocacy because of their full-time employment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Tenants in the District need an independent Chief Tenant Advocate to act on their behalf as repository of information and resources to help guide tenants through the landlord-tenant system in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The establishment of an independent Office of the Tenant Advocate will provide a valuable resource for the government and residents of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History" path="§2063">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2063, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-181" type="History">Oct. 1, 2007, D.C. Law 16-181, § 2(c), 53 DCR 6703</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-181">D.C. Law 16-181</cite>, in par. (6), substituted “independent Chief Tenant Advocate” for “office at the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs”; and, in par. (7), substituted “independent Office of the Tenant Advocate” for “Office of the Tenant Advocate within the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2063 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-181">D.C. Law 16-181</cite> provided: “Section 2 through 4 shall apply as of October 1, 2007.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
