<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3131.15</num>
  <heading>Administrative review and appeal.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 15 days after the designation of an owner’s building as a vacant building, the determination of delinquency of registration or fee payment, the denial or revocation of registration, or the designation of a vacant building as a blighted vacant building, the owner may petition the Mayor for reconsideration by filing the form prescribed by the Mayor. Within 30 days after receiving the petition, the Mayor shall issue a notice of final determination.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 45 days after the date of the notice of final determination under subsection (a) of this section, an owner may file an appeal with the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia on the form prescribed by the Mayor; provided, that the notice of final determination under subsection (a) of this section shall be a prerequisite to filing an appeal with the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Apr. 14, 1906, 34 Stat. 115, ch. 1626, § 15</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-281" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-281, § 101, 48 DCR 1888</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 62, 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-216" type="History">Aug. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-216, § 3(h), 55 DCR 7500</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 2042(f), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-363" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-363, § 3(f), 58 DCR 963</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite> and § <cite path="§47-825.01a">47-825.01a</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> substituted “file a request for a hearing with the Office of Administrative Hearings” for “seek administrative review by the Board of Appeals and Review, or any successor board or agency”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-216">D.C. Law 17-216</cite> rewrote the section which had read as follows: “Within 10 days after a notice of a final determination by the Mayor under § <cite path="§42-3131.08">42-3131.08</cite> or § <cite path="§42-3131.11">42-3131.11</cite>, an owner may file a request for a hearing with the Office of Administrative Hearings.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> rewrote subsec. (a), which had read as follows: “(a) Within 15 days after the designation of an owner’s building as vacant, the determination of delinquency of registration or fee payment, or the denial or revocation of registration, the owner may petition the Mayor for reconsideration by filing the form prescribed by the Mayor. Within 30 days after receiving the petition, the Mayor shall issue a notice of final determination.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-363">D.C. Law 18-363</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia” for “Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(h) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-259">D.C. Law 16-259</cite>, March 8, 2007, law notification  54 DCR 3044).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(h) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-102">D.C. Law 17-102</cite>, February 2, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 4254).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Real Property Tax Reform Temporary Amendment Act of 2010 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 18-153">D.C. Law 18-153</cite>, May 22, 2010, law notification  57 DCR 5381).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(h) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-586, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 353).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(h) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-173, November 2, 2007,  54 DCR 11204).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(h) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-436, July 16, 2008,  55 DCR 8272).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c), of Real Property Tax Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-313, February 22, 2010,  57 DCR 1645).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2042(f) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
