<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3502.20</num>
  <heading>Report of Mayor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No later than October 1, 1988, the Mayor shall report to the Council on the continued need for the rent stabilization program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The report shall be prepared by a person not affiliated with the District government and shall contain:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of new and renovated units which have been placed on the rental housing market since July 17, 1985;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of new and renovated units it is anticipated will be placed on the rental housing market annually until 1996;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An assessment of the effectiveness of the Tenant Assistance Program; the adequacy of monies appropriated for the program; and the projected costs of the Tenant Assistance Program in the absence of rent stabilization legislation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The impact of the rent stabilization program on the cost and supply of rental housing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>An assessment of the present rent stabilization program in terms of its being understandable, efficient, inexpensive, equitable, and flexible;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The impact of the present rent stabilization program upon small housing providers compared to large housing providers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The number of District residents living in substandard housing and their locations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>An assessment of the impact of the proposed civil infractions law on housing code violations, if the law is enacted in a timely manner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>An assessment of the probable impact on the private rental housing market and the present rent stabilization program of the following individual or combination of factors:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Vacancy decontrol;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Luxury decontrol;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Increasing from 4 units to 10 units the maximum rental units exemption under § <cite path="§42-3502.05">42-3502.05</cite>(a)(3); and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Tying the rent stabilization program to the amount of family income available for rent; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Any other information considered appropriate by the drafters of the report.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-10" type="History">July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, § 220, 32 DCR 3089</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2529.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Expiration of Law">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-3502.01">42-3502.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “proposed civil infractions law,” referred to in paragraph (b)(8), was enacted as <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-42">D.C. Law 6-42</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
