<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3502.02</num>
  <heading>Powers and duties of Rental Housing Commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Rental Housing Commission shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Issue, amend, and rescind rules and procedures for the administration of this chapter except rules and procedures subject to <cite path="§2-1831.05|(a)|(7)">§ 2-1831.05(a)(7)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Decide appeals brought to it from decisions of the Rent Administrator, including appeals under the Rental Accommodations Act of 1975, the Rental Housing Act of 1977, and the Rental Housing Act of 1980; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Certify and publish within 30 days after July 17, 1985, and prior to March 1 of each subsequent year the annual adjustment of general applicability in the rent charged of a rental unit under <cite path="§42-3502.06">§ 42-3502.06</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Rental Housing Commission may hold hearings, sit and act at times and places within the District, administer oaths, and require by subpoena or otherwise the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, records, correspondence, memoranda, papers, and documents as the Rental Housing Commission may consider advisable in carrying out its functions under this chapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A majority of the Rental Housing Commissioners shall constitute a quorum to do business, and any vacancy shall not impair the right of the remaining Rental Housing Commissioners to exercise all the powers of the Rental Housing Commission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In the case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpoena issued under paragraph (1) of this subsection by any person who resides in, is found in, or transacts business within the District, the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, at the written request of the Rental Housing Commission, shall issue an order requiring the contumacious person to appear before the Rental Housing Commission, to produce evidence if so ordered, or to give testimony touching upon the matter under inquiry. Any failure of the person to obey any order of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia may be punished by that Court for contempt.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon the written request of the chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission, each department or entity of the District government may furnish directly to the Rental Housing Commission any assistance and information necessary for the Rental Housing Commission to carry out effectively this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development shall employ the staff necessary to assist the Rental Housing Commission in carrying out its functions. Of the staff employed, 3 shall be law clerks who shall assist each member of the Rental Housing Commission in the preparation of decisions and orders.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-10" type="History" path="§202">July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, § 202, 32 DCR 3089</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-30" type="History">Oct. 2, 1987, D.C. Law 7-30, § 2(b), 34 DCR 5304</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 51(a), 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-145" type="History">Aug. 5, 2006, D.C. Law 16-145, § 2(a), 53 DCR 4889</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20" type="History">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 2003(b), 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 215(c), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-377" type="History">June 3, 2011, D.C. Law 18-377, § 19, 58 DCR 1174</annotation>
    <annotation type="Expiration of Law">See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§42-3502.01">§ 42-3502.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Rental Housing Commission Quorum Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-52, April 27, 2011,  58 DCR 3880).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 520 of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-45, April 20, 2011,  58 DCR 3701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 520 of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-693, January 18, 2011,  58 DCR 640).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Rental Housing Commission Quorum Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-460, July 7, 2010,  57 DCR 6058).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2003(b), of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Rent Control Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-470, July 31, 2006,  53 DCR 6772).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-231">D.C. Law 18-231</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-231">D.C. Law 18-231</cite>, in subsec. (b)(2), substituted “One member” for “A majority”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-377">D.C. Law 18-377</cite>, in subsec. (a)(1), inserted “except rules and procedures subject to <cite path="§2-1831.05|(a)|(7)">§ 2-1831.05(a)(7)</cite>”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in subsec. (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite>, in subsec. (d), substituted “The Department of Housing and Community Development” for “The Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-145">D.C. Law 16-145</cite>, in par. (a)(3), substituted “rent charged” for “rent ceiling”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2512.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§42-3502.04">§ 42-3502.04</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
