<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3502.01</num>
  <heading>Continuation of Rental Housing Commission; composition; appointment; qualifications; compensation; removal.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Rental Housing Commission established by § <cite path="§42-4012">42-4012</cite> [expired] is continued and shall be composed of 3 members appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council. The terms of members of the Rental Housing Commission appointed under the Rental Housing Act of 1980 shall expire upon the confirmation of at least 2 new members appointed pursuant to this section but no later than 90 days after July 17, 1985, and the Mayor shall appoint the new members within 30 days of July 17, 1985. The Mayor shall designate 1 member of the Rental Housing Commission as the chairperson and administrative head. The date of swearing in for a majority of the members of the Rental Housing Commission appointed pursuant to this section shall become the anniversary date for all subsequent appointments.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The first members appointed after July 1, 2010, shall serve the following terms:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>One member’s term shall expire July 18, 2012.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>One member’s term shall expire July 18, 2013.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>One member’s term shall expire July 18, 2014.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Upon the expiration of members’ terms pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, Commissioners shall serve 3-year terms.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Rental Housing Commission shall be composed of 3 persons admitted to practice before the District of Columbia Court of Appeals. All members of the Rental Housing Commission shall be residents of the District. No member shall be either a housing provider or a tenant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>A member of the Rental Housing Commission shall possess skills and experience relevant to the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Litigation, preferably including both appellate practice demonstrated by written work product and exposure to the concerns of pro se litigants;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Administrative law, preferably in an area of complex regulation; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Housing law, preferably in the area of rental housing and rent control or rent stabilization.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission shall receive annual compensation equivalent to that received by a District employee compensated at a grade 16 of the District schedule established under subchapter XI of Chapter 6 of Title 1 (“District schedule”). The other members of the Rental Housing Commission shall receive annual compensation equivalent to that received by a District employee at a grade 15 pursuant to the District schedule.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any person appointed to fill a vacancy on the Rental Housing Commission shall be appointed only for the unexpired term of the member whose vacancy is being filled.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall remove any member of the Rental Housing Commission for good cause.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-10" type="History">July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, § 201, 32 DCR 3089</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-30" type="History">Oct. 2, 1987, D.C. Law 7-30, § 2(a), 34 DCR 5304</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-31" type="History">Oct. 7, 1987, D.C. Law 7-31, § 4, 34 DCR 3789</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-248" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-248, § 2, 46 DCR 1113</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-327" type="History">Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-327, § 2(a), 58 DCR 14</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mayoral nomination of Rental Housing Commission, review and approval of Council, see § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system classification policy and grade levels, see § <cite path="§1-611.01">1-611.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-3404.33">42-3404.33</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2511.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-327">D.C. Law 18-327</cite> rewrote subsec. (a); and added subsec. (b-1). Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “(a) The Rental Housing Commission established by § <cite path="§42-4012">42-4012</cite> is continued and shall be composed of 3 members appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council. The members’ terms shall not exceed 3 years. Members may be appointed for successive terms. The terms of members of the Rental Housing Commission appointed under the Rental Housing Act of 1980 shall expire upon the confirmation of at least 2 new members appointed pursuant to this section but no later than 90 days after July 17, 1985, and the Mayor shall appoint the new members within 30 days of July 17, 1985. The Mayor shall designate 1 member of the Rental Housing Commission as the chairperson and administrative head. The date of swearing in for a majority of the members of the Rental Housing Commission appointed pursuant to this section shall become the anniversary date for all subsequent appointments.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Expiration of Law">Section 907 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-10">D.C. Law 6-10</cite>, as amended by § 2(d) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-48">D.C. Law 8-48</cite> and § 818 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-52">D.C. Law 11-52</cite>, provided that all subchapters of the act, except III and V shall terminate on December 31, 2000.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 42-4012, referred to in the first sentence of subsection (a), expired pursuant to § 907 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 3-131">D.C. Law 3-131</cite> on April 30, 1985. See Chapter 40 of this title.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">For temporary amendment to the termination provision of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-10">D.C. Law 6-10</cite>, see § 818 of the Omnibus Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-124, July 27, 1995,  42 DCR 4160).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
