<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3508.05</num>
  <heading>Distressed property improvement plan.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon petition by the housing provider, the Mayor may initiate the development of a distressed property improvement plan utilizing any or all of the mechanisms in § <cite path="§42-3508.04">42-3508.04</cite>(b). The development of the plan shall involve the participation of the housing provider, the tenants or tenants’ association and may include the mortgagor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A distressed property improvement plan may include, but not be limited to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A schedule of repairs and capital improvements;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A schedule of services and facilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A schedule of rents and rent increases;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A schedule of mortgage payments which may reflect additional long-term loans to the housing provider for the housing accommodation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A schedule of additional capital investment in the housing accommodation by the housing provider; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A schedule of property tax payments, which may also reflect moratoria or deferrals on property tax payments and the abatement or deferral of up to 100% of any tax outstanding on the housing accommodation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In the development of the distressed property improvement plan, the Mayor may consider:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The interests of tenants in achieving decent, safe, and sanitary housing at affordable rents;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The long-term interest of the housing provider in achieving a sound investment and a reasonable return on the housing provider’s investment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The long-term interest of the mortgagor in achieving a financially secure mortgage; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The long-term interest of the District in achieving a decent, safe, and sanitary housing accommodation which is fiscally sound and which generates and pays its fair property tax assessment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-10" type="History" path="§805">July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, § 805, 32 DCR 3089</annotation>
    <annotation type="Expiration of Law">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-3508.01">42-3508.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2585.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
