<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <num>42-3801</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-118" type="History">June 11, 1992, D.C. Law 9-118, § 2, 39 DCR 3189</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-60" type="History">Mar. 20, 1998, D.C. Law 12-60, § 1101, 44 DCR 7378</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2221.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority under <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-118">D.C. Law 9-118</cite>, the District of Columbia Government Employer-Assisted Housing Act of 1992, see Mayor’s Order 92-118, October 6, 1992.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 9 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-118">D.C. Law 9-118</cite> provided that the Mayor shall, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, issue rules within 90 days after June 11, 1992, to implement the provisions of this act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 8(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-70">D.C. Law 10-70</cite> added § 6b to <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-118">D.C. Law 9-118</cite>, which provided that the Mayor shall, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, issue rules within 90 days after February 23, 1994 to implement the provisions of the act. The rules shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Government Employer-Assisted Housing Act Rulemaking Approval Resolution of 1992: Pursuant to Resolution 9-358, effective December 11, 1992, the Council approved rules to carry out the purposes of the District of Columbia Government Employer-Assisted Housing Act of 1992.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: (1) An application procedure for the Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program; and.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">(2) A standard of eligibility and selection of Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program applicants. The Mayor may establish priorities for eligibility based on length of residency in the District, geographic location, or other means as deemed appropriate.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">D.C. Law 12-59, title XI, § 1101 ( 44 DCR 7356), eff. March 20, 1998, provided for the temporary repeal of §§ 45-2221 to 45-2226 [1981 Ed.]. Section 2001(b) of D.C. Law 12-59 provided for expiration “after 225 days of its having taken effect.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
