<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3111</num>
  <heading>Damages.</heading>
  <text>In addition to equitable relief granted under this chapter, the plaintiff may request, and the court in its discretion may order damages for each day the drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related nuisance is unabated since the date the defendant first received notice of the drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related nuisance as provided in § <cite path="§42-3103">42-3103</cite>, or knew or should have known of the existence of the drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related nuisance, whichever is earlier. Such damages shall be payable to the plaintiff, or, in the case of an action by the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia or by the Corporation Counsel, to the Drug-, Firearm-, or Prostitution-Related Nuisance Abatement Fund established by § <cite path="§42-3111.01">42-3111.01</cite>. No other damages are recoverable under this chapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-194" type="History">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-194, § 12, 45 DCR 7982</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-81" type="History">Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-81, § 3(b), (d), 53 DCR 1050</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-259" type="History">Nov. 6, 2010, D.C. Law 18-259, § 7(b), 57 DCR 5591</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-3108">42-3108</cite> and § <cite path="§42-3110">42-3110</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-3311.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-81">D.C. Law 16-81</cite> substituted “drug or prostitution-related” for “drug-related”; and substituted “to the Drug-, Firearm-, or Prostitution-Related Nuisance Abatement Fund established by § <cite path="§42-3111.02">42-3111.02</cite>” for “to the General Fund of the District of Columbia”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-259">D.C. Law 18-259</cite> substituted “drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related” for “drug or prostitution-related”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-3101">42-3101</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of chapter, see notes to § <cite path="§42-3101">42-3101</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
