<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3603</num>
  <heading>Preliminary injunction review.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After commencement of an action under § <cite path="§42-3602">42-3602</cite> and upon request of a party, the Court shall hold a hearing to determine if a preliminary injunction should be granted to prevent a tenant from directly or indirectly maintaining a drug haven or nuisance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Court may grant a motion for a preliminary injunction if the plaintiff meets the necessary legal requirements for a preliminary injunction. The factors that the Court shall consider in determining whether the plaintiff is entitled to a preliminary injunction are:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Whether the plaintiff is likely to prevail on the merits of the case;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Whether, in the absence of relief, the plaintiff will suffer irreparable harm;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Whether there will be substantial harm to the defendant or another party if relief is granted; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Whether the public interest favors granting relief.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The housing provider and the Mayor shall not be required to give bond to obtain an injunction.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History" path="§1304">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 1304, 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-3606">42-3606</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of section, see § 1304 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1304 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
