<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3403.02</num>
  <heading>Relocation payment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Required. —</heading>
    <text>If an owner converts a housing accommodation into a condominium or cooperative pursuant to this chapter, the owner shall provide a relocation payment to each tenant who does not purchase a unit or share or enter into a lease or lease option of at least 5 years’ duration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Amount. —</heading>
    <text>An owner shall pay the tenant only if the tenant provides a relocation expense receipt or a written estimate from a moving company or other relocation service provider. Regardless of the amount on the receipt or written estimates, the owner shall pay no less than $125, but is not required to pay more than $1,000 to the tenant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Method. —</heading>
    <text>An owner may pay by check or cash to the tenant or person designated by the tenant, and shall pay within 7 days of receipt of the written estimate or receipt, the amount indicated or an amount required by subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <heading>Entitlement to receive. —</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The tenant who bears the cost of relocation is entitled to the payment. If there is more than 1 tenant who bears the cost of relocation from a unit, the owner shall pay the tenants proportionally.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The owner is not required to make a relocation payment to a tenant against whom the owner has obtained a judgment for possession of the unit.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If an owner does not make a relocation payment as required, the tenant has a private right of action to collect the payment and is entitled to costs and reasonable attorney fees for bringing the action.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-86" type="History">Sept. 10, 1980, D.C. Law 3-86, § 302, 27 DCR 2975</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-27" type="History">Aug. 1, 1981, D.C. Law 4-27, § 2(c), 28 DCR 2824</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-319" type="History">Mar. 21, 2009, D.C. Law 17-319, § 3(a), 56 DCR 214</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Homestead housing preservation, transfers of real estate of persons not electing to purchase, see § <cite path="§42-2107">42-2107</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-2107">42-2107</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-1621.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-319">D.C. Law 17-319</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “is not required to pay more than $1,000 to the tenant” for “is not required to pay more than $500 to the tenant”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of Abatement of Nuisance Properties and Tenant Receivership Temporary amendment Act of 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-237">D.C. Law 17-237</cite>, October 21, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment, see § 3(a) of Abatement of Nuisance Properties and Tenant Receivership Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-420, July 8, 2008,  55 DCR 7703).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of Abatement of Nuisance Properties and Tenant Receivership Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-563, October 27, 2008,  55 DCR 12019).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Reenactment of Law 3-86: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-3401.01">42-3401.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
