<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3226</num>
  <heading>Lease held by an infant or person with a mental disability — Costs of renewal chargeable to estate of infant or person with a disability or deemed charge upon leasehold.</heading>
  <text>All and every sum and sums of money and other consideration, paid or advanced by any such guardian, trustee, committee or other person, for or on account of the renewal of any such lease or leases, and all reasonable charges incident thereto, shall be paid out of the estate or effects of the infant or person with a mental illness for whose benefit the said lease or leases shall be renewed, or shall be a charge and incumbrance upon the leasehold premises, together with interest for the same, as the said court shall direct and determine.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="29 Geo. 2, ch. 31" path="§2">29 Geo. 2, ch. 31, § 2, 1756</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Kilty’s Rep. 253</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Alex. Br. Stat. 789</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Comp. Stat. D.C., 335, § 71</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 64(e), 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 26(b), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-1426.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 45-928.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite> rewrote the section heading, which formerly read: “Lease held by infant or mentally handicapped—Costs of renewal chargeable to estate of infant or handicapped or deemed charge upon leasehold.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “person with a mental illness” for “lunatic.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
