<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3404.03</num>
  <heading>Offer of sale.</heading>
  <text>The owner shall provide each tenant a written copy of the offer of sale by certified mail and post a copy of the offer of sale in a conspicuous place in common areas of the housing accommodation if it consists of more than one unit. The owner shall provide the Mayor with a written copy of the offer of sale by certified mail or by filing it with the Conversion and Sale Administrator within the Department of Housing and Community Development. The owner shall certify to the Mayor that the Mayor and each tenant were provided copies of the offer of sale on the same day. An offer includes, at a minimum:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The asking price and material terms of the sale;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A statement that the tenant has the right to purchase the accommodation under this chapter and a summary of tenant rights and sources of technical assistance as published in the D.C. Register by the Mayor; Provided, however, that if no such statement and summary have been published, the owner will be deemed in compliance with this paragraph;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>A statement as to whether a contract with a third party exists for sale of the accommodation and that the owner shall make a copy available to the tenant within 7 days after receiving a request; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>A statement that the owner shall make available to the tenant a floor plan of the building and an itemized list of monthly operating expenses, utility consumption rates, and capital expenditures for each of the 2 preceding calendar years within 7 days after receiving a request. The statement shall also indicate that the owner shall, at the same time, make available the most recent rent roll, list of tenants, and list of vacant apartments. If the owner does not have a floor plan, the owner may meet the requirement to provide a floor plan by stating in writing to the tenant that the owner does not have a floor plan.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-86" type="History">Sept. 10, 1980, D.C. Law 3-86, § 403, 27 DCR 2975</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-38" type="History">Nov. 5, 1983, D.C. Law 5-38, § 2(i), 30 DCR 4866</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-31" type="History">Sept. 6, 1995, D.C. Law 11-31, § 3(j), 42 DCR 3239</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-234" type="History">Oct. 21, 2008, D.C. Law 17-234, § 2(a), 55 DCR 9014</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-3404.32">42-3404.32</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-1632.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-234">D.C. Law 17-234</law-cite> rewrote the lead-in language, which had read as follows: “The owner shall provide each tenant and the Mayor a written copy of the offer of sale by first class mail and post a copy of the offer of sale in a conspicuous place in common areas of the housing accommodation if it consists of more than 1 unit. An offer includes, at a minimum:”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(j) of Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Temporary Extension Amendment Act of 1994 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-176">D.C. Law 10-176</law-cite>, September 22, 1994, law notification  41 DCR 6076).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(j) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-285, July 8, 1994,  41 DCR 4904).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(j) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-47, May 4, 1995,  42 DCR 2410) and § 3(j) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Congressional Recess Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-96, July 19, 1995,  42 DCR 3837).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Reenactment of Law 3-86: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-3401.01">42-3401.01</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Amendment of section by Law 10-144: Section 2(j) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-144">D.C. Law 10-144</law-cite> purported to amend (4) of this section to read as follows: “The owner shall provide each tenant and the Mayor a written copy of the offer of sale by first class mail and post a copy of the offer of sale in a conspicuous place in common areas of the housing accommodation if it consists of more than 1 unit. An offer includes, at a minimum: ”(4) A statement that the owner shall make available to the tenant a floor plan of the building and an itemized list of monthly operating expenses, utility consumption rates, and capital expenditures for each of the 2 preceding calendar years within 7 days after receiving a request. The statement shall also indicate that the owner shall, at the same time, make available the most recent rent roll, list of tenants, and list of vacant apartments. If the new owner does not have a floor plan, the owner may meet the requirement to provide a floor plan by stating in writing to the tenant that the owner does not have a floor plan.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
