<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3502.09</num>
  <heading>Rent charged upon termination of exemption and for newly covered rental units.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the rent charged for any rental unit in a housing accommodation exempted by § <cite path="§42-3502.05">42-3502.05</cite>, except subsection (a)(2) or (a)(7) of that section, upon the expiration or termination of the exemption, shall be the average rent charged during the last 6 consecutive months of the exemption, increased by no more than 5% of the average rent charged during the last 6 consecutive months of the exemption. The increase may be effected only in accordance with the procedures specified in §§ <cite path="§42-3502.08">42-3502.08</cite> and <cite path="§42-3509.04">42-3509.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A structure or building, including the land appurtenant, which is located in the District in which 1 or more rental units as defined in § <cite path="§42-3501.03">42-3501.03</cite>(33) are established after July 17, 1985, shall subsequently be defined as a “housing accommodation” for the purposes of this chapter. If any rental unit in such a housing accommodation is not otherwise exempted by 1 of the provisions of § <cite path="§42-3502.05">42-3502.05</cite>, the rent charged for the initial leasing period or the first year of tenancy, whichever is shorter, shall be determined by the housing provider and is considered to be the equivalent of making the computations specified in § <cite path="§42-3502.06">42-3502.06</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The rent charged for any rental unit exempted under § <cite path="§42-3502.05">42-3502.05</cite>(a)(5) upon the expiration or termination of the exemption shall be the rent charged on the date the unit became exempt plus each subsequent adjustment of general applicability authorized under § <cite path="§42-3502.06">42-3502.06</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-10" type="History" path="§209">July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, § 209, 32 DCR 3089</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-145" type="History">Aug. 5, 2006, D.C. Law 16-145, § 2(a), 53 DCR 4889</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 184(d), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-3502.05">42-3502.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2519.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-145">D.C. Law 16-145</cite> substituted “rent charged” for “rent ceiling”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Rent Control Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-470, July 31, 2006,  53 DCR 6772).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Expiration of Law">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§42-3502.01">42-3502.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
