<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-404</num>
  <heading>Failures in formal requisites of an instrument.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The failures in the formal requisites of an instrument that may be cured by this act are:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An omission of an acknowledgment or a defective or improper acknowledgment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A failure to attach a clerk’s certificate;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An omission of a notary seal or other seal; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An omission of an attestation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this act shall be construed to eliminate the requirement that a deed be under seal. Any deed accepted for recordation without a seal but made effective by operation of this act shall be deemed a sealed instrument.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this act shall be construed to validate any instrument with respect to which there was any misrepresentation, fraudulent act, or illegal provision in connection with its execution or acknowledgment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any person convicted of a fraudulent act, in connection with the validation of any instrument under §§ <cite path="§42-101">42-101</cite>, <cite path="§42-402">42-402</cite>, <cite path="§42-403">42-403</cite>, and <cite path="§42-602">42-602</cite> shall be subject to the penalties set forth in § <cite path="§22-3222">22-3222</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 56-2-ch854" path="§499c">Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 854, § 499c</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-110" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 1994, D.C. Law 10-110, § 2(g), 41 DCR 1023</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“This act,” referred to in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, is the Act of March 3, 1901, ch. 854. The Act of March 3, 1901 enacted a code of laws for the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-801.3.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-402">42-402</cite> and § <cite path="§42-403">42-403</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
