<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-810</num>
  <heading>Mortgagee may redeem prior mortgage; prior mortgage may not bar.</heading>
  <text>If it so happen there be more than 1 mortgage at the same time made, by any person or persons to any person or persons, of the same lands and tenements, the several late or under mortgagees, his, her, or their heirs, executors, administrators, or assigns, shall have power to redeem any former mortgage or mortgages, upon payment of the principal debt, interest, and costs of suit, to the prior mortgagee or mortgagees, his, her, or their heirs, executors, administrators, or assigns; anything therein contained to the contrary thereof in anywise notwithstanding.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="4 &amp; 5 W. &amp; M." path="§4">4 &amp; 5 W. &amp; M., ch. 16, § 4, 1692</annotation>
      <annotation>Kilty’s Rep. 242</annotation>
      <annotation>Alex. Br. Stat. 579</annotation>
      <annotation>Comp. Stat., D.C. 237, § 26</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-263">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-263, § 1601, 48 DCR 991</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-132">May 7, 2002, D.C. Law 14-132, § 602(b), 49 DCR 2551</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 45-710.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 45-610.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-132">D.C. Law 14-132</cite> revived this section as of November 6, 2001. This section had been previously repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-263">D.C. Law 13-263</cite>, § 1601.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Protections from Predatory Lending and Mortgage Foreclosure Improvements Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-86">D.C. Law 14-86</cite>, March 19, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 2991).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>Section 2 of Act 14-188, the “Protections from Predatory Lending and Mortgage Foreclosure Improvements Emergency Amendment Act”, deemed approved Nov. 27, 2001, without the signature of the Mayor, provided that <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-263">D.C. Law 13-263</cite> shall not apply beginning November 6, 2001, through March 6, 2002.</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) revival of section, see § 403(b) of Home Loan Protection Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-295, March 1, 2002,  49 DCR 2534).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
