<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-1">
  <num type="law">8-1</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Public School Firearm Prohibition Temporary Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-1.pdf">D.C. Law 8-1</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 8-1, the “District of Columbia Public School Firearm Prohibition Temporary Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-130. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 14, 1989, and February 28, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 21, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-8 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 8-1 became effective on May 16, 1989.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag 103 203 975 AN ACT 11~’olle¢10~lgtnal Codification, District of Columbia Code (1989 Supplement) I).C, ACT 8 "8 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MAR Z ["1988 To amend, on a temporary basis, section 16-2301 of the District of Columbia Code to specify that certain individuals charged with the possession of firearms in or within 500 feet of a public school building, property, or a public school-sponsored event shall not be charged as a "child" as defined. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Public School Firearm Prohibition Temporary Act of 1989 Sec. 2. Section 16-2301(3) is amended as follows a) By striking "or" in subparagraph (B b) By striking the at the end of subparagraph (C~ and inserting the phrase or" in its place; and (c) By adding a new subparagraph (D) to read as follows D) charged with the possession or control of a firearm within a District of Columbia public school building, on public school property, or at a public school-sponsored event or within 500 feet of a public school building, public school property, or public school-sponsored event Sec 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Section 16-2301 (b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect. Note, Section 16-2301 Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: March 21, 1989 [] Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: BB-130 Adopted First Readinq, 2-14-89 C] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN CLARKE X CRAWFORD X JARVIS X KANE X LIGHTFOOT X Approv~ COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY MASON X NATHANSON X RAY X ROLARK X SMITH, JR. X N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. X WILSON X WINTER X X Indic.ares Vote B Absent N.V Present, not voting E/RTIFICATION RECORD Date) Secretary to the Counci¢ ’ [] Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Readinq, 2-28-89 Z VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON THOMAS, SR. CRAWFORD NATHANSON WILSON JARVIS RAY WINTER KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting r t ERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the C Item on Consent Calendar Date AYE NAY N.V. ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON C RAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT.H, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N,V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. Secretary to the Council Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-1 "District of Columbia Public School Firearm Prohibition-Temporary Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-130 on first and second readings, February 14, 1989, and February 28, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on March 21, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-8, published in the March 31, 1989, edition of the D.C R.~ister Vol. 36 page 2246) and transmitted to Congress on March 22, 1989 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-1, effective May 16, 1989. ouncil ~a_t~_s_~9_u_n__t_ e_ d_=D_u=r_i_ n t h e 30~d_a~v__C~o_n r e s s i o n a I R_e_v_~i_e_w P e r i o d March April May 22,23 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,25,26,27,28 I ,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
