<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-133">
  <num type="law">8-133</num>
  <heading type="short">Housing Production Trust Fund Board Amendment Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-06-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-133.pdf">D.C. Law 8-133</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 2369</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 8-133, the “Housing Production Trust Fund Board Amendment Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-475, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 27, 1990, and March 13, 1990, respectively. Approved without the signature of the Mayor on April 2, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-187 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 8-133 became effective on March 15, 1990.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 203 304 COUNCIL OF THL DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-133 "Housing Production Trust Fund Board Amendment Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-475 on first and second readings, February 27, 1990, and March 13, 1990, respectively. The legislation was deemed approved without the signature of the Mayor on April 2, 1990, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 8-187, published in the April 13, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 2369) and transmitted to Congress on April 6, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-133, effective \-4 Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: April 18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30 May 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24 June 5,6,7 AN ACT I rotled Codification, District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APR 0 1990 To amend the Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988 to require that the non-government members of any Housing Production Trust Fund Board established by the Mayor be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia. BE IT E~ACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Housing Production Trust Fund Board Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. The Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1988 (D.C. Law 7-202; D.C. Code, sec. 45-3101 et seq is amended by adding a new section 3a to read as follows Sec. 3a. Housing Production Trust Fund Board Any non-government member of a Board established by the Mayor to administer or provide advice on the administration of the Housing Production Trust Fund shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia New, Section 45-3102.1 1 Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations ohuln~nof the District of Columbia DEEMED APPROVED WITHOUT SIGNATURE UPON EXPIRATION OF IO-DAY MAYORAL REVIEW PERIOD. NOT SIGNED Mayor District of Columbia April 2, 1990 2 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill 8-475 Adopted First Reading, 2-27-90 Approved all present COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN, CLARKE CRAWFORD J IVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR, X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting RTIFICATIQN RECORD r~ta o t h e C-(o~ Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR WILSON WINTER AYE NAY Adopted Final Reading, 3-13-90 Approved Date VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Mason ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT_ COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote AYE NAY N.V. AB. COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Counci{ Item on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR, WILSON WINTER AYE NAY Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A,B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE UGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIIH, JR. A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V J A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR WILSON WINTER N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
