<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-135" flag="true">
  <num type="law">8-135</num>
  <heading type="short">REPRESENTATIVE AND SENATORS TERM OF OFFICE, DUTIES, AND USE OF PRIVATE FUNDS FOR PUBLIC PURPOSES AMENDMENT ACT OF 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1990-06-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-135.pdf">D.C. Law 8-135</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 2616</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0488">
      <narrative>Law 8-135 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-488, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 27, 1990 and March 27, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 13, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-191 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 203 376 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OFFICE OF THE GENERAL COUNSEL WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 TRANSMITTAL OF ENROLLED LEGISLATION Short Title: Representative Duties, and Use of Private Amendment Act of 1990 and Senators Terms of Office, Funds for Public Purposes Bill #8-488 Act Date Transmitted Received by LSD: to LSD CC: CC: Council member Kane Codification Counsel (wit ttachment with attachment) Please notify me of any error/comment within 24 hours. II. CLEARANCE OF ENROLLED LEGISLATION L~gf~l-ative Cobns-el~ Office~o)f the Secretary Date Date III. CLEARANCE OF CORRESPONDENCE BY LSU Letter(s) to the ¢ayor Date Letter( s) to Congress Rev. 6/I 5/89 Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-135 "Representative and Senators Term of Office, Duties, and Use of Private Funds for Public Purposes Amendment Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-488 on first and second readings, February 27, 1990, and March 27, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 13, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-191, published in the April 27, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 2616) and transmitted to Congress on April 18, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-135, effective June 8, 1990 z z utlalrma~ of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: April 18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30 May 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24 June 5,6,7 J U N 0 8 990 Codification, District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) A}~ ACT l).C. ACT8 1 9 i IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APR i 3 1990 To amend the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979 to provide that the term of a Representative or Senator elected pursuant to the Initiative shall begin on January 2nd of the year that immediately follows his or her election, to describe the duties and responsibilities of the Representative and Senators, and to allow the use of private funds for public purposes. BE IT E~IACTED BY THE COU~CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Representative and Senators Term of Office, Duties, and Use of Private Funds for Public Purposes Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Section 4 of the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979, effective March i0, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-171; D.C. Code, sec. 1-113 is amended as follows a) Subsection (d)(2) is amended as follows I) By striking the phrase "10 days after his or her certification by the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics and shall expire on January 3, 1992" and inserting the phrase "on January 2, 1991, and shall expire on January 2, 1993" in its place; and (2) By striking the phrase "i0 days after their certification by the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics and shall expire on January 3, 1996, and January 3, 1994" and inserting the phrase "on January 2, 1991, and shall expire on January 2, 1997 and January 2, 1995" in its place b) The following new subsections are added to read as follows e) A Representative or Senator elected pursuant to this act shall be a public official as defined in section 602(a) of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act, approved August 14, 1974 (88 1 Section 1-113 Enrolled Original Stat. 467; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1462(a and subscribe to the oath or affirmation of office provided for in the District of Columbia Government Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code, sec. 1-604.8 f) A Representative or Senator i) Shall inform the Congress and individual members of Congress that the District of Columbia residents meet the standards traditionally required by Congress for the admission of a United States territory as a State of the United States 2) Shall monitor the progress of the petition for admission of New Columbia to statehood pending before the Congress and report on the progress to the District of Columbia residents 3) May advise the District of Columbia on matters of public policy that bear on the achievement of statehood 4) In accordance with subsection (g) of this section, may employ staff and expend funds donated by private sources for public purposes related to the achievement of statehood; and 5) Shall have any other powers or duties as may be provided by law g i) A Representative or Senator may solicit and receive contributions to support the purposes and operations of the Representative’s or Senator’s public office. A Representative or Senator may accept services, monies, gifts, endowments, donations, or bequests. A Representative or Senator shall establish a District of Columbia statehood fund in 1 or more financial institutions in the District of Columbia. There shall be deposited in each fund any gift or contribution in whatever form, and any monies not included in annual Congressional appropriations. A Representative or Senator is authorized to administer the Representative’s or Senator’s respective fund in any manner the Representative or Senator deems wise and prudent, provided that the administration is lawful, in accordance with the fiduciary responsibilities of public office, and does not impose any financial burden on the District of Columbia 2) Contributions may be expended for the salary, office, or other expenses necessary to support the purposes and operations of the public office of a Representative or Senator, however, each Representative or Senator shall receive compensation no greater than the compensation of the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia, as provided in section 403 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act of 1973, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 787; D.C. Code, sec. 1-226 and section 1109 of the District of 2 Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code, sec. 1-612.9 3) Each Representative or Senator shall file with the Director of Campaign Finance a quarterly report of all contributions received and expenditures made in accordance with paragraph (i) of this subsection. No campaign activities related to election or re-election to the office of Representative or Senator shall be conducted nor shall expenditures for campaign literature or paraphernalia be authorized under paragraph (i) of this subsection 4) The recordkeeping requirements of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act, approved August 14, 1974 (88 Stat. 447; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1401 et seq shall apply to contributions and expenditures made under paragraph (i) of this subsection 5) Upon expiration of a Representative’s or Senator’s term of office and where the Representative or Senator has not been re-elected, the Representative’s or Senator’s statehood fund, established in accordance with paragraph (I) of this subsection, shall be dissolved and any excess funds shall be used to retire the Representative’s or Senator’s debts for salary, office, or other expenses necessary to support the purposes and operation of the public office of the Representative or Senator. Any remaining funds shall be donated to an organization operating in the District of Columbia as a not-for-profit organization within the meaning of section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 22, 1986 (i00 Stat. 2085; 26 U.S.C. 501(c h) A Representative or Senator elected pursuant to section 4(d) of the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979, effective March I0, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-171; D.C. Code, sec. l-l13(d shall be subject to recall pursuant to section 17 of an Act To regulate the election of delegates representing the District of Columbia to national political conventions, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 704; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1321 as added by section 2(d) of the Initiative, Referendum and Recall Procedures Act of 1979, effective June 7, 1979 (D.C. Law 3-1; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1321 during the period of the Representative’s or Senator’s service prior to the admission of the proposed new state into the union Sec. 3. Section 602(a) of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act, approved August 14, 1974 (88 Stat. 467; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1462(a is amended by adding the phrase "a Representative or Senator elected pursuant to section 4 of Section 1-1462 3 the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979, effective March I0, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-171; D.C. Code, sec. 1-113 before the phrase "the President and each member of the Board of Education Sec. 4. Notwithstanding the provisions of section 3 of the Statehood Convention Procedural Amendments Act of 1982, effective August 4, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-138; D.C. Code, sec. 1-119 the honoraria limitations imposed by title VIII of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act, approved August 4, 1974 (88 Stat. 447; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1481 et seq shall apply to a Senator or Representative elected pursuant to section 4(d)(2) of the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979, effective March i0, 1979 (D.C. Law 3-171; D.C. Code, sec. l-l13(d)(1 only if the salary of the Senator or Representative is supported by public revenues. Sec. 5. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(i and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia New, Section l-l13a Note, Section 1-119 Mayo r District APPROVED: April 13, 1990 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: 8-488 Adopted First Readinq, 2-27-90 VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT Approved NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE CHMN. CLARKE X MASON X CRAWFORD X NATHANSON X JARVIS X i RAY X ’KANE X I ROLARK X LIGHTFOOT X I SMITH, JR. X AB Absent N.V Present, not voting Date 3-27-90 X Indicates Vote C~ICATION RECORD J Secretary to the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, ApprovedVOICE VOTE: AYE NAY N.V. X X X Recorded vote on request Absent: T homa s ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER’ CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LtGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent ecretary to the Coun Item on Consent Calendar AYE NAY N.V. I A.B. N.V Present, not voting AYE NAY N.V.COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT I, COUNCIL MEMBER A.YE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBERCHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSQN JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT, H, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A,B, N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-131"/>
  </section>
</document>
