<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-168">
  <num type="law">8-168</num>
  <heading type="short">Vital Records Act of 1981 Amendment Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-09-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-168.pdf">D.C. Law 8-168</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 4833</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0450">
      <narrative>Law 8-168, the “Vital Records Act of 1981 Amendment Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-450, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 12, 1990, and June 26, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 12, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-233 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 204 275 5 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-168 "Vital Records Act of 1981 Amendment Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-450 on first and second readings, June 12, 1990, and June 26, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 12, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-233, published in the July 27, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 4833) and transmitted to Congress on July 16, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives nmt~ce that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-168, effective September 26, 1990. Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July 16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30,31 August 1,2,3 September 5,6,7,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25 AN ACT Enrolled Original Codi fi cation District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) D.C. ACT 23 3 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUL 21990 To amend the Vital Records Act of 1981 to permit the Mayor to issue regulations that prescribe the fee to be paid to amend, or correct a vital record, for the issuance of a new certificate or for the processing of adoptions. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Vital Records Act of 1981 Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Section 22 of the Vital Records Act of 1981, effective October 8, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-34; D.C. Code, sec. 6-221 is amended to read as follows Seco 22. Fees for Vital Records and Searches a) The Mayor shall issue regulations that prescribe the fee to be paid for i) An amendment or correction to a vital record that is not the fault of the Mayor or a District government agency 2) A certified copy of a certificate or record 3) A search of a file or record if no copy is made 4) A copy or information provided for research, statistical, or administrative purposes 5) The processing of adoptions; or 6) Issuance of a new certificate of birth b) The fee collected shall be deposited into the general fund of the District government Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental ReOrganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(i and publication in either the District of 1 Section 6-221 Enmtled Original Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia 2 E] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill 8-450 Adopted First Reading, 6-12-90 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N,V Present, not voting ’ COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Date r~ Item on Consent Calendar [;~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [~VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT Adopted Final Reading, 6-26-90 Approved Wilso~ COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent uncil CEI;~ICATION RECORD Item on Consent Calendar AYE NAY N.V. A,B. N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B, COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT.H, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY NV, A.B. N.V Present not votina CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY N.V J J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
