<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-160">
  <num type="law">8-160</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Real Property Tax Reclassification Amendment Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1990-09-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-160.pdf">D.C. Law 8-160</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 4653</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0537">
      <narrative>Law 8-160, the “District of Columbia Real Property Tax Reclassification Amendment Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-537, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 29, 1990, and June 12, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 29, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-223 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 8-160 became effective on September 30, 1990.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag~ 103 201 714 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-160 "District of Columbia Real Property Tax Reclassification Amendment Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-537 on first and second readings, May 29, 1990, and June 12, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 29, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-223, published in the July 20, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 4653) and transmitted to Congress on July i0, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-160, effective September 20, 1990 Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July 10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30,31 August 1,2,3 September 5,6,7,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19 AN ACT Enrolled Original Codification District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) D.C. ACT 8 2 2 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUN 2 9 1990 To amend the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974 to establish 5 real property tax classes and to amend the Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977 to increase the homestead exemption. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Real Property Tax Reclassification Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, approved September 3, 1974 (88 star. 1051; D.C. Code, sec. 47-801 et~_e is amended as follows a) Section 412a (D.C. Code, sec. 47-813) is amended as follows i) By amending subsection (c-l) by inserting the phrase "not covered in subsection (c-2) or (c-3 after the phrase the following classes of real property 2) By adding the following new subsections to read as follows c-2) For the property tax year beginning July i, 1990 and ending June 30, 1991, the following classes of real property are established i) Class i Property A) Class 1 Property shall be comprised of improved residential real property which i) Is occupied by the owner of the property ii) Contains not more than 5 dwelling units, whether as a row, detached, or semidetached structure, or is a single dwelling unit owned as a condominium; and iii) Is used exclusively for nontransient residential dwelling purposes B) Improved residential real property which is owned by a cooperative housing association shall 1 Section 47-813 Uri inai also be classified as Class 1 Property, so long as at least 50% of the dwelling units are occupied by the shareholders or members of the cooperative housing association C) Unimproved real property which abuts improved residential real property qualified as Class 1 Property shall be classified as Class I Property if the unimproved real property and the improved residential real property which it abuts have common ownership D) Unimproved real property which is separated from Class i improved residential real property by a public alley less than 30 feet wide shall be classified as Class 1 Property if the following conditions are met i) The unimproved real property is less than 1,000 square feet in size ii) The zoning regulations adopted by the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia do not allow the building of any structure on the unimproved real property as a matter of right; and iii) The owner of the unimproved real property also owns the Class 1 improved residential real property separated by the alley from the unimproved real property 2) Class 2 Property A) Class 2 Property shall be comprised of improved residential real property, including buildings, which i) Is not occupied by the owner thereof ii) Contains not more than 5 dwelling units, whether as a row, detached, or semidetached structure, or is a single dwelling unit owned as a condominium; and iii) Is used exclusively for nontransient residential dwelling purposes B) Improved residential real property which is owned by a cooperative housing association shall also be classified as Class 2 Property, so long as less than 50% of the dwelling units are occupied by the shareholders or members of the cooperative housing association C) Improved multifamily residential property which contains more than 5 dwelling units and is used exclusively for nontransient dwelling purposes shall also be classified as Class 2 Property D) Unimproved real property which abuts improved residential real property qualified as Class 2 Property shall be classified as Class 2 Property if the unimproved real property and the improved residential real property which it abuts have common ownership E) Unimproved real property which is separated from Class 2 improved residential real property by [.nrotte l Or ¢inat a public alley less than 30 feet wide shall be classified as Class 2 Property if the following conditions are met i) The unimproved real property is less than 1,000 square feet in size ii) The zoning regulations adopted by the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia do not allow the building of any structure on the unimproved real property as a matter of right; and iii) The owner of the unimproved real property also owns the Class 2 improved residential real property separated by the alley from the unimproved real property F) The Mayor may require an owner of real property to submit such information relating to the ownership of unimproved real property as in the Mayor’s judgment will assist in the determination of ownership of the property as required under this section for purposes of real property classification 3) Class 3 Property A) Class 3 Property shall be comprised of improved commercial real property, including hotels, motels, inns, or any other place, which is regularly used for the purpose of furnishing rooms, lodgings, or accommodations to transients B) For purposes of subparagraph (A) of this para@raphf the term "transient" means a person who is merely so3ournlng in the District, including a person who is visiting for a few days, or comes to the District to perform some special service or attend some special event. Any person who is furnished accommodations for a period of 90 consecutive days or more shall no longer be considered a transient but shall be considered a permanent resident of the hotel, motel, or inn 4) Class 4 Property Class 4 Property shall be comprised of A) All improved real property, which is not Class 1 Property, Class 2 Property, or Class 3 Property; and B) Unimproved real property, which is not Class 1 Property, Class 2 Property, or Class 3 Property, if any of the following conditions are met i) The zoning regulations adopted by the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia do not allow the building of any structure on the unimproved real property as a matter of right ii) A building permit has been issued and is in effect as of July i, 1990; or iii) The unimproved real property is used as a parking lot and each approval required from the District of Columbia government for use as a parking lot has been obtained 5) Class 5 Property Class 5 Property shall be comprised of all unimproved real property which is not Class 1 Property, Class 2 Property, Class 3 Property, or Class 4 Property c 3) For the property tax year beginning July 1 1991 and ending June 30, 1992, and for each subsequent tax year, the following classes of real property are established i) Class 1 Property A) Class 1 Property shall be comprised of improved residential real property that i) Is occupied by the owner of the property ii) Contains not more than 5 dwelling units, whether as a row, detached, or semidetached structure, or is a single dwelling unit owned as a condominium; and iii) Is used exclusively for nontransient residential dwelling purposes B) Improved residential real property that is owned by a cooperative housing association shall also be classified as Class 1 Property so long as at least 50% of the dwelling units are occupied by the shareholders or members of the cooperative housing association C) Class 1 Property that becomes unoccupied shall be classified as Class 2 Property if the property becomes unoccupied due to any of the following conditions i) A major fire, flood, or other casualty to the improved real property, which was not intentionally caused by the owner, has occurred during the 12 months preceding the tax year ii) The improved real property is actively for sale at a reasonable market price as of June 30 of the preceding tax year iii) A building or demolition permit has been issued and building or demolition is actively pursued as of June 30 of the preceding tax year; or iv) The improved real property is the subject of a probate proceeding or title to the improved real property is the subject of litigation D) Unimproved real property which abuts improved and occupied residential real property qualified as Class 1 Property shall be classified as Class 1 Property if the unimproved real property and the improved and occupied residential real property which it abuts have common ownership. Emoited E) Unimproved real property which is separated from Class 1 improved and occupied residential real property by a public alley less than 30 feet wide shall be classified as Class 1 Property if the following conditions are met i) The unimproved real property is less than 1,000 square feet in size ii) The zoning regulations adopted by the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia do not allow the building of any structure on the unimproved real property as a matter of right; and iii) The owner of the unimproved real property also owns the Class 1 improved and occupied residential real property separated by the alley from the unimproved real property 2) Class 2 Property A) Class 2 Property shall be comprised of improved and occupied residential real property, including a building, that i) Is occupied, but not by the owner ii) Contains not more than 5 dwelling units, whether as a row, detached, or semidetached structure, or is a single dwelling unit owned as a condominium; and iii) Is used exclusively for nontransient residential dwelling purposes B) Improved residential real property which is owned by a cooperative housing association shall also be classified as Class 2 Property so long as less than 50% of the dwelling units are occupied by the shareholders or members of the cooperative housing association C) Improved and occupied multifamily residential real property which contains more than 5 dwelling units and is used exclusively for nontransient purposes shall also be classified as Class 2 Property D) Unimproved real property which abuts improved and occupied residential real property qualified as Class 2 Property shall be classified as Class 2 Property if the unimproved real property and the improved and occupied residential real property which it abuts have common ownership E) Unimproved real property which is separated from Class 2 improved and occupied residential real property by a public alley less than 30 feet wide shall be classified as Class 2 Property if the following conditions are met i) The unimproved real property is less than 1,000 square feet in size ii) The zoning regulations adopted by the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia do not allow the building of any structure on the unimproved real property as a matter of right; and iii) The owner of the unimproved real property also owns the Class 2 improved and occupied residential real property separated by the alley from the unimproved real property F) Class 2 Property that becomes unoccupied shall be classified as Class 4 Property if it becomes unoccupied due to any of the following conditions i) A major fire, flood, or other casualty to the improved real property, which was not intentionally caused by the owner, has occurred during the 12 months preceding the tax year ii) A building or demolition permit has been issued and building or demolition is actively pursued as of June 30 of the preceding tax year iii) The improved real property is the subject of a probate proceeding or title to the improved real property is the subject of litigation; or iv) An application for a necessary approval for development of the improved real property is pending, as of June 30 of the preceding tax year, before the Board of Zoning Adjustment, the Zoning Commission, the Commission of Fine Arts, the Historic Preservation Review Board, or the National Capitol Planning Commission G) Improved real property described in paragraph (1)(C) of this subsection 3) Class 3 Property A) Class 3 Property shall be comprised of improved and occupied commercial real property, including hotels, motels, inns, or any other place, which is regularly used for the purpose of furnishing rooms, lodgings, or accommodations to transients B) For purposes of subparagraph (A) of this para@raph~ the term "transient" means a person who is merely so3ournlng in the District, including a person who is visiting for a few days, or comes to the District to perform some special service or attend some special event. Any person who is furnished accommodations for a period of 90 consecutive days or more shall no longer be considered a transient but shall be considered a permanent resident of the hotel, motel, or inn C) Class 3 Property that becomes unoccupied shall be classified as Class 4 Property if it becomes unoccupied due to any of the following conditions i) A major fire, flood, or other casualty to the improved real property, which was not intentionally caused by the owner, has occurred during the 12 months preceding the tax year; 6 ii) A building or demolition permit has been issued and building or demolition is actively pursued as of June 30 of the preceding tax year iii) The improved real property is the subject of a probate proceeding or title to the improved real property is the subject of litigation; or iv) An application for a necessary approval for development of the improved real property is pending, as of June 30 of the preceding tax year, before the Board of Zoning Adjustment, the Zoning Commission, the Commission of Fine Arts, the Historic Preservation Review Board, or the National Capitol Planning Commission 4) Class 4 Property A) Class 4 Property shall be comprised of all improved and occupied real property, which is not Class 1 Property, Class 2 Property, or Class 3 Property B) Class 4 Property that becomes unoccupied shall be classified as Class 4 Property if it becomes unoccupied due to any of the following conditions i) A major fire, flood, or other casualty to the improved real property, which was not intentionally caused by the owner, has occurred during the 12 months preceding the tax year ii) A building or demolition permit has been issued and building or demolition is actively pursued as of June 30 of the preceding tax year iii) The improved real property is the subject of a probate proceeding or title to the improved real property is the subject of litigation; or iv) An application for a necessary approval for development of the improved real property is pending, as of June 30 of the preceding tax year, before the Board of Zoning Adjustment, the Zoning Commission, the Commission of Fine Arts, the Historic Preservation Review Board, or the National Capitol Planning Commission C) Unoccupied improved real property that is not classified as Class 1 Property, Class 2 Property, or Class 3 Property shall be classified as Class 4 property if the property is I) A historic landmark pursuant to the Historic District Protection Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-144; D.C. Code, sec. 5-1001 et seq or 2) The subject of an agreement ~n-at runs with the land and provides for the preservation of certain historic features of the improvement D) Unoccupied improved real property that has been unoccupied since completion of initial construction or total renovation pursuant to a building permit issued during the 24 months preceding the tax year shall be classified as Class 4 Property. during the 24 months preceding the tax year shall be classified as Class 4 Property E) Unimproved real property, which is not classified as Class 1 Property, Class 2 Property, or Class 3 Property, shall be classified as Class 4 Property if any of the following conditions are met i) The zoning regulations adopted by the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia do not allow the building of any structure on the unimproved real property as a matter of right ii) The unimproved real property is the subject of a public hearing set down by the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia on a proposed overlay zone or on a proposed downzoning, other than a downzoning pursuant to sections 6 and 7 of the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984, effective May 23, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-129; to be codified at D.C. Code, secs. 1-249 and 1-250 iii) The unimproved real property is encumbered by a deed of trust that was recorded during the 24 months preceding the tax year iv) A building permit has been issued and building is actively pursued as of June 30 of the preceding tax year v) The unimproved real property is used as a parking lot and each approval required from the District of Columbia government for use as a parking lot has been obtained vi) The unimproved real property is the subject of a probate proceeding or title to the unimproved real property is the subject of litigation; or vii) An application for a necessary approval for development of the unimproved real property is pending as of June 30 of the preceding tax year before the Board of Zoning Adjustment, the Zoning Commission, the Commission of Fine Arts, the Historic Preservation Review Board, or the National Capitol Planning Commission F) Improved real property described in paragraphs (2)(F) and (3)(C) of this subsection 5) Class 5 Property A) Class 5 property shall be comprised of all real property which is not Class 1 Property, Class 2 Property, Class 3 Property, or Class 4 Property B) Unimproved real property that abuts and has common ownership with real property subject to the apportionment provision of subsection (f) of this section and cannot be classified as Class 1 Property, Class 2 Property, Class 3 Property, or Class 4 Property shall also be classified as Class 5 Property 3) A new subsection (d-l) is added to read as follows d-l) For the purposes of subsection (c-3) of this section i) The term "occupied" means the use of or residence in improved real property on a regular basis. Improved residential real property that is occupied only by a person who serves as a caretaker of the improvement shall be considered unoccupied 2) To assist in the determination of real property classification for the tax year beginning July i, 1991 and ending June 30, 1992 and each subsequent tax year, the Mayor shall devise a form and mail the form to the owner of real property classified as Class 2 Property, Class 3 Property, Class 4 Property, or Class 5 Property between January i, 1991 and June 30, 1991 and biennially thereafter. The owner shall complete the form and return it to the Mayor within 30 days of the date the form was mailed to the owner. The Mayor may grant a reasonable extension of time, not to exceed 30 days, to file the form if the Mayor deems that good cause exists for an extension of time 3) The Mayor may require an owner of real property to submit any information that the Mayor deems relevant to the determination of real property classification 4) In a case in which the occupancy of improved real property is disputed, the Mayor shall require the owner of the real property to submit at least 2 of the following items A) A certificate of occupancy B) Registration or claim of exemption filed with the Rent Administrator C) Water and sewer bills paid for the period of occupancy claimed on the form D) Gas bills paid for the period of occupancy claimed on the form E) Electricity bills paid for the period of occupancy claimed on the form F) A lease agreement for the period of occupancy claimed on the form G) A sales tax return required by section 135 of the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Stat. 118; D.C. Code, sec. 47-2015 for payment of the tax imposed under section 125 of the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Stat. 115; D.C. Code, sec. 47-2002(1 or H) Any other evidence that the Mayor deems relevant to the determination of whether improved real property is occupied. 9 5) An owner of real property that becomes unoccupied shall notify the Mayor within 30 days of the date that the property becomes unoccupied. Failure to timely notify the Mayor that real property has become unoccupied shall subject the owner to a penalty equal to 25% of the real property tax owed for the tax year. The Mayor may waive the penalty for just cause 6) If an owner of real property subject to the reporting requirements of this subsection fails to complete or return the required form or falsifies the required form, the real property shall be reclassified in accordance with the provisions of subsection (c-3) of this section and the owner shall be assessed a penalty equal to 25% of the real property tax owed for the tax year or $5,000, whichever is greater 4) Subsection (e) is amended by striking the phrase b) and (c and inserting the phrase b c c-l c-2 and (c-3 in its place 5) Subsection (f) is amended by striking the phrase c) and (c-l wherever it appears and inserting the phrase c c-l c-2) and (c-3 in its place b) Section 413 (D.C. Code, sec. 47-815) is amended by striking the phrase "47-813(b wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "subsections (c-l c-2 and (c-3) of section 412a of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, effective September 28, 1979 (D.C. Law 3-37; D.C. Code, secs. 47-813(c-i c-2 and (c-3 in its place c) Section 424a (D.C. Code, sec. 47-823(a)(2 is amended by striking the phrase "47-813(c and inserting the phrase "subsections (c-l c-2 and (c-3) of section 412a of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, effective September 28, 1979 (D.C. Law 3-37; D.C. Code, secs. 47-813(c-i c-2 and (c-3 in its place d) Section 425 (D.C. Code, sec. 47-824) is amended by striking the phrase "fiscal year" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "tax year" in its place e) Section 426 (D.C. Code, sec. 47-825) is amended as follows i) By striking the phrase "fiscal year" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "tax year" in its place 2) By amending subsection (g) as follows i) By striking the phrase "June 30" and inserting the phrase "June 15" in its place; and (ii) By adding the following sentence at the end The Mayor is authorized to make an administrative or clerical correction to any assessment or correct any real property classification only for the current or immediately forthcoming tax year I0 Section 47-813 Section 47-823 Section 47-824 Section 47-825 (3) By amending subsection (i) by striking the word "classification" wherever it appears; and (4) By adding a new subsection (j) to read as follows j) Any person aggrieved by a real property classification may appeal the classification to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in sections 3 and 4 of Title IX of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, effective May 16, 1938 (52 Stat. 371; D.C. Code, secs. 47-3303 and 47-3304 within 6 months after October 1 of the calendar year in which the classification is made Sec. 3. Section 3 of the Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977, effective February 28, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-45; D.C. Code, sec. 47-850 is amended as follows a) Subsection (c)(1) is amended by striking the phrase "the amount of $22,000" and inserting the phrase "the amount of $22,000 or, commencing with the tax year beginning July I, 1990, the amount of $30,000" in its place b) Subsection (d)(2) is amended as follows i) By striking the phrase "the amount of 44 and inserting the phrase "the amount of 60 in its place; and (2) By striking the phrase "the amount of $22,000" and inserting the phrase "the amount of $22,000 or, commencing with the tax year beginning July i, 1990, the amount of $30,000" in its place. Sec. 4. The Mayor shall, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et s_9_q issue proposed rules to implement the provisions o the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Reclassification Amendment Act of 1990. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 60-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 60-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved. Nothing in this section shall affect any requirements imposed upon the Mayor by title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et se Sec. 5. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as Section 47-850 Note, Section 47-813 47-815 47-823 47-824 47-825 47-850 ii Original provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(i and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia 12 Item on Consent Calendar :E~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Approved Crawford [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVtS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote AB Absent B8-537 Reading, 5-29-90 J J AYE NAY NV. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. THOMAS, SR WILSON WINTER CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, N.V Present, not voting Date 6-12-90 VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: a i 1 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVlS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote Approved pre sent COUNCIL MEMBER AYE MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council AYE NAY NV. Item on Consent Calendar NAY N.V. ’A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER N.V Present, not voting Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT.H, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
