<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-179">
  <num type="law">8-179</num>
  <heading type="short">DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA REGIONAL AIRPORTS AUTHORITY ACT OF 1985 AMENDMENT ACT OF 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1990-10-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-179.pdf">D.C. Law 8-179</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 5037</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0602"/>
    <search-text>I~viktag 103 203 518 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-179 "District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985 Amendment Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-602 on first and second readings, June 26, 1990, and July 10, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 18, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-247, published in the August 3, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 5037) and transmitted to Congress on July 20, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-179, effective October 2, 1990 ’ ’n Tin A. CLARKE "’C I Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period; July 20,23,24,25,26,27,30,31 August I ,2,3 September 5,6,7,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28 October J LAW 8-179 OGT 0 21990 r- rr~ i~ Codification District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) AN ACT l C. kCT 8 -247 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUL 199o To amend the District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985 to increase the authorized maximum civil penalty for violations of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority rules establishing a noise limitation on aircraft that operate at Authority facilities. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985 Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Section 7 (e) of The District of Columbia Section Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985, effective December 7-1101, note 3, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-67; D.C. Code, sec. 7-1101, note is amended by striking the figure 2,500" and inserting the figure 50,000" in its place. Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Enrolled Original Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia ~lunicipal Regulations or upon enactment of a similar provision by the state of Virginia, whichever oc/c~/rs later. Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: July 18, 1990 [] Item on Consent Calenea,r [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE :OL}UNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Adopted First Reading, 6-26-90 Approved Wilson 8-602 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT RYE NAY N,¥ COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK LIGHTFOOT I SMITH, JR. X Indicates 4:Lte A.B Absent r 41:,CAT,ON RECORD Secretary to the u ncil z~ltem on Consent Calendar J AYE NAY N.Y. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR WILSON WINTER NV Present, not vo!incj Date ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading {VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent all present ROLL CALL VOTE REShtT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V_ A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFQRD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. A.B AbsentX Indicates te y- Secretary to the Council Item on Consent Calendar 7-10-90 ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: AYE NAY NV. A.B. N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Date AYE NAY NV. [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESt.JET AYE NAY N A.B. X ’Indicates ~ote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIIH, JR. AB Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
