<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-209">
  <num type="law">8-209</num>
  <heading type="short">Real Estate Transaction Amendment Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1991-03-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-209.pdf">D.C. Law 8-209</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 8464</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0514">
      <narrative>Law 8-209, the “Real Estate Transaction Amendment Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-514, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 13, 1990, and December 4, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 14, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-284 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 202 668 O 0 0 0 0 0 0 ¯ AN ACT Codification, District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) D,C, ACT 8-284 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC, 14, 1990 To amend the District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act to discourage discrimination against owners and occupants of real property, including individuals who are HIV-infected or who have AIDS, by providing that certain non-physical circumstances concerning real property are not material facts that~must be disclosed to prospective purchasers of the real property. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Real Estate Transaction Amendment Act of 1990" Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982, effective March I0, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-209; D.C. Code, sec. 45-1921 et seq is amended to read as follows a) Section 3 (D.~C. Code, sec. 45-1922) is amended by adding the following subsections to read as follows 15 Psychological impact" means any fact or suspicion with respect to circumstances, other than the physical condition of the property, that creates a fear, belief, or mental condition 16 Material fact" means information that, if known, would be likely to induce a reasonable person to enter into or not enter into or consummate a real estate transaction b) Section 17 (D.C. Code, sec. 45-1936) is amended by adding a new subsection (f) to read as follows f)(1) Notwithstanding the possibility that a fact may have a psychological impact on a purchaser, lessee, or sublessee, it shall not be a material fact that must be disclosed in a real estate transaction that A) An occupant of real property, at any time, was infected or was or is suspected to have been infected with a human immune deficiency virus B) An occupant of real property, at any time, has been diagnosed, was infected, or was suspected to Section 45-1922 Section 45-1936 have been diagnosed as having acquired immune deficiency syndrome or any other disease that has been determined by medical evidence to be highly unlikely to be transmitted through occupancy of property alone; or C) The property, at any time, has been or was suspected to have been the site of a suicide, homicide, or other felony 2) A cause of action shall not arise against an owner of real property, a real estate broker, a real estate salesperson, a property manager, a lessee, or sublessee for the failure to disclose to the purchaser lessee or sublessee that the real property was the site of any circumstances described in paragraph (i) of this subsection Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations Chairman ~Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 14, 1990 ~UNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: B 8 514 [] Item on Consent Ca|ende~ [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted First VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: al i present [] ROLL CALL VOTE E~SULT Reading, 11-13-90 COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N~ A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. A.B AbsentX Indicates ~ote CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request all present Absent COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. N.V Present, not voting Date 12-04-90 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. AYE NAY N.V. cOUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN, CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT, H, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V.A.8 Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
