<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-227">
  <num type="law">8-227</num>
  <heading type="short">SALE OF GOVERNMENT PUBLICATIONS AMENDMENT ACT OF 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1991-03-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-227.pdf">D.C. Law 8-227</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 224</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0480">
      <narrative>Law 8-227 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-480, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1990, and December 18, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-310 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 203 329 O0 0 (D 0 r~ o - O 0 0 "Z Codi fication Bistrict of Columbia Code {1991 Supplement) AN ACT D,C, ACT 8-310 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC, 27, 1990 To amend An Act To grant additional powers to the Commissioners of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, to authorize the Mayor to sell government publications. BF IT ENACTED By THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Sale of Government Publications Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Section (i){l) of An Act To grant additional powers to the Commissioners of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved December 20, 1944 (58 Star lq; D.C. Code, sec. 1-337(i)(I is amended to read as follows i) Purchase and sale of maps and publications; issuance without charge; delegation of authority; payment of cost The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered within his or her discretion I) To purchase and sell maps and to sell copies and subscriptions of the District of Columbia Statutes-at-LarGe, the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, other government publications, an~ other data and information government materials including binders for material, at prices the Mayor or his or her designated agent determines to be necessary to approximate the cost of the material, including the cost of distribution. The Mayor shall not charge the Council of the District of Columbia for copies or subscriptions of ~overnment materials or any other rule, regulation, or document that has general applicability and ].e~al effect which the Council needs to perform its legislative responsibilities. All receipts from the sale of such material shall be deposited in the General Fund Sec. 3. Section 4 of the Omnibus Narcotic and Abusive Dru~ Interdiction Amendment Act of 1990, effective June 13, Section 1-337 Section 33-565 1990 (D.C. Law 8-138; D.C. Code, sec. 33-565(e is amended by striking the phrase 52 Stat. 793; D.C. Code, sec. 33-556(e and inserting the phrase 52 Stat. 793; D.C. Code, sec. 33-~65(e in its place. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day perio~ of Congressional review 9ollowing approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the CouDcil of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia ~elf-C~overDment add C~overnmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-273(c){ add publication in either the District of Columbia Pegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Pequlations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: December 27, 1990 2 [] Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE D~STRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Readinq, 12-04-90 Approved B8-480 Recorded vote on request all present Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD JARVlS RAY KANE LIGHTFQOT ¯ COUNCIL MEMBER NATHANSON RQLARK SMITH, JR AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Item on Consent Calendar ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, Date 12-18-90 Approved VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request WilsonAbsent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secreta to the--Council Item on Consent Calendar Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Fq ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFQOT SMIT.H, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not votincj CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
