<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-226">
  <num type="law">8-226</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Low-Level Radioactive Waste Generator Regulatory Policy Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1991-03-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-226.pdf">D.C. Law 8-226</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 219</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0378">
      <narrative>Law 8-226, the “District of Columbia Low-Level Radioactive Waste Generator Regulatory Policy Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-378, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1990, and December 18, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-309 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag 103 201 036 c- O 0 I .[ AN ACT D, C, ACT 8-309 Enrolled Original Codi fi cati on District of Columbia Code New Chapter 37 of Title 6 (1991 Suppl ement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC, 27, 1990 To require a generator of low-level radioactive waste in the District of Columbia to reimburse the District government for costs associated with the disposal of waste at a regional facility, to require a person who generates radioactive waste to register with the Mayor, and to require a generator of radioactive waste to submit a detailed annual report to the Mayor. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Low-level Radioactive Waste Generator Regulatory Policy Act of 1990" Sec. 2. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term I Disposal" means the permanent isolation of low-level radioactive waste at a regional disposal facility as defined in section 2 of the Low-level Radioactive Waste Policy Act, approved December 23, 1980 (94 Stat. 3347; 42 U.S.C. 2021b Waste Policy Act 2 Generator" means any public or private individual, institution, corporation, association, group, or other legally constituted enterprise that produces low-level radioactive waste in the District of Columbia District 3 Low-level radioactive waste waste means radioactive material that A) Is not high-level radioactive waste, spent nuclear fuel, transuranic waste, or byproduct material as defined in section lle of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, approved August 30, 1954 (68 Stat. 923; 42 U.S.C. 2014(e and (B) The United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission has classified, consistent with I0 CFR 61.55, as low-level radioactive waste 4 Regional facility" means a low-level radioactive waste disposal facility in operation on January New section 6-3701 1 Enrolled Original I, 1985, or subsequently established and operated pursuant to the Waste Policy Act. Sec. 3. Reports. New (a) Pursuant to rules issued by the Mayor in section accordance with section 7, by May 15, 1991, and on February 6-3702 1 of each subsequent year, any person who generates low-level radioactive waste in the District shall submit to the Mayor a report that details for the previous calendar year I) The class and quantity of any waste generated, stored by the generator for decay or for later transfer to another facility, or transferred by the generator to another facility 2) The general type of generator (e.g medical, university, industry, electric, utility, government, or nonprofit 3) Any additional information as the Mayor may require on the nature and characteristics of the waste (including chemical and physical characteristics, properties, or constituents, radionuclides present, curie content or concentration of radioactivity and (4) The extent of reduction in quantity and the nature and extent of reduction or other change in nature of characteristics of the waste as a result of treatment or interim storage after generation and before delivery to a facility for permanent disposal of the waste b) The Mayor shall, pursuant to rules issued in accordance with section 7, provide the appropriate procedures for the preparation and submission of the report when more than one person is the generator of the same waste c) Any generator who fails to report as required by this section shall be fined an amount not to exceed $5,000 for each day of noncompliance and may be required to forfeit any right, license, permit, or privilege to possess radioactive materials in the District d) Beginning on July I, 1991, and on April 1 of each subsequent year, the Mayor shall submit to the Council of the District of Columbia Council a report that summarizes and categorizes by type of generator, the nature, characteristic, and quantity of waste generated in the District during the previous calendar year. Sec. 4. Registration; fee. Pursuant to rules issued by the Mayor in accordance with section 7, beginning in 1991, any person who generates waste in the District shall register annually with the Mayor on a form prescribed by the Mayor and pay an annual registration fee to be established by the Mayor. Any New section 6-3703 F..rolled OriEinal generator who fails to register as required by this section shall be fined an amount not to exceed $5,000 for each day of noncompliance and may be required to forfeit any right, license, permit, or priviledge to possess radioactive materials in the District. Sec. 5. Fund; assessment a) There is established within the District Treasury a non-lapsing revolving fund to be known as the Low-Level Radioactive Waste Fund Fund The Fund shall consist of any revenue collected pursuant to this act and any funds paid to the District pursuant to section 5(d)(2) of the Waste Policy Act (42 U.S.C. 2021e(d)(2 Any revenue deposited in the Fund shall be used exclusively to offset the District’s actual and operating expenses for the disposal of waste generated in the District at a regional facility b) The Mayor shall establish reasonable rates and fees to be paid by any generator for the disposal of waste generated in the District at any regional facility to fully recover all costs of the District including actual and operating expenses. The fee shall be apportioned by the category of generator and the amount of waste disposed of by individual generators within each category annually, except that the total amount assessed non-profit educational institutions and non-profit health care providers shall not exceed 45~ of the District’s total annual cost. Full remittance of each annual assessment shall be made to the District within a reasonable time period to be established by the Mayor and be accompanied by any report or other documentation as the Mayor may require. Any generator who fails to make full remittance within the required time period shall be assessed a penalty not to exceed the full amount of the delinquent annual assessment. New section 6-3704 Sec. 6. Citizen right of action. Any person aggrieved by the failure of a generator of low-level radioactive waste in the District to comply with this act may sue for relief in any court of competent jurisdiction. The court may grant any declaratory or injunctive relief it deems necessary. Reasonable attorney’s fees and court costs may be awarded to the prevailing party, other than the District government, for actions brought under this section. New ,section 6-3705 Sec. 7. Rules. New By May I, 1991, the Mayor shall, pursuant to title I of secti0n the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, 6-3706 approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq APA issue rules to implement the Enrolled Original provisions of this act including rules regarding rates, fee and payment schedules, registration forms, reporting guidelines, and other operational provisions deemed necessary to fully implement and enforce the provisions of this act. Sec. 8. The Radiation Protection Regulations, issued July 9, 1970 (Reg. 70-33; 17 DCR 39 are amended as follows a) Section 1 (17 DCR 39) is amended as follows I) By designating the existing text as subsection (a and (2) By adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) The Mayor may, pursuant to title I of the APA, amend the rules set forth in Appendix 1 of the Radiation Protection Regulations (20 DCMR 2000-2299) to develop standards for protection from radiation in the District of Columbia including rules regarding the registration and inspection of persons, facilities, and establishments, and the development of licensure and registration fees. The Mayor may incorporate by reference, in whole or in part, any private association or group standards for protection from radiation, if the Mayor deems those standards appropriate to protect the public health, safety, and welfare b) Section 2:1002 of title 8 of Appendix 1 of the Radiation Protection Regulations (20 DCMR 2099) is amended by striking the 2nd sentence in the definition of the term "person 20 DCMR 2099 Sec. 9. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Enrolled Originai Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 27, 1990 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted First Reading, 12-04"90 [] VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.8, COUI&amp;lt;ICIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON 3ARV~S RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote AB Absent AYE NAY N.V, A.B. B8-378 N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final {~,VOICE VOTE: Approved COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER } AYE NAY N.V. Date Reading, 12-18-90 Recorded vote on request Absent: Wilson ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT CQUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASQN CRAWFQRD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR, X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voti0g COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER CERTiFiCATION RECORD SeCretary to the Cour~cil r Item on Consent Calendar Date AYE NAY N.V. ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE I NAY N.V. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN, CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT, H, JR, X Indicates Vote AB Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V PresenL not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCI~ MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR, WILSON ["’ WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1501"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1502"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1503"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1504"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1505"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1506"/>
  </section>
</document>
