<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-236">
  <num type="law">8-236</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Consumer Credit Service Organization Amendment Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1991-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-236.pdf">D.C. Law 8-236</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 306</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0070">
      <narrative>Law 8-236, the “District of Columbia Consumer Credit Service Organization Amendment Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-70, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1990, and December 18, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-319 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 203 050 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-33 "Closing of a Public Alley in Square 2960, S.O. 87-273, Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-71 on first and second readings, June 13, 1989, and June 27, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 7, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-58, published in the July 21, 1989, edition of the D.C ister Vol. 36 page 5033) and transmitted to Congress on July 12, 1989 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-33, effective September 22, 1989 Chairman of the Clounci] Dates Counted During the 30-da £_n~e~ssional Review Period: July 12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28,31 August 1,2,3,4 September 6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21 AN ACT Enrolled Original Codification, District of Columbia Code (1990 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUL O? ]~9 To provide conditional approval of the closing of a public alley in Square 2960, bounded by Eastern Avenue, N.W Georgia Avenue, N.W Alaska Avenue, N.W Kalmia Road, N.W, and 12th Street, N.W in Ward 4. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Closing of a Public Alley in Square 2960, S.O. 87-273, Act of 1989 Sec. 2. Pursuant to section 201 of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March I0, 1983 D.C. Law 4-201; D.C. Code, sec. 7-421 the Council of the District of Columbia Council finds that the public alley in Square 2960, as shown on the Surveyor’s plat filed under S.O. 87-273, is unnecessary for alley purposes and orders the public alley closed, with title to the land to vest as shown on the Surveyor’s plat filed under S.O. 87-273, only if there is first filed in the Recorder of Deeds Division of the District of Columbia Department of Finance and Revenue Recorder of Deeds a covenant between the District of Columbia and the owners of the lots that abut the alley to be closed that incorporates the following conditions I) An order of the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia, which modifies Zoning Commission Order No. 584 in Case No. 87-37C, adopted August 8, 1988 (35 DCR 7520 et seq by reducing the maximum height to not more than 60 feet and the number of residential units to not more than 126 units in the previously adopted Planned Unit Development in that case 2) The fire prevention and protection conditions set forth by the Fire Department of the District of Columbia 3) The conditions set forth by the District of Columbia Department of Public Works; and Section, 7-421 ¯ urolled Original (4) The conditions required by the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982 Relocation Assistance Amendment Act of 1986, effective August 7, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-133; D.C. Code, sec. 7-429 Sec. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations or on October I, 1989, whichever occurs later, unless within that time an instrument is filed in the Recorder of Deeds which conveys title from the present owner of any property that abuts the alley to any other person. If, during that time, such an instrument is filed with the Recorder of Deeds, this act shall be null and void b) If the covenant required by section 2 is not filed within 2 years of the effective date of this act, this act shall expire. Cha i rma~ Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: July 7, 1989 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill 8-71 Adopted First Reading, 6-13-89 [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [~ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN, CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT Approved AYE NAY N.V. ’A.8. COUNCIL M£MBER AYE NAY x MASON X X NATHANSON X RAY x x ROLARK X X SMITH, JR X COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR, X WILSON x WINTER X X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, ]~] VOICE VOTE: Date 6-27-89 Approved, Member Jarvis voted no Recorded vote on request Absent: Lightfoot ~m ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. CHMN, CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVlS KANE LIGHTFOOT COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY NV. X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Counci~ Item on Consent Calendar Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICEVOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALLVOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORO NATHANSQN JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK UGHTFOOT SMIIH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B N,V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
