<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-242" flag="true">
  <num type="law">8-242</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Underground Storage Tank Management Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1991-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-242.pdf">D.C. Law 8-242</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 344</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0382">
      <narrative>Law 8-242, the “District of Columbia Underground Storage Tank Management Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-382, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1990, and December 18, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-325 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-242 "District of Columbia Underground Storage Tank Management Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-382 on first and second readings, December 4, 1990, and December 18, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 27, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-325, published in the January 11, 1991, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 38 page 344) and transmitted to Congress on January 15, 1991 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-242, effective Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January February March 15,16,17,18,22,23,24,25,28,29,30,31 1,4,5,6,7,19,20,21,22,25,26,27,28 1,4,5,6,7 Enrolled Original Codification District of Columbia Code New subchapter VII of Chapter 9 of Title 6 (1991 Supplement) AN ACT D,C, ACT 8-325 IN THE COUNCIL OF THF DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC, 27, 1990 To provide for the development and implementation of a comprehensive re~u]atorv proaram for under~round storaae tanks .to Drotect human health and the environment from soil, ground, and surface water contamination that results from leaking underground storaae tanks, an~ to authorize the formation of an underaround storage tank trust fund to ensure that corrective action wi]] be initiated where a solvent owner or operator cannot be identified. BF Tm FN~CTF~ BY ~MF COUNCIL OF TMF DISTPICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Un@eraroun~ Storage ~ank Management Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Definitions. For the Durposes of this act, the term i Facility" means 1 or more underground storaae tan~s at a ~iven location 2 C~uarantor" means a~y person, other than the owner or operator, who provides evidence of financial responsibi!i~v £or the under~round storage tank facility 3 Operator" means any person in control of, or bavi~ responsibility for, the ~aily operation of a ~acility, and includes A) Tn the case of an underground storage tank in use on or after November 8, 1984, any person who owns an un~eroroun~ storage tank used for the storage, use, or dispensing of regulated substances; or In the case of any underaround storage tank in use before November 8, 1984, but no longer in use on that ~ate, any person who owned a tank immediately before discontinuation of its use Person" means ~ny individual, partnership, corporation (includin~ a ~overnment corporation trust, firm oint stock company, association, consortium, joint venture, commercial entity, State, municipality, commission, New section 6-1001 Enrolled Orificial political subdivision of a State, the District of Columbia istrict aoverpment, the Unite~ States aovernment, a foreian aovernment, or any interstate body 6 Petroleum" means petroleum, including crude oil or any fraction of crude oil, that is liquid at standard conditions of temperature an ressure of 60 de~rees Fahrenheit an~ 14.7 pounds per s~uare inch absolute. {7 Pe~u]ate~ substance" means: {A ny substance defined in section 101(4) of the Comprehensive E~viro~menta] Pespo~se, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, approved Pecember ii, 1980 (94 Star. 27~7 2 [~.S.C. 960 The term "regulated substance" shall not include any susbstance regulated as a bazar@ous waste un@er subtitle C of title II of the Solid Waste Disposal Act, approved October 21, 1976 (90 Star. 2P06; 42 I~.S.C. 6~21 et sea P) Petroleum; or (C V other substance designated by the Mayor in accordance with rules issued pursuant to section Pelease" means any spill, leak, emission, discharae, escape, ]each, or disposal from an underground storaae ta 9% { Pesponsib]e party" means i n o~er or operator as defined in this section; {ii person who caused or contributed to a release from an underqround storage tank system iii) A perso~ who caused a release as a result of transfer of a reeu]ated substance to or from an un~erero~]n@ storaee ta~ system; or (iv person found to be ne~liqe~t, includine any perso~ who previously owned or operated an un~ereround storage tan~ or facility, or who arranged for or aereed to the placement of an underground storage tank system BV aereement or otherwise B) If the owner and operator of a petroleum underqround storage tan~ are separate persons, only the o~er sba] ] be reeuire~ to demonstrate financial responsibility. Poth the o~er and operator shall be liable in the event of noncompliance with the requirements of 40 CFP 2~0.90 et see i0 Un~ereround storage tank" means 1 or any combination of tanks, including underground pipes that connect tan~s, that is used to contain an accumulation of regulated substances, and the volume of which (including the volume o9 the un~ereroun~ pipes connected thereto) is 10% or more beneath the surface of the eround Underground storaee ta oes not mean a tank that is exempted in accordance with rules issued pursuant to section 13. Emlled Original Sec. 3. Notification. fa ithin 120 days after the effective date of this act, the owner of an underground storage tank shall notify the Mayor of the existence of any tank and specify the age, size, type, location, and use of the tank and any other information reauired by the Mayor b) Notice shall not be not required if the owner of an underqround storaae tank has I) maken the tank out of operation on or before January I, 1974; or {2) Previously filed a federal underaround storaqe tank notification form with the Mayor. {c ny owner who brinas into use an underground storaqe tank after the effective date of this act, shall noti{v the Mayor within 30 days of the existence of the tank as provided in subsection (a) of this section d nv owner of tan~s ~ocated at different facilities shall file a separate notification form for each facility e n owner shall submit notice to the Mayor 30 days prior to a permanent removal from service or a change in the reported use, contents, or ownership of aD under~round storage tank f) Pe~innin~ 30 days after the Mayor issues rules pursuant to section 13 re~ardin~ performance standards for new under, round storage tanks, any person who deposits regulated substances into an underground storage tank or sells or ~eases an under~round storage tank shall notify the owner of the tank of the notification requirement pursuant to section 3 ec De]ease notification requirements a ny person who knows or has reason to know of a release from an underaround storage tank shall notify the Mayor of the release b) The notification shall consist of, if known, the name of the owner, operator, and any other responsible part s well. as the ~ocatioD, date, time, volume, and substance of the release. The notification shall include, if ~nown, any immediate and onaoin~ action taken to mitigate the release, any subsequent hazardous conditions caused by the release, and an evaluation of any potential environmental hazard evident by the condition or disposition of the tank. Sec. K. Interim prohibition for installation. From the effective date of this act until the effective date of the rules issue~ pursuant to section 13 regarding performance standards for new underground storage tanks, no person may install an under~roun~ storage tank to store a regulated substance unless the tank, whether of single or 3 New section 6-1002 New section 6-1003 New section 6-1004 Enrolled Origin t double wall construction, complies with the District of Columbia ~ire Prevention Code and the new tank performance standards set forth in 40 CF~ 2P0 et seq. Sec. 6. t~nderaround Storaae man rust Fund. {a he District of Columbia Underground Storage Tank Trust Pund "Fund is hereby established as a nonlapsing, revolvina fund, to be administered by the Mayor and used for the implementation of the District’s regulatory program for underqround storage tanks that contain regulated substances b be Fu~ sba]~ be financed through, tank registration fees, civil penalties, costs recovered, grants, contributions, and monies received as reimbursement pursuant to the provisions of this act 1) Tnterest earned on the Fund shall be credited to the Fund 2) If the monies in the Fund reach $3,000,000, collection of the annual registration fee shall be suspended until the non-obliaated balance falls to ~2,750,000, at which time the fee shall be reinstituted. Funds in excess of 93,000,000 at the eD~ of the fiscal year shall remain in the Fund c) The Fund shall be accounted for under procedures established pursuant to the District of Columbia Fund 3ccou~t 3ct of ~QP0, effective June 14, 1980 D.C. Law 3-70; D.C. Code, sec. 47-371 et se and any other apD]icab]e law d) Disbursements from the Fund may be made to undertake corrective action including site assessment, c]ean-uD, and housi~ and relocation assistance. A disbursement may be made if there is a release of a reou]ated substance ~nto the environment from an underground storage tank, based upon a priority system to be established by the ~avor, if the action is necessary to protect human health or the environment, and 1 or more of the following exist } No person can be found within 90 days or a shorter period, as may be necessary to protect human health or the environment, who is: 13} ~n owner or operator B) Subject to the corrective action rules issue~ pursuant to section 3; and (C) Capab]_e of proper implementation of the required corrective action. 12) 3 situation exists that requires immediate action by the Mayor to protect human health and the environment 3) Corrective action costs at a facility exceed the amount of coverage required by the Mayor pursuant to the financial responsibility requirement imposed in the rules, New section 6-1005 Enrolled Original and expenditures from the Fund are necessary to ensure an effective corrective action 4 be responsible party for the tank has failed or refused to comply with an order issued by the Mayor that reauires compliance with the corrective action rules e) The District government’s share of the cost of corrective action with respect to any release of regulated substances into the environment from an underground storage taD~ u~derta~en under a cooperative agreement with the United States Environmental Protection Agency shall be in accordance with the provisions section 9003 (h)(7)(B) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act, approved November 8, 1984 (98 ~tat. 397 2 U.S.C qqlb(h 7 B f) Disbursements from the Fund may be provided for administrative and operational costs incurred by the Mayor in the implementation of the provisions of the underground storage taD~ re~u]atorv program.  If costs are incurred by the District government for uD~erta~in~ any corrective or enforcement action with respect to the release of a regulated substance from an un~erorouD~ storage ta the responsible parties shall be ~ointly and severally liable to the District government for the costs. In addition to any other enforcement action, the Mayor may assess any reasonable costs of the correction of the condition and anY relate~ expenses as a tax against the property, carry the tax on the regular tax rolls, and collect the tax in the same manner as real estate taxes are collected. In determining the e~uities for seeking the recovery of costs under this subsection, the Mayor may consider the amount of financial responsibility required to be maintained under the rules issued pursuant to section 13 h) Nothing in this section shall be construed to make the ~istrict oovernment responsible for corrective action costs to any person in excess of the monies in the Fund. Sec. 7. Certification, reoistration, and licensing a) The Mayor may require the licensing of any business and the certification of any individual who installs, removes, or tests underground storage tanks. The Mayor may, by rules issued in accordance with section 13, establish prerequisites for licensing and certification inc]u~in~ minimum aua~ifications, proof of financial responsibility, application fees, and procedures b ny owner of an un~er~round storage tank that contains a regulated substance shall re~ister the tank with the Mayor o~ an annual basis Dursuant to the rules issued and shall pay the required fee. A copy of the registration certificate shall be ~eDt conspicuously displayed and available for inspection at any facility where the un~er~rou~ storage tan~ is located. New section 6-1006 Enrolled Original (c) The annual registration fee shall be i 500 for an initial registration and 200 for a renewal registration for a tank over 10,000 gallons; and (2 00 for an initial registration and i00 for a renewal registration for a tank under i0,000 gallons d) robe Mayor may adjust fees in accor4ance with rules issue@ pursuant to section 13 beginning 2 years after the effective date of this act. Sac Denial, suspension, or revocation be Mayor may suspend, revoke, or refuse to issue, renew, or restore a license or certificate issued under section 7 to protect the public health, safety, or welfare if the ~ayor finds that the applicant or holder has ]) Failed to meet an8 maintain the standards established by this act or rules issued pursuant to this act 2 eubmitte4. a false or fraudulent record, invoice, or report 3) Fn~a~e~ in frau~ or misrepresentation in the application for licensure or certification 4 a~ a history of repeated violations; or (5 ad his license or certification denied, revoked, or suspe~ed in another state or jurisdiction eec. 9. Pight of entry; inspections; analyses; corrective action a) For the purpose of enforcing this act or any rule issued pursuant to this act, the Mayor or his or her desiQpated representative may, at any reasonable time, upon the presentation of appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge i) Fnter without de]~ay any place where an underground storaqe tan~ is or has been located 2 nspect and obtain samples of any regulated substance contained in the tank; { 3) Inspect an8 copy any record, report, information, or test result required to be maintained pursuant to this act, rules issue4 pursuant to this act, or relevant to the operation of any underground storage tank; add [ Conduct monitoring or testing of any tank, associated eouipment, contents, surrounding soils, air, surface water, or eroun~ water. t b) If the Mayor is 8enie~ access to any place where an underground storaee tank is or has been lo~ated, the Mayor may apply to a court of competent jurisdiction for a search warrant c) If a desienated representative or employee of the Mayor obtains any sample prior to leaving the premises, he 6 New section 6-1007 New section 6-1008 EmoII I O i&amp;amp;inal or she shall give the owner, operator, or agent in charge, a receipt that describes the sample obtained, and if reouested, a portion of the sample eaual in volume or weight to the portion obtained. If any analysis is made of a sample, a copy of the results of the analysis shall be furnished promptly to the owner, operator, or agent in charae d} The Mayor may require the responsible party to provide any information or record with respect to any underaround storaae tank or system if the information or recor~ is necessary to determine compliance with the rules or to conduct monitoring or testinq of the tanks, associated eauipment, contents, surrounding soils, air, or surface water or Ground water. The Mayor may reauire the responsible party to take any necessary corrective action e) After notification to the owner, operator, or agent in charqe, the Mayor may take summary corrective action if a release of a reaulated substance from an underqround storage tank creates an imminent threat to human health or the environment. The Mayor shall provide an opportunity for review of the summary action, without pre@u~ice to the authority of the Mayor to take and complete the action. The owner, operator, or agent in charge shall be ~otified by persona] service or by registered mail to the last known address and by conspicuous posting on the property. If the owner, operator, or agent in charge is unknown or cannot be located, notice shall be provided by conspicuous postin~ on the property. Sec. 10. Enforcement; Penalties a) Yf the Mayor believes or has reason to believe that there is a violation or a threatened violation of this act or the rules issued pursuant to this act, the Mayor may give written notice of the violation or threatened violation to the owner, operator, or any other responsible party deemed appropriate by the Mayor, and may require the person to ta~e the corrective measures the Mayor considers reasonable and necessary i) The notice shall state the nature of violation or threatened violation, afford the right to a bearing, an~ allow a reasonable time for the performance of the necessary corrective measures, consistent with the ]i~eliboo~ for harm and the need to protect health, safety, life, property, and the environment b) If a person fails to comply with. a notice of violation issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section w~tbin the time stated i~ the notice, the Mayor may issue a compliance order, a cease and desist order, or institute a court action for injunctive relief or recovery of any corrective action costs, as may be necessary to promptly and New section 6-1009 Enrolled Origin i effectively terminate the violation or threatened violation, and protect life, property, or the environment c) The Mayor may issue an immediate compliance order or seem a temporarv restraining order, without first providing reasonable notice and an opportunity for a hearing as provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, to restrain any person from engaging in any unauthorized activity that immediate].v endangers or causes damaae to public health or the environment ] compliance order or cease and desist order issued under this section shall become final unless any perso~ named in the order reauests a public bearinq within 15 days after the order is served. If reauested, the public heari~a shall be conducted in compliance with the reauirements of section i0 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1208; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1509 APA d) Any person who fails to comply with a compliance order or a cease and desist order issued pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be liable for a civil penalty of not more than $25,000 for each day of noncompliance e ny owner who knowingly fails to notify or submits false information pursuant to section 3 shall be subject to a civil ~ena].ty ~ot to exceed SI0,000 for each violation f ny person who fails to comply with any applicable rules issued pursuant to sectioD 3 or with the requirements of section 5 shall be subject to a civil penalty not to excee 0,000 for each tank for each day of violation A civil fine, penalty, or fee may be imposed as an alternative sanction for any infraction of the provisions of this act or the rules issued in accordance with this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Pistrict of Columbia Civil Infraction Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6 D.C. Code, sec. 6-2701 et sea Civil Infractions Act Adjudication of any infraction shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Civil Infractions Act. {h) Any prosecution under this section shall be in the Superior Court of the ~istrict of Columbia Court in the name of the Pistrict of Columbia, and shall be instituted by the Office of Corporation Counsel i) In any action brought for civil penalties, damage, or eauitable relief under this act, the statute of ]_imitations shall not begin to toll until the injury is discovered or, with reasonable diligence, should have been discovered. Sec I. Summary action a) If the Mayor determines during or after an investisation, that the conduct of any business or New section 6-1010 Enrolled Original individual who installs, removes, or tests an underground storaoe taD~ presents an imminent danger to the health or safety of the residents of the District, the Mayor may summarily suspend or restrict, without a bearing, the license of the business or certificate of the individual b) At the time of the summary suspension or restrictioD, the Mayor shall provide the licensee or certificate bol~er with a written notice stating the action that is being taken, the basis for the action, and the right of the licensee or certificate holder to reguest a hearing c) A licensee or certificate holder shall have the right to request a hearing within 72 hours after service of notice of the summary suspension or restriction of the liceDse or certificate. The Mayor shall hold a hearing within 15 days of receipt of a timely request, and shall issue a ~ecision within 15 days after the hearing d) Any decision and order adverse to a licensee or certified holder shall be in writing and accompanied by findings of fact and conclusions of law. The Mayor shall provide a copy of the decisioD and order and findings of fact and conclusions of law to each party or his or her attorney of record e nv !ice, see or certificate holder aggrieved by a decision and order may file an appeal in accordance with sectio 1 of the ~PA (D.C. Code, sec. 1-1511 ec. 12. Citizens right of action a V perso~ a~srieved by a violation of any requirement of this act or rule issued pursuant to this act may commence a civil action on his or her own behalf against any person who is alleged to be in violation b) mbe Court shall have jurisdiction in any action brought pursuant to subsection (a) of this section to e~force the requirement or to order any action necessary to correct the violation, and to impose any civil penalty provided for the vio]~ation c) No action may be commenced under subsection (a) of this section until 30 days after the plaintiff has given notice of the violation to the Office of Corporation Counsel for the District of Columbia and to the alleged violator. { No action may be commenced under subsection (a) of this section if the Mayor has commenced and is diligently prosecutin~ an action to obtain compliance with the requirement of this act or rule issued pursuant to this act concerned e) The Court, in issuing any final order in any action brought pursuant to this section, may award costs of ti~ation, iDcludinG reasonable attorney and expert witness fees, to the prevailing or subtantially prevailing party if the court ~etermi~es an award is appropriate. 9 New section 6-1011 Enrolled Original Sec. 13. Nules a) mhe Mayor shall pursuant to title 1 of the APA (D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq issue and may revise, as aDpropriate, rules necessary to carry out the purposes and implement the provisions of this act, including rules reaar~ina reouirements for I) The maintenance of leak detection, prevention, inventory control, and tank testing systems 2) The maintenance of records of any monitoring or lea~ detection system or an inventory control or tank testing system 3) mbe reporting of releases and any corrective action taken; fd be abandonment in place, closure, or removal of underground storage tanks to prevent future releases of reou]ated substances into the environment 5) The maintenance of evidence of financial responsibility in order to take corrective action and compensate any 3rd party for bodily injury or property damage which shall conform to the federal financial responsibility requirements issued pursuant to section 9004 of the Solid Waste Disposal ~ct, approved November 8, 1984 (98 Star. 3282; 42 USC 6991c 6 be establishment of standards of performance for new under~round storage tanks 7) The taking of corrective action in response to a release from an underground storage tank that meets District and federal clean-up objectives 8) Public participation in the development, revision, implentation, aD~ enforcement of this act 9) Standards and fees for the registratlon, installation, an@ abandonment of tanks; and (I0) Tanks that are exempt from regulation. {b ntil the Wayor, by rule, determines which tanks shall be exempt from regulation, the exemptions set forth in sectio 001 of the Solid ~aste Disposal Act (42 U.S.C. 6Q91(I shall be applicable. Sec 4. Conforming amendment Section ll(c) of the Water Pollution Control Act of IQ effective March ~16, Iq85 (D.C. Law 5-188; D.C. Code, sec 30(c is amended by adding the phrase "in conformity with the reouirements of the Pistrict of Columbia Underground Storage Tank Management Act of 1990" after the word "leaks Sec. 15. Fffective Date. This act shall ta~e effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the i0 New section 6-1012 Section 6-930 Enrolled Original District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in sectio~ 602(c)(i) of the Pistrict of Columbia Self-Covernment and Governmental Peorganization Act, approve~ December 24 73 7 Stat 13; P.C. Code, sec. 1-233{c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Peaister, the ~istrict of Columbia Statutes-at-Larae, or the District of Columbia Municipal Peculations Chairman Council of the Pistrict of Columbia APPROVED: December 27, 1990 ii Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE D~STRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Approved B8-382 Recorded vote on request all Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote present COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER J i AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Item on Consent Calendar [~ACTION&amp;amp;DATE: Adopted Final Reading VOICE VOTE: Approved Date 1 9-!8-90 Recorded vote on request Wilson Absent: COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVlS KANE LIGHTFOOT ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY N.V. A.B. X Indicates Vote Secretary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY NV. A.B J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER N.V Present, not vot!ng Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVlS KANE LIGHTFOOT AYE NAY NV. A.B. X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIT.H, JR. A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.08"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.09"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.10"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>12</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.11"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>13</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-113.12"/>
  </section>
</document>
