<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-247">
  <num type="law">8-247</num>
  <heading type="short">DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COMPULSORY SCHOOL ATTENDANCE AMENDMENT ACT OF 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1991-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-247.pdf">D.C. Law 8-247</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 376</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0239">
      <narrative>Law 8-247 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-239, which was referred to the Committee on Education and Libraries. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1990, and December 18, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-331 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>¯ kwiktag ® 103 202 183 0 ee Enrolled Original Codification, District of Col~mlbia Code (1991 Supplement) AN ACT D.C. ACT 8-331 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC. 27, 1990 To amend An Act To provide for compulsory school attendance, for the taking of a school census in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, to require parents, guardians, and others who have custody or control of minors who are already or will become 5 years of age on or by ~ecember 31st of the current school year to place these minors in regular attendance in public, independent, private, or parochial schools, or in private instruction; and to establish penalties for failure to assure the regular instruction of these minors. BF TT FNACTFD BY THF COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Compulsory School Attendance ~mendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. An Act To provide for compulsory school attendance, for the taking of a school census in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved February 4, Iq25 (43 Star. 806; D.C. Code, sec. 31-401 et se_9_q is amended as follows a) Prticles I and II (D.C. Code, secs. 31-401 through 31-410) are amended to read as follows APTICLE I DEFINITIONS Sec. i. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term i Board" means the District of Columbia Board of Education 2 District" means the District of Columbia 3 Minor" means a person who has not reached IP years of aqe, pursuant to section 2 of the District of Columbia Age of Majority Act, effective July 22, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-75, D.C. Code, sec. 30-401 4 School year" means the period, established by the Board, from the openinq of regular school programs, Section 31-401 Enrolled Original typically in September, until the closing of regular school proarams, typically in June TICLE II COMPULSORY SCHOOL ATTENDANCE "Sec. i. Establishment of school attendance reauirements a very parent, guardian, or other person, who resides permanently or temporarily in the District during any school year and who has custody or control of a minor who has reached the age of 5 years or will become 5 years of aae on or before December 31st of the current school year shall place the minor in regular attendance in a public, independent, private, or parochial school, or in private instruction during the period of each year when the public schools of the Pistrict.are in session. This obligation of the parent, guardian, or other person having custody extends until the minor reaches the age of 18 years. For the purpose of this section placement in summer school is not reauired b) Anv minor who has satisfactorily completed the senior high school course of study prescribed by the Board, and has been granted a diploma that certifies his or her qraduation from high school, or who holds a diploma or certificate of qraduation from another course of study determined by the Board to be at least equivalent to that required by the Board for graduation from the public senior high schools, shall be excused from further attendance at school c) Any minor who has reached the age of 17 years may be allowed flexible school hours by the Superintendent of Schools provided he or she is actually, lawfully, gainfully, and regularly employed, but in no case shall he or she be excused entirely from regular attendance or excused to the extent that his or her timely graduation would be jeopardized or prevented d) The Board shall, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1203; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et se_g_q APA issue rules to establish requirements to qovern acceptable credit for studies completed at independent or private schools and private instruction, to govern the validity of applications for permission to be absent from school, to govern the selection and appointment of appropriate staff members to carry out the provisions of this act under the direction of the Superintendent of Schools, pursuant to the District of Columbia Merit Personnel Act, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code, sec. 1-601.1 et sea and in respect to other matters within the scope of’ authority of the Board that relates to this act Sec. 2. Fnforcement; penalties. Section 31-402 Section 31-403 Enrolled Original a) An accurate daily record of the attendance of all minors covered by sections 1 and 2 of this article shall be kept by the teachers of each public, independent, private, or parochial school and by every teacher who gives instruction privately. These records shall be open for inspection at all times by the Board, the Superintendent of Schools, school attendance officers, or other persons authorized to enforce this act {b) It shall be the duty of each principal, head teacher, or school administrative officer as designated in each public, independent, private, or parochial school, and of each teacher who gives private instruction to report to the ~oard the school attendance of any minor covered by section l(a) who is enrolled in a school or who is enrolled for private instruction and who is absent from school or instruction for more than 2 full-day sessions or 4 half-day sessions in any school month, along with a statement of the reasons for the absences c he absence of a minor covered by section l(a) without valid excuse shall be unlawful d} The parent, guardian, or other person who has custody or control of a minor covered by section l(a) who is absent from school without a valid excuse shall be guilty of a misdemeanor e ny person convicted of failure to keep a minor in regular attendance in a public, independent, private, or parochial school, or failure to provide regular private instruction acceptable to the Board may be fined not less than ~I00 or imprisoned for not more than 5 days, or both for each offense f) Fach unlawful absence of a minor for 2 full-day sessions or for 4 half-day sessions during a school month shall constitute a separate offense g) For the ist offense, upon payment of costs, the sentence may be suspended and the defendant may be placed on probation {h) For any person convicted under this section, the courts shall consider requiring the offender to perform community service as an alternative to fine or imprisonment or both Sec. 3. Census of minors The Board, or its designee, shall conduct, annually or as frequently as may be found necessary or desirable, a complete census of all minors 3 years of age or more who permanently or temporarily reside in the District. The census record shall be amended from day to day as changes of residence occur among minors within the age group and as other persons come within or leave the age group, and as other persons within the age group become residents of or leave the District. The census record of minors shall give Section 31-404 the full name, address, sex, and date of birth of each minor, the school attended by him or her and, if the minor is not at school, the name and address of his or her employer, if any, and the name, address, telephone numbers, if any, and occupation of each parent or guardian Sec. 4. Report of enrollments and withdrawals The principal or head teacher of each public, independent, private, or parochial school, and each teacher who gives private instruction, shall, in accordance with the rules adopted by the Board pursuant to title I of the APA, report to the Board the name, address, sex, and date of birth of each minor who resides permanently ~or temporarily in the District who transfers between schools or who enrolls in or withdraws from his or her school Sec. 5. Penalty for failure to provide correct information Any parent, guardian, custodian, principal, or teacher of a minor who has reached the age of 3 years who willfully neglects or refuses to provide the information required by sections 1 through 5, or who knowingly makes any false statement, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor b) Sections 1 and 2 of Article III (D.C. Code, sec. 31-411 and sec. 31-412) are repealed. Sec. 3. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section ~02(c){i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(i and publication in either the District of Columbia Pe~ister, the District of Columbia Section 31-405 Section 31-406 Sections 31-411 31-412 Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal ~eau]ations the District of Columbia [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 12-04-90 B8-239 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request all present Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.M. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER NATHANSON SMITH, JR. A.8 Absent AYE ’NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR, WILSON WINTER ECORD Secretary to the Council J Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, VOICE VOTE: Approved Date 12-18-90 Recorded vote on request WilsonAbsent: [3 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting G~I. TIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the CouKe Item on Consent Calendar J J J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATF" [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V, A.Bo COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT.H, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B, N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER A.B. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
