<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-30">
  <num type="law">8-30</num>
  <heading type="short">Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children Authorization Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1989-09-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-30.pdf">D.C. Law 8-30</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 4744</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0107">
      <narrative>Law 8-30, “Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children Authorization Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-107, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 30, 1989 and June 13, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 27, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-53 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 204 095 5 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-30 "Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children Authorization Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-107 on first and second readings, May 30, 1989, and June 13, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 27, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-53, published in the July 7, 1989, edition of the D.C. Resister Vol. 36 page 4744) and transmitted to Congress on June 30, 1989 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-30, effective September 20, 1989 ’ e D irman of the Cou c’l Dates Counted Durin~ the 30-da~v o~n essional Review Period: July 10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28,31 August 1,2,3,4 September 6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19 D.C. LAW -30 A BILL i),c, L’T 8-53 En~olled Orlglnal Codification, New Chapter 10~o/f~Title~32 (1990 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To authorize the District of Columbia to enter into the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children Authorization Act of 1989 Sec. 2. The Mayor of the District of Columbia District is authorized to execute a compact on behalf of the District with any state that legally joins the compact in the form Substantially as follows: ARTICLE I. Purpose and policy. It is the purpose and policy of the party states to cooperate in the interstate placement of children to the end that I) Each child who requires placement shall receive the maximum opportunity to be placed in a suitable environment with a person or institution that has appropriate qualifications and facilities to provide necessary and desirable care 2) The appropriate authority in a state where a child is to be placed may have full opportunity to ascertain the circumstances of the proposed placement in order to promote full compliance with applicable requirements for the protection of the child 3) The appropriate authority of the sending state may obtain the most complete information on the basis of which to evaluate a projected placement before it is made 4) Appropriate jurisdictional arrangements for the care of children are promoted. ARTICLE II. Definitions. For the purposes of this compact the term: New, Section 32~I042 0 0 ’- C C O0 vO ’ c’I 0 F (’b 0 O~ 0 En~olled Orlg~nal party jurisdiction. Withdrawal of a party state shall not affect the rights, duties, or obligations under this compact of any sending state with respect to a placement made prior to the effective date of withdrawal. ARTICLE X. Construction and severabil i ty. The provisions of this compact shall be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes of the compact. If this compact is held to be contrary to the constitution of any party state, the compact shall remain in effect as to the remaining states and in effect as to the state affected as to all severable matters. Sec. 3. The term "appropriate authority" as used in this compact means, with reference to the District, the Director of the Department of Human Services. Sec. 4. An officer of the District that has the authority to place children and an official of a private agency licensed as a child placement agency by the District government pursuant to An Act to Regulate The Placement of Children in Family Homes and For Other Purposes, approved April 22, 1944 (58 Stat. 193; D.C. Code, sec. 32-1001 et seq is authorized to enter into an agreement with th~ appropriate officer or agency in another party state pursuant to paragraph (b) of Article V of the compact. Sec. 5 (a If a child is adjudicated delinquent and committed to the custody of the District of Columbia Department of Human Services DHS pursuant to D.C. Code, sec. 16-2320, and DHS, pursuant to Article Vl of the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children Compact places the child in another party jurisdiction, the rules issued pursuant to section 5 shall apply for purposes of meeting the requirements of Article Vl of the compact b) DHS shall afford an opportunity for an administrative hearing to the parents or legal guardian before placing a child. Subsequent to the hearing, the decision to make a placement upon request of the parent or guardian of the child, may be reviewed at a court hearing in the Juvenile Branch of the Family Division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. The court hearing shall be held within 30 days after a request is made. The decision to place the child in an institution in another party state shall be upheld if the court finds that 1) Equivalent facilities for the child are not available within the jurisdiction of the District; and New, Section 32-1041 New, Section 32-1043 New, Section 32-1044 5 ¯ nrolled Original (2) Institutional care in another state is in the best interest of the child and will not produce undue hardship c) Except as provided in this section, the manner and standard of review by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall be as set forth in DCAPA d) A court review in accordance with this section shall not authorize the court to i) Order DHS to pay for the care or treatment of a child who has not been committed to its custody 2) Order specific placement in another party state if the child has been committed to the custody of DHS 3) Review a decision by DHS to return a child to the District; or (4) Set aside the placement decision of DHS, unless an abuse of discretion is found e) This section shall not affect the authority of the court to order a specific placement. Sec. 6. This act shall take effect afte~ a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. of Columbia APPROVED: June 27, 1989 6 Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Adopted First Approved Lightfoot [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. 8-107 Reading, 5-30-89 AYE NAY N.V. A,B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. ’WILSON WINTER X Indicates Vote Absent N.V Present ’ 2f’~ICATION RECOR D not voting ~unc G b/Date Item on Consent Calendar ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, 6-13-80 AYE NAY [3{VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request all presentAbsent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT ’ AYE NAY N,V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV.COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER X Indicates Vote acl Absent N.V Present, not voting Secretary to the Councii Date [] Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIIH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J J~-J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1421"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1422"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1423"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1424"/>
  </section>
</document>
