<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-51">
  <num type="law">8-51</num>
  <heading type="short">Natural Disaster Consumer Protection Temporary Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-51.pdf">D.C. Law 8-51</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 8-51, the “Natural Disaster Consumer Protection Temporary Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-330. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 27, 1989 and July 11, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 1, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-85 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 8-51 became effective on October 19, 1989.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag® 103 203 215 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-51 "Natural Disaster Consumer Protection Temporary Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-330 on first and second readings, June 27, 1989, and July 11, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on August I, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-85, published in the August II, 1989, edition of the D~.C Re e ter Vol. 36 page 5801) and transmitted to Congress on August 8, 1989 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, ’cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-51, effective October 19, 1989. ¢ Chairman of the Council Dates Counted Durin~ the 30-da ssional Review Period: September 6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,25,26,27,28,29 October 2,3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,16,17,18 D 0 LL 0 0 0 0 -4J (D 0 J.r- 0 E E E 0P 0 j 0 J 0 ¯ ¯ 0.0 I&amp;lt; 0 Enrolled Or~glnal Sec. 5. Effective date a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire/on the 2,~Z, Sth day of its having taken effect i rman Council of the District of Columbia Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill 8-330 Adopted First Reading, 6-27-89 Approved Recorded vote on request all presentAbsent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B, COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON ¯ JARVIS -’ RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote Secretary to the Council [~ltem on Consent Calendar ~[ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL k4E~’BER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY AB A~$ent N.V Present, CERT~TION RECORD not votin£1 Date Adopted Final Reading, 7-11-89 ~{:VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Approved all present r~ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARViS KANE LIGHTFOOT C~UNCIL M~MBER AYE NAY N A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER MASON ITHOMAS, SR. NATHANSON WILSON RAY WINTER S_MITH, JR X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting c AT ON RECORD Secreta~ to the Council [/7 Date AYE NAY N.V. Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICEVOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSO~’ RAY ROLAR~’ SMIIH;JR. A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD u ’ COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V, THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
