<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-58">
  <num type="law">8-58</num>
  <heading type="short">Construction Codes Temporary Amendment Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-01-30</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-58.pdf">D.C. Law 8-58</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 7382</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0344">
      <narrative>Law 8-58, the “Construction Codes Temporary Amendment Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-344, which was retained by Council. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 11, 1989 and September 26, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 13, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-88 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 204 365 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-58 "Construction Codes Temporary Amendment Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-344 on first and second readings, July 11, 1989, and September 26, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 13, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-88, published in the October 27, 1989, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 36 page 7382) and transmitted to Congress on October 18, 1989 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-58, effective January 30, 1990 ff Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: October November January 18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30,31 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,13,14,15,16,17,20,21,22 23,24,25,26,29 AN ACT 8 8 8 ¯ ~mroXZe~ OrL~izml~ Codification, District of Columbia Code (] 990 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE: DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCT 3 To amend, on a temporary basis, the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986 to authorize the denial of a building permit when necessary to protect the security and safety of the President or Vice President of the United States. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Construction Codes Temporary Amendment Act of 1989" Sec. 2. Section 4 of the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986, effective March 21, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-216; D.C. Code, sec. 5-1303 is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows d) No permit required under the Construction Codes shall be issued if it is determined by the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs that the United States Secret Service has established that the issuance of the permit would adversely impact the safety and security of the President or Vice President of the United States Sec. 3. Section 2 shall apply to each permit application that has not been granted by the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs on the effective date of this act. Sec. 4 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(i and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Note 1-229 Note, 5-1303 Note, 5-1303 ¯ u~olled Or~Etna~ Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: October 13, 1989 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Item on Consent Calendar I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: 8-344 Adopted First Reading, 7-11-89 Approved Crawford [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS 1 KANE LtGHTFOOT AYE MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V RTIFICATION RECORD /’ Secretary to the Council l~ Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Adopted Final Readinq, Approved all present NAY N.V.A.B Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR, WILSON WINT’im Date 9-26-89 A,B. [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT, COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT" ’ X Indicates Vote Secretary to the Council A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. RAY I WINTER ROLARK SMITH, JR. A.B. Absent N.V Present, not voting RECORO a Date [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ~I.V. CHMN, CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIIH, JR. A.B Absent NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER ~AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
