<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-71">
  <num type="law">8-71</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Public School Firearm Prohibition Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-02-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-71.pdf">D.C. Law 8-71</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 7746</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0240">
      <narrative>Law 8-71, the “District of Columbia Public School Firearm Prohibition Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-240, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 10, 1989, and October 24, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 2, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-108 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 202 190 ACT o.c. Act o 8’ Enrolled Codification, District of Columbia Code (1990 Suppl~nent) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL~BIA NOV 0 ~1, 1989 To amend section 16-2307 of the District of Columbia Code to specify that a person under the age of 18 years charged with the possession of a firearm in or within 500 feet of a public school building or property or a public school sponsored event may be charged as an adult. BE IT ENACTED BY THE CO~CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Public School Firearm Prohibition Act of 1989" Sec. 2. Section 16-2307(a) of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) By striking "or" in paragraph (2 b) By striking the at the end of paragraph (3) and inserting the phrase or" in its place; and (c) By adding a new paragraph (4) to read as follows 4) a child under the age of 18 years is charged with the illegal possession or control of a firearm in or within 500 feet of a District of Columbia public school building, public school property, or a public school-sponsored event Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Section 16-2307 1 ¯ n~olled O~igl Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chalrman Council of the District of Columbia 2 COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVlS KANE LIGHTFOOT COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: I~ Item on Consent Calendar ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted First I~ VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY N.Y. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. B8-240 Reading, 10-10-89 AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER X i’ndicates Vote A.B 7~ bsent N.V Present, not voting CERT~,I£ATION RECORD V Secretary to the Council U Date Item on Consent Calendar ~ACTION&amp;amp;DATE: Adopted Final Reading,10-24-89 AYE i NAY N.V VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Ray and Wilson [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT I SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote’ A.8 Absent ~oun~il CERTIF ORD [] Item on Consent Calendar J AYE NAY N.V.AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOO X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIT.H, JR. A.B Absent I AYE NAY N.V.A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER J AYE NAY N.V. A.B. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
