<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-87" flag="true">
  <num type="law">8-87</num>
  <heading type="short">Protection of Children from Exposure to Drug-Related Activity Amendment Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1990-03-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-87.pdf">D.C. Law 8-87</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 50</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0139">
      <narrative>Law 8-87, the “Protection of Children from Exposure to Drug-Related Activity Amendment Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-139, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 21, 1989, and December 5, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-137 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag® 103 201 515 I 0 0 AN AC’r Enrolled Original District of Columbia Code (1990 Supplement) D.C. ACT 8 1.9 IN THE COU] CIL O.F THE DI[~TRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC 1989 To require a law enforcement officer or health professional in the District. of Columbia to report the presence of a child living in a home environment where illegal drug-related ac, tivity takes place; and to r~equire that the Child Protective Services Division of the District of Columbia Department of Human Services investigate these reports, provide treatment for and counseling to families involved in drug-related activity, and initiate any other necessary proceedings to protect the best interest of t[he child. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act rosy be cited as the "Protection of Children from Exposure to Drug-related Activity Amendment Act of 1989" Sec. 2. An Act To prowLde for the mandatory reporting by physicians and in.st:[t.utions, in the District of Columbia of certain physical abuse of children, approved November 6, ]966 (80 Stat. 1’35 D.C. Code, sec. 2-135] et seq is amended as follows a) By amend:[ng section 2 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-1352) by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows d) In addition to the requirements in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, any health, professional. licensed pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision. Act, of Ig85, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Code, sec. 2-330!.1 et seq or a law enforcement officer, exceFt an undercover officer whose identity or investigaticn m].ght be jeopard.~zed, shall report immediately, in writing, to the Child Protective Services Division of the Department of Human Services, that the law enforcement officer or health professional has reasonable cause to believe tha.t a child i~ abused as a result of inadequate care, control~ or subsistence in the home environment due to e.~{posu].-e to drug-related activity. The 2-1352 Enroiled Original report shall be i.n accordance with the provisions of section 3 of this act b) By amen.din~g section 3(a)(2 D.C. Code, sec. 2.-1353(a)(2 by ad&amp;lt;lin~7 the ph]:ase "or if the abuse involves drug-related ’ actl%ity after the word Pol.ice Sec. 3. The iPrevention c.f Child Abuse: and Neglect Act of 1977, effective 5".eptember .2.’.’ 1.9"77 (D.C. Law 2-22; D.C. Code, sec. 6-2~01 ![ e is amended as follows a) By amending section 1102 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-2101) by adding the following new subsections to read as follows j Drug" shall have the same meaning as the term "controlled substance" has in section I02 of the District of Columbia Uniform Cont c’,lled Substances Act of 1981, effective August 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-29; D.C. Code, sec. 33-501 k Drug-related activity" means the use, sale, distribution, or manufacture of a drug or drug paraphernalia without a legally valid license or medical prescription i Law enforcement officer" means a sworn officer of the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Co lumbi a m Abused when used with reference to a child, means a child whose parent, guardian or custodian inflicts or fa~.is to make ree.sonab!e efforts to prevent the infliction of physical cr mental injury upon the child, including excessive corpo]:a.l punishment, an act of sexual abu:~e, mo].estation or exploitation, or an injury that ults from exposu’.[.e t drug-]:elated activity b) By adding a new section ].06a to ]:ead as follows See. 106a a) [[’[he Division shall, upon receipt of a report from a law er~.forcement off.icer or a health professional that a child is abused as a result of insdequate care, ¢:o:n.trol, or subsistence due to exposure to drug-related activity :[in the home environment I) Co;m~[~ence an initi.al investigation in accordance with sections 1.04(b) and 106 of this act 2) Dete:rmine whether the child should be removed temporarily from the home environment or can be protected in the home env~_ronment in accordance with section 107(a) of this act 3) Con’m:~enc, e a social investigation and provide social services in ccord n.ce ~zith section ].09(b) of this act, if the initial, inv.esi igation results i.n a supported report b) A social investigation pursuant to ’.paragraph (a)(3) of this section ’.hall inc].ude I) A determinatic,,z of whether there is reasonable evidence that any member of the child’s home 2-1353 6-2101 New 6-2104.1 environment uses drugs illegally, is dependent on drugs, or needs drug abuse treatment 2) A determ.~[nation of whether there is reasonable evidence that the child is expos~ed regularly to drug use in the home environment 3) A deter~ination of whether there reasonable evidence tb.~t he 4istrihution or sale of illegal drugs or drug paraphe~nslia occurs in the child’s home environment; and A determination of whether there is reasonable evidence that drug-related activity has contributed to or is likely to centribute to violent conduct within the child’s home environment c) The social service~ required by paragraph of th~s section, shall include I) Provisien of drug treatment to any member of the child’s home environment 9~’ho ~s determined to be in need of drug treatment according to the District of Columbia Substance Abuse Treatment and Prevention Act of 1989, passed on 2nd reading on October 3] 989 (Enrolled version of Bill 8- 4.03 2) Mea~,ures to facilitate action by the child’s family, w~th the ass an e of the D~vision and the Police if necessary, to eliminate the child’s exposure to drug use or "to the distribut:[on or sale of illegal drugs or drug paraphernalia in. the home environment; and 3) Any other service authorized or re~ired by this act or other appl:[cable laws or rules of the District c) By amending section ~09(b D.C. Code, sec 107(b as follo s ]) By amending subparagraph by striking the period and insert~.ng’ the phrase an(]" in its place; and (2) By adding new subparagraph (5) to read as fo]. l ows 5) refer:ring the fam:[ly to &amp;lt;:]rug treatment services in the even.t of neglect or abuse that. results from drug-related activity d) By amend.in~E section 203(a)(2} (D.C. Code, sec. 6-2113 2 by 8~dd.ing the ph.r~se or abused" after the phrase "sllegedly n.~gle.,ted e) By amending s ct~on 3C~3 (D.C, Code, sec. 6-2123) by adding a new subsectRon (c) to read as follows c) The Ch i of ~Le Division and the Director of the Department of Human Res,~u~ces shall ~mplement the Protection of Children from Exposure to ~rug-related Activity Amendment Act of 1989 The h~ef of the E, ivision and the Director of the Department of Human Services s~all provide the services authorized pursuant to t]] s section to a child who is abused 6-2107 as a result of inadequate care, control, or subsistence due to exposure to drug re lated activity Sec. 4. Title [6 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) By amending section 16-2301(23) to read as follows 23) The term "abused when used with reference to a child, means a ch:[Id whose parent, guardian, or custodian inflicts or fails to make reasonable efforts to prevent the infliction of physical or mental injury upon the child, including excessive corporal punishment, an act of sexual abuse, molestation, or exploitation, or an injury that results from exposure to drug-related activity in the child’ s home environment and (b) By amending section 16--2353(b) as follows I) By amending paragraph (3) by striking the word "and 2) By amendin(j paragraph by striking the period and inserting the phrase and" in its place; and (c) By adding a new paragraph (5) to read as follows 5) Evidence that drug-related activity continues to exist n a child’s home environment after ntervention and services have been provided pursuant to section 106(a) of the Pr’e~ention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977, effective SeI:tember 23, 19"7’7 (D.C. Law 2--22; D.C. Code, sec. 6-.2[~.01 t s__e.g Evidence of continued drug-activd.ty shall be given great weight. Sec. 5. This act shall take effect, after a 30-day period of Congressional review fol].owing approval by the Mayor (or in the ev~:nt of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Gove.r mental Reorganization Act, approved December 24 [[973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. ].-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia 16-2301 16-2353 £nroiled Origina~ S t atute s- at- Large, Regulations. the DisL ict o~ Col bia Municipal Cou:~cil of the District: of Columbia aY°D ri strict o~ APPROVED: December 21, 1989 5 [] Item on Consent Calendar 5~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill 8-139 Adopted First Rearing 11-21-89 Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present E3 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN, CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE I ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates e A.B Absent N.V TION RECORD Secretary to the ~oouncil [~ Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Thomas Present, not voting Reading, 12-5-89 Date ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ~AY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON THOMAS, SR. CRAWFORD NATHANSON WILSON JARVIS RAY WINTER KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. AYE NAY N.V X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent N.V Present, not voting ON RECORD Secretary to the o~ Item on Consent Calendar Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALLVOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIT, H, JR. A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON i WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
