<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-89">
  <num type="law">8-89</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-03-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-89.pdf">D.C. Law 8-89</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 644</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 8-89 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-265, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 5, 1989, and December 19, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 8, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-140 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag 103 202 274 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-89 "District of Columbia Codification Amendment Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-265 on first and second readings, December 5, 1989, and December 19, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on January 8, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-140, published in the January 19, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 644) and transmitted to Congress on January 23, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-89, effect~e March 15, 1990 rman of the Counci Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January February March 23,24,25,26,29,30,31 1,2,5,6,7,8,20,21,22,23,26,27,28 1,2,5,6,7,8,9,12,13,14 AN ACT l).C. ACT 8 140 Enrolled Original Codification, District of Columbia Code (1990 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JAN 8 19.90 To amend the District of Columbia Codification Act of 1975 to exclude from the prior’ publication requirement any resolution that pertains to the internal operation or organization of the Council. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Codification Amendment Act of 1989 Sec. 2. Section 204(f) of the District of Columbia Codification Act of 19’75, effective October 8, 1975 (D.C. Law 1-19; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1602 is amended to read as fol].ows f) No act or resolution shall be effective until the act or resolution has been published in the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or .tlhe Dis%.rict of Columbia Municipal Regulations, except that any emergency act or resolution, approved pursuant to section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act of 1973, approved December 2 ]973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Code, sec. 1-229(a or any resolution that pertains to the internal operation or organization of the Council, shall be effective without prior publication but shall be published as soon as practicable Section 1-1602 Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act pproved December 2 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in the either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Enrolled Original Statutes-at-Large, cr n.e Dist ic’l~ of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia Di~tzict of Columbia APPROVED: January 8, 1990 I~ Item on Consent Calendar I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: 1~ VO ICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill 8-265 Adopted First Reading, 12-5-89 Approved Absent: Thomas [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote A.B COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANS’ON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. A.B Absent { ’ AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THO~IAS, SR. WILSON WINTER N.V. Present, not votin9 C CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to th6(-’~ouncil Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Fina’l Reading, Date 12-19-89 [~VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Approved Ray [3 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. I COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON THOMAS, SR CRAWFORD NATHANSON WILSON JARVIS RAY WINTER KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent Secretary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar RECORD N.V Present, not voting Date I AYE NAY N.V. [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICEVOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent [] ROLL CALLVOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N,V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMNCLARKE MASON CRAWPORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMItH, JR X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
