<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-9" flag="true">
  <num type="law">8-9</num>
  <heading type="short">Fiduciary Investment Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-06-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-9.pdf">D.C. Law 8-9</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 3361</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0140">
      <narrative>Law 8-9, the “Fiduciary Investment Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-140, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 4, 1989, and April 18, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 27, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-25 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwik’tag 103 201 522 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-9 "Fiduciary Investment Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-140 on first and second readings, April 4, 1989, and April 18, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 27, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-25, published in the May 12, 1989, edition of the D.C. Re~_ister Vol. 36 page 3361) and transmitted to Congress on May 2, 1989 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-9, effective June 16 1989 ,I ~t i~v~i\ I DAVID ~C’LARKE ’ Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30 a_y__Co_n~g._r__essional Review Period: May 2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,31 June 1,2,5,6,7,8,9,12,13,14,15 AN ACT Enrolled OrtgtneL Codification, District of Columbia Code (1989 Supp B,C. ACT 8 5 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APR 7 ’!989 To amend title 21 of the District of Columbia Code to authorize a fiduciary, acting pursuant to a trust instrument that directs or authorizes investment in obligations of the government of the United States, to invest in the obligations through an investment company registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940, when the portfolio of the investment company is limited to obligations of the government of the United States or repurchase agreements collateralized by obligations of the government of the United States. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Fiduciary Investment Act of 1989" Sec. 2. Title 21 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) By amending the table of contents for the title by striking the phrase "Uniform Fiduciaries Act Sections 21-1701 to 21-1712 and inserting the phrase "General Fiduciary Relations Sections 21-1701 to 21-1721 in its place b) By amending the table of contents for Chapter 17 by I) Striking in the Chapter heading the phrase "Uniform Fiduciaries Act" and inserting the phrase "General Fiduciary Relations" in its place 2) Adding after the Chapter heading the phrase "Subchapter I. Uniform Fiduciaries Act and (3) Adding at the end of the table of contents "Subchapter II. General Provisions c’) By amending section 21-1712, by striking the word "chapter" and inserting the word "subchapter" in its place; and (d) By adding a new section 21-1721 to read as follows: Section 21-1712 New, Section 21-1721 C 0 c I) 0i 0 EUrolled Original Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia istrict ~f ColumbiaAPPROVED: April 27, 19~ 3 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted First Reading, 4-4-89 Approved 8-140 [] VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. Recorded vote on request Absent: Jarvis and Kane [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V, A.B, COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent ’ IERTI,FICATION RECORD I Secretary to the Council ~ltem on Consent Calendar ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, N.V Present, not voting Date 4-18-89 [~VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Ray ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB CHMN CLARKE CRAW ORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote and Wilson COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V, i Present, not voting ONRECORD Secretary to the Counc’ l Item on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT tCOUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVlS KANE LIGHTFOOT AYE NAY N.V. A.B. t X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANS.ON RAY ROLARK SMIT.H, JR. A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not votin@ CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
