<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1131.06</num>
  <heading>Appointment and duties of Chief Financial Officer.</heading>
  <text>The Department shall have a Chief Financial Officer (“Department CFO”), who shall be appointed by the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia (“District’s CFO”) in collaboration with the Director. The Department CFO shall:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Be qualified by experience and training to carry out accounting, budgeting, and financial management functions;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Directly report to, be ultimately responsible to, and be under the supervisory direction of the District’s CFO, through the Director;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Engage in the accounting, budgeting, and financial management functions authorized by the District’s CFO;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Serve as a member of the Department’s management team;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Advocate for and advance the policy objectives of the Director, to the extent consistent with the Department CFO’s ultimate responsibility to and supervisory control by the District’s CFO; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Be subject to evaluation, discipline, and transfer by the District’s CFO, in collaboration with the Director.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-56" type="History" path="§106">Dec. 18, 2001, D.C. Law 14-56, § 106, 48 DCR 7674</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 106 of Mental Health Service Delivery Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-144, October 23, 2001,  48 DCR 9947).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 6 of Department of Mental Health Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-101, July 23, 2001,  48 DCR 7123).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 6 of Department of Mental Health Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-55, May 2, 2001,  48 DCR 4390).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 6 of Department of Mental Health Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-51">D.C. Law 14-51</cite>, October 30, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 10807).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
