<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1141.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Behavioral health” means a person’s overall social, emotional, and psychological well-being and development.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Behavioral health services” means stand-alone and co-occurring, integrated treatment services for substance abuse and mental health disorders that are designed to promote a person’s behavioral health.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Comprehensive Psychiatric Emergency Program” or “CPEP” means a 24-hour/7-days a week program providing emergency psychiatric evaluation and stabilization.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the Department of Behavioral Health.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Director” means the Director of the Department of Behavioral Health.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Recovery” means a process of change through which individuals improve their health and wellness, live a self-directed life, and strive to reach their full potential.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Recovery support services” means substance abuse treatment, care coordination, and community-based support that promote recovery.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Substance abuse” means a pattern of pathological use of a drug or alcohol that causes impairment in social or occupational functioning or produces physiological dependency evidenced by physical tolerance or physical symptoms when the drug or alcohol is not used.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History" path="§5112">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5112, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) DHS MOU for substance abuse treatment, see § 5132 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5112 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) DHS MOU for substance abuse treatment, see § 5132 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5112 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 5132 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that for fiscal year 2014, the Department of Human Services (“DHS”) shall enter into a Memorandum of Understanding of up to $2.5 million with the Department of Behavioral Health (“DBH”) for a substance abuse treatment program for Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (“TANF”) clients. DHS shall work with DBH, other agencies, and community-based experts as necessary to establish an integrated system of care for TANF beneficiaries living with barriers, including mental health disorders, alcohol and substance abuse, and HIV/AIDS. DHS shall present the integrated system of care plan to the Committee on Human Services no later than December 1, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 5131 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle L of Title V of the act may be cited as the “Department of Human Services Memorandum of Understanding Authority for Substance Abuse Treatment Act of 2013”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 5111 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle J of Title V of the act may be cited as the “Department of Behavioral Health Establishment Act of 2013”.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
