<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-176</num>
  <heading>Certain ordinances of Board of Health legalized — Force and effect; exemptions from enforcement; alternative sanctions; adjudication of infractions.</heading>
  <text>Except as provided in <cite path="§7-175">§ 7-175</cite>, the ordinances of the late Board of Health of the District of Columbia, as legalized by §§ <cite path="§7-174">7-174</cite> and <cite path="§7-175">7-175</cite>, are hereby declared to have the same force and effect within the District of Columbia as if enacted by Congress in the 1st instance, and the powers and duties imposed upon the late Board of Health, in and by the said ordinances, are hereby conferred upon the Director of the Department of Human Services of said District, and all prosecutions for violations of said ordinances and regulations shall be in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the name of the said District; provided, that said regulations shall not be enforced against industries established on Aug. 7, 1894, which are not a nuisance in fact. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infractions of the late Board of Health of the District of Columbia, as legalized by §§ <cite path="§7-174">7-174</cite> and <cite path="§7-175">7-175</cite>, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of those sections, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infraction shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 53-2-ch232" path="">Aug. 7, 1894, 28 Stat. 257, ch. 232</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Apr. 1, 1942, 56 Stat. 190, ch. 207, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 1, 1950, 64 Stat. 393, ch. 513, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-60" type="History">July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-42" type="History">Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-42, § 478, 32 DCR 4450</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Office of Director of Public Health abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§7-101">§ 7-101</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-113.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-112.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
