<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>51-108</num>
  <heading>Payment of benefits and refunds.</heading>
  <text>Moneys shall be requisitioned from the District of Columbia account in the Unemployment Trust Fund solely for the payment of benefits and refunds as provided under §§ <cite path="§51-104">51-104</cite>(i) and <cite path="§51-101">51-101</cite>(2)(E)(iv) in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Director. The Director shall from time to time requisition from the Unemployment Trust Fund such amounts not exceeding the amounts standing to the District of Columbia’s account therein as the Director deems necessary for the payment of benefits and refunds for a reasonable future period. Upon receipt of the amount requisitioned, the Director shall deposit it in the benefit account of the District Unemployment Fund in the Treasury of the United States as a special deposit to be used solely to pay the benefits and refunds provided in this subchapter. All payments of benefits shall be made by checks drawn by the Director, or the Director’s duly authorized agent, shall be made through the employment offices designated by the Director, and shall be subject to a post, but not a prior, audit by the Office of the Inspector General.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 28, 1935, 49 Stat. 950, ch. 794, § 9</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">renumbered § 8, June 4, 1943, 57 Stat. 114, ch. 117, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-15" type="History">Sept. 24, 1993, D.C. Law 10-15, § 206, 40 DCR 5420</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§51-101">51-101</cite>, § <cite path="§51-114">51-114</cite>, and § <cite path="§51-116">51-116</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 46-109.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 46-308.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 113 of District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Comprehensive Improvements Temporary Amendment Act of 1992 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 9-260">D.C. Law 9-260</cite>, March 27, 1993, law notification  40 DCR 2330).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
