<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>51-117</num>
  <heading>Records and reports; inspection; penalties for violation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Every employing unit, whether or not liable to pay contributions under § <cite path="§51-103">51-103</cite>, shall keep such true and accurate work records with respect to all individuals employed by it as the Director may prescribe. Such records shall be open to inspection by the Director and shall be subject to being copied by the Director or the Director’s authorized representative at any reasonable time and as often as may be necessary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director may require from any employing unit any sworn or unsworn reports in connection with its business, covering employment, employees, wages, earnings, unemployment and related matters, as the Director deems necessary to the effective administration of this subchapter. Except as hereinbefore provided in § <cite path="§51-113">51-113</cite>(f), information thus obtained may not be divulged. Any person who violates any provision of this section or § <cite path="§51-113">51-113</cite>(f) shall be fined not less than $20 nor more than $200 or imprisoned not longer than 90 days, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 28, 1935, 49 Stat. 955, ch. 794, § 18</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">renumbered § 17, June 4, 1943, 57 Stat. 122, ch. 117, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-15" type="History">Sept. 24, 1993, D.C. Law 10-15, § 215, 40 DCR 5420</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 46-118.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 46-317.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 215 of District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Comprehensive Improvements Temporary Amendment Act of 1992 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 9-260">D.C. Law 9-260</cite>, March 27, 1993, law notification  40 DCR 2330).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
