<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-128">
  <num type="law">3-128</num>
  <heading type="short">Closing of a Portion of a Public Alley in Square 5263; the Police Officers, Firefighters, and Teachers Retirement Amendments; the District of Columbia Depository Act of 1977 Amendments; and the District of Columbia Motor-Vehicle Fuel and Sales Tax Act and the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act Amendments of 1980 Act of 1980</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1981-03-04</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-128.pdf">D.C. Law 3-128</citation>
      <citation type="register">28 DCR 246</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-128, the “Closing of a Portion of a Public Alley in Square 5263; the Police Officers, Firefighters, and Teachers Retirement Amendments; the District of Columbia Depository Act of 1977 Amendments; and the District of Columbia Motor-Vehicle Fuel and Sales Tax Act and the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act Amendments of 1980 Act of 1980,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-394, which was referred to the Committee on Transportation and Environmental Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 25, 1980 and December 9, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 7, 1981, it was assigned Act No. 3-337 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>J 11 II COL"NCIL OF THE DISTRICT Of COL:.r.1SIA NOTICE D. C. Lalof 3- 128 closing of a Portion of a Pulbic &amp;gt;.J.ley in Square 5263; t he Police Officers, Firefighters and Teachers Retirement Ame nc111ent.s; t!le Dis t rict cf Col umbia Depository Act of 1977 Amendments; and the Di strict of Col~~bia Motor-Ve hicle Fuel and Sales Tax Act and the llistrict of Col umbia Sales Tax Act Amendments of 1980 Act o f l9SO Pursuant to Sec tion 4~2 of t he District of Col1.m1bia Self- Government and Gove rnmental Reorgani zat ion Ac t L. 93- 198 the Act t he Council of the Distr ict of Columbia adop ted Bill No. 3-394 o n first and second readings, November 25, 1980 and Oece:nber 9, 1980, respectively Following the signature of the Ma yo r on January 7, L98 l this legislation was a ss i gned Ac t No 3- 337 published in t h e J anuary 16, 1981 edition o f the O.C. Rea i ster Vol 28 page 246 and transmitted to Congress on January 13, 1981 f or a 30-Cay review, ir. accordance with Sect ion 602 {c l f the Act. The Council of t~e Distr ~ct o f Col bia here by g ives notice t hat t~e 30-day ~r.gress ional Revi ew Perice has ex? ired, anc erefo re, ci tes th i s enac~"ent as c. Law 3-12S, effect ive Marc~ 4, 198.l Da~es Coc~~e~ Dur~no the 3~-dav Ccr.cressiona l ~eview Pe~:cc anuacy 3, l 4 I 15 I 5 I 9 t 2 a r 211 2 2 2 3 r 2 6 t 2 7 I 2 6 2 9 I Jc 2 3 4, s, 6 I 1 I, 1 s I 1 9 I 2 0 2 3 i 4 I 2 5 16 2 7 I M.a:ch L,3 D.C. lJWI 3- 128 M:.R 4 1'281 AN AC. T D.C. ACT 3 3 3 7 l~ THE oJ~CIL J F T~E O!STA !Cr OF C0Lu~81A JAN 0 7 1981 To ordar tne c losing of tne oortion of tne east-•eSt ouol ic alley ao~ttinq lot s 36 s. 6• an~ \q in Square 5263 oo~noeo ov Oix Street N. e and 59tn Street e O 7q 39 Ravisad Ward 1 to a .nend t:ie Pol ice &amp;lt;1nq Fire~en s etire~ent and Oisaoilitv Ct and n ct fo r tml lt;ati r e ·11ent of ouol ic scnool t e&amp;lt;1cner s in t ne Oi strict o f Col umoi a to orov id• for t ne OJtiona l. vo luntary reti re~ent of oolice officars• firafignt ers ano teac~ers: to aneno tne Oi scrict Jf Columoi~ Jeoositor v tee Jf 1~77. tJ al lo w f o r cont inuat ion f or one (11 vaar of d~oosicorv contra~ts e~oiring in Fiscal vaar l qSL no t o mov e cne Jate fo r suon i ttinq soci11 criter i5 in fo rmati on from Oec~moer l to "3Y L: ano to aneno t ne Ol st rict of Columo i a ot o r·vanic l e Fue l ano Sal es Tax •Ct ano tne Dis tr ic t of Co lumoi~ Sal es Ta ct: ano for ot:'ler ouroosas 11uo l i c 1 1 ev I n :ioua re 5Zi&amp;gt;3: t ne 00 1 i c a Off i c e rs en i st r i ~t of Co l umoia ~ot ~r -van i c e F~e l ano Sa l es Ta ct Jn: cn e i str i :t of :olu~o i a Sal ~s T3~ 4Ct 1 meno~•nts ~f 4 z Se Z Tne Cou:tc i l of tna Jistri:t ot :o tu~oia finos tMilt a) A ouollc neilrinq was neld 0 n Jul y 30, l~SO oncerni nq an 3ootic3tion to close t ne oortion of tne east est ouol l c 3llev iiicii aouts lots 3 gt s b ano l~ In 5oua r e SZ6 l oounoeo ov J ix Str eet 3no 59tn Str eet e 3S sno n on 3 11ao on fil e in t,e Office of tne Sur veyor o f t~e District of :ol u inoia S. a 7~-439 Ol J,e oroooseo closino as refer reo to tne ~ational Caoital e&amp;gt; l anni:to C.om11ission for its recommendation ICJ Suoseouent to tne oubl l e ne3rinq a rev i seo olat sl~ned ov tne owners of lo ts 5 ano l as fileo in tne ~ff i :e o f t n e Survevor o f tne Jistri:t of Columoi3 re~uestl10 tne closing of tne oortio1 of tne easc est ouo l i c al l e y ni :n aouts l ots 36 s. 6 ano 1 9 Souare s2~3. oo~nje~ ov OiK Street. N.E a10 59t:t Street i t n t i t le to t ne l a ne t o rever t to t n e o ters of lot lo (S. O. 79-4 3 9-~evi s ea Se 3 Tne Counci l of ene J i str i :t of ~o l umo i a avinq :o~sioer eo tie oroooseo closinq is Jf tne ooinion tnat the Jort l o~ of tne ouclic allev re f erreo to i n section ZCct s n~ul o c2 cl Jsea. Sec 4 arsu~nt to sect i on l of The Stredt Jort io, of tne Public alley 35 sno•n on the Pl3t filed in t n e Jffi:e of tne Su rvey o r of tne Oistrict of Columo i a O. 79-~39-Revisedl is ordered close itn t i t le to tn~ land mediately after tne effective date of t n is !Ct• t ne Sur ve yor of t ne Oi str ict of Co1umo i3 sn3 ll caus a 3 ouolic notice of tnis oroer co be q i ven oy aavertise~ent ana sn al I se rve. 3 cooy of t n i s order on lcn o•n er of orooertv abuttinc t ne puoli: 3llev to ba cl osaa in accoraance •itn t ne o rJcaour es s~t fortl'I in section r of Tne Straet ~e30j ustnent 4ct of tne District of :01u~o ia aoor Jv eo Sec. b f no oo jec t ion is ~ace in wr itinq oy a nv 03rtv incer e steo i tn in t nir t v 30 &amp;gt; aavs arter tne se rvi:e of t ne or:er re ferr? o to in sect ion 5· tne su rv eyor of t na vis trict of Col~~oi3 sn3 11 reco ro in n is Of fi:e !I coov of t nis oroer 3na tne aoorooriate olat or ol3ts T,e Se&amp;lt; ratarv to tne :o~nci l of tne Distr i ct of olumoia snail transnit tr ue and ~cc 4rste eoa ie~ of tni s 3Ct• uoon its a f fective aa te• to tne av~r o f t ne Dis trict 'ie 9 c:r:rr c i o.c Ce sec. 4-52!:l 2ffect.ive lctooer z. lQ80 Ct 3- 254; 27 OCR 442l is cne Poli:e Officers anc c1refiqnters Retirement Emer~encv •ct of ioeo. wni:n ever occurs first Sec 9 Section 3(e) of ~n Act cor tne recirenent. o~ ouolic-s:nool ce3cners in tne ~istri:t of :olumola. 300roved AU OUSt 7 19 ~6 (bO St3t· 876: o.c. coce s2c. 31-723 3S ~mended ov secti on 5 of tne se:urities Act •mendnent.s Personnel ACt Clarlfic3tlon. and Vol~ntarv R2tiremenc Act of l980 a f fect iv2 Jctooer 2. 1~80 (A:t 3 254; 27 OCR 4422 is 3menceJ ov stri~i n~ t ne on ra se "or t~e d3te of exoir3tion of tne re ~cners voluntary ~et i renent Eneroency Act of 19d0 n i c~ever ~c:urs fi~ St Sec t ion c) of tne Ois tri:t of Columoia 3-32: J CJd sec 1 z1 31 c1) is 3mencec 3S fo1 lo s al P3r 3Qraon Z l i s 3mendeJ av eel et i nq tne gt;nrase o~ 13ter t~an Oe:enoer L. 1977 nless an earlier Jate is cnree 1; 1 ve:rs tner?afte r 3n:l inserc i nq cne onrase n 3 Y D.C.c:xie, sec. 31-72: D.C.Code, sec. 47-27: i 4 5 t n reo f Dl P3raQraoh (2) is amen::le::I oY oeletinq tne :inrase ins ertln~ tne onrase nicn snall Decome effective tne fol l o.in~ uctooer lst in I iau t~ereof cl ParaQr3oh is amenoeo oy !laainq tne fol lo inq seneen~e at tne eno tnereof to rea::I as folto s on~ra:.t.s cerminat lna orior to Octooer l 1991 nav oe e•ten::ieo for :ierioas no t to exce•o one (ll ye!lr •it nout comoetit i on Tha ct ent ielaa an •ct To orov ioa for a tax is A ta• of ll cents oer ~allon on all motor-ve~ icle olso:ise~ of ov an imoortar or ~s~r or useo oy tnen In a notor-v icl e oo e r!ltea fo r n 1re Jr For commerc i !l l i. o.c.c ce sec. 47- l.9v anner n a re i 13fter orovioea cne race of ta~ imoosea oy t n is se::tion is incre3s eo t o 13 cants oar oallon taK 3s c J ntainaO in tne f i rst oara r3pn of tn is sec t i on l st Jf s.icn ye3r ano s h all Da ~eterminea in tna e" is ti no on Aoril lStn nul t iol iao Dy ona olus t ne for t ne first calan03r vear inmeO i 3te l v precedinq T~e c~nsu ~er ori c! inoe c rafar r ea to in tha or ec:ain sen ten::e sna11 oa tne annual 3verac;a •asni n~t:&amp;gt;n gt 311 li:ems ons.imer orice ino21 f or a ll uro3 1 o ns umars as ouo li s ne a ov tn~ 3ure3u o f La,or &amp;gt t .s c ic s of cne s Oeo3r t me n c :if L3C:&amp;gt;r 7 suo~ it to t~e Cou~c il of tna ~istri c:.t of :olumoia a new motor-venicle fuel ~xc:.ise tax rate 35 c31culatea in s ucsect ion fa) 3cove to ca aoolied oeqinninq on the followin~ June 1st: P~OVIOEi tnan five c~nts (S~l oer qallon tne lowest sa l ~s ta~2s i noosao on ftotor fuel s in tne s urrounaino ju r isdic t ions of ~ontqomer y County ano County• v i r~;nia. aoove siall t3Ke effect on June 1st of eac:.n year unlass th&amp;lt;i C:ounc:.il. after OJC.lic nearinO• srH!l does not anacc oiffarent race for cne year o r ior •a 11 orocaeos of t~e taces i maosea unaer sections 2 L reoistration ano ti t linq of 11otor venicles lnc.luoin::i fees cn3rded for tne issuance of per~ics to ooer3ta of tne Oi strict of columoia 3S estaolisned ov tne ~e~eiue ~unos •v3ilaoilitv ct of 1975 effectiv e riot.e lo I Sect ion 2(cJ of sue ct co c ode se lt;.7 inoorter" In tn e last sentence dnd lnser t inq oetween tne (c) Section 2 of such .Act t'l Code• sec lt;.7-1.~0Zl is amenJeo ov ajoi n d new suo s ection at t n e enc tnereof co I( l imoort:r or olstrioutor Mo sells use s or otnerwise oc.io Col Sect i on 31a1 of s ucn Act co c. cooe sec lt;.7- insertino in lieu thereof the ri~ure "S 50 00v e l 'ne f i rst sencenca of s ec. t ion 3fc of s~c ct cc c o~e se lt 7- l903 c J J i s amen::e'l to re3o 35 f;,l l o 5 o.c.c.ooe. sec 4i -l9C o.c.e:x:e, sec. 4i 19C D .c .Coc:ie, sec. 47-l9C i:&amp;gt C.c.:x:e i-190 b ii '1 I l 1 9 "If 3ny imoort e r f3ils refuses. or ne~lect.s to rlle tne ov tnis Ct• t ne ~ayor sn31 1 oro~oclv notify tne i11oorcer 3na t~e :iondinq eo.,p3ny oy notiee se:it oy reqistarl!d mail or ov certified mail co sucn imoorter reauirinq nim t o snow 3.,se ny t.ne 1 i ense s:,oul a not oe revol&amp;lt;eo {f) Section 6 of such Act gt Coae. see 7-l 'IO!&amp;gt;I is an::t &amp;lt;1ddinci 3 ne suosection 101 co raaa as follo s: ot.,er•ise oisooses of 11otor-ven l el e fual in the ·Ji strict not oeen oaio ne snall oe l i ao l e for cne tax oenal ies ano Interest on sucn "Otor-veni::le fuel 35 orovideo for in tnis Ac Q) Section 7 of sucn ACt l C:ioe sec 7-l907) is I •or e ro ~use t n I Section ll of sucl'I •ct 10 c oae. sec lt;.7-l'Hll i s Se llla nv oerson reo.1ired to file a re turn t nr s ~c no snal I f3i 1 or ,eJ l ect to fi I e sucn rit.1rn o.c.o:ce sec. 47- 19 o exe, sec 7-1 o.c.c::r;e, se&amp;lt 47-l &amp;lt reouiree snail uoon conviction tnereof oe fine~ not nore tnan s1.ooo or imorisoneo fJr not more tnan six (bl Th e oenaltv oroviaeo herein sna ll Je in aooition to tne 0) Any person reouireo tJ file a return or reJort or to perform anv act under tne orovisions of tn is ~Ct no willfully fails or refuses to file s ucn return or reoort or to oerform Suen act i tnin tne t ime reouirea snal\ uoon conviction tnereof, oe f ineo ,ot nore tnan 5 000 or imorisoneo fJr not more tnan one (ll vear, Jr ootn Tne oenaltv orJvioed nerein snail oe in aoaiti on tJ tne ot,er oenal ties Jrovioeo fJr in t nis II t c or tne our ooses of t, i s section cne tern 'c erscn a l so in~ luoes any off i c!r of a ;oroorat i on an~ anv emolJvee of a co rooracion resoJnsiole for tne oerfor~ance of any ace unoer tn is •ct; any memoer of a oar e r sni o or assoc i at i on, ana ~ny emoloyee of a oerfor~anc~ of any ace unaer tnis &amp;amp;ct til c o110. i no sect ion 19 Jf s~c ct co .c ooe se o.c.c ce. sec. 47-1916 1 4 l t "Sec 1~ 1 3 1 rne ~ayor snai l de termine rejetermine• as5ess or reasse ss 3nv tax imoosed unoer t n t ne &amp;lt;:3Se of a fraucul en t on~n l v reoo~t or f3 il ure t o file a montnly raoort• tne t3x I Z I [f tne t a x as imoos e o oy t ni s Act i s a~eer~ ine~ t o oe aue from any oerson ot ne r tnan a licensee unoer tn i s Act su:n tax mav oe ~s ses sea at any ti-:1e 3) t n t ne case of 3n incorrect reoor t ne t~x s na il o e 3ssesseo or re asses sed w i tni five C5) If a r~oorc re~uiraa ov tn i s •ct i s not f il!O or if cne reoort wne1 flleo is Incorrect or in s u fficien t or i f e tax a s imooseo ov cn i s •ct n as o een ~ecermined co oe cue f ro 3 licensee or 3nv ocn er oerson tne a~ounc of tax oue sna il oe sna i l oe ~iven co c ne l i c ?nse~ or to an v oe r s on Suen oet~r inat ion snail finally ana ir revocaolv fix tne ,1 I J t I I 1; I ,1 I r :1 I l 2 assasseo it nin tnirtY C30J oavs after t,e oivin:&amp;gt; of such c:eter-.i nation, snal 1 :iool v to tne ilvor for- a naarinQ or unless tn2 ~ayor of n i s o-n motion sn;il 1 reoeter11i ne t ne same reaeternination t,e 3vor s,all Qive noti;e of nis t3x is assesseo O J Any li censee or oener oer son reQuireo to fi l e 3 r e oort a notor oay tne tax no tails to file sucn fails to p;iy t,e t~x to tne Ois tri:t ot co1u~ola witnin tne time reauireo by tnis acc. s,;ill be suo jec t to ;i or fraction tnaraof ourin q nic sucn f;ii lure continues (1 l/2J ,er :ent um of sucn tax f&amp;gt; r eacn nont n or fr3ceion t,ereof aur i nQ n r cn su:n failure continues t3 AC t• Tn a :ienalty ano interest prov i oec for In this oef i: I ency c) oav aole a Perso~al oeot of t na Jerson 1 iaole co oay t ne same t o tna Di~trict of :olumoia For tne ourooses of tnis suosection. tne ter oe~soi also incluaas any offi:er of a corooration. and 3ny ~moloyee of 3 corooration resoons lole for ene oavment of tne tax: any ~enoer of a oartiersnio er associae ion and any emcloye~ cf 3 o•rtnarsni~ or •ssoc i at ioi r esoon s iole for tne Se 2·J The taxes imoosed oy ei is Act ano ~aver in tie manner orovioeo ov lil for tne collect ion 1 i~ns for tne taxes imooseo oy tiis Act •no ce nalties ano interest t ereon ii" oe acJu i reo i .i tne sa- manner tl"l'!t I iei s fJr oe,.sonal :i,.oo~rtv ~ilxes a,.e acc..1irec. tf tne avo oel iaves t:iat the col 1 !Ct ion of anv tax o.c.e cs. sec. 47-l.S oa1i1q suci tax nas exo ir e a i~med ia tely assess sucn t ax toCl tner i t tl all interest :in:i oenalti es. tne Suen tax ie~ano s~all be ~ade Dy tne ~ayor for tne gt;ayment tt'I er 110 f. tJoon f ail ure or refus:il to cay s ucn t!IX Se Zl nere :inv tax nas Deen erroneously or o.c.exe, illeoally collacted oy t ne District tne tax snail oe sec. 47- 1916 J refunoea if aoo l ic3tion unoer :iatn is fileo itn ~ne Suen aoo licat l~n must De maoe ov tne 3ctu3ll y :iaid tna t3K. s 311 :ie m;iae. tie ay::ir sn3ll qiv&amp;lt;1 noci:e c nereof t o tn11 30 gt;I ic3nt l5 "S.e zz. Anv oers:in aaarievea ov a fin a l aetermin3tion of t3x or ova 02nial of a claim for o.c.eo::e, sec. 47-1916 refund itner than 3 refund of tax f inally aater~ineo in section lq of tnis •ct av ~itl"lin six montns from cn2 aace of 3ssess~a nt of t l"l e aefi iencv or fr o tne Oate of tl"la oeni al of a cl ai 11 for refuno• aooeal t:i tne Suoer i:i r Court of ti"le Di stri t of :otumoia in tne sa~e ~anner ano t:i tne sa~e extent 3s set rtn in $act ions 3 an of title rx of tne Oistrict of Columoia ~evenue ~ct :if l~37 aoorovea ~av l6• 1938 (52 Stat. 371: o.c. Coaa se:s 7-Z~03 &amp;amp 7-z~o~&amp;gt; as amenoea se 23. All ~otor-venicle fu~ls founo in anv o.c sec. 47-19l6 olace in t ne Oistrict of Columoi3 at sucn time ano unaer su:n cir umstances t na t t ne taxes l eviQO a~o ino:isaa ov ~Ct• s nal 1 oe aeclar~o contraoano ~ooas ana oe forfeitea sucn motor-v el"licle fuels wnerev er tney are founo gt re~s :in to suscect ~n3t any venicle i s :ar r~ i nq m~t~r 1 of any orovision of t ~is Act• tne notor-veni:le fuel ana Cc I resoonsi~le in any court f~r t~e seizure or tne 'onfiscation of any Tiotor-venicle fuel or veni:les wnicn are se i zeo or :onfiscate~ unjer tne or3vislons of tnis •ct ny Tio t or-venicle fuel or venicles so seozeo snail ~e solo in tne same nann2r as Personal prooertY se i zeo for tn e oayment of Dis t rict of CJ l Jmo i a ta~es. and tne or3ceejs of su:n sales snall oe 3eoositeo to tne creoit of tne Dist rict 3f Columoia otw i tnstandinq tne orovisio,s of thi s seccion if t,e ~ayor celieves tnat anv fail ure to comolv with t,e orovisions of cnis ct I s e x:us3~te. cne Mayor may• in nis discret i on retJr, to ve ,icles seizeo un3er tne pr3vis1ons of tn is sect i on Se lZ Section t28 of tne District of Co1Jmoia Sales re;io as follows: A u I o.c.Co:le, see. 4i-26.&amp;lt; l 7 Sec 13 rne ~avor ~av issu~ rules 3no reou la t ions not inconsistent itn tne orovisions of section ll or 12• or ootn in or o~r to orooer lv !Cmi ni ster t ne orovi s ions of Se l i If a ny oro~ i sion of sact ion 11 or iz or ootn. in:lu~in~ 3ny amenoment ~aoe ov section 11 or 12, or ircumstance i s nelo invalia t~e r~mainaer of tne orov lsions of secc ion ll or 12 ir oocn. i~c lua i nq tne :ir:iv l s i on to o tner cersons or :irc~ms:ances snall ~ot :ie :iotn anv oro isi:&amp;gt;n of la sn3ll ,ct affect anv !Ct o:&amp;gt;r iefore t,e a ff~ctive oata :if sec~i:in 11 or 12• or ootn or iate of secti on 11 or 12 ir o:t o~t a ll s cn riqnts ano o:Je 128 o r tne J is trict o.c.o:.c.e. se 47-lSlE o.c.o:ce. se 4 i-l.~nE l -l eel Al l o f fen se s co~m itte o ano a ll o an a lti es inc Jrre o orior t a t ~e e ff~c t i ve 03 ta o f s ~C t i Jn ll or 12• o r oo tn oros acut i O ana Pun i s neo in t ne same •ann er and ~itn the same a ffe c t a s i f saction ll or 1 2 or Oo tn nao not oeen eriacte o. Tni s ac t s n a i l t a k e effect a f t e r a t n i r t y 30) 3av oe riJd of :ono r ess ional r ev i ew f J l lo~ in9 aoo rova l J y t ne J rov ioeo i n s ect i on b02( Cl!ll of t~e Oi stri ct of Co lu mo 1 3 aoorovac Oec amJe r 2 iq13 &amp;lt;87 Stat e 13; o CJOe sac l- l 7 c lJ J APPROVED: January 7 a fE e: a: U t t t iii:'l l.1.;c.'lC cc s 3- 394 .toe':1C Acoctec Fi=st Reacing 11-25- RQ il VClC veu 0 1'1 ll n~im=o u::s all present iJ ;ct i t \T'Tt'\~ I I I I ir_ I I I C 1(1\. r-n•J I I t I l I I gt SO~ I I I ClJ &amp;gt;I I 1"'11 I I I 3.Q~ I I I r I C l I I I 1"\• I I I t 1 r I I I I I I 1 orr-c I I I n v I I I I I I I I I A~octed Fi~al Readinq,Cons Calendar, 12-9-80 t§ 'IOICZ CT o n;;411=im=o u s ilu c C~l~a~r k;;e I f I I I I I I J v \ I I I I a r I I I I I v I I IC ,J.t"T tr I I I I l :7 I Y f\CO I I I I C I I I I o v I I I I I I I I I I I I T C I I I I 1 I I I •I I I I I i .IC::CY CJ ·ic JC 1 I f u r </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
