<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-131">
  <num type="law">3-131</num>
  <heading type="short">Rental Housing Act of 1980</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1981-03-04</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-131.pdf">D.C. Law 3-131</citation>
      <citation type="register">28 DCR 326</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-131, the “Rental Housing Act of 1980,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-321, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first and second readings on November 12, 1980, November 25, 1980, and December 9, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 7, 1981, it was assigned Act No. 3-340 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> co1JNcr o ur!tuan o Sec-t gt;n 2 o: t he n st c~ of C::li b a 5el Go?ecn en~ and Gcvecru:1ental ~eccqanization Ac 93 198 the Ac~n, th~ Council of the Distric~ of Cclumbia adop':ed 3ill Ne 3-321 on !i:st, a~ended f irst and s ec::inc read i ngs ove~be 1, 1980, Novembe: 25, 1980 and ~ece~cer 9 l 99C s iec v e this l eg i sla tion was ass i;ned Act Ne 3- 340 bl ~shed i he Jan~ary 23, 1981 edition o! the D.C. Recister ol 28 page -3 26 and transmi tteQ. t o Congcess on Janua c;r 13 1 1981 foe a 30 lav rev iew, in-.acco.c-dance with Sec tion 602 (cl of t::e ~e Council of t he Oi s ricc o! C::ilt.:r.tbia :ie eby g i'les r.otice thac t~e 30-day ccngcessional Review ?eciod ha~ e~p i =ec A lP.INGTON O: XCN Chair:nan o! t ee ccuncil ~ates Coun-:ed Duri na &amp;lt;:he 30-dav Conaressional Revi ew Perice January 13,14, 15,16 19 ,20, 21 ,42,23,25,27 ,29, 29,3C ?eb.c-ua 2,3 5,6 17, lS,19, 20,23,24,25,2 6 2 7 March 2, 3 0.C. L;W 3 3 1 0.C. ACT 3 3 O IN T~E CJUNCI L OF THE OIST T a oLu~B!A JAN o 7 em To orov i ~e ra l oc3~ i o n 3ss i s:3nc~st3o il i ze re s i :ent ial r e n ts, pro v i e ev i :ti on c ont rols an~ for Jtner ~urposes Se l Ol r i noin~s Sec l OZ ur~oses )ec. 103 efinitions Se 201 Aool i: i on of Rental Ac onmoc3t i ons Com~ is s ion Se 20 2 Es ta ol i snmen t o f ~in ta l ~ousin onmi ss ion uel ific3t i o n s; Comoe~sat ion Remova l Se 203 Ju t ies of t ne ~ental Mous i nq Comm i ssion Sa 20 4 ental Acc ommooac i ons J ffi e ec 2~5 J u t i es o f ~an: A:~in s trat o r Se 2 amp eo i stration a no Cove r 3ce Sec 2 0'7 e lt Ce i l inQ Set 208 l.O ;ust:nents in t nQ Rl'nt ei l in;i SeC 2::1'1 u3l i ficat ions for Increases A OO"e t~e Basa ~ent z Se 210 e"lt Ce; I lq U;:io:i Te~m i n3t i O:'I f;:i r 'lewl y-Coverea Ran t 3l Jn• ts Se 211 a:&amp;gt;i cal tmor gt;vemencs Se 212 Ser vi ce s ano F3c ilities Se 213 arosnio Peti t ion Se 21 4 va:ant •ccommooat ions Se 215 5u:&amp;gt;stantial Rena oil i ca~ i on Sec• 216 voluntary Aqreement Se 211 amp;d just11ent Procedu re Se 21s Jud i cial Rev iew Sec 219 e e::ly Sec 220 Secu r i ty Oeoosit ~e 301 Definitions Se 302 i:s tao l isnmen t 1f lt;antal Suoolement Pro~r:tm Se 303 El io ioi I icy Sec. 304 ental Supplement jrants Sec 305 AO'Tlinistrati::»n Sec 30c Co"ltinue::I El iqibi 1 i tv Se 307 Termination of El iqioH i tv Se 3 0 B. Tax Exemotion TITLE Iv REvENJE Se 4 0 1 Annu:il Rental Uni t i=ee T&amp;lt;TLE v v1cr1 JNS ANO ~ETALIATJ~Y ~CTION Se 50 1 Evic t i::»ns Sec soz et.al i atorv Act i 1n Se 601 o"lvers lon of 3 ~ousi n ac::o'Tlm:&amp;gt;o3tion Sec 602 gt;e 'Tlo 1 i t i on of a ~ous in J •c co:nmooat ion TITLE VI I i.ELO:&amp;amp;rI JN SSIST•~CE FO~ TENA~TS OISOL &amp;amp;C~O B1 SUB~T•'ITlAL ~E ~AaILI TaTI ON OEMOLl TICN OR ~OJSIN lSC~NT!~U AN :E Se 71Jl loti:e of ~i~nt to Rel~c:itiO"l Sec 71JZ e l i ai o i 1 i ty ite::iu i remllnts fo r &amp;lt lt 1 oc lt ion Assistance Se 703 elo:ati::1n Ass i st a "lca ~a yments Se 70 elocat i on AC!vis~ry Servicas 3 Se 7J5 7g~ant H~c Line Se a Am~n~ments to ~ent3 l "ousin~ Con~~rs i o~ 3n~ Sala Ac t of 1 980 Se 302 m~n:ment t o tne Confirm3t ion ~ct ~f 197 3 TITLE !x lSCELLA~EuUS Se 9 l Penalties Sei 902 4. t torn~y Fees Sec 1 03 Severao i 1 i ty Sec 904 Suoers2c:ure Se 905 gt;ervic2 Se 906 ffe: t ive Oate Se 90i Termi n3tion TIT E t Tn oun:il of tne Distr i ct gt;f C gt;lumoi3 fi~as (a) T'lere is 3 severe snort3qe gt;f r~neal nousino avail3ola to citizens of tne Oiserict of :o tumt&amp;gt;ia orimarily conaominiuTIS• tha ~ithdr3w3l of nousinq units fr gt;m tne housing mar~et. aetarioration of axisti~q housing u~its• 3nd tha lack of jeveloomant gt;f naw or renaoil itatej no~sin~ units c) r~e snort~G• of housinq is felt most (di Sue~ lo and moa~r3ta-incone renters are finainq 3 snrinking oool of 3v3ilaola nousing ax:essiva gt;ercantage of their in:ones el C3sas of rental costs excaeoinq fifty gt;ercant (50~J of a tan3nt•s qross in:one are not (3~.0001 ranter no~sanolos ware re gt;oreaa to nave Ti 7 cc:rr!O..T D Co:ie, sec 5-:601 -5 f tie i r q ross i nc:omi!S on ren~ i i l9 77 nvers i n of re.·u il gt;ro:ierty to Othilr uses "i 11 (Q I;ncroved oroc:eoures wit n tr.a Re'1ta1 ac In ena:tinq this ac:t t:ia Coun:ll Jf tne serl:t of ColumOia suc:iorts tne following To orot!C:t lo ano znoottra:t- i l'\c:o.11e c:e~ants from ne erosion of tnelr in:one fron ~mcraaseo nousinq :osts: canstr uc:ti":Jn of rent31 units 3nd tne (C:l To imorova :na acnlnistr3tive mac:~inery for tna resolution of :isovtts a no c:on~ro~trsias c.c.c c.e e 4.S €02 llOusin fr:im c:in ·1ersion to otner uses; 3nC (e) T:&amp;gt; oravent tl"le erosion of m:&amp;gt;oar3i:;aly crr i caC! rental nousin:;i wtiile orovidin::i l3nclorcs 3nd develooers witn a reasonable rat if rat~rn on c.neir investnents. For tne gt;ur~:isas of tnis a:t. tne term ll "A:&amp;gt;artnent Inprove~ent Program" neans t~ e Jr:&amp;gt;ara nicn is aoministerea ~icn grant f~nas fr:im t i tle I of tne ~ousing and :onm~nity Develoomant ~ct of 1974• aoproved ~u::iust 22. 1974 (83 Stat 33; 42 u. s sec. 5301) oy i:;ne Jistri;t of :olumoia Daoartment gt;f H:&amp;gt;usinq and :o nmunity )eveloomant. developad oy t~e cn e ~ati:inal Neiohoorhood ~einvestnent corooration Act. aJproved Jcto:ier 31. 1978 2 Stat 211S; 42 J.s sec 81Jl&amp;gt and ooerateC! unoer tne suoervision of tne ouol i:-orivata ,artnersniJ onm i ttee. wn i n oroqram tias oeen estaol i s eo for tne ouro:ise Jf findinq s:ilutions to tne ec:inomic ana ohysica l distress of moderate in:one rant31 l D.C.cede, sec. 45 603 7- ranc1 oro otano i o r ano t~a ~is~ r i:t of :oluno ia =overnnent in a :ol l active eff ort 2 oase r ent means tna t rent le;al1y ri:irqe in r-2oruary i. 1973• ano al 1 rent inc r eases au t~or izao fo r tne t rental unit oy orior rent c:&amp;gt;ntr:il la s :ir any administra: i va dec i sion issu ao tner e~noer. o r any r e nt i ncreases autnori zae Cy a :ourt of c omcetenc j~r1 sdi:t ion 3t "Buildi nq morov ement Plan" neans the Jiscri t of Colu~o i a qovernme n t• at 3 orooerty oeinq c rea t ej un er tna •oartmen t I mo rovemant or qr a nicn aqreenenc se ts fo r tn tna r eme~ies t o cne orooerty s istress incluoinq cue not 1 i mi te:3 to l A scnadula of repa irs a~o caoit~l cna orooart y i~to suostantial c onp1 ian:e witn J A s:r.aoula of serv i :es ~n :3 fa i 1 i i ~s 9- i) i &amp;gt;tr i :t of :ol umoi a qover"lment until i t exJires Joon cJmoletion of a l l p'1ysic3l in:luoed t nerein 41 c:ioi tal imorovement" m&amp;lt;?ans an imJrovemen t Jr renovation other tnan oroinary r eoa ir reolacement or naintenance: PP -JVIOEO rnat SJC, imorovement i~ oee~eo ~eoreciaole unaer (51 "Council" means tne Council of tne of tne Oist rict of Columoia Self-Government :ind 2 1973 7 Stat 7 85; J Cod e Sl!C l-141 f6 oormit:&amp;gt;ry" means any structure or gt;uiloi,Q o• ned ov an institution of ni~ner eoucdtio~ o r priva~e ooaroinq scnoJl, in nicn at leas t ninetv- five Jercen t (95 of tne uni ts are sucn institu~ion of ni~ner education o r orivai:e ooaroino s:nool tct l 11 ;ilue o f l 1 e"lc umorances on t.,e ncus ing structu r e or ilding I n the District of Cclumoia contaiilnq o~e (ll or mo re rental un i ts ano t ne accomm:&amp;gt;aatio s nail not inc Juce any n c te l or in n .c i th ii cert ifi a te of oc u:&amp;gt;a:icy 9 Housing Regulations N 11eans tne most recent edition of the ~ousin e~ulations cf cne LL L955 lJ J "init i al le a sinq oerioo" 11ean1&amp;gt; tnat For un it s oes:ribea in rents su:n rental ~n i t i~medi ate lv afc~r tne oate it is first gt;ffereo for rent as a re.,tal unit nicn is net otner~ is e e~e~ot fro m t nis act 11 interest p a y~ents" means t ne amount cf in terest oai o cur in~ a reccrt ino oer lo o en a Ct 10 ort~a e er jeec of trust on a nousi,o ac 011mod3t ion 121 landlord eans an O• ner l essor suol assor assiqnea any aqent t n ereo f or a :i y ot~er oerson r eceiving or entitled to rec e ive r ents or benefits fo r tne use or occ 1oancy of any r e'1tal uiit •ithin a nousin~ accom11o::iat i on i ni11 tne Oiitr i ct of olumo i a ll nana~enen t fe e e ans t he amoun t i i t o 3 na na~ino a~ent ano any oro rata sal a r i es of of f site a~mini strative oersonnel oaid ov tne l a:ial ore1: P~O~IOEJ Tnat tne duties of su:n oerson1el are co:inected wi tn t he o oeration of the no us in ac:onmooat i on l4l maxim..1m oossi ol a rent31 i come" means t ha su'l'I of t'le rents for all renta l 1n i ts in t gt;e "o~sin~ ac:o11mod at i on wnetn er occupi e d or noc twelve (l2 J :on seCJtive nontns witn i n t ne fiftaen rLSl moncns oreceoin~ tne ~ate of anv fil i10 rea..1 i red o r oermitteo un~er tnis act 15 3yor" me3ns tne Office of t~e ~3yor of t n e O i~tr i ct o f :olumo i a as asc ao l is ie~ unoe r $ect io 21 of tne Distric t of Col~moi 3 sel f ll cl7} "operatinq exoenses" means tn e exoenses reouir ?d for ~ne OJerat i o n of a nou s ing acco~mJoa~ion for th e twelve !12) cJn se=u eive th~ date o f its usa in any comou ta~ iJn requi reo oy anv o r ovision of ~nis ac t. incluoinq out not 1 imicej to exo~nses fo r salaries of o~-site reJairs. utilitiiS orofassional f'?es• on-site 18 ot~er income wnicn is oeri.ea from tne tnan r?nts• whicn a landlord earn s oacause of nis =r ner o .nersnip of a no usi n~ ac~o1\J11oa a~ion. in=l~dino Jut not l i~ite~ to fQes onmlssions in=one fro~ ¥endin g nacnines in=o~e fro~ l aunarY r ecr eat i Jn a 1 f ;ac i l it i es 12- inaivi1uals. 3no tneir resoective su:cessors 3:ia ass i :inees 20 oroperty taxes- neans tne 3mount levjej ~Y tne District of Columoia qovernnent for real ~roperty t3X on a no~sinq ac:onmo~3tion aurinq a ta~ ve~r 121 relate-:l f3cjli:y" 11eans anv fa::i. lity. tenant or 3 landlora the use of wni:n is autnorizeo oy tne oavment of tne rent cnargea for 3 rental u:'lit. inclu:ii;q any use of a oe:itcnen. oatn. la.1n::irv fa::ilitY c.r1&amp;lt;inq fa::ilitv r ene onmon use of anr conmon roo11. y~ra. or otner onmon area. orovioeo bv a lanolord• reauireo by 13• or oy tne terms of a r~ntal aqreement. to oe orovioea oy a lanolorcr to a tenant in connection ~itn tne use ana oc::uoancy of 3 rental unit• in:lJCinq reoairs L3- i31'l i tori 31 s ;i:-v i :e s or tha re'llo 1 Jf i:ras:i :inc refuse je'llandaa re:eived. or c~arged ov 3 landlorc as a :onoitio~ of o:cuoancy or use of 3 r =ncal unit i ts r elatec:I servic;is no its related facilitl2s in or :onoutac:I ul'loar sec~ion 201 25 ental Accomnoda tions •ct of 1975 means t na Rel'\tal A:comno::Sation Ac t of 1975 affect ive ovenoar l 1975 co. c a~ l-33; o.c. Coa e. sec 5- lb3t es s 27 re~ta l uni t" means a l'ly oart of a nousin~ acconmoaacion a s aaf ineo in se:ti on t03(el i:n i s rante~ o r offarad for rant for res i del'ltial aoartman roon• sinqle- f3'llily nouse ano t~ e land 30ourt~nant tnarato su i te of rooms. or auol;ix 14 29 su:istanc i al re"laoi 1 i ta ti :in" ne3ns 3nY imorovamant to or renovation of 3 noJsinq acco~mocacio, for wnicn: ca} t,e OJiloin; oermit as qranted on or after Feoruarv l• 1973; and I renovation eQuals or exceeds fifty percent (SOZ) of t"1e assessed value of tne housing accomnooation oefore sucn renaoil itation. of wnich violates the Housinq ~equlations• or any otner statute or regu lation re lative to tne condition of resident ial ore~ises anj nay enoanqer or materially imoair tne naaltn ana s3fety of any (3J tenant" includes a tanant suote anc lessee suolessee. or otner oerson e,titleo to c,e ooss2ssion oc:uoa,CY• or th2 oenefits t,ereof of (3 11 un:oll2cteo rent• neans tne amount of rent ana otn2r cnarg2s due for at le ast thirty tine any statenEnt• form. or pe"titioi is fi1?a oursuant to tnis act 15 lo a "o unt sn31 1 ce i :\cluoeo cnerein for uni ts :ic u o i eo gt;y 3 l a n o lo r d o r :iis or em~ l oyees or otner i se n;;it of f ered f;;ir rent TITL E II ~istri :t of Columoia Rental Acconmod3tions o .itm i s si on as estao1isned Under seetion lOl(a) of ~ct of 1~7 7 is aool isneo 0) Inoiviau~ls s e rvi on the ~enta1 tnis 3:t s n al 1 remain in off i ce un t il t n e .11e::1oers ~f t,e Rental Ho us in~ Conmissio~ are au l y sworn in:o ofPica al o.c .c:c sac 45- 1 1 c Cc rec l.5 16 ansenc of Council. tna first nenoers of t,e ~encal 1ousin~ co~mission cnin t,irtv (301 oays of the effective oata of t.his act oer of tne ~enta l Housing Comnission as tne cr&amp;lt;ai roarsori bl Tne ~encal Housinq :o~mission snail oe onposao of t i CZJ inoivi::lu:tls 3onittao co or:tcci::e befo ra cna Oistri: t of Columoia Court of ~p oeals. and one (l) accountant• All me111bers of th ental Housino Comn•ssion snall oe residents of t,e Oiscricc of Columoia o mamoer shall oe aicnar a lan t lor::I or a tenant Cl Eacn nencer of tna ~ental Hous inq Conmission s~all r:ceive annual :ompansation oavaole i n r:qular installments at c,e rate of conpensation eauivalent to tnac receiv:o Dy an :moloy:e comoensaced at a raaa 14 of cne· Jistri::t. Scne~ule establ isn:o unoar Title XI of tne Oistri:t of :o lumoia Government :onpre ,ensive Merit ~erson."lel Act of 1~7 8 effecci~e January l iqao Law 2-13q; J Coae sac. l-341.l l 17 O) Tne ay:&amp;gt;r s i all remove any :ie11oer of c.ne ~enc.al iusiio C:imnissi on ~no fails t o main 1in n e lua1ific a iois of :i ~e'flo er or i:i fa il s eo scne:ula enta 1 Housinq Commission- neat inq s ~el i th i n any tnree (3 mcnth perio al Tne Rene.a l Housing onmissi::in snall t issua• ameno ano rescin: rules ano (2) deci de acpeals brougnt t:&amp;gt; it from 2ecis i ins of t :ie Rant AClli ni strator i ·icludinq aooeal s ~noer ne ~enta1 Accomnoaac i:in s ~cc :if (3) cerc i fy ano cuo1 ish •ic.nin thirt.y (3 ~1 o~ys 3fter cne effect i ve oac.e of tn i s act and irior to Mare n l o f each year cher3afeer tne annua l a:i jus me.ic :if c;eneral a ool i :a:&amp;gt;i 1 i Cy in ne re"I&amp;lt c: i linq for a r!!nt.a l unie u11oer secti:in 207(0 t:&amp;gt C L I The ~eital ~cusinq Comni ssion na~ nola 1 18- 3~teno3nce anc tastinonv of itnes ses and tne nenoranoa. pacers and documents as tne ~eital ~ousinq Commission may dee~ aovisaole in carryinq out its functions under tnis act 21 In t ne case of contuna:v or refus~l to ooey a suopoe,a issue~ unjer oara~r apn (1) ov ousiness wi tnin tna Jistrict Of :olumbia. tna Suoerior Court of tne Jistrict o f Columoia at tne ~ritten reouast of tne Rental ~ousinq Commission. sh311 issue an order reouirinq tne contumacious :onmi ssion• to projute evi~enca if sJ oroereo or to Qive testimony toucning uoon tne nacter unaer inou iry ny failure of c ne person to ooey any or~er of tne Super ior :curt of tne District of :olumoia mav oe ounisned ov that court as contamot t nereof cl Uoo, tne •rit ten reouest of tne :nairo~rson of tne Rental ~ous ino onmission eacn jeJartnent or ~ntitv of tne District of Colu~oia oo ~ernnent may fur~isn airectly to t,e Rental 19 inform3~ion. 3S ~av oe nec :ss3ry f r ~ne Kent31 (a) Tnere is continueo as an agen:y of the ~nicn s nall nave as its nead a R:nt o~ini strator to be ao~ointeo ov tne Mayor bl Tne Rent o:ni ni stra t or snal 1 cossess ex::ierien~e of a tecnnical nature in lanolord- tenant affairs or in a fielo Girectl1 relateo tneret snall be a resident Of t ne Jistric~ of :olumoia a~o snall oe entitled t~ r e :eive annual conpensation (oav3ole in reqular installments) at tn e rate of ~race 15 of tne ~istr i:t S:neaule estaol isneo unoer title XI of the Oistrict of :olumoia G~vernmenc :onorenensiv er i t Personnel ~ct of 197 3. effect ive January l 1930 co Law ot al ne Rant ~on ini scracor snal I iraft ru le s f t~ i s act r C.~C2, sec. 45-l.6"-4 U~C.c=c.e sec. 43- 1015 i zo o oa rans~i~tea co tne Rantal ~ousinq conmission for its action purs u ant to sacti:&amp;gt;n .2'.l3(a l Cb) T'le Rent ~oninistrator shall arry out ic::ordi nq tO rul as ano procedures estaol i sneo ov th ental Housinq Com~ission unoer se:tion Z03(a)Cll• tne rent Stabil iZation gt;roqram esca~lisneo under title II and snail oerform sucn otner juties as ~ar be nacessary. ao:&amp;gt;rooriate. ano o'ls i s t e'lt i t n the gt;rovisions of en s act c) Tne Rant ~dni n istrator or n i s or ner gt;esi~nee snall have jurisdiction over tnose onplaints and petitions arisinq under titles II• v. VI. ano VII wnic:n may be disposed of throuqn aonin i strative oroceeoinqs Ol Tne Rent ~011i n i strator snal 1 gt;rop:ise an an nual buoqet ano re::o•meno sucn Staff as ~ill enable t'le Office 3na the Rental Housinq :onmissi:in to arry out tneir respective autno rities unoer orovisions of tnis a::t e)Cll Tne ~ent Aoministrator may e•oloY ith sucn funos as may oe availa~le to cne Rene inc l uoino nearino ~xaminers and le;al ounsel, as to c3rry out e provisi)ns 3C t Adn inis t ra cor nay ~eleqa te autnor i t y t tnose emol oyees aooointed in conformity ~i t n garaqraah l l Su :h a~t.nority may include ut is not l imi t e::ito LI hearing acminist r3 t ive Oe titions file or i ni iet.ec unoer t ni s :c l i ss..Ji ng oec ision s on s uc n Jetitions and 3 I renaerinq final Jrde rs on any oetition heard by sucn emoloyae f rne ~en t Aoministrator s nal 1 a ss i st and orovioe staff s uooor t to t ne Renta l ~o using :oTim is si:&amp;gt;n Col rne ~ent Admi n istrator or nis or ner tesi:inee snail a::t en:s all 111e:.t.in is of the ent.3 1 ~ousi n o~mi s sion no shall ~a~e availabl e t o ar rv )ut effe t i vely t hei r :iut ies u~ae r t~is 3Ct lhl(l 22- 3oninistar oat~s no reouire av SJoaoena or a~ner~ise the attenoan=e and test i no ny of =orras~onden:e• nenoranda. paoars. ano ooc~mants as tne Ren t 4dninistracor nay jeem necessary in carrviiq out his o r ner functions ~noer tnis act 2) In tne case of cant u na:y or refusal any oersan ~no resioes i s fauno ar transacts ausiness ~itn in the District Of Columoiao the Suoerior Court of the Oistri :t of Colu~oia. at tne ritten request af t ne Rent oninistrator snail issue to sucn contumacious cerson an oroer r~ouirin~ su:n o~rson to aooear oefore tne Rent aninist rator. ta oraauce evidence if so ordarao• or ta tive testinony touchinq uoan tne matter un::ier in::tuiry nv failure af sucn aerson to ooev a nv orjer of tne Suoerior Court af tne Oiscrict of tnereof IJ Uaon tne ritten request af tne Rent ~onin i strator eac ieoa rtnent or antit v of tne Jistri:t of :olunOia gov ernment nay furnisn E r r 23 il Tne lane ·o.&amp;lt;H1inis raeor shall ouolisn in the effectiva oate of this a:t a boo~l~t or otner such writtan m3teria1 oescrioing tne rignes ano niis material snall oe cistrioueeo tnrouqn tne District of ColulllOia 1 iorarias ano other District of Columoia offices in wnicn t ne publlc ~as frec~ent con t act nicn reouasts to oistriauee sucn ~aceriaT k) Tl'le ~ant Ad iii ni si:.rator snal 1 :iuol i s11 of tnis 3Ct 3nd orior to 3rtn l of aath yaar "etroool it3n Scatistic31 Are:i (S'IS~i ur inq ene oracadinQ cale~d:ir year i o o.c occ, se lt;;S-~5:.5 24- unit i ena Jistrict of Columbia e~caot l l an y rental unit in any feoeral l y- o r nousinq acco11mooation with rasoect t hicn tne nort i a ie or re~t is federally gt;r District- suo si di ze d ex:eot units suosi~ized 'ursuant t:&amp;gt; t i t la c:r 21 3ny rent3l unit in a:iv nawly- constructed nousin::i accommodation for hiCl'l tn·e ouildinq oerni t 35 issued after O~camoer 3l• 1975 ir any rental Jnit in a nousin ac co 11m,d tion for nic h t h e initia l :ertificate o f Jc: u gt;a ~cv for nousin use #35 is5ueo after January l l9BJ RJVIOEO OWEVER· Tnat tnis exemotion ;n3ll 'l ot aooly to any housinq acc::1m11ocati:&amp;gt;n• tne constr uction of hicn reouired tne d em:&amp;gt;l ition of 3n y no~ sinq acco11mooat io:i suoject to tnis act. Jnless t,e n~moer :if newly-c:&amp;gt;nstru;teo rental Jnits exceed s tne ,u11oer of denol isheo rental Jn i ts is ithin cne s3ma structure or not Al such nousing 3cconmodation is owne: ov not more tnan four (4) natu~al persons; CB l none ~f sucn owners nas an interest eit,er directly or indire:tly. in any :itnet re.ital u:iit in the District of Columoi3; 3no {C) tne owner(s) of suc:i nousin oninistr3cor a clain of e~enptior. statement wnicn s:'lall o,·sist of an oatn or affir:nacion ov sucn tn3 si:na:uras of 33cn oerson n3~i 3n interest nousin: 3cconmoa3tion or cnanga in tne o~ner•s interest in any otner nousinq acconmooation "nicn reoortac in •rit inG to tne Rent ~cninistrator lt iny nousin icco .nmoo3tio .1 nicn nas re1tal a:raenent since January i. 1930 2b e~ulations hen offered for rent 5) any rental unit ooeratel ov a foreign oersonnel l housing accommodations for hicn a (Al Tne 6uildinq Imorovemen t Plan cco~o3niej ova Certif i cation si Q,el ov t~e te,ants of seventy percent (70 tJ of the occuoied uni t s is fi lel 4 itn tne Office 3t t~e time of CBI uoon exoiracion of cne auiloinq tmorovement ?lan tna exemotion oroviaea pursuant to t~ is oa r 3qraPn sn3ll terminate anJ sucn nousinq acco~modation ill aqain be suoJect to sections 20~{0) tnrouqh 220: ana (Cl Ucon axoiration of tne ~uilainq Cmorovament ~lan ano notw itnstanain~ tne o r ovisio,s of se:tion 210 tne s:hea~la or rent :ellin~s services and facili t ies estaollsnea ov -27 t:.a.:ilis'1e: for tn: ourposes of ti~l; rr. Col ?rior t o cna execution of a laase or r.r,r.c:reases for the ac.c.ommodation are Ct regul i!tea ir tne Rant StiloiliZiltion °rogra11 C Tnis act sna11 not ap:)lY to t~e followin; {ll any rental unit in iln estaolisnment iin:luainq, cut n::i lim iteo -i i. nospitals ar-e homes; CZl anv :crmitorv 31 follo~in~ a determination cy t~e 26 es s t~3, tne gt;3ymen t oy tne landl:&amp;gt;r~ for ~aeratin~ costs interest oaynents Tna landlord =naritaole c:iroorat i:&amp;gt;n tnat ooaratas tne un it as a12rt of 3 co11prene."\sive social ser i:es o r o9r3:n f a r su:n f ;im i 1 ies di it~in ninety (qQ) days of th e affective o t exe iteo b y t his act a nc not reqiscereo unoe r the ~ent.;il H::iusinq Act of 1977• sn a ll file witn tn e ~e,t Administrator on a forn 3p::irovea bY tne for ea:n nousinq a:comnoaation in tne )istr ic t of :olu~Oi3 f gt;r w~i:n ne or sne is re:eivinq rent or is entitled to receive rent Any gt;er s::in wno oe cones a l3"10lord of such a r e n t 31 unit after tne effective ~ate of tnis act snall h~ve thi r tv (301 ~a ys Rit~ in ~nicn to file 3 registr3ti gt;n statement The re~ist r at i on form s~all c::intain out not oe 1 i mit aa to 11 for eacn 3ccom:nooati gt;n reou irinq a ,unoe r s if t n at nous i nq ousi ness license 3no the -29 er::ific3t2s of oc:~pancy ~nara re:uirac ~Y l aw• i~suad cv tna District of Columoie ~overnnent 2) for eacn acc:im':looa::i:&amp;gt;n not ra iuire:l to oot3 i 3 nous in; ousiness 1 icanSe• tne informat i on :entaine~ cnerein an:l tl'la ~ate ana nuuoer of tna certifica::es of oc:uoancy issued by tne Cistrict of Colu~bia qovarnment• and a copy of (31 cne oase rent for each rent.al unit in cne a:comno:lacion• the relate: services in:luaed. anj tl'le related facil itias ana cnarges tl'larefor 4) the nunbar of oedroo11s in the nousin::i acco111noaaeion 51 3 1 i st of any outsta.,ain viol at ions of tne HousinQ Raqulations aop! i aola to Suen ac:onmooaeion or an affi:iavit Oy cne ouild i nq owner or manaqar tnat there are no kno•n oucstaidinq v i olations; and l tna rate oF return for ene nousi"9 ac:ommooaeio, anj the :onputations maca oy tne 13,alord t~ 3rrive at suen rata of r:tJrn oy aool ie3tio f t~e for~ula provide~ in section 213 J o 30- suo1ec t to req is tration under tnis a:t w i~nin t n i rtv (301 13ys of any i!vent nic:i :n3nqe~ or fa: i 1 i c: i es r 1: ne o n e r sh i p or 11 an a qe ne n t of any re,t al unit in 3 reqisc:erea housin accommooation ursuant to se:tion 207(0 lt;fl Eacn re:iistrac:ion statenent fileo unaer c:nis section snall oa ava il aole for gt;uolic insoecti on at cne Jffice ana ea:n lan::ilora sna il &amp;lt;~eo a d JCl i ate of t ne req isc:rac:i:&amp;gt;n statenenc: oosc:.20 i a ou gt;l ic pl ace on c:ne orem i s es of c:na ,ousin:i acconmoaac:ion to wn i:n SJC:"l re~istrati gt;n stac:ament ao:&amp;gt;lies: PROvIOEO rnat eac n lanalora tay lieu o f oostinq i n eacn ,ousin:i ac:o11moaatio onp r ise of a s inqla rent al un it na i l t gt; ea:n tenant of sucn nousln q ac:o11mocation a cuol icata of tne r~g istrat ion statami!nt lt;cl Eac, reqistration statene,c: fileo unoer t ni s section wni :n ~eets tne minimJm reouire11e n c:s -31- oe assiq.,ed 3 re::ist~ation numoer hi Eac certificate of o:cuc;an::y ano e;ic ousin ousi.,ess 1 icense issuej to a.,y lanj l orj in tna Oistri::t of Columoia after t.,e effac:ive aate of tnis act snall ontain the re:;istration numoer :er:i fic3te or 1 icsnse aool i as. Se 2'J7 n t e i 1 i no I al e~cao: to t ne extant orovia:c in suosacti ons (OJ and (CJ• no lano1ord of .anv rental unit suojec t to tnis act may cnarga or collect r~nt for sucn rental unit in e~cass of tne a~ount .all re increases a~:norizej after Seotemoer 30• 1960 for tna rental unit oy tni; act. oy orior rent control 13ws. ano any a::ministrative aecision tnereuncar. ano oy a court of co~petent jurisdic:ion. NJ enant may suolet a rental unit lanclord onmission snall ce:ar~ i ne an aaju~t~en: of ener31 :1001 ic.aoil itv in tne rent ei l in 32- astao l i sne iv subse:-t ion cal iener31 :i c:&amp;gt;l ic&amp;lt;ibi 1 i i;y sh:ill oe e:iu:i1 t:&amp;gt; t.na cnan ge '4e troc:&amp;gt;l it3n St.ati stic;il Are.:i o nsumer Pri :e Index for Jroan ~a:ie E:irners and Clerical ~orkers (CPI l f':lr A 11 I te.,s our i n :i t na orecaoi nq al en03r ve.:ir: D~OVIOED T nat no aa j ustment gt;f g eneral :iol i caoi 1 i tv snal l excee:i ten oercent 10 4 l3naloro may n:&amp;gt;i: incl e ment 3n ao j ust Tie n t of iener31 :1001 i cacil itv• or 3n adjustment oe rmitte:s )y suose:1:iOn tel for 3 rent.:il ~nit ~itnin t~elv e ClZJ m:&amp;gt;ntns of tne effective aate of a Prev ious ao just.Tient of :ieneral aool icaoi 1 i tv• or in 1 ieu tn a reof i n 3a justnent permit.t ee cv su:&amp;gt;sec t ion (c) in t ne r ant :eil i nq fo r t h 3t u n it cl At tne landloro•s eteetiO·°l in lieu of 2 13 Sucl"I 3 :i2i:ition s!"lall oe clearly ioe n t ifieo ;is an e l ect i)n i'1 lieu of the Qener al C just:nent s i!utnorizaa c v se::tion 201(0 Tne Rent -33- 3fter the gt;etiti gt;n has bee~ filea. In the case if anv Jetition filed unoar this suosacti::in as to riicn 3 final decisi::in h3S not been rendered Cy t~a ~ent Aoministrat::ir or nis ir her dasignee at the ena ~f ninety (9J) days from the d3te of fil inq t,e reaf (and as to ~hicn tne Jana lore is not in oef3ult in conplyinq wicn any infor11ation re~uest na~e uncer section Zl7(C tne rent oe condit ion31 1y inolementeo by tn~ l3nalord at the enc if sJcn ninety (90) dav oeri::io• Suen s1.1 gt;iacc to· S:JOsecuen c 11ooifiC3ti::in Cly tne fi.131 ae:ision of tne ~ent Administrator or nis or her if a near ina h3s been nelc on cna oeticion. the ~ei Jministrat::ir or n is or her oasigiee snal 1. ov orcar served uoon tne cartias at le35c cen (LO ays. nal(e a provision.ill fino i'lq as co tne ri!nt :eilin ojustne'lt j~stifi~d ov su:n orc~r. if :xceo~ to tne extent mocifiea ~erein. cne t o a n y 3 j justment Ol r f Jn tne e ffective dat e J f t is act t h e :e i lin tnat re n t snail ce reouceo t o tne allowaole re,t ceiling effec tive tne next oate 30Ti i n i str at i ve ly aJo r o veo unoe r t h e ~ent a l acco11mJ 03 tions a c t of 1 9 75 en tal Jusi n~ act of 19 77• Jr a,v rent Increase autnoriz e J J Y a cJu r t Jf CJmoetent jarisdiction. Tne Janoloro snall ,oti f y t n e tenant i n writi nq of an v Je=rease reJui reo our su ~nt to t n is act Jr ior co t ne ee l A ten;int 11ay cnallenge a re,t aojustment Je t itiJn wi tn c n e ent Aoministr atJr u noe r sect iJn 217 Tne rent ceil i, g for a parti:ul a r rental unit coTipu ted accJr~i,q t J tne orJceoure s sJecifieo i n :asoe may ce: 7 J I o eoce sec 45- 161 8 -35- {a) acc:r:inq gt; sec: i on 2:1 to al 1 o~ for tne t~&amp;gt; accoroinq t.o sect.ion 2L2 t.o allow for any i n:.re3 se or f:i ilities CJ acc gt;r:inq to any final orjer of haroshi P (dJ eccoro inq c o sect.ion 21~ 3s ne result :if (el ac:cor:inc to sec:ion 215 oecause of suosca;t.ial renaoil it:ition or (fl acc gt;.rdi ng t.o section 21!&amp;gt; oec::i;ise of :i (a)(tJ ~ot.witnsc andinq :iny oroviSion of tnis act t.~e rent for any ren t.3 1 u:'\i t snal I no t. oe increase cove t ne case ren t. unless l t ne su::is tant i al :o 110 I i :in:.e i t.n i;:ii o Js l n e:ul:iti gt;ns gt;~OVI OE Tnac. nonc::imol i3nce is not ;v icen:e o f s u:.n s.iost en t. i a l non:.011cl i ;nee sn~ ll gt;e limitaa t gt o.is in equ l ac. io_ns vi o l ation c c::ee, s 45-:E:9 -3o Toti=efs) issuao bv t~e Jistrict of :olu'l'loia Jeoartnent of ~ousin~ and CoTimunity )eve looment a.no sue~ ot:n&amp;lt;!r offers of proof as the ~ental i. t.s rulemaKi:io orocedures ill t:ne housinq acco'l'!mod3tio, is raqistereo in accoroance ~ith sectio:'l 206 1 Cl tne landlora of su::n nousi .ng ac::onmoa3tio, is orooerly l icensao OJrsuant co a statu t e or requl ations if sucn statute or nanaqer of SJcn accoTimodation wne, otner enan tne owner. is orooarly raqistere::i oursuant to tna ~ousin e~ulations if sucn requlations re~uire ;u::n raqistration; ano (El notice of SJcn in::rease cone.lies wit sections 208(0 ino ~os 21 ~nera tna ~ent Aoministr3tor finas enat t,ere nave 'ean e~cessive ana proJonqed vio1atio,s of t n a ~ousinq ~equlations affecting tna nealtn safety ana security of the tenants or ~na naoitaoi I ity oF tne nousinq ac::onmooation in ~hicn such tenants resioe and that tne lanaloro ,as failao t~ corrl!Ct su~n violations. tne ~ant ~o" i strator 11av rol 1 1&amp;gt;;1ck tne re ri t. s for t he ~f fe ct:eo ran ta I un i ts. to 3'1 alflou:it i en S'1a1 l not -37- oe i ass cr.3n tne ;eoru3ry l 1~73, 03Sa ren~ f gt;r su=n rencal units unt.il su:n ime as 't,e viola ions have oeen aoaceo O l nous inq accomilooati gt;n a no e3cn of t ~e ren"ta l units 't n~re in sna ll oe deemeo to oe in suostant.ial onpl lan:e wl n t he ~ousin e~u lat.ions ll if for ourooses of cha aojustnen'ts na:e i i tne ren ceil inQ i n set.t ion s 2J7 a nc z 311 s u gt; Stan'ti;;il i 1acions citec 3t tne tine of c~e las't ins gt;e:"tion of ene nousing accom~ooation ov ene Deoar tment of Housinq ano Comnunlty jevelo:imenc orior t o cne effective o~ce o f 'tne increase ere aoa"tao ~itnin a forcv-f i ve S J oav gt;erioa f:illo inq c ,e issuance of 't ne cit3'tio,(SJ or t nac tine Gran ec Oy tne Oeoarc"enc of ~ous;nq ~no Conmuni ty De eloomer.t ano t1e Oeo arcmant of ~o~sin~ 3nd :onm~ni'ty Oevelooment nas =ercifi e a t na 30d't?ment or t na owner or e e 2n3n as :Qr'tifiea en? 30atamant and nas Jr?san~e= Rv ioanc~ Tn:tt n:i tertific3 io~ of aoa'tenent snal 1 estiol i sn conpl i;in:;e itri tha Ou5in:;i lt;eQul3ti~n un1? 5S 'tna -38 21 if. for purposes of tna fili~g of ~etiti ~ns for ao justTie nt s in t ne rant :eil ing as ~ras:ri bad in section 217 tne nousing n~ve o a~ n inspa&amp;lt;:tej at t ne reouest of aa:n l anolo ro oy tne De,artment of ~ousin~ and :o~munlty Develoomant ~it~in tne tni rty &amp;lt;30) oays i111ne .J i 3te l y gt;r;ecaoi n cha fi li nq of a gt;etition for ao i ust nent CJ tanant gt;f a housing acc:&amp;gt;mnodation wno after receipt of n:&amp;gt; less t~an five (5) d ays ritten no ti:e tnat tna landlord oasires an insoection of t~e tenant s rental ~nit f:&amp;gt;r tne ouroosa gt;f caternining wnethe r tne h:&amp;gt;using acconm:&amp;gt;datio, is in suostantial co11p1 iance witn gt;f tne Oeo3rtment gt;f Housinq a no Comnunity 9evelo:&amp;gt;men t for tne gt;urpose of insoect inq tne tenant's rental unit. or wno refusas witnou t qooo cause to acmit or to cause to oe aomi ~ceo the r.-ii:'ltlt t.o c lal 1 ~nqe t:ie val i oi tv gt;f tn~ prooosea m i a~ r:iy sucn tan.ant is n:&amp;gt;t irt su:istantlal (Gl ~othinq in tnis sectiort shall oe c:&amp;gt;nstrueo 1 imit or aorc~ate a tanant'S rignt to i,itiat e ocwit:istaiding any otner or:&amp;gt;vision of cf'T'·iiS' a:t. no rent snal 1 o~ a juste:i Jnoer tni s ac:t ;s;t::ao1 i sninq t,e rent for sucn rental .Jni1 for t'"le eer.-m o f sucn written lease or rerttal a~re~nent f) tn iod :e of an iajuse~~nt :iurs"arit t:i r uir:o ~v &amp;gt;e:tioi 206(:1 a statement of t ne .L°t:.iil i-eies :01o1 re:1 :iv t:ie rant nic:n jusei fv tne tncra.:1se. Tha ioc.i e s;ial l al so in: l JOe a sunmary of tena n t ri qnts u~oer t n is act ano a 1 ist :if s:&amp;gt;urcas of te:hnical assi stance as out&amp;gt;l i sned in (q o aojustments in rent under ti•s act nay oe i~olenented unlass and until a full one hundred ao just Tienc al Excapt as proviaed in s ubse:ti on (cJ, tne reit caili q for any rental unit i:i a nous i n acconmooatiO;i exemo teo l&amp;gt;Y sect ion 20 exceoc. s u osact i:&amp;gt;n (3 2 u gt;oi t n e exoi r ac.i)n or termi n:ic. ion of suc:-i exemot i on shall gt;e t ne avera:;e rent cnarqed ouri n tne last S i x l consecu t i ve Tiont:is o f tne exemotion increased t&amp;gt;y no more tn:in ~u ri no c.ie l 3sc. si x (b) consecut i ve nont ns of t n e exemoti on Tna incraase may be effe:ted only i n &amp;gt;e i ons 2 ·J9(QJ :in as I J D.C.:ctle, sec. 45 1620 -41 gt;J structure or ouil:ing, in:iuOin lana aoourtenant t.nereto n icn is 1~C3t3: in tne re!'ltal units as definea an section l:l3(2bl is est3c1isne~ 3fter the affective date of tnis 3ct• sh311 ~e tnereafter detinea as a "nousing a~:onmoc3tiO!'l" for tne purooses of tnis act amp any rent.al u!'lit in s~cn a nousinq ac:onmocation •s not otnerwis~ axamotad oy one {ll of t!le orovisions of se:t.ion 206. tne rant :eil in; for tna initial leasin; oeriod or the first year of tenancy ni:never is snorter. snail oe cetermir.ed of m3kin~ the :onp~t3tions soecifiad in se:tion 207(3 Cl Tne rent :eilin~s for any rental unit ?xoiracion or termination of tne exenotion snal l oe tne r:nt :ailinq on tne d3t.3 the ~nit came ex~mot plus aa:n s~ose~uent acjustnent of nera\ acolicaoil itv autnoriz:a under section 207(01• O.C.CX.e, sec 4:-2621 gt;2 over c ne :osc of :ao i ta l i~o rovamancs to 3 rent al J ni t or nousin~ ac:onmooation: PRJVIDED Tnat Ill Tne inorovenent wo ulc protect or ania~ca tne nealth• s3fetY ano se:urity of t he tenants or tne nao i tabil itv of tne housing ac commodat ion; or { 21 Tne i norove·nent wi 11 affe:-c a nat savinq i the use of e ne rgy by tne nousinq ac co11modat1 0 1 or is inteno ad to conpl y i tn aoolicaole environnental orotectio1 regulations ROVIOEO inat any savinqs in ener~y costs are oassed on t o t ne tenants bJ in 1 :inolora sn:11l est ao l i sn to tna s a tis fact i on of tna ~en t ministrator Ill Tnat ;u:n inprovenent woula ca aeemaa jeoreciaole unjer the Internal RavenJe Coca 26 J. s. c. 1 2) Tne anount of tne cos t of Suen imorovemant exclusive of interest ana service ch:iroes ind 3 J Tna t reauiraa qover1m antal oermits 3nj :ioorov :ils nave oeen securea aa lus~ nent of tne r ent ce il ing lJ In the ase of a ouildinq io a na jor seventy-two (7ZJ month per iod o f anortizat ion ano units in ~ne nousino accommodation: Tnat n:&amp;gt; increase undar t ni s s uosect i gt;n may exc:eo ce i l in:i 2 1 r the ase of l i mitej imorov ements t o one (ll or ~ore rental un it s i n a housing eion t 43 month oar i oo of anortization ano Dy Oi v ioi,q t ni s r e su l t by the nu ~oer o f rent al units rece i v in tne imorovement: P'l.:Jvro~o rriat no oercent (l 5 J aoova tne c ur rent r ent cei 1 q. Tne or gt;t ac ce:i Ol gt;1 an s con tr acts scec i ficati o, s ano :ierm i t&amp;gt; r el ati iq t gt; s u::h caoi a l i ncrove;ien t:s z t stl"9'11 ie ra tainej for ine (ll year y tna lanolorc is~ nis or ne r oesi :tndted :iqen t f::ir S .Jcn i nspec t i::in oy;a f fected t enant s as sucn tena,ts nay r eouest at t~ la,alor d s place of ousines s t n a Oistrict gt;.ff C:&amp;gt;L.a m:ii;i ourinq ondng nours If c.ne landlord not nave a i l ace :i f business in tne Oi str ice Jff C gt;lumoia tne plans cont r acts s::ie:if i cat i:&amp;gt;ns o e rm i t s rel at inq t gt; tne caoital im:&amp;gt;r:&amp;gt;vamants sn·aJ 1 gt;e maoe av iii 1 aol e upo n raauest by tne ~f~ectea tanancs at tna Rental A:c:&amp;gt;m no j ati gt;ns J.fif·i c e I e l l je: I s i :m o y t n e Rent A am i n i s tr at:&amp;gt; r on ii r~nt a~ j ustm a nt oursuant t:&amp;gt; this section snail be r~,aerao •itnin si~tv (60) oav s after receiot of a :o:~pl ete "etitio'1 for Caoi t31 I mor:&amp;gt; vam ant fl •nv tenant disolac e d fron a re,tal u n it oy t ·tta ca gt;ital i mor:&amp;gt;vamen t of tne unit gt;r tne n::iusinq a~~o~m:&amp;gt;dat ioi under this section s,all nave a r.-i qnt t o r2-rent t le renta l un it i11m!!diatelv uoon t~e co~ol et i:&amp;gt;n of tne work q) Tn~ lanalo r o may mal&amp;lt;e eaoi tal mcr:ivements to1 tne oro:&amp;gt;er tv '31 i or to tne a ocro v.i l :if tne rent 3d j ustnent ov t n e ~e,t Adm l n i stra~:ir f:&amp;gt;r 5Jc~ c:·aoi ta l im:&amp;gt;r gt;vemants here sue~ ca:ii tal (nl A landlord may aajust tne ren~ ce i l inq for :a::iital imo r ovements wnich are reQuire:l oy :ir::ivis ion s of any feaeral or local stacute or requlatton Decominq •ffective on or after ~ovenoer i m:irovaments• ana the cost of such iTicrove~ents itnin tne h~usinq accom~oa~ti~n wnj;n benefit from $ucn im:ir:&amp;gt;vement by filing wit, t ne gt;ff ice a :ertificate of Calculation for Man aatea Ca~ital lmorov eman t I ncr ease l) rnat sv~n i~proveTient is reoui reo OY the :irovisioris of a fe:ieral or- local statute or reoulation cecominq effective after ~ove~oer l 19~0 ZJ Tne anount of t~e cost :if $ucn (3) T.iat reouirad qovernmental gt;er.nits ani~istra~or for aooroval of the r e 1t aajustment suJse&amp;lt t i in j i f sue oetiti:&amp;gt;n i&amp;gt; filed tn t:ne ~ent Ajministrat:&amp;gt;r wit: nin ten {l~l calanaar ~ays fr:im tne installation of sucn caoital imorovemants. If the servic s or relat:ed facilities s11o::ilie:1 Oya lanalora for a housinQ accom.nodation or for anv rental unit therei n are suostant:ially i ncreasea or decraasej. tne ~ant aninistrator ~ay increase or services or facilities a) wnere an election nas oae1 naje cursuant to s~ct i :in 2)7(c) to see~ a ren t 3d jJStment tnrouq, a narosnio oetition. tne Rent ~dninlstrator snal 1. after revie if tne fig~res an:i conout:~tions set forth in the lanalorc•s as woula qener3ta no m:ire than a t en oercent (1 0 gt gt C c0 3ec 45 52 D.C.C:x:e, sec 45- 1623 ~ate af recurn comcute~ ac:oreinc ~o sucse i on (bl O) Ii je:ermining :ne rate of re:urn for twelve ClZJ nontns wit.nin fifteen (L5) months orecadin tha filing of a oetition uioer tnis act. snal 1 oe useo co: C!l ootain tne net income oy suotractins fr m t.'1e S.Jm of :iaxl ·num oossiole r .a1H.al inCo.ne •nicn :an oe aeriveo fro~ a nousin; accommooaeion end tne na~imu~ amount·of all oener income wnich :an oe derived fron the nousing ac:o~mooation tne fol i owi n Al tne ooeratiiq e~Pense PRJvrO!O. Tnat tne followinq itens snail not oe al lo~e~ as ooeracing exoenses ll memaersnio fees in orqanizations est.aol isneo to infl.Jence 1e;ii;1ation. and r-equl.ac.ions 2) contritlutions to loooviic efforts: fees in c.na orosecution of class a:tion cases; C~l oolici:al contriouo:ions to c=inaioetes for office 5) nort:;ac ori.,cioal Oay.nent.s gt;} m,ai.,ten:ince 8 ettl ement 1uoo11ent for oamages ac;reao u'JO J3vmentS or any ot~er metno 71 a t t'Jr nev s fees l it i~ation relataa to actions orou;nt ov tne ~istrict of :olumD ia government :lue to tne landloro s reoeate failure to comol v itn aoJ l icao le Housino ~ea~lations as 2v iaance~ oy -ioJsin~ an:J :onmun ity )eveloJm!!nt; a ia l~l an y exoe"'lses for w,i:n tne tenant nas t a~ful Iv caio lirectly S) tne manaqament fee wner e ene a c i nu11 rental i ,come of t'"le nous i ,c; ac:onmoa ;ltion .1nless an aaaitional ano.Jn t •s 3ooroveo ov tne ~ent Aoministrator as follo s: nav reauire iiclu:l i:'l Q• out not 1 i11i:e:i to tne nane o f tne oavee: oaseo on tne oetition and sucn otne r infornation 49 C) prooerty taxes Dt oeprec i ation ~xoe1sas to tna assess':l lt S: {El vacancy losses for the nousin~ ac:o~modatio1 of no nore tnan six oercent (64) of the ma~inu• reital housinq income of tne housing acco~modation un1 ess an additiona l anount is aoorovad bY tha aent A=m i nis:rator F l uncollec ao ran ts: ano (Gl in~arast oaymants 2) Than. o i vide t:ie nat i"lcome or the oeterm i na tna rate oF return Cl ine Rant a.d:ni :ii serator sn;il 1 :iccoro an axoeoite= review orocess for a Petition fileo .Jnoer e:-iis sect i on ana snall issue 3.,a ouelisn a oetition nas been f i leo I f t rie ;i ant r so- r enoer 3 final cacision i tni n ninat v 1q D) cays landlord i s not in default 1n 011olyin ith any information reauast nade unoer sacti:&amp;gt;n 21-1c tne rent ceil i nq aojustmene r eoueseej in tne peti t ion ~av oe c:ino itionally i 11o l e mentao bv tne l3ndloro Suen c:in:jiti:&amp;gt;na l ranr. c:e i liriq adjust.nent snail ca oe:i si:&amp;gt;n of t h a ~e1t Administrator o r n i s :ir ner jesiqnae on the :ietiti:in if a nearinq has oeen neld on the oeti ti:in. ano :iroer serv e o uoon tna oarties at laasr. ten 110) oa vs ori:&amp;gt;r t:i the ex:i i ra~i:in of suc:n ninety qO l e ilino aajust11ent justif i ed ov tna gt;etiti:in; tn a landlord m3y i11ple~ent only tne am:&amp;gt;un t of tna re nt :el l i n o ad jus tnent a utnorizeo gt;y tne oroar x:eot t:i tna ax ten~ mooifieo oy tnis suosect i on• r.na o rovi s i oi s of sect. io n 217 s rHll ao:ilv to any ad 1ustnent unoar tnis section D.C.Ccde, sec 45-1524 -st- wa:ate f~r any of tne following :aJsas l f l"!is or ner tenancy or (3) usa of tne rental llr'li t f r an i l le::ial ourposa or P·Jr;:ioses :is ete rn1i ·n~d OY a :ourr f comioe:en j:.JriSaic'tion e i l in ni en ou1 :l gt;-cnerwi s1 oe B:&amp;gt gt;l i :aol e to su:h r1nta l un i t u,der tnis act o l us tBn percent tlO thereof on:e par t elv l2l month period. or l tne rant :eiling of a suostanti ally OAJV!OEO That no in:rease unoer this sect i on snall be oermitted unless tne nousing acco nmooac ion nas oeen raqistered Jn~er se:tion 20!&amp;gt gt O o~ tne purooses of tn i s sa:tion• rental ~nits snall :ie cefined to oe "suosta,tially identi:al" wnere tney contai n essentially cne sane to:B~ i ons itn res:&amp;gt;ect to exoosure ano ne i gnt (if -52 onpar3ole pnysicat :on dition al If tha ~ent AO mi nlstr 3tor di r ine s (l) 3 rant.al unit is to be s u:&amp;gt;stan t i a l\ y rena:&amp;gt;i l it.atej; a na (2) s ucn renaoilitation os in the interest. of t he t enants of suc n Jnit 3no t ne re,aoil i t3c:ion. an Incr e ase in t.ne rent ceiling for sucn rental unit: PROVID:o Tnat sucn rent ,unore j t went y- five oercent (125 of t ne rent amp;ilin::i 3polic3ble to such rental unit prior t o su=&amp;gt;sta,t ial renaoilitation bl In oetermin i nq whetner a nousin~ Jnit i s soecificat.io,s~ anj orojecte~ costs for su:n re.'l30 i I i tat ion n i c:i snal I oe .naae ;iv 3iIa:&amp;gt;1 e c:O o cxe, sec. 45-1625 -53- re"laoil itatiof'I cf 3 ncus i n; 3c:;oT1m::io:1t.ion is i:i ~c~inistr3cor sh311 consider. 3mong otner relevant fo::tors l) th: imoact of Suen rahaoil itation on ano J tr.e :xistinq condition of th: rental unit or nousinq 3Ccom~ooation a:id tne deQre: to wnich 3ny violatio:is of the ~ousinq 'e:iulations in s~cn rent31 unic or housing accomT1ooation ~onstit.~te an imoairnent of the nealth el fare• and saf:tv of tn2 te,,a."\tS foll gt in:i: 111 any rental unit ~itn r:soect. t.o suos ta:it. i a 11 v renao i 1 i tace 2 l i!n re"ltal unit of tn i s ac Al en: landlord nas n:&amp;gt;t.ifieo ene :ino (9} ;il 1 ttH? t'i!"lancs lave 1 :ft. o .c.c:e lf sav:nty o:r:ent 7C~J of tn: cenant5 of a -5'&amp;gt for i11 rent.31 uni ts in the nousi n; 3c:ommoo3tion 3a juste o ~v 3 speci fi e o oercenta~e· the ~ent it.oni ni s-t.rator shal 1 i mneOi ati!l \I cen:i fy aoo roval gt;f tne- iicrease The aqreement sna 1 l incl uoe the ee,,ant s rental unit or apartment tne s::iecifi 3 statement that tne aqreenent wi t i the Janoloro oer:i::in on t he oart of tne lanalord of the nousino acco11modation Se 217 ca I Tne Pent 4dministrator ir nis o r ner :Jes i onee s n a il c:&amp;gt;nsi ier 3d 1u st ne nts a l 10 e:l i y sections 2l l• 21 2• 213• and 21s. or 3 cnal lenqe to 3 se::tion 207 3o jus tnent upon a ca tit ion fileo oy the landlord or te11ant Suen petitio1 snall oe filed itn tne Rant 4d11inistrator gt;n a f::irn inform.;iti oi as t1e Rent 4dmin i straeor gt;r tne •oninistracor :ir ni s or ner :lesi~ni!e s:iall issue a :le:isi::in 3n'.l an orJer aporovin~ o r oanvinq in o » 1 D.C.CXe, sec. 45- 162 55- cwanty 20) da ys after sucn pe:i: i o, i S fi lac ~icn e Rant &amp;amp;a~in i stracor• axcendao only oy writtan agree~en~ Olt~een e ianolord anc tanant of sucn rental unic O) uoon receipt of sucn cetition tne ~ent ~a~1niscracor or his or ner desi~nee snail notify cha no,-oetitionin~ oarty lanolorj or tBn anc) oy :er:if i ej ~ail or any otner form of servica •nic~ assures jel i very of sucn petition anj of t,e rig,t cf eitner oartv to makB• witnin fift:e n (15) oavs 3fcer the receipt cf sucn notice. a written reauese for a nearinq on the oetit io 1 f a ,earin: is t i mely re~uesteo cv eitner oartv• notice of cna tine anc place cf tna ,ear in: snall oe fur,ished :ne oarcies Oy te~tifiej naii or any ot,er form of service wn icn assures :el iverv ac least fifteen (15) days oefore tne comnence~ent of suc:1 nearinc t~a oar~ies of nis or ner ri~ne to r?t3in 1 1 ounse1 to raoresent ni111 or ner 3t tne 1'aar i lt;;i c) Eac~ lanoloro of anv renta l u~it •it~ rescact to w, i tn a oat i tion is fil:a or init i ate~ Jnjer t~ i s sact i on s~all suo~it to t,e ~ant -56- Aom~nistracor 1r n i s or ne r oe si~n?e i c h in f i f t?e J.5) oay s afo::er de'Tlano t:-terefor i s maoe. 3nn inf gt;rna ti gt;n state~ent on a f gt; rn ao gt;r gt;veo Oy c~e e,t Admini s trator. co,~a;ning t,e infornaci gt;n tba e,t ~dminisc rat gt;r or the Rental H gt;us i ,g :o,mi s si::1n may reouire Ol T'1e Rant Ad11i n i strat.or gt;r his o r rier 1esion?e may c::1nsol i::1ate oetitio,s a, c n eari,cs relac i,q t gt; n1nt i l un its in t 11! s ane nousi lo ac 011m gt;o :it i o e) T,e Rent ~oninistrat.or ir nis or ner le~jqnee may ith::1ut noldinq a nearin g. refuse to aa~ust t.,e r?nt :eil ing for any re,tal uni t• a nd nay l i smiss any gt;etit.i gt;n f gt;r a::1jJStm:nc. if a fiial le=isi gt;n nas oeen ma::le o n a gt;et ito gt;n filea J P::ler t~is secti gt;n. tne ~ental A:c::1m110::1ati gt;ns Act gt;f l975. or th e ~e ti!l Housinq Act of lt;;77 f::1r aatustnent as to t,e same rental u,its wit,in tn e s ii&amp;lt gt 6) 11ont,s inmeoiately prec:eaing t'le filing :if t oenoino 1et iti::1n f) All oat it i ons filea under tni s se:t i on 311 ne3rinqs nel:i relatinq t;:iereto 3n:l 31 l 30 gt;e3l~ t a~ e1 fr~m a:cis i o:is of cne ~e,t &amp;gt;.aninistrator gt;r nis or ner 1esiqn2e. sriall oe -57- c~is sectian enc i tle I of tne Ois~ri:t of !n tne :ase of anv :irect olumbia &amp;amp;oministrative Proceoure ~cc snall 1revai J qi Decisions of tne ~ent ~jminiscrator or relatinq to any oetition filed wi t i nin or ner ILrt 3oc:eel from :inv decisio&amp;lt;"I of tne rlent of tne Rent ~c11inistrator or nis or ner aesiqnee ecisiJn of :ne ~eit Acministrator or nis or ner ~esi~nee on its 0~1 initiative ine Rental o sin o.11missi::in m;iy reverse. in wncle or in oart. anv oe:ision of cne ~ent A~ministrator or 58 J::F t ni s 3c or unsuooorted JV suost3ntia1 ~i.oen:e i" the re:oro of the gt;r=&amp;gt;c?e~i '19S gt;efore i'Q: m:iv aff i rn i no 1 e gt;r in Jart tne ;tent &amp;gt;\Q.-n-inis-c rator s Jr his or ner :1esi~nee s decisior r:h e'1 t:31 Housinq CJm:niss io:1 snall i s sue a ~ecisiJn wi t n rescect to an ec gt;ee l wi t'lin t nir ty 3&amp;lt l sh3l 1 oe inple~ented unless tn? t enant =x&amp;gt;~cerne gt; n3S Deen qiven written n:&amp;gt;tice oursu3nt ~o:ninistrator gt;r his or ner oesi~nee gt;r Oy tne o~ m9iled ov certified m3il or a'1y otner f gt;rn of S c1'1 O ?C i S i 0 j) Tne ~ent Ad11i11istrator 3n:l wnere 3cc~ro ori gt;rltv to a l3ndlor:i "ards h iD cetition :o~&amp;amp;rinc 3 n:&amp;gt;usi nq :icc:&amp;gt;m~o gt; ati:&amp;gt;n f gt;r w'1icn tne 59- not oe~un ~itnin forty-five 5) c3ys imme:iately followin:l the filing of th oeeition. Pro:essing of suc"I ietition(s) snall oeqin no l:itar t lan five &amp;lt;SJ days aftar raceiot ov the ient Aoministrator feoeral aqen:y kl 'to rant i n:rease aoove i::iat au:;hori zec ov landloro a ·Jrinq the :iendenc.y of an a:&amp;gt;caal oy t:iat landlord to th• Commission or tne Oisi:rict of :olumoia C:&amp;gt;urt of •ooeals #Mere the apoeal oncerns tne val icity of tnat incraase. oenanc or re:~iva a se:urity oaoosit fro n, jQJn t"le effective Cata of tnis act• w"lere no se:uricy cac:&amp;gt;sit nao oeen oemandao or receiv cf affe:~iva oate of cnis ace eoosits for nawly c.onstruci:ao units or wnits Sac Jr i t v :i.c.cx.e, sec. 45-l£2S oo- l sndlord or t e nant may &amp;lt;:ommence a :ivil lt;:tion i n tne Su,erior Court of tne District o f :o l u m~ia t gt; e~forc&amp;amp; dnY rule or decisi:&amp;gt;n issJed Jn~er tnis 3C t Anv gt;erS:&amp;gt;n or ~ental H gt;usi"lq C:&amp;gt;m11ission or Dy 3ny failure on tne gt;art of tna ~ental H:&amp;gt;usinq C:&amp;gt;mn ission or Rent Adnini st rator to act witnin anv t i ne certain sucn aec1sion or a ;i oroe r co11oel l i"lQ SJCn aeci s i:in gt;v filin~ a :ietition f or revie~ i n tne District :if olumoia Court of •poeals TITLE III ~or t ne gt;urc:&amp;gt;ses or t nis t i tl e tne term: D. c xie I sec 4S-162S u cce, sec 5-1630 D.C.C.:Ce, sec. 45-1641 -61 l and i c30le~ oerson ne3ns 3 lerson wno :r nar seTf. or ~o an;aqe in an occupation Zl Senior citizan" ne3ns 3 oerson sixty C3l r,ss i n:o:ne ne3ns 31 l i tams cons i c2r2c in r::o-11e f r O i s tr i c t o f C 1 u mo i a r f lt;l 2 r al t 3 x gt;ll!r:&amp;gt;osas. 3n:l 311 gt;tner :non i es or oavm2nts re:eivad by 3ny inaivioual resid i n~ in tne rental unit• i n:ludinq. cut not limit~d to s:icial ~anetary qifts in ax:ess of threa ~u~ared ~ollars (S300l 3nd sucn cner sums as the ~3vor or t~e :et.ermi na rent31 SJOJlamant orogram as prov i ~e~ OY cnis o.c4 sec. 45-16-~2 P~JVI D ED rnat notni"q 1n thiS titl e s,al l )e construec as raatinq a n ant i l ement t o rent s uoclement oavnents in t~e aos:nce of (Ol I.n aiv fistal year tha '13yor snall limit If i .1 anv fi s c.al gt;a vmentS will ~x:eeO a gt;orooriatiOnS t "Hl "layor sn a i l tran smit to the :ounci l of r;1e Dis tr ict; of Colunoia prooose~ ao)ustnent s to el ioioil ir;y cri t:r i a in:one i~eli nes. or s u:io le~ent :iavm:nts to reou:e oaynent s unoer tnis title to an amoun t; no r; ii ex:e ss of aooroori a t io is cl rne ~ayor snall i s sue re ul:i t i:&amp;gt;ns ef fi:i:nt :idn in istration Of the re"ta1 suool ement oroqr a n t I nia ren't:tl su ool ement orovi~eo oy t~i s tir;la sn:il I oe ;ivai I a gt;l e to an y 't nant gt;f a rent 31 unit in r;n e istri:r; of :olunoia l n o is a oona fi ce res i oent :if a w i c .eoc sec 164 3 :as i nae 2 J nos a urranc. an-iual i 1come 1camoi-ie::1 •ith tie income of a11 oc.ner oerso,s resi inq in ·suc n rental unit.t totals l~ss an tne fo11owinq oercantaqes of tne most re:entlv auol is,ej uniteo States Oeoart~ent of ~aoor ~o -er !ujqet far an Uroan =amlly of ~our far tne interin oasis oy tne Uniteo St3t~s Oeoartmer.t of Laoor ne-oersan nousenolo two-cerson nousenold tnree-oerson house,olo or a one- or t•O gt;erson nouseholc containi1q any oerson wno is a senior citizen or •no is nandicaooeo four-person nousaho1d more :na, fiwe person nousenal: 77 8 oerceri 100 gt;er::e;it lll I ;er::erit 1 22 2 oe e.,t (31 wnose rent (oetermineo witnou: re::aro far t,e renc.al assistan::e crowi:ec ,ereon) 3r I ut il it ie s (utilities for t e iur:iose of tnis se::i:ion snall in:luae neatinq fuel acer an se er. qener:il pur:iose ele ri i tv inJ ool&amp;lt;ino fu?l &amp;gt; 1 i en? exce,t oai y suc"l te i c l ex::eeo cnircy-five :ierc?nt (35 of tne comoineo ;ross in::o11e of al I gt;ers::ins residing su:.n rencal Jn i c an :l nose total assets (cono i neo itn cn e assets of :t ll otner oersons resi:ling in su::n rental u"litl ex luoinq casn surreioer value i n any 1 ife insur:in::e col icy In an amouic of t anty- f i ~e c,ousa n:i vollars S25 0001 or l ess. personal :locninq auto110?ile furniture and furnisninqs lo not excee:i ten tn:&amp;gt;usand dolla r s lO OO:&amp;gt in 11alua 101 Not i enstan:iinq aiv ocnar prov is ion in tl"lis section. no tenant shall oe eli~i :ile to re:.e ive renc:tl suool~men cs he reunaer if :inv oerson residi,q i'l tne re,c al unit ll is receiving monetary :tssistance Jn:ler :ir:ivisions of the Conoominiun ict of 1~7b effe::tive ~arcn 29• 1977 (O l3w i e o.c. Cooe se 5 1281 i'lS l; or Z 1 i s r e s i a i n q i n a p i o 1 i 1 v- or ori vatelv-owieo rent.al unit: acidnist.areo jparacaa nain~ained or subsi~ ize :i. in nole or ~RJVIDEO c~~ve Tnat a t•na"1t ~no rasioes in a sinqle-f3mily ren~31 a:com~o~ation fin3nceo unoer ~OUSin~ Adninistration hapter 37, Title 38 J~s.c snail not cy r eason o f su:n rasidance oe :eemaa ineliqiola ~n~er tnis title C ien3"1ts re:e iv i nq renc:il suool aman:s unoar craai: uncar cne provisions of sac c ion a of tne Jist ri: t of :olumoia Income ano cran:hise Tax Act Coae sac 7 1567qJ cnis act 10 tan;int sr.:ill oe initi:illy eli~i gt;le to re:eiva rent:il sucolaments nereunaar if tne rent -bb- N?n-Han:i:aoo ac Parso:is Resioin~ in Unit l z 3 4 5 For Senior i t izens or Hanji:aopad lunoar of Persons Res i di nq in U~ it l 2 3 4 6 R2nc. 3e i n oa i c P2r lon n s 2 l S28l S32l S3bl S4.:l l S3Zl S3Zl S. 3 21 sa ~e as no,-aloerlv ta:&amp;gt;l a ao o113 lo perso shall oe cee ·ned inelio iol e t:&amp;gt; co·Hor1ue to recaive rental suople~e~ts ~n~er ni s t t le oecaus a a re,t ajjustmant autnor izao o~rsuant t O tnis ;i::t aft ar tno time n e initi31 re, t suoole~ent as cra,tac cau ses c.ne re,t cai; Jer nontn to E•C aeo cna Tia• iTIU'll al lo. eol a amou, t as uosacti::in snal1 not oe cons i cerad in tne :o~outation of tne rantal suoplement. Tnese li~its snall 01 revise~ annually ov thl ~ayor :o r(:fl act· tne avaraqe annual i ncreas in renta l nousi n o :osts i n tne District of ColJmoia. T"le ~ayor av :na.&amp;lt;e rental suoolement i:jran-:s availaola on a yaarly oasis to eliqiole rent.ars in accoroance witn the provisions of this title. Tne amount of su.:n yearl Y rental s1.1pol 1m1nt qrant oers~ns residi,q i, such rental ~nit fro~ tne vear:y r;nt du on tnat unit hat in no c3s1 snall such grant e~caea fortY (Ol On or Defora tne t~antiat Z~tnl cay of ona-twelftn (ltl2J ~f such rental suoolement qrant D C C=C sec 45-:644: f ·orm i~si ·t:.o ries of the gt; istric:t of :ol umoia and s nail amp;'5iion2e enti tie to receive rental gt;ayment s for ttle: 3Doli c:int's .in it d) e:ic r eit :il s.iool emen r J3vm nt cnec1&amp;lt TaJl gt;e ara~n i n su:n a m3nner :is t gt gt;ec:one voi Fartv- fi ve 51 av s after its issuance Se 305 al sn"3·.l 1 gt;e s;.1o ni ttO!o t gt; tna 'layer :ina sh:i l I ie on :i Su:n forn sn:il 1 Pnforn insofar :is p::issio l a t o f gt;rns used :iv tne ffe,oe r a l qovernment for its rental 3ss i stanc:e vnoer gt tn or 3ffirmation :is t gt; tna trutn of t ne nq.cters :ont:iineo tnera in v.er·i fi:a t i:&amp;gt;n orocedures n~v gt;e reoJ ire::i :is are D.C.CoCe, sec S 645 -o9- 1 ite: to ertif ie~ co:iies of tax returns of a&amp;lt;l ~ortn of all tnose residing in tne unit• copies of leases• rent receiots, or cancelled :necKS, ana verifi:ation of oeneflts from the Social Security e 1 i q i o i 1 i t 'f o F t :ie a op 1 i an -i Tne aopl icant snai l oe notified in writinq o• aoorova1 or disaoproval finoinqs of inel iqioil ity Cl Action on all ao0 l ications fileo unoer 3nd all acoeals ta&amp;lt;en from oecisiois of tne ~ayor shall ae c:insioere~ and neld accor~ii9 to the ano title I of the Cistrict of Columoia l9oa (32 Stat. 120 o.c o~e. se l -l5Cl-l3lOJ n tne c3sa of any air~c: ano irre:oncilaole :olumoia &amp;amp;amin i strativa ~roceaure ~ct i:ne -70 i:r rv is i o"s of tn2 J i s r.r i ct of :o1 u noi a (a) To c.:oe 2xtent ora:tic al all inform3ti o, Oll"Jvia a o t&amp;gt;v ;in a ooli::ant s al l bl o ifioen:i 1 ano sr.t-:il l ,o·t De a i s:l gt;s2a in suctl :i fJr'n :is t gt; oaentifv tne rl!nt suosiay ~rant aool ic an t Se 30 3 l s:n ;il I ,o: i f y in r i t i ng tne ten ant r ac: i i "G a suool e~ent qr ant i s about t o e~pira an:&amp;gt; tnat tne tnirt·1 (30 iav s u!:lon receipt. of suci ioti :e r e t enant s ,a1 1 r aa gt;oly Dy execu t ino un~e r gt; att1 or :tft'irmation ~statement Of c gt;n ti u20 elioi gt;i l i ty Ex:e gt;t as gt;t~er w i se or gt;viaaa i n this sect i on tne or::ivisi ons of &amp;lt;;ectio'I 305 sn;i11 :ipoly to tne Proces sil"lo Jf 0nless t"le iv gt;r dater'nines tl"lat Suen gt;ers l"I is not aliqiole f::ir a ral"ltal suJOl e11ent c .c.x:a" sec. 45- 1546 -71- PRJVIJEO. rnat t~e suoplements nereunjer fails to satisfy tne r~~uir:m:nts of se:tio~ 303 relatinq to .conoitions in:l ic;ioil itv. or nas c:asej to el iqiOle tnerefor tna ~3yor setting fortn tn: reasons for such determination ext day t,e rent is oue occurrinq :t least thirty Jnless i:nin fifteen (\5) cays 3ft:r tne rac:iot of sue, noci:e tne tenant suo~ies to :ne ~ayer a in lucinq anv availaole suooortinQ COCJmants l C.C::Ce, se 45-1647 72 o'ltinue::i eliqioility ithin tnirty (30) oavs ro11 J wi n cn a re::eipt Jf suc n statamanc an::i iecermin:ition of sucn tenant s eli~iJility f::ir :ontin ed re:eipt Jf rental suoolenents JY anv tanant throuqn rental s~polemant qrancs un~er cnis ac t are nareov exam:&amp;gt;t fron inco~e taxes J aya ol e J ur suant tJ tna Oi str i :t o f col u ~oia lo 19~7 (ol Stat. 3ZS; o CJae sac 7 lSOl ss. TITLE [I/ REVENUE landlord reouire::i to reg i ster un::ier this act snall :J3Y a fee if si~ jollars (S 00) for eacn rental un i t a nousin::i ac:ommocation re~istereo ov the l anoloro r e f ee s:ial1 oe gt;aio a .inually to tne Jistri:t of Colu~oia qJvernmant 3t tie time cne I and lord aJo1 i es f-:ir his or ner ius 1,ess I icense or a ranew-:11 t!"lereof gt;r in tria case of a nO·JS i riq J C c:de sec. 45-1648 iJ .c. CoC.e, sec. 45 65 13 o~mission may oeterTiine. Sue fees s:ial 1 oe aeoositories cesiqnace:i OY. t:'le Oistric:t of Columoia qovarnmant. for such ourooses. TITLE V (a xcept. 3s provioeJ in tnis se:tion. no -ic.twitnstandin~ the exoiracion of nis or her lease rent.al aqreement• so lonq as ne or She entitlea for SJC!"1 rental unit o tenant snal I oe evic:ce: from 3 rental unit for a:;y reason ocner then for nonoevment of rent unless ne or s:;e nas 11eets t.ne re;uir~ments of this seccion. Notices to vac~ta for all reasons ot:;er c:;an for .i. 1 I ·no ti es t.o reason(s) for tne eviction• ano if tne nousinq D.C.c=Ge, sec. 45-1662 74- 3c::onmja3tio is r3o uireo to oe re~ ist?rea ov tnis 3Ct• 3 statenent t.,3t t~ e nousinq 3c:o~m gt;C3 t ion •s reoistareo witn th e &amp;lt;ent Admin is tr3t:&amp;gt;r ano tl"le r e~istrat i on num::ier if tne nousi,o a:c:&amp;gt;mno::ation OI "13.idloro m3y recover D gt;ssesslo of 3 rel'ltdl unit here the tenant is vi:&amp;gt;lati nQ an obli::i:iti:&amp;gt;n of nis ir ner tenancy 3"'10 fails t:&amp;gt orr?ct su:n violation •i tnin tnirty (3 0 iavs after re::eivin::i from tne landlord a noti:e t:&amp;gt orrecc s u:n violation or vacate. tel A 13"'\0lord may recover possession of 3 re.,t31 unit n•r3 3 toJrt gt;f comoete"'lt juriscicti gt;n n3s d3ter n ine o that t"'\e tenant n3s oerfo rTie:l 3n illeoa1 3tt witn in su::h r31" t31 ·unit serve on tne tenant a thirty (30 l3Y ,oto:e t:&amp;gt; va:ate. Cdl 6. n3t;uo-al oerson tl"I a free.,010 terest in t ne rental uni t may rec gt;v3r Possession of a re.,tal unit nere le or sne seeks in gt;oo faitn to re:over oossess i::in of sucn rental unit f::ir nis or ,er imne:ii at3 an:&amp;gt; Jers gt;nal use a,o o:c up ~n;:y ~s a :lwel Ii nq. T:ie 1 andl gt;ro sn~ l 1 serv~ Jn tne tenant 75 s ~r her e:tic o recover :osse5sion of e re~tal u ~i: in i,sc~ncas arisin~ U1d!r tnis ren~ for any rental uni~ wnicn he or s:'le nas reoossessed uncer this suose:~ion :uri,q tne c a1ve (l2J 11ont:'l oeriod oeginninq o, the date na or s:'le recovereG possession of sucn rent~l unit stoccholder of a coooerative housi,q association ith a riqnt. of oossession in a re,t.31 U:'lit .nay ?xer:ise tne ricn~s of a natural person wi:h a freenold in~erest under this suose:tion e) A lanaldrd may r•covar oos1ession of a ren tal u,it ~here ,e or sne nas in qood f3itn :ontra:ted i .1 rit inq to se11 the rencal unit or cne no~sino ac:onmooation in wni:n s~cn uni: is 1o:3tej for c.ne im•ediate en: oersona1 use 3,d oc:uoaicy oy anotner oerson, so lonq as at cne t.i11e t1e o~n•r offers t.ne rent.31 unit or housing ac:a•mocacion fer sale• c.ne lanaloro nas so ioc ifiec c.ne t•nant in ~ricing and e~tenoeo to t~e tena a n opportunity to cur:nasa as crovi in tn e~~al usi C:inversion an~ Sale ~C! of 19~0 ffe:e i ve Se:i~~moer 10. 19~0 (J L3W 3-6!&amp;gt Cl C :ice, s lt 5- l gt; 9 9 LO l T ne lt J -7b- landloro s"lal 1 serve on the tenant a ninetv «•O av "oti:e to va=ace in aovanca of nis or ner action to re=over oossession of tne rental cnit lo person snal l ienano or receiv e rent for any rental unit nicn nas oeen repossessed unoer tn is suosect i on aur inq tne twelve ClZ} nontn oeriod oe.:iinnin~ on the 03te on wnith t"le ren ta l ~nit w3s oriqin:illy racossesseo oy tne landloro f)(l) A L1n:ilor.:1 '113 re.:over oossession of a r e"l ta l u"it for tna i mnediate ourpose of makin: alterations or renovations to tne re1tal unit -nicn :annot safely or reasonaoly oe accomol isne nile cne rental unit is occupi e O• s~ long 35 t ne olans For su=n alter3tions or r e~ovations 1ave oe an previously file l tn and aoorove::l oy tne ~ent A::l~inistrator ano s ucn clans ienonstrate t nat tn e arooosed alterations or renovations cannot safely or reason ably be acconpl isnea wni le tne n it is oc:uoiea Tne 13nOlor:i snal i serve on t ne tenant a one hunoreo t-enty (120 ay notice to va=ate in ~d~anc2 of his or ner 3ction ~o recover oossas s i on of tna re~tal unit gt;u:n notic~ to 77- nis or her riqnt to relo:acion assiscance gt;ursuant (2) IITTnedi=tely upon co~o1etion of tne orooos:d elcer3tiO'ls or renovations. sucn tenant snal 1 ave t "le a;:isol ui;e riqnt to ra e.it t e renta l unit 3) ere ne:essarv co brin~ cne rental unit into suosce,tiel :onol iance wicn the ~ousin e~ulacions. sucn cen3nt may re-rent 3t tne s3ne rent and under tne same ooliqations as were in effect at che tine tne tenant -as oisoossessed R~VIOEO· That sucn renovations or alterations -ere not m3Ce necessary ov tne neql i~e"t or al i :i gt;us :o,,aucc :if sucn cena'lt l Tenant~ oispla:eo oy actions under this s~cse:tion snail oe encitleo to receive relocation assist3'lCe as set fortn title VII Jvro~o. Tn;it t:"le ten3nts meet t!"I i ;gioi1 ity :ri~~rid of tn3 itle q)(l landloro may recover ~os session of a rental unit for the ourcose ~f i~m:ciately ~enolisnin~ tn oJsin~ ac:o~mooa~ion in wn icn sucn rental uni~ is locate~ 3no re~lacinq it it W'\ filec icn t,e Rant Aam i nis~racor. ana P~OVI!)EJ U~T~E r,at tne reouirements of titl a VII n ave ~een Cjmoliej tn the tenant a one hun~rea eiqntv (130) cav notice t o v acata in ajvan:e of nis or nar action to Such o t ices to vacate shall cot1oly wit:'I anc notif y cne tenant of nis jr her r ignt tj relo: a tijn assistance p~rsuan t co tne Provisijns jf title VI I 21 Teiant s cisplacea Jy a:tions uncer t nis ~Jose:tion snail oe e nt itleo to receive l&amp;gt;RJV!OcD Tnat t:ie tenan ts meet tne el iqioi l ity :riteria of that title h)(l) A lanalord may racover Possession of a renta l unit for t na ourpose of inme aia te ic:o11mJOatio PROVIDED Tnat tne reo~iret1encs of secci on 215 ana title VII nave oee1 :onolleo witn u,arej t~enty (l2J) oav notice to vacate in -79- 3ovanc f nis or ner actic re:ov~r ~ossassi~n :o~o ly wi~n 3na notify t:nant of nis or ner r iqn~ to raloc3~ion assis~ance pursuant o t i tle vrt 21 iny tenant oiso13ceo fro~ a rental unit by th2 suost:.aqtial renaoilitation of the ousin ac::o11m gt;dil::io.1 in mien t.-ie rantal unit is locatej snall iave a riqnt to re-rant the renta l 4nit iTim:oiately uoon th cnoletion of tn: su!:lst3nti al re"l&amp;lt i l i tati on 3) Tenants oisolaceo oy a:tions unoer this s~b se~tion snall oe entitleo to receive relocati on assistance as set forth in titla v1r: PRJVID::o. That tne t:nants meet the al igi bi' i ty :ritaria of tnat t itle iJ(iJ A lanoloro 11ay recover ooss:ssion of a rental unit for tna im11eoiat: ouroos: jf jiscontinuin~ tn: iousinq usa ano oc:uoancy of su i r:ntal unit A) t"le 1 anol oro sna J l se·rv;i on ~ne te.,ait a one nundrea eigntv tlSOJ oay ioti::e to •a:ate advance of his or ner acti~n to re::over Su::n n~tice c.o ao is o r ner r io nt to reloc a tion assistaice ours~ai o t ne or o v isl on s of tit l e VI I B) t:'le 1 ;sndl gt;rj sna l l not :ause cne iousino acco11mooation. of ~nicn tna unit is a ~art• to oe suostantiallv renaoil itatej for a =o ntinu ous t~elve !12 1 month perioj oegi nn inq f rom 1t11 e da e t ia t s u::n use is discontiiueo oursu3nt to tn i s section; IC) t:ie l and l r::1 s na l 1 io es u11e ~n v no u si n or c omnercia l usa of tne ui it for a :oit inuous t~elva (121 month oeriod oe~innin; from tn a dace tnat su:n use is aiscontii uao Pursuant to t n i s sac t i on C l t:ie lan::ilor::J sh;il1 not resune anv nOJsin~ us e of t:ie unit otner th3n ran:al no J s i n :i tE uoon resunption o f tna iousin se tie landlord snail not re-rant tn e unit at a ~r ater rent tn31 ~oul::i nave oaei oermitte::I o u rs ua1t to tn is a~t nao tne nousiio use noc oee n :ii SC nti iuao FJ t"le l andl gt;ra s.h3l J. on a for111 :Je v i sej gt;Y tne R2nt AOTiinistrator f il ith t,e len t A S minis~r~t:&amp;gt;r 3 stateme nt c lu j i 1Q• out not a1- 3no fu t u ra o l a ns f or ~ne prooer y GI if tne l3nolorc c~ sires to resume a rental nousing use of tne unit he or sne sh:l l notify tne l lt nt i. ami ni s-:rator wno snal 1 oece rmi ne et.ne r tne orov i sions of tnis par agraon (HI tne 1 andl oro s:-isl l ;iot oeTiana or r eceive re~ t for any rent31 un it hicn ne or sne nas reoossesseo unoer tnis sucse:tion for a tw~lve (121 nontn oerioa beqinning on cne da te he or sne recovere~ oossession of s ucn renc3l unit 21 Tenants olsolaceo ov actions unoer th is s~osect.ion snsl 1 oe entitleo to receive r elo:a:ion ~ssistanca as set forcn ii title v II: PR:JVt C!:D Th:it t ie t en:in cs m~t the el i&amp;lt;;loi 1 ity j I I n 3:iy cas a ne re tl"le l ;i.,al ore seeoe:s t~ re:ove r oossession of a rental unit or nousinq -s2- 5eotemJer 10 1960 (O c L3w 3 8 o c ode. sec. Se 5:J2 iamalora sna11 take any retal iat:&amp;gt;ry action a~ainst or ner ~v tnis act oy any rule Jr oraer issuea pursu an t th e r eto or oy a,y otn e r ~r:ivision s of l a acti:&amp;gt;n or oroceeoinq not otne r~ ise oe rTiittea law wni ch seeks to r ecover oossession of a rental u n i t; a::tion nich would in rease rent rease s e rvi::es Inc rease tne gt;oli ~at i on of a i n::onv en i e nce v io late tne p r i vacy o f tne tenant arass re:lu e t ne a ual ity or iuanti ty of service anv refusal to honor a 1 ease or re"lt:i l agreement or a n y orov is i :in of a 1 ease or rental aqreament efusal t.o r ;inew a 1 e ase or re"ltal a:;r ee 01ent eermi n :it lon of a t enanc y wi tnout cause or any :it ner for 01 of threat or coercion a t anol ord a;:iainst a tenant is re t3l iatcry ac iO"I D.C.Ccee, sec 45-1662 -a e~~ant•s f~vor unless th2 lanolord comas for~ard tn::tl'l1:ns pre:edinq sucn lanoloro•s a:tion, tne enant 11 nas 11aoe a wjtnessec oral or ~rittan n·e:essary tOd:&amp;gt;ri q tne nousing a:c:&amp;gt;mno::ati:&amp;gt;n or th• rental unit into comol ianca ~itn tne H:&amp;gt;using (21 contacted ao:&amp;gt;rooriata gt;fficials of ena Oistrict of :olumoia qovernment eitner orally in tne presence of a witness or in wri tinq oncarninq existin::i violations of the ~ousinq ~eculati:&amp;gt;n s in tne rantal unit ne or sne occ uo i es or oert3in i n~ to tne nousinq a:comnod:c i on in l"licn su:h rental mit is locateO• or reoorted t gt; sucn o f ficials SJSoe::r.eo violations nicn. if cot'\f i r11e::i ould ranoer su:h rent3l .in it or ~c~sin equla:ions a4 3) le~allv ithneld all o r gt;arc of ;iis rr n;ir rant fter nav inc ive;i a reas:&amp;gt;naole rro:.tice i gt; tl"le lanolord eitner orally in t.,e tr·-asan::e of a itn ass gt;r in otriting of a i•n-vol v?O in any la ful a::tivities oertaininq t .o C ant oroani zati on: r 5 Tiede a n e f fort t gt; se::ure or en fo r ce any gt;f su::n tenant s r i qnts u.,car tne tenant s l!e:~s a or contract .itn tne lanalor or i l orougn t l eqal acti :in a;iai nst t le Jtano lo ro ca Tner e is astaol isneo a concil ia t i :in swrvic e itnin t ne Office bl Tne service snall orovioe a voluntary rro ao~ersar ial forun for t he re solution of Distri t of Columbia cJ Tne staff of the servica snal l oe !Ml gt;ointeo ov t ne Rant ~Oninis t rator and oe persons D.C.~e, s 45-1663 1 85- Col Eitner 3 13na1oro or a tenant may initiate a proceeoinq before tne sarvi:e e; No oers::in snal l oe :011cel 1 e::i tO atte.no a session of tne servi:e nor parti:i::iate in any oersons 03rtv to sucn 'rocaedinq a;rae to oe oound oy tne out:o~e of su:h proceeoinq o ev i oence oertaininq to the :oncil iation pro:eaoing sn3 ll oe \ ~dTiissiole in 3ny 1uoicial cro:eeoinq under o~ner orovisio,s of la. re13ting to lanoloro 3nd tenanc i SClJ S TITLE vr o~v~~SIJN o OEMOLIT!O~ o~ QE~T&amp;amp;L HOUSIN~ D.C.CcC otwit~stanoing any otner orovisio, of 13w• no sec 4S-167l oermit cne conve rsion of any housi a:commoOati::in tr3nsi~nc resioentiai oc:uoancy 86 C.C:Ce al ~otJithst3nalnq any otne r pr o vi s ion of 1a no oerson s nall o amolisn ana tne ~avo r sha ll :ons tr uc cina o r exoanoinq a nocel mJca l inn or e ffective aa te of this act or unless ~1qin2erinq stJo ies er t ify that tne •alls ano f Juiaation are structJr~lly unsound and u~saf a bl No oer son snail constru:t o r axoanc anc cne ~a1o r snail noe ~ermic t ne construc t io~ or exJ ans io n of a notal notel. inn. or ocner transient resio e ntia l occ::uoancy or a1 y othe r non residential us e on tne s i t e of a nous ing ac::c::onmodation or rental unit damol isieo af cer th e effect ive oa t~ of t his act unless nore t nan one a lf (l/21 of the in:o"'e fron tna nOJsi nq Jurooses 35 of t ne e f fective oata of tnis act or 87- unless encinaerinc sc~cies cer:ifiea :nat uns.3fe. T!il.E VI I D.C Ce sec No lanclord snail suostantielly renaoilit~ta. je~ol isn~ or dis:ontinue any nousinq accommodation unless tnere nas first been serveo u:ion each tenant rasidin~ therein a ~ritten noti:e of intent sot (C:l I or (iJ is ac!Jroori:!te• Suen notice relo:ati:in assistance uncer this ac: or any ot"ler :onmission snail grescrioe tne conceit of su:n \ 3c:onm:ioa-t.io:1 r&amp;gt;ic the lanc\oro i ·1tan::s to -ee 1is conti~ue no~s in; use (or nicn tn a l andlor d i n::enos t o sal l to :inotne r oerson h gt to cna l anolorc s kno~l eo9e i ntencs co s..1ost:inti3lly renaoili ate tenolish or disc:o ri"t:in..1e nousinq us a 1nless tri is sect i on nas !lean c:omo l ie:1 i tr'lc 'llo t h i nq containe:I ·in tnis se:tion shal 1 oe construea to 1 imit a l andlora•s ri ;nt to e&amp;gt;1ict a :ib l i CJa t i in of t :ie tenanc v: P'lovr E O· T:i3t sucn 3Ction t o e vict is i n :omol i a nc:e it, sec~ion 501 Sec 702 Each lanol:ira c:o~menc:inq suostant i al r e nao i l itation le11ol it ion or n gt;usi19 tn is a: c. sh311 gt;aY r el oc3tion ass is tance in :in amount calculate:1 oursu3nt to sec:c101 703 to all tenants gt;f s..1ch nous i nq 3cc:onmo03t io 1 no al we r e liv inq in tne rent31 ui i ts c:on ca i n eo cnerein from wn icn tney are oe in lisola:ed at t ne t i ne t i e notice re:iu ireo ov sect ion 50 1 is given bl are ai s gt;13cea fro11 ren tal u1its oec:iuse D.C.COd2, sec. 45- 1682 -e9- lc~at.e: is t e suostantially r~h:oi 1 i"t~t::o a) T:ie a11ount of reloc3tion 3ssistance as follo.is: relo:acion a;sis~a,ce in t,e a11oun: of one nunorec unit s:iall be oavaoie o tne tenants or suotanants For tne ourposes of thi~ Paragraoh• the term "room• in a rental unit means any soace ~ixtv (cj) souare feet o~ larqer w,i:h nas a fixed :ei\inq 3nd a floor ano is suooivioe itn fixeo (2J ~elocation assis::ance in tne a-nount of sev:nty fiv2 oo11ars (S75) for ecl:n P3ntrY D C C Ce se 45-l.6d:3 Jayao i t o e ten ;ints or suotan3nts O?ari.,g t ~e os t of reno vinq t"le major itv of t ne furnisnin 3 l Trie wtayor snal l aajust t "le a'llount to oa oaia tenan ts for relocation ass ista.,ca from tine to time or~er to refJe:t cna.,qas tne cost of ~ovinq witni"I the ~asninqt; on J•C Stana ara ~etroooli tan Statistica l 4rea 1s ~SA Su:n a::i justments snall oe onade pursuant to t i tl e I o f tne District of Columoia Aa~inistrative ?r:iceoJre ~ct aoo r ove~ Jctooer 21 l'l!:io 2 Stat l2J4; J C:ioe sec l-l5~l-l5lO not no r e tnan once any :alenoar vear {Ol Relocation assistance snail oe oaia to el iqiole tenants not later th;in t.,e,tv-four (2'-1 ours :irior to t"le oate tne re,e•l u"l i t is to oe va:atej oy t"le tenant(S) or suotenanersi: PRJVIDEO That t "le landlor::i nas re eiv ed at least ten (lJ) oavs 1e~cluaing Saturoays Sunoays, ano "lol ioavsJ ad va nce ritten no ti:e of tn e Oa te uoon ~nic n tne unit is to ba vac ateo joes nJt orovije t"le lanjlorj itn at le3st a ten ClJJ oay noti ce• t ne relocation asiiscance sna11 oe paij icnin t~irtv (30) asv s 3f ear cne unit is -91 hicn is tne suo je ct of an outstanji,g _juc;ment fo r oossassion o gtaineo oy tne 1anoloro or te,ants or suote~ants for a cause of action 4netner such cause of action arises oefore or re.,a!Jili.tate denolisri. or ois:ontinc.Je hou in; If tne juc~ment for oossession is oaseo upon intent to rena~il itate• de~olisn. or discontinue cna· lanoloro or tna court renoerinq the juog~ent for ocssassi:m nenevar a o~iloing in tne Oistrict of Columoia is :onverted From rental to conoo~inium un i ts. or is suosc:intially renaoilitateo or camolis"leo, or is :iscontinuao frow nousing use. t,e ~a1ocation ~ssist3n:e Office sn:l 1 orovioa relo:aeicn l oC.C=C.eJ sec S-l6d4 2 i-enol i nad ir oiscontinue::i ouil::inq. T n is ll ascartainin; tne reJo:ation nee::is f o r a:i h housenold 2 l gt;rovidinq :urrant information on tne :ivail:ibilitv :if eouivalant su os titute h:&amp;gt;usinq 3) s.u::iplyinq information :bnc ern i na Feoer3l end District nousin; Proqr:i~s in o 4 gt;roviai·n-i itner :iovisory ser.,i:es to Jis e:eo oe r s:in s in or o er t:&amp;gt i nin i ze n a ro s n i os i n a~ j Jstina to relo~ a tion e'1t'1l Housi1q C:&amp;gt;mTlission stHll estaolish 3 T~nant gt;t Lina is to orovice :issist:in:e tj 10 in::i no::lerace income tenants• To carry out tnis ouro o s a tne functions and resoot'lsibilities sn:ill in: l uO a but not oe limited tO• th f ol l o win a l a ns er i 1q rant control gt;r gt;c ed.Jra l ouas ti::ins 31d directinq tenants t gt;w:ir~ ooss io le ~curses :if a:tiot'I in resolvi'1q prool ~ms c l e~c l :iininq rent incre:ises D.C.COde s 45-168 Cc I oroo1i~inc g.ii::anc 2 :in e.,er ;e y s \ e 1 2 r e I prov i :l i :ic; q..i i :llHIC:e :i r. n us i assisteno:;e gt;r :icir ans f l p r o vl:&amp;gt; inQ gu i :anc~ in r es gt;1 .i t ion 0 f •3ter ne,at. i nq• re oairs a net o t.her cir oolems re so::mse -r.:i all e::iai ion s of narassmen ir neql ect gt;y l an :1 l ~r :1 s h\ ans~er inq prel i~inary c~estlons a:iout tn evi:.t.ion; arid fl oro11 i :1inq q i idanc:a on otner t e nan t. TITLE VIII ~9ac. effe:t.ive Saot 2moer 10· 1980 (l L 3-ab; foll::i s lo~"l lJ3(l:11 is anende t::i re,o as follo s F nouse,o lo i n tne nousino acco~mooa~ion i~oing tnose no~senolos in ~nic n no memoer nas iriie tv C~Ol jays ano tnose housenolas in wni any '1111!11lber nas oeen an e11ployee of t,e o ner aurinq lttte Jreceaino one nunor e j twenty (lZJl cays 0 l Section 2DZ!al (D.c ooe. sec 45- aec 5-l5?9 2 1.0tic:e to v aca te for tne immeaiate o~roose of iisconti nu i nq tne nousinq use an::i oc:uoancy of a rental u,it oursua'lt to section S01(il(ll(AJ Of tne ~e~tal Mousino ACt of 1980 or a OJrc:naser from SJCn ow,er or SJC: cessor in ineerest to su c:n conver t tne ,ousin~ acc:omm~dation in wnic:n tne re ntal unies are locatec Cl Section 203 10 Cooe sac 5 D.C.Coie, sec. 4 599 202 cualifieo v:ita r neao of nousenolo resioinq in eac:n rental ~nit of tne nousin ac:onmooation is -95- ClZO) javs orior t:i the ate of ap:llication for e1;qibil itY or unless ne :ir s:ie is a nead of Th e 'l:iyor snal I jeteril'l i ne i e e l i c;i ol l i tY of v:iters gt;r i or to tne election a1d snall devise such f:&amp;gt;rns and orocedJres as nay gt;e necessa ry t:i verify aliqioi \ itY un:ier tnis subsection lt;ll Section 2·:3(a) 10 C:ooe. s ec 45- i..o lt 2'.l6( all is ;ir.ienoe:l in t:ie first s entence :iy i nseri:in~ imne:&amp;gt;iai:ely followin~ the ;ihrase •an owner t:ie onrese •oF a reni:al unit in a n:&amp;gt;usi~g tn is a is amenceo in tne thiro sent;en:e Oy si:ri~ln9 tne in 1 ie J tnar eo f J e e D c. c E: I s 4$-1599.20€ D.C.C Ce, 5 43-2639 1 Se:tion 2 of t~e Confirmation Act of 1978 effec i ve '4 arc n 3. 197 Q C. La 2- 142; J C gt;Ol sac l-3o2. 7) i s amenoe:i Jy insert ing onrase •tne ~ent A:lministrator TITLE IX '4I SCELL A'IE0US E~FECTIVE DATE; TER ATIJN (a) Any oerson no ~no~inqly l le~anas or rec:a i ~es .an v rent for a re-it a l un i t in e&amp;gt;i:Cl!SS of t.ne maii:imum allo aole rent aop l i a gt;l a to tnat reri'tal urii t under cne orovisions of t itla II: o r 2 su osta ntially re:iu:es :ir el i 11ti nates uni t. snail oa nelo 1 i ao le ov t.ne Rent AOnin i stra tor, or ~erital Housinq Com ni ssion. as 3001 icaole for tna amoun t ov nicn t nl! rerit. cnat anoun t an:l/or for a rol l oac:K o f t~e rent to o.c.c:x:e, sec. l.-36Z i.c.c.oce, sec 45-159 lt cusin o~mission sn311 oe~ernine O}Cl ny oerson w~o willf.Jl ly colle:ts a as oean revarse: oy a court of conpetent Ct 3 3ny oerson wno willf1.111y cornnits any oener :i~t in violation of •nv orovision of tnis oursu3nt to t~is :i:t; or lt;.J anv oers:m .no 11 f.Jl l v fai 1 s to ne&amp;lt;tt o il io3tions reouireo unaer t~is act. sn:il1 oe fineo iot nore tnan five tncus:ino Jollars (S5.~C for ea:n violation 98 r s cacenent in oraer to oot3;n or fo r cne 03y~ent; or any Person :e3sin to oacome i lli.oi ole for suc:i rElnt or D3y:nent and wno coes "lll!tt imnediataly notify t:ie Mayor of n; s or her ii1111a:l iqioil i cy. snal l oe fine:i 110: less tnan f'i ftY Suen gt;erson foun:i ~ullcv or naKinq false or fr:iu:ulent reoort s state~ents or of fail inq to oronor.lv notify tne 3111~r of nis .or ner ineli&amp;lt;;iioil itY• s.,a11 reoay t gt; c:JTe Qi stric t of :olumoia qove r nment :inv :ina a ll Nern11eni: i rel i :in·:e on sucn false or fr;iuoul ent :ocrl ic;ition. reo:ut or statement• or 31 l amouni:s r interest o~ su:n amounts 3t tne race of one l! f of ;in oercent I 1/2 per montn u1til reoai a Tne ~ant ~e:s gt;n;iole attornev fees to cn e or?vail in~ o;ircy D.C.a:de, Se 45-1692 ~1i ic: i~n 3u \or i z 1naer se ion 5Ct Se 903 S :v~r":Oi l j If an v orovision of :i:r wor::i o r tne a-oo 1 i :3t ion tnereo f. sni! 11 in ·any l"~in:ier· of tne a:t and of the 3o;i1 ication of any Se 90 eemad t:i suoers~oe the 'lenta 1 A:c;im11o:ia i ons ~ct oi1" Fl75. and t le Rental iousinq Act of 1977: 8C:EPT. rnat a Petition filed -itn cne Rent &amp;gt I J e oe r~ine:l un:ier tne orJvi si on s of tne (a I un less otnerwise orovioeo ov ~e~tal -tous l no o mission re91Jlat!o11s. any information or ~ocu ent reoulreo co oe served uoo 3ny oerson reores encaci~e oesiqnated oy t~a t oerson or ov t~e v c.c.ecc A 1 se i-_c l.C.CoCe, sec. 45-1694 o.c .ecce, sec. 45-15?5 f!N3 ora service n a l l oe .naoe uoo n t "l3t =onp1etej Jv anv of tn: foll gt;winQ •a•s l l gt;y handi nq t:ie oocument to tne Jerson ov leavi,q it at sucn oers gt;n's olace o f ~usiness witn sone resoonsiole oarson in c:iarqe or i 1 e;a" ino it at t:'le person s isual J1 ac2 of r ~si~ e nce i t n 3 02rson of s ui ta J le 3Q a ano i scre ti on ore sent t~erein gt;r 121 Jy t2leqra wnen tne :ontent of t,e ;nformation or oocument is given to 3 te1eoraon :onp~nv orooerly add r essed and oreoaio; or (31 ov ma il or Oe gt;osit tn tne Unitea States Postal Serv ic2 orooer l y stanoaa ano ac:resseJ; or JY a "ly otn er mea,s t,at i s i i onfornity wit n an oraer of the ~eital H gt;USi:iG :onmis sion or tne ~ent ~oministr a tor in anv Jr gt;ceeoi"lq 0) N gt; rent i1creasas hetner gt;ursuant to tni s act. tne ~ental A.ccomniooati gt;ns 1ct of 1~75 the ~ental Housino ~Ct of 1q17 or a1v ao~ inis t rati •e oec isions issueo tnereu:ioer sna ll gt e ff Ctive U'lt.il t :1e first O:lY 0 .1 nicn rent. is 101 ormallv oa i :i oc.:urr ino nore a, t~irtv &amp;lt;30 1 03Ys te:1a n't a I Tl'll s act sl'l al l ta«e effect after a thirty 3o i ia v gt;er i oo ~avor (O r in t l'le event of veto ov the ~avor to overrioe tne veto) as orovioeo in sect i~n ~02 1 1 o f t ne Oistrict o f Colum:&amp;gt;ii Se l f- aoo roved Oecemoer 2 l 973 (87 Stat e13; o l9SO. e ffective Seotemoer 2o t9~0 Li 3- l Oo 1 n I cnever sn~l I 1 ast occ..Jr. ex:eot a gt;irov i cao in suosecti on O Ol Section 8Jl s~all tak e effe:t af ttr d ~i str i: t of :olumoia t o overriae t ,e vatol as or ovi a!a in se:tion ~02 11Ll of t ne Oi str i ct of r ct:.e o.c cx..ef sec. 45 6~4 102 a ll3: ci c o::e. sec l &amp;lt;.7 (cl{lJJ Ji Jistr i :t of :alu~oia APPROVED January 7, 1981 All titles :Jf tnis Xe, sec s- 1€96 &amp;lt;\ Q .e L c~rr o c~unc11 Of the Jistrict Of :olumoia I i I I 2 &amp;gt; G C C-:a CC NC: § VC!C C I t ° J.=5 1 c ser.t lt;:a I I 1 J en 1 l I o I I nTvg~ I I I I J K ITT: 1 I J I ~S t C TV~J I I i I tr i~&amp;lt;t I I I I I Jl.SON I I fS?11 L I I I I r- ll!l{T I I I 1:-0011 I I I I tT'T J I I I I U,1,nV I I I I l V I I I I I I I I l T1?'°7 I I I I j 0'1T l Ct( I I i I I I I I J c r I I L t t lt la 1 J 1 I I p 1 y 'ICtC 1u z o;.r a i_u_s u c_l _a l&amp;lt;_e 4 l'CO C I I u1oo m 1 1 I I 1 </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>401</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-4051"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>601</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-4071"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>602</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-4072"/>
  </section>
</document>
