<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-169">
  <num type="law">3-169</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1981-03-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-169.pdf">D.C. Law 3-169</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 5368</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-169 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-107, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 28, 1980 and November 12, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-300 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. Law 3-169 "District of Columbia Antitrust Act of 1980 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 3-107 on first and second readings, October 28, 1980 and November 12, 1980, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 25, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-lOO, published in the December 5, 1980 edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 27 page 5368 This act was originally transmitted to Congress on December 4, 1980, and resubmitted on January 14, 1981 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 3-169, effective March 5, 1981. ARRINGTON D 1 Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January February March 14,15,16,19,20,21,22,23,26,27,28,29,30 2,3,4,5,6,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27, 2,3,4 r l.AW 3@ 16 9 EFFtcrrv£ O.\Tf: MAR 0 5 1981 A.N ACT D.C. ACT3 IN T~E C)U~CIL OF THE DIST~I:T o oLuMBlA NOV 2 5 1980 To requl3te the :onduct of ousiness Jper~tions in th e Distri:t of :olumoia consist ent with t~e ~o3ls of a free enterprise svsten. BE IT EN~CTE) BY T~E COU~CIL QF THE DIST~ICT QF :OLU~BIA• Th3t tnis 3ct ~av De cited as the "District of :ol umoia Antitrust Act of l9B0 Se z. SJOtitl e II of titl e 28 ot the J fol lo win~ ne naoter to r e3d as t:&amp;gt;l lo s S ec 23-~5 0 1. Definition ~nd ~urpose 2 502. Contract• comDination. or conspir3cy to restr3in tr30e 29-~503. Monopolization 2 504. E~clusions 2&amp;gt;i 5Q5. Civil investiqati11e d~m3nd. CODIFICATION D.C.Code, as in text r n t 2 "28-~506. CriTiinal enforcement DY tne Jistrict of :olumbia 2 9 5 J7 Dam3qes and injunctive relief for injuries to or within tne District ~f ColcJmoia 23-4508. Relief for oriv3t2 ~arties 2 509 11direct ourcnasers 29-~510. Judqment in f3v~r of tne District of Columbia 35 orima f3Cie evidence 29-C+5ll 28-~512. n 2 j- C+5 l 3 and st3tes 2'3-4514 2 51 5 2 i 5l.6 2'3-1+517 29-1+5ld. Limitations on acti~ns. Assurance of disc~nti1u~nce. c~ooeration witn fejeral qovernment Remedies cunulative. U'"litormity. District of C~lumoia Antitrust Sever ao i l i tY• Rel3tion to otn2r l3w S2c. 28-4501. Definition anj ouro~se 3 s usej in tnis chapter. t;ie terTI 'parson• includes an individual. corooration usiness trust. oartners'lio. ousiness 3ssociation Jr a11y or.n r laqal e'ltity. 3 r&amp;gt The ouroose of tnis :n3pter is t:&amp;gt; or gt;mote the JnnaTipered freedom of :oTimerce and inaustry tnr gt;uqnout the aistrict of :olumoia OY orohibitinq restraints of traae and nonoool istic or act ices Sec. 28-4502 ontract onoination• or consoiracv to restrain trade Every contract. comoination i, tna form of a trust or otner~ise. or conspiracy in restraint of trade or comnerce all or any part gt;f wnicn is ~ithin the District of Columbia is declared to De 11 Sec. 28-4503 4onoool i zati gt;n It snal l oe unlawful for any oerson to nonoool ize• attemot to monopolize. or comoine or :o ,soire wit, 3ny ot,er oerson or oersons to nonoool ize anv part of trade or conmerce. al I or any oart of ~nicn is witnin the Ji strict of Co I umo i a Sec. 28-450 Exclusions a) Laoor of a human oeinq is ,at a :oTimoditv or an 3rticle of commerce. \lotn i nq containej in t,is chapter snall oe construea t gt; f oroid t,e e~istence ana ooerati gt;n ot laoor v v n dQricultur:31 or norticultur:il gt;rqaiizations. institut e d f:&amp;gt;r tne curoose of mutual h e lo~ ana not navinq capital stock or conauctej for orofit• or to foroid or restrain individual memDers of such or~anizations from l:3wfullv carryinq out tne le::iitiTiate ODjects tnereof; nor sn3ll such orqanil3tions. or the ~emoers tnereof. be ne1a or coistrueJ to be illeqal conbinations or consoira ies i n restraint of trade { gt This cnaoter does not naKe illeqal the 3C t i V i t V 0 f H l any non-profit corporation trust gt;r orq anization estat&amp;gt;lisnej ex:lJsiv e lv tor rel i qi ous. cnari taol e. l iterarv. or educational ourposes to the extent tnat the :le ti vi tv is r e l i qi ous C'Bri taol l iterarv• or e :1 u::at i m31 gt;r 2 tne wasnington ~etropol itan Area Tr ansit ~uthority Sec 3 henever the Corooration Couns e l has r eason to Del ieve tnat any person nay Je in oossession. custody• or control of any aocumentary nateri 31 r mdy ha v e anv informatioi• relev:3nt to 5 3 civil 3ntitrust investiqatio1. tne Corooration Counsel mav• prior to the institutio~ of a oe servej pon sue, oerson. a civil investiqative ~enand r eouirinq sucn oerson to orJdJCe such reorodJCt i on. to 3~swer written interroqatories• to qiva oral tasti:nony conc:erninq :lo:u11ent3rV nateri31 or information. or to t~rnish any :oITTDin3tion of sucn ~aterial. 3nswers. or test.imonv gt Ea~n sucn demand snail: II 1 state the nature of the conduct un:ler investiQ3tio~ co~stitutinq tne all~qad 3ntitrust vi gt;l:ttion; or Fi) investiqatio1 whicn. if c:onsum113ted. may result in 1n antitrust violation; 3nd c the apolicable provision of l 3 2 if it is a deman~ for oroauction of docJm?ntarv material tl l J n A gt;f d gt;c.Jmentary m3teri al to oe or:&amp;gt;duc~a witn sufficient definiteness as t gt; permit sucn material to oe fairly ide,tifiea B orescribe a return oate gt;r jates ~hie, 4ill orovide a reasonaole gt;eriod of ti11e f:&amp;gt;r tne material ana naje avail~ole f:&amp;gt;r insoection ana coDyinq or reoroauction nd identify tne custoaian to #nom such mat~r i al snal I oe 111aae ~vai 1 aol e 3 ritte, interr:&amp;gt;qat gt;ries A oropound witn ~efiniteness tne ~ritten intP.rroqat gt;ries to oe answer~a 1 r~scriDe a Jate or aates dt ~hie, tine a,S#ers to #ritten interr~oatories shall oe suo11itted; ana io entifv tne C.Jstoaian t gt; wnom such answers s,all be suomittea; or 4) if it is a de~and f gt;r tne qivinq of or a l t s t i 110 n v iJ 7 l) J13c~ 3t wni:h oral testimony sh311 Je comTienced BI identify an 3ssist3nt coroor3tion :o.Jnsel no shall conauct the ex3min3tion and tne custodian to wnon the transcriot of su:h exa~ination snail be suomitteo I ~o s.Jcn jeTiand snail require tne suomission of any answers to written interroqatories, or the qivinq of anv oral testimony, if su:h material, ans ers• or testimony oul1 ~e protected from disclosure u,oer l tne stanaards aopJ ica~l e to )uoerior Court of the Oistri:t of :olumoia in aij of 3 Qr3'1d 1urv investiqation; or 2) tne standarjs aopli:aol2 to jiscov2ry re~uests unaer tne Superior :curt of tne Jistri:t of Colu~Dia Rules of Civil ~rocedure. to to any S1Jcn jeTiana is aporooriate anj :onsistent ith t'le provisions and ourooses of this cnaJter j) l\nv su::h dem3nd sn3l l gt;e served in any n3nner provided for service of process in the Su:&amp;gt;erior Court of the )istrict of :olumDia. or if the oerson to oe served nas no Pl3ce of ousiness ~itnin tne District of Columoia• tne aernana ~ay oe served Dy 1eoositinq a duly executed coov in tne Jnited States mails ov reqistered mail. return recei Pt re11ueste:i. aaaressed to su::n per so at tn~t person's orin::ipal office or ~tace of ousiness e) The oroduction of docu~entary material in resoo,se to a demana served oursu3nt to tni~ s e :tion snall oe made under 3 sworn ertificate. in s~cn form as the demand designates. ov the 1 i re t e d or i f not a n at u r a I Der son o v a o er son or persons navinq ~nowledqe of tne facts ana :ircumst3nces relatinq to such production. to the effect t,at all of tne documentary material required by the ae~ana and in the oossession ustOdY• or ontrol of tne Person to wno~ the ae~ano is directeo nas oeen oroduced and made availa~le to tne CJstooian. II f Ea:n interro~atory in d denana served ~ursua,t to this section snall De 3nswereo seoarately ana fully in writinq unaer oath• unless su:h procedure is gt;DJected to. in whicn event the re3sons for the objection sh3ll gt;estated Nitn specificitv in lieu of an answer. anj sucn reasons shall oe s~onitteo under a s~orn certificate l l T~e exa~ination of any Jerson oursuant to 3 demand for oral testimony serveo Jnder this section snall oe taken oefore an officer autnorized to ad~inister 03t,s and 3ffirm3tions DY tne laws of the Jistrict of :olumbia. T,e officer Defore ~hom tne testinonv is to oe t3ken snall put tne witness on oath or atfirmation an'.l shall oersonallv gt;r DY soneone ~fficer•s oresen:e. record tne testinony ot tne j tness. Tna testimonv shall De recorded and transcr i gt;eel hen tne testi~ony is tullv transcrioed. tne officer before ~hom tne testimony is taken snall promptly transmit a copy of tne transcri:&amp;gt;t of the testimony to tne CJstodian 2 Tne assistant corooration counsel :onducti,q t,e exanination snail exclude from the u n 10 gt;l~c here tne examination is nelj 31 I otner gt;ers gt;ns: oerson•s cou,sel. the officer oefore wno~ tne testimonv is to oe taken. and anv stenoqraoner t3Kinq suc11 testimonv 3) Tne oral testimonv of a,v oerson section sn:Jll oe taken i11 the e&amp;gt;istri:t of Columbia. or in such Other Place as nav oe aqreed uD gt;n ov the assistant corporatio, counsel :onducti,q tne eKa~ination and sucn gt;erson 4 wnen the testimony is fully tr3nscri:&amp;gt;e1. tne assistant coroorati:&amp;gt;n couns~l or the gt;ff i er shall 3fford tne wi t;iess ho TI3V gt;e ~ccomp:Jnie~ DY counsel J a re3son3ole O:&amp;gt;Dortunity sn:Jl 1 oe r ea 1 to or oy tne itness. Jnless sucn ~xamination 3nd readinq are waived Dy the itness. 4ny cn3nqes in forTI gt;r substance wni:h tne witness desires to make shall De entered a,d identified upon tne tra;iscript ov the officer or the dssistant corporation counsel with a state11ent of tne reasons qi~en Dy the witness for makin~ such The transcriot snail tnen gt;e siqnej ov 11 tne witness. unless the witness in writinq w3ives the siqninq s ill. C3nnot De found. or refuses to siqn itness within 30 days of the witness oeinq 3fforded a reasonaole opoort~nity to exaTiine the transcriot• the officer or tne 3ssist3,t corporation counsel shall siqn the tra1script and state on tne recor1 the fact of the ~aiver. illness, aosence of the witness. or the refusal to siqn. coqether witn the reason. if any, qiven therefor. ft 5 Tne officer shall certify on the officer and that tne transcript is a true recoro ot tne testiTiony qiven DY the witness. and tne of ficer or a ssistant corooration cou1sel snal I ~romotly deliver or send tne transcript oy reqistered mail• return receipt reouested 6 Uoon request, tne assistant corpor 3t ion ounse 1 sha 11 furn i sn 3 :ooy of the transcri~t ac no cost to tne wit1ess onl Ex:EPT. Tnat tne Corooration Counsel mav for qooj lZ c3u se limit such witness to insoectiJn of tn 2 offici a l transcript of tne witness•s t e st:i~onv 7 Any oerson compellea to aDpear ~naer 3 jemand for oral testimony oursuant to this section nav Je a:comoanied• reoresentea. ana oerson. in confijerice eitner upon t,e request of sucn person or uoon :ounse1•s own initiative• with reso ect to a,v Question as~ed of sue, oerson ucn person or cou,sel may ob1ect on t,e recorj to any questi on in wnole or in pdrt. ana snail 1rieflv st3t e for th e record tne r eason for tn e 0D1e:tion. An 001e:tion ~av orooerly ce TI3je. receivea 3nJ enterej upon tne r ecorj #hen a claim is 30 2 th~t sucn oerson is entitl aa to retuse to 1 ns ~er t~e auestion on qrounds of 3nv on s t i tu t i on al or o t ne r 1 e q a l r i n t Jr p r i 11 i I ea e incluain~ the orivileqe aqainst self- incriminatiori. Such person sh~ll not otnerwise 001ect to or refuse to answer any question. ana snall not Dy himself or throuqn :ounsel otnerwiSe 1nterr~pt the oral examination. If su:n person r efu ses to a,s-er any question• tn e :orporation :ounsel may Jetition tne Superior :o~rt ot t~e l3 Jistri:t of :olumoia pursu~nt to t,is section for an order co~oellinQ sucn oarson to a,s"er su c n ~u2stion. If SJcn oerson refuses to 3nswer any Juestion on tha ~rounds of privileqe dQainst salf- incrimin3tio1. tne testiTiony of su:n parso, Tiay oe :onpellej Dy order of court upon tne Qrantinq of im11unity. No testimony or other dis:l osura co~pellej unjer :ourt oraer or any information jire:tly or injirectly derived froTI sucn Ordered testi mony or disclosure may oe usej 3qainst tne oerson in 3ny crimin31 casa axceot 3 prosecution for ~er jJry or other"ise fdi linq to :onply witn th oraer 8 Any parson apoearin~ for oral section 5h311 oe entitled to tne sam~ ni leaqe reimoursements w,ich are paid to wit,esses in the 5u~erior Court of the Distri:t of :01umoia. whenever any oerson fails to comply "itn 3ny :i 11i 1 in11estiq3ti ve cJe11and dul v servecJ uoon that oarson under tnis section or "n?never satisfactory coovinq or reoroduction of any such naterial cannot oe oone and sucn oerson refuses to surranaer sucn m3tarial. t,e Coroor3tion Counsel n n c olumbia and s~rve uoon such person Detiti gt;n tor an order of su=h court for tne enfor:eTient of tnis A oerson wno• with tne intent to avoiO gt;revent• or gt;bstruct c gt;rnol i ance. in ~hole gt;r in gt;art ith an investiq3tive deTI~nd dJl v anj oroperly m~de under this section ith,olds. nisrepresents. removes tro~ 3nv ol3ce. conce3Js. covers u gt destroys. mJtilates. 3lters. or by otner neans falsifies 3ny docunent3rr nateri3J nswers to written i,terroqatories gt;r oral n gt; 3tte nots t:&amp;gt; jO s gt; or solicits tn gt;trier to do so sh3 l l Jpon conviction thereof ~e fined not more tn~ n $S.JOD or inprisonea not nore t11n one (ll ve.:ir or gt;otn i sucn civil i1v~stiqative jem3na upon anv person gt;r 3t ~nv tiTie before the return date specified in the jenand hicnever oerioo is sh:&amp;gt;rter. or ~ithin such period exceedinq 20 davs after service or in e x:ess of su:h return aate as nav gt;e prescri gt;ed in investiqator n3med in t~e denand. su:n perso'l n~y 15 file. 1n tne Suoerior Court of t,e District gt;f :olurnoia and serve uoon tne Corpor3tio, counsel 3 Jetition for an order of sucn court nojifyinq or settin~ aside such demana. The tine allowea for :oTipl ian:e witn the aeTiand in •hole or in oart as jeemed orooer ~nd oraerea DY tne Court snall not run jurinq tne penjencv of sue, oetition i~ tne coJrt. e~cept that Suen oerson snall comply •ith 3ny oortion of tne aemana not souqnt to oe Tiodified or set aside. such petition shall specify each qrounj upon wni:h tne petitioner relies i, seekinq such rel iet. ana m3y oe oasea gt;rovisio~s of this section. or uoo nv o nstitution,,tl or gt;tner leqal ri1ht gt;r pri11ileqe I At anv tine durinq •hie, any cust gt;Oian is in :ustodv or control of any jo:unentarv nateri~l or answers to interroqatories delivered gt;r tra1scriots of oral testi~ony qiven oy any oers gt;n i, cornp1 iance witn any such aemand• sucn gt;erson may file. in the Suoerior Court of the 1istri:t of Columoia. ana serve Joon SJcn ust gt;ctia1 3 gt;etition tor an or1er gt;t sJcn :ourt lo requirin1 th erfornance Dy s&amp;lt;.1c ustoaian of 3ny jutv inposed uoon the cus todi3n ov t,is section nv orJc?Oure. otnar tnan 3n action to anf orc 3 aenand oursuant to subse:tion (h or testimonv ta~en or m3terial orod uced un der tnis s~ctio1 or vol&amp;lt;.1ntarily in tne course ot an investioatio1 shall oe exe~pt f~Jm t,e provisions Jf tne Dist rict of Columoia ~ree10~ of Infornation ~ct. aoproved ~arcn 29• 1977 (J l3w 1-q o.c o j e se c 1-1521 C?t g dnd s"'lall o~ 1&amp;lt;e::it corifid ?ntii l n v th orooration :o&amp;lt;.1nsel Detore Jrin~i1q an action aqainst a per;o1 Jnjer tnis c haote r tor the violation unjer inve st iqati on Jnless confiJe 1tial ity is ~aivea by or~ouced m~terial n mlteri-31 gt;r i nforna tion proauced Jn::Jer tnis se:ti o1 nav oe disclos e o by the :orporation :ounsel to any officer or emoloyee of any feaeral or state l~w enfor:enent aqencv &amp;lt;.1pJn tne prior ce rtification of an officer of Jnv SJCn feoeral gt;r state l3# enforcement aqency t"'lat su:n testi nonv• na teri a l. or infornation will De 11ai1taineo in l7 contidan:e a,d will oe usea gt;nly f:&amp;gt;r official la enforcemant ourposes l unless otherwise autnorizej gt;r raauirea oy law. any amoloyee of the District of Columoia ~ho shall intentionally jisclose infornation Kept co1fidanti~l Dy su:&amp;gt;section (1&amp;lt snail Da quilty of nisdemeanor ~unisnaole Dv a fine uo to ssoo Sec. 28-450b riminal Enforcenent Dv tne District of Columoia E~erv oarson no violates secti:&amp;gt;ns 28-4502 or 28-4503 gt;t t'"tis chapter shall oe quiltv of a nisdamaanor. and gt;n c gt;nviction tharaof. snall oa gt;u,ished Dv a tine not e1&amp;lt;ceeai1q S5Q.OJO. or ov imorisonnent not e1&amp;lt;ceeainq one (ll year. or gt;Oth• Th e Corp:&amp;gt;ration :ounsel Shdl 1 conmen:e ana try all gt;r:&amp;gt;secJtions for violations of sectiJns 28-4502 or 28-4503 nenevar a corporation violates sectio1s 28-4502 gt;r 2 5J3• the indivijual directors• ofticers, or aqents of sucn corporation no nave inte1tionallv ~uth:&amp;gt;rized. oraerej gt;r ratifiea the acts constitutinq sucn violation snail De ounish~ble in accordance witn this saction lt;1 18 e 2B-45Q7. o~maqes and i1JJn:tive relief For in1uries to or witnin the Oistri:t of :olumoia. ft 3 n?never tne District of CJlumoi iovern11ent is in1urea in its ousinass or pro~ertv oy a violation of this cnaoter. the :orooration :ounsel may or i n i a civil action in tne naTle of aporoor i ate injunctive or otner eaui taol e rel i 2f• uistrict of :olumbia to orinq siTiilar or identical 3Ctions unjer anv Jtner statute. In s.Jcn an action. in ajaitio1 to any aoprooriate inJun:tive or equit:ible reli?f. th e court 11ay iward the J istri:t of :olu~bid aamdqes ana t,e cost of suit. incluain i re~son3ble attor1ev•s te~s gt Tna Coroorat1on Counsel ~av gt;rin~ a i11il :tction in the name of tn~ Jistri:t of Columbia as oarens oatriae on Denalf of any injivijudl resiain i in tne District of Columoia in :i nv :ourt of comoetent j.Jrisji:tion for injury sustai1ej Dy sucn individual to such irioiviaual9s or~oartv by reason or any viol:ition ot tnis h aoter. 19 II l T~e court snall a#ard tne District of Colum~i as Tionetary reliet. tnraefold tne total 13 ·Tiaqes sustai le I oy sucn "latural oersons. and tne cost of suit. includinq reasonable 'lttorn e y•s faes 2 ction unaer tnis suosection snail A) De aistriDute I in suc"l Tianner as tne court mav autnorize; or Bl be leemed a civil oenaltv by the court and deposited witn the District of Columoia. subject in either case to tne requireTient tnat any jistri~ution pro:edures aaopted shall first aftora eacn oerson a reasonaDle opoortunitY co secure eacn sucn oerson's aJorooriate portion of the n~t ~onetary rel iet l) In any action brouqnt u1aer suosection (D the orporation Counsel shall. at sucn times. in suc"l Tianner. an I with sucn content ~s tne court may direct• cause notice to be qiven DY publ icati:&amp;gt;n. It the court finas tnat notice qiven solely by ouolication woulj je"ly aue process of law to any oerson or oersons. t"le court snal I l, 20 jirect fJrtner notice to sue~ oerson or oersons 3ccoroin~ to tne cir:umstances of th e :ase 2 Any Person on whose behalf an 3Ction is orouqht under subsection gt mav elect to e ~cluje froTI ad judication tne oortion of tne Distri:t of :olumoia claim for monet3ry relief 3ttriDJt3ble to that person by fil inq ,oti:e of s u c h election ~ith tne court witnin sucn time 3S soacifiej in the notice qiven pursuant to oar3qr iPt'\ I l j) In anv action under suosection (D in ~nicn ther~ nas oeen a oeterTiination tnat 3 jefend3nt violat ed 3 provision ot tnis c n3o t e r. j anaqes n3y oe provej and assessed i, the aqqreqate Dy tne comoutation of illeqal ov e r haries. or DY sucn otner redsonaole systeTI of es tinaci,q aqqreqate oamaqes as th e :oJrt nay ~e rmit ithout the necessity of separately or:&amp;gt;vinq th e inoivi::ludl claim of, or 3mount of J dmdqe to. persons on wnose oenalf t,e suit was or gt;uqht e) The :ourt Tiay awarj unjer this section• Du rsuant t gt; a TIOtion ov the Jistri:t of COiumbia romptly m ~oe. simole interest O'"l 3c~ual oamaqes 21 tor th gt;eriod beqinninq on the j3te of service ot the o lea::linq of the District of :olumoia setti,q fortn 3 clain under this cnaoter and enoinq on tne date of judqnent. or f gt;r any snorter oerio::l therein. if tne court finds that tne a•aro ot sucn interest tor sucn Jeriod is just u,O?r t~e c ircl.lmst:1nces. In deterTiininq wnether an a~ar::l of interest under tnis section for 3ny Jerioa is JUSt un::ler the c ircumstances• tne court s,all consider on 1 y l wnether tne District of Columoi~ or the opposinq oartv• or eitner oartt's reJresentative. made motions or ~ssertea =lains or defenses so lackinq in merit as to Ddd f iith 2 action involved. tne District of Columoia or the gt;poosinq party• or eitner Jartv's statJte. or court oraer orovidin~ for orovidinq for exoeniti:&amp;gt;us oroceeJinqs; and n 22 3) wriether tne District f Columoia r the Jpoosinq p~rtv• or eitner Jartv's reJresentati11e, enqaqed in condu:t oriTiarilv for the ouroose of delayinq tne litiqation or in:reasinq tne CJst thereof S~c. 28-4508 elief far private 0:1rties l) Anv oerson who is in1urej in tnat Jerson•s business or prooerty oy reason at anytninq foroijden ov this cnaoter may orinq a :i11il 3ction for damaqes, for aD:Jropriate in1uncti11e or otner eQuitaole rel ;et. or for ootn• In SJC, an action, in dddition to ~nv aoorooriate in1uricti11e or eqLJitaole relief• the :ourt shall aw .H· j 3 s mo net oi r v re I i e f l) t,reefold trie total 1anaqe SJStained by such person; and (2) as 1etermin ed DY tn ourt• tne cJsts ot suit in:ludin~ reasonable attornev•s tees J JursJ~,t to a Tiotion ov such person oromotly maoe, siTiple interest on a:tual ja~a~es for the oeriod oeqinnin~ on tne aate of service of sucn person's Jleaai,q settinq forth a claim unaer t,is :naoter and enji,q on th~ aate of juaqment r tor anv snort~r Jeri Jo tner~in, if t~e court tinas tnat 23 the ~w3r~ of sucn interest tor sue, Jerioa is 1ust In deternininq wnetner an 3#3rd of interest under tnis section tor 3ny oeri od is just under tne ci rcuinstances. tne court l wnether sucn oerson or the opoosinq 03rtv• or eitner party's reorese~t3tive. made l3:kinq in merit 3S to sno~ th3t sucn 03rty or reoresent3tive 3Ctea intentionally tor aelav• or otner~ise actea in oaa taitn 2 3Ction i,volve1, sucn oerson or tne opoosinq ~iol~ted 3ny aool icaole rule. statute• or co urt or1er Jrovidinq for sanctions tor 1il3tory Oeh3vior or otner~ise orovidinq for exDe'.1itious orocee::iinqs; 3na 3) wnetner such oerson or the opposinq oartv• or either oarty's reorese,tative. en~a~ed in conauct priTiarily for tne puroose of del-iyinq the litiqation or in:reasi,q tne cost tnere:&amp;gt;t \ n n c) 11 anv :lass action brouq1t under tnis se:tio1 oy p~r:nasers or sellers. the fact ot injurv 3na tne a~ount of a~maqes sustainea ov tne meTibers :Jf tne class mdy be Dr:Jven 01 a class--iae :Jasis. wit1out reqJirinq proof of su:n m~trers ov e3:h i1dividLJal menber of the class. The oercantaqe of total jamaqes attribut~ole t'.J 3 nenoer of sucn class snall oe tne sane as tna ratio of suc1 ~enoer•s purcnases or sales to tne ourcnases or s~les of the class as a wnole Sec. 28-450 Indirect our:nasars. nanufa:ture. proju:tion. or jistri:&amp;gt;ution of qooas gt;r ser11i:es. uoo11 or:Jot of pay11ent of -il 1 or any gt;art of an{ gt;vercnarqe for sue, qooas :Jr services. §hal 1 oe deenej to oe injured ~itnin t,e meaninQ of t:ii s :n1oter. II gt In 3Ctions wnere Oot, jire:t and injire:t pur:n3sers are involved. a Jefenaant snall oe entitlej to prove as a oartial or :onplete defense to a claim for Ja11a~es thdt the il leqal ov rchar~e has oeen oassea on to others •h:&amp;gt; are themselves entitled to rac:&amp;gt;v?r so as to av:&amp;gt;ij Juolicatio1 of recoverv of oam~aes 1 25 In any C3Se in wnich claims are asserted the :oLJrt nav transfer and consol i1ate cases tpoortio, aanaqes ana delay disDursenent of :13TI3:les to =tvoid m.Jlti olicity gt;f sLJits 3nO j u:&amp;gt;l ication of recov er y of clamaqeS• ana to ootain suostantial fair'less Sec. JLJOqment in tav:&amp;gt;r of the Ji strict of Columbia as orim3 facie evidence A final jLJOqment or decree determining tnat a Jers gt;n has violated tnis cna:&amp;gt;t~r in an action 28 -4506• other tna'1 =t consent 1ua q11ent or aecrae ent erecJ efore anv testi 11ony at tr i a I rias gt;een taKen or ent e reo pLJrsuant to a Olea Jt nol:&amp;gt; contenaere. shall De ori11a tacie evi::lence dQdinst such oerson in any other action ~gainst such Jers gt;n under sections 28-4508 or 2 509 as to all 11acters ~ith resoe:t t gt nicri tne Jujqnent or aecree w gt;uld oe 3n estopoel oet~ een tne oarties to tn=tt jJdqment or decree S ec 28-4511. r n n 26 1) reco11er 3 crimin3l oen:Jlty is t&amp;gt;arred if tn2 3ction is not commenced witnin four (41 years 3fter tne :ommission of 3n act constitutinq in wnole or in J3rt tne off2nse or ~ronqful action :n3rqed gt 4n action under sections 2 507 or 28 5J8 tJ recover jamaqes is O:Jrrej if tne action is not coTimen:ea ~ithin four (4) ye3rs ~tter tne :3~se of action 3ccrues. or ~itnin one (1) vaar 3fter th onclusion of 3ny tinelv a:tion orouqnt JV tne Oistrict of Columoia under se:tion 28-450b• oased in wnole or in p3rt on a,v m3tter coTiplained of the 3Ction for d~maqes una2r s2ctions 28 5D7 or 28-450 w,i:n e v er is later. 11 S2c. 28- 4512 1) In enforcin q tnis cna ot2 r. tn2 :orporation Counsel ~ay ~cce~t a, 3ssurance ot j isconti,u3nce of an act or oracti:e considered in 11iolation of tnis chapter from any 02rson anqaqed in tne a:t or oractice J) Tne assurance of aisconti,uance snall 02 in writinq and s~al 1 oe effective only uoon tne ~ooroval of tn e Suoerior Court of tn District of :o l u mo i a 27 ~e consijerej for any ~urpose as an 3dTiisSion of a i gt; 1 at ion. Pr gt;of of failure to COTiply witn tne assura1ce of ois:ontinuance is Prina facie e vidence of a &amp;gt;1iolation af tnis cnapter Sec. 28-4')13. Coooeration ~itn feaeral ~0&amp;gt;1ernnent and states. nE~cept as proviaed in sectiJn 2~-4505(K tne :orooratio ounsel mav cooperate tn tne federal 10&amp;gt;1ernnent and tne states in tne enforcement of "Sec. 28-4514 eTieaies cumulative. usec. 28-4515. listri:t of :olumbia tnat in c gt;n~truin~ tnis :n~oter. a c gt;urt of :o~petent 1urisdicrion may use to comoaraole antitrust statutes. Se 28-it516. District of C gt;lUmJi a Antitrust i The r e i s est ab 1 i shed a "D i gt; t r i ct o t :o lumnia Antitrust Funa nereafter reterrea to as 28 "tne FJnj to De gt;perated as a nr:&amp;gt;oriet3ry fund 4itn a; s~ts ,ot to e xceed iSOO.OJO at 3ny tine. Th e fund snall c:&amp;gt;nsist of such SJmS 3S may oe ap~ropri3ted to the fund. such sums as may De tr~nsferrea to tne fund oursuant t:&amp;gt; a court oraer gt;r judqment in an antitrust acti:&amp;gt;n iifts gt;r ~r3nts mad e to suoDort 3ntitrust activities. sucn suns as nay oe r eceived oy tne District gt;f olu:noia as :riminal or ci11il De1'a,ties or i'l recovery of costs and attornev's fees in an 3ntitrust ~cti:&amp;gt;n. 3nd such sums as m~y De receiv ed oy tne Di strict gt;f C:&amp;gt;lumDia ourSJ3nt t:&amp;gt; a \lo 'l- aoDroori3ted monies in tne funa srHll re11ain 3V3 ila gt; le with:&amp;gt;Ut ti SC::t l year li:nitati:&amp;gt;n. Any gt;~l::i 'l c~ in e~c e ss of t'lat allowej tne fun d S'l31l oe deoosit ~o in the ~eneral ~u ~d of tne District gt;f C:&amp;gt;lum:&amp;gt;i::i gt Tne District of :01u~Dia Antitrust Fund sh:il I Je avail aDle for use o v the :orp:&amp;gt;r::ition ounsel for the oavment of costs. ex)enses. and cna r::ies incurr ed in and reasonably related to th e investiqation. preoaration• institution. d'ld a inte~ance Jf d'ltitrust a c tio'ls uno e r t'l e Jistri:t of :olumbia Antitrust A:t ana ~eaeral O)ntitrust la#S c) sn3lJ Je audited annually oy tne M3yJr and re~orted to th ouncil of the District ot :olumoia. Requests for aporoori3tio,s shall oe forw~r1e1 to tne Council of the Qistrict of :olumoia DY the ~ayor in tne S3me Tidnner as Dudqet re~uests for other aqencies Sec. 28-4517. Se11eraoi 1 i tv If 3ny orovision of tnis Ch3oter Jr t,e 3p~lic3tion thereof to anv perso, or circuTistance is h e lJ in113li h tne invalidity joes not aft:?Ct C3, Je qiv~n effect ~ithout the inv3l iJ orovision Jr aJclic3tiJn• an~ to tnis end the JrJvisions ot "Sec. 28-451B. 3PJ1 ic3ole tJ conduct or activity specifically requlatea. oerTiitteo. or requirej Jy any re~ulatory bJdY• aqencv• or :omrnissiJ r ~ctinq olumoia or tne Jnit ?d States r \ \ 30 Se 3 3 suotitle II of title 28 is a~ended DY 3d~i~Q t~e foll:&amp;gt;win~ onr3se to end thereof EST~A.INTS OF TR&amp;amp;\OE 28-4501 DI S3cti on 4 of tne Funj Ac:ountinq Act C:&amp;gt;ae. sec. 47-293) is a'TlenOed as foll gt;ws l Su o s ec t i gt;n 3 2 I i s a ne no e d o v insertinq 3t the eno tnereof tne pnr3s~ to read 35 to 1 I ow s 21 Suosection (3)(2 is imenoed gt;V (3) 5uosection i){ZIC)I 1c Jmended DY striKinq tne oerio1 3t tne end t~ere)f ano by insertinq a se'Tli-colon in I ieu tnereof; and lt u gt; s ec t i gt; n o i s :i men j e 1 d s follows A) bv striKinq tne D?riod 3t tne end thereof and insertinq a se'Tli-c:&amp;gt;l:&amp;gt;n in I ieu thereof; ano (91 bY insertinq tne followinq ne~ suooar3qr3Dn :Jt the ?nd thereof to r?ad as fo l lows 10) Antitrust Fund t:&amp;gt; 3c:ount for the investiQ3tion. oreoarati•n institutio anc D.C.Co::le, sec. 47-293 31 (cl Section 2J4(al of tne District of :olurnoi~ A1 ministr3tive ~r;Jcedure ~Ct• eff~ctive L524(a is 'lmen:ie1 3s f;Jllo s l gt;ara;:ir3pn (6) is anend?ci bv stri.c:inq r:rt ore n1 t rte :Jeri:&amp;gt;d at trte enj th e reof 3n 1 ins e rt1n i trte .Jt1r3se Jn in li eu 1:,ereof inj l t rt i r t y 3 0 la v oe r i gt; d o f on qr es s i o 1 I re i w fol 1 owin i :tpor:&amp;gt;v31 n the ~avor (or in tne event gt;f veto y tne "1:iyor iction Dy the :oJncil gt;f t,e gt;rovided in section ~OZ(cl(l gt;f tne nistrict of D.C.Code, sec. 1-1524 32 r I \ I 1\\ \ \_\ 'j J Cna i rTian J c~uncil Of ne Distri:t/ Ot :olumo•a avor District of :oJu~oia APPROVED: November 25, 1980 i I I CC C B 3-10 7 c~cN: Adopted First Read ing. 1 0/2 8 8 0 £i C!CZ 'IC M a~J.1.0 O r._i l;t._y Al sent: Moore I f :lOt C..\t C7 c C CA I I I I A u c:a c••C I I I I 1 c 1 r e j I ni:-xm.1 I I I i :\ E I I I I 5 1 C J I I I r T '\J I I I I l.SO lt; I I I I 1 5 C i. I I I n Qi I I I I 1008 I I I I t r I I I I l'\V I I I I i v I I i I 1 I I I I 1 t nr i tn Ole ~c~cN A_d~o~p~t~e~d~F~i~n~a~l R~e a=d=i~n~qu l~l 1:2 8~0 J C rC IC Unanimous Aa sen K_a_n_e M_a_s~o~n a~n~d M~o o~r~e {J Ct C.\L IC:Z ac c a ot r. AC CN lj 'IC !C 1 /C Al::lsec RC t c.;r 1IC 7 r w I n </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
