<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-21">
  <num type="law">3-21</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Statute of Limitations Extension Act of 1979</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1979-09-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-21.pdf">D.C. Law 3-21</citation>
      <citation type="register">26 DCR 386</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-21, the “District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Statute of Limitations Extension Act of 1979,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-132, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 5, 1979 and June 19, 1979, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 12, 1979, it was assigned Act No. 3-65 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. LAW 3-21 "District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Statute of Limitations Extension Act of 1979" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill on first and second readings, June 5, 1979 and 1979 respectively. Following the signature of the July 12, 1979, this legislation was assigned Act 3-65, published in the July 27, 1979, edition of the Register Vol. 26 page 386) and transmitted to Congress 18, 1979 for a 30-day review, in accordance with 602 (c l) of the Act. Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and, refore, cites the following legislation as D.C. Law 3-21, ective September 28, 1979 ARRINGTON DIXON Chairman of the Coun·cil Counted Durin the 30-da Period: 18, 19, 20, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27' 30, 31, 1, 2, 3 5, 6, 7, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 24, 25, 26, 27 EDrolled Or iginal 0111 3 2 l I itJ t I 1 1·SE? 2 J iSi3 A~ ACT D.C. ACT3 6 5 I~ THE :auNCIL DF T~E DISTRICT OF CJLUMBIA To extend• on a gt;ermanent oasis. tne period gt;f 1 imitation up gt;n assessment and collection of taxes ad~inisterad under the provisions of the District of Columoia Income anj Franchise Tax Act of 1947. SE IT ENACTEO av THE COU~CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU~8IA. That t,is act nay oe cited as tne "District of C gt;lumoia lncome and Francnise Tax Statute of Li~itati gt;ns Extension Act of 1~79 Sec. 2. Section 10 of Title XII )f tne District of :olumbia Income anj Franchise Tax Act gt;f 1947• approved J uly lo• l9Ct7 l Stat. 354; D.c. C gt;de. sac t7-l58o i as amended. i s further amended as follo~s a) Suosect i on (a) is amended oy striking out tna )hrase a) General Rule Exceot as or gt;vided in suosecti gt;n (D gt;f triis section and insertinq the gt;hrase a) General ~ule Except as provided in subse:t i ons &amp;lt gt;&amp;gt c)t (j) and (e) of tnis section in lieu thereof b) 4 new suosection (a) is adje:2 to raad as f gt;llo s e) Extension of Period of Limitation If t ne am~unt of taxaDle inco~e for any taxable year ~r part thereof f any tax~ayer as daclarej ~Y sucn taxpayer or n is ~olled Original z duly autnorized 3qant to the Unitej States Treasury ~part~ent f~r Federal income tax ourposes is changed or correctej ov tne Commissioner of Inter,al ~e~enue. or oy any court of the unitej States. or by any :ourt of the District ~f Col~moia or if the amount of taxaole incone for any taxaole year or oari tnereof of any taxpayer as jeclared by such taxoayer or his duly auth~rized agent to the District of Columoia for Oistrict of :olu~oia i,come or franchise tax ourposes is chanqe1 or corre=ted by any court of tne United St3tes or oy any court of the Oistri:t of :olumbia. such taxpayer or nis july autnorized aqent shall. witn i n ninety davs after such cnanqe or correction is finally jetermined. report in Nritinq such cnanged or corrected taxaole incoTie District of Columoia. The ~avor or his duly 3uthorized representative may Nithin one hunared and eignty ~avs froTI the date of the receipt of written notice from tne taxpayer or nis duly autnorized aqenc ~f sucn cnan~ed ~r orrected taxable income as fi,ally jetermined. assess or t!Ssess tne amount of any tax iTiposed oy this article: JVIOEO, HO~eve That. in the event tne date of receipt ov District of :olumbia of a noti:e from the taxpayer or july aut,orizect aqent is m~re th~n one hundred and iqhty days Jrior to tne expiration ~f the aJplicaole oeriod f limit~tions provided for in sucse:tion (a f tnis Enrolled Original 3 section. tne Mayor or nis duly aJtnorized reoresentative shall ,ave until the expiration of SJC1 apolicable perioa to reassess the a~ount of any tax inposed by this Failure to report such changed or corrected taxable incone as finally determined with the tiTie stated susoend the runninq of tne oeriod of linitation of one ~undred and eighty days after tne jate from tne taxoayer or his auly autnorizea agent received oy the District of Columoia For tne purooses of t~is suosection. tne words •fin~Jly ~etermined• nean a~v irrevocable deternination or 3djustnent tne taxoayer•s 1 iabil ity for ta fron ~hicn there exists fJrther riqnt of appeal or review. either administr~tive r judicial. This suosection shall apJly with resoect to oe~inning on or after Ja~uary l• 1975 Enrolled Original 4 Sec. 3. This act snall take effe:t pursuant to the or~visions of section b02(c)(l) of tne District of C~lumoia Self-Government and Govern~ental Reorganization Act. I o~f t~h!l J~i s h: i a APPROVED: July 12, 1979</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
