<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-45">
  <num type="law">3-45</num>
  <heading type="short">Realty Violations Correction Fund Act of 1979</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1980-01-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-45.pdf">D.C. Law 3-45</citation>
      <citation type="register">26 DCR 2305</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-45, the “Realty Violations Correction Fund Act of 1979,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-136, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 25, 1979, and October 23, 1979, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 9, 1979, it was assigned Act No. 3-123 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE l 1979 O. C. LAW 3-45 "Realty Violations Correction Fund Act of Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Colw4bia adopted Bill No. 3-136, on first and second readings, September 25, 1979. and October 23, 1979 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on Novemoer 9, 1979, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-123, published in the November 23, 1979, edition of the D.C. Register, {Vol. 26 page 2305) and transmitted to Congress on November 19, 1979 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 {c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and, therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 3-45 effective January 5, 1980 r IXON Chairman o the Coun il Datls Counted During the 30-day Consressional Review Period: NovE$nber 19, 20, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30 December January 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 17, 18, 21, 24, 26, 27, 28, 31, 2, 3, 4, 20 D.C. lAW 3•f4 5 v' JAN 0 5 1980 t 4 4 Enrolled Original AN ACT D.C. ACT 3 1 2 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOV 0 9 1979 To amend the Act to provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes, to authorize the Mayor of the District of Columbia to correct conditions on real property violative of law and to establish a speciat revolving fund for the purpose of financing the correction of such conditions, and for other purposes. BE IT ENACTED 8Y THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Realty Violations Correction Fund Act of 1979 Sec. 2. Section 1 of An Act to provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes, approved April 14, 1906 (34 Stat. 11 o.c. Code sec. 5-313) is ·amended to read as follows: I w(a) Whenever the owner ~f any real property in the r&amp;gt;istrict of Columbia shall fail or. refuse after the service of reasonable notice ir the manner provided in section 3 of this Act (O.c. Code• sec. 5-315) to correct any condition t F.nrolled Original 2 which exists on or has arisen from such Ii· property in violation of law or of any regulation made by authority of law. with the correction of which condition said owner is by law or by said -regulation chargeable. or to show cause. sufficient in the judgment ~f the Mayor of said District. why he should not be required to correct such condition. then. and in ·that instance. the Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to~ cause such condition to be corrected; assess the cost of correcting such condition and all expenses incident thereto (including the cost of publication. if any. herein provided for) as a tax against the property on which such condition existed or from which such condition arose. as the case may be; and carry such tax on the regular tax rolls of the District. and collect such tax in the same manner as general taxes in said District are collected: PROVIDED. That the correction of any conditjon aforesaid by the Mayor of said District under authority of this section shall not relitve the owner of the property on wh..f ch such r 7 3 condition existed. or from which such condition arose. fro~ criminal prosecution and punishment for having caused or allowed such unlawful condition to arise or for having fatled or refused to correct the same b}(l) There is hereby established in·the District of Columbia ·a permanent revolving fund which shall be available without fiscal year limitation. for the purpose of paying the costs of correction of any condition. and all expenses incident thereto. that the Mayor may order or -cause pursuant to subsection (a Z) There shall be deposited to the credit of the fund such amounts as may be appropriated r for the fund or for the purposes of the fund; qrants from any source to the fund or to the District of Columbia for the purposes of the fund; interest earned from th~ deposit or investment of monies of the fund; amounts assessed and collected as a tax against real property pursuant to subsection a including any interest and any penalties thereon, dr otherwise received to recoup any amounts! incidental expenses or costs incurred lt I t 4 obligated or expended for the purposes o~ 1 the fund; and all other receipts of whatever nature derived from the operation of the fund 3) The Mayor shall include in the budget esti~ates of the District of Columbia for each fiscal year. and ·there are authorized to be aporopriated annually. such amounts out of the revenues of the District of Columbia as nay be necessary for the capitalization of the fund 4t Not later than six (6) months after the end of each fiscal year, the Mayor shall submit to the Council of the District of Columbia a report of the financial condition of the fund and the results of the operations and collections for such fiscal year. Said report should include. but not be 1 imited to, the itemized amounts of unrecovered taxes and penalties. the names of delinquent property owners, and the nature of corrected building violations t gt o r z fl z i T i 5 Sec. 3. This act shall take effect as provided fo~ acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section J b02(c)(1) of the District of Columoia Self-Government and Govern~ental Reorganization Act. APPROVED: November 9, 1979 l \ l t \ CClmNClll Of Tir!E DI ST~~Cl OF COlBitA E:a&amp;amp;eDJ m: m=Rrn mimcn.ACnm ooett: NO: Bill 3-136 t I l: To Adopt (9- 25-79) I VOIC% l/O?I 1.IJJ;In~a i.Pl..li~m:u,Q~lli Si AJJ Present u f I 1;:aw•cu HS ¢ C 4»CC f A PW I KANE SrLA.CKI. ETNJ R I MASON SP~ULDTNG I ~OORE wTT C f\f I I I RAY I lt;iT A c j To Aciopt l Q-?3-79) I/CIC~ I/OT Unanimous Aesem: All Present •MA I t t I c• t P' t I I I I I ror..n I I I C A n M \&amp;gt;\ I I I 'A&amp;amp;C:f"\T\T I I I C P A TTT T'\T\11 I j I ~OORE I I rJT1' c:n1 I I I I ~AV I t I I I I I t ~m 1 I I I :i l t IQ&amp;amp 1 ICt I/OT Ab•ecl T I I I I I I I I al I C f t f. I c c:w'9C• I C t t lt t c~•c I 1 t l I I I I vl~ I I I i I I V C:f"\M I I I I I t l'Ar"lr"I gt I I I i i I :f ti v I I I I i I IT _l tlV j I t a.e I I :6HAC"tCT.ETONI I I io? Al1..D ING I t I 1tnr c: rr'r I I i 11 I I I lj i 4 I I I l I I I I I i i i. I I i t I I</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
