<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-65">
  <num type="law">3-65</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Newborn Screening Requirement Act of 1979</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1980-04-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-65.pdf">D.C. Law 3-65</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 1087</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-65, the “District of Columbia Newborn Screening Requirement Act of 1979,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-126, which was referred to the Committee on Human Resources. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on January 22, 1980 and February 5, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 4, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-163 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. LAW 3-65 "District of Columbia Newborn Screening Requirement Act of 1979" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 3-126, on first and second readings, January 22, 1980 and February 5, 1980 respectivel y. Following the signature of the Mayor on March 4, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-163, published in the March 14, 1980, ed i tion of the D.C. Register Vol. 27 page 1087) and transmitted to Congress on March 7, 1980 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Sect i on 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the Di strict of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Co ngressional Review Pe riod has expired, and, therefore, cites t h is enactment as D.C. Law 3-65 effective Apr il 29, 1980. Dates Counted During the 30-day Congress i onal Review Period: March April 7, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 24, 25 26, 27, 28, 31 1, 2, 3, 15, 16, 17, 18, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 28 D.C. LAW 3~ 6 5 EF~T~VE APR 2 0 1980 Alll ACT D.C. ACT 3 1 6 3 1( IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA IAR 04 1sao To reQuire certain screeninq tests to be administered to all infants oorn in hospitals in the Distr ict of Columoia. BE IT ENACTEO SY THE COUNCIL OF THE OIST~ICT OF COLUMBIA Th~t tnis 3ct ~ay oe cited as the "District of Columoi3 ~e~born Screeninq ~equirement 4ct of 1979 Sec. 2. Sec 3. Sec. 4. Sec. 5. Sec. b. Sec. 1. Sec. a. Sec. 9. Sec. 10. Sec. 11. Table of Contents CODIFICATION D.C. Code, Ti tle 6, Chapter 2, Pu r C&amp;gt;O se. Sul:x hapter I I Definitions. D.C. Code, sec. 6-211 Test i nq and Fo 110111-up f gt;r Hypothyroid is 1119 et seq. PKU. and other Metabolic Disorders of the ~ewborn. Principles Governinq ~e~born Screeninq. ComTiittee on Metabolic Oisorders Craated. Duties of tne Committee on Metabolic Disorders. Annual Report to the ~ayor and the Council L3bar3tory Costs. PayTient Authorization. Effective Date D.C. Code sec 6-211 Ii nro 1 z It is the purpose of this leqis13tion to provide flr the ea~y identificatiJn of certain metaoolic disorders in ne~borns in the Oistrict of Columbia s~ that referral and tr 3tmentt where aopro~riate, may oe provided. Unless other~ise specified tne fQllo~ing definitions (a) The ter metabolic disorder" means a dis~rder 'T ~h~ch results in a defact in tne function of a specific en!"y111e or orotein b) The term "hypothyroidisn" me3ns tnose clinical r CO,d i ti OnS which result from aonormally lo~ circulating lelels of thyroid normone c) The ter newoorn" me~ns any infant born in t~e r 0 is tr i ct who is unjer four (4) weeks of aqe. D.C. Code, sec. 6-212 (d) The tern "pnenylketonuria hereinafter referred to s ~PKU eans the metabolic disease of the newoorn in h~ch metaoolites of phenylalanine appear in urine. Sec• 4. 1~tli:!9 Q_f2 2?C\!Q _f~.J:!Yl2£?1t!YrQLl!ll f~t 11d:.QJ;;nec.)1~~boU~Oi ~Llt~LOf bOt[ D.C. Code sec. 6-213 (a) All hospitals in the District of Columbia sna11 3d~inister to all newborns a blood test to screen for yoothvroidism• and PKU. Testinq for other metabolic r d i sorders ~ay 3lso be required if the Mayor so specifies by 3 re~lation. with the advice of the District of Columbia Co~~ittee on Metabolic Disorders bl Eacn test shall be forwarde1 to a single laooratory de~iqnated by the ~ayor. The designated laboratorv must be ~n~ whicn is currently certified by the College of American oa~holoqists and regularly participates in tne appropriate ~u itv control progra~ for such testing by the College or is ~urrently certified by the United States Center f~r Oi~ease :ontrol and regularly participates in the r poropriate quality control proqra1 for such testing by the r Ce~ t er or has a federal license under the Clinical La~ oratories l~prove~ent Act of 19&amp;amp;7, approved Oecemoer 5 1q'7 (81 Stat. 536; 42 u.s.c. 2o3a wnic:h permits tne la oratory t:&amp;gt; solicit 3nd acceot in interstate c:&amp;gt;m.nerc2 hu~an specimens for the ourpose of performing clinical l3~oratory examin3tions, for the purpose of detecting ~e abolic disorders c) All test results shall be returned to the hospital he re the aaov w3s born. In addition. all positive test •T results shall oe returned to the parent 3nd to a physician desiqn3ted by the District of Columbia government. The 7 ohvsician shall assist a parent and ner physician in securinq aopropriate follo~-up testinq and treatment wnen i n i C3tea 4 Sec s. fd l eLGo~r.nLag e-b2£~Scurn.n i ng. The fl1avor sha 11 insure that a) Carriers of metabolic disorders should not be st i q mat i zed 3nd should not be discrininated against oy any ~erson within the Oistrict of Columbia b) District of Columbia policy regarding metabolic 1 i s orders should be made with full public knowledge. in r o.c. Code, sec. 6-214 1 i 1ht of expert ~pinion. and shoul~ oe periodically reviewed to consider chanqing medical kno~ledqe and ensure full ou~l ic protection c) Participation of persons in metab~lic disorder r or J qra~s in the District of Columbia should oe wholly vo•untarv• and tnat all information obtained from pers~ns -r in volved in Tietabolic disorder proqr3ms in the District of :o•umbia should be held strictly c~nfijential. except as or ~vided for in oaraqraph (4t; and tnat in carryinq out the andate of this suosection the M3yor snall further insure r th3t 1 o test be performed on any newborn over tne r b e ctions of his or her parent and that no test be -r-v- oer f or~ed unless such parent is fully informed of the lt our~ose of testinq for metabolic dis~rders. and is given a 'W" re3 s onable ooportunity to object to such testing; 5 (Z o program requires ~andatory participation r restr i ction of childbearing. or be 3 prerequisite to p el~qibility for. or receipt of any other servi ce or 3ssi st3nce from or to particip3tion in any other progr3m 3) All oarticipants in pr~qrams on metaoolic di s orders oe protected fro~ undue physical or mental h3rm be inforTied of tne nature of risks involved in participation in s uch a or~qram or project e inforTied of the nature and e CO ~t of available therapies or maintenance programs for those affected by metabolic disorders, and be informed of th oossible benefits and risks of such therapies and or gt;q ra11s; and (4) Except for statistical data compiled witnout re rence to the identity of any i11dividua1. all infor:nation ob ined fro:n any individual. or fro~ specimens from any e ~e~born shal l be held confidential a11d oe considered a co~f idential medical record except f~r sucn information as th J oarent consents to be released. Tne parent wust be in~ormed of the scope of the inforTiation requested to oe re·eased and tne purpose for releasinq sucn information or i or to the release of 3ny confid2nti:1l information Sec. 6 omm i tt~_Q!L~Uru:?li£_Qi~r&amp;lt;1~L£ 1· D.C. c.crle f sec. 6-215 (a) Tne Com11ittee on Metabolic Disorders nereinafter re'erre&amp;lt;1 to as the "Co~mittee snail be co~posed of nine 6 \ 91 members. The members shall oe aopointed by the ~ayor Each member shall serve a term of three (3) years or until his or her successor is appointed and qualified. eKcept that r in the initi31 aopoint~ents three (3) members sh311 serve for one (1) vear. three (3) members for two (2) years and t thr~e (3) me~bers for three (3) years. No member shall oe r ~p3ointed to more th3n three (3) consecutive three (3) year terms. The members of the Com~ittee shall serve witnout co11pensation b) Four (4) ne~bers of the Comnittee sndll be consumer .IC embers. A consumer is defined 3S a person who is not a he~1th professional. nor involved in the administration or w~ershio of any health care institution or hedlth insur3nce .I" or~3nization. nor the spouse of a health professional ad~inistrator. or owner. Two (2) of tne consumer Tiembers sh~~l oe aopointed from a list of five (5) names submitted to the M3yor by the District of Columbia Association for e~arded Citizens. Inc. Five (5) of tne members of the o~mittee shall be non-consumers. Four (4) of the non co~sumer memoers shall be licensed physici1ns knowledgeaole in the diaqnosis 3nd tre~tment of netaoolic disorders. 4t le~st one (1) of the physicians sh3ll be eitner 3 geneticist or an endocrinoloqist. The Director of the Oeoartment of 7 r Yuman Resources. or his or her designate. sh3ll serve 35 an. 7" ex ~off icio n~n-voting member of the Committee c) Wnen a vacancy on the Com~ittee occurs for any re~ son other than the norm31 e(piration of a term of office. t: 3 ~8 ~ber shall be promptly appointed. to complete the :r. un expired term of the resiqninq me~ber. The replaceTient I e~ber shall be selected in the sa~e manner as outlined i n su s ecti on (t&amp;gt d) The Mayor shall aopoi~t a c~a i rperson from among th meTibers of tne Committee to serve from the time of tne Co ~mitte e formation until December 31st of the year of the formation of the C~mmittee. Tnereafter the ~ayor. each ve 1r. shall appoint a chairperson to serve a one (1) year te r m to run from January 1st to QeceTiber 31st of eacn year e) Tne full Committee shall meet at least twice ~ach ve 1r. Business Tiay be conducted if a ~ajor i ty of the e ~bers are oresent. Sec. 7. O~ties of the ComTiittee on ~etaboiic Disorders The Committee shall a) Gather and disseminate information to further the ou ic's und~rstanding of metaoolic disordersi (b) Consult the public. espec i ally co~mittees and ti' qr o~ps of oerson~ particularly affected by metabolic jisorder proqrams D.C. Code, sec. 6~216 8 (c) Make availaole to the public information on the r paration of all proqrams on metabolic disorders within the r Oistrict of Columbia, except for confidenti~I information d) Reevaluate on a continuous oasis the need for and ef'icacv of 3dministerinq the olood screening test for {' hyJothvroidism, and PKU to all newoorns in tne District of (e) Recommend to the ~ayor any additional screening I test s for ~etabolic disorders that snould oe added to those ,4 re ~uired under section 4 (a f) Recommend to the Mayor any screening tests for eL a bolic disorders required under s~ction a) that should be deleted Q) Consider the incidence of eacn metabolic disorder 301 the cost of detection 3nd TianaqeTient of each metabolic di~order. anj where appropriate cons~lt. District of co~umbia and national experts concerning tne medical i:&amp;gt; s ·i c ho 1 o q i c a 1 et h i c a 1 soc i a 1 and econ om i c e f f e ct s of I roqra~s for the detection and management of metab~lic 7 1isorders h) Keeo the Mayor informed as to new and prove techniques f~r screeninq and testing newborns for -etaoolic disorders; and } i Recoinmend to the Mayor the single 1 :tbor:ttory where· th~ screeninq tests for metabolic disorders will be f" oerfor11ed. Sec a llllLReoort_!2._UHL~'lQL~Lt.t!~CoY £ L• The Committee sh3 11 submit to the ~ayor 3nd the Council on. January lst of each year a report summ3rizing the lC~ivities of the Committee, and containinq 3ny d to the uavor and the Council which tne re comm·m at' ons n nec:ess~ry reqardin~ Droblems of ~etaooli 011m it tee deems disorders. Laboratory costs of the screeninq tests shall be borne by the District of Columbia qovern~ent. No hospital may f' Ch 3rqe f~r tne test There is hereby authorized to De aoprooriated out of the ~e~eral revenues of the District of Columbia qovernment su~ficient funds to carry out the requiremants of this act in ~ludinq tre3tment when the parent is unaole to pay f~r it This act shall take effect on Jctooer l. 1980. after a th~rty (30) day oeriod of Congressio~al review following 1poroval by thg Mayor (or in the event of veto by the ~ayor ction oy the Council of the District of Columoia to D.C. Code, sec. 6-217 D.C. Code, sec. 6-218 D.C. Code sec. 6- 219 10 ov e rride the veto) as provided in section b02(c)(l) of the ¥ i s trict of :olumbia Self-Govern~ent and Governmental e~rqanizati~n Act. approved Oecemoer 24• 1973 (87 Stat. r a1 o.c. Coae. sec. 1-147(c)(l \ the Oistric~ of Columbia ~avo ~i trict of Columbia APPROVED: March 4, 1980 CCUJNClll OF me DI STlllCT OF COUlllllilA i EARID «JI= GRAa.M mmmt9.M:nml I i oocxrr NO: Bill 3-126 ACUON: To Adou t (1-22-80) Fi r s t Re adipg g V'OtC! VOTE U n~a~n i~rn O~u~s ­ AQseat Spa u l ding and Wils on D aou CAI.I. von cewaczt amp uc C:;IYNC:I c.eca I 6,.Cll C••C:t. TY ll'nN KANE SHACKLE'T'm ltTT~i:'P MASON SPATTT nTNG rr .l 1nr;;o MOORE wTT c::nv lUPTW PAV T t:HTT C! PnT d. PV c 01 \ l a ~l 1 Afll v CtR~ON CF RECORD lt;L c ACT!ON: To Adopt (2-5-80) Final Read i n g S.:Atart ta tp'ounc:il {!i V'O!C! von U n a n i rn o u s uisent C~l~a~r~k~e D R.OU. c.w V'O't amp C.M.a ll i aw,.c:a f. rl n rvn1'T I V A\n C::U 6 VT l T"(i~ T.f 1"1 T''l tl VA C::t"'t1"T C gt;l &amp;lt;1 TTT 1'T\1/C l"'T A'QTl'14' MOORE i.f T Cl"'t\T U il. PT'IV PAV TA t&amp;gt; U C 1uir A 'QTl' l 111 ica•P1 ·1 l t r u tSlilJllC cz.,m~c ON O r !\ZCCa::l .C\ ecratary ca t!l~uac:il ACTION D l/O!et: VOT D ROU. CALI. VO 40 9C C C d c \lllOC!'I c:oie•&amp;amp;11 I lnr mN v I SHACKLETON I i TJT &amp;gt;.J'l''l Q i M A C!l'\'llT PATIT.DING I I I f'1 t&amp;gt; V'l I \.(l'\l'\t)1 IW°TT C::nf\T I I i I 'Q 1 0T'IV I t&amp;gt v I I I I I T A t&amp;gt;U C! t&amp;gt;l"IT \ 1'V I I I I 1c t 4 Q J..0 </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-831"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-832"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-833"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-834"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-835"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-836"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-837"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-838"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-839"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-840"/>
  </section>
</document>
