<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-81">
  <num type="law">3-81</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1980-08-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-81.pdf">D.C. Law 3-81</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 2632</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-81 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-236, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 22, 1980 and May 20, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 4, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-195 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> I \ 1 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 3-81 "District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Amendments of 1980 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 3-236, on first and second readings, April 22, 1980 and May 20, 1980, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 4, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-195, published in the June 20, 1980, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 27 page 2632) and transmitted to Congress on June 10, 1980 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c}(l} of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and, therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 3-81 effective August 7, 1980. r. £&amp;gt I ARRINGTON DIXON Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: June 10,ll,12,13,16,l7,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30 July 1,2,21,22,23,24,25,28,29,30,31 Aug ust 1,4,5,6 \ D.C. LAW 3-40! 01 EFFl:CTIVE Au~ CATE 7 197D AN ACT D.C. ACT3 1 9 5 1N T~E CJU~CIL OF THE DIST~ICT OF CDLU~BIA JUN 0 4 1980 To 3mena the orovisions of the District of :olumoia Government Comprenensive ~erit Personnel Act of 1978• o.c. La~ 2-139. witn respect to tne rate of comoensation oaid to me~oers of ooaras and commissions; tne 3poointment of attorneys; the tr3nsfer of oersJnnel 3nd cases from tne Boara of Laoor Relations to tne Puol ic Employee Re13tions 6o3rd; tne temoorarv continu3tio, of autnority in tne Mayor to near administr3tive oersJnnel 3p~e3ls; tne provisions of Title XXIII rel3tinq to disaoil ity compensation; and for ot ler ouroosas. 3E IT EN ACTED 9Y THE COU~CIL OF TH~ OIS T~ICT O~ COLUMBIA• That t~is act may oe cited as the "District of Columoia Government Co~prenensive ~erit Personne l Act Am e naments of 1980 Se 2. The District Of Co lurnoi a Government onprene,sive ~erit Personnel Act of 1978• effective ~arch 3. 1979 (O.c. La~ 2-13q: o.c ode s e c l 3 3 l L i s amend ed a s f o 1 l J w s a) Section 202(c) is amende:l to r eaa as tallows X)DIFICATir D.C.Code, sec. 1-332 2 lt;c&amp;gt; Exce:&amp;gt;t as Qtnerwise gt;r:&amp;gt;video i1 tnis act. e3cn neTiber of a board or c:&amp;gt;mTiission intermittent outies is entitlej to p3y as ~rovideo in section 1108 of this act• Full-time emoloyees in accorjance with the provisions of sections 1104 or llll of tnis act embers of boards anj :o~missions are covered oy the Provisions of t i tles XVIII. xx111. xxv. xx1x. xxx. ano xxxI and s e ctions 4 08 a~d 8Jl(e) of this act and shall. if e l i qi bl e under tne terms of an a::ireenent entered into by the ~avor and a federal ~qency unoer the gt; rovisions of titl e XXVIII of this a:t. oe covered oy tne provisions of titles xxI. xx11, and xxYI of this a ct. Tnis section shall not apolv to coTipensation rec e ived oy tne Board of Eoucation as or gt;vi de o in section 1110 of this act b) Section 204-(c) is amenaea oy stri1&amp;lt;inq the gt;hrase "VIIIA or section 904" anj insertin::i th e ohrase "VIII~ or sections 904- or 909~ in lieu thereof Cl Section 30l(o) is amende :J to read as fo ll gt;ws D.C.Code, sec. 1-332.4 D.C.Code, sec. 1-333.1 3 D) The term 'Do~rjS and cJmnissions• TJeans ooaies established by la or by gt;raer Jf the ~avor of tne District of Columoi 1 conSistinq of aooointej nenbers to perform a trust or exec~te of f i c i 3 l f u n ct i on s on oe n a 1 f of t n e J i st r i ct of Columbia Qovernment Co:npens3tion or rei moursement of expenses, if 3nv• to such mernoe rs snall De oro~idea according to sectiJn 1108 Jf tnis act: PRJVIOEO O~EVE Tn3t full-time emo l oyees snall De oaij in accoraance Nith tne orovisio,s of sections 1104 or 1111 Jf tnis ict d Section 503 is amenaea ov :hJnqinq tne ,e 3 din~ tn 2reof to "Tr3nsition Procedures" 3nd by adJinq at the ena of tne section an suose:tion (c) to reaj as follo.,s c) All :3ses oendinq oefore t'1e Boara Puol ic Enolovee ~elations Boarj on t,e ~ffective jate of titles v and XVII of tnis iCt 3S Jr e scrioec Dy se:tion 3602(1) of tnis 3ct Tne any su:n tr3nsferrea case. snall taK su c n ~ction e l a tiJns ours~ant to laoor-nana~enent relations D.C.Code, sec. 1-335.3 J -tt- orJqraTis as they existed wnen the case was filed• incluoin~ those oroqra~s referrej to in section 32J7(3) of tnis act e) Section ~Ol(f) is amendej to read 3S follows f) Each memOer of the Office is entitled to co~pensation at the rate of one nunore1 twenty-five aollars (Sl25) oar die~ or fifteen 1oll3rs sixty-two cents (Sl5.62) oer hour ~hicne~er oroviaes less. wnile actuallv in tne service of t~e Office. Should a memoer serve in excess of eiqht (8) nours on a p3rticular day. such memoer Tiav oe p3i1 3adition3l comoenS3tion for such period of service. to 3 maximum of two {2) oer 1iem paynents for anv consecJtive twenty- four (24) nour oeriod djustment to such rates of comoe1sation shall De made in 3ccordance Nith sectio1 1108(b) Jf tnis act fl Section 703(3) is 3mendej DY strikinq tne onrase "conditions 5ll(C ano inserting tne ohrase "conditions as provided under section Sll(dl~ in lieu thereof. D.C.Code, sec. 1-336.l D.C.Code, sec. 1-337.3 -5 q) Section 60l(e)(3) is a~end2a by stri&amp;lt;inq the onrase "of p3raqraoh (3 30d insert.inq cn2 onr3se "of oaraqraoh (2 in 1 ieu th e reof h) Section B01A is amended as fJllows 3 in suosection b 2)(0) by strikinq th e ohrase "oaraqraons (l 2) and (3) of this subsection" ana insertinq the onrase "sut&amp;gt;oaraqraons (A S s uos ection 2)(E F ana (G) ov striKinq tne Jhrase "oaraqr3ph (4) of tnis suosection" 3na insertinq th e ohrase "suoparaqraon (J) of this oa raarapn" i, 1 ieu tnereof where~er it aop ears; 30 J (C) in S.Jbsection (d)(3) bv strioc:inq tne Jhrase "Jaraqrapn (3 and inserting tne p,ras a "oaraqra oh (2 in lieu thereof i) Section 902 is amended bv jelecing tne Jnras e 0 se c tion QQ4-(3) and gt of t h is ict" ana insertinq tne phrase 11 sections 9J4(a ina (o lr sectio~ 1C9 of tnis act j\ neto1 se t.ion 909 is acidea at the en:J of tit l e Ix to reaa as follows All ind i viduals hirea as attorn ey s ~Y tne ~avor. a n ~q ency unaer tne o e rso,nel autnority of D.C.Ccx:ie, sec. 1-338. 1- D.C.Code, sec. 1-338.2 D.C.Code, sec. 1-339.2 D.C.Code sec. 1-339.9 I -o- the ~ayor. or 3ny inaeoend ent 3qency snall meet sh3ll en joy su:n eTiployment ri~hts as a re in ~ffect for individU3ls 3Dpoint ed as attorneys oy t n e ~avor. an aqency under tne perso~nel autnority of t ne Mayor, or an indeoendent aq en:y on oeceTiber 31, 1979 K) section 1108 is amendea to r ea a as f 01 l ow s a) Eacn memoer of any ooara or coTimission wno receives compensation or reimoursement of e~penses on January l, 1990. shall receive such rates of comp~nsation or reim~urs e ment of e~penses as are proviaed in existinq law. rule. requlation or orjer. or in this act. ex:eot as nay oe modifiej from time to tine Dv rules ana requlations ouolis,ea Dursuant to s ection llO D } bl The ~avor of tne District gt;f :olumDia is 3uthorized to estao l isn ov rule and reimoursement of eKpenses for Tienoers of 3ny 003rd or comnission. includinq 3ny board or :o~mission estaDlisned 3fter January l• l98J lt;\ny s uch rul ~s D.C.Code; sec. 1-341.8 -7- 3nj requlati~ns oroposed by the ~ayor Sh311 oe transmitted to tne Council of the District of :olumoia for a tnirty (30) day (ex:ludinq Saturaays. Sundays. nol idavs• and days on #hicn the Council of tne District of columoi3 is on recess) review period. such rules a,a requl3tions snall oecone effective only if tne Council of tna Distri:t of Colu~bi3 does not ddOpt. witnin tnirty (3D) a3ys (excludinq S3turdavs. sund3ys. hol id3YS• 3nj days on ~hicn tha Council of t,e District of :olumbia is on recess) fro~ tne date of the ~3vor•s suomission. 3 resoluti~n diS3porovinq such rules 3nd requlations in whole or in part otwit,standinq the orovisions of se:tion ~05 of this act. rules 3nd requlations ouolisned under this Subsection shall De effective no earlier than thirty (30) days after tneir publication i~ the 1 Sect i on l l l l c i s a ne n d ea D v st r i I( i n q t n e oh r3se "fear or" 3nd insartinq tne p,r3se fed r of" in lieu thereof m) Section lll2(b) is a:nenaed Dy stri'&amp;lt;inq tne ohr3se as provided in section 3~02 1 2) 30 1 3 D.C.Code sec. 1-341.11 D.C.Code, sec. 1-341.12 a n) Section lll2(c) is amended tJ re3d as l follows A3jJstments to the rate of co~pensation orJvided in this saction snaJl be na3e in 3ccord3nce witn section 1108(0) Jf t,is title o) Sectiori l203(m)(2) is 3mende:l DY StriKinq tn~ reterence "601 gL~9 3n3 inserting the refererice "6J8" in lieu thereof. CPI Section 2306 is amended to read as follows c) a partially diS3blea emoloyee who l refuses to s eeK suitable work 2) refuses or neqle:ts to worK 3fter suit~ole worK is offered to. pro:urea Jy or secured for nin or her• is not entitled to :onpensation a110 sucn oavment shall Je susoenae:l q) Section 2307(c)(5) iS anend~a DY striKinq the ohrase "one ,unarea six (1J6 ana inserting the Jnrase "one nundrea sixty (l~Ol" in li~u thereof nal D.C.Ccxie, sec. 1-341. JX D.C.Code, sec. 1-342.3 D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.6 D.C.Code, sec. J.-353.7 D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.10 _q- insertinq the ohrase otwitnstandin~ Jaraqr3ph (2 in lieu tnere:&amp;gt;f S) Secti:&amp;gt;n 2313(D) is amenjed to read as follows If an indivijual witnout g:&amp;gt;oj cause fails to a:&amp;gt;ply for and underqo vocational re~a~ilitaton when so directed u,der secti:&amp;gt;n 230~ of tnis title. tne Mayor may revie• su:h failure unjer section 2328 of this title. If the ayer JOon review• f injs tnat in the aosen:e of sucn failure the waqe-earninq capacity of tne injivijual w~uld prooaDly nave s~bstantially increased. tne ~ayor may reduce gt;rosoectivelv the nonetarv comoensation of tne individJal in accord3nce witn what would prooaolv ,ave been nis or h e r w~Q e-earnin~ caoacity in the absenc e of the f a ilur until such time as the individual in qood faitn :onol ies witn the direction of tne Mayor t) Secti:&amp;gt;n 2316(3)(4) iS anenaea DY striking th e gt;hrase "suoc~aoter II" ana i,serti,g t~e onrase "su ocnaoter III" in 1 ieu ther ~of u) Secti gt;n 23lt&amp;gt;(D) is amended )y strikinq the onrase gt;urcnased entirely by em:&amp;gt;loy ee contri:&amp;gt;utions D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.13 D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.16 D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.16 10 v) Section 2317(3) is amenjej ~Y strikinq the ohrase "first tw 2) days" 3nj insertin~ the ohrase "first tnree (3) d3ys w) Section 2318(al is a11enOed DY stri1&amp;lt;inq tne ohrase "oaraqraDn (l and inserti~q tne pnrase "subsection (a in 1 ieu thereof a,d Dy striKinq th e ohrase other tnan those referr~a to in suoparaqraon (Bl x) Section 232l(f} is aTiendad ov stri~inq the th e ohrase "subsections (c) throuq f ii lieu ther eof y) Se:tion 2322 is 3mendej oy striKin~ out tne nuTit&amp;gt;er a iqhte en (18&amp;gt and inserti,q t ne nuTI Da r "twantv-one (21 in 1 ieu tne re of z) Secci gt;n 2324(0)(2) is aTiena aa bY insertin~ imTiedi3t e lv followinq tne ~ord "proceaur e tne pnras e "or ov t,e p r o~isions of tn e )istri:t of :olu~Dia Administrative Proc8aur e (a 3) Section 2328 is amendej ~Y a aa inq 3t tne D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.17 D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.18 D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.21 D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.22 D.C.Code, sec. l-353.l4 D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.28 ·i I 1 1 l I -11 c) Notwithst~ndinq suose::tion (b) of tnis section. an action in wnich tne unite t3tes Jeoartnent of Laoor (or Other fe:1eral autnoritv) oarticipateo at anv St3Qe of tne aajJOication allowinq or denvinq oavment under this title oursua,t to 3n aqreement witn the District of :olumoia is l final and conclusive for all ourposas and witn respect to all q~estions of la 2) not suoject to review oy 3 ourt ov m3ndaTius or other~ise DD) Section 2332 is amended oy inserting imTiedi3tely followinq the onrase "sh3ll refund to the J i st r i ct of Co 1 u mb i 3 q over nm en t t e on r as e "tne amoJnt of comoensation oaia Dy the District of Columoi3 qovernnent ano by striKinq tne gt;nrase 1istriouti::rn. an amount" and insertinq tne gt;hrase "Jistrioution. to retain an aTiount" in lieu thereof c Section 2337(a)(2) is amenjed Dy striKi,q tne pnrase "place irresoe::tive of tne 03sis adooted. tne Mayor may at any tine and insertin~ the ohrase "o13Ce• Irrespective of the J.r,q D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.32 D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.37 I -12- oasis 3dooted. tne Mayor may at any tine in liau thereof Oj) Section 2343 is amended oy strikinq tha ohrase "shall nave such leave restored to nis or ,er creait at no cost to tne eTIPloyee" ana insertinq the ohrase ay have sucn leave restored to his or ner craait" in lieu thereof. Cee) Section 2~02 is amenaea by stri~ing the ohrase "Exceot as orovided in se:tio, 2603 of this act. existinq" and insertinq tne worj "Existing" in l ieJ thereof. {ff) Section 2805 is aoded to read as "Tha ~ayor is autnorize1 to enter into aqreemants witn aooropriate federal aqencies to authorize them tJ continue tne processinq of aoTiinistrative aooeals of oersonnel actions oy )istri:t qovernment emoloyees. until sJcn tine as the rules anj requlations of the Office of tne =moloyee auoeals are issued and tne JrJvisions of title XVI of t,is act oecone effective. Tne aoreement of tne Mayor may orovije for tne existi1q stanaar~s of cause for 1iscipl inary D.C.Code, sec. 1-353.43 D.C.Code, sec. 1-356.2 D.C.Code, sec. 1-358.5 -13- 3Ctions to conti~ue in effect for the :iuration of tne aqreement qq) Sections 3204(f)(l 3205(v l 32J5(y)(l 3205(m l 3205(nn 3205(QQ 32J5(djd)(l 3205(eee and 3205(fff) are ielete:i hn) Se:tion 3207(a) is amended to re30 as follows a) ComTiissioner's Orjer ~o. 70-229 (0rqaniz3tion Order ~o. 25 June 19• 1970; InteriTI Laoor ~anaqement Re13tions PJl icy for the Jniversity of the Jistrict of ColuTibia ay 4• tne ~ules of the District of Columoi3 ~odra of Ed uc3t io n. J3nuary 16, 1978, 24 o 6445-5475; the Seot?mDer 1975 Ar~ory 303rd JOl i:y re13tinq to laJor relations; and any other l3bor-m3n3qement rel3tios oolicv inconsistent wit~ this 3ct 3re jeemed to De Supersede::J oy tnis 3Ct: i:&amp;gt;RQVIDED O~EvE Tnat nothinq herein snail orecluoe tne ~avor. t,e Board of Trustees of th~ Jniv~rsity of the District of :olumbia. the 3o3rd of Ejucation or the Armory 3oard from adootin q ,e• la oor D.C.COde, see:s. 31-1714, 1-11 31-2004, 2-1234, 5-426, 5-617, 49-40 2-103 amp; 32-1319 D.C.COde, sec. 1-362.5 -14- this a:t or with requ13tions issi.Jej gt;y the Public Emoloyee Rel3tions 8o3rd pursuant to tnis act i i Section 3602 is 3mended 3S follows 1) su gt;section (3) is 3menaect oy strikinq the onrase "3nd 907" anct insertinq the ohrase Q07• and 909" in 1 ieu tnereof 2) subsection j) is 3menctect oy strikinq the word "502k" 3nd insertinq the wora "503" in 1 ieu tnereof 3) suosection (1) is amended by insertinq immedi3tely tollowinq the Jhrase "3nd XVII" the ohrase "anct se:tion 32:J3(o 4) subsection (n) is 3menje:J Dy striki,q tne p~r3se "and 907 nct inserting the gt;hrase 907, and 909" in lieu thereof 5) su gt;section (o) is amended oy adding 3 ne follows 14) Section 3203(a) an::i (c} shall oecome effective on January l. l~B:J i i The taole of contents is anenoea bY (l) stri&amp;lt;inq tne pnrase "Transfer of ProoertY and Personnel" ana insertinq the phr3se "Tr3nSition Procedures" in liei.J tnereof 2) actdinq a ne section 10Q to tne list of secti gt;n hea:Jinqs 3t t~e ena of title Ix to reaa as follows: D.C.Code sec. 1-366.l -15 A~pointnent of Attorneys 3n 3) 3djinq a new section 2805 to the list of section ,eadinqs at the enj of title XXVIII to read 35 f:&amp;gt;llows Aqreenents for Di sci pl inary Aop~als Se 3. Tne amendments made by se:tion 2(p) throuqh (dd) of this act snall not aoply to apolic':Jtions for disaoilitv compens3ti:&amp;gt;n fil ea gt;etween ~av 3. 1979. 3nd Auqust 16. 1979• ana on Se 4. Tni s act sh3l l taKe effact after 3 thirtv (30) aav oeriod of Conqressio,al re11i~w followinq aooroval DY the ~ayor (or in tne event Ji s tri:t of :olumbia to overrije t,e veto) as or:&amp;gt;vided in se:tion b02(C)(l) of tne Oistrictof :olumbia Sel f-Go11ern~ent and Gover,m ntal ~e o rqanization A:t• aporoved Decemoer 24• 1973 (o7 or Di strict of C6lurrbia APPROVED: June 4, 1980 \ Note, D.C.Ccxle, sec. 1-353.46 f Columbia I l J I i I t CCODICDL OF THE DI SiRDCT OF COLU!llA ;ea,n «IF Cl&amp;amp;iRCIM. camai::a.Aalm OOCU'l' NO: Bill 3-236 AC!ION: To Adopt (4-22-80) First Beadjng a VOta vcm J,l.l.lin~a~n i.i;;im~a.Lln.liis All Present 0 ROU. CAu. VOTE en co I 1nTXnN KANE SHAnn.nm !Al I N 1 t- K MASON ~pt.TTT THNG f'T Ii l1rn MQORF. t.TTT en C lil1'nV '111!.V TA D~TTi Ol'IT /i 1)T i a&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;e Cl:R.m'!C.\!ION CF JU:CORD tJt tZ7 &amp;amp;t;o Couazd ACr:ON T o_A d_op~t S-_2_0 s_o F ina~l R_e_a 1n-~s li VOICE VOU U na~m=·m~O U~s Absenc fl~a r~d•y l •rC a Y'Cf 6111C&amp;amp Yo 1 T'IT"Vf'\1\T v .1 \ft CAl"VT m I T. o v \fACl't"!\T en A TTT n T"!\Tr. I f'T A DT(l nni:ll f.TTT C'"1\T I 'C.HH'IV l1t.V I TAO"l"TTC: DnT t.l)tr I ;c r r 1 CI!\Ill'!C.\uO N 0 F ~c:cao 4!£f?.4~ ACT:ON iJ VOICt VO'n Abaec amp;aWlltCll amp caar c:a « 1 cow-a « I lnnnl-1 v .I. U"C HACXI.ETONl j M V l 'VA Cl'\1\T I pAIJlT'IT"T\Tr. I I lf'T l Dvi i vn I I JTT C::f'\1\1 I j i l 11'T'IV i ~v I t I I T 41'~TT I T '1'V I I I I 1111::1 t l </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <para>
      <num>(ff)</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-628.05"/>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
