<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 6-116">
  <num type="law">6-116</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1986-05-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/6-116.pdf">D.C. Law 6-116</citation>
      <citation type="register">33 DCR 2432</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 6-116 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 6-165, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 11, 1986 and March 25, 1986, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 8, 1986, it was assigned Act No. 6-151 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>411r17'11%1 Or1giaa1 District agency Price penalty' means the ollar amount which is added to the bid or proposal price submitted by an offeror with business interests in thd Republic of South Africa or Namibia Prohibited list' means the most recent list of companies doing business in or with the Republic of South Africa or Namibia issued by the Mayor pursuant to section 5 of the Prohibition of the Investment of Public Funds in Financial Institutions and Companies Making Loans.to or Doing Business with the Republic of South Africa or Namibia Act of 1983, effective March 8, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-50; D.C. Code, sec. 47-139 10 Quantitative evaluation' means an evaluation that reviews the criteria specified in the solicitation document, and which may include the use of the relative ranking technique, the weighted factors technique, or other method specified in the solicitation document Sec. 1003a. Determination of entities with business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia a) An offeror shall be designated as having business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia if 1) The offeror states in the affidavit required by section 1005a that it or any parent, subsidiary, or affiliated organization has business interests in the New, D.C. Code, SF 1-1192.3 (1987 supp Republic of South Africa or Namibia; The offeror is included on the prohibited list, has not petitioned the Mayor for removal from the list pursuant to.rules.issued by the Mayor, and has not submitted to the agency convincing documentary evidence to show why it should not be included on the list; or The agency has established through other documentary evidence that the offeror has business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia within the meaning of this title b) An agency, upon determining that an offeror is an entity with business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia, shall provide the offeror with written notice of the determination and the impact the determination will have on the offeror's bid or proposal Sec. 1004a. Sanctions Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a limited sanction shall be imposed against an offeror which has business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia. When a quantitative evaluation of bids or proposals is used, the sanction shall be demerits assigned to offerors with business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia and shall in no case exceed 6% of the maximum possible point score as indicated in the formal 5 )rlg Origi.reLZ. ew C. COcie —1192.4 1987 solicitation. When a lowest price evaluation of bids and proposals is used the sanction shall be a price penalty, based on a sliding scale that takes into account the estimated amount of the formal solicitation and shall in no case exceed 6% of the lowest bid or proposal price. When the imposition of a price penalty would leave the offeror as the lowest bidder, the contract shall be awarded in the mount of the offeror' s original bid, consistent with the District Government Procurement Regulations. If the imposition of a penalty pursuant to this section results in an equal quantitative evaluation or an equal lowest price evaluation between an offeror with business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia and an offeror who does not have these business interests, the contract shall be awarded to the offeror with no business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia Sec. 1005a. Notice and affidavit requirements. Each formal solicitation issued by a District agency under its procurement authority shall state the provisions of this title concerning the award of contracts to entities with business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia. Each offeror shall be required to submit a sworn New, D.C. Code, sec 1-1192.5 (1987 supp 6 60 da Ortgiai• to si di real ain 60- the o r en( rpc reef affidavit stating whether the offeror, its parent corporation, or any of its subsidiaries or affiliates has any business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia. An affidavit submitted by or on behalf of a joint venture shall state whether any participant in the joint venture or a parent corporation, subsidiary or affiliate of the participant has any business interests in the Republid of South Africa or Namibia. Inclusion of an offeror on the prohibited list shall create a rebuttable presumption that the entity has business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia. The contracting agency shall make the affidavits required by this section available for inspection by the public at the time of filing and at any time thereafter during normal business.hours e) The contracting agency shall make all reasonable efforts to verify the accuracy of affidavits submitted pursuant to this section f) Misrepresentations of the existence of business interests in the Republic of South Africa or Namibia in affidavits submitted pursuant to this section shall be grounds for suspension or debarment of the offeror from consideration for award of contracts or subcontracts Sec. 1006a. Rules. 7 a) Within 60 days of the effective date of this tie, the Mayor shall issue, as a part of the District ernment Procurement Regulations, rules necessary to lement the provisions of this title. The rules issued by the Mayor shall be transmitted the Council for a 60-day review period, excluding turdays; Sundays, holidays, and days of Council recess. The Council may, by resolution, approve or eapprove the rules, in whole or in part, within the 60-day eliperiod. If the Council, by resolution, does not rove or disapprove the rules before the expiration' of the day review period, the rules shall become effective at expiration of the 60-day review period Sec. 3. The District of Columbia Procurement Practices of 19E5, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; to codified at D.C. Code, sec. 1-2181.1 et seq is amended read as follows a) Section 107(2 D.C. Code, sec. 1-1181.7) is ded by inserting after "means" the phrase for oses other than those set forth in title Xa D.C. Code, SE 1-1181.7 (1987 supp b) Section 205 (D.C. Code, sec. 1-1182.5) is amended D.C. Code, se 1-1182.5 follows 1987 supp 1) Subsection (a)(3) is amended by striking the ae"30-day review period" and inserting the phrase -day review period" in its place;</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
