<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 22-16">
  <num type="law">22-16</num>
  <num type="bill">22-242</num>
  <num type="act">22-99</num>
  <heading type="short">Fiscal Year 2018 Local Budget Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To adopt the local portion of the budget of the District of Columbia government for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-08-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/37845/B22-0242-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 22-16</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 6581</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0242">
      <vote date="2017-05-30" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2017-05-30" reading="Motion"/>
      <vote date="2017-06-13" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2017-06-13" reading="Amendments"/>
      <vote date="2017-06-13" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-07-10</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Fiscal Year 2018 Local Budget Act of 2017".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Adoption of the local portion of the Fiscal Year 2018 budget.</heading>
    <text>The following expenditure levels are approved and adopted as the local portion of the budget for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018.</text>
    <container>
      <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA BUDGET FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING SEPTEMBER 30, 2018</heading>
      <container>
        <prefix>PART</prefix>
        <num>A</num>
        <heading>SUMMARY OF EXPENSES</heading>
        <text>The following amounts are appropriated for the District of Columbia government for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018 ("Fiscal Year 2018"), out of the General Fund of the District of Columbia ("General Fund"), except as otherwise specifically provided; provided, that notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in section 450A of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved November 22, 2000 (114 Stat. 2440; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.50a), and provisions of this act, the total amount appropriated in this act for operating expenses for the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2018 shall not exceed the lesser of the sum of the total revenues of the District of Columbia for such fiscal year or $13,896,758,000 (of which $7,984,013,000 shall be from local funds (including $351,231,000 from dedicated taxes), $1,015,271,000 shall be from Federal grant funds, $2,343,137,000 shall be from Medicaid payments, $662,920,000 shall be from other funds, $3,866,000 shall be from private funds, $80,900,000 shall be from funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress as Federal payments pursuant to the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017, and $1,806,652,000 shall be from enterprise and other funds); provided further, that of the local funds, such amounts as may be necessary may be derived from the General Fund balance; provided further, that of these funds the intra-District authority shall be $683,882,000; in addition, for capital construction projects, an increase of $2,791,855,000 of which $2,226,605,000 shall be from local funds, $1,000,000 shall be from Private Grant funds, $218,017,000 shall be from local transportation funds, $47,931,000 shall be from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, and $298,302,000 shall be from Federal grant funds, and a rescission of $1,201,205,000 of which $846,662,000 shall be from local funds, $100,000,000 shall be from Federal Payment funds, $165,501,000 shall be from local transportation funds, $26,501,000 shall be from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund and $62,541,000 shall be from Federal grant funds appropriated under this heading in prior fiscal years, for a net amount of $1,590,650,000, to remain available until expended; in addition, provided, that all funds provided by this act shall be available only for the specific projects and purposes intended; provided further, that amounts appropriated under this act may be increased by the amount transferred from funds appropriated in this act as Pay-As-You-Go Capital funds; provided further, that amounts provided under this heading are to be available, allocated, and expended at the rates and subject to the provisions set forth under the heading "Division of Expenses"; provided further, that this amount may be increased by proceeds of one-time transactions, which are expended for emergency or unanticipated operating or capital needs; provided further, that such increases shall be approved by enactment of local District law and shall comply with all reserve requirements contained in the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 777; D.C. Official Code § 1-201.01 <em>et seq.</em>); provided further, that this amount may be further increased by such sums as may be necessary for making refunds and for the payment of legal settlements or judgments that have been entered against the District of Columbia government and such sums may be paid from the applicable or available funds of the District of Columbia; provided further, that local funds are appropriated, without regard to fiscal year, in such amounts as may be necessary to pay vendor fees, including legal fees, that are obligated in this fiscal year, to be paid as a fixed percentage of District revenue recovered from third parties on behalf of the District under contracts that provide for payment of fees based upon and from such District revenue as may be recovered by the vendor; provided further, that, in addition, there are appropriated any amounts received, or to be received, without regard to fiscal year, from the Potomac Electric Power Company, or any of its related companies, successors, or assigns, for the purpose of paying or reimbursing the District Department of Transportation for the costs of designing, constructing, acquiring, and installing facilities, infrastructure, and equipment for use and ownership by the Potomac Electric Power Company, or any of its related companies, successors, or assigns, related to or associated with the undergrounding of electric distribution lines in the District of Columbia, and any interest earned on those funds, which amounts and interest shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, but shall be continually available until expended for the designated purposes; provided further, that this amount may be further increased by amounts deposited into the Attorney General Restitution Fund, which shall be continually available, without regard to fiscal year, until expended; provided further, that amounts appropriated pursuant to this act as operating funds may be transferred to enterprise and capital funds and such amounts, once transferred, shall retain appropriation authority consistent with the provisions of this act; provided further, that there may be reprogrammed or transferred for operating expenses any local funds transferred or reprogrammed in this or the 4 prior fiscal years from operating funds to capital funds, and such amounts, once transferred or reprogrammed, shall retain appropriation authority consistent with the provisions of this act, except, that there may not be reprogrammed for operating expenses any funds derived from bonds, notes, or other obligations issued for capital projects; provided further, that the local funds (including dedicated tax) and other funds appropriated by this act may be reprogrammed and transferred as provided in subchapter IV of Chapter 3 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code, or as otherwise provided by law, through November 15, 2018; provided further, that during Fiscal Year 2018 and any subsequent fiscal year, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the District of Columbia may expend funds as necessary to pay capital and operating obligations created by the District of Columbia and the National Parks Service in annual or multiyear agreements to improve, maintain, operate, or manage National Parks located in the District of Columbia, and such sums may be paid from the applicable or available funds of the District of Columbia, which, once allocated, shall retain appropriation authority consistent with the provisions of this act, without any limitation as to amount, duration, or fiscal year; provided further, that any unspent amount remaining in a nonlapsing fund described in Part B of this act at the end of Fiscal Year 2017 is to be continually available, allocated, appropriated, and expended for the purposes of such fund in Fiscal Year 2018 in addition to any amounts deposited in and appropriated to such fund in Fiscal Year 2018; provided further, that the Chief Financial Officer shall take such steps as are necessary to assure that the foregoing requirements are met, including the apportioning by the Chief Financial Officer of the appropriations and funds made available during Fiscal Year 2018.</text>
      </container>
      <container>
        <prefix>PART</prefix>
        <num>B</num>
        <heading>DIVISION OF EXPENSES</heading>
        <container>
          <heading>Governmental Direction and Support</heading>
          <text>Governmental direction and support, $807,604,000 (including $699,486,000 from local funds, $31,543,000 from Federal grant funds, $75,053,000 from other funds, and $1,522,000 from private funds), to be allocated as follows; provided, that any program fees collected from the issuance of debt shall be available for the payment of expenses of the debt-management program of the District:</text>
          <para>
            <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Council of the District of Columbia. - $25,338,000 from local funds; provided, that not to exceed $25,000 shall be available for the Chairman from this appropriation for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with section 26 of the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10); provided, further that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Council Technology Projects Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Office of the District of Columbia Auditor. - $5,860,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Advisory Neighborhood Commissions. - $1,027,000 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Agency Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Uniform Law Commission. - $51,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>Office of the Mayor. - $14,018,000 (including $10,472,000 from local funds and $3,546,000 from Federal grant funds); provided, that not to exceed $25,000 of such amount, from local funds, shall be available for the Mayor for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with section 26 of the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10); provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Emancipation Day Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>Mayor's Office of Legal Counsel. - $1,634,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>Office of the Senior Advisor. - $3,149,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(8)</num>
              <text>Office of the Secretary. - $4,058,000 (including $2,958,000 from local funds and $1,100,000 from other funds);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(9)</num>
              <text>Office of the City Administrator. - $8,920,000 (including $7,657,000 from local funds, $280,000 from other funds, and $983,000 from private funds); provided, that not to exceed $10,600 of such amount, from local funds, shall be available for the City Administrator for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with section 26 of the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(10)</num>
              <text>Deputy Mayor for Greater Economic Opportunity. -  $3,247,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(11)</num>
              <text>Office of Risk Management. - $3,965,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(12)</num>
              <text>Department of Human Resources. - $9,282,000 (including $8,866,000 from local funds and $416,000 from other funds);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(13)</num>
              <text>Office of Disability Rights. - $1,733,000 (including $1,105,000 from local funds and $628,000 from Federal grant funds);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(14)</num>
              <text>Captive Insurance Agency. - $2,320,000 (including $2,123,000 from local funds and $197,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Agency Fund (Free Standing Clinics/Insurance Fund) are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Captive Insurance Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(15)</num>
              <text>Office of Finance and Resource Management. - $24,706,000 (including $24,264,000 from local funds and $442,000 from other funds);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(16)</num>
              <text>Office of Contracting and Procurement. - $24,116,000 (including $22,840,000 from local funds and $1,276,000 from other funds);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(17)</num>
              <text>Office of the Chief Technology Officer. - $77,312,000 (including $68,876,000 from local funds, $32,000 from Federal grant funds, and $8,404,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the DC-NET Services Support Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(18)</num>
              <text>Contract Appeals Board. - $1,490,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(19)</num>
              <text>Department of General Services. - $289,725,000 (including $281,483,000 from local funds and $8,242,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Eastern Market Enterprise Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the West End Library/Firehouse Maintenance Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(20)</num>
              <text>Board of Elections. - $8,908,000 (including $7,907,000 from local funds and $1,000,000 from Federal grant funds);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(21)</num>
              <text>Office of Campaign Finance. - $2,908,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(22)</num>
              <text>Public Employee Relations Board. - $1,440,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(23)</num>
              <text>Office of Employee Appeals. - $2,129,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(24)</num>
              <text>Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments. - $520,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(25)</num>
              <text>Board of Ethics and Government Accountability. - $2,329,000 (including $2,179,000 from local funds and $150,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Lobbyist Administration and Enforcement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(26)</num>
              <text>Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia. - $97,699,000 (including $63,616,000 from local funds, $23,040,000 from Federal grant funds, $10,504,000 from other funds, and $539,000 from private funds); provided, that not to exceed $10,600 of such amount, from local funds, shall be available for the Attorney General for official reception and representation expenses; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Child SPT-TANF/AFDC Collections Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Child SPT-Reimbursements and Fees Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Child SPT-Interest Income Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Drug-, Firearm-, or Prostitution-Related Nuisance Abatement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Litigation Support Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Attorney General Restitution Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(27)</num>
              <text>Statehood Initiatives Agency. - $234,000 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the New Columbia Statehood Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(28)</num>
              <text>Office of the Inspector General. - $18,368,000 (including $15,521,000 from local funds and $2,848,000 from Federal grant funds); and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(29)</num>
              <text>Office of the Chief Financial Officer. - $171,119,000 (including $126,627,000 from local funds, $450,000 from Federal grant funds, and $44,042,000 from other funds); provided, that not to exceed $10,600 of such amount, from local funds, shall be available for the Chief Financial Officer for official reception and representation expenses; provided further, that amounts appropriated by this act may be increased by the amount required to pay banking fees for maintaining the funds of the District of Columbia; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the OFT Central Collection Unit Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Recorder of Deeds Surcharge Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Economic Development and Regulation</heading>
          <text>Economic development and regulation, $649,347,000 (including $319,218,000 from local funds (including $1,170,000 from dedicated taxes), $93,940,000 from Federal grant funds, $235,888,000 from other funds, and $302,000 from private funds), to be allocated as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development. ­ $46,346,000 (including $13,000,000 from local funds, $1,250,000 from Federal grant funds, and $32,096,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Industrial Revenue Bond program are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the H Street Retail Priority Area Grant Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Soccer Stadium Financing Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Economic Development Special Account are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Walter Reed Redevelopment Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Walter Reed Reinvestment Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the St. Elizabeths East Campus Redevelopment Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Office of Planning. - $10,402,000 (including $9,657,000 from local funds, $525,000 from Federal grant funds, $200,000 from other funds, and $20,000 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Historic Landmark and Historic District Filing Fees (Local) Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Historical Landmark and Historic District Filing Fees (O-Type) Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Department of Small and Local Business Development. - $15,089,000 (including $14,632,000 from local funds and $457,000 from Federal grant funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Small Business Capital Access Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Streetscape Loan Relief Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Ward 7 and Ward 8 Entrepreneur Grant Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Office of Cable Television, Film, Music, and Entertainment. - $12,757,000 (including $1,662,000 from local funds and $11,095,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Film, Television and Entertainment Rebate Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Cable Franchise Fees Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>Office of Zoning. - $3,069,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>Department of Housing and Community Development. - $82,237,000 (including $23,104,000 from local funds, $54,587,000 from Federal grant funds, and $4,546,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Compensation Units 1 and 2 Affordable Housing Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Department of Housing and Community Development Unified Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Land Acquisition for Housing Development Opportunities (LAHDO) Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the RLF Escrow Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Rehab Repay Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Home Again Revolving Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the HPAP-Repay Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Housing Preservation Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>Department of Employment Services. - $142,699,000 (including $62,380,000 from local funds, $35,355,000 from Federal grant funds, $44,705,000 from other funds, and $260,000 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Workers' Compensation Administration Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the UI Administrative Assessment Tax Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the UI Interest/Penalties Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Workers' Compensation Special Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Reed Act Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(8)</num>
              <text>Real Property Tax Appeals Commission. - $1,715,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(9)</num>
              <text>Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. - $60,098,000 (including $21,958,000 from local funds and $38,140,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Basic Business License Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Green Building Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Real Estate Guaranty and Education Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Nuisance Abatement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the OPLA-Special Account are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Board of Engineers Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Corporate Recordation Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Re-Appraisal Fee Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Vending Regulation Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(10)</num>
              <text>Office of the Tenant Advocate. - $4,008,000 (including $3,538,000 from local funds and $471,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Rental Unit Fee Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(11)</num>
              <text>Commission on the Arts and Humanities. - $29,689,000 (including $28,835,000 from local funds, $720,000 from Federal grant funds, and $133,000 from other funds); provided, that grant funding is competitively awarded to nonprofit fine and performing arts organizations based in and primarily serving the District; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Special Purpose Revenue Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(12)</num>
              <text>Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration. - $8,655,000 (including $1,170,000 from local funds (including $1,170,000 from dedicated taxes) and $7,485,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the ABC­Import And Class License Fees Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Dedicated Taxes Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(13)</num>
              <text>Public Service Commission. - $14,599,000 (including $589,000 from Federal grant funds, $13,989,000 from other funds, and $22,000 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Operating-Utility Assessment Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the PJM Settlement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(14)</num>
              <text>Office of the People's Counsel. - $8,063,000 from other funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Advocate for Consumers Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(15)</num>
              <text>Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking. - $28,623,000 (including $200,000 from local funds, $457,000 from federal grants, and $27,966,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Foreclosure Mediation Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Capital Access Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(16)</num>
              <text>Housing Authority Subsidy. - $85,980,000 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the DCHA Rehabilitation and Maintenance Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(17)</num>
              <text>Housing Production Trust Fund Subsidy. - $48,317,000 from local funds; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(18)</num>
              <text>Business Improvement Districts Transfer. - $47,000,000 from other funds.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Public Safety and Justice</heading>
          <text>Public safety and justice, $1,327,530,000 (including $1,112,225,000 from local funds, $163,970,000 from Federal grant funds, $80,000 from Medicaid payments, $48,340,000 from other funds, $14,000 from private funds, $435,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for the District of Columbia National Guard" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017, $1,900,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017, and $565,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017), to be allocated as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Metropolitan Police Department. - $518,074,000,(including $503,729,000 from local funds, $6,145,000 from Federal grant funds, and $8,200,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Asset Forfeiture Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department. - $254,570,000 (including $249,681,000 from local funds, $3,054,000 from Federal grant funds, and $1,836,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department EMS Reform Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Police Officers' and Firefighters' Retirement System. - $105,596,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Department of Corrections. - $145,188,000 (including $124,077,000 from local funds and $21,111,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Correction Trustee Reimbursement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Welfare Account are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Correction Reimbursement-Juveniles Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>District of Columbia National Guard. - $13,908,000 (including $5,188,000 from local funds, $8,285,000 from Federal grant funds, and $435,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for the District of Columbia National Guard" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017); provided, that the Mayor shall reimburse the District of Columbia National Guard for expenses incurred in connection with services that are performed in emergencies by the National Guard in a militia status and are requested by the Mayor, in amounts that shall be jointly determined and certified as due and payable for these services by the Mayor and the Commanding General of the District of Columbia National Guard; provided further, that such sums as may be necessary for reimbursement to the District of Columbia National Guard under the preceding proviso shall be available pursuant to this act, and the availability of the sums shall be deemed as constituting payment in advance for emergency services involved;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency. - $136,570,000 (including $4,827,000 from local funds and $131,743,000 from Federal grant funds);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure. - $295,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(8)</num>
              <text>Judicial Nomination Commission. - $270,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(9)</num>
              <text>Office of Police Complaints. - $2,601,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(10)</num>
              <text>District of Columbia Sentencing Commission. - $1,179,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(11)</num>
              <text>Office of the Chief Medical Examiner. - $11,445,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(12)</num>
              <text>Office of Administrative Hearings. - $10,089,000 (including $10,009,000 from local funds and $80,000 from Medicaid payments);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(13)</num>
              <text>Criminal Justice Coordinating Council. - $3,302,000 (including $1,238,000 from local funds, $150,000 from Federal grant funds, $14,000 from private funds, and $1,900,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(14)</num>
              <text>Office of Unified Communications. - $48,092,000 (including $32,736,000 from local funds, and $15,357,000 from other funds);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(15)</num>
              <text>Department of Forensic Sciences. - $26,309,000 (including $25,787,000 from local funds and $523,000 from Federal grant funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Department of Forensic Sciences Laboratory Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(16)</num>
              <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice. - $1,613,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(17)</num>
              <text>Office of Neighborhood Safety and Engagement.- $2,129,000 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Neighborhood Safety and Engagement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(18)</num>
              <text>Corrections Information Council. - $748,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(19)</num>
              <text>Office of Victim Services and Justice Grants. - $44,849,000 (including $28,941,000 from local funds, $14,071,000 from Federal grant funds, and $1,837,000 from other funds); provided, that $5,027,835 shall be made available to award a grant to the District of Columbia Bar Foundation for the purpose of administering the Access to Justice Initiative program, established by section 201 of the Access to Justice Initiative Amendment Act of 2011, effective September 14, 2011 (D.C. Law 19-21; D.C. Official Code § 4-1702.01), of which not less than $200,000 shall be available to fund the District of Columbia Poverty Lawyer Loan Repayment Assistance Program, established by section 401 of the Access to Justice Initiative Amendment Act of 2011, effective September 14, 2011 (D.C. Law 19-21; D.C. Official Code § 4-1704.01); provided further, that $4,500,000 shall be made available to award a grant to the District of Columbia Bar Foundation for the purpose of administering the Civil Legal Counsel Projects Program, established by section 3053 of the Expanding Access to Justice Amendment Act of 2017, passed on 2nd reading on June 27, 2017 (Enrolled version of Bill 22-244); provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Crime Victims Assistance Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Domestic Violence Shelter and Transitional Housing Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Community-Based Violence Reduction Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Private Security Camera Incentive Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(20)</num>
              <text>Criminal Code Reform Commission. - $701,000 from local funds.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Public Education System</heading>
          <text>Public education system, including the development of national-defense education programs, $2,473,785,000 (including $2,141,461,000 from local funds (including $4,676,000 from dedicated taxes), $249,960,000 from Federal grant funds, $20,935,000 from other funds, $1,428,000 from private funds, $30,000,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Resident Tuition Support" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017, and $30,000,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for School Improvement" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017), to be allocated as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>District of Columbia Public Schools. - $829,953,000 (including $789,567,000 from local funds, $14,712,000 from Federal grant funds, $9,263,000 from other funds, $1,411,000 from private funds, and $15,000,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for School Improvement" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017); provided, that not to exceed $10,600 of such local funds shall be available for the Chancellor for official reception and representation expenses; provided further, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the District of Columbia Public Schools on July 1, 2018, an amount equal to 10 percent of the total amount of the local funds appropriations provided for the District of Columbia Public Schools in the proposed budget of the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2019 (as transmitted to Congress), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for the District of Columbia Public Schools for Fiscal Year 2019; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the E-Rate Education Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the ROTC Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the DHHS Afterschool Program-Copayment Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the At-Risk Supplemental Allocation Preservation Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that the District of Columbia Public Schools ("DCPS") is authorized to spend appropriated funds to pay for DCPS-sponsored student travel, including the cost of transportation, lodging, meals, and admission fees for students and adult chaperones, to locations and venues outside DCPS facilities in accordance with rules promulgated by the Chancellor pursuant to section 105(c)(5) of the District of Columbia Public Education Reform Amendment Act of 2007, effective June 12, 2007 (D.C. Law 17-9; D.C. Official Code § 38-174(c)(5)); provided further, that such travel be related to the students' curriculum or for the purpose of rewarding student curricular or extra-curricular achievement;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Teachers' Retirement System. - $59,046,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Office of the State Superintendent of Education. - $450,426,000 (including $170,062,000 from local funds (including $4,676,000 from dedicated taxes), $234,317,000 from Federal grant funds, $1,047,000 from other funds, $30,000,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Resident Tuition Support" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017, and $15,000,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for School Improvement" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017); provided, that of the amounts provided to the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, $1,000,000 from local funds shall remain available until June 30, 2018, for an audit of the student enrollment of each District of Columbia public school and of each District of Columbia public charter school; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Special Education Compliance Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Charter School Credit Enhancement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Student Residency Verification Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the State Athletic Acts Program and Office Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Community Schools Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Special Education Enhancement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Child Development Facilities Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Access to Quality Child Care Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Common Lottery Board Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>District of Columbia Public Charter Schools. - $813,739,000 from local funds; provided, that there shall be quarterly disbursement of funds to the District of Columbia public charter schools, with the first payment to occur within 15 days of the beginning of the fiscal year; provided further, that if the entirety of this allocation has not been provided as payments to any public charter schools currently in operation through the per pupil funding formula, the funds shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018 for public education in accordance with section 2403(b)(2) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code § 38-1804.03(b)(2)); provided further, that of the amounts made available to District of Columbia public charter schools, $230,000 shall be made available to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer as authorized by section 2403(b)(6) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code § 38-1804.03(b)(6)); provided further, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the District of Columbia public charter schools on July 1, 2018, an amount equal to 35 percent, or for new charter school Local Education Agencies that opened for the first time after December 31, 2017 an amount equal to 45 percent, of the total amount of the local funds appropriations provided for payments to public charter schools in the proposed budget of the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2019 (as transmitted to Congress), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for such payments for Fiscal Year 2019; provided further, that the annual financial audit for the performance of an individual District of Columbia public charter school shall be funded by the charter school;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>University of the District of Columbia Subsidy Account. - $78,180,000 from local funds; provided, that this appropriation shall not be available to subsidize the education of nonresidents of the District at the University of the District of Columbia, unless the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia adopts, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, a tuition-rate schedule that establishes the tuition rate for nonresident students at a level no lower than the nonresident tuition rate charged at comparable public institutions of higher education in the metropolitan area; provided further, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the University of the District of Columbia on July 1, 2018, an amount equal to 10 percent of the total amount of the local funds appropriations provided for the University of the District of Columbia in the proposed budget of the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2019 (as transmitted to Congress), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for the University of the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2019; provided further, that not to exceed $10,600 of the amount provided for the University of the District of Columbia Subsidy Account shall be available for the President of the University of the District of Columbia for official reception and representation expenses;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>District of Columbia Public Library. - $61,787,000 (including $59,323,000 from local funds, $931,000 from Federal grant funds, $1,515,000 from other funds, and $17,000 from private funds); provided, that not to exceed $8,500 of such amount, from local funds, shall be available for the Public Librarian for official reception and representation expenses; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Copies and Printing Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the SLD E-Rate Reimbursement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Library Collections Account are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Books from Birth Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>District of Columbia Public Charter School Board. - $9,110,000 from other funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(8)</num>
              <text>Non-Public Tuition. - $70,021,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(9)</num>
              <text>Special Education Transportation. - $92,292,000 from local funds; provided, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the Special Education Transportation agency under the direction of the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, on July 1, 2018, an amount equal to 10 percent of the total amount of the local funds appropriations provided for the Special Education Transportation agency in the proposed budget for the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2019 (as transmitted to Congress), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for the Special Education Transportation agency for Fiscal Year 2019; provided further, that amounts appropriated under this paragraph may be used to offer financial incentives as necessary to reduce the number of routes serving 2 or fewer students;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(10)</num>
              <text>State Board of Education. - $1,711,000 from local funds; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(11)</num>
              <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Education. - $7,520,000 from local funds.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Human Support Services</heading>
          <text>Human support services, $4,769,449,000 (including $1,962,243,000 from local funds (including $86,907,000 from dedicated taxes), $417,402,000 from Federal grant funds, $2,343,057,000 from Medicaid payments, $41,147,000 from other funds, $599,000 from private funds, and $5,000,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Testing and Treatment of HIV/AIDS" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017), to be allocated as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Department of Human Services. - $554,740,000 (including $365,269,000 from local funds, $156,422,000 from Federal grant funds, $31,250,000 from Medicaid payments, and $1,800,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the SSI Payback Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Child and Family Services Agency. - $225,037,000 (including $158,633,000 from local funds, $65,383,000 from Federal grant funds, $1,000,000 from other funds, and $21,000 from private funds);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Department of Behavioral Health. - $255,555,000 (including $229,066,000 from local funds, $20,279,000 from Federal grant funds, $1,430,000 from Medicaid payments, $4,234,000 from other funds, and $547,000 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the APRA-Choice in Drug Treatment (HCSN) Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Department of Health. - $230,697,000 (including $74,016,000 from local funds, $131,673,000 from Federal grant funds, $19,977,000 from other funds, $32,000 from private funds, and $5,000,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Testing and Treatment of HIV/AIDS" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Health Professional Recruitment Fund (Medical Loan Repayment) are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Board of Medicine Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Pharmacy Protection Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the SHPDA Fees Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Civic Monetary Penalties Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the SHPDA Admission Fee Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the ICF/MR Fees and Fines are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Human Services Facility Fee Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Communicable and Chronic Disease Prevention and Treatment Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>Department of Parks and Recreation. - $49,462,000 (including $46,762,000 from local funds and $2,700,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Department of Recreation Enterprise Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>Office on Aging. - $45,554,000 (including $35,617,000 from local funds, $7,592,000 from Federal grant funds, and $2,345,000 from Medicaid payments);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>Unemployment Compensation Fund. - $6,680,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(8)</num>
              <text>Employees' Compensation Fund. - $21,709,000 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Worker's Compensation Rev­Settlement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Agency Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(9)</num>
              <text>Office of Human Rights. - $4,930,000 (including $4,600,000 from local funds and $330,000 from Federal grant funds);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(10)</num>
              <text>Office on Latino Affairs. - $3,301,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(11)</num>
              <text>Office on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs. - $855,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(12)</num>
              <text>Office of Veterans' Affairs. - $472,000 (including $467,000 from local funds and $5,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Office of Veterans Affairs Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(13)</num>
              <text>Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services. - $96,885,000 from local funds; provided, that $12,000 shall be used to fund the requirements of the Interstate Compact for Juveniles;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(14)</num>
              <text>Department of Disability Services. - $168,106,000 (including $116,612,000 from local funds, $32,921,000 from Federal grant funds, $10,810,000 from Medicaid payments, and $7,763,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Randolph Shepherd Unassigned Facilities Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Cost of Care­Non-Medicaid Clients Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Contribution to Costs of Supports Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(15)</num>
              <text>Department of Health Care Finance. - $3,103,677,000 (including $799,984,000 from local funds (including $86,907,000 from dedicated taxes), $2,803,000 from Federal grant funds, $2,297,222,000 from Medicaid payments, and $3,668,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Healthy DC Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Nursing Homes Quality of Care Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Stevie Sellows Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Medicaid Collections-3rd Party Liability Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Bill of Rights (Grievance and Appeals) Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Hospital Provider Fee Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Hospital Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(16)</num>
              <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Health and Human Services. - $1,787,000 from local funds.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Public Works</heading>
          <text>Public works, including rental of one passenger-carrying vehicle for use by the Mayor and 3 passenger-carrying vehicles for use by the Council of the District of Columbia and leasing of passenger-carrying vehicles, $877,828,000 (including $651,088,000 from local funds (including $85,572,000 from dedicated taxes), $40,195,000 from Federal grant funds, and $186,546,000 from other funds), to be allocated as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Department of Public Works. - $148,440,000 (including $139,966,000 from local funds and $8,474,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Solid Waste Disposal Fee Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Super Can Program Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Department of Transportation. - $119,972,000 (including $82,903,000 from local funds, $11,408,000 from Federal grant funds, and $26,662,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Bicycle Sharing Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Performance Parking Program Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Tree Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the DDOT Enterprise Fund-Non Tax Revenues Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Sustainable Transportation Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that, in addition, there are appropriated any amounts received, or to be received, without regard to fiscal year, from the Potomac Electric Power Company, or any of its related companies, successors, or assigns, for the purpose of paying or reimbursing the District Department of Transportation for the costs of designing, constructing, acquiring, and installing facilities, infrastructure, and equipment for use and ownership by the Potomac Electric Power Company, or any of its related companies, successors, or assigns, related to or associated with the undergrounding of electric distribution lines in the District of Columbia, and any interest earned on those funds, which amounts and interest shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, but shall be continually available until expended for the designated purposes; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Vision Zero Pedestrian and Bicycle Safety Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Transportation Infrastructure Project Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Department of Motor Vehicles. - $39,362,000 (including $29,800,000 from local funds and $9,561,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Motor Vehicle Inspection Station Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Department of Energy and Environment. - $126,270,000 (including $18,115,000 from local funds, $28,787,000 from Federal grant funds, and $79,367,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Storm Water Permit Review Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Sustainable Energy Trust Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Brownfield Revitalization Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Anacostia River Clean Up and Protection Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Wetlands Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Energy Assistance Trust Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the LUST Trust Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Soil Erosion and Sediment Control Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the DC Municipal Aggregation Program Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Fishing License Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Renewable Energy Development Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Special Energy Assessment Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Air Quality Construction Permits Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the WASA Utility Discount Program Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Pesticide Product Registration Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Stormwater Fees Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Stormwater In Lieu Fee Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Economy II Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Residential Aid Discount Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Residential Essential Services Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Benchmarking Enforcement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Product Stewardship Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>Department of For-Hire Vehicles. - $13,634,000 (including $4,095,000 from local funds and $9,539,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Taxicab Assessment Act Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Public Vehicles for Hire Consumer Service Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission. - $141,000 from local funds; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. - $430,009,000 (including $376,067,000 from local funds (including $85,572,000 from dedicated taxes) and $53,942,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Dedicated Taxes Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Parking Meter WMATA Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Financing and Other</heading>
          <text>Financing and Other, $1,184,564,000 (including $1,098,292 from local funds (including $172,906,000 from dedicated taxes), $18,262,000 from Federal grant funds, $55,010,000 from other funds, and $13,000,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017), to be allocated as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Repayment of Loans and Interest. - $710,762,000 (including $686,969,000  from local funds, $18,262,000 from Federal grant funds, and $5,531,000 from other funds), for payment of principal, interest, and certain fees directly resulting from borrowing by the District of Columbia to fund District of Columbia capital projects as authorized by sections 462, 475, and 490 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 777; D.C. Official Code §§ 1-204.62, 1-204.75, and 1-204.90);</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Debt Service - Issuance Costs. - $8,000,000 from local funds for the payment of debt service issuance costs;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Repayment of Revenue Bonds. - $7,832,000 from local funds (including $7,832,000 from dedicated taxes) for the repayment of revenue bonds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Commercial Paper Program. - $8,503,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>Settlements and Judgments.- $21,825,000 from local funds for making refunds and for the payment of legal settlements or judgments that have been entered against the District of Columbia government; provided, that this amount may be increased by such sums as may be necessary for making refunds and for the payment of legal settlements or judgments that have been entered against the District of Columbia government and such sums may be paid from the applicable or available funds of the District of Columbia;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>John A. Wilson Building Fund. - $4,082,000 from local funds for expenses associated with the John A. Wilson building;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>Workforce Investments. - $68,488,000 from local funds for workforce investments; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Compensation Units 1 and 2 Compensation and Classification Reform Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(8)</num>
              <text>Non-Departmental. -  $5,622,000 (including  $3,804,000 from local funds and $1,818,000 from other funds), to be transferred by the Mayor of the District of Columbia within the various appropriations headings in this act, to account for anticipated costs that cannot be allocated to specific agencies during the development of the proposed budget;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(9)</num>
              <text>Emergency Planning and Security Fund. - $13,000,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017; provided, that, notwithstanding any other law, obligations and expenditures that are pending reimbursement under the heading "Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia" may be charged to this appropriations heading;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(10)</num>
              <text>Master Equipment Lease/Purchase Program. - $19,254,000 from local funds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(11)</num>
              <text>Pay-As-You-Go Capital Fund. - $106,123,000 (including $59,960,000 from local funds and $46,162,000 from other funds) to be transferred to the Capital Fund, in lieu of capital financing;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(12)</num>
              <text>District Retiree Health Contribution. - $44,500,000 from local funds for a District Retiree Health Contribution;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(13)</num>
              <text>Highway Transportation Fund. - Transfers. - $24,936,000 from local funds (including $24,936,000 from dedicated taxes); and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(14)</num>
              <text>Convention Center Transfer. -  $141,636,000 (including $140,138,000 from local funds (including $140,138,000 from dedicated taxes) and $1,498,000 from other funds).</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Enterprise and Other Funds</heading>
          <text>The amount of $1,806,652 from enterprise and other funds (including $185,557,000 from enterprise and other dedicated taxes), shall be provided to enterprise funds as follows; provided, that, in the event that certain dedicated revenues exceed budgeted amounts, the General Fund budget authority may be increased as needed to transfer all such revenues, pursuant to local law, to the Local Transportation Fund, the Highway Trust Fund, the Washington Convention Center and Sports Authority, and the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority</heading>
          <text>For operation of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, $561,947,000 from enterprise and other funds, of which no outstanding debt exists for repayment of loans and interest incurred for capital improvement projects and payable to the District's debt service fund. For construction projects, $3,244,625,000, to be distributed as follows: $720,917,000 for Wastewater Treatment; $475,214,000 for the Sanitary Sewer System; $580,569,000 for the Water System; $51,336,000 for Non Process Facilities; $1,155,759,000 for the Combined Sewer Overflow Program; $101,311,000 for the Washington Aqueduct; $21,349,000 for the Stormwater Program; and $138,170,000 for the capital equipment program; in addition, $65,000,000 from Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment to the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority" in the Fiscal Year 2018 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2017; provided, that the requirements and restrictions that are applicable to General Fund capital improvement projects and set forth in this act under the Capital Outlay appropriation heading shall apply to projects approved under this appropriation account.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Washington Aqueduct</heading>
          <text>For operation of the Washington Aqueduct, $61,419,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Office of Lottery and Charitable Games</heading>
          <text>For the Lottery and Charitable Games Enterprise Fund, established by the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1982, approved December 4, 1981 (Pub. L. No. 97-91; 95 Stat. 1174), for the purpose of implementing the Law to Legalize Lotteries, Daily Numbers Games, and Bingo and Raffles for Charitable Purposes in the District of Columbia, effective March 10, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-172; codified in scattered cites in the D.C. Official Code), $240,000,000 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that, after notification to the Mayor, amounts appropriated herein may be increased by an amount necessary for the Lottery and Charitable Games Enterprise Fund to make transfers to the General Fund and to cover prizes, agent commissions, and gaming related fees directly associated with unanticipated excess lottery revenues not included in this appropriation.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>District of Columbia Retirement Board</heading>
          <text>For the District of Columbia Retirement Board, established pursuant to section 121 of the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act of 1979, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Stat. 866; D.C. Official Code § 1-711), $41,644,000 from the earnings of the applicable retirement funds to pay legal, management, investment, and other fees and administrative expenses of the District of Columbia Retirement Board; provided, that the District of Columbia Retirement Board shall provide to the Congress and the Mayor and to the Council of the District of Columbia a quarterly report of the allocations of charges by fund and of expenditures of all funds; provided further, that the District of Columbia Retirement Board shall provide to the Mayor, for transmittal to the Council of the District of Columbia, an itemized accounting of the planned use of appropriated funds in time for each annual budget submission and the actual use of such funds in time for each annual audited financial report.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Washington Convention and Sports Authority</heading>
          <text>For the Washington Convention Center Enterprise Fund, $160,216,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Housing Finance Agency</heading>
          <text>For operation of the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency, $12,320,000 from enterprise and other funds, of which no outstanding debt exists for repayment of loans and interest incurred for capital improvement projects and payable to the District's debt service fund. For capital projects, $2,582,130, to be distributed as follows: $1,957,130 for Information Technology Initiatives and Infrastructure; $125,000 for Capital Equipment; and $500,000 for Infrastructure Investment; provided, that the requirements and restrictions that are applicable to General Fund capital improvement projects and set forth in this act under the Capital Outlay appropriation heading shall apply to projects approved under this appropriation account.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>University of the District of Columbia</heading>
          <text>For the University of the District of Columbia, $161,935,000 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that these funds shall not revert to the General Fund at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for expenditure until September 30, 2018, without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Unemployment Insurance Trust Fund</heading>
          <text>For the Unemployment Insurance Trust Fund, $165,419,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Housing Production Trust Fund</heading>
          <text>For the Housing Production Trust Fund, $99,156,000 from enterprise and other funds (including $50,838,000 from enterprise and other dedicated taxes); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Housing Production Trust Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Tax Increment Financing (TIF) Program</heading>
          <text>For Tax Increment Financing, $53,709,000 from enterprise and other funds (including $53,709,000 from enterprise and other dedicated taxes).</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Ballpark Revenue Fund</heading>
          <text>For the Ballpark Revenue Fund, $61,557,000 from enterprise and other funds (including $48,821,000 from enterprise and other dedicated taxes).</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Repayment Of PILOT Financing</heading>
          <text>For Repayment of Payment in Lieu of Taxes Financing, $31,189,000 from enterprise and other funds (including $31,189,000 from enterprise and other dedicated taxes).</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Not-For-Profit Hospital Corporation</heading>
          <text>For the Not-For-Profit Hospital Corporation, $128,000,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Health Benefit Exchange Authority</heading>
          <text>For the District of Columbia Health Benefit Exchange Authority, $28,143,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Revised Revenue Estimate Contingency Priority</heading>
          <para>
            <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The amount appropriated as local funds shall be increased by the amounts the June 2017 and September 2017 revised revenue estimates exceed the revenue estimate of the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia dated February 28, 2017.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The funds authorized to be obligated and expended by this section shall be obligated as follows:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Fifty percent shall be deposited in the Workforce Investment account;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Fifty percent shall be allocated as set forth in the Revised Revenue Contingency List Act of 2017, passed on 2nd reading on June 27, 2017 (Enrolled version of Bill 22-244).</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The District of Columbia may obligate and expend any increase in the amount of funds authorized by this section only if the Chief Financial Officer certifies the increase in revenue and certifies that the use of the amounts is not anticipated to have a negative impact on the long-term financial plan of the District.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Cash Flow Reserve Account</heading>
          <text>All funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Cash Flow Reserve Account, established pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-392.02(j-2), are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Fiscal Stabilization Reserve Account</heading>
          <text>All funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Fiscal Stabilization Reserve Account, established pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-392.02(j-1), are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2018.</text>
        </container>
        <container>
          <heading>Capital Outlay</heading>
          <text>For capital construction projects, an increase of $2,791,855,000 of which $2,226,605,000 shall be from local funds, $1,000,000 shall be from Private Grant funds, $218,017,000 shall be from local transportation funds, $47,931,000 shall be from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, and $298,302,000 shall be from Federal grant funds, and a rescission of $1,201,205,000 of which $846,662,000 shall be from local funds, $100,000,000 shall be from Federal Payment funds, $165,501,000 shall be from local transportation funds, $26,501,000 shall be from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund and $62,541,000 shall be from Federal grant funds appropriated under this heading in prior fiscal years, for a net amount of $1,590,650,000; to remain available until expended; provided, that all funds provided by this appropriation heading shall be available only for the specific projects and purposes intended; provided further, that amounts appropriated under this heading may be increased by the amount transferred from funds appropriated in this act as Pay-As-You-Go Capital funds.</text>
        </container>
      </container>
    </container>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Local portion of the budget.</heading>
    <text>The budget adopted pursuant to this act constitutes the local portion of the annual budget for the District of Columbia government under section 446(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 801; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.46(a)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>As provided in section 446(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 801; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.46(a)), this act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in 602(c)(l) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(l)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
   <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.46" type="Budget Legislation" history="false">
    For approval and adoption of expenditure levels as the local portion of the budget for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-16">the Fiscal Year 2018 Local Budget Act of 2017, effective August 28, 2017 (D.C. Law 22-16; 64 DCR 9325)</cite>.
  </codify:annotation>
</document>
