<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 22-12">
  <num type="law">22-12</num>
  <num type="bill">22-150</num>
  <num type="act">22-90</num>
  <heading type="short">St. Mary's Way Designation Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To symbolically designate a portion of the public alley system in Square 42 that partially adjoins St. Mary's Church, which is located at 728 23rd Street, N.W., in Ward 2, as St. Mary's Way, in honor of the church's 150th anniversary.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-08-19</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/37558/Signed_Act/B22-0150-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106392">D.C. Law 22-12</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 6243</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B22-0150">
      <vote date="2017-05-16" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2017-06-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-06-28</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, this bill designates the public alleyway on the south side of St. Mary's church at 728 23rd Street, N.W., as St. Mary's Way. The alleyway to be designated is in Ward 2.</summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "St. Mary's Way Designation Act of 2017".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Pursuant to sections 401, 403a, and 423 of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-201; D.C. Official Code §§ 9-204.01, 9-204.03a, and 9-204.23), the Council symbolically designates a portion of the public alley system in Square 42, as shown on the Surveyor's plat in the committee report for this act, as "St. Mary's Way".</text>
    <codify:street-designation-anno action="the Council symbolically designates a portion of the public alley system in Square 42 as &quot;St. Mary's Way"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Transmittal.</heading>
    <text>The Council shall transmit a copy of this act, upon its effective date, to the District Department of Transportation and the Office of the Surveyor.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
