<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 22-188">
  <num type="law">22-188</num>
  <num type="bill">22-898</num>
  <num type="act">22-470</num>
  <heading type="short">D.C. General Resident Relocation Temporary Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To require, on a temporary basis, that demolition at the current D.C. General Family Shelter site meet all applicable environmental, health, and safety standards and that current D.C. General Family Shelter residents be relocated into safe, appropriate housing.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2018-07-10</introduced>
    <effective>2018-11-27</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/40657/Signed_Act/B22-0898-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106526">D.C. Law 22-188</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/40657/Signed_Act/B22-0898-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106526">D.C. Act 22-470</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 11412</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B22-0898">
      <vote date="2018-07-10" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-09-18" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-10-10</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "D.C. General Resident Relocation Temporary Act of 2018".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The abatement, deconstruction, or demolition of any existing structure at the D.C. General Family Shelter site shall meet all applicable environmental, health, and safety standards.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Beginning on July 27, 2018 and weekly thereafter until there are no shelter residents remaining at the D.C. General Family Shelter, the Mayor shall report to the Council the number of samples taken at the D.C. General Family Shelter site for lead or asbestos testing and whether any of those samples exceeds permissible Environmental Protection Agency and Occupational Safety and Health Administration exposure limits for lead or asbestos.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Relocation of shelter residents from the D.C. General Family Shelter shall be to appropriate permanent housing as defined by section 2(4) of the Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005, effective October 22, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-35; D.C. Official Code ยง 4-751.01(4)), to the facilities constructed to provide temporary shelter pursuant to the Homeless Shelter Replacement Act of 2016, effective July 29, 2016 (D.C. Law 21-141; 63 DCR 8453), or to any units under contract by the District specifically for the purpose of housing D.C. General Family Shelter residents.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Mayor shall provide a report to the Council, beginning on July 27, 2018 and weekly thereafter, indicating the current number of families continuing to reside at the D.C. General Family Shelter, the number of exits detailed by program, and the number of families confronting significant barriers to lease-up.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Upon closure of the D.C. General Family Shelter, the Mayor shall provide a report to the Council indicating the number of families that remained at closure that necessitated a swift exit and the status of those families.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง4-753.01" action="requirement that demolition at the current D.C. General Family Shelter site meet all applicable environmental, health, and safety standards and that current D.C. General Family Shelter residents be relocated into safe, appropriate housing"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code <strong>ยง</strong> 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
