<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 22-105">
  <num type="law">22-105</num>
  <num type="bill">22-431</num>
  <num type="act">22-306</num>
  <heading type="short">Great Streets Technical Amendment Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Retail Incentive Act of 2004 to establish in statutory law the various retail priority areas designated by resolution relating to the Great Streets program; and to amend the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Incentive Act of 2010 to extend the authority to issue grants from the H Street Retail Priority Area Grant Fund through September 30, 2018.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2018-06-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/38712/Signed_Act/B22-0431-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106228">D.C. Law 22-105</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/38712/Signed_Act/B22-0431-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106228">D.C. Act 22-306</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 3784</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B22-0431">
      <vote date="2018-02-06" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-03-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-04-04</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, this bill makes technical amendments to the Retail Incentive Act of 2004 to centralize and consolidate resolutions and acts that pertain to the Great Streets Program. It clarifies the boundaries of the existing Great Streets corridors and updates the date of authority to issue funds under the H Street Retail Priority Grant Fund, among other things. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Great Streets Technical Amendment Act of 2018".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Retail Incentive Act of 2004, effective September 8, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-185; D.C. Official Code § 2-1217.71 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows.</text>
    <para codify:path="§2-1217.73">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 4 (D.C. Official Code § 2-1217.73) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(e)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (e) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(g)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (g) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num>(g)</num>
            <text>There is established the H Street/Bladensburg Road/Benning Road, N.E., Corridor Retail Priority Area, which shall include the parcels, squares, and lots within the area bounded by a line beginning at the intersection of the center lines of Massachusetts Avenue, N.E., Columbus Circle, N.E., and 1st Street, N.E.; continuing northeast along the center line of 1st Street, N.E., to the center line of K Street, N.E.; continuing east along the center line of K Street, N.E., to the center line of Florida Avenue, N.E.; continuing southeast along the center line of Florida Avenue, N.E., to the center line of Staples Street, N.E.; continuing northeast along the center line of Staples Street, N.E., to the center line of Oates Street, N.E.; continuing southeast along the center line of Oates Street, N.E., until the point where Oates Street, N.E., becomes K Street, N.E.; continuing east along the center line of K Street, N.E., to the center line of 17th Street, N.E.; continuing south along the center line of 17th Street, N.E., to the center line of Gales Street, N.E.; continuing northwest along the center line of Gales Street, N.E., to the center line of 15th Street, N.E.; continuing south along the center line of 15th Street, N.E., to the center line of F Street, N.E.; continuing west along F Street, N.E., to the center line of Columbus Circle, N.E.; and continuing south and circumferentially along the center line of Columbus Circle, N.E., to the beginning point. Beginning at the intersection of Holbrook Street, N.E., and Mount Olivet Road, N.E.; thence east on Mount Olivet Road, N.E., to Bladensburg Road, N.E.; thence south on Bladensburg Road, N.E., to 17th Street, N.E.; thence south on 17th Street, N.E., to H Street, N.E.; thence east on H Street, N.E., to 19th Street, N.E.; thence south on 19th Street, N.E., to Benning Road, N.E.; thence east on Benning Road, N.E., to Oklahoma Avenue, N.E.; thence southwest on Oklahoma Avenue, N.E., to Clagett Place, N.E.; thence northwest on Clagett Place, N.E., to 20th Street, N.E.; thence northwest along the rear boundaries of all properties with frontage along the southwest side of Benning Road, N.E., to 19th Street, N.E.; thence south on 19th Street, N.E., to Gales Street, N.E.; thence northwest on Gales Street, N.E., to 15th Street, N.E.; thence west on G Street, N.E., to 14th Street, N.E.; thence north on 14th Street, N.E., to Florida Avenue, N.E.; thence west on Florida Avenue, N.E., to Holbrook Street, N.E.; thence north on Holbrook Street, N.E., to the point of beginning.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(l)">
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Subsection (l) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(m)">
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Subsection (m) is amended by striking the phrase "U Street/14th Street Retail Priority Area" and inserting the phrase "14th  and U Street, N.W./Adams Morgan/Mt. Pleasant Retail Priority Area" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>U Street/14th Street Retail Priority Area</find>
          <replace>14th  and U Street, N.W./Adams Morgan/Mt. Pleasant Retail Priority Area</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(n)">
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Subsection (n) is amended by striking the phrase "Tenleytown Retail Priority Area" and inserting the phrase "Wisconsin Avenue Retail Priority Area" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>Tenleytown Retail Priority Area</find>
          <replace>Wisconsin Avenue Retail Priority Area"</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>New subsections (o), (p), (q), (r), and (s) are added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(n)"/>
            <num>(o)</num>
            <text>There is established the Ward 4 Georgia Avenue Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within the following area: beginning at the intersection of Euclid Street, N.W., and Georgia Avenue, N.W.; continuing north along Georgia Avenue, N.W., to Kenyon Street, N.W.; thence continuing west along Kenyon Street, N.W., to Sherman Avenue, N.W.; continuing north along Sherman Avenue, N.W., to New Hampshire Avenue, N.W.; thence continuing northeast along New Hampshire Avenue, N.W., to Spring Road, N.W.; thence continuing northwest along Spring Road, N.W., to 14th Street, N.W., thence continuing north along 14th Street, N.W., to Longfellow Street, N.W., thence continuing east along Longfellow Street, N.W., to Georgia Avenue, N.W., thence continuing north along Georgia Avenue, N.W., to Eastern Avenue, N.W., thence continuing southeast along Eastern Avenue, N.W., to Kansas Avenue, N.E.; thence continuing southwest along Kansas Avenue, N.E., to Blair Road, N.W., thence continuing south along Blair Road, N.W., to North Capitol Street, N.E., thence continuing south along North Capitol Street, N.E., to Kennedy Street, N.W., thence continuing west along Kennedy Street, N.W., to Kansas Avenue, N.W., thence continuing southwest along Kansas Avenue, N.W., to Varnum Street, N.W.; thence continuing east along Varnum Street, N.W., to 7th Street, N.W.; thence continuing south along the center line of 7th Street, N.W., until the point where 7th Street, N.W., becomes Warder Street, N.W.; thence continuing further south along Warder Street, N.W., to Kenyon Avenue, N.W.; thence continuing west along Kenyon Avenue, N.W., to Georgia Avenue, N.W.; and thence south on Georgia Avenue, N.W., to the beginning point.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(o)"/>
            <num>(p)</num>
            <text>There is established the Martin Luther King Jr. Avenue/Good Hope Road/South Capitol Street Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within or abutting the boundary of the following areas:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The area bounded by a line beginning at the intersection of the center line of Suitland Parkway, S.E., and Martin Luther King, Jr. Avenue, S.E.;  continuing northwest along the center line of Suitland Parkway, S.E., to the center line of Interstate 295; continuing northeast along the center line of Interstate 295, to the center line of the entrance ramp from 13th Street, S.E., onto Interstate 295; continuing south along the center line of the entrance ramp from 13th Street, S.E., to the center line of Ridge Place, S.E.; continuing east along the center line of Ridge Place, S.E., to the center line of 16th Street, S.E.; continuing north along the center line of 16th Street, S.E., to the center line of R Street, S.E.; continuing east along the center line of R Street, S.E., to the center line of 18th Street, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of 18th Street, S.E., to the center line of Good Hope Road, S.E.; continuing west along the center line of Good Hope Road, S.E., to the center line of Fendall Street, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of Fendall Street, S.E., to the center line of V Street, S.E.; continuing west along the center line of V Street, S.E., to the center line of 16th Street, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of 16th Street, S.E., to the center line of W Street, S.E.; continuing west along the center line of W Street, S.E., to the center line of 14th Street, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of 14th Street, S.E., to the point where 14th Street, S.E., becomes High Street, S.E.; continuing southwest along the center line of High Street, S.E., to the center line of Maple View Place, S.E.; continuing further southwest along a straight line to the intersection of the center lines of High Street, S.E., and Morris Road, S.E.; continuing further southwest along the center line of High Street, S.E., to the center line of Howard Road, S.E.; continuing northwest along the center line of Howard Road, S.E., to the center line of Bowen Road, S.E.; continuing southwest along the center line of Bowen Road, S.E., to the center line of Sheridan Road, S.E.; continuing further southwest along a line extended from the center line of Bowen Road, S.E., to the center line of Suitland Parkway, S.E.; and continuing northwest along the center line of Suitland Parkway, S.E., to the beginning point;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The area bounded by a line beginning at the intersection of the center line of 4th Street, S.E., and Savannah Street, S.E.; continuing north along the center line of 4th Street, S.E., to the center line of Martin Luther King, Jr. Avenue, S.E.; continuing southwest along the center line of Martin Luther King, Jr. Avenue, S.E., to the center line of Waclark Place, S.E.; continuing north along the center line of Waclark Place, S.E., to the center line of Parkland Place, S.E.; continuing due north to the center line of Malcolm X Avenue, S.E.; continuing east along the center line of Malcolm X Avenue, S.E., to the center line of Oakwood Street, S.E.; continuing northwest along the center line of Oakwood Street, S.E., to the center line of 5th Street, S.E.; continuing northeast along the center line of 5th Street, S.E., to the center line of Lebaum Street, S.E.; continuing further northeast along an extension of the center line of 5th Street, S.E., to the center line of Persimmon Street, S.E.; continuing northeast along the center line of Persimmon Street, S.E., to the center line of Redwood Drive, S.E.; continuing east along the center line of Redwood Drive, S.E., to the center line of Sycamore Drive, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of Sycamore Drive, S.E., to the end of Sycamore Drive, S.E.; continuing along a straight line to the intersection of the center lines of 8th Street, S.E., and Malcolm X Avenue, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of 8th Street, S.E., to the center line of Alabama Avenue, S.E.; continuing southwest along the center line of Alabama Avenue, S.E., to the center line of 6th Street, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of 6th Street, S.E., to the center line of Savannah Street, S.E.; and continuing west along the center line of Savannah Street, S.E., to the beginning point;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>The area bounded by a line beginning at the intersection of the center line of Martin Luther King, Jr. Avenue, S.W., and Danbury Street, S.W.; continuing north along the center line of Martin Luther King, Jr. Avenue, S.W., to the center line of Chesapeake Street, S.W.; continuing west along the center line of Chesapeake Street, S.W., to the center line of 2nd Street, S.W.; continuing northeast along the center line of Second Street, S.W., to the center line of Xenia Street, S.W.; continuing northeast along an extension of the center line of 2nd Street, S.W., to the center line of South Capitol Street; continuing southeast along the center line of South Capitol Street to the center line of Martin Luther King, Jr. Avenue; continuing northeast along the center line of Martin Luther King Avenue, S.E., to the center line of 1st Street, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of 1st Street, S.E., to the center line of Danbury Street, S.E.; continuing west along the center line of Danbury Street, S.E., to the center line of South Capitol Street; and continuing further west along the center line of Danbury Street, S.W., to the beginning point; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>The parcels, squares, and lots abutting Good Hope Road, S.E., beginning at the intersection of Good Hope Road, S.E., and Anacostia Drive, S.E., thence southeast on Good Hope Road, S.E., to its intersection with Naylor Road, S.E.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(p)"/>
            <num>(q)</num>
            <text>There is established the Minnesota/Benning Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within or abutting the boundary of the following areas: Beginning at the intersection of the center line of A Street, S.E., and 35th Street, S.E.; continuing north along the center line of 35th Street, S.E., to the center line of East Capitol Street; continuing northeast along the center line of 35th Street, N.E., to the center line of Blaine Street, N.E.; continuing northwest along a straight line to the intersection of the center lines of Clay Street, N.E., and 36th Street, N.E.; continuing north along the center line of 36th Street, N.E., to the center line of Dix Street, N.E.; continuing west along the center line of Dix Street, N.E., to the center line of Anacostia Avenue, N.E.; continuing north along the center line of Anacostia Avenue, N.E., to the end of this section of Anacostia Avenue, N.E.; continuing east in a straight line to the intersection of the center lines of Anacostia Avenue, N.E., and Foote Street, N.E.; continuing northeast along the center line of Anacostia Avenue, N.E., to the center line of Hayes Street, N.E.; continuing southeast along the center line of Hayes Street, N.E., to the center line of Kenilworth Terrace, N.E.; continuing northeast along the center line of Kenilworth Terrace, N.E., to the center line of Nannie Helen Burroughs Avenue, N.E.; continuing southeast along the center line of Nannie Helen Burroughs Avenue, N.E., to the center line of Minnesota Avenue, N.E.; continuing southwest along the center line of Minnesota Avenue, S.E., to the center line of Grant Street, N.E.; continuing east along the center line of Grant Street, N.E., to the center line of 42nd Street, N.E.; continuing south along the center line of 42nd Street, N.E., to the center line of Benning Road, N.E.; continuing northwest along the center line of Benning Road, N.E., to the center line of 41st Street, N.E.; continuing south along the center line of 41 Street, N.E., to the center line of Clay Place, N.E.; continuing west along the center line of Clay Place, N.E., to the center line of 40th Street, N.E.; continuing south along the center line of 40th Street, N.E., to the center line of East Capitol Street; continuing west along the center line of East Capitol Street to the center line of B Street, S.E.; continuing southwest along the center line of B Street, S.E., to the center line of Ridge Road, S.E.; continuing northwest along the center line of Ridge Road, S.E., to the center line of Minnesota Avenue, S.E.; continuing southwest along the center line of Minnesota Avenue, S.E., to the center line of A Street, S.E.; and continuing west along the center line of A Street, S.E., to the beginning point.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(q)"/>
            <num>(r)</num>
            <text>There is established the Pennsylvania Avenue, S.E., Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within or abutting the boundary of the following areas:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The area bounded by a line beginning at the intersection of the center line of Naylor Road, S.E., and Q Street, S.E.; continuing northwest along the center line of Naylor Road, S.E., to the center line of 22nd Street, S.E.; continuing north along the center line of 22nd Street, S.E., to the center line of Fairlawn Avenue, S.E.; continuing northeast along the center line of Fairlawn Avenue, S.E., to the center line of N Street, S.E.; continuing southeast along the center line of N Street, S.E., to the center line of Minnesota Avenue, S.E.; continuing northeast along the center line of Minnesota Avenue, S.E., to the center line of 28th Street, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of 28th Street, S.E., to the center line of Q Street, S.E.; and continuing west along the center line of Q Street, S.E., to the beginning point;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The area bounded by a line beginning at the intersection of the center lines of 30th Street, S.E., and Park Drive, S.E.; continuing north along a straight line to the intersection of the center lines of 30th Street, S.E., and S Street, S.E.; continuing north along the center line of 30th Street, S.E., to the center line of O Street, S.E.; continuing southeast along the center line of O Street, S.E., to the center line of Carpenter Street, S.E.; continuing northeast along the center line of Carpenter Street, S.E., to the center line of 33rd Place, S.E.; continuing southeast along the center line of 33rd Place, S.E., to the center line of Pennsylvania Avenue, S.E.; continuing northwest along the center line of Pennsylvania Avenue, S.E., to the center line of 33rd Street, S.E.; continuing south and west along the center line of 33rd Street, S.E., to the center line of Branch Avenue, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of Branch Avenue, S.E., to the center line of Park Drive, S.E.; and continuing west along the center line of Park Drive, S.E., to the beginning point; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>The area bounded by a line beginning at the intersection of the center lines of 37th Street, S.E., and Suitland Road, S.E.; continuing north along the center line of 37th Street, S.E., to the center line of Alabama Avenue, S.E.; continuing northeast along the center line of Alabama Avenue, S.E., to the center line of Q Street, S.E.; continuing southeast along the center line of Q Street, S.E., to the center line of Fort Dupont Street, S.E.; continuing south along the center line of Fort Dupont Street, S.E., to the center line of Southern Avenue, S.E.; continuing southwest along the center line of Southern Avenue, S.E., to the center line of Suitland Road, S.E.; and continuing northwest along the center line of Suitland Road, S.E., to the beginning point.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(r)"/>
            <num>(s)</num>
            <text>There is established the 7th Street/Georgia Avenue Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within or abutting the boundary of the following areas: Beginning at the intersection of the center line of Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., and 11th Street, N.W.; continuing north along the center line of 11th Street, N.W., to the center line of Florida Avenue, N.W.; continuing southeast along the center line of Florida Avenue, N.W., to the center line of Barry Place, N.W.; continuing northeast along the center line of Barry Place, N.W., to the center line of Georgia Avenue, N.W.; continuing north along the center line of Georgia Avenue, N.W., to the center line of Howard Place, N.W.; continuing east along the center line of Howard Place, N.W., to the center line of 6th Street, N.W.; continuing south along the center line of 6th Street, N.W., to the center line of W Street, N.W.; continuing east along the center line of W Street, N.W., to the center line of 5th Street, N.W.; continuing south along the center line of 5th Street, N.W., to the center line of Rhode Island Avenue, N.W.; continuing northwest along the center line of Rhode Island Avenue, N.W., to the center line of 6th Street, N.W.; continuing south along the center line of 6th Street, N.W., to the center line of New York Avenue, N.W.; continuing southwest along the center line of New York Avenue, N.W., to the center line of Mount Vernon Place, N.W.; continuing west along the center line of Mount Vernon Place, N.W., to the center line of Massachusetts Avenue, N.W.; and continuing northwest along the center line Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., to the beginning point.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§2-1217.73b|(b)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 4b(b) (D.C. Official Code § 2-1217.73b(b)) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(2)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (2) is amended by adding a new subparagraph (A-i) to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="2">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(A)"/>
            <num>(A-i)</num>
            <text>Manufacturers, distributors, incubators, and accelerators; provided, that each includes an on-site retail component that sells general or merchandise goods;</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(3)|(C)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (3)(C) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="2">
          <para>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Execute an employment agreement with the Department of Employment Services pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03">section 4 of the First Source Employment Agreement Act of 1984, effective June 29, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-93; D.C. Official Code § 2-219.03),</code-cite> and Mayor's Order 83-265, dated November 9, 1983 (30 DCR 5990); and</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(4)|(A)">
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (4)(A) is amended by striking the phrase "into thirds or fourths and disbursed accordingly" and inserting the phrase "and disbursed" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>into thirds or fourths and disbursed accordingly</find>
          <replace>and disbursed</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code">
    <num>3</num>
    <text>H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Incentive Act of 2010, effective April 8, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-354; D.C. Official Code § 1-325.171 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§1-325.171">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 1-325.171) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(5)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (5) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(6)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the phrase "H Street, N.E. Retail Priority Area" and inserting the phrase "H Street/Bladensburg Road/Benning Road, N.E., Corridor Retail Priority Area" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area</find>
          <replace>H Street/Bladensburg Road/Benning Road, N.E., Corridor Retail Priority Area</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§1-325.172|(c)|(3)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 3(c)(3) (D.C. Official Code § 1-325.172(c)(3)) is amended by striking the phrase "September 30, 2017" and inserting the phrase "September 30, 2018" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>September 30, 2017</find>
        <replace>September 30, 2018</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§1-325.173">
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 4 (D.C. Official Code § 1-325.173) is amended by striking the phrase "H Street, N.E. Retail Priority Area" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "H Street/Bladensburg Road/Benning Road, N.E., Corridor Retail Priority Area" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="3">
        <find>H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area</find>
        <replace>H Street/Bladensburg Road/Benning Road, N.E., Corridor Retail Priority Area</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text>The Great Streets Neighborhood Retail Priority Areas Approval Resolution, effective July 10, 2007 (Res. 17-257; 54 DCR 7194), is repealed.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02 (c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
