<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 22-20">
  <num type="law">22-20</num>
  <num type="bill">22-363</num>
  <num type="act">22-124</num>
  <heading type="short">Southwest Waterfront Exemption Temporary Amendment Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, section 25-314 of the District of Columbia Official Code to create an exemption to the 400-foot restriction for taverns, multipurpose facilities, and off-premises retailers located in the Southwest Waterfront area.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-09-20</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/38452/Signed_Act/B22-0363-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106256">D.C. Law 22-20</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 7424</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B22-0363">
      <vote date="2017-06-27" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2017-07-11" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-07-28</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Southwest Waterfront Exemption Temporary Amendment Act of 2017".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 25-314(b) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "paragraphs (2) through (5)" and inserting the phrase "paragraphs (2) through (8)" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (3) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Designate the exist text as subparagraph (A).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new subparagraph (B) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="2">
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The exception in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not apply if the currently functioning establishment holding a license of the same class is exempt from the 400-foot restriction under paragraph (8) of this subsection.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (8) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>The 400-foot restriction shall not apply to an application for an on-premises retailer's license, class CT, DT, CX, or DX, or an off-premises retailer's license, class A or B, located in the Mixed Use-12 Zone, Square 473 according to the official atlases of the Zoning Commission of the District of Columbia.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง25-314"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
