<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 22-264">
  <num type="law">22-264</num>
  <num type="bill">22-574</num>
  <num type="act">22-590</num>
  <heading type="short">Paperwork Reduction and Data Collection Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To establish the Data Sharing and Paperwork Reduction Advisory Council to serve as an advisory body to the Mayor, the Council, and District government agencies on matters pertaining to improving efficiencies in data collection, information sharing, and information resources management.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2017-11-07</introduced>
    <effective>2019-03-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/39182/B22-0574-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 22-264</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/39182/B22-0574-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-590</citation>
      <citation type="register">66 DCR 1388</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0574">
      <vote date="2018-11-27" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-12-18" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2019-01-19</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, this bill establishes a Data Sharing and Paperwork Advisory Council to improve efficiencies in data collection, information sharing, and information resources management to serve as an advisory body to the Mayor, the Council, and District agencies. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Government Operations</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Paperwork Reduction and Data Collection Act of 2018".</text>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="2" after="17" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
      <num>17A</num>
      <heading>Improving Efficiencies in Data Collection, Information Sharing, and Information Resources Management.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="2|17A" num-value="2-1731"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Data Sharing and Paperwork Reduction Council.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is established the Data Sharing and Paperwork Reduction Advisory Council ("DSPRC").</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The DSPRC shall be composed of the following10 ex officio members or their designees:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Chief Technology Officer;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Chief Data Officer;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Department of Small and Local Business Development;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Department of Employment Services;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>The Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(8)</num>
        <text>The Executive Director of the District of Columbia Board of Elections;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(9)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(10)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Department of Health.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>In addition to the members serving pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, the Mayor shall appoint 5 community representatives who are small business owners in the District; provided, that 2 of the community representatives appointed shall own businesses holding an on-premises retailer's license pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-113">D.C. Official Code § 25-113</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The community representatives shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; provided, that of the 5 initial appointments, 3 shall be appointed by the Mayor for a term of 2 years and 2 shall be appointed by the Mayor for a term of one year. Community representatives may be reappointed.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment to the position that became vacant. Community representatives who are appointed to fill vacancies that occur before the expiration of a community representative's full term shall serve only the unexpired portion of the community representative's term.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Chief Technology Officer or the Chief Technology Officer's designee shall serve as chairperson of the DSPRC.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The chairperson shall designate a vice-chairperson from among the DSPRC's community representatives to assist the chairperson in the performance of the chairperson's official duties.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The DSPRC shall meet on at least a quarterly basis, and may meet more often as needed, at times to be determined by the chairperson of the DSPRC.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The DSPRC shall provide public notice of all meetings and shall conduct its meetings in compliance with <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|IV">the Open Meetings Amendment Act of 2010, effective March 31, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-350; D.C. Official Code § 2-571 <em>et seq</em>.)</code-cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The Office of the Chief Technology Officer shall provide the DSPRC with an annual operating budget, which shall include funds to maintain a website where the DSPRC shall provide a public listing of members, meeting notices, and meeting minutes and solicit community input.</text>
    </para>
    <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1731" applicability-path="§5" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="2|17A" num-value="2-1732"/>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Duties of the DSPRC.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The DSPRC shall evaluate:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The process by which District agencies compile, maintain, and update data received from residents and organizations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The data collection and entry policies of District agencies for inefficiencies, duplicative practices, and redundant paperwork;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The need for and ability of District agencies to access data through an interagency data sharing system; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>The ease and ability of residents and organizations to update information provided to agencies.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The DSPRC shall identify:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The extent to which the same or similar data requested of different agencies may be reduced;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The time and resources that the District could save by reducing the request of duplicative data and sharing data by agencies;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The viability of sharing data with other agencies; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>The extent to which requesting data by multiple agencies produces errors in information.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The DSPRC shall issue recommendations regarding:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Reducing redundant paperwork across District agencies;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Improving the process for residents and organizations to update information across multiple agencies; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The resources necessary to compile, protect, and update data collected and shared by multiple District agencies.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "interagency data sharing system" means a platform that gives users the ability to share the same data resource with other applications or users.</text>
    </para>
    <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1732" applicability-path="§5" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="2|17A" num-value="2-1733"/>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Report.</heading>
    <text>Within one year of <span codify:value="[insert applicability date]">the applicability date of this act</span>, and on the anniversary of the first report each year thereafter, the DSPRC shall submit a report to the Council that addresses each of the duties required by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1732">section 3</code-cite>.</text>
    <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1733" applicability-path="§5" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="2|17A" num-value="2-1734"/>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|17A">This act</code-cite> shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 22-264" path="§2" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 22-264" path="§3" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 22-264" path="§4" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|17A">this act</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the  District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
