<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 22-203">
  <num type="law">22-203</num>
  <num type="bill">22-996</num>
  <num type="act">22-502</num>
  <heading type="short">Parent-led Play Cooperative Temporary Amendment Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Child Development Facilities Regulation Act of 1998 to exempt parent-led play cooperatives from the requirements of the Child Development Facilities Regulation Act of 1998.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2018-10-02</introduced>
    <effective>2019-02-22</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/41046/Signed_Act/B22-0996-SignedAct.pdf?Id=107011">D.C. Law 22-203</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/41046/Signed_Act/B22-0996-SignedAct.pdf?Id=107011">D.C. Act 22-502</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 12336</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B22-0996">
      <vote date="2018-10-02" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-10-16" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-10-31</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Parent-led Play Cooperative Temporary Amendment Act of 2018".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Child Development Facilities Regulation Act of 1998, effective April 13, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-215; D.C. Official Code § 7-2031 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2031) is amended by adding a new paragraph (5A) to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(5A)</num>
          <text>"Parent-led play cooperative" means a group of parents, step-parents, or legal guardians of participating children, including a group organized through a nonprofit organization, who have agreed to supervise the participating children during group meetings and that:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Meets at predetermined times for less than a full day;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Meets at locations other than a home of one of the parents, step-parents, or legal guardians in the group;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Does not require payment by parents, step-parents, or legal guardians, other than to cover the costs of administering the group, including rent, insurance, equipment, and activities;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Does not employ any individual to supervise participating children on behalf of parents; provided, that a parent-led play cooperative may employ an individual to:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Facilitate activities while parents, step-parents, or legal guardians supervise the participating children; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Assist with administering the group;</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>Requires, as a prerequisite to joining the group, that a parent, step-parent, or legal guardian of each participating child in the group volunteer a minimum number of hours to supervise the participating children during meetings, regardless of whether the group requires parents, step-parents, or legal guardians of every child to be present at every meeting; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(F)</num>
            <text>Notifies, upon registration with the group, the parents, step-parents, and legal guardians of each participating child in the group that the group is not a child development facility licensed pursuant to this act.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2031"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 4 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2033) is amended by adding a new paragraph (2A) to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(2A)</num>
          <text>Parent-led play cooperative;</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2033"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
