<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 22-35">
  <num type="law">22-35</num>
  <num type="bill">22-194</num>
  <num type="act">22-169</num>
  <heading type="short">DC HealthCare Alliance Recertification Simplification Amendment Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Health Care Privatization Amendment Act of 2001 to provide that DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees shall only be required to complete one in person face-to-face interview in a 12-month period for recertification and that any additional required interviews for recertification may be completed over the phone with the Department of Human Services, and to allow applicants and enrollees who are hospitalized, disabled, elderly, or caring for a household member who is hospitalized, disabled, or elderly to be exempted from any face-to-face interview requirement.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-12-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/37695/Signed_Act/B22-0194-SignedAct.pdf?Id=106641">D.C. Law 22-35</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 10929</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B22-0194">
      <vote date="2017-09-19" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2017-09-19" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2017-09-19" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2017-09-19" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2017-10-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-10-24</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced it requires that the Mayor permit DC HealthCare Alliance program enrollees to complete the face-to-face interview requirement with a qualified community health organization, or over the phone with the Department of Human Services. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Human Services</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "DC HealthCare Alliance Recertification Simplification Amendment Act of 2017".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Health Care Privatization Amendment Act of 2001, effective July 12, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-18; D.C. Official Code § 7-1401 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended by adding new sections 7b, 7c, and 7d to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="7|14" num-value="7-1407" history-prefix="as added"/>
        <num>7b</num>
        <heading>DC HealthCare Alliance recertification.</heading>
        <text>If DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees are required to complete an interview as a recertification requirement more than once in a 12-month period, the Mayor shall:</text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Only require DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees to complete one in person face-to-face interview for recertification during a 12-month period; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Allow DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees to complete any additional required interviews for recertification over the phone with the Department of Human Services.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-18" type="History" path="§6">July 12, 2001, D.C. Law 14-18, § 7b</annotation>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1407" applicability-path="§3" action="creation of"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="7|14" num-value="7-1408" history-prefix="as added"/>
        <num>7c</num>
        <heading>Special certification and recertification procedures for certain individuals.</heading>
        <text>Upon request from an applicant or enrollee who is hospitalized, disabled, elderly, or caring for a household member who is hospitalized, disabled, or elderly, the Mayor shall exempt the applicant or enrollee from any required face-to-face interview if the applicant or enrollee is unable to complete a face-to-face interview.</text>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-18" type="History" path="§6">July 12, 2001, D.C. Law 14-18, § 7c</annotation>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1408" applicability-path="§3" action="creation of"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="7|14" num-value="7-1409" history-prefix="as added"/>
        <num>7d</num>
        <heading>Reporting requirements.</heading>
        <text>Beginning February 1, 2018, and on an annual basis thereafter, the Mayor shall submit a public report to the Council that shall include, for each of the last 12 months, the following information:</text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The number of DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees required to recertify;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The number of DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees required to recertify who successfully completed recertification;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The number of DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees who did not recertify;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>The number of DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees who re-enrolled in DC HealthCare Alliance within 30 days after termination and the number of enrollees who re-enrolled within 60 days after termination;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>The number of DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees required to recertify who completed interviews, whether face-to-face or over the telephone, disaggregated by interview type.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(6)</num>
            <text>The number of recertification interviews conducted at each location where interviews are offered;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(7)</num>
            <text>The average time enrollees waited in line at each location where interviews were offered in order to complete a face-to-face interview with an explanation of how the data was collected, with wait times measured both from the point the enrollee first checks in at the service center and from the point the enrollee gets in line outside the service center if there is a line to enter the service center;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(8)</num>
            <text>The average time enrollees waited on the telephone before being served in order to complete interviews over the telephone;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(9)</num>
            <text>The number of requests made before, or during, an interview for an accommodation due to disability, disaggregated by interview type;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(10)</num>
            <text>The number of requests made before, or during, an interview for service in a language other than English, disaggregated by interview type; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(11)</num>
            <text>The number of requests for waivers of face-to-face interviews that were:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Made;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Granted; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>Denied, and the grounds for denial.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-18" type="History" path="§6">July 12, 2001, D.C. Law 14-18, § 7d</annotation>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1409" applicability-path="§3" action="creation of"/>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 22-35" path="§2" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
