<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 22-6">
  <num type="law">22-6</num>
  <num type="bill">22-225</num>
  <num type="act">22-54</num>
  <heading type="short">Defending Access to Women's Health Care Services Temporary Amendment Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Women's Health and Cancer Rights Federal Law Conformity Act of 2000 to require insurers to cover preventive services for women without cost-sharing.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-07-11</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/37810/Signed_Act/B22-0225-SignedAct.pdf?Id=105874">D.C. Law 22-6</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 4905</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B22-0225">
      <vote date="2017-04-04" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2017-05-02" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-05-17</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Defending Access to Women's Health Care Services Temporary Amendment Act of 2017".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Women's Health and Cancer Rights Federal Law Conformity Act of 2000, effective April 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 13-254; D.C. Official Code § 31-3831 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended by adding a new section 5b to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <num>5b</num>
        <heading>Coverage of women's preventive health services.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>An individual health plan or group health plan, a health insurer offering health insurance coverage for prescription drugs, and health insurance coverage through Medicaid and the DC Alliance program shall provide coverage for, and shall not impose any cost-sharing requirements on, women for the following preventive health services required to be covered under section 2713 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, approved March 23, 2010 (124 Stat. 131; 42 U.S.C. § 300gg-13), and the act's implementing regulations, guidelines, and recommendations:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Those evidence-based items or services that have in effect a rating of "A" or "B" in the recommendations of the United States Preventive Services Task Force as of April 4, 2017, available at https://www.uspreventiveservicestaskforce.org/Page/Name/uspstf-a-and-b-recommendations/;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Such additional preventive care and screenings not described in paragraph (1) of this subsection as provided for in comprehensive guidelines supported by the Health Resources and Services Administration as of April 4, 2017, available at https://www.hrsa.gov/womensguidelines/; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Any additional preventive services identified by the United States Preventive Services Task Force or the Health Resources and Services Administration after April 4, 2017.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) of this section shall be construed consistently with all provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, approved March 23, 2010 (124 Stat. 141; 42 U.S.C. § 18001 <em>et seq</em>.).</text>
        </para>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-3834.01" action="addition of § 31-3834.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
