<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>14-501</num>
  <heading>Proof of record.</heading>
  <text>An exemplification of a record under the hand of the keeper of the record, and the seal of the court or office where the record is made, is good and sufficient evidence to prove a record made or entered in any State, territory, commonwealth or possession of the United States. The certificate of the person purporting to be the keeper of the record, accompanied by the seal, is prima facie evidence of that fact.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Dec. 23, 1963, 77 Stat. 520</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-241" type="History">Pub. L. 88-241, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Certificate of incorporation, presumptive evidence of facts stated in certified copies, see § <cite path="§29-201.36">29-201.36</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Corporate stock books, presumptive evidence of facts, see § <cite path="§29-201.26">29-201.26</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation records, certified copies as evidence, see § <cite path="§3-3616">3-3616</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Domestic life insurance company, presumptive evidence of facts contained in stock book, see § <cite path="§31-4415">31-4415</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Fraternal benefit association, articles of association as prima facie evidence of existence and due incorporation, see § <cite path="§31-5709">31-5709</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Fraternal benefit association, original policies of liability of successor corporation as prima facie evidence upon division of insurance business, see § <cite path="§31-5725">31-5725</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Insurance superintendent, effect of authentication of papers, see § <cite path="§31-4301">31-4301</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public Utilities Commission, transcribed copy of proceedings, admissibility as evidence, see § <cite path="§43-622">43-622</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 14-501.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 14-501.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
