<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-187">
  <num type="law">11-187</num>
  <heading type="short">Alcoholic Beverage Underage Penalties Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-187.pdf">D.C. Law 11-187</citation>
      <citation type="register">43 DCR 4515</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0606">
      <narrative>Law 11-187, the “Alcoholic Beverage Underage Penalties Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-606, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 19, 1996, and July 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 22, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-340 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-187 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C ACT 11-340 Codi) ication District oj Columbia Code 1997 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 22, 1996 To amend the District of Columbia Alcoholic Beverage Control Act to provide for criminal and civil penalties for misrepresentation of age or purchase, possession, or consumption of alcoholic beverages by persons under 21 years of age. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Alcoholic Beverage Underage Penalties Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 30 of the District of Columbia Alcoholic Beverage Control Act, approved January 24, 1934 (48 Stat. 335; D.C. Code § 25-130 is amended as follows a) New subsections (b-l) and (b-2) are added to read as follows b-l) Any person under 21 years of age who falsely represents his or her age for the purpose of procuring alcoholic any beverage shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and be fined for each offense not more than $300, and in default in the payment of the fine shall be imprisoned not exceeding 30 days b-2) A civil fine may be imposed as an alternative sanction for any infraction of this section, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I through III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Code § 6-2701 et seq Civil Infractions Act Adjudication of any infraction of this section shall be pursuant to titles I through III of the Civil Infractions Act b) Subsection (c) is amended in the lead-in language by striking the phrase "provided in section 33" and inserting the phrase "proved in subsections (b-l) and (b-2) of this section" in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code Section 25-130 ENROLLED ORIGINAL § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1- 233(c)(1 and publication in t~e District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: July 22, 1996 COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COU~NCIL VOTE BII-606 Docket No. [ ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I ETION&amp;amp;DAT~ADOPTED FIRST READING, 06 9’96 APPROVEDD~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT CHMN. CLARKE, BRAZIL, JARVIS AND WHITTINGTON [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result CoUllcihuember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay N AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, Sr. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote AB Absent NV. Present not Voting ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [)~ACTION&amp;amp;DATE ADOPTED FINAL READING, 07-03-96 APPROVEDVOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result CHAVOUS Councibnember Aye Nay NW AB Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans t9 )L X’indicatesI S e c t~e Compel ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot !’Thomas, Sr. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Aye Nay NV AB NW.Present not young ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST AP, SENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Couocilmember ] Aye Nay NV AB Councihnember Chinn. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Light foot Chavo~s Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X Indicates Vote .C Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB Absent Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
