<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-171">
  <num type="law">11-171</num>
  <heading type="short">Community Development Corporations Money Lender License Tax Exemption Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-171.pdf">D.C. Law 11-171</citation>
      <citation type="register">43 DCR 4484</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0473">
      <narrative>Law 11-171, the “Community Development Corporations Money Lender License Tax Exemption Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-473, which was referred to the Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 4, 1996, and July 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 19, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-318 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-171 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwikta 062 318 289 (5) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11- 171 "Community Development Corporations Money Lender License Tax Exemption Amendment Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-473, on first and second readings, June 4, 1996 and July 3, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 19, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-318, and published in the August 23, 1996, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 43 page 4484) and transmitted to Congress on January 10, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-171, effective April 9, 1997. CHARLENE DREW JARVIS i Chairman Pro Tempore of the Coun~l~ Feb. Mar. Apr. 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,24,25,26,27,28 3,4,5,6,10,I 1,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21 7,8 Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: ENROLLED ORIGINAL Doe, AN ACT ACT 11-318 Cod~icagon D~trict Columb~ Code 1997 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 19, 1996 To amend An Act To regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms, and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real estate brokers in the District of Columbia to authorize the Mayor to waive certain bonding requirements and to exempt certain community development corporations acting as money lenders from the money lender license tax. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Community Development Corporations Money Lender License Tax Exemption Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. An Act To regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms~ and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real estate brokers in the District of Columbia, approved February 4, 1913 37 Stat. 657; D.C. Code § 26-701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 26-703) is amended by adding a new sentence at the end to read as follows The Mayor may waive the bonding requirements of this section, if alternative surety arrangements are secured, in cases involving parties specified in section 10 b) Section 10 (D.C. Code § 26-710) is amended by adding new subsections (c) and (d) to read as follows c) For the purposes of this section, the term 1 Community Development Corporation" or "CDC" means any community development corporation recognized by, and under contract with, the District of Columbia Department of Housing and Community Development (or any successor agency) that is engaged in business and economic development activities in the form of making microloans Section 26-703 Section 26-710 ENROLLED ORIGINAL through the use of funds loaned to them by nationally or locally chartered banks or financial institutions for the specific purpose of microlending, and which organization is organized under the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act, approved August 6, 1962 (76 Stat. 265; D.C. Code § 29-501 et seq and whose articles of incorporation and bylaws are consistent with rules and regulations issued by the Mayor of the District of Columbia pursuant to the District of Columbia Economic Development Finance Corporation Act of 1984, effective June 29, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-89; D.C. Code § 1-2211 et seq 2 Microloans" or "microlending" means a CDC engaging in the practice of making or issuing any loans up to, and including 25,000 to any person engaged in business within the District of Columbia 3 Person" means any natural person, partnership, limited partnership, or corporation, including corporations taxed under Subchapter S of the Internal Revenue Code d) No money lender license tax contained in this act shall be held to apply to a CDC engaged in microlending where the funds used for the microlending program were loaned to the CDC by a nationally or locally chartered bank or financial institution for the specific purpose of microlending, provided that the CDC operates and makes loans only in the geographical service area defined in their agreements with the District of Columbia Department of Housing and Community Development Sec. 3. The provisions of this act will have no negative fiscal impact on the General Fund of the District of Columbia. Community development corporations currently pay no money lender license tax to the District of Columbia, and will not participate in money lending programs if required to pay such tax. The loans being made do not replace any private commercial lending by institutions that would otherwise pay such tax. It is anticipated that microloans made by community development corporations under programs facilitated by this act will have a small positive economic impact on the fortunes of various District of Columbia neighborhoods, and thus a small, positive fiscal impact on the city’s General Fund. Revenue estimates for FY ’96 did not anticipate these taxes being paid, and therefore this act will not cause any change in revenue estimates. Under the narrow definition contained in the act, no more than 10 community-based ~oups will qualify for the waiver. The maximum amount that community development corporations engaged in microlending would pay to the District if not granted a waiver by the provisions of this act would be $8,000 in license taxes. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- ENROLLED ORIGINAL Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and/publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: July 19, 1996 3 l rrE~ os COSSF~r CALENVAR I~ ACTmS &amp;amp; VAn [~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE t~o. BII-473 ADOPTED FIRST READING~ 6-4-96 APPROVED EVANS AND CHAVOUS [ } ROLL CALL VOTE. Rtsult Councilmember Aye Nay Chran. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X. ndicates Vote ITEM ON CONSF~NT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE Coundlmember Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Aye Nay N’V AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington Ray AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD ~cretary to the Cotmdl NV- Present not V?ti~,g ADOPTED FINAL READING~ 7-3-96 APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councflmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X-indica~tes no I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR CHAVOUS Aye Nay NV AB Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB-Abs*mt CERTIFICATION RECORD NV-Presellt not vot~g bad ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray X Indicates Vote AB Absent Cotmcilmember Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington Aye Nay NT AB 1 NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Cotmdl Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
