<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-144">
  <num type="law">11-144</num>
  <heading type="short">Contribution Limitation Initiative Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1996-06-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-144.pdf">D.C. Law 11-144</citation>
      <citation type="register">43 DCR 2174</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0427">
      <narrative>Law 11-144, the “Contribution Limitation Initiative Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and Assigned Bill No. 11-427, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 5, 1996, and April 2, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 18, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-261 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-144 became effective on June 13, 1996.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 331 603 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-144 "Contribution Limitation Initiative Amendment Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-427, on first and second readings, March 5, 1996 and April 2, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 18, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-261 and published in the April 26, 1996, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 43 page 2174) and transmitted to Congress on May 1, 1996 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-144, effective June 13, 1996. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: May 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,17,20,21,22,23,24,28,29,30,31 June 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT ii-261 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APRIL 18, 1996 Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To repeal section 401 of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act and to amend the District of Columbia Contribution Limitation Initiative of 1992 to consolidate the election contributions provisions, to resolve inconsistencies between the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act and the Initiative, and to modify certain contribution limitations and reporting and disclosure requirements. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Contribution Limitation Initiative Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 401 of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act, approved August 14, 1974 (88 Stat. 459; D.C. Code §1-1441 is repealed. Sec. 3. The District of Columbia Contribution Limitation Initiative of 1992, effective March 17, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-204; D.C. Code § 1-1441.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code §1-1441.1) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended as follows A) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase 100" and inserting the phrase 2,000" in its place B) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase 100" and inserting the phrase 1,500" in its place C) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase 100" and inserting the phrase 1,000" in its place D) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrase 50" and inserting the phrase 500" in its place E) Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the phrase 50" and inserting the phrase 200" in its place F) A new paragraph (6) is added to read as follows 6) In the case of a contribution in support of a candidate for a member of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission 25 2) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows: Section I-1441 Section 1-1441.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL b)(1) No person shall make any contribution in any 1 election for Mayor, Chairman of the Council, each member of the Council, and each member of the Board of Education (including primary and general elections, but excluding special elections which when combined with all other contributions made by that person in that election to candidates and political committees exceeds $8,500 2) All contributions to a candidate’s principal political committee shall be treated as contributions to the candidate and shall be subject to the contribution limitations contained in section (a) through (6) of section 3) New subsections (d) through (i) are added to read as follows d)(1) No person shall make contributions to any 1 political committee in any 1 election (including primary and general elections, but excluding special elections) that, in the aggregate, exceeds $5,000 2) For the purposes of this subsection, the term "political committee" does not include an individual e) No person shall make a contribution in the name of another person, and no person shall knowingly accept a contribution made by 1 person in the name of another person f) Any expenditure made by any person advocating the election or defeat or any candidate for office which is not made at the request or suggestion of the candidate, any agent or the candidate, or any political committee authorized by the candidate to make expenditures or receive contributions for the candidate is not considered a contribution to or an expenditure by or on behalf of the candidate for the purposes of the limitations specified in this act g) All contributions made by any person directly or indirectly to or for the benefit of a particular candidate or that candidate’s political committee, which are in any way earmarked, encumbered, or otherwise directed through an intermediary or conduit to that candidate or political committee, shall be treated as contributions from that person to that candidate or political committee and shall be subject to the limitations established by this section h)(1) No candidate or member of the immediate family of a candidate may make a loan or advance from his or her personal funds for use in connection with a campaign of that candidate for nomination for election, or for election, to a public office unless that loan or advance is evidenced by a written instrument fully disclosing the terms, conditions, and parts to the loan or advance. The amount of any loan or advance shall be included in computing and applying the limitations contained in this section only to the extent of the balance of the loan or advance which is unpaid at the time of determination 2) For purposes of this subsection, the term "immediate family" means the candidate’s spouse, parent, brother, sister, or child, and the spouse of a candidate’s parent, brother, sister or child i) No contributions made to support or oppose initiative, referendum, or recall measures shall be affected by the provisions of this section b) Section 5 (D.C. Code §1-1441.3) is amended by striking the phrase 25" and inserting the phrase 50" in its place wherever it appears. Sectioli 1-1441.3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 4. The provisions of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act, approved August 14, 1974 (88 Stat. 446: D.C. Code § 1-1401 et seq shall apply to this act. sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1- Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(c and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in ~]/ta Register d~rn~an Council of the District of Columbia Note, Sections 1-1401, 1-1442, 1-1441.1 M~ Distr~ct of Columbia 18, 1996APPROVED: April ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B11-427 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST I ADING, 03-05-96 APPROVED, CHAVOUS CROPP, AND PATTERSON VOTED NO Xl VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTEON REQLrXST JAIRVIS VOTED PRESENT ABSENT LI GHTFOOT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Nay "iV B Com~c*|tnember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Smith. Jr. Lightfoot Thomas. Sr. Mason Whittington Patterson Evans Ray A~ X Indicates/L~ w V°te Setre~t~/’t~-thgrCounci! [ i ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [~i ACTION &amp;amp; DATE AB Absent N%’ Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ADOPTED FINAL READING, 04-02-96 VOICEVOTE APPROVED. CHAVOUS CROPP, JARVIS LIGHTFOOT AND RECORDED vorE ON rEQrESTPATTF.R~ONVOTED NO ~I~SENT ALL P~SENT ROLL CALL VOTE R~ulI Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray Aye Nay NV AB Counolmember Aye Nay NV AB Counc/hnember Aye Nay NW AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV-Present not votingX-!ndicates &amp;lt Cotmcil ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE vOICE VOTE AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB Cotmct~t~mtb~r Aye Nay NW AB Counc~nember X Indicates Vote Jarvi~ Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB- Absent lt; Aye Nay NW AB NV. Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTttICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D,C. 2C~004 APR 0 5 1996 The Honorable Marion Barry, Jr. Mayor of the District of Columbia 441 Fourth Street, N.W 1 lth Floor Washington, D.C. 20001 Re: Transmittal of Bill 11-427 "Contribution Limitation Initiative Amendment Act of 1996 Date of Council" Action: 04-02-96 Dear Mayor Barry: The above named enacted bill is hereby transmitted in accordance with Section 404(e) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to this bill, for your information, is the report of the Council’s standing committee with jurisdiction over this matter. Sincerely, David A. Clarke Chairman of the Council Eft.closure ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT 1N THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To repeal section 401 of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act and to amend the District of Columbia Contribution Limitation Initiative of 1992 to consolidate the election contributions provisions, to resolve inconsistencies between the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act and the Initiative, and to modify certain contribution limitations and reporting and disclosure requirements. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Contribution Limitation Initiative Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 401 of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act, approved August 14, 1974 (88 Stat. 459; D.C. Code §1-1441 is repealed. Sec. 3. The District of Columbia Contribution Limitation Initiative of 1992, effective March 17, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-204; D.C. Code § 1-1441.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code §1-1441.1) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended as follows A) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase 100" and inserting the phrase 2,000" in its place B) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase 100" and inserting the phrase 1,500" in its place C) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase "S10W and inserting the phrase 1,000" in its place. i D) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrase 50" and inserting the phrase 500" in its place E) Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the phrase 50" and inserting the phrase 200" in its place F) A new paragraph (6) is added to read as follows 6) In the case of a contribution in support of a candidate for a member of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission 25 2) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows: Section 1-1441 Section 1-1441.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL b)(1) No person shall make any contribution in any 1 election for Mayor, Chairman of the Council, each member of the Council, and each member of the Board of Education (including primary, and general elections, but exc!uding special elections which when combined with all other contributions made by that person in that election to candidates and political committees exceeds $8,500 2) All contributions to a candidate’s principal political committee shall be treated as contributions to the candidate and shall be subject to the contribution limitations contained in section (a) through (6) of section 3) New subsections (d) through (i) are added to read as follows d)(1) No person shall make contributions to any 1 political committee in any 1 election (including primary and general elections, but excluding special elections) that, in the aggregate, exceeds $5,000 2) For the purposes of this subsection, the term "political committee" does not include an individual e) No person shall make a contribution in the name of another person, and no person shall knowingly accept a contribution made by 1 person in the name of another person f) Any expenditure made by any person advocating the election or defeat or any candidate for office which is not made at the request or suggestion of the candidate, any agent or the candidate, or any political committee authorized by the candidate to make expenditures or receive contributions for the candidate is not considered a contribution to or an expenditure by or on behalf of the candidate for the purposes of the limitations specified in this act g) All contributions made by any person directly or indirectly to or for the benefit of a particular candidate or that candidate’s political committee, which are in any way earmarked, encumbered, or otherwise directed through an intermediary or conduit to that candidate or political committee, shall be treated as contributions from that person to that candidate or political committee and shall be subject to the limitations established by this section h)(1) No candidate or member of the immediate family of a candidate may make a loan or advance from his or her personal funds for use in connection with a campaign of that candidate for nomination for election, or for election, to a public office unless that loan or advance is evidenced by a written instrument fully disclosing the terms, conditions, and parts to the loan or advance. The amount of any loan or advance shall be included in computing and applying the limitations contained in this section only to the extent of the balance of the loan or advance which is unpaid at the time of determination 2) For purposes of this subsection, the term "intermediate family" means the candidate’s spouse, parent, brother, sister, or child, and the spouse of a candidate’s parent, brother, sister or child i) No contributions made to support or oppose initiative, referendum, or recall measures shall be affected by the provisions of this section b) Section 5 (D.C. Code §1-1441.3) is amended by striking the phrase 25" and inserting ~the phrase 50" in its place wherever it appears. Section 1441,3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 4. The provisions of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act, approved August 14, 1974 (88 Star. 446: D.C. Code § 1-1401 et seq shall apply to this act. Note, Sections 1-1441,1 Sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1- 233(c)(3 Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(c and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in ~Ta Register. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia 3 ’ ’ |TEM N CONSENT CtLENDAR X] kCTIO amp; D%FE COLNCIL OF THE D{STRIL-I F COLUMBIA COL NCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE BII-427 D ket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 03-05-96 APPROVED, CHAVOUS CROPP, AND PATTERSON VOTED NO ~EUC~ST JARVIS VOTED P~SENT LI GHTFOOT i I rC t her I \~e \a~ \ B C l her e. I ~’I \ B I C I ber k i t.B Chmn.(larke 1 ,larv~ Smith. Jr. Brazil Li~htfoot [homas. St. Cha~ous Mason ’ hittington Cropp I)atters,m E~ans Ray [ ITEM  CO~SENT CALENDAR ~OPTED FINAL ~ING, 04-02-96 XI~,I)tCE~,OTE APPROVED: CHAVOUS, CROPP; JARVIS, LIGHTFOOT AND ~CO~D~D~OrEO asTpATTERSON VOTED NO ALL P~SENT ROLL CALL %OTE R~ult t ,un~ilmember ’ t)e ~y ~V AB Co~lmember kye Nay NV B Cow.ember Aye %ay B Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Cha~ ous Mason Cropp Patterson E~ans Ray ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Smith. Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington I ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE vOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Jarvts Brazil Lightfoot Chavous 1 ason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray Aye Nay NV AB Cogncfln~m~.r Aye Nay N’V AB Cotm~ahneml~r Aye Nay N%’ AB X Indicates Vote Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington AB bscnt Present not glng C ERrlFICATION RECORD Secr~ary to the Council Dart</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
