<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-247" flag="true">
  <num type="law">11-247</num>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-247.pdf">D.C. Law 11-247</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>EN MENT(S) kwiktag ¯ 062 331 968 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-247 "Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 Time Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-922, on first and second readings, November 7, 1996 and December 3, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 24, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-507 and published in the March 7, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 1225) and transmitted to Congress on January 31, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-247, effective April 9, 1997 CHARLENE DREW JARVIS I Chairman Pro Yempore of the Counc~ Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,24,25,26,27,28 Mar. 3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21 Apr. 7,8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT ¯ D,C, ACT ii-507 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA ¯ DECEMBER 24, 1996 Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To amend, on a temporary basis, the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 to extend the time for mortgage lenders and brokers to obtain a license and to allow the Superintendent of the Office of Banking and Financial Institutions the authority, if necessary, to issue provisional licenses. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 Time Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. The Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996, effective September 9, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-155; t0be codified at D.C; Code § 26-1001 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 4(a to be codifi, e,d at D.C. Code § 26-1003(a is amended to read as follows a) No person shall engage in business as a mortgage lender or mortgage broker, or both, or h01d himself or herself out to the public to be a mortgage lender or mortgage broker for 150 days after the effective d~ite of this act, unless such person has first obtained a license under this act b) Section 5(b to be codified at D.C. Code § 26-1004(b is amended to read as follows b) The Supei’intendent shall approve or deny each application for a license within 60 days after the date. from when the application and bond are filed and the fees are paid. The Superintendent may issue a provisional license to an applicant who has filed the application and bond and paid all required fees if the Superintendent determines that he is unable to complete the application review process within 60 days Sec. 3. This act will not have a fiscal impact on the General Fund of the District. The act provides the Office of Banking and Financial Institutions with additional time to complete Note, Section 26~1003 Note, Section 26-1004 ENROLLED ORIGINAL the application review and licensing process involving mortgage lenders and brokers. Sec. 4 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and pul~li,~ation in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 2~ays its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 24, 1996 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALF~NDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU.~4~IA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE BII-922 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-7-96 ,x Vo,cE voTE APP ROVFD RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT CROPP, RAY AND THOMAS { I ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Cmmcilmember Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans I Aye Nay NV AB Counc$1membcr Aye Nay NV AB Councilmeml~r Aye Nay Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lighffoot Thomas, St. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray X l~mes vote i |1 ]" ] to~eCo~ [ [ ITEM ON CO~ENW CALeNdAR AB- Alm~nt CERTIFICATION RECORD ACTION &amp;amp; DATE NV AB ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-3-96 {~ VOICE VOTERECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT { ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmcmhe~ Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X-indicates no ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALEN])AR ] ACTION&amp;amp;DATE APPROVFn LIGHTFOOT AND MASON £ Aye Nay NT AB Couaci~member Aye Nay NV AB Counciimember Ay~ Nsy NV AB Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray AB-Absc~t CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Ceuncila~mber Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray Smith. Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington AB- Absent .NW. Pr~eat ~ot VmlltgX Indicates Vote CERTIFICATION RECORD Secret~ry. to the Council Dale ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia C e 1997 Supp. To amend, on a temporary basis, the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 to extend the time for mortgage lenders and brokers to obtain a license and to allow the Superintendent of the Office of Banking and Financial Institutions the authority, if necessary, to issue provisional licenses. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 Time Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. The Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996, effective September 9, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-155; to be codified at D.C. Code § 26-1001 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 4(a to be codified at D.C. Code § 26-1003(a is amended to read as follows a) No person shall engage in business as a mortgage lender or mortgage broker, or both, or hold himself or herself out to the public to be a mortgage lender or mortgage broker for 150 days after the effective date of this act, unless such person has first obtained a license under this act b) Section 5(b to be codified at D.C. Code § 26-1004(b is amended to read as follows b) The Superintendent shall approve or deny each application for a license within 60 days after the date from when the application and bond are filed and the fees are paid. The Superintendent may issue a provisional license to an applicant who has filed the application and bond and paid all required fees if the Superintendent determines that he is unable to complete the application review process within 60 days Sec. 3. This act will not have a fiscal impact on the General Fund of the District. The act provides the Office of Banking and Financial Institutions with additional time to complete Note, Section 26-1003 Note, SecAion 26-1004 ENROLLED ORIGINAL the application review and licensing process involving mortgage lenders and brokers. Sec. 4 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 2~5 idays 0f its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIl. OF D~CT OF COLL,’M~IA COUNCI~ PEI~OD CO~ OF O~ C~N~ V N. BII-922 ADOPTED FIRST READING~ 11-7-96 APPROVF~ CROPP, RAY AND THOMAS { I ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Aye Nay NV AB Councflmember Aye Nay N ABCov~ciimember Chmn. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans I Ray x" Tcates vine [ I ITEM ON CONSENT CALF~N’DAR [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE AB Al~teat CERTIFICATION RECORD Cmmdlmembcr Aye Nay NV Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington NV. Preseat a~t Vetiag ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-3-96 [~ VOICE VOTERECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result APPROVFB LIGHTFOOT AND MASON Councllmember Aye Nay Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X-indicates no ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE NW AB Coua~Imember Aye Nay [ NV AB Cetmcilmembcr Aye Nay N’V AB Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray AB-Abse~t CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALl, VOTE Result Councilmember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans .C m) Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NW AB Ceunctlmtqabcr Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas.Sr. WhiUington AB Ab~eatX Indicates Vote Present met ¥ottag CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary. to the Council I)~te</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
