<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-202">
  <num type="law">11-202</num>
  <heading type="short">Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-202.pdf">D.C. Law 11-202</citation>
      <citation type="register">43 DCR 6054</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0627">
      <narrative>Law 11-202, the “Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-627. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 3, 1996, and July 17, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 5, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-367 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-202 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 319 270 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C, ACT 11-367 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA AUGUST 5, 1996 Codi) ication District o) Columbia Code 1997 Sopp. To amend the Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Act of 1992 in order to implement requirements of the Medicare supplement minimum standards as mandated by the Social Security Act Amendments of 1994. These changes to the regulatory programs will ensure that the District of Columbia maintains approval as meeting minimum federal standards. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. The Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Act of 1992, effective October 1, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-170, D.C. Code § 35-2611 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(6 D.C. Code § 35-2611(6 is amended by striking the phrases "sectionSeetio, 1833" and "13951 or" and by striking the phrase "authorized pursuant to amendments to the 35-2611 federal Social Security Act" and inserting the phrase "specified in 42 U.S.C. § 13955s(g)(1 in its place. Section (b) Section 3(a D.C. Code § 35-2612(a is amended by striking the phrase "in 35-2612 section 5 c) Section 3(c D.C. Code § 35-2612(c is amended by striking the word "The" and Sectio. 35-2612inserting the phrase "Except as otherwise specifically provided in section 6(d the" in its place d) Section 6(d D.C. Code § 35-2615(d is amended by striking the phrase "by reasonSectio, of age" 35-2615 Section(e) Section 6(d)(3 D.C. Code § 35-2615(d)(3 is repealed. 35-2615 (f) Section 6(d)(4)(D.C. Code § 35-2615(d)(4 is repealed. Section 35-2615 Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code ENROLLED ORIGINAL § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Section 8 of the Mutual Holding Company Act of 1996, signed by the Mayor on June 21, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-290; 43 DCR is amended to read as follows Sec. 8. Limitations of actions Any action challenging the validity of or arising out of acts taken or proposed to be taken under this act shall be commenced within 30 days after the effective date of any plan submitted for approval pursuant to this act Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1- 233(c)(1 and u publication i mbia Register fhairman Council of the District of Columbia Section 35-3727 District of Columbia APPROVED: August 5, 1996 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEWEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE D o. BII-627 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 7-3’96 APPROV[D RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST CHAVOUS ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result J. Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye NayCouncilmember Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X ¯ Indica~ Vote ITEM ON CONSF~NT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Council Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV AB AB Absent NV preset not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ADOPTED FINAL READING, 7-17-96 VOICE VOTE APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON ~QUEST ABSENT BRAZIL, CROPP, CHAVOUS, THOMAS &amp;amp;WHITTINGTON ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Chlnn. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray J ecreeo’ to the Coond| ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALEN3AR ] ACTION &amp;amp; DA~E Aye Nay NW AB Councilmember Aye Nay N’V AB Coundlmembcr Aye Nay NV AB AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV-Present not voting VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Aye Nay Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans x. Indicates Vote NW A B Councilmember Aye Nay NW AB Councilmember Aye Nay NW AB Jarv~ Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB- Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secreta to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codij ication District o) Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To amend the Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Act of 1992 in order to implement requirements of the Medicare supplement minimum standards as mandated by the Social Security Act Amendments of 1994. These changes to the regulatory programs will ensure that the District of Columbia maintains approval as meeting minimum federal standards. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. The Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Act of 1992, effective October 1, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-170, D.C. Code § 35-2611 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(6 D.C. Code § 35-2611 (6 is amended by striking the phrases "sectionsection 1833" and "13951 or" and by striking the phrase "authorized pursuant to amendments to the 35-2611 federal Social Security Act" and inserting the phrase "specified in 42 U.S.C. § 1395ss(g)(1 in its place, sectio b) Section 3(a D.C. Code § 35-2612(a is amended by striking the phrase "in 35-2612 section 5 c) Section 3(c D.C. Code § 35-2612(c is amended by striking the word "The" andSe~tio. 35-2612 inserting the phrase "Except as otherwise specifically provided in section 6(d the" in its place d) Section 6(d D.C. Code § 35-2615(d is amended by striking the phrase "by reasonSection of age" 35-2615 Section (e) Section 6(d)(3 D.C. Code § 35-2615(d)(3 is repealed. 35-2615 (f) Section 6(d)(4)(D.C. Code § 35-2615(d)(4 is repealed. Se~tio, 35-2615 Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. ¯ The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code ENROLLED ORIGINAL § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Section 8 of the Mutual Holding Company Act of 1996, signed by the Mayor on June 21, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-290; 43 DCR is amended to read as follows Sec. 8. Limitations of actions Any action challenging the validity of or arising out of acts taken or proposed to be taken under this act shall be commenced within 30 days after the effective date of any plan submitted for approval pursuant to this act Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1- 233 (c)(1))’ and publicati°i umbia Register" Council of the District of Columbia Section 35-3727 Mayor District of Columbia 2 ITEM ON CONSF2~T CALF~VDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE voxc~ vo~ COUNCIL OF THE DLSTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFI~CIAL COUNCIL VOT BII-627 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 7-3’96 APPROVED ~CO~ED ~OTEO.~T CHAVOUS ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- ResuR Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay N AB Co~mcilmemb~r A~ Nay Chron. Clarke JarvB Smith, Jr. Brazil Lightfoot Thomas, St. Chavous Mason Whittington Cropp Patterson Evans Ray [ I ITEM ON CONSF~"Ir CALENDAR ADOPTED FINAL READING, 7--17--96 ACTION &amp;amp; DATE NV P~sent ~ot Voting APPROVEDVOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT BRAZIL, CROPP, CHAVOUS, THOMAS &amp;amp; WHITTINGTON [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councihnember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Cha~ous Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay N AB Counctlmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, Sr. Mason Whittington Cropp Evans Ray X-Indicates no ~the Council Patterson AB-Abse~t CERTIFICATION RECORD ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR NW.Prese~t not voting U I Dat¢~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE. Result £ C~amcilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans A.~e Nay .N AB Counci|member JarvB Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray X Indicates Vote Aye Nay NW AB Coun cilmember Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB- Absent Aye Nay N AB Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretar)’ to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
