<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-215">
  <num type="law">11-215</num>
  <heading type="short">Oyster Elementary School Modernization and Development Project Temporary Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-215.pdf">D.C. Law 11-215</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 11-215, the “Oyster Elementary School Modernization and Development Project Temporary Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-828. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 17, 1996, and October 1, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 15, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-413 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-215 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwikta 062 319 441 (5) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-215 "Oyster Elementary School Modernization and Development Project Temporary Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-828, on first and second readings, July 17, 1996 and October 1, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 15, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-413, and published in the November 15, 1996, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 43 page 6070) and transmitted to Congress on January 15, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-215, effective April 9, 1997 Chairman Pro Tempore of the Co¢/ Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. Mar. Apr. 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,24,25,26,27,28 3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21 7,8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 11-413 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 15, 1996 Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To provide, on a temporary basis, authorization to modernize the James F. Oyster Elementary School, to privately develop a portion of the Oyster school site, and to fund the improvements to Oyster School and other public school facilities through payments in lieu of taxes on the privately developed portion of the Oyster School site. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Oyster Elementary School Modernization and Development Project Temporary Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Definitions. For purposes of this act, the terms 1 Board" means the Board of Education of the District of Columbia 2 Council" means the Council of the District of Columbia 3 District" means the District of Columbia Government 4 Mayor" means the Mayor of the District of Columbia 5 Payments in lieu of taxes" means payments into the Board of Education Real Property Improvement and Maintenance Fund, established by section 2(b)(1) of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Code § 9-402(b)(1 of the equivalent of Class 1I property taxes at 100% of the assessed valuation of the privately owned building or structure occupying any portion of the Oyster School site 6 Privately owned structure" means any building or structure not owned by the District of Columbia govemment or any of its agencies that is erected on the Oyster School site under a long-term lease or other agreement between a developer and the District of Columbia Public Schools. Sec. 3. Authorization of private development on the Oyster Elementary School site a) The Board of Education, pursuant to the District of Columbia Board of Education Leasing Authority Act of 1982, effective September 29, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-158; D.C. Code § 31-201 is authorized to enter into a long-term land lease for private development of part of the James F. Oyster Elementary School site. Pursuant to section 2(c) of the District of Note, Section 31-209 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Columbia Board of Education Leasing Authority Act of 1982, effective September 29, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-158; D.C. Code § 31-201(c all proceeds derived from the private development, including payments in lieu of taxes PILOTS shall be deposited into the Board of Education Real Property Improvement and Maintenance Fund. Any proceeds which remain after paying the costs of modernizing Oyster Elementary School shall be used for repair, modernization and improvements of other school system facilities b) Privately owned or used structure, erected or constructed on the Oyster School site, shall annually pay in lieu of taxes an amount that is equivalent to Class II property taxes at 100% of the assessed valuation of the privately owned or used structure. Sec. 4. Conforming amendment. Section 2(c-1) of the District of Columbia Board of Education Leasing Authority Act of 1982, effective September 29, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-158; D.C. Code § 31-201(c-1 is amended to read as follows c-l) All proceeds received by the Board of Education for leasing school properties, including payments in lieu of taxes, shall be deposited into the Board of Education Real Property Improvement and Maintenance Fund established by section 2(b)(1) of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Code § 9-402(b)(1 and shall be available for expenditure, for the purposes set forth in that act until actually expended Sec. 5. Rulemaking. The Mayor, or in a control year, the Chief Financial Officer on behalf of the Mayor, shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. The rules shall be submitted to the Council of the District of Columbia within 60 days of enactment of this act. Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement a) The total estimated cost of the Oyster Elementary School modernization project is: Modernization/Construction Telecommunications Upgrade, Temporary Moving and Relocation, and Furnishing Costs Total Project Cost $5,500,000 600,000 $6,100,000 (b) It is expected that a land lease for the Oyster School modernization and development project will be executed in December of 1996. The land lease is expected to be of at least 70 to 80 years duration. Its value is expected to approximate $4,140,000, based on an anticipated land lease per unit present value of $20,000. Once the actual value is determined as a result of the prevailing bid in response to a Request for Proposals CRFP the developer, instead of actually making annual land lease payments to the school system, will repay the value ENROLLED ORIGINAL of the land lease by performing the construction necessary to modernize Oyster Elementary School. Thereafter, no revenue stream will derive from the land lease insofar as repayment of financing and related costs to modernize Oyster Elementary School will, in effect, constitute full payment for the land lease over its lifetime c) Using standard valuation techniques, the total value of the privately developed portion of the Oyster School modernization and development project is estimated at $22,021,400, or 80% of total projected hard costs of $22,021,400, as follows: Apartment Building Garage Other Site Work Total Project Hard Costs Valuation @ 80 17,782,000 3,823,300 416,200 $22,021,400 $17,61%120 (d) Using a land lease per unit value of $20,000 for 207 apartment units, the total value of the land lease will approximate $4,140,000, or $1,960,000 less than total project costs of $6,100,000. The difference of $1,960,000--or the project costs that will not be covered by the value of the land lease--will also be financed by the developer, according to the project’s draft RFP at an estimated 10% rate of interest over a 30 year period (though if a School Management and Construction Authority, or some similar entity, is established in the near future, it is likely that the funds borrowed by the developer can be refinanced at a lower annual interest rate Annual repayments to retire the costs of the developer’s additional financing, assuming a 10% annual rate of interest, would approximate $207,915 e) The 207 unit matter-of-right high density apartment building is expected to be constructed and ready for occupancy between July and September 1999. Assuming the property valuation of $17,617,120 in subsection (c) of this section, and the existing class II real property tax rate of $1.54 for each $100 of assessed value, it is projected that annual payments in lieu of taxes (PILOTs) will approximate $265,000, which would result in a net revenue stream beginning no later than in fiscal year 1999 of some $57,805, or funds sufficient to leverage borrowing of some $500,000 at 10% annual interest. Assuming no growth in property valuation or increase in class 11 real property tax rates, the Oyster School modernization and development project can be expected to generate net revenues of at least $1,734,150 over the first 30 years of the project, though it is very possible that the net revenues generated from the project could be much higher, especially if the per unit valuation exceeds $20,000 per unit f) The Oyster School modernization and development project will have no impact on the District’s operating or capital budgets until at least fiscal year 1999. All project costs, including financing and borrowing, will be paid off without the expenditure of any public funds. Beginning with fiscal year 1999, net revenues derived from this project and deposited into the Board of Education Real Property Improvement and Maintenance Fund will have to be annually appropriated, in accordance with existing law and practice. Before then, and once the project is ENROLLED ORIGINAL underway and the timing of a net revenue stream can more accurately be projected, the District’s multi-year plan as it pertains to DCPS should be adjusted to reflect the net revenues to be derived annually from this project as well as the amount and types of annual facilities-related costs to be funded from net project revenues. Sec. 7. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Govemmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act sha~xpire after 225 days of its having taken effect. \ \ Chairman Council of the District of Columbia May~r V Dist~ct of Columbia APPROVED: October 15, 1996 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE ~CO~ VO~ ON ~QU~ COUNCIL OF THE DISTRIC~ OF COLILMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE ~o. BII-828 ADOPTED FIRST READING~ 07-17-96 APPROVED ABSENT CHAVOUS AND SMITH [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilnl~tber Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember ’ Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, St. Mason Whittington Patterson Evans Ray X- In ¢~ V~t AB- Ab.s.e.nt f C~RTIFICATION RECORD secretary to th¢counca [~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE ADOPTED FINAL READING, 10’01’96 [~VOICEVOTE RECORDED VOTEONREQUEST ABSENT APPROVED LIGHTFOOT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Com~eilmember Aye Nay NV AB Cotmdimember Chron. Clarke Jarvis razil Lighffoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson E~ans Ray ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Aye Nay NV AB Corot ~nesnber Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington Aye Nay NV VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Cotmcilmember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB Cotmcilmember X Indicates Vote Jarvis Lighffoot Mason Patterson ,Ray Aye Nay NV AB Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Cottndl Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
