<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-275">
  <num type="law">11-275</num>
  <heading type="short">Second Criminal Code Technical Amendments Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-06-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-275.pdf">D.C. Law 11-275</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 1408</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0909">
      <narrative>Law 11-275, the “Second Criminal Code Technical Amendments Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-909, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-520 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-275 became effective on June 3, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN MEN (S) kwiktag 062 331 919 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-275 "Second Criminal Code Technical Amendments Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-909, on first and second readings, November 7, 1996 and December 3, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 24, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-520 and published in the March 14, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 1408) and transmitted to Congress on January 30, 1997 for a 60-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(2) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 60-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-275, effective June 3, 1997. Acting Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 60rday Congressional Review Period: Feb. Mar. Apr. May June 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,24,25,26,27,28 3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21 7,8,9,10,14,15,16,17,21,22,23,24,25,28,29,30 1,5,6,7,8,9,12,13,14,15,16,19,20,21,22 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C. ACT 11-520 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 24, 1996 Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to correct a punctuation error and to delete extraneous language; to amend the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953 to correct a grammatical error; to amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to correct typographical errors; to amend An Act In relation to pandering, to define and prohibit the same and to provide for the punishment thereof to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Anti-Intimidation and Defacing of Public or Private Property Criminal Penalty Act of 1982 to correct a grammatical error; to amend An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes to make stylistic corrections; to amend An Act To define and punish vagrancy in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes to make a stylistic correction and correct a section reference; to amend An Act To provide for the treatment of sexual psychopaths in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes to correct a section reference; to amend the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982 to make stylistic corrections, correct punctuation errors, and add clarifying language; to amend the Anti-Sexual Abuse Act of 1994 to make stylistic corrections and delete extraneous language; to amend Title 23 of the District of Columbia Code to make grammatical, stylistic, and clarifying corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953 to correct a grammatical error; to amend the Medical and Geriatric Parole Act of 1992 to correct a grammatical error; to amend the Resocialization Furlough Act of 1976 to correct a punctuation error and paragraph and subsection designations; to amend An Act To establish a program for the rehabilitation of alcoholics, promote temperance, and provide for the medical and scientific treatment of persons found to be alcoholics by the courts of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes to correct a grammatical en’or; ENROLLED ORIGINAL BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Second Criminal Code Technical Amendments Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 907a(b)(1) of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved July 29, 1970 (84 Stat. 599; D.C. Code § 22-104a(b)(1 is amended by striking the phrase "territories and adding the phrase "territories; and" in its place. Sec. 3. Section 806(b) of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1322; D.C. Code § 22-504(b is amended by striking the phrase b) Stalking Any" and adding the phrase b) Any" in its place. Sec. 4. Section 205(a) of the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953, approved June 29, 1953 (67 Stat. 95; D.C. Code § 22-505(a is amended by striking the phrase "campus and" and adding the phrase "campus or" in its place. Sec. 5. Section 801a(b) of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, effective September 26, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-153; D.C. Code § 22-2404.1(b is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the word "kidnaping" and adding the word "kidnapping" in its place b) Paragraph (11) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end. Sec. 6. Sections 4 and 5 of An Act In relation to pandering, to define and prohibit the same and to provide for the punishment thereof, approved June 25, 1910 (36 Stat. 833; D.C. Code §§ 22-2708 and 22-2709 are amended by striking the phrase "less than 1" and adding the phrase "less than I year" in its place. Sec. 7. Section 2(1) of the Anti-Intimidation and Defacing of Public or Private Property Criminal Penalty Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-203; D.C. Code § 22- 3112.1 (1 is amended by striking the word "and" at the end and adding the word "or" in its place. Sec. 8. Section 1 of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Stat. 650; D.C. Code § 22- 3201 is amended as follows a) Subsection (h) is amended by adding the phrase as used in this act after the word "Playground b) Subsection (i) is amended by adding the phrase as used in this act after the word Section 22-104a Section 22-504 Section 22-505 Section 22-2404.1 Sections 22-2708, 22-2709 Section 22-3112.1 Section 22-3201 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "arcade c center Subsection (j) is amended by adding the phrase as used in this act after the word Sec. 9. An Act To define and punish vagrancy in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved December 17, 1941 (55 Stat. 808; D.C. Code § 22-3302 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 1 (8 D.C. Code § 22-3302(8 is amended by striking the phrase "And all" and adding the word "All" in its place b) Section 6 (D.C. Code § 22-3306) is amended by striking the figure "6" and adding the figure "4" in its place. Sec. 10. Section 209 of An Act To provide for the treatment of sexual psychopaths in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved June 9, 1948 (62 Stat. 350; D.C. Code § 22-3511 is amended by striking the figure "209" and adding the figure "208" in its place. Sec. 11. Section 209(a) of the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953, approved June 29, 1953 (67 Stat. 97; D.C. Code § 22-3601 is amended by adding the word "year" after the phrase "not less than 1" Section 22-3302 Section 22-3306 Section 22-3511 Seclion 22-3601 Sec. 12. The District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code § 22-3801 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 103 (D.C. Code § 22-3803) is amended as follows: Sectio 1) The lead-in language is amended by striking the word "both" and adding the22-a8o3 phrase "the same act or course of conduct for the following" in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and adding a period in its place and by striking the phrase "for the same act or course of conduct at the end b) Section 112 (D.C. Code § 22-3812) is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the word "lst" and adding the word 22-3s12 "first" in its place and by adding the phrase "in the first degree" after the word "theft 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "2nd" and adding the word "second" in its place and by adding the phrase "in the second degree" after the word "theft Sec. 13. The Anti-Sexual Abuse Act of 1994, effective May 23, 1995 (D.C. Law 10- 257; D.C. Code § 22-4101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 201 (D.C. Code § 22-4102) is amended as follows 1) The lead-in language is amended to read as follows A person shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life, and in addition, may be fined in an amount not to Section 22-4102 3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL exceed $250,000, if that person engages in or causes another person to engage in or submit to a sexual act in the following manner 2) Paragraph (4) is amended to read as follows 4) After administering to that other person by force or threat of force, or without the knowledge or permission of that other person, a drug, intoxicant, or other similar substance that substantially impairs the ability of that other person to appraise or control his or her conduct b) Section 202 (D.C. Code § 22-4103) is amended as follows 1) The lead-in language is amended to read as follows A person shall be imprisoned for not more than 20 years and may be fined in an amount not to exceed $200,000, if that person engages in or causes another person to engage in or submit to a sexual act in the following manner 2) Paragraph (2) is amended as follows A) By striking the word "actor" and adding the word "person" in its place; and act B) Subparagraph (C) is amended to read as follows C) Incapable of communicating unwillingness to engage in that sexual Section 22.4103 (c) Section 203 (D.C. Code § 22-4104) is amended as follows: Sea~on (1) The lead-in language is amended to read as follows A person shall be 22-4104 imprisoned for not more than 10 years and may be fined in an amount not to exceed $100,000, if that person engages in or causes sexual contact with or by another person in the following manner 2) Paragraph (4) is amended to read as follows 4) After administering to that person by force or threat of force, or without the knowledge or permission of that other person, a drug, intoxicant, or similar substance that substantially impairs the ability of that other person to appraise or control his or her conduct d) Section 204 (D.C. Code § 22-4105) is amended as follows: Sect~o 1) The lead-in language is amended to read as follows A person shall be 22-41os imprisoned for not more than 5 years and, in addition, may be fined in an amount not to exceed $50,000, if that person engages in or causes sexual contact with or by another person in the following manner 2) Paragraph (2) is amended as follows A) By striking the word "actor" and adding the word "person" in its place and by adding the word "other" before the phrase "person is and (B) Paragraph (C) is amended to read as follows C) Incapable of communicating unwillingness to engage in that sexual contact 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 14. Title 23 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows: s~cnon 23-109 (a) Section 23-109 is amended by striking the word "attorney" and adding the word "Attorney" in its place b) Section 23-523(a) is amended by striking the phrase "23-521(0(7 and adding thes~aion phrase "23-521 (0(6 in its place. 23-523 (c) Section 23-541 is amended as follows: s~cnon (1) Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the word "and" and adding the word23-541 "or" in its place 2) Paragraph (8)(A) is amended by striking the word "and" and adding the word "or" in its place d) Section 23-555(a) is amended by striking the phrase Courff’ and adding the wordsectio,,23-555 "Court" in its place e) Section 23-704(e) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrases~aio subsection (d 23-7o4 (f) Section 23-1322(f)(2)(C) is amended by striking the phrase "section 502 of the s~ctio District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 198223-1322 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code § 22-722 and adding § 22-722 in its place. Sec. 15. Section 405(3) of the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953, approved June 29, 1953 (67 Stat. 105; D.C. Code § 24-106(3 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Sec. 16. Section 2(2) of the Medical and Geriatric Parole Act of 1992, effective May 15, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-271; D.C. Code § 24-261(2 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Sec. 17. Section 4 of the Resocialization Furlough Act of 1976, effective April 23, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-130; D.C. Code § 24-483 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended as follows 1) By striking the phrase "subsection (b and adding the phrase "subsection (c in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the semicolon and adding a period in its place; and (3) Paragraph (4) is amended by redesignating it as subsection (b) and by striking the phrase "of this subsection" and adding the phrase "of subsection (a in its place b) Subsection (b) is redesignated as subsection (c c) Subsection (c) is redesignated as subsection (d d) Subsection (d) is redesignated as subsection (e Section 24-106 Section 24-261 Section 24-483 5 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 18. Section 3(a)(2) of An Act To establish a program for the rehabilitation of alcoholics, promote temperance, and provide for the medical and scientific treatment of persons found to be alcoholics by the courts of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved August 4, 1947 (61 Stat. 744; D.C. Code § 24-523(a)(2 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Section 24-523 Sec. 19. The act makes technical amendments to existing legislation and therefore has no fiscal impact. Sec. 20. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provid.ed in s~tion 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmen¢ l~(tnization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code~-2~y] bfication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia A~PROVED: December 24, 1996 6 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR AC~ON ¯ DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL,’MBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN ~O~OFO~,LCO~VOTE BII-909 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-7-96 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUF.~f ABSENT APPROVED THOMAS { ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay AB Coundlmember Aye Nay ~ AB Cotmcilmember Aye Nay NT All Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, Sr. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray X ¯ Indicates Vote ~the Council AB- Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE NV. pr ttt not Vo~ng ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12’3-96 I vo, cE VOTE AP P ROVEDI~ECORDED VOTE ON RF.QUEST ABSENT RAY { ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councflmembec Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X-indicates no [ ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [ ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Aye Nay NV AB Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB CouncilmemberAye Nay Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray AB-Absmt CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV AB r f A NV-Pr ett not voting Date [ 1 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT | I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB Counciimember Aye Nay Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray X Indicates Vote AB- Absent AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV. Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to correct a punctuation error and to delete extraneous language; to amend the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953 to correct a grammatical error; to amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to correct typographical errors; to amend An Act In relation to pandering, to define and prohibit the same and to provide for the punishment thereof to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Anti-Intimidation and Defacing of Public or Private Property Criminal Penalty Act of 1982 to correct a grammatical error; to amend An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes to make stylistic corrections; to amend An Act To define and punish vagrancy in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes to make a stylistic correction and correct a section reference; to amend An Act To provide for the treatment of sexual psychopaths in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes to correct a section reference; to amend the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982 to make stylistic corrections, correct punctuation errors, and add clarifying language; to amend the Anti-Sexual Abuse Act of 1994 to make stylistic corrections and delete extraneous language; to amend Title 23 of the District of Columbia Code to make grammatical, stylistic, and clarifying corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953 to correct a grammatical error; to amend the Medical and Geriatric Parole Act of 1992 to correct a grammatical error; to amend the Resocialization Furlough Act of 1976 to correct a punctuation error and paragraph and subsection designations; to amend An Act To establish a program for the rehabilitation of alcoholics, promote temperance, and provide for the medical and scientific treatment of persons found to be alcoholics by the courts of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes to correct a grammatical error; ENROLLED ORIGINAL BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Second Criminal Code Technical Amendments Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 907a(b)(1) of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved July 29, 1970 (84 Stat. 599; D.C. Code § 22-104a(b)(1 is amended by striking the phrase "territories and adding the phrase "territories; and" in its place. Sec. 3. Section 806(b) of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1322; D.C. Code § 22-504(b is amended by striking the phrase b) Stalking Any" and adding the phrase b) Any" in its place. Sec. 4. Section 205(a) of the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953, approved June 29, 1953 (67 Stat. 95; D.C. Code § 22-505(a is amended by striking the phrase "campus and" and adding the phrase "campus or" in its place. Sec. 5. Section 801a(b) of An Act To establish a code of law for t.he District of Columbia, effective September 26, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-153; D.C. Code § 22-2404. l(b is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the word "kidnaping" and adding the word "kidnapping" in its place b) Paragraph (11) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end. Sec. 6. Sections 4 and 5 of An Act In relation to pandering, to define and prohibit the same and to provide for the punishment thereof, approved June 25, 1910 (36 Stat. 833; D.C. Code §§ 22-2708 and 22-2709 are amended by stlSking the phrase "less than 1" and adding the phrase "less than 1 year" in its place. Sec. 7. Section 2(1) of the Anti-Intimidation and Defacing of Public or Private Property Criminal Penalty Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-203; D.C. Code § 22- 3112.1(1 is amended by striking the word "and" at the end and adding the word "or" in its place. Sec. 8. Section 1 of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Stat. 650; D.C. Code § 22- 3201 is amended as follows a) Subsection (h) is amended by adding the phrase as used in this act after the word "Playground b) Subsection (i) is amended by adding the phrase as used in this act after the word Section 22-104a Section 22-504 Section 22-505 Section 22-2404.1 Sections 22-2708, 22-2709 Section 22-3112.1 SectiOl~ 22-3201 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "arcade c center Subsection (j) is amended by adding the phrase as used in this act after the word Sec. 9. An Act To define and punish vagrancy in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved December 17, 1941 (55 Stat. 808; D.C. Code § 22-3302 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 1 (8 D.C. Code § 22-3302(8 is amended by striking the phrase "And all" and adding the word "All" in its place b) Section 6 (D.C. Code § 22-3306) is amended by striking the figure "6" and adding the figure "4" in its place. Sec. 10. Section 209 of An Act To provide for the treatment of sexual psychopaths in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved June 9, 1948 (62 Stat. 350; D.C. Code § 22-3511 is amended by striking the figure "209" and adding the figure "208" in its place. Sec. 11. Section 209(a) of the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953, approved June 29, 1953 (67 Stat. 97; D.C. Code § 22-3601 is amended by adding the word "year" ’after the phrase "not less than 1 Section 22-3302 Section 22-3306 Section 22-3511 Section 22-3601 Sec. 12. The District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code § 22-3801 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 103 (D.C. Code § 22-3803) is amended as follows: Se~on (1) The lead-in language is amended by striking the word "both" and adding the 22-3803 phrase "the same act or course of conduct for the following" in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and adding a period in its place and by striking the phrase "for the same act or course of conduct at the end b) Section 112 (D.C. Code § 22-3812) is amended as follows: Seaion (1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the word "lst" and adding the word z2-3sn "first" in its place and by adding the phrase "in the first degree" after the word "theft 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "2nd" and adding the word "second" in its place and by adding the phrase "in the second degree" after the word "theft Sec. 13. The Anti-Sexual Abuse Act of 1994, effective May 23, 1995 (D.C. Law 10- 257; D.C. Code § 22-4101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 201 (D.C. Code § 22-4102) is amended as follows 1) The lead-in language is amended to read as follows A person shall be imprisoned for any term of years or/’or life, and in addition, may be fined in an amount not to Section 22-4102 ENROLLED ORIGINAL exceed $250,000, if that person engages in or causes another person to engage in or submit to a sexual act in the following manner 2) Paragraph (4) is amended to read as follows 4) After administering to that other person by force or threat of force, or without the knowledge or permission of that other person, a drug, intoxicant, or other similar substance that substantially impairs the ability of that other person to appraise or control his or her conduct b) Section 202 (D.C. Code § 22-4103) is amended as follows 1) The lead-in language is amended to read as follows A person shall be imprisoned for not more than 20 years and may be fined in an amount not to exceed $200,000, if that person engages in or causes another person to engage in or submit to a sexual act in the following manner 2) Paragraph (2) is amended as follows A) By striking the word "actor" and adding the word "person" in its place; and act B) Subparagraph (C) is amended to read as follows C) Incapable of communicating unwillingness to engage in that sexual Section 22-4103 (c) Section 203 (D.C. Code § 22-4104) is amended as follows 1) The lead-in language is amended to read as follows A person shall be 41o4 imprisoned for not more than 10 years and may be fined in an amount not to exceed $100,000, if that person engages in or causes sexual contact with or by another person in the following manner 2) Paragraph (4) is amended to read as follows 4) After administering to that person by force or threat of force, or without the knowledge or permission of that other person, a drug, intoxicant, or similar substance that substantially impairs the ability of that other person to appraise or control his or her conduct d) Section 204 (D.C. Code § 22-4105) is amended as follows: Se~o 1) The lead-in language is amended to read as follows A person shall be 41os imprisoned for not more than 5 years and, in addition, may be fined in an amount not to exceed $50,0000, if that person engages in or causes sexual contact with or by another person in the following manner 2) Paragraph (2) is amended as follows A) By striking the word "actor" and adding the word "person" in its place and by adding the word "other" before the phrase "person is and (B) Paragraph (C) is amended to read as follows C) Incapable of communicating unwillingness to engage in that sexual contact 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 14. Title 23 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows: sel..tiOl|23-109 (a) Section 23-109 is amended by striking the word "attorney" and adding the word "Attorney" in its place b) Section 23-523(a) is amended by striking the phrase "23-521(f)(7 and adding thesection phrase "23-521(f)(6 in its place. 23-5z3 (c) Section 23-541 is amended as follows: seetio|| (1) Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the word "and" and adding the word 23-541 "or" in its place 2) Paragraph (8)(A) is amended by striking the word "and" and adding the word "or" in its place d) Section 23-555(a) is amended by striking the phrase Court}" and adding the word secret 23-555 "Court" in its place e) Section 23-704(e) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phraseswat,| "subsection (d 23.704 (f) Section 23-1322(f)(2)(C) is amended by striking the phrase "section 502 of the Se~o, District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 198223.132z (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code § 22-722 and adding § 22-722 in its place. Sec. 15. Section 405(3) of the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953, approved June 29, 1953 (67 Stat. 105; D.C. Code § 24-106(3 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Sec. 16. Section 2(2) of the Medical and Geriatric Parole Act of 1992, effective May 15, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-271; D.C. Code § 24-261(2 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Sec. 17. Section 4 of the Resocialization Furlough Act of 1976, effective April 23, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-130; D.C. Code § 24-483 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended as follows 1) By striking the phrase "subsection (b and adding the phrase "subsection (c in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the semicolon and adding a period in its place; and (3) Paragraph (4) is amended by redesignating it as subsection (b) and by striking the phrase "of this subsection" and adding the phrase "of subsection (a in its place b) Subsection (b) is redesignated as subsection (c c) Subsection (c) is redesignated as subsection (d d) Subsection (d) is redesignated as subsection (e Section 24-106 Section 24-261 Section 24-483 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 18. Section 3(a)(2) of An Act To establish a program for the rehabilitation of alcoholics, promote temperance, and provide for the medical and scientific treatment of persons found to be alcoholics by the courts of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved August 4, 1947 (61 Stat. 744; D.C. Code § 24-523(a)(2 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Sec. 19. The act makes technical amendments to existing legislation and therefore has no fiscal impact. Sec. 20. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in sO’ion 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmen~ R/ao anization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)¢ n~tC~blication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Section 24.523 Mayor District of Columbia I~ IT~t oN CONSF~Cr CALF~NV~ [ ACTION ¯ DATE COL~NCIL OF THE DI~"RICT OF COLL,’MBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN REco~o, om co~vo~ BII-909 l)o~kct No ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-7-96 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABS F~N’T APPROVED THOMAS [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay N’V AB Councilmember Aye Nay NT AB Councilmember Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, St. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote AB Absent ~o CERTIFICATION RECORD~he Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALEN~)AR ~AC~O~*DATE ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-3-96 ~’O,CE VOTE APP ROVEI)RECORDED VOTE ON REQU ABSE RAY NV. P~t not, Voting I ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilm~nber Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB I Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Counciiratmimr Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, Sr. Mason Whittington patters°n Ray Ai~Abs~t CERTIFICATION RECORD not voting Date [ ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Counci,member Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NW AB Counctlmember Aye Nay AB Coundimember Aye Nay NV All Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray X htdicatm Vote Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB.Absent NW Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Sect-teary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
