<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-39">
  <num type="law">11-39</num>
  <heading type="short">Business Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-09-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-39.pdf">D.C. Law 11-39</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 3273</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0051">
      <narrative>Law 11-39, the “Business Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-51, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 2, 1995, and June 6, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 19, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-72 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-39 became effective on September 8, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENRO M kwiktag 062 319 597 N (S COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11- 39 Business Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Governmem and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-51 on first and second readings, May 2, 1995 and June 6, 1995, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 19, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-72 and published in the June 30, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 3273) and transmitted to Congress on June 22, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-39, effective September 8, 1995. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: June July Aug. 22,23,26,27,28,29,30 10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28,31 1,2,3,4 Sept. 5,6,7 AN ACT D, C, ACT 11- 72 ENROLL!!O ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Codo Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 19, 1995 To amend the District of Columbia Business Corporation Act of 1954 to allow corporations to file 5-year reports instead of annual reports and to increase the fees associated with filing reports. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Business Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Business Corporation Act, approved June 8, 1954 (68 Star. 179; D.C. Code § 29-301 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 98 (D.C. Code § 29-398) is amended as follows: Seetio, 29-398 (1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "of each year, an annual" and inserting the phrase "of each fifth year from the date of incorporation, if there has been no change in material facts, a 5-year" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "annual" and inserting the phrase "5-year" in its place b) Section 112 (D.C. Code § 29-399.13) is amended as follows: Seetio 1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "of each year with the 29-399.13 Mayor an annual" and inserting the phrase "of each fifth year from the date of authorization to do business in the District of Columbia, if there has been no change in material facts, a 5-year" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase "Such annual report" and inserting the phrase "Such 5-year report" in its place c) Section 115 (D.C. Code § 29-399.16) is amended as follows: Seetio 1) Subsection (a)(6) is amended by striking the word "annual" and inserting the29-399.16 phrase "5-year" in its place 2) Subsection (b)(2) is amended by striking the word "annual" and inserting the phrase "5-year" in its place d) Section 121 (D.C. Code § 29-399.22) is amended as follows: Section 29-399.22 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (1) Subsection (d) is amended as follows A) By striking the phrase "an annual report fee of $100" and inserting the phrase "a 5-year report fee of $500 B) By striking the phrase "the annual report" and inserting the phrase "the 5-year report and (C) By striking the last sentence in its entirety 3) Subsection (e) is amended by striking the word "annual" in each place it appears and inserting the phrase "5-year" in its place e) Section 122 (D.C. Code § 29-399.23) is amended by striking the word "annual" in the title and in every other place it appears and inserting the phrase "5-year" in its place f) Section 128 (D.C. Code § 29-399.29) is amended by striking the word "annual" in the title and every other place it appears and inserting the phrase "5-year" in its place g) Nothing in this act shall be construed or interpreted as repealing or affecting any requirement of a domestic or foreign corporation to prepare and submit annual tax forms, or to pay any appropriate District or federal taxes, as provided in accordance with the laws of the District of Columbia or the United States. Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1R9e7g~s(t~r7’ St~;t .D~t3r~c tD "o cC°dolt~ b~i ~’~t3a3t (c)0~n-u 9~s,~t-L 2g ep?Ob~i~iOD sil/ni cel toh~ rctohle Dumi~ai c~ o2i cCiOplat~nbia Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia Section 29-399.23 Section 29-399.29 Note, Section 29-398 APPROVED: June 19, 1995 ITEM ON coNsK’cr C~Ait ACTION ¯ DATE COU.~NCII. O DISTIUCT Oft’ COUNCIL PgIaIOD O~D OF OffiCIAL CO~ICIL VOTg B11-51Dodr~,t No. Adopted First Reading, 05-02-95 1~ voicg vo~ R~O~DI~ VOTE ON R~QL’EST Approved ai i present I ] ROLL CALL VOTE Cutmcilmember Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NT AB Cotmcilmember Jarvis Light foot Mason Patte~on Ray Nay N’V AB Cotmcdmemi~r Aye Nay N% AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. CERTIFICATION RECORD eta~ to the Cotm XAC~O~*OA opted Final Reading, 06-06-95 ApprovedVOICE VOTE RECedED vo’rr o r~~T BsE~T Brazi I and Tho~s ROLL CALL VOTE. Result C.uncdmember j te a V AB Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Cotmcflmember ~ye Nay N3 AB Councflmember Jarvis Smith. Jr. Lightfoot Thomas. St. WhittingtonMason Patterson Ray AB-Abs~tt ] ITEM ON CONSF~N~r CALENI)AR CERTIFICATION RECORD Aye Na NV B NW-Pr~tmt not voting [ I ~ll~Vcr¢ ON REQUEST [ I itOI,LCALLVOTg. RmIll Clmm. Clm’ke Brazil Chavote~ Crel~ Eva Aye Nay AB Comldimem~r Aye Nay An C~m¢~melkm" Aye Nay NV A~ JarvM Light feet Mason Patterson Ray smirk, Jr. Thom~ St I COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 dUN 0 9 1995 The Honorable Marion Barry, Jr. Mayor of the District of Columbia 441 4th Street, N.W 1 lth Floor Washington, D.C. 20001 Re: Transmittal of Bill 11-51 Business Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995 Date of Council Action: 06-06-95 Dear Mayor Barry: The above named enacted bill is hereby transmitted in accordance with Section 404(e) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to this bill, for your information, is the report of the Council’s standing committee with jurisdiction over this matter DfvSince~ Chairman of the Council Enclosure AN ACT ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Codc 1996 Supplement) 1N THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Business Corporation Act of 1954 to allow corporations to file 5-year reports instead of annual reports and to increase the fees associated with filing reports. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Business Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Business Corporation Act, approved June 8, 1954 (68 Stat. 179; D.C. Code § 29-301 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 98 (D.C. Code § 29-398) is amended as follows: S~ction 29-398(1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "of each year, an annual" and inserting the phrase "of each fifth year from the date of incorporation, if there has been no change in material facts, a 5-year" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "annual" and inserting the phrase "5-year" in its place b) Section 112 (D.C. Code § 29-399.13) is amended as follows: Section(1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "of each year with the 29-399.13 Mayor an annual" and inserting the phrase "of each fifth year from the date of authorization to do business in the District of Columbia, if there has been no change in material facts, a 5-year" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase "Such annual report" and inserting the phrase "Such 5-year report" in its place c) Section 115 (D.C. Code § 29-399.16) is amended as follows: Scctio I) Subsection (a)(6) is amended by striking the word "annual" and inserting the29-399.16 phrase "5-year" in its place 2) Subsection (b)(2) is amended by striking the word "annual" and inserting the phrase "5-year" in its place d) Section 121 (D.C. Code § 29-399.22) is amended as follows: Section 29-399.22 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (1) Subsection (d) is amended as follows A) By striking the phrase "an annual report fee orS100" and inserting the phrase "a 5-year report fee of $500 B) By striking the phrase "the annual report" and inserting the phrase "the 5-year report and (C) By striking the last sentence in its entirety 3) Subsection (e) is amended by striking the word "annual" in each place it appears and inserting the phrase "5-year" in its place e) Section 122 (D.C. Code § 29-399.23) is amended by striking the word "annual" in the title and in every other place it appears and inserting the phrase "5-year" in its place f) Section 128 (D.C. Code § 29-399.29) is amended by striking the word "annual" in the title and every other place it appears and inserting the phrase "5-year" in its place g) Nothing in this act shall be construed or interpreted as repealing or affecting any requirement of a domestic or foreign corporation to prepare and submit annual tax forms, or to pay any appropriate District or federal taxes, as provided in accordance with the laws of the District of Columbia or the United States. Section 29-399.23 Section 29-399.29 Note, Section 29-398 Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Colusnbia Statu!~e’s-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia 2 DATE IgCOID o~ Ot~CIAL COt2~CIL VOTI Adopted First Reading, 05-02o95 Approved al I present ROLL CALL VOTE. Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp E~ans Jarvis Smith. Jr. Thoma&amp;amp; St.Lightfoot Mason Patterson [ndlca|e~ Vcxe X ITEM I1% CONSENT CALENDAR CTN)N &amp;amp; DATE Adopted Final Readi ng, 06-06-95 x cr. ’.~rE ’Approved REC }Pd)ED VOTE 0’~ REQLE3T Brazi 1 and Thongs Chmn. Clarke Cha~ous Crupp l~ arts Jar~i~ Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Al~Abmt [ t [T,~M ON CONSF r CALKNDAR CERTIFICATION RKCORD Counclh~mber ~ve gt g Smith. Jr ] Thom St, Whittington Jar~ Li~ttfoot Masea</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
