<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-36">
  <num type="law">11-36</num>
  <heading type="short">INSURANCE OMNIBUS TEMPORARY AMENDMENT ACT OF 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1995-09-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-36.pdf">D.C. Law 11-36</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 3257</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0181"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 330 251 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11- 36 Insurance Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-181 on first and second readings, May 2, 1995 and June 6, 1995, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 19, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-69 and published in the June 30, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 3257) and transmitted to Congress on June 22, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-36, effective September 8, 1995 F Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: June July Aug. Sept. 22,23,26,27,28,29,30 10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28,31 1,2,3,4 5,6,7 £NROLL[D ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT ii-69 Codification District of Columbia Code 996, Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 19, 1995 To amend, on a temporary basis, the Insurers Rehabilitation and Liquidation Act of 1993, the Risk Retention Act of 1993, the Reinsurance Intermediary Act of 1993, the Annual Audited Financial Reports Act of 1993, the Law on Credit for Reinsurance Act of 1993, the Law on Examinations Act of 1993, the Holding Company System Act of 1993, the Fire and Casualty Act of 1940, and the Life Insurance Act of 1934 to correct technical errors and omissions. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the Insurance Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 Sec. 2. Section 50(c) of the Insurers Rehabilitation and Liquidation Act of 1993, effective October 15, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-35; D.C. Code § 35-2849(c is amended by striking the phrase "county in which the principal business of the company is located, or the county in which its principal office or place of business is located and inserting the phrase "District of Columbia" in its place. Note, Section 35-2849 Sec. 3. The Risk Retention Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-46; D.C. Code § 35-2901 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(12)(C D.C. Code § 35-2901(12)(C is amended to read as follows C) Which is chartered and licensed as a liability insurance company and authorized to engage in the business of insurance under the laws of any state; or which, before January 1, 1985, was chartered or licensed and authorized to engage in the business of insurance under the laws of Bermuda or the Cayman Islands and, before that date, had certified to the insurance commissioner of at least one state that it satisfied the capitalization requirements of that state, except that any group shall be considered a risk retention group only if it has been engaged in business continuously since that date and only for the purpose of continuing to provide insurance to cover product liability or completed operations liability, as these terms were defined in the federal Product Liability Risk Retention Act of 1981, approved September 25, 1981 (95 Stat. 949; 15 U.S.C. 3901 et seq before the date of the enactment of the Liability Risk Retention Act of 1986, approved October 27, 1986 (100 Stat. 3170; 15 U.S.C. 3901 et Note, Section 35-2901 I IIIOLLHI OIIIWAL seq b) Section 2(12 D D.C. Code § 35-2901(12)(D is repealed c) Section 2(12)(H)(ii D.C. Code § 35-2901 (12)(H)(ii is amended by striking the phrase 9)(F and inserting the phrase 9)(G in its place d) Section 4(1)(A D.C. Code § 35-2903(1)(A is amended by adding the phrase "on a form prescribed by the NAIC" after the phrase "submit to the Mayor e) Section 4(4 D.C. Code § 35-2903(4 is amended to read as follows 4) Any risk retention group, its agents, and representatives shall comply with District law governing fraud or deceptive practices. If the Mayor seeks an injunction regarding this conduct, the injunction shall be obtained from a court of competent jurisdiction f) Section 4(5 D.C. Code § 35-2903(5 is amended to read as follows Any risk retention group shall comply with the laws governing the proper transaction of insurance business as provided by the District g) Section 12(d D.C. Code § 35-291 l(d is amended by striking the phrase "8(c and inserting the phrase "9(b in its place. Note, Section 35-2901 Note, Section 35-2901 Note, Section 35-2903 Note, Section 35-2903 Note, Section 35-2903 Note, Section 35-2911 Sec. 4. The Reinsurance Intermediary Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-47; D.C. Code § 35-3101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 7(4)(E D.C. Code § 35-3106(4)(E is amended by striking the phrase "Names and addresses of reinsurers and inserting the phrase "Names and addresses of ceding insurers in its place b) Section 1 l(a)(3)(D.C. Code § 35-3110(a)(3))is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" and inserting the word "Superintendent" in its place c) Section 1 l(b D.C. Code § 35-3110(b is amended by striking the phrase "managing general agent" and inserting the phrase "reinsurance intermediary" in its place. Note, Section 35-3106 Note, Section 35-3110 Note, Section 35-3110 Sec. 5. Annual Audited Financial Reports Act of 1993, effective October 2 l, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-48; D.C. Code § 35-3201 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 4(6)(A D.C. Code § 35-3203(6)(A is amended to read as follows A) A reconciliation of differences, if any, between the audited statements to be filed with the Mayor and the NAIC annual statement filed pursuant to the insurance laws of the District of Columbia; and b) Section 6(a D.C. Code § 35-3205(a is amended to read as follows a) The Mayor shall not recognize any person or firm as a qualified independent certified public accountant that is not in good standing with the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants in all states in which the accountant is licensed to practice, or, for a Canadian or British company, that is not a chartered accountant c) Section 6(d)(1 D.C. Code § 35-3205(d)(1 is amended to read as follows 1) Has been convicted of fraud, bribery, a violation of the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act, approved October 15, 1970 (84 Stat. 941; 18 U.S.C. § 1961 et seq or any dishonest conduct or practices under federal or state law d) Section 8 (D.C. Code § 35-3207) is amended to read as follows Financial statements furnished pursuant to section 4 shall be examined by an Note, Section 35-3203 Note, Section 35-3205 Note, Section 35-3205 Note, Section 35-3207 2 EHROLLED ORIGINAL independent certified public accountant. The examination of the insurer’s financial statements shall be conducted in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards. Consideration should also be given to such other procedures illustrated in the Financial Condition Examiner’s Handbook promulgated by the NAIC as the independent certified public accountant deems necessary e) Section 9(c D.C. Code § 35-3208(c is amended by striking the word "Mayor" and inserting the word "accountant" in its place f) Section 11(5 D.C. Code § 35-3210(5 is amended to read as follows 5) The accountant is properly licensed by. an appropriate state licensing authority and is a member in good standing in the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants Sec. 6. Section 2(a) of the Law on Credit for Reinsurance Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-36; D.C. Code § 35-3301 (a is amended by inserting the phrase"(1 before the phrase 2 3 4 or (5 Sec. 7. Section 5(d)(2)(A) of the Law on Examinations Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-49; D.C. Code § 35-3604(d)(2)(A is amended by striking the sentence "The Mayor shall not appoint an examiner as an authorized representative to conduct the hearing Sec. 8. The Holding Company System Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-44; D.C. Code § 35-3701 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 7(a)(4 D.C. Code § 35-3706(a)(4 is amended by striking the number "10" and inserting the number "12" in its place b) Section 7(c)(2 D.C. Code § 35-3706(c)(2 is amended by striking the phrase "5(a)(1 and inserting the phrase "7(a)(1 in its place c) Section 1 l(b)(2 D.C. Code § 35-3709(b)(2 is amended by striking the word "3" and inserting the word "4" in its place. Sec. 9. The Fire and Casualty Act, approved October 9, 1940 (54 Stat. 1063; D.C. Code § 35-1501 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 of chapter I (D.C. Code § 35-1503)is amended by amending the definition for "admitted assets" to read as follows Admitted assets" includes the investments authorized or permitted pursuant to the National Association of Insurance Commissioners Accounting Practices Manual b) Section 27 of chapter II (D.C. Code § 35-1531) is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) A filing fee of $25 shall be paid to the District of Columbia through the Superintendent of Insurance for each rate, rule, or rate and rule filing for use in the District Sec. 10. Section 2(b) of chapter II of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1934 Note, Section 35-3208 Note, Section 35-3210 Note, Section 35-3301 Note, Section 35-3604 Note, Section 35-3706 Note, Section 35-3706 Note, Section 35-3709 Note, Section 35-1503 Note, Section 35-1531 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (48 Stat. 1130; D.C. Code § 35-402(b is amended to read as follows b) For filing charter or articles of incorporation or association, or deed of settlement or copy thereof, required by law 300; for each company certificate of authority 200, renewal fee 200; for license of each general agent 100, renewal fee 100; for license of each agent, or solicitor 50, renewal fee $50; for license of each broker 100, renewal fee 100. For each appointment fee for each agent, general agent or each solicitor 25 fee 25 renewal fee; provided, however, that beginning October 1, 1994, the license and renewal fee of each general agent, agent or solicitor, and broker shall be payable biennially in accordance with the rulemaking procedures in section 3(a)(2 Sec. 11. Effective date a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This ~t shall elpire on the 225th day of its having taken effect or upon the effective date of the Ins~endment Act of 1995, whichever occurs first. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Note, Section 35-402 ITEM ON" CONSENT CALENDAR C~rlO amp; bATE COLLNCIL OF ’THE DISTRICT OF COLL,’MBIA COLLNCIL PERIOD RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE ~o tSo. B1 1 1,81 Adopted First Reading, 05.02,-95 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VO~E ON REQUEST ABSENT Approved Jarvis, Lightfoot and Ray [ 1 ROLL CALL VOTE- Result C0llncJ|nlelBber e Nay NV AB Coull~lmelllber Chron. Clarke .Jarv Brazil Light foot ~Chavous Mason [Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X [ndi~tes Vole i~ iTEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE Vt)TE RECORDkD VOFE ON REQU~T I NV AB I Ct~tmcilmember Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Aye Nay NV AB XB Absent NV Present not Voting Adop,ted Fi ha Readi nq, 06-06,,95 Approved Brazil and Thomas ’ R{ LL CALL VO’I’E Result "’ i C.uncthuelub,er NV Chron. Clarke Brazil Light foot Chav~us Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray Nay NV AB CoUncllmen~ber Aye Nay )JNV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD N’/-Present not voting U ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST AgSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Co~mcilmember Aye Nay NW AB Coancilmembcr Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lighffoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray x lndltmt~ Vote Aye NW AB Cotmdlmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Tkom~s, Sr. Whittington AB- Absent NV. Present not Voting CI~RTIFICATION RECORD Sec~tary to t~ Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
