<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-49">
  <num type="law">11-49</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Courses Temporary Amendment Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-49.pdf">D.C. Law 11-49</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 11-49, the “District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Courses Temporary Amendment Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-309. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 6, 1995, and June 20, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 6, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-91 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-49 became effective on September 20, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN N (S) kwiktag 062 317 37’1 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA D.C. LAW 11-49 "District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Courses Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-309 on first and second readings, June 6, 1995 and June 20, 1995, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 6, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-91 and published in the July 14, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 3632) and transmitted to Congress on July 11, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-49, effective September 20, 1995 i ’~ DAVID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July 11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28,31 Aug. 1,2,3,4 Sept. 5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 11-91 Codification District of Columbia Code 1996 i SupplementJ IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 6, 1995 To authorize, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Board of Education to charge fees for all adult, community, and continuing education courses. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, that this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Courses Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Select Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Courses Act of 1994, effective March 16, 1995 (D.C. Law 10-221; 41 DCR 8047) is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 31-131) is repealed b) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 31-132) is amended as follows 1) By amending subsection (a) to read as follows a) The District of Columbia Board of Education Board of Education is authorized to charge fees for all adult, community, and continuing education courses; provided that no additional fees shall be charged for ongoing courses in Academic Year 1994-1995 and Fiscal Year 1995 until those courses are completed 2) By amending subsections (b c d and (e) by striking the word "select" wherever it appears; and (3) By amending subsection (d) by striking the phrase "fiscal year 1995 Supplemental Budget" and inserting the phrase "Annual Budget Request Act" in its place. Sec. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, Note, Section 31-131 Note, Section 31-132 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c 1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect or upon the effective date of the District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Co~~95, whichever occurs first. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia 2 [ ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [ X ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUbIBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE D N~ Bli-309 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 06-06-95 [~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED BRAZIL EVANS AND RAY [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Co~ncilmonber Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X [ndht~tes Vo(e Aye Nay NV AB Councllmember Aye Nay NV AB Coun ¢ilmember Jarvis Smith, Jr. Aye Nay NV AB Lighffoot Mason Patterson Ray Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ADOPTED FINAL READING. 06-20-95 APPROVED ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Councilmember Chmn. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Ligl~tfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X-indicaffs no L ~the Council ALL PRESENT Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington AB-Absent NV.Present not voting Date ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE CERTIFICATION RECORD [ ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Clarke l Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X Indicates Vote £ Cotmcilmember Aye Nay NV AB Counc~member Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson. Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV .Pr ent not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
