<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-63">
  <num type="law">11-63</num>
  <heading type="short">College and University Campus Security Amendment Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-10-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-63.pdf">D.C. Law 11-63</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 4109</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0152">
      <narrative>Law 11-63, the “College and University Campus Security Amendment Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-152, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 20, 1995, and July 11, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 25, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-120 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-63 became effective on October 18, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LL N (S) kwiktag~ 103 225 881 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA D.C. LAW 11-63 "College and University Campus Security Amendment Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-152 on first and second readings, June 20, 1995 and July 11, 1995 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 25, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-120 and published in the August 11, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 4109) and transmitted to Congress on July 28, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-63, effective October 18, 1995 197kVIl~ A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July Aug. Sept. Oct. 28.31 1,2,3,4 5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,25,26,27,28,29 10,11,12,13,17 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 11-120 Codification District of Columbia Code 1996 _Supplement} IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 25, 1995 To amend title 6A of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations by adding a new chapter 12 to allow special police officers to be designated as campus and university special police officers and to amend the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953 to make laws against assaulting members of the police force applicable to campus and university special police officers. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "College and University Campus Security Amendment Act of 1995 Sec. 2. Title 6A of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (Police Personnel) is amended by adding a new chapter 12 to read as follows CHAPTER 12 "Sees 1200 "1201 "1202 "1203 "1204 "1205 "1206 "1207 "1208 CAMPUS AND UNIVERSITY SPECIAL POLICE Appointment: General Provisions Appointment: Section 4-114 Appointments Restrictions Revocation and Termination of Appointment Applications Duration [Reserved] Uniforms Disciplinary Action "1200 APPOINTMENT: GENERAL PROVISIONS "1200.1 Campus and university special police officers may be appointed by the Chief of Police for duty in connection with the property of, or under the charge of, an academic institution of higher education requesting the appointment. DCMR ENROLLED ORIGINAL "1200.2 Campus and university special police officers appointed pursuant to § 1200.1 shall be strictly confined in their authority to the particular place or property they are commissioned to protect 1200.3 Commissions issued to campus and university special police officers shall specify the following information a) The particular place or property they are commissioned to protect b) Any waiver of the uniform requirement; and c) In the case of § 1201.2, any requirement for storage or special provision for transportation of firearms or other dangerous weapons 1200.4 Each appointment of a campus or university special police officer shall be made for a period of two (2) years 1200.5 No person appointed as a campus or university special police officer shall legally exercise any authority conferred by that appointment after the date of expiration of that appointment 1200.6 Upon termination of employment, the campus and university special police officer shall return the commission of authority to the issuing agency. In addition, campus and university special police officers commissioned to carry firearms shall submit annually a certification of annual firearms qualification to the Security Officers Management Branch, Intelligence Division, Metropolitan Police Department 1200.7 Campus and university special police officers appointed under the provisions of § 1202.4 shall be subject to the rules promulgated for the Metropolitan Police Department insofar as those rules are applicable 1200.8 No person shall be appointed as a campus or university special police officer under the An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred, and for other purposes, approved March 3, 1899 (30 Stat. 1057; D.C. Code § 4-I 14 or section 6 of An Act providing a permanent form of government for the District of Columbia, approved June 11, 1878 (20 Star. 107; D.C. Code § 4-130 unless that person meets the following requirements a) Is at least twenty one (21) years old b) Is a citizen of the United States c) Is of good moral character d) Is approved for appointment by the Chief of Police e) Receives one (1) week (40 hours) of indoctrination training prior to performing any patrol duties. In addition, armed campus and university special police officers must successfully complete a fifty-six (56) hour basic firearms course. The firearms training course shall include, but not be limited to, lethal and nonlethal force shoot, don’t shoot and police liability. Armed campus and university special police officers are required to qualify with their firearms on a semi-annual basis; and f) Completes the Campus Law Enforcement Academy (250 hours) or an equivalent law enforcement academy within two (2) years of receiving a campus and university special 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL police officer commission or has previously completed an equivalent law enforcement academy. Previous law enforcement or security training of two hundred and fifty (250) hours may be substituted to meet the requirements of this subsection 1201 APPOINTMENT: SECTION4-114 APPOINTMENTS "1201.1 For the purposes of this chapter, the term "D.C. Code § 4-114" refers to An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred, and for other purposes, approved March 3, 1899 (30 Stat. 1057; D.C. Code § 4-114 1201.2 Campus and university special police officers may be appointed under the provisions of D.C. Code § 4-114 to protect the campus property of an academic institution of higher education. The term "campus" shall include any building or property owned or controlled by the academic institution of higher education 1201.3 The duties of the campus and university special police officers appointed pursuant to § 1201.2 shall consist of integrating the principles of private and public policing and adapting them to the academic community. The names and addresses of the academic institution of higher education and the location of the property to be protected shall be specified upon the face of the commission issued to that campus or university special police officer 1202 RESTRICTIONS "1202.1 No person appointed as a campus or university special police officer under the provisions of D.C. Code § 4-114 shall display a badge, weapon, or other evidence of authority in any place other than the property owned by, or under the control of, the academic institution of higher education upon whose account he or she was appointed and by whom he or she is paid 1202.2 Each person appointed as a campus or university special police officer under the provisions of D.C. Code § 4-114 shall carry his or her commission on his or her person when on duty, in uniform, or armed 1202.3 Firearms or other dangerous weapons carried by a campus and university special police officer on the premises for which he or she holds a commission shall be left on the premises when that officer is not actually on duty 1202.4 Nothing contained in this chapter shall prevent a campus or university special police officer appointed under the provisions of D.C. Code § 4-114 from exercising his or her authority as an officer outside of the property or area he or she is appointed to protect when in fresh pursuit of a felon or misdemeanant from, or immediately adjacent to, the property or area to which he or she is commissioned to protect 1203 REVOCATION AND TERMINATION OF COMMISSION "1203.1 Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the exercise of authority as a campus or university special police officer in carrying or using firearms, other dangerous weapons, or emblems of authority, in violation of §§ 1202.1, 1202.2, and 1202.3, shall be cause ENROLLED ORIGINAL of immediate revocation of the commission of such officer, in addition to the penalties under any laws of the United States or the District of Columbia which may be violated by the campus or university special police officer 1203.2 Within twenty-four (24) hours after the expiration or revocation of his or her commission or upon the termination of his or her employment by the academic institution of higher education, each appointed campus and university special police officer shall deliver to the Chief of Police his or her commission. Upon his or her failure to do so, he or she shall, upon each conviction thereof in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, be punished by a fine of not more than three hundred dollars 300 1204 APPLICATIONS "1204.1 Applications for the appointment of campus and university special police officers shall be made jointly in the names of the prospective officers and the name of the academic institution of higher education or corporation representing the academic institution of higher education in connection with the campus for which the appointment is sought, upon forms supplied by the Chief of Police 1204.2 The forms supplied pursuant to § 1204.1 shall contain an agreement by the academic institution of higher education to notify the Chief of Police of any termination or change in the employment status of the prospective campus or university special police officer 1204.3 The form to be approved pursuant to the requirements of this chapter shall contain the following information a) Space for the entry of the information required by this chapter; and b) Printing on the reverse side of the form indicating the provisions of this chapter in the Manual of Rules and Regulations of the Metropolitan Police Department and the substance of the provisions of D.C. Code § 4-114, with reference to campus and university special police officers 1204.4 The commission shall be made out in duplicate, with the original delivered to the campus or university special police officer appointed, and the copy retained in the files of the Chief of Police with the endorsement on that copy that the applicant has received the original and agrees to its terms 1204.5 Campus and university special police officers shall report to the Chief of Police, within five (5) days after termination, the name of the academic institution of higher education specified on their commission at which they are no longer employed 1205 DURATION "1205.1 A commission as a campus or university special police officer under the provisions of D.C. Code § 4-114 shall be effective for a period of two (2) years. Renewal of a commission for additional two (2) year periods may be made in the discretion of the Chief of 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Police 1206 RESERVED "1207 UNIFORMS "1207.1 Unless, for good cause shown, the wearing of a uniform is specifically waived upon the face of the commission by the Chief of Police, campus and university special police officers, while on duty, shall wear distinctive uniforms. A director or chief of a campus or university special police officer department shall have the authority to temporarily waive the uniform requirement for an employee of their department for a period not to exceed forty-eight (48) hours upon verbal approval by the Chief of Police and written authorization transmitted by facsimile 1207.2 On each uniform for campus and university special police officers, there shall be sewn on the left sleeve of the uniform blouse, coat, or shirt (if worn without blouse) a distinctive shoulder patch, the top of which is to be two (2) inches below the shoulder 1207.3 The distinctive shoulder patch required pursuant to § 1207.2 shall conform to the following requirements a) Be of a different shade from the color of the uniform to which it is attached b) Be at least three (3) inches in height and width; and c) Carry thereon in suitable contrasting colors the words "CAMPUS SPECIAL POLICE" or "UNIVERSITY SPECIAL POLICE" in letters not less than one half (½) inch high, together with the name or abbreviation of the employer of the campus and university special police officer 1207.4 Campus and university special police officers employed by the government of the District of Columbia shall wear a four (4) inch half-circle patch, carrying thereon in one (I) semicircular line the words "SPECIAL POLICE CAMPUS SPECIAL POLICE or "UNIVERSITY SPECIAL POLICE" in letters not less than three-eighths (3/8) inch high at the top of the half-circle 1207.5 Uniforms of campus and university special police officers shall be furnished with nickel-plated or comparable buttons. The use of brass or yellow buttons is prohibited, except that sergeants, lieutenants, and captains may wear gold buttons 1207.6 Nickel-plated or comparable buttons on the front of the uniform blouse or coat shall be at least seven-eighths (7/8) inch in diameter and buttons used elsewhere on the uniform shall be at least five-eighths (5/8) inch in diameter. The buttons may bear on their face the letters "CP" or the letter "P 1208 DISCIPLINARY ACTION "1208.1 The District commanders shall report to the Chief of Police any information supplied to them by the patrol force of the several police districts concerning conduct by any campus or university special police officer which, in the commander’s judgment, requires ENROLLED ORIGINAL disciplinary action Sec. 3. Section 205(a) of the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953, approved June 29, 1953 (67 Stat. 95; D.C. Code § 22-505(a is amended by inserting the phrase "including any campus and university special police officers after the phrase "or interferes with any officer or member of any police force operating in the District of Columbia See. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statute-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Note, Section 22-505 District APPROVED: July 25, 1995 6 iTEM ON CONSF~NT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD EI~EVEN BECORD OF OF~CIAL COL~ICIL VOTE BII-152 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 06-20-95 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSF~/T APPROVED ALL PRESENT I } ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans ~Cotmcil Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Cotmctlmember Aye Nay .NV AB Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington AB- Absent N’V ¯ Preset not Votin~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACT/ON &amp;amp; DATE CERTIFICATION RECORD Date ADOPTED FINAL READING, 07-11-95 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED CHAVOUS ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X-indicates ~o [ I ITEM ON CONSENT CALendAR Aye Nay NV AB Cotmcilmembef Aye Nay NV AB Cotmdhnember Aye Nay NN AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, Sr. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray Al~-Abse~t NV-Present not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD { I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE [ ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSF~NT { ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Coencilmember Chron. Clarke Jarvis Smith, Jr. Brazil Lighffoot Thomas, St. Chavoas Mason Whittington Cropp Patterson Evans Ray Aye Nay NV AB Cotm~/Imemb~r Aye Nay NN AB Cotmcflmember Aye Nay N’V AB X htdlcates Vote AB Ab~t NV. Pr nt not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Se~’emry to the Couneii Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
