<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-97">
  <num type="law">11-97</num>
  <heading type="short">Community Development Corporations Money Lender Licensing Fee and Bonding Exemption Temporary Amendment Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-97.pdf">D.C. Law 11-97</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 11-97, the “Community Development Corporations Money Lender Licensing Fee and Bonding Exemption Temporary Amendment Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-460. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 10, 1995, and December 5, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-180 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-97 became effective on March 5, 1996.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LLMENT(S) kwikta 062 318 239 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA D.C. LAW 11-97 "Community Development Corporations Money Lender Licensing Fee and Bonding Exemption Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-460 on first and second readings, October 10, 1995 and December 5, 1995 respectively. The legislation was deemed approved without the signature of the Mayor on December 27, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-180 and published in the January 5, 1996, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 43 page 2) and transmitted to Congress on January 22, 1996 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore cites this enactment as D.C. Law l 1-97, effective March 5, 1996. k I)AVID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Jan. Feb. March 22,23,24,25,26,29,30,31 1,2,5,6,7,8,9,12, l 3,14,15,16,20,21,22,23,26,27,28,29 1,4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT ii-180 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 27, 1995 Codification District of Colutnbia Code 1996 Supp. To amend, on a temporary basis, An Act To regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms, and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real estate brokers in the District of Columbia, to exempt certain community development corporations acting as money lenders from all of the money lender licensing fee and bonding requirements. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Community Development Corporations Money Lender Licensing Fee and Bonding Exemption Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 Sec. 2. Section 10 of An Act To regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real estate brokers in the District of Columbia, approved February 4, 1913 37 Stat. 660; D.C. Code § 26-710 is amended by adding new subsections (c) and (d) to read as follows c) For the purposes of this section, the term 1 Community Development Corporation" or "CDC" means any community development corporation recognized by, and under contract with, the District of Columbia Department of Housing and Community Development (or any successor agency) that is engaged in business and economic development activities in the form of making microloans through the use of funds loaned to them by nationally or locally chartered banks or financial institutions for the specific purpose of microlending, and which organization is organized under the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act, approved August 6, 1962 (76 Stat. 265; D.C. Code § 29- 501 et seq and whose articles of incorporation and bylaws are consistent with rules and regulations issued by the Mayor of the District of Columbia pursuant to the District of Columbia Note, Section 26-710 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Economic Development Finance Corporation Act of 1984, effective June 29, 1984 (D.C. Law 5- 89; D.C. Code § 1-2211 etseq 2 Microloans" or "microlending" means a CDC engaging in the practice of making or issuing any loans up to, and including 25,000 to any person engaged in business within the District of Columbia 3 Person" means any natural person, partnership, limited partnership, or corporation, including corporations taxed under Subchapter S of the Internal Revenue Code d) No money lender licensing fee and bonding requirements contained in this act shall be held to apply to a CDC engaged in microlending where the funds used for the microlending program were loaned to the CDC by a nationally or locally chartered bank or financial institution for the specific purpose of microlending, provided that the CDC operates and makes loans only in the geographical service area defined in their agreements with the District of Columbia Department of Housing and Community Development Sec. 3. The provisions of this act will have no negative fiscal impact on the General Fund of the District of Columbia. Community development corporations currently pay no money lenders license fees to the District of Columbia, and will not participate in money lending programs if required to pay such fees. The loans being made do not replace any private commercial lending by institutions that would otherwise pay such fees or bonds. It is anticipated that microloans made by community development corporations under programs facilitated by this act will have a small positive economic impact on the fortunes of various District of Columbia neighborhoods, and thus a small, positive fiscal impact on the city’s General Fund. Revenue estimates for FY 96 did not anticipate these fees being paid, and therefore this act will not cause any change in revenue estimates. Under the narrow definition contained in the act, no more than 10 community-based groups will qualify for the waiver. The maximum amount that community development corporations engaged in microlending would pay to the District if not granted a waiver by the provisions of this act would be $8,000 in license fees. Sec. 4 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(c and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register. ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) This act shall expire after the 225th day of its having taken effect or on the effective date of the Community Development Corporations Money Lender License Exemption Amendment Act of 1995, whic~ever occurs first. airman Council of the District of Columbia DEEMED APPROVED WITHOUT SIGNATURE UPON EXPIRATION OF THE IO-DAY MAYORAL REVIEW PERIOD. NOT SIGNED Mayor District of Columbia December 27, 1995 3 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result COUNCIL OF THE DI~I’RIc’T OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Oo,,e, No. B11-/46Q ADOPTF1 FIRST READING; 10-10-95 APPROVED BRAZIL, CROPP, AND RAY CUlLB ¢ihne~llber Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans i A)e N’ay V &amp;amp;B Coundlmember Aye ay ] NV AB Councilmember Jarvis Smith. Jr. Lightfoot Thomas. Sr. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray Aye Nay [ NV I B I ° Indtcates Vote ary to the Council AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV Present not Voting Date ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR CTIO~OATE ADOPTED FINAL READING; 12-05-95 APPROVEDVOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST SENT BRAZIL, CHAVOUS, THOMAS, AND WHITTINGTON ROLL CALL VO’rE Result Omncilmember ] Aye [ Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NW AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV B Chron. Clarke ] Jarvis Smith. Jr. Brazil Lightfoot Thomas, Sr. Chavous Mason Whittington Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X-indicates~no AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD e Counal ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I ACTION &amp;amp;DATE NV-Present not voting Date ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember I Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Chron. Clarke ] Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X Indicates Vote Aye Nay AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
