<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1001</num>
  <heading>Findings and objectives.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council finds and declares that the District of Columbia faces critical social, economic, and environmental problems arising in significant measures from:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The concentration of poverty in areas of the city;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Overcrowding and deterioration of housing, exacerbated by inadequate construction of new units for the growing number of households, and inadequate resources to provide for the rehabilitation of existing units for use by residents of the affected areas;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Inadequate and inappropriate public and private investment and reinvestment in housing and other physical facilities, and related public and social services, resulting in the growth and persistence of urban slums and blight and the marked deterioration of the quality of the urban environment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Lack of essential commercial facilities and services in many of the city’s communities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Need to improve the overall quality of the urban environment for the people of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Council further finds and declares that the future welfare of the District of Columbia and the well-being of its citizens depend on the establishment and maintenance of the District of Columbia as a viable physical, social, economic, and political community, and require for the benefit of the communities being directly affected:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Systematic and sustained action to eliminate blight, to conserve and renew aging urban neighborhoods, to improve the living environment of low and moderate income families, and to develop new residential and economic activity centers throughout the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Substantial expansion of and greater continuity in the scope and level of federal and local financial assistance together with increased private investment in support of community development activities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Continuing effort at all levels of government to develop programs to meet identified needs and to improve the functioning of departments and agencies responsible for planning, implementing, and evaluating community development efforts;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Ongoing assistance to the secondary market for residential mortgages on housing for low-and moderate-income families by increasing the liquidity of mortgage investments and reinvesting investment proceeds for residential mortgage financing; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Management and liquidation of District of Columbia owned mortgage portfolios in an orderly manner in accordance with procurement requirements, with minimum loss to the District government.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The primary objective of this chapter is the maintenance and development of the District of Columbia as a viable urban community, by providing decent housing, a suitable living environment and expanding economic opportunities, principally for persons of low and moderate income. Consistent with this primary objective the chapter provides for the support of community development activities which are directed toward the following specific objectives:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The elimination of slums and blight and the prevention of blighting influences and the deterioration of property and neighborhood and community facilities of importance to the welfare of the community;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The elimination of conditions which are detrimental to health, safety, and public welfare and the establishment of programs to protect and improve the quality of the urban environment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The conservation and expansion of the District’s housing stock in order to provide a suitable living environment for all persons, principally those of low and moderate income;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The expansion and improvement of the quantity and quality of community services, particularly for persons of low and moderate income, which are essential for sound community development and for the development of a viable urban community;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A more rational utilization of land and the better arrangement of residential, commercial, industrial, recreational, and other needed activity centers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The reduction of the isolation of income groups within the community and the promotion of an increase in the diversity and vitality of neighborhoods through the expansion of housing opportunities for persons of low and moderate income, particularly those with large families;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The restoration and preservation of properties of special value for historic, architectural, or esthetic reasons;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The establishment of data-gathering, planning, policy, and program development which will ensure effective monitoring of and programming responsive to the changing numbers, characteristics, and needs of the people of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The continuation of development activities in those areas previously covered by urban renewal or neighborhood development plans until completed; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Promote access to mortgage credit throughout the District of Columbia by increasing the liquidity of mortgage investments and improving the distribution of investment capital available for low-and moderate-income persons to acquire residential mortgage financing.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Following the approval of a Community Development Program in such areas as the Council of the District of Columbia, upon recommendation of the Mayor, shall designate, the Mayor is authorized to prohibit any new construction in any area designated for this purpose as a community development area in a Community Development Program; new construction includes substantial remodeling, conversion, rebuilding, and enlargement or extension of major structural improvements on existing buildings, but does not include ordinary maintenance, remodeling, or changes necessary to continue occupancy.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-39">Dec. 16, 1975, D.C. Law 1-39, § 2, 22 DCR 3436</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-115">Feb. 26, 1981, D.C. Law 3-115, § 3, 27 DCR 5630</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-9">June 11, 1999, D.C. Law 13-9, §§ 2(a), (b), 46 DCR 3640</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 5-901.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 5-1001.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-9">D.C. Law 13-9</cite>, in subsec. (b), struck the word “and” following “activities” in par. (2), substituted a semicolon for the period following “efforts” in par. (3), and added pars. (4) and (5); and, in subsec. (c), struck the word “and” following “Columbia;” in par. (8), substituted “; and” for the final period in par. (9), and added par. (10).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a), (b) of Community Development Program Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-246">D.C. Law 12-246</cite>, April 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 4159).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) and (b) of the Community Development Program Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-557, January 12, 1999,  45 DCR 635).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2(a), (b) of the Community Development Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-61, May 10, 1999,  46 DCR 4451).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of the DC Beautiful Pilot Program, see § 2142 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of the Strategic Plans for Economic Opportunity in Ward 7 and Ward 8, see § 2152 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Mayor's Orders</heading>
      <text>Delegation of functions with respect to Capital City Business and Industrial Park: See Mayor’s Order 85-125, July 18, 1985.</text>
      <text>Amendment of Mayor’s Order 85-125, delegation of functions with respect to Capital City Business and Industrial Park: See Mayor’s Order 88-64, March 15, 1988.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Capitol Gateway Project: <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-84">D.C. Law 4-84</cite> provided that new construction, substantial rehabilitation, subdivision formation, or street and alley closings in the Capitol Gateway Project area is prohibited.</text>
      <text>Minor Modification of CD-15 Through Cd-23 Program Years Under the Community Development Block Grant Program Emergency Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-498, effective May 5, 1998, the Council approved a modification of CD-15 through CD-23 program years under the Community Development Block Grant Program administered by the Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
      <text>Section 2142 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> provided: “DC Beautiful Pilot Program.</text>
      <text>“(a) The Office of Planning shall create a one-year pilot program during Fiscal Year 2016 to beautify 2 or more street segments in Ward 7 or Ward 8 that are not located in a Business Improvement District, as that term is defined in section 3(7) of the Business Improvements Districts Act of 1996, effective May 29, 1996 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-134">D.C. Law 11-134</cite>; D.C. Official Code  Section 2-1215.02(7)).</text>
      <text>“(b) For the pilot program, the Office of Planning shall allocate 2 employees who shall design, plan, and coordinate efforts of private actors and government agencies to beautify the selected street segments by, at a minimum:</text>
      <text>“(1) Engaging community members and local businesses to determine priorities for beautification;</text>
      <text>“(2) Soliciting private organizations for resources and assistance; and</text>
      <text>“(3) Identifying and coordinating beautification services from various District agencies to:</text>
      <text>“(A) Increase the number of tree boxes and planters;</text>
      <text>“(B) Abate graffiti;</text>
      <text>“(C) Survey the designated area to ensure an adequate number of trash and recycle bins;</text>
      <text>“(D) Maintain bus shelters and triangle parks;</text>
      <text>“(E) Landscape tree boxes, planters, and triangle parks; and</text>
      <text>“(F) Clean up litter.”</text>
      <text>Section 2152 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> provided:</text>
      <text>“Strategic Plans for Economic Opportunity for Ward 7 and Ward 8.</text>
      <text>“(a) In Fiscal Year 2016, the Deputy Mayor for Greater Economic Opportunity is authorized to prepare, publish, and submit to the Council a comprehensive Strategic Plan for Economic Development for Ward 7 and a comprehensive Strategic Plan for Economic Development for Ward 8, no later than September 30, 2016.</text>
      <text>“(b) The plans required by this section shall:</text>
      <text>“(1) Include analysis of data related to education, housing, employment, transit, and economic development in each ward;</text>
      <text>“(2) Include a needs assessment for each ward that takes into account existing data;</text>
      <text>“(3) Include analysis of strategies that have been successful in spurring economic development in similar communities within the District and across the country;</text>
      <text>“(4) Include specific recommendations for improvements in the areas of education, housing, employment, transit, and economic development; and</text>
      <text>“(5) Include assessments of and recommendations to achieve viability of existing commercial corridors in each ward.</text>
      <text>“(c) The plans required by this section shall identify any new legislation necessary to implement its recommendations and provide recommendations concerning how to fund the provisions of the plan.”</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
