<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <num>6-1071</num>
  <heading>Creation of Neighborhood Investment Fund.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-131" type="History">Mar. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-131, § 2, 51 DCR 1797</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20" type="History">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 2132, 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-123" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-123, § 2, 55 DCR 1513</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-219" type="History">Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 7044, 55 DCR 7598</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2061, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-338" type="History">Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-338, § 2, 58 DCR 616</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 202, 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 2022, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  9017(a), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-1072">6-1072</cite> and § <cite path="§10-1202.43">10-1202.43</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite>, in subsec. (a), inserted “The purposes of the Neighborhood Investment Fund shall be to fund the development and implementation of neighborhood investment plans under § <cite path="§6-1072">6-1072</cite> and to finance and assist revitalization activities that will benefit residents of Neighborhood Program Target Areas designated in § <cite path="§6-1073">6-1073</cite>.”; in subsec. (b), inserted “The requested expenditures shall be consistent with the purposes of the Neighborhood Investment Fund set forth in subsection (a) of this section.”; and added subsec. (g).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-123">D.C. Law 17-123</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “17.4%” for “15%”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite>, in subsec. (a), deleted “, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act” following “subchapter”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “the program” for “a 5-year program”; and added subsecs. (h) to (j).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-338">D.C. Law 18-338</cite>, in subsec. (j)(2), substituted “following programs” for “following Main Street programs” in the introductory language, substituted “Main Street Program;” for a semicolon in subpars. (A), (B), (E) to (I), and (K), substituted “Main Street Group;” for a semicolon in subpars. (C) and (D), and substituted “Main Street Program; and” for “; and” in subpar. (J).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> added subsec. (k).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “There shall be deposited into the fund such funds as may be appropriated from time to time.” for “Subject to appropriations, there shall be deposited annually into the Neighborhood Investment Fund 17.4% of the personal property tax imposed by § <cite path="§47-1522">47-1522</cite>(a); provided, that the amount deposited into the Neighborhood Investment Fund from the personal property tax shall not exceed $10 million annually.”; repealed subsecs. (h) and (i); and added subsec. (l).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Neighborhood Investment Amendment Temporary Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-207">D.C. Law 16-207</cite>, March 2, 2007, law notification  54 DCR 2505).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-179">D.C. Law 18-179</cite>, in subsec. (j)(2), deleted “Main Street” from the lead-in language, substituted “Main Street Program;” for a semicolon in subpars. (A), (B), (C), (E), (F), (G), (H), (I), and (K), substituted “for direct service delivery managed through, or for an organization chosen by, the Department of Small and Local Business Development for the commercial corridor designated as Vinegar Hill South Main Street” for “to Vinegar Hill, N.W.” in subpar. (D), and substituted “Main Street Program; and” for “; and” in subpar. (J).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-179">D.C. Law 18-179</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Lower Georgia Avenue Job Training Center Funding Authorization Temporary Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-3">D.C. Law 17-3</cite>, April 18, 2003, law notification  54 DCR 6582).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-221">D.C. Law 18-221</cite>, in subsec. (j)(2)(E), substituted “to an organization currently providing business services for the commercial corridor designated as Georgia Avenue Main Street or for direct service delivery managed through the Department of Small and Local Business Development for the commercial corridor designated as Georgia Avenue Main Street” for “to Georgia Avenue, N.W.”.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Neighborhood Investment Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-468, July 31, 2006,  53 DCR 6761).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Neighborhood Investment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-517, October 27, 2006,  53 DCR 9101).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Neighborhood Investment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-8, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1468).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) enactment, see § 2 of Lower Georgia Avenue Job Training Center Funding Authorization Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-12, January 26, 2007,  54 DCR 1517).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2132 of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2061 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2062 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2061 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2062 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Adams Morgan Main Street Group Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-342, March 22, 2010,  57 DCR 2852).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Georgia Avenue Main Street Authorization Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-434, June 14, 2010,  57 DCR 5384).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Adams Morgan Main Street Group Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-677, January 12, 2011,  58 DCR 595).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 202 of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of this section, see §§ 9017(a) and 9029 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of this section, see §§ 9017(a) and 9029 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of this section, see §§ 9017(a) and 9029 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title: Section 201 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> provided that subtitle A of title II of the act may be cited as “Neighborhood Investment Fund Implementation Amendment Act of 2010”.</text>
      <text>Short title: Section 2021 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle C of title II of the act may be cited as “Neighborhood Investment Fund Amendment Act of 2011”.</text>
      <text>Short title: Section 2131 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite> provided that subtitle M of title II of the act may be cited as the “Neighborhood Investment Amendment Act of 2007”.</text>
      <text>Short title: Section 2060 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle G of title II of the act may be cited as the “Neighborhood Investment Fund Implementation Plan Amendment Act of 2009”.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Resolutions</heading>
      <text>Resolution 16-589, the “Neighborhood Investment Act Spending Plan for FY 2006 Resolution of 2006”, was approved effective March 7, 2006.</text>
      <text>Resolution 16-596, the “Neighborhood Investment Act Spending Plan for Fiscal Year 2006 Resolution of 2006”, was approved effective April 4, 2006.</text>
      <text>Resolution 16-955, the “Neighborhood Investment Act Spending Plan for FY 2007 Emergency Approval Resolution of 2006”, was approved effective December 19, 2006.</text>
      <text>Resolution 17-433, the “Neighborhood Investment Act Spending Plan for FY 2008 Emergency Approval Resolution of 2007”, was approved effective November 6, 2007.</text>
      <text>Resolution 17-824, the “Neighborhood Investment Act Spending Plan for Fiscal Year 2009 Emergency Approval Resolution of 2008”, was  approved effective October 7, 2008.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 2062 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided:</text>
      <text>“Sec. 2062. NIF Fund Balance.</text>
      <text>“There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Fiscal Year 2010 NIF Fund (‘Fund’) into which the Chief Financial Officer shall deposit $3.2 million in fiscal year 2009 funds from the anticipated fiscal year 2009 Neighborhood Investment Fund carryover. All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in section 2(j) of the Neighborhood Investment Act of 2004, effective March 30, 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-131">D.C. Law 15-131</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§6-1071">6-1071</cite>(j)) (‘Act’), without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress. No funds shall be transferred from the Fund until October 1, 2009, at which time the funds shall be used in accordance with section 2(j) of the Act.”</text>
      <text>Section 203 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> provided: “Sec. 203. Applicability. This subtitle shall apply as of October 1, 2010.”</text>
      <text>Section 9029 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> provided that the repeal by § 9017(a) of the act shall apply as of September 30, 2014.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
