<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-1061.03</num>
  <heading>Approval of the Plan.</heading>
  <text>The Plan, as amended by this part, is approved.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-278" type="History" path="§103">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-278, § 103, 54 DCR 895</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2(b) of Workforce Housing Production Program Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-44">D.C. Law 17-44</cite>, November 24, 2007, law notification  55 DCR 3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-244">D.C. Law 17-244</cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 104. Authority to transfer moneys to the workforce housing pilot program from the Housing Production Trust Fund and the Industrial Revenue Bond special account.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Mayor may transfer $4 million from the Housing Production Trust Fund to such accounts or sub-accounts as may be established pursuant to the trust agreement to be entered into pursuant to section 102(e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b)(1) The Mayor may transfer $1 million from the Industrial Revenue Bond special account established under D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§47-131">47-131</cite>(c)(4) to such accounts or sub-accounts as may be established pursuant to the trust agreement to be entered into pursuant to section 102(e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The funds transferred pursuant to this subsection may be used to assist households whose annual incomes do not exceed 120% of the area median income; provided, that the annual incomes of the households assisted through an allocation or proceeds from the Housing Production Trust Fund, established pursuant to section 3 of the Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 7-202">D.C. Law 7-202</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§42-2802">42-2802</cite>), shall not exceed 80% of the area median income.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) For the purposes of this subsection, the term ”area median income“ shall have the same meaning as provided in section 2(1) of the Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 7-202">D.C. Law 7-202</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§42-2801">42-2801</cite>(1)).”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-244">D.C. Law 17-244</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of Workforce Housing Production Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-104, July 27, 2007,  54 DCR 8212).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of Workforce Housing Production Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-201, November 26, 2007,  54 DCR 11903).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of Workforce Housing Production Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-440, July 16, 2008,  55 DCR 8290).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
