<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-1053</num>
  <heading>Presentation of Comprehensive Housing Strategy; public meetings.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 12 months after the Council’s confirmation of the Mayor’s nominations to the Task Force, the Task Force shall present the Comprehensive Housing Strategy to the Council and the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall hold at least 2 public meetings, which shall be convened at the following times:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 60 days after the Council’s confirmation of the Task Force members; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>After a draft of the Comprehensive Housing Strategy has been developed but prior to presenting the final Comprehensive Housing Strategy to the Council and the Mayor under section (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>At least 30 days before a public meeting, the Task Force shall provide the general public the following information regarding the meeting, the:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Time;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Date; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Location.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall provide all interested persons a reasonable opportunity to be heard at the public meetings.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-73" type="History">March 10, 2004, D.C. Law 15-73, § 4, 50 DCR 10909</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-1054">6-1054</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 4 of Comprehensive Housing Strategy Temporary Act of 2003 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-52">D.C. Law 15-52</law-cite>, December 9, 2003, law notification  51 DCR 1787).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of Comprehensive Housing Strategy Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-143, July 29, 2003,  50 DCR 6888).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of Comprehensive Housing Strategy Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-215, November 7, 2003,  50 DCR 10023).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
