<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1032</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Housing and Community Development Reform Advisory Commission; membership; chairperson.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Housing and Community Development Reform Advisory Commission (“Commission”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall consist of the following 7 members:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Three ex officio members, as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia (“Council”), or a designee of the Chairman;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The chairperson of the Council’s Committee on Economic Development, or a designee of the chairperson; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development (“Director”), or a designee of the Director;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Four public members, appointed by the Mayor, subject to the advice and consent of the Council under § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>(f). The public members shall be nominated as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Two members shall have expertise in government regulations related to grants managed by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development; provided, that the member shall not be a current or former officer, employee, agent, or other affiliate of an organization that has received funding from the Department of Housing and Community Development within the prior 5 years; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>One member shall have expertise in human resources and organizational management; provided, that the member shall not be a current or former officer, employee, agent, or other affiliate of an organization which has received funding from the Department of Housing and Community Development within the prior 5 years; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>One member shall have expertise in financial systems and information technology; provided, that the member shall not be a current or former officer, employee, agent, or other affiliate of an organization which has received funding from the Department of Housing and Community Development within the prior 5 years.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall nominate the public members of the Commission within 45 days after October 1, 2002.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Chairperson of the Commission shall be designated by the Mayor in consultation with the chairperson of the Council Committee on Economic Development.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1142, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Housing and Community Development Reform Advisory Commission Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-91">D.C. Law 15-91</cite>, March 10, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 3611).</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Housing and Community Development Reform Advisory Commission Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-223, November 25, 2003,  50 DCR 10700).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
