<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1041.04</num>
  <heading>Enforcement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A violation of this subchapter or the rules issued under authority of this subchapter shall be a civil infraction for the purposes of Chapter 18 of Title 2 and be grounds for revocation of any building permit and certificate of occupancy for the market rate portions of the Inclusionary Development.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as sanctions for infraction of § <cite path="§6-1041.02">6-1041.02</cite> or any rule promulgated under its authority pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to such fines, penalties, and fees as may be established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the following fines shall be imposed for violations of § <cite path="§6-1041.02">6-1041.02</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any person found to have sold a inclusionary unit at a price greater than that permitted by the Mayor shall pay a fine equal to the amount by which the purchase price exceeded the price allowed plus 10%.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any person found to have rented an inclusionary unit for a rent greater than that permitted by the Mayor shall pay a fine equal the amount by which the rent paid exceeded the rent allowed plus 10%. The fine amount shall continue to be paid until the owner provides proof satisfactory to the Mayor that the rental payment has been reduced to the maximum allowed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All other violations of the Inclusionary Zoning Program are Class I infractions and subject to the fine schedule set forth at 16 DCMR § 3201.1, as that schedule may be amended.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All fines collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the Housing Production Trust Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia may institute court proceedings to enjoin violations of the Inclusionary Zoning Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The District government shall not issue or reissue any license or permit, including a building permit or certificate of occupancy, to any applicant for a license or permit if the applicant is the owner of any Inclusionary Development or unit and found, after a hearing, to be in violation of the Inclusionary Zoning Program until such time as the Mayor certifies that the Inclusionary Development or unit is again in compliance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-275" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-275, § 104, 54 DCR 880</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-1041.07">6-1041.07</cite> and § <cite path="§42-2802">42-2802</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
