<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-1041.03</num>
  <heading>Establishment of maximum rent and purchase price; publication requirement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish the maximum rent or purchase price for the first sale of an inclusionary unit based upon either the actual income of the household selected by the Mayor to lease or purchase the unit or based upon a rental and price schedule as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Rents based upon the actual income of a household shall be established so that the household will not expend more than approximately 30% of its annual income on rent and utilities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Purchase prices based upon the actual income of a household shall be established so that the household will not expend more than approximately 30% of its annual income on mortgage payments, including principal, interest, and property insurance and taxes, home owner association or condominium fees, and utilities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Maximum rent and purchase prices established through a schedule applicable to low-income households shall be set so that a household earning 50% of the Metropolitan Statistical Area median will expend no more than approximately 30% of its annual income on the applicable housing costs identified in subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Maximum rent and purchase prices established through a schedule applicable to moderate-income households shall be set so that a household earning 80% of the Metropolitan Statistical Area median will expend no more than approximately 30% of its annual income on the applicable housing costs identified in subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The initial rental and prices schedule shall be published in the District of Columbia Register. The schedule may be modified as necessary to maintain the affordability of inclusionary units. The initial and revised schedules need not be offered for public comment through publication of a notice of proposed rulemaking, but shall not become effective until publication in the District of Columbia Register. Each published schedule shall identify the assumptions underlying the prices and rents established, such as the mortgage term and the average interest rate, taxes, insurance, condominium fees used.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (d) the purchase price, for the second and all subsequent sales of an inclusionary unit shall equal not more than the purchase price paid by each seller plus the costs of the improvements permitted by regulation to be added to the purchase price, which amount shall be either multiplied by the percentage by which the consumer price index has risen or fallen since the date on which that seller purchased the property, or calculated pursuant to another formula as determined and published by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The purchase price for the second and all subsequent sales of an inclusionary unit sold to the Mayor shall equal the purchase price paid by each seller plus the costs of the improvements permitted by regulation to be added to the purchase price, which amount shall be multiplied by 25% or the percentage that the consumer price index has risen or fallen, whichever is lower, since the date on which that seller purchased the property.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-275" type="History" path="§103">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-275, § 103, 54 DCR 880</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Inclusionary Zoning Implementation Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-304, February 22, 2008,  55 DCR 2514).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Inclusionary Zoning Implementation Temporary Amendment Act of 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-161">D.C. Law 17-161</cite>, May 13, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 5894).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-1041.02">6-1041.02</cite> and § <cite path="§42-2802">42-2802</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
