<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1107</num>
  <heading>New construction.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before the Mayor may issue a permit to construct a building or structure in an historic district or on the site of an historic landmark, the Mayor shall review the permit application in accordance with this section and shall place notice of the application in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Prior to making the finding on the permit application required by subsection (f) of this section, the Mayor may refer the application to the Historic Preservation Review Board for a recommendation, but shall so refer all applications that are not subject to review by the Commission of Fine Arts under the Old Georgetown Act (§ <cite path="§6-1201">6-1201</cite> et seq.) or the Shipstead-Luce Act (§ <cite path="§6-611.01">6-611.01</cite>). The Mayor shall consider any recommendation by the Review Board or by the Commission of Fine Arts pursuant to such referral.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Within 120 days after the Review Board receives the referral, the Mayor shall make the finding required by subsection (f) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the Review Board recommends against granting the application, it shall promptly notify the applicant in writing of its recommendation and the reasons therefor. If the Commission of Fine Arts recommends against granting the application, the Historic Preservation Office shall notify the applicant of the Commission of Fine Arts’ recommendation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>In any case where the Mayor deems appropriate, or in which the applicant so requests, the Mayor shall hold a public hearing on the permit application.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The permit shall be issued unless the Mayor, after due consideration of the zoning laws and regulations of the District of Columbia, finds that the design of the building and the character of the historic district or historic landmark are incompatible; provided, that in any case in which an application is made for the construction of an additional building or structure on a lot upon which there is presently a building or structure, the Mayor may deny a construction permit entirely where he finds that any additional construction will be incompatible with the character of the historic district or historic landmark. Notwithstanding a finding of incompatibility, the Mayor may find that issuance of the permit is necessary to allow the construction of a project of special merit.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-144" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-144, § 8, 25 DCR 6939</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-185" type="History">Nov. 16, 2006, D.C. Law 16-185, § 2(j), 53 DCR 6712</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-249" type="History">Apr. 30, 2015, D.C. Law 20-249, § 2(d), 62 DCR 1512</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-1104">6-1104</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1106">6-1106</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1108">6-1108</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1108.01">6-1108.01</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1110">6-1110</cite>, and § <cite path="§6-1113">6-1113</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-1007.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-827.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-185">D.C. Law 16-185</cite>, in subsec. (d), inserted “If the Commission of Fine Arts recommends against granting the application, the Historic Preservation Office shall notify the applicant of the Commission of Fine Arts’ recommendation.”; and, in subsec. (f), inserted “Notwithstanding a finding of incompatibility, the Mayor may find that issuance of the permit is necessary to allow the construction of a project of special merit.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-249">D.C. Law 20-249</cite> would have rewritten (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-249">D.C. Law 20-249</cite>: Section 3  of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-249">D.C. Law 20-249</cite> provided that (1) the act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan; (2) that the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification; and (3) that the Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register and the date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
