<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-1112</num>
  <heading>Administrative procedures.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In any case of demolition, alteration, subdivision, or new construction in which a hearing was held, the Mayor’s decision on such application shall not become final until 15 days after issuance. In all applications for which a hearing is held, the Mayor’s decision must be issued within 120 days after the hearing record is closed, including the filing of any required post-hearing submissions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All proceedings pursuant to this subchapter shall be conducted in accordance with the applicable provisions of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-144" type="History" path="§13">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-144, § 13, 25 DCR 6939</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-86" type="History">Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-86, § 503(c), 45 DCR 1172</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 403(b), 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-313" type="History">June 19, 2001, D.C. Law 13-313, § 20(b), 48 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-1012.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-832.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “120 days” for “60 days” and deleted “, or the application shall be deemed approved by the Mayor” at the end of the second sentence, and in subsec. (b), struck the second and third sentences, which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“The hearing by the Review Board upon the filing of an application to designate a historic landmark shall be conducted under the contested case procedures contained in § <cite path="§1-1509">1-1509</cite>. Any final order of the Mayor under this act and any final order of the Review Board regarding the designation of a historic landmark shall be reviewable in the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-313">D.C. Law 13-313</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “alteration, subdivision,” for “subdivision”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2, 3 of (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-197">D.C. Law 13-197</cite>, October 21, 2000, law notification  47 DCR 8987).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 403(b) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see §§ 2(a), (b) and 3(a), (b) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-381, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6695).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 403(b) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Because of the codification of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-69">D.C. Law 5-69</cite> as subchapter II of this chapter, and the designation of the preexisting text of Chapter 11 as subchapter I, “subchapter” has been substituted for “chapter,” where applicable, in this section.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 20(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-313">D.C. Law 13-313</cite>, amends <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite> by adding a new section 403a which provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 403a. Applicability. Section 403(a) and (b)(1)(A) and (B) shall app only prospectively to hearings held by the Mayor or the Historic Preservation Board after the effective date of this title.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
