<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-1108</num>
  <heading>Application for preliminary review.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An applicant may apply to the Mayor for a preliminary review of a project for compliance with the provisions of this subchapter relating to new construction, and to any demolition, alteration, or subdivision necessary for such new construction. Upon the provision of such information and upon compliance with such other conditions as the Mayor may require, such application shall be considered by the Mayor without the necessity of the applicant completing other permit requirements not necessary for a finding under this subchapter. Where an application for a preliminary review is received pursuant to this section, the Mayor will determine, in accordance with the procedures and requirements specified in §§ <cite path="§6-1104">6-1104</cite>, <cite path="§6-1105">6-1105</cite>, <cite path="§6-1106">6-1106</cite>, and/or 6-1107, as applicable, whether to issue a preliminary finding of compliance with this subchapter; provided, that no permit shall be granted except in accordance with all other permit requirements, and after final review by the Mayor under this subchapter; provided further, that where the final review shows that the project is not consistent with the preliminary review, the application will again be processed in accordance with the procedures and requirements of §§ <cite path="§6-1104">6-1104</cite>, <cite path="§6-1105">6-1105</cite>, <cite path="§6-1106">6-1106</cite>, and/or 6-1107, as applicable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A prospective permit applicant may apply to the Historic Preservation Review Board for conceptual review of a project for compliance with the provisions of this subchapter relating to demolition, alteration, subdivision, or new construction. After receipt of such information as it may require, the Review Board shall consider the application without requiring the applicant to complete other permit requirements not necessary for its review. To assist in conducting conceptual review, the Review Board may appoint advisory committees composed of two or more Review Board members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall not determine compliance with § <cite path="§6-1104">6-1104</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1105">6-1105</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1106">6-1106</cite>, or § <cite path="§6-1107">6-1107</cite> based on an application for conceptual review, but the Mayor may consider the Review Board’s recommendation on an application for conceptual review as evidence to support a finding on a related application submitted for review under § <cite path="§6-1104">6-1104</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1105">6-1105</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1106">6-1106</cite>, or § <cite path="§6-1107">6-1107</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-144" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-144, § 9, 25 DCR 6939</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-185" type="History">Nov. 16, 2006, D.C. Law 16-185, § 2(k), 53 DCR 6712</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-249" type="History">Apr. 30, 2015, D.C. Law 20-249, § 2(e), 62 DCR 1512</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-1008.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-828.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-185">D.C. Law 16-185</cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-249">D.C. Law 20-249</cite> would have added “in accordance with this subsection and § <cite path="§6-1108.03">6-1108.03</cite>” in (a) and (b); and would have added (a-1) and (b-1).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Because of the codification of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-69">D.C. Law 5-69</cite> as subchapter II of this chapter, and the designation of the preexisting text of Chapter 11 as subchapter I, “subchapter” has been substituted for “chapter,” where applicable, in this section.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-249">D.C. Law 20-249</cite>: Section 3  of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-249">D.C. Law 20-249</cite> provided that (1) the act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan; (2) that the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification; and (3) that the Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register and the date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the act.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
