<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1309</num>
  <heading>Application to international organizations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Secretary may make § <cite path="§6-1306">6-1306</cite>, or any other provision of this chapter, applicable with respect to an international organization to the same extent that it is applicable with respect to a foreign mission if the Secretary determines that such application is necessary to carry out the policy set forth in § <cite path="§6-1301">6-1301</cite>(b) and to further the objectives set forth in § <cite path="§6-1304">6-1304</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, “international organization” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>a public international organization designated as such pursuant to the International Organizations Immunities Act (22 U.S.C. §§ 288 — 288f-4) or a public international organization created pursuant to a treaty or other international agreement as an instrument through or by which 2 or more foreign governments engage in some aspect of their conduct of international affairs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>an official mission (other than a United States mission) to such a public international organization; including any real property of such an organization or mission and including the personnel of such an organization or mission.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 97-241" type="History">Aug. 24, 1982, 96 Stat. 289, Pub. L. 97-241, § 209</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-1302">6-1302</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1305">6-1305</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1314">6-1314</cite>, and § <cite path="§6-1315">6-1315</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-1209.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">For effective date of amendment made by title II of Pub. L. 97-241, Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§6-1301">6-1301</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “International Organizations Immunities Act,” referred to in (b), is the Act of Dec. 29, 1945, C. 652, 59 Stat. 669, as amended, and is codified as  22 U.S.C. §§ 288—288f-4.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
