<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1411</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the District of Columbia Building Rehabilitation Code Advisory Council.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish the District of Columbia Building Rehabilitation Code Advisory Council consisting of the following members from among whom the Mayor shall designate a Chair:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director of Housing and Community Development, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director of the DCRA, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Chief of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Chair of the Historic Preservation Review Board, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Chair of the Mayor’s Committee on Persons with Disabilities, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Chair of the Building Code Advisory Committee established by Mayor’s Order 89-257, November 7, 1989, who shall serve as an ex-officio member; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Fourteen members appointed by the Mayor, as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Four representatives of the building trades who are directly involved or have experience in code setting or enforcement, including plumbers; electricians; heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractors; and boiler operators;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Two architects practicing in the District whose practice involves a significant portion of rehabilitation projects;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A professional engineer;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Two contractors specializing in rehabilitation construction;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>A commercial and industrial building owner or developer;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>A multifamily building owner or developer; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Three members of the general public.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The members shall serve a 4-year term; provided, that for the initial appointments under subsection (a)(6) of this section, ½ of the members shall be appointed for 2-year terms.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A member may continue to serve after the expiration of his or her term until a successor is appointed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A member appointed to fill a vacancy, or after a term has begun, shall serve only for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Appointed members shall serve no more than 2 terms.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Members shall serve without compensation and shall be reimbursed for reasonable expenses.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Council shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Advise the Mayor on the development, adoption, and revisions to the BRC;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Develop, to the extent possible, the BRC to avoid increased costs to the District arising from implementation of the BRC; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide, to the extent District funds are available, training on the BRC for District personnel responsible for administering the BRC and for public and private construction-related professionals.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>DCRA shall provide administrative and staff services to the Rehabilitation Council.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-216" type="History">Mar. 21, 1987, D.C. Law 6-216, § 10b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-162" type="History">as added June 25, 2002, D.C. Law 14-162, § 201(a)(3), 49 DCR 4438</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-1410">6-1410</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3(e) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-181">D.C. Law 19-181</cite> repealed this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 8 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-181">D.C. Law 19-181</cite> provided that any order, rule, or regulation in effect under a law replaced by this act shall remain in effect until repealed, amended, or superseded.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 9 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-181">D.C. Law 19-181</cite> provided that sections 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7 of the act shall apply upon the Mayor’s issuance of a comprehensive final rulemaking governing signs on public space and private property pursuant to section 2 of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 11(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-181">D.C. Law 19-181</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section, see § 3(e) of the Sign Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-387, July 11, 2012,  59 DCR 8491).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary repeal of section, see § 3(e) of the Sign Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-499, October 26, 2012,  59 DCR 12749), applicable after the Mayor’s issuance of a comprehensive final rulemaking governing signs on public space and private property, and with the condition that any order, rule, or regulation in effect under a law replaced by this act shall remain in effect until repealed, amended, or superseded.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 301 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-162">D.C. Law 14-162</cite> provided: “Pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), the Mayor may issue rules to implement the provisions of this act.”</text>
      <text>Section 3(e) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> would have repealed this section.</text>
      <text>Section 9 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> provided “Any order, rule, or regulation in effect under a law replaced by this act shall remain in effect until repealed, amended, or superseded.”</text>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite>, § 3: Section 10 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> provided that sections 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, and 8 of the act shall not apply until the Mayor’s issuance of a comprehensive final rulemaking governing signs on public space and private property pursuant to section 2 of the act. Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> rewrote §§ <cite path="§1-303.21">1-303.21</cite> and <cite path="§1-303.23">1-303.23</cite>, and repealed § <cite path="§1-303.22">1-303.22</cite>.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
