<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <num>6-301.03</num>
  <heading>District of Columbia Redevelopment Land Agency — Established; composition; appointment; Chairman; term of office; vacancies; compensation; corporate powers; procedures for disposition of claims; facilities donated as local noncash grant-in-aid; maintenance of rental property; waiver of special assessments.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 2, 1946, 60 Stat. 793, ch. 736, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-198" type="History">Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 778, Pub. L. 93-198, title II, § 201(a)-(c)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-231" type="History">May 10, 1989, D.C. Law 7-231, § 18, 36 DCR 492</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-144" type="History">Sept. 11, 1998, D.C. Law 12-144, § 31(a), 45 DCR 3747</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-188" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-188, § 3(2), 49 DCR 6516</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-803.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-703.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-804.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-704.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) repeal of section, see § 9(a)(2) of the Redevelopment Land Agency-RLA Revitalization Corporation Transfer Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-66">D.C. Law 14-66</cite>, Feb. 27, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 2276).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 10 of Prevention of Unauthorized Switching of Customer Natural Gas Accounts Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-13">D.C. Law 14-13</cite>, July 10, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 6589).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 9(a)(1), (b) of Redevelopment Land Agency-RLA Revitalization Corporate Transfer Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-259, January 30, 2002,  49 DCR 1424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 232(d) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act  15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 232(d) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For purported temporary (90 day) repeal of section, see § 232(c) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For purported temporary (90 day) repeal of section, see § 232(c) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 33(b)(1) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-144">D.C. Law 12-144</cite> provided that § 31(a) shall take effect on the latter of: (A) September 11, 1998; or (B) the Dates determined by the Board, but not later than one year after the initial meeting of the Board.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Transfer of United States property: Act of September 26, 1978, 92 Stat. 749, Pub. L. 95-385, provides for the transfer of certain United States property to the District of Columbia Redevelopment Land Agency.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Compensation for board members of Agency: Section 120(c) of Pub. L. 103-127, 107 Stat. 1346, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1994, provided that notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Board of Directors of the District of Columbia Redevelopment Land Agency shall be paid, during any fiscal year, a per diem compensation at a rate established by the Mayor.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-188">D.C. Law 14-188</cite> repealed this section on a permanent basis. <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite> also purported to repeal this section. The repeal by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite> was ineffective.</text>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
