<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-341.03</num>
  <heading>Transfer of rights-of-way by Agency to District authorized.</heading>
  <text>The Agency is authorized to transfer to the government of the District of Columbia all right, title, and interest of the Agency in that portion of the right-of-way formerly occupied by the railroads, which is now a part of the land included in the District of Columbia highway system, for which the Agency compensated the railroads and acquired the interest of said railroads, and the Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized in this instance to pay the Agency the sum of $82,896 for said sites, which are described as follows:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Part of Thirteen-and-a-Half Street Southwest, and E Street Southwest described in 1 piece as follows: beginning for the same at the intersection of the east line of Thirteen-and-a-Half Street Southwest with the northeasterly line of Maine Avenue Southwest; and running thence north 51 degrees 37 minutes 00 seconds west 119.22 feet to the southerly line of said Thirteen-and-a-Half Street and E Street closed by plat recorded in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia in book 140, page 73; thence along said line south 71 degrees 17 minutes 15 seconds east 106.13 feet to the south line of said E Street; thence along said line due west 7.04 feet to the east line of said Thirteen-and-a-Half Street; thence along said line due south 40.0 feet to the point of beginning containing 1,990.50 square feet; all as shown on plat of computation recorded in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia in Survey Book 174, page 308.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Part of 13th Street Southwest, described as follows: beginning for the same at the intersection of the east line of Thirteenth Street Southwest with the northeasterly line of Maine Avenue Southwest; and running thence north 71 degrees 17 minutes 15 seconds west 116.14 feet to the west line of said Thirteenth Street; thence along said line due north 42.37 feet to the southerly line of Thirteenth Street closed by plat recorded in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia in book 140, page 73; thence along said line south 71 degrees 17 minutes 15 seconds east 15.21 feet; thence still along said line due east 95.59 feet to the said east line of Thirteenth Street; thence along said line due south 74.75 feet to the point of beginning containing 6,209.20 square feet; all as shown on plat of computation recorded in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia in Survey Book 174, page 308.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-317" type="History">Nov. 2, 1965, 79 Stat. 1184, Pub. L. 89-317, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-838.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-735.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
