<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-405</num>
  <heading>Exceptions for existing buildings; control of parking.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia, whenever he deems it desirable in the interest of economy, may permit buildings existing at the time said building lines are established and which project beyond said lines to remain until such time as the owner of said buildings desires to reconstruct or substantially alter the said buildings; provided, that § <cite path="§6-404">6-404</cite> shall apply to all parkings established under this chapter, and the control of said parkings otherwise shall be vested in the Mayor of the District of Columbia, and the Council of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized to make, and the Mayor is hereby authorized to enforce, all reasonable and necessary regulations for their care and preservation.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 59-1-ch3505" path="§4">June 21, 1906, 34 Stat. 385, ch. 3505, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-205.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-205.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(116) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
