<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-611.02</num>
  <heading>Plats of restricted area.</heading>
  <text>The Council of the District of Columbia, in consultation with the National Capital Planning Commission, shall prepare plats defining the areas within which application for building permits shall be submitted to the Commission of Fine Arts for its recommendations.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 71-2-ch291" path="§2">May 16, 1930, 46 Stat. 367, ch. 291, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Airspace leases, conditions for execution of lease, see § <cite path="§10-1121.04">10-1121.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Rental and utilization of public space, conditional authorization to construct structures, federal and district governments, see § <cite path="§10-1121.11">10-1121.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Rental and utilization of public space, public space on or above ground, see § <cite path="§10-1102.01">10-1102.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§10-1102.01">10-1102.01</cite>, § <cite path="§10-1121.04">10-1121.04</cite>, § <cite path="§10-1121.11">10-1121.11</cite>, and § <cite path="§25-374">25-374</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-411.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-411.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">“National Capital Planning Commission” was substituted for “National Capital Park and Planning Commission” in view of the Act of June 6, 1924, ch. 270, § 9, as added by the Act of July 19, 1952, 66 Stat. 790, ch. 949, § 1, which transferred the functions, powers, and duties of the National Capital Park and Planning Commission to the National Capital Planning Commission.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(121) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
