<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-641.03</num>
  <heading>Zoning regulations — Existing regulations continued; public hearing on amendments required; notice.</heading>
  <text>The regulations prior to June 20, 1938, adopted by the Zoning Commission under the authority of § <cite path="§6-621.01">6-621.01</cite> and in force on June 20, 1938, including the maps which at said date accompany and are a part of such regulations, shall be deemed to have been made and adopted and in force under this subchapter and subchapter V and shall be and continue in force and effect until and as they may be amended by the Zoning Commission as authorized by said this subchapter and subchapter V. The Zoning Commission may from time to time amend the regulations or any of them or the maps or any of them. Before putting into effect any amendment or amendments of said regulations, or of said map or maps, the Zoning Commission shall hold a public hearing thereon and provide notice of the hearing in accordance with the requirements of subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2. Such published notice shall include a general summary of the proposed amendment or amendments of the regulation or regulations and the boundaries of the territory or territories included in the amendment or amendments of the map or maps, and the time and place of the hearing. The Zoning Commission shall give such additional notice of such hearing as it shall deem feasible and practicable. At such hearing it shall afford any person present a reasonable opportunity to be heard. Such public hearing may be adjourned from time to time and if the time and place of the adjourned meeting be publicly announced when the adjournment is had, no further notice of such adjourned meeting need be published.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 75-3-ch534" path="§3">June 20, 1938, 52 Stat. 798, ch. 534, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-275" type="History">Apr. 27, 1999, D.C. Law 12-275,§ 5, 46 DCR 1441</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Parking facilities, establishment, see § <cite path="§50-2605">50-2605</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public parking authority, parking districts, see § <cite path="§50-2511">50-2511</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-641.07">6-641.07</cite>, § <cite path="§50-2511">50-2511</cite>, and § <cite path="§50-2605">50-2605</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-415.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-415.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Zoning Review Task Force: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§6-641.01">6-641.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
