<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-641.15</num>
  <heading>Federal public buildings excepted from this subchapter.</heading>
  <text>The provisions of this subchapter shall not apply to federal public buildings; provided, however, that, in order to ensure the orderly development of the national capital, the location, height, bulk, number of stories, and size of federal public buildings in the District of Columbia and the provision for open space in and around the same will be subject to the approval of the National Capital Planning Commission.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 20, 1938, 52 Stat. 802, ch. 534, § 16</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">National Capital Planning Commission, proposed developments, projects and acquisitions, see § <cite path="§2-1004">2-1004</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Rental and utilization of public space, conditional authorization to construct structures, federal and district governments, see § <cite path="§10-1121.11">10-1121.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1004">2-1004</cite> and § <cite path="§10-1121.11">10-1121.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-432.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-428.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">“National Capital Planning Commission” was substituted for “National Capital Park and Planning Commission” in the proviso in this section in view of the Act of June 6, 1924, ch. 270, § 9, as added by the Act of July 19, 1952, 66 Stat. 790, ch. 949, § 1, which transferred the functions, powers, and duties of the National Capital Park and Planning Commission to the National Capital Planning Commission.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">This subchapter and subchapter V do not apply to buildings constructed on property transferred or conveyed pursuant to the Act of October 8, 1968, 82 Stat. 958, Pub. L. 90-553, as amended by the Act of May 25, 1982, 96 Stat. 101, Pub. L. 97-186.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
