<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-641.13</num>
  <heading>Appropriations authorized; compensation.</heading>
  <text>Appropriations are hereby authorized to carry out the provisions of this subchapter for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1938, and thereafter the Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and directed to include in his annual estimates such amounts as may be required for salaries and expenses incident to such purposes. Each member of the Zoning Commission and of the Board of Zoning Adjustment shall be entitled to receive compensation. Members of the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia shall receive compensation in accordance with § <cite root="6-621.01">6-621.01</cite>(b). No compensation shall be paid to a member of the Board of Zoning Adjustment who is also a full-time officer or employee of the District of Columbia government or who serves on the Board of Zoning Adjustment as a federal government representative pursuant to § <cite root="6-641.07">6-641.07</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>June 20, 1938, 52 Stat. 802, ch. 534, § 14</annotation>
      <annotation>Oct. 28, 1949, 63 Stat. 972, ch. 782, title XI, § 1106(a)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-1">May 13, 1975, D.C. Law 1-1, § 1, 21 DCR 3938</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 3205(nn), 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-81">Aug. 7, 1980, D.C. Law 3-81, § 2(gg), 27 DCR 2632</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-168">Sept. 29, 1988, D.C. Law 7-168, § 2, 35 DCR 5747</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Merit system, effective date provisions, see § <cite root="1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Taxes and license deposits, refunds, see § <cite root="47-1317">47-1317</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 5-430.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 5-426.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Application of § 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-168">D.C. Law 7-168</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-168">D.C. Law 7-168</cite> provided that the compensation provided for in § 2 shall be paid for services rendered on or after May 1, 1988.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
