<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-701.03</num>
  <heading>Duty of owner to provide fire safety measures.</heading>
  <text>It shall be the duty of the owner entitled to the beneficial use, rental, or control of any building used or intended to be used as set forth in § <cite path="§6-701.01">6-701.01</cite> where fire escapes are required, or any building in which 10 or more persons are employed, as set forth in § <cite path="§6-701.02">6-701.02</cite>, where fire escapes are required, also to provide, install, and maintain therein proper and sufficient guide signs, guide lights, exit lights, hall and stairway lights, standpipes, fire extinguishers, and alarm gongs and striking stations in such locations and numbers and of such type and character as the Mayor of the District of Columbia may determine; except that in buildings less than 6 stories in height, standpipes will not be required when fire extinguishers are installed in such numbers and of such type and character as the Mayor of the District of Columbia may determine.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 19, 1906, 34 Stat. 70, ch. 957, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 2, 1907, 34 Stat. 1247, ch. 2566</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 4, 1934, 48 Stat. 843, ch. 388</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Fire Protection Study Commission, see § <cite path="§3-1101">3-1101</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-503.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-303.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2, of Fire Alarm Notice and Tenant Fire Safety Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-314, February 22, 2010,  57 DCR 1649).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
