<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-703.01</num>
  <heading>Fees for inspection of buildings; fees for annual hauling permits for certain multiaxle motor vehicles.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and directed, from time to time, to prescribe a schedule of fees to be paid for inspecting passenger elevators and for inspecting hotels, public halls, moving-picture shows, theaters, and other places of amusement which are required to have annual licenses, and for inspecting buildings which are required by law to have fire escapes; and he is further authorized and directed to impose fees for all inspections of service to be performed by any public officer or employee of the District of Columbia under any law or regulation in force July 11, 1919, or thereafter enacted; said fees to cover the cost and expense of such inspections or service; and a schedule of such fees shall be printed and conspicuously displayed in the office of the said Mayor, and said fees shall be paid to the Collector of Taxes, District of Columbia, and paid for each fiscal year into the General Fund of the District of Columbia. Notwithstanding the provisions of the preceding sentence, in the case of a single unit motor vehicle which has 3 or more axles and is designed to unload itself and which is operated in the District of Columbia under an annual hauling permit of the District of Columbia, the fee for such permit shall be as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>$680 if such motor vehicle is first placed in service after July 1, 1970;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If such motor vehicle is in service on or before July 1, 1970, and operated at a gross weight:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In excess of the weight permitted under normal operations under applicable regulations of the Mayor of the District of Columbia but less than 50,000 pounds, a fee of $380;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Of 50,000 pounds or more but less than 55,000 pounds, a fee of $480;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Of 55,000 pounds or more but less than 60,000 pounds, a fee of $580; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Of 60,000 pounds or more, not to exceed 65,000 pounds, a fee of $680.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to increase, from time to time, the fees prescribed by paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) of this section, taking into account expenditures for the purpose of repairing or replacing highway structures and roadway pavements requiring such repair or replacement as a result of the operation of the motor vehicles for which hauling permit fees are prescribed under the preceding sentence. Proceeds from fees from annual hauling permits for such vehicles shall be deposited in the highway fund created by § <cite path="§47-2301">47-2301</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 66-1-ch7" path="">July 11, 1919, 41 Stat. 69, ch. 7</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 22, 1921, 41 Stat. 1144, ch. 70, § 7</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 28, 1944, 58 Stat. 533, ch. 300, § 18</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-650" type="History">Jan. 5, 1971, 84 Stat. 1930, Pub. L. 91-650, title I, § 104(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-231" type="History">May 10, 1989, D.C. Law 7-231, § 17, 36 DCR 492</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 9036, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Fees collected by District, disposition, see § 47</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-703.02">6-703.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-516.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-316.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “General Fund” for “Treasury of the United States to the credit of the General Fund”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to An Act Making Appropriations to Provide for the Expenses of the Government of D.C. for the FY Ending June 30, 1920 and for Other Purposes; and to the License Fees and Charges Act of 1976, see Mayor’s Order 99-158, October 13,</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Office of Collector of Taxes abolished: The Office of the Collector of Taxes was abolished and the functions thereof transferred to the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia by Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1952. All functions of the Office of the Collector of Taxes including the functions of all officers, employees and subordinate agencies were transferred to the Director, Department of General Administration by Reorganization Order No. 3, dated August 28, 1952. Reorganization Order No. 20, dated November 10, 1952, transferred the functions of the Collector of Taxes to the Finance Office. The same Order provided for the Office of the Collector of Taxes headed by a Collector in the Finance Office and abolished the previously existing Office of the Collector of Taxes. Reorganization Order No. 20 was superseded and replaced by Organization Order No. 121, dated December 12, 1957, which provided that the Finance Office, consisting of the Office of the Finance Officer, Property Tax Division, Revenue Division, Treasury Division, Accounting Division, and Data Processing Division, would continue under the direction and control of the Director of General Administration, and that the Treasury Division would perform the function of collecting revenues of the District of Columbia and depositing the same with the Treasurer of the United States. Organization Order No. 121 was revoked by Organization Order No. 3, dated December 13, 1967, Part IVC of which prescribed the functions of the Finance Office within a newly established Department of General Administration. The executive functions of the Board of Commissioners were transferred to the Commissioner of the District of Columbia by § 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967. Functions of the Finance Office as stated in Part IVC of Organization Order No. 3 were transferred to the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue by Commissioner’s Order No. 69-96 dated March 7, 1969.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
