<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-701.04</num>
  <heading>Regulations authorized for enforcement of part.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and directed to issue such orders and the Council of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and directed to adopt, and the Mayor to enforce, such regulations not inconsistent with law as may be necessary to accomplish the purposes and carry into effect the provisions of this part, and the Mayor is hereby authorized and directed to require any alterations or changes that may become necessary in buildings now or hereafter erected, in order properly to locate or relocate fire escapes, or to afford access to fire escapes, and to require any changes or alterations in any building that may be necessary in order to provide for the erection of additional fire escapes, or for the installation of other appliances required by this part, when in the judgment of the Mayor such additional fire escapes or appliances are necessary.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 59-1-ch957" path="§4">Mar. 19, 1906, 34 Stat. 71, ch. 957, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 4, 1934, 48 Stat. 844, ch. 388</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(118) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Development of model construction codes: See Act of July 1, 1983, <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-15">D.C. Law 5-15</cite>,  30 DCR 2661.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-304.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-504.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Rules and regulations, Council and Mayor, power to make and enforce, see §§ <cite path="§1-303.03">1-303.03</cite> and <cite path="§1-303.04">1-303.04</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
