<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-751.02a</num>
  <heading>Visual alert systems.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The owner of each hotel or motel shall have available on the premises at least 1 visual alert system for every 50 units or less.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each hotel or motel shall provide a visual alert system to any guest or patron upon request. In circumstances in which the number of requests for visual alert systems exceeds the number of visual alert systems available, the hotel or motel shall make arrangements to procure additional systems, which shall be provided to the guest or patron within 8 hours of his or her request.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A notice informing guests and patrons of the availability of visual alert systems for deaf or hearing-impaired persons shall be posted either conspicuously in the lobby of the hotel or motel or placed conspicuously in the room of each guest or patron.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon the request of a deaf or hearing-impaired person, the owner of each dwelling unit, hospital, nursing home, or residential-custodial care facility shall provide a visual alert system in each room in which a deaf or hearing-impaired person resides.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon the request of a deaf or hearing-impaired person, the Mayor shall provide a visual alert system in each dwelling unit, hospital, nursing home, jail, prison, or residential-custodial care facility owned by the District of Columbia in which a deaf or hearing-impaired person resides.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-81" type="History" path="§3a">June 20, 1978, D.C. Law 2-81, § 3a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-84" type="History">as added Mar. 9, 1988, D.C. Law 7-84, § 2(b), 34 DCR 8122</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-530.1.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
