<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-751.05a</num>
  <heading>Smoke and carbon monoxide detector and battery program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall develop a program to test and install smoke and carbon monoxide detectors and batteries in District residences, and to educate District residents on the use of the detectors. The program shall be re-developed annually. The program may include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Door-to-door outreach;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A public information campaign, including printed and mass media materials, or community events in each ward of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The provision or installation of a smoke or combination smoke/carbon monoxide detector in a person’s residence; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Detector installation by personnel of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department, other District personnel, or such other persons who are willing to provide this service at no cost on behalf of the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The program shall specify that any person who agrees to receive and install a smoke or combination smoke/carbon monoxide detector shall permit a representative of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department to inspect the installation of the unit to confirm that the installation occurred and was done properly.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any resident or property owner participating in the program shall indemnify and hold harmless the District, its officers, employees, agents, and assigns for the provision and installation of the smoke or combination smoke/carbon monoxide detectors or batteries.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-81" type="History" path="§6a">June 20, 1978, D.C. Law 2-81, § 6a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-313" type="History">as added Mar. 20, 2009, D.C. Law 17-313, § 2, 56 DCR 37</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
