<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-910</num>
  <heading>Service of notice.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any notice required by this chapter to be served shall be deemed served when served by any of the following methods: (1) when forwarded to the last known address of the owner as recorded in the real estate assessment records of the District of Columbia by registered or certified mail, with return receipt, and such receipt shall constitute prima facie evidence of service upon such owner if such receipt is signed either by the owner or by a person of suitable age and discretion located at such address; provided, that valid service upon the owner shall be deemed effected if such notice shall be refused by the owner and not delivered for that reason; (2) when delivered to the person to be notified; (3) when left at the usual residence or place of business of the person to be notified with a person of suitable age and discretion then resident or employed therein; (4) if no such residence or place of business can be found in the District of Columbia by reasonable search, then if left with any person of suitable age and discretion employed at the office of any agent of the person to be notified, which agent has any authority or duty with reference to the land or tenement to which said notice relates; (5) if any such notice forwarded by registered or certified mail be returned for reasons other than refusal, or if personal service of any such notice, as hereinbefore provided, cannot be effected, then if published on 3 consecutive days in a daily newspaper published in the District of Columbia; or (6) if by reason of an outstanding unrecorded transfer of title the name of the owner in fact cannot be ascertained beyond a reasonable doubt, then if served on the owner of record in a manner hereinbefore provided. Any notice to a corporation shall, for the purposes of this chapter, be deemed to have been served on such corporation if served on the president, secretary, treasurer, general manager, or any principal officer of such corporation in the manner hereinbefore provided for the service of notices on natural persons holding property in their own right; and notices to a foreign corporation shall, for the purposes of this chapter, be deemed to have been served if served personally on any agent of such corporation, or if left with any person of suitable age and discretion residing at the usual residence or employed at the usual place of business of such agent in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In case such notice is served by any method other than personal service, notice shall also be sent to the owner by ordinary mail.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For purposes of receiving notice required by this chapter, a person who is a nonresident owner of vacant property in the District of Columbia shall appoint and continuously maintain a registered agent for the service of process. The appointment shall be made by filing a statement with the Mayor. The registered agent shall be an individual who is a resident of the District of Columbia or an organization incorporated in the District of Columbia. If the nonresident owner changes the registered agent or if the name and address or any other information about the registered agent changes after the statement is filed with the Mayor, the nonresident owner shall file a statement notifying the Mayor of the change. A nonresident owner of vacant property in the District of Columbia who violates this section shall be subject to a penalty of $300.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall serve as the registered agent for a nonresident owner of vacant property if a registered agent is not appointed by the nonresident owner or if the individual or organization named as registered agent ceases to serve in that capacity or cannot be located after reasonable diligence.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 1, 1906, 34 Stat. 159, ch. 2073, § 10</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 28, 1954, 68 Stat. 887, ch. 1032</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-326" type="History">Nov. 7, 1965, 79 Stat. 1216, Pub. L. 89-326, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 2072(c), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-710.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-625.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2072(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2072(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
