<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-919</num>
  <heading>Suits and proceedings under prior law; time limits.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All suits and proceedings instituted by or against the Board for the Condemnation of Insanitary Buildings in the District of Columbia created by former § <cite path="§6-801">6-801</cite>, or the Board for the Condemnation of Insanitary Buildings established by the Commissioners under the authority of Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1952, prior to September 27, 1954, shall be deemed to have been taken by, or instituted by or against, the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>With respect to any building or part of building condemned by either of the Boards aforesaid prior to September 27, 1954, and which building or part of building stands condemned as of September 27, 1954, the 6-month period provided by § <cite path="§6-903">6-903</cite> shall commence running from September 27, 1954.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 1, 1906, ch. 2073, § 19</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 28, 1954, 68 Stat. 889, ch. 1032</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-281" type="History">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-281, § 103(j), 48 DCR 1888</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-719.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-634.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-281">D.C. Law 13-281</cite> repealed subsec. (c) which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) Wherever any provision of this chapter refers to any order of the Board for the Condemnation of Insanitary Buildings, such provision shall mean the order of such Board, or, if such order be reviewed by the Condemnation Review Board, as such order has been affirmed or modified by the latter Board; and wherever this chapter establishes any time limit within which there shall be compliance with an order of the Board for the Condemnation of Insanitary Buildings, such time limit shall begin running from the date on which the owner of the property affected by said order is served with notice thereof, or, if such order be reviewed by the Condemnation Review Board, from the date on which the owner of such property receives notice that such order has been affirmed or modified by the latter Board.”</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
