<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-623.01</num>
  <heading>Office of Zoning — Established.</heading>
  <text>There is established as an independent agency of the District of Columbia (“District”) government an Office of Zoning to provide professional, technical, or administrative staff assistance to the Zoning Commission for the District (“Zoning Commission”) and to the Board of Zoning Adjustment in the performance of their functions and any other duties provided by law.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-163">Sept. 20, 1990, D.C. Law 8-163, § 2, 37 DCR 4676</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="6-623.03">6-623.03</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 5-412.1.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) provisions regarding the source of funding, see § 305 of the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-110, July 28, 1999,  46 DCR 6320).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) Office of Zoning additional space need provisions, see § 1202 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) Office of Zoning additional space need provisions, see § 1202 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <annotation>Short title of subtitle S of title I of Law 15-205: Section 1201 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> provided that subtitle S of title I of the act may be cited as Office of Zoning Additional Space Needs Act of 2004.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 1202 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> provided: “Not later than September 30, 2004, the Office of Property Management shall provide additional space within the District government office building located at 441  4th Street, N.W. (‘One Judiciary Square’) to the Office of Zoning (‘OZ’) to address OZ’s increased space requirements. The additional space to be provided shall include the Suite 200-S and other space on the second floor of One Judiciary Square.”</text>
      <text>Section effective October 1, 1991: Section 7(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-163">D.C. Law 8-163</cite> provided that the provisions of the act shall not apply until October 1, 1991.</text>
      <text>Section 305 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-38">D.C. Law 13-38</cite> provided: “The exclusive source of funding for the Office of Zoning shall be appropriated local funds.”</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
