<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-131.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
  <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Domestic violence” means an intrafamily offense as defined in § 16-1001(5) [now (8)].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Employee” means any individual employed by an employer, but shall not include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any individual who, without payment and without expectation of any gain, directly or indirectly, volunteers to engage in the activities of an educational, charitable, religious, or nonprofit organization;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Any lay member elected or appointed to office within the discipline of any religious organization and engaged in religious functions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Any individual employed as a casual babysitter, in or about the residence of the employer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>An independent contractor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>A student; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Health care workers who choose to participate in a premium pay program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>“Employer” means a legal entity (including a for-profit or nonprofit firm, partnership, proprietorship, sole proprietorship, limited liability company, association, or corporation), or any receiver or trustee of an entity (including the legal representative of a deceased individual or receiver or trustee of an individual), who directly or indirectly or through an agent or any other person, including through the services of a temporary services or staffing agency or similar entity, employs or exercises control over the wages, hours, or working conditions of an employee.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The term “employer” shall include the District government.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Family member” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>A spouse, including the person identified by an employee as his or her domestic partner, as defined in <cite path="§32-701|(3)">§ 32-701(3)</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>The parents of a spouse;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Children (including foster children and grandchildren);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>The spouses of children;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>Parents;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(vi)</num>
        <text>Brothers and sisters; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(vii)</num>
        <text>The spouses of brothers and sisters.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A child who lives with an employee and for whom the employee permanently assumes and discharges parental responsibility; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A person with whom the employee shares or has shared, for not less than the preceding 12 months, a mutual residence and with whom the employee maintains a committed relationship, as defined in <cite path="§32-701|(1)">§ 32-701(1)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Paid leave” means accrued increments of compensated leave provided by an employer for use by an employee during an absence from employment for any of the reasons specified in <cite path="§32-131.02|(b)">§ 32-131.02(b)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Premium pay program” means a plan offered by an employer pursuant to which an employee may elect to receive extra pay in lieu of benefits.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Sexual abuse” means any offense described in <cite path="22|30">Chapter 30 of Title 22</cite> [<cite path="§22-3001">§ 22-3001</cite> et seq.]</text>
    <text>
      <em>et seq.</em>
    </text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Student” means an employee who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Is a full-time student, as defined by an accredited institution of higher education;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Is employed by the institution at which the student is enrolled;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Is employed for less than 25 hours per week; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>Does not replace an employee subject to this chapter; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is employed as part of the Year Round Program for Youth, as established by the Department of Employment Services.</text>
    </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-152" type="History" path="§2">May 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-152, § 2, 55 DCR 3452</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-89" type="History">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-89, § 2(a), 61 DCR 317</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-293, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1215).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-292, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1211).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, §  7, see §  4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-188, Oct. 27, 2015,  62DCR 14224).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of section, see § 12 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-164, Oct. 16, 2015,  62 DCR 13734).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite>, § 3, see § 7003 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite>, § 3, see § 7003 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite>, § 3, see § 7003 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 8 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-76">D.C. Law 21-76</cite>, Feb. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 264).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-57">D.C. Law 21-57</cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,  62 DCR 15602).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite> rewrote (2); and substituted “who directly or indirectly or through an agent or any other person, including through the services of a temporary services or staffing agency or similar entity, employs or exercises control over the wages, hours, or working conditions of” for “who employs” in (3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">As to applicability of chapter being contingent upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, see <cite path="§32-131.17">§  32-131.17</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014, and that the act shall apply to violations occurring after October 1, 2014.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite> was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7003, effective Feb. 26, 2015.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7095 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> repealed section 18 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-152">D.C. Law 17-152</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
