<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1301</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>Whenever used in this chapter:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Employer” includes every individual, partnership, firm, general contractor, subcontractor, association, corporation, the legal representative of a deceased individual, or the receiver, trustee, or successor of an individual, firm, partnership, general contractor, subcontractor, association, or corporation, employing any person in the District of Columbia; provided, that the word “employer” shall not include the government of the United States, the government of the District of Columbia, or any agency of either of said governments, or any employer subject to the Railway Labor Act (45 U.S.C. § 151 et seq.).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Employee” shall include any person suffered or permitted to work by an employer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2A)</num>
      <text>“Living Wage Act” means <cite path="2|2|X-A">subchapter X-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2</cite> [<cite path="§2-220.01">§ 2-220.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2B)</num>
      <text>“Minimum Wage Revision Act” means <cite path="32|10">Chapter 10 of this title</cite> [<cite path="§32-1001">§ 32-1001</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2C)</num>
      <text>“Sick and Safe Leave Act” means <cite path="32|1A">Chapter 1A of this title</cite> [<cite path="§32-131.01">§ 32-131.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Wages” means all monetary compensation after lawful deductions, owed by an employer, whether the amount owed is determined on a time, task, piece, commission, or other basis of calculation. The term “wages” includes a:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Bonus;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Commission;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Fringe benefits paid in cash;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Overtime premium; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Other remuneration promised or owed:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Pursuant to a contract for employment, whether written or oral;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Pursuant to a contract between an employer and another person or entity; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Pursuant to District or federal law.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designated agent or agents.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>“Working day” means any day exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays, or legal holidays.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 84-2-ch924" path="§1">Aug. 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 976, ch. 924, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 2062(a), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-157" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-157, § 2(a), 61 DCR 10157</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(285) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 2061 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle G of Title II of the act may be cited as the “Wage Theft Prevention Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-293, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1215).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-188, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14224).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 2(c) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-544, Dec. 29, 2014,  62 DCR 243, 20 STAT 4458).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2062(a) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-57">D.C. Law 21-57</cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,  62 DCR 15602).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-240">D.C. Law 20-240</cite>, March 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1332).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite> substituted “firm, general contractor, subcontractor, association, corporation, the legal representative of a deceased individual, or the receiver, trustee, or successor of an individual, firm, partnership, general contractor, subcontractor” for “firm, association, corporation, the legal representative of a deceased individual, or the receiver, trustee, or successor of an individual, firm, partnership” in (1); deleted “except any person employed in a bona fide executive, administrative, or professional capacity (as such terms are defined and delimited by regulations promulgated by the Council of the District of Columbia)” from the end of (2); and added (2A), (2B), and (2C).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> rewrote (3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 36-601.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-101.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§2-220.08">§ 2-220.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014, and that the act shall apply to violations occurring after October 1, 2014.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-300">D.C. Law 19-300</cite> designated the existing provisions of Chapter 13 as subchapter I, and enacted subchapter II.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
