<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1653</num>
  <heading>Funding of students.</heading>
  <text>Pursuant to <cite path="§51-109.01">§ 51-109.01</cite>, a student enrolled in an Educational Stepladder program approved course and who maintains a satisfactory level of attendance and achievement in the program and who is:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Receiving unemployment insurance compensation shall be eligible for an extension of benefits for the duration of the program, up to a maximum amount of 52 times his or her weekly benefit amount, or 100% of the wages for employment paid the individual by employers during his or her base period, whichever is the lesser; this total amount includes regular benefits and any federal extension that may be in effect; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Not receiving unemployment insurance compensation may be eligible for a weekly monetary benefit equal to the unemployment insurance compensation weekly benefit amount a person earning minimum wage would receive, to the extent that funds are available, for the duration of the program, up to a maximum of 52 times the calculated weekly benefit.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History" path="§1154">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1154, 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1153 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1153 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
