<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-170">
  <num type="law">14-170</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Public Schools Free Textbook Amendment Act of 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2002-06-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-170.pdf">D.C. Law 14-170</citation>
      <citation type="register">49 DCR 4726</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0036">
      <narrative>Law 14-170, the “District of Columbia Public Schools Free Textbook Amendment Act of 2002”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-36, which was referred to the Committee on Education, Libraries and Recreation. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 26, 2001, and April 9, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 3, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-361 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-170 became effective on June 28, 2002.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act to provide books and educational supplies free of charge to pupils of the public schools for the District of Columbia to require the Board of Education to issue each public school student textbooks, workbooks, and adequate instructional materials, free of charge, for each core curriculum subject by the second week of each new semester, to provide that the Board of Education may require a refundable deposit for textbooks issued to students in grades 7 through 12 to offset costs associated with lost or damaged textbooks, to require the Superintendent to certify to the Board of Education within 30 days of the beginning of each new semester that each student has been issued textbooks, workbooks, and adequate instructional materials, free of charge, for each core curriculum subject, to require the Board of Education to review all books in use every 5 years and certify that the books meet accepted industry standards and advance the educational policies of the Board, and to authorize the Board of Education to promulgate regulations to implement the provisions of this act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Public Schools Free Textbook Amendment Act of 2002 Sec. 2. Section 1 of An Act To provide books and educational supplies free of charge to pupils of the public schools of the District of Columbia, approved January 31, 1930 (46 Stat. 62; D.C. Official Code § 38-701 is amended to read as follows a) The Board of Education shall issue to each student of the public elementary schools, public junior high schools, and public senior high schools textbooks, workbooks, and adequate instructional materials for each core curriculum subject, free of charge, by the second week of each new semester. The Superintendent shall certify to the Board of Education, within 30 days of each new semester, that each student has been issued textbooks, workbooks, and adequate instructional materials for each core curriculum subject, free of charge b) The Board of Education shall evaluate and certify every 5 years that all textbooks used in the public school system meet the Board of Education's goals and objectives and the Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2002 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 38-701 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2V:\ENROLL14\B14-036.PER curriculum framework established for District of Columbia public schools c) The Board of Education may require a refundable deposit for textbooks issued to students in grades 7 through 12, to offset costs associated with lost or damaged textbooks. If the Board of Education requires a textbook deposit pursuant to this subsection, the Board of Education shall provide for a refund of the deposit at the conclusion of the relevant semester or school year for which the textbook was issued d) The Board of Education shall adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this section Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
