<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-184">
  <num type="law">14-184</num>
  <heading type="short">Washington Convention Center Authority Oversight and Management Continuity Amendment Act of 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2002-10-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-184.pdf">D.C. Law 14-184</citation>
      <citation type="register">49 DCR 6059</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0521">
      <narrative>Law 14-184, the “Washington Convention Center Authority Oversight and Management Continuity Amendment Act of 2002”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-521, which was referred to the Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 7, 2002, and June 4, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 21, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-384 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-184 became effective on October 1, 2002.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994 to extend the terms of certain public members of the Board of Directors of the Washington Convention Center Authority until December 31, 2003. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Washington Convention Center Authority Oversight and Management Continuity Amendment Act of 2002”. Sec. 2. Section 205(b)(1) of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective September 28, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-188; D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.05(b)(1 is amended as follows a) Strike the phrase “terms. No” and insert the phrase “terms, and no” in its place b) Add the phrase “; provided, the term of a public Board member who is serving in his or her second consecutive term on May 15, 2001, shall terminate on December 31, 2003” before the final period. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2002 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 10-1202.05 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
