<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-262">
  <num type="law">14-262</num>
  <heading type="short">Special Education Task Force Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-262.pdf">D.C. Law 14-262</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 14-262, the “Special Education Task Force Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2002”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-944, and was retained by Council. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 2002, and December 3, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 23, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-559 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-262 became effective on March 27, 2003.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend, on an temporary basis, the Special Education Task Force Temporary Act of 2002, to add two parents of special education children to the composition of the Special Education Task Force. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Special Education Task Force Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2002”. Sec. 2. Section 5(b) of the Special Education Task Force Temporary Act of 2002, effective October 19, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-210; 49 DCR 7848 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (8) is amended by striking the word “and” at the end b) Paragraph (9) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place c) A new paragraph (10) is added to read as follows: “(10) Two parents of District of Columbia Special Education students.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. This act will have no fiscal impact. Sec. 4 Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2003 Supp. West Group Publisher Note, § 38-2501 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
