<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-298" flag="true">
  <num type="law">14-298</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-298.pdf">D.C. Law 14-298</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend, on a temporary basis, the Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988 to establish a defined period of minimum required affordability for housing units assisted with the Housing Production Trust Fund. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Housing Production Trust Fund Affordability Period Temporary Amendment Act of 2002”. Sec. 2. The Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-202; D.C. Official Code § 42-2801 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 42-2801) is amended by adding a new paragraph (3B) to read as follows 3B) Continuing affordability means A) For rental units, a period of at least 40 years; and B) For for-sale units, a period of at least 10 years.” b) Section 3(d)(8 D.C. Official Code § 42-2802(d)(8 is amended by striking the phrase "targeted populations and inserting the phrase “targeted populations; provided, that the Department shall not be required to assure affordability on a continuing basis where assistance is provided for the rehabilitation of owner-occupied single-family homes or where assistance is provided under the Homestead Housing Preservation Act of 1986, effective August 9, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-135; D.C. Official Code § 42-2101 et seq or another statutory program in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2003 Supp. West Group Publisher Note, § 42-2801 Note, § 42-2802 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Sec. 4. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
