<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-286">
  <num type="law">14-286</num>
  <heading type="short">Council Review of the Exclusive Right Agreement for the Redevelopment of the Existing Convention Center Site Amendment Act of 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2003-04-04</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-286.pdf">D.C. Law 14-286</citation>
      <citation type="register">50 DCR 944</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0814">
      <narrative>Law 14-286, the “Council Review of the Exclusive Right Agreement for the Redevelopment of the Existing Convention Center Site Amendment Act of 2002”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-814, which was referred to Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 3, 2002, and December 17, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 22, 2003, it was assigned Act No. 14-620 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-286 became effective on April 4, 2003.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To require Council review and approval of any proposed exclusive right agreement for the redevelopment of the existing convention center site. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Council Review of the Exclusive Right Agreement for the Redevelopment of the Existing Convention Center Site Amendment Act of 2002”. Sec. 2. The Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective September 28, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-188; D.C. Official Code § 10-1201.01 et seq is amended by adding a new section 215a to read as follows: “Sec. 215a. Redevelopment of existing convention center site. “Any proposed exclusive right agreement to redevelop the existing convention center site, which is legally described as Square 374 and Lot 848 and excluding Lot 829, shall be submitted with a proposed resolution by the Mayor to the Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed resolution within the 30-day period of review, the proposed resolution and exclusive right agreement shall be deemed approved.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2003 Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
