<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-235">
  <num type="law">14-235</num>
  <heading type="short">Motor Vehicle Definition Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device Exemption Amendment Act of 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2003-03-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-235.pdf">D.C. Law 14-235</citation>
      <citation type="register">49 DCR 9788</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0550">
      <narrative>Law 14-235, the “Motor Vehicle Definition Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device Exemption Amendment Act of 2002”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-550, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 2, 2002, and October 1, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 23, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-497 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-235 became effective on March 25, 2003.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Compulsory/No Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982, An Act To provide for the regulation of finance charges for the retail installment sales of motor vehicles in the District of Columbia and for other purposes, An Act To provide for the annual inspection of all motor vehicles in the District of Columbia, An Act To provide for the recording and releasing of liens by entries on certificates of title for motor vehicles and trailers and for other purposes, the Motor Vehicle Safety Responsibility Act of the District of Columbia, the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, the Rental Vehicle Tax Reform Act of 1978, the District of Columbia Implied Consent Act, the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1925, the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, the District of Columbia Motor Vehicle Parking Facility Act of 1942, and Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, to define "electric personal assistive mobility device to exempt electric personal assistive mobility devices from the definitions of "motor vehicle to authorize the Mayor to promulgate regulations to exempt electric personal assistive mobility devices from the requirements pertaining to motor vehicles. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Motor Vehicle Definition Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device Exemption Amendment Act of 2002 Sec. 2. Section 3(17) of the Compulsory/No Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982, effective September 18, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-155; D.C. Official Code § 31-2402(17 is amended to read as follows 17) The term “motor vehicle” means any device propelled by an internal- combustion engine, electricity, or steam, including any non-operational vehicle that is being restored or repaired. The term “motor vehicle” does not include traction engines used exclusively for drawing vehicles in fields, road rollers, vehicles propelled only upon rails and tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201(l and Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2003 Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 31-2402 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Sec. 3. Section 1(6) of An Act To provide for the regulation of finance charges for retail installment sales of motor vehicles in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved April 22, 1960 (74 Stat. 69; D.C. Official Code § 50-601(6 is amended to read as follows 6) “Motor vehicle” means any automobile, mobile home, motorcycle, truck, truck tractor, trailer, semi-trailer, or bus. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include any boat trailer, any vehicle propelled or drawn exclusively by muscular power, any vehicle designed to run only on rails or tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201(l and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Sec. 4. Section 8 of an Act to provide for the annual inspection of all motor vehicles in the District of Columbia, approved February 18, 1938 (52 Stat. 78; D.C. Official Code § 50- 1108 is amended to read as follows Sec. 8. As used in this act the term '”motor vehicle” means all vehicles propelled by internal-combustion engines, electricity, or steam. The term 'motor vehicle' shall not include traction engines, road rollers, vehicles propelled only upon rails or tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201(l and battery- operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Sec. 5. Section 1 of An Act To provide for the recording and releasing of liens by entries on certificates of title for motor vehicles and trailers, and for other purposes, approved July 2, 1940 (54 Stat. 736; D.C. Official Code § 50-1201 is amended as follows a) The undesignated subsections are designated as subsections (a) through (i b) The newly designated subsection (i) is amended to read as follows i) “Motor vehicle” shall mean all vehicles propelled by internal-combustion engines, electricity, or steam. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include traction engines, road rollers, vehicles propelled only upon rails or tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201(l and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Amend § 50-601 Amend § 50-1108 Amend § 50-1201 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Sec. 6. Section 2(4) of the Motor Vehicle Safety Responsibility Act of the District of Columbia, approved May 25, 1954 (68 Stat. 120; D.C. Official Code § 50-1301.02(4 is amended to read as follows 4) Motor vehicle Every vehicle which is self-propelled and every vehicle which is propelled by electric power obtained from overhead trolley wires, but not operated upon rails. The term 'motor vehicle' shall not include electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201(l and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Sec. 7. Section 1(a) of Title IV of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 679; D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.01(1 is amended to read as follows a) The term “motor vehicle” means any vehicle propelled by internal-combustion engine, electricity, or steam, including any non-operational vehicle that is being restored or repaired. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include road rollers, farm tractors, vehicles propelled only upon stationary rails or tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201(l and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Sec. 8. Section 2(b) of the Rental Vehicle Tax Reform Act of 1978, effective March 6, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-157; D.C. Official Code § 50-1505.01(2 is amended to read as follows: “(b) The term “motor vehicle” means any device propelled by an internal-combustion engine, and designed to carry passengers. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include road rollers, farm tractors, trucks, motorcycles, motorized bicycles, vehicles with a seating capacity of ten or more persons, vehicles propelled only upon rails and tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201(l and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Sec. 9. Section 1(8) of the District of Columbia Implied Consent Act, approved October 21, 1972 (86 Stat. 1016; D.C. Official Code § 50-1901(8 is amended to read as follows 8) The term “motor vehicle” means all vehicles propelled by internal combustion engines, electricity, or steam. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201(l and Amend § 50-1301.02 Amend § 50-1501.01 Amend § 50-1505.01 Amend § 50-1901 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Sec. 10. The District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.02) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows: “(a) The term “motor vehicle” means all vehicles propelled by internal-combustion engines, electricity, or steam. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include traction engines, road rollers, vehicles propelled only upon rails or tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by subsection (l) of this section, and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour 2) A new subsection (l) is added to read as follows l Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device" or "EPAMD" means a device, designed to transport only one person, with an electric propulsion system that limits the maximum speed of the device to 10 miles per hour or less b) A new section 6a is added to read as follows Sec. 6a. Regulations for electric personal assistive mobility devices a) The Mayor shall promulgate regulations to exempt electric personal assistive mobility devices from the regulations governing motor vehicles b) Regulations promulgated pursuant to this section shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days of Council recess. If the proposed rules are not approved within the 45-day period of review, the rules shall be deemed disapproved c) A new section 9a is added to read as follows Sec. 9a. Age requirement for operation of an electric personal assistive mobility device No person under 16 years of age may operate an electric personal assistive mobility device in the District of Columbia d) Section 7(f D.C. Official Code § 50-1401.01(f is amended to read as follows f) For purposes of this section and sections 8 and 13 the term “motor vehicle” means all vehicles propelled by internal-combustion engines, electricity, or steam. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include traction engines, road rollers, vehicles propelled only upon rails or tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1 and battery- operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Sec. 11. Section 102(e-1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2301.02(5A is amended to read as follows: Amend § 50-2201.02 New § 50-2201.03a New § 50-2201.04a Amend § 50-1401.01 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 e-1) The term “motor vehicle” means all vehicles propelled by an internal-combustion engine, electricity, or steam. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include traction engines, road rollers, vehicles propelled only upon stationary rails or tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201(l and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Sec. 12. Section 2 of the District of Columbia Motor Vehicle Parking Facility Act of 1942, approved February 16, 1942 (56 Stat. 91; D.C. Official Code § 50-2602 is amended to read as follows a) The undesignated paragraphs are designated as paragraphs (1) through (5 b) The newly designated paragraph (5) is amended to read as follows 5) The term “motor vehicle” means any device propelled by an internal- combustion engine, electricity, or steam. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include traction engines, road rollers, vehicles propelled only upon rails or tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by section 2(1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201(l and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour Sec. 13. Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (Vehicles and Traffic) is amended as follows a) Chapter 12 is amended as follows 1) Subsection 1200.4 is amended to read as follows 1200.4 No operator's permit shall be required for the operation of a bicycle or an electric personal assistive mobility device 2) Subsection 1200.6 is amended to read as follows 1200.6 No points shall accrue toward the loss or suspension of a motor vehicle operator's permit by reason of a violation committed while operating a bicycle, sidewalk bicycle, or an electric personal assistive mobility device 3) Subsection 1200.8 is amended to read as follows 1200.8 No person, except for impoundment by the Mayor, shall tamper with any bicycle or electric personal assistive mobility device which has been locked, placed in a rack, or otherwise secured. Any person found tampering with any bicycle or electric personal assistive mobility device may be required to pay a fine of $100 4) Subsections 1201.2, 1201.9, 1201.10, 1201.11, and 1201.12 are amended to read as follows: Amend § 50-2301.02 Amend § 50-2602 DCMR ENROLLED ORIGINAL 6Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 1201.2 A person shall operate a bicycle, sidewalk bicycle or electric personal assistive mobility device in a safe and non-hazardous manner so as not to endanger himself or herself or any other person 1201.9 There shall be no prohibition against any person riding a bicycle or electric personal assistive mobility device upon a sidewalk within the District, so long as the rider does not create a hazard; provided, that no person shall ride a bicycle or operate an electric personal assistance mobility device upon a sidewalk within the Central Business District except on those sidewalks expressly designated by Order of the Mayor, nor shall any person ride a bicycle upon a sidewalk in any area outside of the Central Business District if it is expressly prohibited by Order of the Mayor and appropriate signs to such effect are posted 1201.10 Any person riding a bicycle or electric personal assistive mobility device upon a sidewalk shall yield the right-of-way to pedestrians, and shall travel at a speed no greater than the posted speed limit of the adjacent roadway; provided, that such speed is safe for the conditions then existing on the sidewalk 1201.11 A person propelling a bicycle or operating an electric personal assistive mobility device upon and along a sidewalk or while crossing a roadway in a crosswalk shall have all the rights and duties applicable to a pedestrian under the same circumstances, except that the bicyclist or electric personal assistive mobility device operator must yield to pedestrians on the sidewalk or crosswalk 1201.12 The operator of a bicycle or electric personal assistive mobility device emerging from, or entering an alley, driveway, or building, shall upon approaching a sidewalk, or the sidewalk area extending across any alleyway, yield the right-of-way to all pedestrians approaching on said sidewalk, and upon entering the roadway shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles approaching on said roadway, to the extent necessary to safely enter the flow of traffic b) Subsection 2217.5 of Chapter 22 is amended to read as follows 2217.5 No vehicle except buses proceeding on a designated bus route, bicycles, electric personal assistive mobility devices, and authorized emergency vehicles shall travel on those streets or portions of streets designated as bus streets or bus lanes except as provided in §§ 2217.6, 2217.7, 4005 and 4006 c) Chapter 40 is amended as follows 1) Subsection 4005.1 is amended to read as follows 4005.1 The traffic lane closest to the right hand curb on the streets listed in this subsection shall be designated a Restricted Lane and reserved for the use of buses, carpools, taxicabs, bicycles, motorized bikes, motorcycles, electric personal assistive mobility devices, or other designated vehicles during the hours and on the days indicated 2) Subsection 4006.1 is amended to read as follow: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 7Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 4006.1 No vehicles shall travel on bus streets except buses proceeding on designated bus routes, bicycles, electric personal assistive mobility devices, or authorized emergency vehicles, except as otherwise provided in this section d) Chapter 99 is amended by adding the following new definition to section 9901 Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device" or "EPAMD" means a device, designed to transport only one person, with an electric propulsion system that limits the maximum speed of the device to 10 miles per hour or less Sec. 14. Sunset. This act shall expire on October 1, 2005. Sec. 15. Fiscal impact statement. There is no fiscal impact associated with the provisions of the Motor Vehicle Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device Amendment Act of 2002. Funds are sufficient in the FY 2003 through FY 2006 budget and financial plan to implement the proposed legislation. Sec. 16. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602 (c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia Note, §§ 31-2402, 50-601, 50-1108, 50-1201, 50-1301.02, 50-1501.01, 50-1505.01, 50-1901, 50-2201.02, 50-2201.03a, 50-2201.04a, 50-1401.01, 50-2301.02, 50-2602</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
