<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-257">
  <num type="law">14-257</num>
  <heading type="short">Public Health Laboratory Fee Amendment Act of 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2003-03-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-257.pdf">D.C. Law 14-257</citation>
      <citation type="register">50 DCR 244</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0679">
      <narrative>Law 14-257, the “Public Health Laboratory Fee Amendment Act of 2002”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-679, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 2002, and December 3, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 23, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-554 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-257 became effective on March 27, 2003.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Act of 2001 to expand the authority of the Public Health Laboratory to charge fees for all the services and forms it provides to the public. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public Health Laboratory Fee Amendment Act of 2002 Sec. 2. Section 4905 of the Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 7-734 is amended by striking the first sentence and inserting in its place a new sentence to read as follows The Mayor is authorized to establish a schedule of fees for forms and for performing laboratory analysis of biological and environmental samples obtained from humans, animals, or various environmental media for the purpose of identifying environmental contaminants and performing epidemiological surveillance, including for cases of lead poisoning, tuberculosis, rabies, and sexually transmitted diseases Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2003 Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 7-734 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
