<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-237">
  <num type="law">14-237</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Flag Adoption and Design Act of 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2003-03-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-237.pdf">D.C. Law 14-237</citation>
      <citation type="register">49 DCR 10485</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0647">
      <narrative>Law 14-237, the “District of Columbia Flag Adoption and Design Act of 2002”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-647, which was referred to the Committee on the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 2, 2002, and October 1, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 23, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-516 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-237 became effective on March 25, 2003.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To adopt an official flag for the District of Columbia, to proclaim the unique status of the District of Columbia as the only place in the United States where citizens are fully taxed without being fully represented in the Congress of the United States by temporarily redesigning the flag of the District of Columbia to include the words "DC" and "No Taxation Without Representation and to establish a commission to advise the Council regarding the placement and design of such language. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “District of Columbia Flag Adoption and Design Act of 2002 Sec. 2. District of Columbia official flag. The flag of the District of Columbia shall be 3 red stars in the upper portion of the flag (the chief with 2 red horizontal bars on a field of white. All proportions described in this section are expressed in relation to the flag's vertical dimension (the hoist The chief shall be 3/10 of the hoist, the horizontal red bars shall be 2/10, the base and white space between the 2 bars shall be 2/10 and 1/10, respectively. The red stars shall be 2/10 in diameter, and shall be spaced equidistant in the fly. The length of the fly shall depend on the proportions of the flag upon which this design may be displayed. Sec. 3. Inclusion of “DC” and “No Taxation Without Representation” within District of Columbia flag a) After the design adopted under subsection (b) of this section becomes effective, the flag of the District of Columbia shall temporarily contain the language "DC" and "No Taxation Without Representation b) The placement and design of the language prescribed in subsection (a) of this section shall be established by act of the Council c) The flag adopted pursuant to section 2 and subsection (b) of this section shall be flown officially as of 90 days following the effective date of the act specified in subsection (b) of this section d) The language prescribed in subsection (a) of this section shall be removed from the Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2003 Supp. West Group Publisher New Subchapter V, Chapter 1, Title 1 New § 1-171 New § 1-172 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. flag when District of Columbia registered voters are able to vote for 2 Senators and one Representative with full rights and privileges in the Congress of the United States e) The language prescribed in subsection (a) of this section shall not be required in instances where a reproduction of the flag is placed as a symbol on motor vehicles, District of Columbia government letterhead, or other objects. Sec. 4. Flag Design Advisory Commission a) There is established a Flag Design Advisory Commission Commission with the purpose of preparing a recommendation for the placement and design of the language “DC” and “No Taxation Without Representation” on the District of Columbia flag b) The Commission shall be composed of 7 members: the Mayor, or his or her designee; the Chairman of the Council, or his or her designee; the Chairman of the Council's Subcommittee on Labor, Voting Rights, and Redistricting, or his or her designee; 2 persons appointed by the Mayor; and 2 persons appointed by the Chairman of the Council. The Chairman of the Council shall designate the Commission Chairman. All appointments shall be made within 30 days of the effective date of this act. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the initial appointment was made c) The Commission shall submit its recommendation in the form of a report to the Council no later than 4 months after the effective date of this act. The Commission shall approve its recommendation by a majority vote d) Costs of the Commission and its members shall be borne by the members or paid through private contributions. The Commission is authorized to receive private-sector contributions. The Commission is authorized to use space and supplies owned or rented by the District of Columbia government, and to use staff loaned from the Council or detailed from the Mayor for such purposes consistent with this act as the Commission may determine e) The Commission shall have the authority to create and operate under its own rules of procedure f) The books and records of the Commission shall be public documents. Sec. 5. Use of donations and grants for flag replacement. The Mayor is authorized to solicit, receive, accept, and expend donations or grants from private sources to defray the costs of replacing existing District of Columbia flags with flags that include the language prescribed in section 3(a Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 7. Effective date. New § 1-173 New § 1-174 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-151"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-152"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-153"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-154"/>
  </section>
</document>
