<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-210">
  <num type="law">14-210</num>
  <heading type="short">Special Education Task Force Temporary Act of 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-210.pdf">D.C. Law 14-210</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 14-210, the “Special Education Task Force Temporary Act of 2002”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-711, and was retained by Council. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 4, 2002, and July 2, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 23, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-445 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-210 became effective on October 19, 2002.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establish, on a temporary basis, a Special Education Task Force that would assist the District of Columbia Public Schools in implementing its Seven Point Plan for Special Education. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Special Education Task Force Temporary Act of 2002 Sec. 2. Establishment. There is established a Special Education Task Force Task Force with the purpose of serving as a collaborative body of District agencies that will monitor, support, and implement Special Education reform within the District of Columbia Public Schools. Sec. 3. Functions. Specific functions of the Task Force shall include the following 1) Within 60 days of the approval of the Board, adopt by a majority vote, the Special Education Reform Plan developed pursuant to section 4 2) Convene monthly or more frequently as deemed necessary and appropriate by its members to report on the progress, identify obstacles, and recommend amendments to the Reform Plan 3) Identify ways that better coordinate and improve special education service delivery 4) Monitor the Special Education Reform Plan, developed by the Superintendent for the District of Columbia Public Schools and approved by the Board of Education for the District of Columbia, to determine whether its being executed in an appropriate and timely manner; and (5) Determine specific savings targets for Fiscal Year 2004 and beyond, including those associated with the Tobacco Settlement funds provided to the District of Columbia Public Schools in Fiscal Year 2003. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2002 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Note, § 38-2501 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Sec. 4. Special Education Reform Plan. The Superintendent shall develop a Special Education Reform Plan Reform Plan which shall include the following 1) Measurable goals 2) Time line for deliverables 3) Roles and responsibilities of all District agencies that provide special education related services 4) Proposed legislative amendments 5) Targeted savings activities for fiscal years 2003-2005; and (6) Review and input from Task Force members. Sec. 5. Composition of the Task Force a) The Task Force shall be comprised of the following 9 members, or designees thereof 1) The Mayor of the District of Columbia 2) The Chair of the Committee on Education, Libraries and Recreation for the Council of the District of Columbia 3) The chair of Committee of Finance and Revenue for the Council of the District of Columbia 4) The President of the Board of Education 5) The District of Columbia Public Schools Superintendent 6) The State Education Officer of the District of Columbia 7) The Deputy Mayor for Children, Youth, Families and Elders; and (8) The Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia; and (9) The Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia Public Schools b) The following shall serve as advisory, nonvoting members of the Task Force 1) All the members of the Council's Committee on Education, Libraries and Recreation 2) The department head or designee of the Office of Special Education 3) The department head or designee of the Committee on Special Education and Student Services for the Board of Education 4) The department head or designee of the Office of Corporation Counsel 5) The department head or designee of the Department of Mental Health 6) The department head or designee of the Child and Family Services Agency 7) The department head or designee of the Medical Assistance Administration 8) The department head or designee of the Office of Medicaid Public Provider Operation Reform; and (9) The representative of the State Advisory Panel on Special Education in the District of Columbia. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 c) The Task Force shall be co-chaired by the Mayor and the Chair of the Committee on Education, Libraries and Recreation d) The Director of the State Education Office shall provide staffing for the Task Force. Sec. 6. Memorandum of Understanding. The voting members of the Task Force shall adopt and sign a Memorandum of Understanding regarding the implementation of the Reform Plan. Sec. 7. Fiscal impact statement. This act shall have no fiscal impact. Sec. 8 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
