<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-34">
  <num type="law">14-34</num>
  <heading type="short">Corrections Information Council Temporary Amendment Act of 2001</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-34.pdf">D.C. Law 14-34</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 14-34, the “Corrections Information Council Temporary Amendment Act of 2001”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-233, which was retained by Council. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 5, 2001, and June 26, 2001, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 12, 2001, it was assigned Act No. 14-96 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-34 became effective on October 13, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend, on a temporary basis, the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 to establish additional duties for the Corrections Information Council CIC to establish procedures for its meetings, and to provide the CIC with management and support services. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Corrections Information Council Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 Sec. 2. Section 11201(g) of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 Revitalization Act approved August 5, 1997 (111 Stat. 736; D.C. Official Code § 24-101(h is amended to read as follows h) District of Columbia Corrections Information Council 1) Establishment There is established a council to be known as the District of Columbia Corrections Information Council (hereafter referred to as "CIC 2) Membership The CIC shall be composed of 3 members, appointed as follows A) Two members appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia B) One member to be appointed by the Council of the District of Columbia, by resolution C) Of the members first appointed, the Mayor shall appoint one member for a one-year term. The other mayoral appointee and the Council appointee shall serve 2-year terms. Thereafter, members shall be appointed for terms of 2 years D) The Mayor shall designate the Chairperson of the CIC 3) Compensation Members of the CIC shall not receive compensation for their service 4) Duties The CIC shall A) Report to the Director of the Bureau of Prisons with advice and information regarding matters affecting the District of Columbia sentenced felon population B) Conduct comprehensive inspections, unannounced whenever possible, of facilities housing District of Columbia sentenced felons and interview selected staff Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition West Group Publisher Note, § 24-101 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. at each facility C) Review documents related to the conditions of confinement at each facility housing District of Columbia sentenced felons, including, but not limited to, inmate files and records, inmate grievances, incident reports, disciplinary reports, use of force reports, medical and psychological records, administrative and policy directives of the facility, and logs, records, and other data maintained by the facility; and D) Transmit to the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, the Mayor, the Council, and the Director of the District of Columbia's Department of Corrections the following reports, copies of which shall be made available to the public i) An annual report on the conditions of confinement of District of Columbia sentenced felons; and ii) A report on each inspection of a facility housing District of Columbia sentenced felons 5) Meetings and hearings A) The CIC shall meet as necessary to conduct official business B) The presence of 2 members shall constitute a quorum necessary for the CIC to take official action C) The CIC may act by an affirmative vote of at least 2 members 6) Management and support services A) The Chief Financial Officer shall provide financial support services and oversight for the CIC using personnel assigned to provide financial support services and oversight for the District of Columbia's Department of Corrections B) The Chief Procurement Officer shall provide contracting and procurement support services and oversight for the CIC using personnel assigned to provide contracting and procurement support services and oversight for the District of Columbia's Department of Corrections. The CIC is authorized to contract with qualified private organizations or individuals for services in accordance with the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Official Code § 2-301.01 et seq C) The CIC is authorized to appoint one employee to the Excepted Service established by Title X of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-609.01 et seq Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council of the District of Columbia has earmarked $100,000 in the District of Columbia's Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Request Act to fund one full-time equivalent staff member and to pay for non-personal services needed to support the work of the Corrections Information Council. Therefore, funds are available in the District of Columbia's financial plan and budget to support the work of the Corrections Information Council. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Official Code § 47-392.03(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect or upon the effective date of the Corrections Information Council Amendment Act of 2001, passed on 2nd reading on June 26, 2001 (Enrolled version of Bill 14-221 whichever occurs first. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
