<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-94">
  <num type="law">14-94</num>
  <heading type="short">Child and Family Services Agency Licensure Exemption of Certain Court Personnel Amendment Act of 2001</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2002-03-19</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-94.pdf">D.C. Law 14-94</citation>
      <citation type="register">49 DCR 658</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0379">
      <narrative>Law 14-94, the “Child and Family Services Agency Licensure Exemption of Certain Court Personnel Amendment Act of 2001”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-379, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 2001, and December 18, 2001, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 8, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-223 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-94 became effective on March 19, 2002.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977 to provide for the waiver of licensure requirements for certain persons who are employed by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, assigned to the Child Abuse Unit of the Social Services Division of the Superior Court in the position of probation officer, and who have been satisfactorily performing case management and other social work services for children and families in the Child Abuse Unit. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Child and Family Services Agency Licensure Exemption of Certain Court Personnel Amendment Act of 2001 Sec. 2. Section 302a of the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977, effective April 4, 2001 (D.C. Law 13-277; to be codified at D.C. Official Code § 4-1303.02a is amended by adding a new subsection (j) to read as follows j)(1) Notwithstanding the provisions of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code § 3- 1201.01 et seq no more than 10 individuals employed by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia Superior Court in the position of probation officer and officially assigned to the Child Abuse Unit of the Social Services Division of the Superior Court by the Superior Court who have performed satisfactorily in that position for at least one year prior to April 4, 2001, or for at least one year prior to October 1, 2001, may continue to perform case management and other related social work services for children and families under the immediate direction of the Child and Family Services Agency in cases pending before the Neglect Branch of the Family Division of the Superior Court, or in cases where allegations of abuse or neglect have been substantiated, without obtaining a social work license or otherwise meeting the requirements for social work licensure. This exemption shall apply only for so long as the individual works under the immediate direction of the Child and Family Services Agency, and shall not extend past October 1, 2004. To continue performing case management and other related social work Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2002 Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 4-1303.02a ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. services for the Child and Family Services Agency, individuals who receive exemptions under this subsection shall be required to meet all District of Columbia social work licensure requirements on or before October 1, 2004 2) This subsection expires on October 1, 2004 Sec. 3. Appropriations. This act shall be subject to the availability of appropriations. Sec. 4. Applicability. This act shall apply as of October 1, 2001. Sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
