<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-1610</num>
  <heading>Prohibition against discrimination in use of AIDS tests.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No insurer shall inquire about the sexual orientation  or gender identity or expression of an applicant in an application for health, life, or disability income insurance coverage or in an investigation conducted by an insurer or insurance support organization on behalf of an insurer in connection with an application for the coverage.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Sexual orientation or gender identity or expression, shall not be used as a factor in the underwriting process or in the determination of insurability.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Insurance support organizations shall be directed by insurers not to investigate, directly or indirectly, the sexual orientation or gender identity or expression of a proposed insured.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An insurance company shall not use sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, lifestyle, living arrangements, occupation, gender, or beneficiary designation to determine whether to test an individual who applies for life, health, or disability income insurance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-132">Aug. 7, 1986, D.C. Law 6-132, § 11</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-208">as added Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-208, § 2(h), 36 DCR 471</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-177">June 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-177, § 15(c), 55 DCR 3696</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 35-230.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-177">D.C. Law 17-177</cite>, in subsecs. (a) and (c), substituted “sexual orientation or gender identity or expression” for “sexual orientation”; in subsec. (b), substituted “Sexual orientation or gender identity or expression, shall not” for “Sexual orientation shall not”; and, in subsec. (d), substituted “sexual orientation, gender identity or expression” for “sexual orientation”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
