<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-1131.07b</num>
  <heading>Continuing education.</heading>
  <text>All individual title insurance producers shall fulfill the following continuing education requirements:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Eight hours biennially for District of Columbia barred attorneys in courses specific to District of Columbia real estate laws and related regulations, and any other continuing education courses approved by the Commissioner;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Sixteen hours biennially for resident title insurance producers in instruction specific to District of Columbia real estate laws and related regulations, and continuing education courses approved by the Commissioner of which not more than 8 hours may be completed through on-line or video-based courses; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Four hours of instruction biennially for nonresident title insurance producers in instruction specific to District of Columbia real estate laws and related regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-264" type="History" path="§7b">Mar. 27, 2003, D.C. Law 14-264, § 7b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-155" type="History">as added May 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-155, § 2(h), 55 DCR 3683</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 2166(d), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-40" type="History">Nov. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 20-40, § 6(c), 60 DCR 12304</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “The Commissioner may establish continuing education requirements for resident insurance producers.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-40">D.C. Law 20-40</cite> rewrote this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2166(d) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
