<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-107</num>
  <heading>Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking funding.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Control of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund, and all monies required to be deposited therein, pursuant to Chapter 7 of this title, is transferred to the Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-2)</num>
    <text>There is established within the General Fund of the District of Columbia a trust fund designated as the Securities and Banking Regulatory Trust Fund (“Fund”), to which shall be credited all proceeds from licensure and any funds obtained pursuant to securities regulation and banking regulation. All funds received but not expended in a fiscal year shall revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia. All funds received and deposited in the Fund shall be used to fund the expenses of the Securities and Banking Bureau in the discharge of its administrative and regulatory duties as prescribed by law. All licensing fees, fines, and any other fees imposed, assessed, and collected for securities regulation and banking regulation shall be deposited into the Fund. The Mayor, through the Commissioner, shall administer the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The administrative costs of the Department, including the compensation of the Commissioner and the Department’s central administrative staff, shall be charged on a pro-rata basis to each of the respective Bureau trust funds in a manner reflecting the central administrative costs associated with the operation of each Bureau. In no circumstances shall monies collected and deposited pursuant to the statutory funding requirements of the District of Columbia Securities Act, the Investment Advisors Act, and the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act, be commingled or used to fund the regulatory activities of a bureau other than the bureau regulating the activities for which the respective funds were established.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit to the Council, as part of the annual budget, a budget for the Department and a request for an appropriation for expenditures from the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund and the Securities and Banking Regulatory Trust Fund. The Mayor’s request shall be based on an estimated projection of the expenditures necessary to perform the administration and regulatory functions of the Department. This estimate shall include, but not be limited to, expenditures for salaries, fringe benefits, overhead charges, travel, training, supplies, technical, professional, and any and all other services necessary to discharge the duties and responsibilities of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 8, 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-166" type="History">June 11, 2004, D.C. Law 15-166, § 3(g), 51 DCR 2817</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 2112(d), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 9039, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-5041.02">31-5041.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-127.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-166">D.C. Law 15-166</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “Department” for “Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation”; added subsec. (b-1); and, in subsec. (d), substituted “, the Security Regulatory Trust Fund, and the Banking Regulatory Trust Fund” for “and the Security Regulatory Trust Fund”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> repealed subsecs. (b) and (b-1); added subsec. (b-2); and, in subsec. (d), substituted “and the Securities and Banking Regulatory Trust Fund” for “, the Securities Regulatory Trust Fund, and the Banking Regulatory Trust Fund”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>, in subsec. (b-2), substituted “all proceeds from licensure and any funds” for “all funds”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(g) of Consolidation of Financial Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-381, February 27, 2004,  51 DCR 2653).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2112(d) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">The “District of Columbia Securities Act”, referred to in (c), is the Act of August 30, 1964, 78 Stat. 620, Pub. L. 88-503, which is codified primarily as § <cite path="§3-3601">3-3601</cite> et seq.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">The “Investment Advisors Act”, referred to in (c), is <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-216">D.C. Law 9-216</cite>, which is codified as § <cite path="§3-3701">3-3701</cite> et seq.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">The “Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act”, referred to in (c), is <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-40">D.C. Law 10-40</cite>, which is codified as § <cite path="§31-1201">31-1201</cite> et seq.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
