<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-1131.16</num>
  <heading>Reciprocity.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except for the requirements imposed by § <cite root="31-1131.08">31-1131.08</cite>, the Commissioner shall waive any requirements for a nonresident license applicant with a valid license from his or her home state, if the applicant’s home state awards nonresident licenses to residents of the District on the same basis. The Commissioner may waive any requirements, except for those imposed by § <cite root="31-1131.08">31-1131.08</cite>, for a nonresident license applicant with a valid license from the applicant’s home state if the applicant’s home state does not award nonresident licenses to residents of the District on the same basis.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A nonresident insurance producer’s satisfaction of his or her home state’s continuing education requirements for licensed insurance producers shall constitute satisfaction of the District’s continuing education requirements if the nonresident producer’s home state recognizes the satisfaction of its continuing education requirements imposed upon insurance producers from the District on the same basis. The Commissioner may determine that a nonresident insurance producer’s satisfaction of his or her home state’s continuing education requirements for licensed insurance producers constitutes satisfaction of the District’s continuing education requirements if the nonresident producer’s home state does not recognize the satisfaction of its continuing education requirements imposed upon insurance producers from the District on the same basis.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A license issued to a nonresident of the District shall grant the same rights and privileges as a resident licensee.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-264">Mar. 27, 2003, D.C. Law 14-264, § 16, 50 DCR 260</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-155">May 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-155, § 2(m), 55 DCR 3683</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-155">D.C. Law 17-155</cite>, in subsec. (a), inserted: “The Commissioner may waive any requirements, except for those imposed by § <cite root="31-1131.08">31-1131.08</cite>, for a nonresident license applicant with a valid license from the applicant’s home state if the applicant’s home state does not award nonresident licenses to residents of the District on the same basis.”; in subsec. (b), inserted “The Commissioner may determine that a nonresident insurance producer’s satisfaction of his or her home state’s continuing education requirements for licensed insurance producers constitutes satisfaction of the District’s continuing education requirements if the nonresident producer’s home state does not recognize the satisfaction of its continuing education requirements imposed upon insurance producers from the District on the same basis.”; and, in subsec. (c) deleted: “An applicant may qualify for a license under this chapter as a nonresident only if the applicant holds an equivalent license in his or her home state.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
