<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-1332</num>
  <heading>Domiciliary liquidator’s proposal to distribute assets.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 120 days of a final determination of insolvency of an insurer by a court of competent jurisdiction of the District of Columbia, the liquidator shall make application to the court for approval of a proposal to disburse assets out of marshalled assets, from time to time as the assets become available, to a guaranty association or foreign guaranty association having obligations because of the insolvency. If the liquidator determines that there are insufficient assets to disburse, the application required by this section shall be considered satisfied by a filing by the liquidator stating the reasons for this determination.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The proposal required by subsection (a) of this section shall at least include provisions for:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reserving amounts for the payment of expenses of administration and the payment of claims of secured creditors, to the extent of the value of the security held, and claims falling within the priorities established in § <cite path="§31-1340">31-1340</cite>, classes 1 and 2;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Disbursement of the assets marshalled to date and subsequent disbursement of assets as they become available;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Equitable allocation of disbursements to each of the guaranty associations and foreign guaranty associations entitled thereto;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The securing by the liquidator, from each of the associations entitled to disbursements pursuant to this section, of an agreement to return to the liquidator those assets, together with income earned on assets previously disbursed, required to pay claims of secured creditors and claims falling within the priorities established in § <cite path="§31-1340">31-1340</cite> in accordance with those priorities. No bond shall be required of such an association; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A full report to be made by each association to the liquidator accounting for all assets so disbursed to the association, all disbursements made therefrom, any interest earned by the association on the assets, and any other matter the court may direct.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The liquidator’s proposal shall provide for disbursements to the associations in amounts estimated at least equal to the claim payments made or to be made thereby for which the associations could assert a claim against the liquidator, and shall further provide that if the assets available for disbursement from time to time do not equal or exceed the amount of the claim payments made or to be made by the association, then disbursements shall be in the amount of available assets.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The liquidator’s proposal shall, with respect to an insolvent insurer writing life or health insurance or annuities, provide for disbursements of assets to any guaranty association or any foreign guaranty association covering life or health insurance or annuities, or to any other entity or organization reinsuring, assuming, or guaranteeing policies or contracts of insurance under the acts creating the associations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Notice of the application shall be given to the association in and to the commissioners of insurance of each of the states. Such a notice shall be deemed to have been given when deposited in the United States certified mails, first class postage prepaid, at least 30 days prior to submission of the application to the court. Action on the application may be taken by the court provided the above required notice has been given, and, provided further, that the liquidator’s proposal complies with subsection (b)(1) and (2) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-35" type="History">Oct. 15, 1993, D.C. Law 10-35, § 33, 40 DCR 5773</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-1323">31-1323</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-2832.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
