<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-1131.05</num>
  <heading>Examination prior to licensure.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An individual applying for a resident insurance producer license shall pass a written examination unless the individual is:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Applying for a limited lines insurance producer license or a license in the surplus lines line of authority; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Exempt from examination under <cite path="§31-1131.05b">§ 31-1131.05b</cite> or <cite path="§31-1131.09">§ 31-1131.09</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>The examination required by subsection (a) of this section shall test the knowledge of the individual concerning the lines of authority for which application is made, the duties and responsibilities of an insurance producer, and the insurance laws and regulations of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may make arrangements, including contracting with an outside testing service, for administering examinations and collecting a nonrefundable fee for the examination.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each individual applying for an examination shall remit a nonrefundable fee for the examination as prescribed by the Commissioner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An individual who fails to appear for the examination as scheduled or fails to pass the examination may reapply for an examination. The individual shall remit all required fees and forms before being rescheduled for another examination.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-264" type="History" path="§5">Mar. 27, 2003, D.C. Law 14-264, § 5, 50 DCR 260</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-155" type="History">May 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-155, § 2(c), 55 DCR 3683</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 2166(a), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2166(a) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> substituted “<cite path="§31-1131.05b">§ 31-1131.05b</cite> or <cite path="§31-1131.09">§ 31-1131.09</cite>” for “<cite path="§31-1131.09">§ 31-1131.09</cite>”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-155">D.C. Law 17-155</cite> rewrote the section name line which had read as follows: “ Application for examination”; rewrote subsec. (a); added subsec. (a-1); and, in subsec. (d), substituted “may reapply for an examination. The individual shall remit” for “shall reapply for an examination and remit”. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “(a) A resident individual applying for an insurance producer license shall pass a written examination unless exempt under <cite path="§31-1131.09">§ 31-1131.09</cite>. The examination shall test the knowledge of the individual concerning the lines of authority for which application is made, the duties and responsibilities of an insurance producer, and the insurance laws and regulations of the District. Examinations required by this section shall be developed and conducted under rules and regulations promulgated by the Commissioner.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§31-1131.05a">§ 31-1131.05a</cite>, <cite path="§31-1131.05b">§ 31-1131.05b</cite>, <cite path="§31-1131.07">§ 31-1131.07</cite>, and <cite path="§31-1131.08">§ 31-1131.08</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
