<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-1209</num>
  <heading>Annual audit of Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund or District of Columbia Health Benefit Exchange Authority Fund.</heading>
  <text>Upon a vote of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Bureau taken in accordance with its bylaws, the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Bureau, at its own expense, may annually arrange for an independent audit of the expenditures made in any fiscal year by the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund or the District of Columbia Health Benefit Exchange Authority Fund established in § <cite path="§31-3171.03">31-3171.03</cite>(a). The Commissioner, the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking, the Executive Director of the District of Columbia Health Benefit Exchange Authority, and all other elements of the District of Columbia government shall cooperate with such an audit and shall make available all documents and records reasonably necessary to the conduct of the audit.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-40" type="History">Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-40, § 10, 40 DCR 6009</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-235" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-235, § 24(l), 44 DCR 818</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(y), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 36(c), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-166" type="History">June 11, 2004, D.C. Law 15-166, § 4(h)(4), 51 DCR 2817</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 5082(c), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-2709.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-166">D.C. Law 15-166</cite> substituted “Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking” for “Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(h)(4) of Consolidation of Financial Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-381, February 27, 2004,  51 DCR 2653).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5082(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5082(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5082(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
