<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-1312</num>
  <heading>Powers and duties of the rehabilitator.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner as rehabilitator may appoint 1 or more special deputies, who shall have all the powers and responsibilities of the rehabilitator granted under this section, and the Commissioner may employ any counsel, clerks, and assistants deemed necessary. The compensation of the special deputy, counsel, clerks, and assistants and all expenses of taking possession of the insurer and of conducting the proceedings shall be fixed by the Commissioner, with the approval of the court, and shall be paid out of the funds or assets of the insurer. The persons appointed under this section shall serve at the pleasure of the Commissioner. The Commissioner, as rehabilitator, may, with the approval of the court, appoint an advisory committee of policyholders, claimants, or other creditors, including guaranty associations, should that committee be deemed necessary. The advisory committee shall serve at the pleasure of the Commissioner and shall serve without compensation other than reimbursement for reasonable travel and per diem living expenses. No other committee of any nature shall be appointed by the Commissioner or the court in rehabilitation proceedings conducted under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In the event that the property of the insurer does not contain sufficient cash or liquid assets to defray the costs incurred, the Commissioner may advance the costs so incurred out of any appropriation for the maintenance of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking. Any amounts so advanced for expenses of administration shall be repaid to the Commissioner for the use of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking out of the first available money of the insurer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The rehabilitator may take such action as deemed necessary or appropriate to reform and revitalize the insurer. The rehabilitator shall have all the powers of the directors, officers, and managers, whose authority shall be suspended, except as they are redelegated by the rehabilitator. The rehabilitator shall have full power to direct and manage, to hire and discharge employees subject to any contract rights they may have, and to deal with the property and business of the insurer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If it appears to the rehabilitator that there has been criminal or tortious conduct, or breach of any contractual or fiduciary obligation detrimental to the insurer by any officer, manager, agent, broker, employee, or other person, he or she may pursue all appropriate legal remedies on behalf of the insurer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If the rehabilitator determines that reorganization, consolidation, conversion, reinsurance, merger, or other transformation of the insurer is appropriate, the rehabilitator shall prepare a plan to effect the changes. Upon application of the rehabilitator for approval of the plan, and after any notice and hearings the court may prescribe, the court may either approve or disapprove the plan proposed, or may modify it and approve it as modified. Any plan approved under this section shall be, in the judgment of the court, fair and equitable to all parties concerned. If the plan is approved, the rehabilitator shall carry out the plan. In the case of a life insurer, the plan proposed may include the imposition of liens upon the policies of the company, if all rights of shareholders are first relinquished. A plan for a life insurer may also propose imposition of a moratorium upon loan and cash surrender rights under policies, for such a period and to such an extent as may be necessary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The rehabilitator shall have the power under §§ <cite path="§31-1324">31-1324</cite> and <cite path="§31-1325">31-1325</cite> to avoid fraudulent transfers.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-35" type="History" path="§13">Oct. 15, 1993, D.C. Law 10-35, § 13, 40 DCR 5773</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(z)(2), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-166" type="History">June 11, 2004, D.C. Law 15-166, § 4(i)(4), 51 DCR 2817</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-1311">31-1311</cite> and § <cite path="§31-1314">31-1314</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-2812.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-166">D.C. Law 15-166</law-cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking” for “Department of Insurance and Securities” both times it appears.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(i)(4) of Consolidation of Financial Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-381, February 27, 2004,  51 DCR 2653).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
