<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-1372.12</num>
  <heading>Additional investment authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Solely for the purpose of acquiring investments that exceed the quantitative limitations of §§ <cite path="§31-1372.02">31-1372.02</cite> through <cite path="§31-1372.09">31-1372.09</cite>, an insurer may acquire under this subsection an investment, or engage in investment practices, described in § <cite path="§31-1372.08">31-1372.08</cite>; provided, that an insurer shall not acquire and investment, or engage in investment practices, described in § <cite path="§31-1372.08">31-1372.08</cite> under this subsection if, as a result of and after giving effect to the transaction:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The aggregate amount of investments held by an insurer under this subsection would exceed 3% of its admitted assets; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The aggregate amount of investments as to one limitation in §§ <cite path="§31-1372.02">31-1372.02</cite> through <cite path="§31-1372.09">31-1372.09</cite> held by the insurer under this subsection would exceed 1% of its admitted assets.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In addition to the authority provided under subsection (a) of this section, subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an insurer may acquire under this subsection an investment of any kind, or engage in investment practices described in § <cite path="§31-1372.08">31-1372.08</cite>, that are not specifically prohibited by this chapter without regard to the categories, conditions, standards, or other limitations of §§ <cite path="§31-1372.02">31-1372.02</cite> through <cite path="§31-1372.09">31-1372.09</cite> if, as a result of and after giving effect to the transaction, the aggregate amount of investments held under this subsection would not exceed the lesser of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Ten percent of its admitted assets; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Seventy-five percent of its capital and surplus.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An insurer shall not acquire any investment or engage in any investment practice under this subsection if, as a result of and after giving effect to the transaction, the aggregate amount of all investments in any one person held by the insurer under this subsection would exceed 3% of its admitted assets.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to the investments acquired under subsections (a) and (b) of this section, an insurer may acquire under this subsection an investment of any kind, or engage in investment practices described in § <cite path="§31-1372.08">31-1372.08</cite>, that are not specifically prohibited by this chapter without regard to any limitations of §§ <cite path="§31-1372.02">31-1372.02</cite> through <cite path="§31-1372.09">31-1372.09</cite> if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commissioner grants prior approval;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The insurer demonstrates that its investments are being made in a prudent manner and that the additional amounts will be invested in a prudent manner; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>As a result of and after giving effect to the transaction, the aggregate amount of investments held by the insurer under this subsection does not exceed the greater of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Twenty-five percent of its capital and surplus; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>One hundred percent of capital and surplus, less 10% of its admitted assets.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An investment prohibited under § <cite path="§31-1371.05">31-1371.05</cite> or § <cite path="§31-1372.10">31-1372.10</cite> or additional derivative instruments acquired under § <cite path="§31-1372.10">31-1372.10</cite> shall not be acquired under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-297" type="History">Apr. 11, 2003, D.C. Law 14-297, § 212, 50 DCR 330</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-1371.03">31-1371.03</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
