<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-1804</num>
  <heading>Books and records; reinsurance intermediary brokers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For at least 10 years after expiration of each contract of reinsurance transacted by the reinsurance broker, the reinsurance broker will keep a complete record for each transaction showing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The type of contract, limits, underwriting restrictions, classes, or risks and territory;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Period of coverage, including effective and expiration dates, cancellation provisions, and notice required of cancellation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reporting and settlement requirements of balances;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Rate used to compute the reinsurance premium;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Names and addresses of assuming reinsurers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Rates of all reinsurance commissions, including the commissions on any retrocessions handled by the reinsurance broker;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Related correspondence and memoranda;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Proof of placement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Details regarding retrocessions handled by the reinsurance broker including the identity of retrocessionaires and percentage of each contract assumed or ceded;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Financial records, including, but not limited to, premium and loss accounts; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>When the reinsurance broker procures a reinsurance contract on behalf of a licensed ceding insurer:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Directly from any assuming reinsurer, written evidence that the assuming reinsurer has agreed to assume the risk; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If placed through a representative of the assuming reinsurer, other than an employee, written evidence that the reinsurer has delegated binding authority to the representative.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The insurer will have access and the right to copy and audit all accounts and records maintained by the reinsurance broker related to its business in a form usable by the insurer.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-47" type="History" path="§5">Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-47, § 5, 40 DCR 6093</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-3104.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-1803">31-1803</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
