<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-1131.07</num>
  <heading>License.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless denied licensure under § <cite path="§31-1131.12">31-1131.12</cite>, persons who have met the requirements of §§ <cite path="§31-1131.05">31-1131.05</cite> and <cite path="§31-1131.06">31-1131.06</cite> shall be issued a resident insurance producer license. An insurance producer may receive qualification for a license in one or more of the following lines of insurance permitted under law or regulations:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Life, consisting of insurance coverage on human lives, including benefits of endowment and annuities, benefits in the event of death or dismemberment by accident, and benefits for disability income;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Accident and health or sickness, consisting of insurance coverage for sickness, bodily injury, or accidental death, including benefits for disability income;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Property, consisting of insurance coverage for the direct or consequential loss or damage to property of every kind;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Casualty, consisting of insurance coverage against legal liability, including that for death, injury, or disability, or damage to real or personal property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Variable life and variable annuity, consisting of insurance coverage provided under variable life insurance contracts and variable annuities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Personal lines, consisting of property and casualty insurance coverage sold to individuals and families for primarily noncommercial purposes;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Bail bonds, consisting of insuring or guaranteeing that a person will attend court when required, or will obey the orders or judgment of a court, as a condition to the release of the person from confinement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Surplus lines, consisting of insurance coverage provided pursuant to § <cite path="§31-2502.40">31-2502.40</cite>(a) by a company not otherwise authorized to do business in the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Any of the following limited lines of insurance:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Car rental;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Credit;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Crop;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C-i)</num>
        <text>Portable electronics;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Surety;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Travel;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>A limited line of insurance established by the Commissioner by rule; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>A line of insurance the Commissioner recognizes as a limited line of insurance for the purposes of complying with § <cite path="§31-1131.08">31-1131.08</cite>(e).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>A person shall not be issued a license in the bail bonds or surplus lines line of insurance unless the person holds, or is simultaneously issued, a license in the property or casualty line of insurance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The license shall contain the licensee’s name, address, personal identification number, the date of issuance, the lines of authority, the expiration date, and any other information the Commissioner considers useful or necessary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>To assist in the performance of the Commissioner’s duties, the Commissioner may contract with a third party, including the NAIC, or its affiliates or subsidiaries, to perform any ministerial functions, including the collection of fees, related to producer licensing that the Commissioner may consider appropriate.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-264" type="History" path="§7">Mar. 27, 2003, D.C. Law 14-264, § 7, 50 DCR 260</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-155" type="History">May 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-155, § 2(g), 55 DCR 3683</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-306" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-306, § 201, 60 DCR 2746</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-306">D.C. Law 19-306</cite> added (a)(10)(C-i).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-155">D.C. Law 17-155</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-1131.02">31-1131.02</cite> and § <cite path="§31-1131.08">31-1131.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Portable electronics insurance, § <cite path="§31-5051.01">31-5051.01</cite> et seq.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
