<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-1401</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Company” means any person engaging in or proposing or attempting to engage in any transaction or kind of insurance or surety business and any person or group of persons who may otherwise be subject to the insurance laws of the District of Columbia, including fraternal benefit associations and excluding the District of Columbia Life and Health Guaranty Association and the District of Columbia Property and Liability Insurance Guaranty Association.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2A)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Examiner” means any individual or firm having been authorized by the Mayor to conduct an examination under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Person” means any individual, aggregation of individuals, trust, association, partnership, or corporation, or any affiliate thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-49" type="History" path="§2">Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-49, § 2, 40 DCR 6110</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(ff)(1), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 39, 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-166" type="History">June 11, 2004, D.C. Law 15-166, § 4(j), 51 DCR 2817</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 10 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-49">D.C. Law 10-49</cite> provided that the Mayor shall, pursuant to <cite path="1|15|I">subchapter I of Chapter 15 of Title 1</cite> <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, 2001 Ed., issue rules to implement the provisions of this chapter.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-49">D.C. Law 10-49</cite>, the Law on Examinations Act of 1993, see Mayor’s Order 94-54, March 7, 1994 ( 41 DCR 1433).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(j) of Consolidation of Financial Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-381, February 27, 2004,  51 DCR 2653).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-166">D.C. Law 15-166</cite>, in par. (2A), substituted “Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking” for “Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-3601.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
