<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-2502.27</num>
  <heading>Filing and approval of policy forms.</heading>
  <text>The Commissioner may require that all policy forms used by every company covering risks in the District be filed with the Commissioner. The Commissioner shall have authority to disapprove, within 60 days after the date of the receipt of a filing, the use in the District of any policy form which is inequitable, or does not comply with the requirement of the law of the District. If a policy form is not disapproved for use within the 60-day period described above, the Commissioner may not disapprove it for use unless it does not comply with the requirements of the law of the District.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 76-3-ch792" path="§27">Oct. 9, 1940, 54 Stat. 1076, ch. 792, ch. II, § 27</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-90" type="History">Feb. 27, 1996, D.C. Law 11-90, § 9(b), 42 DCR 7155</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-160" type="History">Sept. 20, 1996, D.C. Law 11-160, § 3, 43 DCR 3722</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(r)(2), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-1531.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-1331.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 9(b) of Insurance Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-36">D.C. Law 11-36</cite>, September 8, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 5305).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 10(b) of the Insurance Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-48, May 15, 1995,  42 DCR 2544) and § 9(b) of the Insurance Omnibus Congressional Recess Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-97, July 19, 1995,  42 DCR 3844).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Report by Commissioner of Insurance and Securities: Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-160">D.C. Law 11-160</cite> provided that “Within two years of September 20, 1996, the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities shall prepare and submit to the Council of the District of Columbia for its review a report on the impact of this act on the private passenger motor vehicle insurance market or any part thereof, the funding for the Office of Insurance, the District of Columbia insurance premium tax, the number of insurers doing business in the District, and the number of insurers domiciled in the District of Columbia. In preparing such report, the Commissioner may request from specific private passenger motor vehicle insurers doing business in the District, or from all such insurers, reasonable and pertinent information. Information which is proprietary to any affected insurer shall be treated as confidential by the Commissioner, but may be used in the aggregate with other information from other affected insurers for statistical or other reporting purposes.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Department of Insurance abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§31-2501.03">31-2501.03</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
