<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-2502.11</num>
  <heading>Kinds of insurance authorized.</heading>
  <text>Any company authorized to do business in the District may, when empowered by its charter, make all or any 1 or more of the kinds of insurance and reinsurance comprised in either or both of the following classes, subject to and in accordance with the provisions of this chapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <heading>Fire and marine. —</heading>
    <text>On houses, buildings, and all other kinds of property against loss, damage, or damages by fire, lightning, or storm; to insure against loss or damage by water to any goods or premises arising from the breakage or leakage of sprinklers or water pipes; and to make all kinds of insurance against loss of or damage to goods, merchandise, or other property caused by fire, risks of transportation, or navigation, the action of the elements or adverse manifestations of nature, as well as all and every risk or peril to which the subject of insurance may be exposed, against which it is not contrary to public policy to insure, including every insurable interest therein or in the use thereof, or profit or income therefrom, or legal liability therefor, but not to include injury to the person nor loss caused by breach of trust; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <heading>Casualty. —</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Upon the health of persons, or against injury, disablement, or death of persons resulting from traveling or general accidents by land or water, and against liability of the assured for injuries to employees or other persons;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Against liability of the assured for loss or destruction of or damage to property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Upon the lives of domestic animals;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Against loss of or damage to glass and its appurtenances;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Against loss of or damage to any property resulting from the explosion of or injury to any boiler, heater, unfired pressure vessel, pipes, or containers connected therewith, any engine, turbine, compressor, pump, or wheel or any apparatus generating, transmitting or using electricity, or any other machine or apparatus connected with or operated by any of the previously named boilers, vessels, or machines; and including the incidental power to make inspections of and to issue certificates of inspection upon, any such boilers, apparatus, and machinery, whether insured or otherwise;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Against loss by burglary or theft, or both, and against loss of or damage to moneys and securities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>To guarantee and indemnify merchants, traders, and those engaged in business and giving credit, from loss and damage by reason of giving and extending credit to their customers and those dealing with them;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(H)</num>
      <text>Against loss or damage by water or other fluid or substance to any property resulting from the breakage or leakage of sprinklers or water pipes; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(I)</num>
      <text>To insure against any other casualty risk which may lawfully be the subject of insurance, and which it is not contrary to public policy to insure; provided, that this section shall not be construed as having any effect whatever upon the right or authority of any solvent company to make contracts of fidelity or surety.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 76-3-ch792" path="§11">Oct. 9, 1940, 54 Stat. 1069, ch. 792, ch. II, § 11</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 29(a), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Employees’ Compensation Act, insurance under, see § <cite path="§31-5205">31-5205</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Prohibition against wagering policies, see § <cite path="§31-2601.01">31-2601.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-1514.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-1314.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
