<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-2706</num>
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <heading>Filing requirements of organizations of companies; unfair practices; supervision of rating organizations.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 80-2-ch324" path="§303">May 20, 1948, 62 Stat. 245, ch. 324, § 6</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-233" type="History">Mar. 21, 1995, D.C. Law 10-233, § 7, 42 DCR 24</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-110" type="History">Apr. 18, 1996, D.C. Law 11-110, § 39, 43 DCR 530</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997,D.C. Law 11-255, § 40, 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(t), 44DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(jj), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-265" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-265, § 126(c), 48 DCR 1225</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">redesignated § 303, Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 20(b), 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For purported temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(x) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003,  50 DCR 6896).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-1506.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-1706.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Department of Insurance abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§31-2701">§ 31-2701</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Office of Collector of Taxes abolished: The Office of the Collector of Taxes was abolished and the functions thereof transferred to the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia by Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1952. All functions of the Office of the Collector of Taxes including the functions of all officers, employees, and subordinate agencies were transferred to the Director, Department of General Administration by Reorganization Order No. 3, dated August 28, 1952. Reorganization Order No. 20, dated November 10, 1952, transferred the functions of the Collector of Taxes to the Finance Office. The same Order provided for the Office of the Collector of Taxes headed by a Collector in the Finance Office, and abolished the previously existing Office of the Collector of Taxes. Reorganization Order No. 20 was superseded and replaced by Organization Order No. 121, dated December 12, 1957, which provided that the Finance Office (consisting of the Office of the Finance Officer, Property Tax Division, Revenue Division, Treasury Division, Accounting Division, and Data Processing Division) would continue under the direction and control of the Director of General Administration, and that the Treasury Division would perform the function of collecting revenues of the District of Columbia and depositing the same with the Treasurer of the United States. Organization Order No. 121, was revoked by Organization Order No. 3, dated December 13, 1967, Part IVC of which prescribed the functions of the Finance Office within a newly established Department of General Administration. The executive functions of the Board of Commissioners were transferred to the Commissioner of the District of Columbia by § 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967. Functions of the Finance Office as stated in Part IVC of Organization Order No. 3 were transferred to the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue by Commissioner’s Order No. 69-96, dated March 7, 1969. The collection functions of the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue were transferred to the District of Columbia Treasurer by <cite path="§47-316">§ 47-316</cite> on March 5, 1981.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">D.C. Act 15-145, § 3(x) and <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-38">D.C. Law 15-38</cite>, § 3(x), purported to amend subsec. (c)(5) of this section previously repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
