<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-2231.03</num>
  <heading>Misrepresentations and false advertising of insurance policies.</heading>
  <text>No person shall make, issue, circulate, or cause to be made, issued or circulated, an estimate, illustration, circular or statement, sales presentation, omission, or comparison that:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Misrepresents the benefits, advantages, conditions, or terms of a policy;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Misrepresents the dividends or share of the surplus to be received on a policy;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Makes a false or misleading statement as to the dividends or share of surplus previously paid on a policy;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Is misleading or is a misrepresentation as to the financial condition of an insurer or as to the legal reserve system upon which a life insurer operates;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Uses a name or title of a policy or class of policies misrepresenting the true nature thereof;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Is a misrepresentation, including an intentional erroneous quotation of a premium rate for the purpose of inducing, or tending to induce, the purchase, lapse, forfeiture, exchange, conversion, or surrender of a policy;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Is a misrepresentation for the purpose of effecting a pledge or assignment of, or effecting a loan against, a policy;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Misrepresents a policy as being shares of stock; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Uses a name which deceptively infers or suggests that it is an insurer if it is not an insurer.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-265" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-265, ยง 103, 48 DCR 1225</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
