<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-2901</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Baseline mammogram” means a screening mammogram that is used as a comparison for future examinations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Screening mammogram” means a low dose x-ray used to visualize the internal structure of the breast.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Cytologic screening” means a pap test to detect cervical cancer through the simple microscopic examination of cells scraped from the surface of the cervix.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Health benefit plan” means any accident and health insurance policy or certificate, hospital and medical services corporation contract, health maintenance organization subscriber contract, plan provided by a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or plan provided by another benefit arrangement. The term “health benefit plan” does not mean accident only, credit, or disability insurance; coverage of Medicare services or federal employee health plans, pursuant to contracts with the United States government; Medicare supplemental or long-term care insurance; dental only or vision only insurance; specified disease insurance; hospital confinement indemnity coverage; limited benefit health coverage; coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance, insurance arising out of a workers’ compensation or similar law; automobile medical payment insurance; medical expense and loss of income benefits; or insurance under which benefits are payable with or without regard to fault and that is statutorily required to be contained in any liability insurance policy or equivalent self-insurance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-225" type="History">Mar. 7, 1991, D.C. Law 8-225, § 2, 38 DCR 217</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-312" type="History">June 18, 2003, D.C. Law 14-312, § 401(a), 50 DCR 306</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-2401.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-312">D.C. Law 14-312</cite> rewrote par. (4) which had read as follows: “(4) ‘Health insurance policy’ means any health insurance policy that provides for the payment of indemnity on account of sickness and is offered by Group Hospitalization and Medical Services, Incorporated, a health insurance company, a health self-insured, an insurance purchasing trust, or any health maintenance organization that offers insurance benefits or health plans in the District of Columbia (‘District’). The term ‘health insurance policy’ shall not include a hospital indemnity policy, a disability insurance policy, an accident only policy, or a student accident policy.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
