<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-2001</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Adjusted RBC Report” means an RBC report that has been adjusted by the Commissioner in accordance with § <cite path="§31-2002">31-2002</cite>(g).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Corrective order” means an order issued by the Commissioner specifying corrective actions which the Commissioner has determined are required.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Domestic insurer” means any insurance company domiciled in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Foreign insurer” means any insurance company which is licensed to do business in the District, but is not domiciled in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Life or health insurer” means any insurance company licensed to underwrite life or health insurance, or a licensed property and casualty insurer writing only accident and health insurance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“NAIC” means the National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Negative trend” means, with respect to a life or health insurer, negative trend over a period of time, as determined in accordance with the “Trend Test Calculation” included in the RBC Instructions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Property and casualty insurer” means any insurance company licensed to underwrite property and casualty insurance, but does not include monoline mortgage guaranty insurers, financial guaranty insurers, and title insurers.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“RBC” means risk-based capital.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“RBC Instructions” means the RBC Report including risk-based capital instructions adopted by the NAIC, as such RBC Instructions may be amended by the NAIC from time to time in accordance with the procedures adopted by the NAIC.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“RBC Level” means an insurer’s Company Action Level RBC, Regulatory Action Level RBC, Authorized Control Level RBC, or Mandatory Control Level RBC where:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>“Company Action Level RBC” means, with respect to any insurer, the product of 2.0 and its Authorized Control Level RBC;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>“Regulatory Action Level RBC” means the product of 1.5 and its Authorized Control Level RBC;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>“Authorized Control Level RBC” means the number determined under the risk-based capital formula in accordance with the RBC Instructions; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>“Mandatory Control Level RBC” means the product of .70 and the Authorized Control Level RBC.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>“RBC Plan” means a comprehensive financial plan containing the elements specified in § <cite path="§31-2003">31-2003</cite>(b). If the Commissioner rejects the RBC Plan, and it is revised by the insurer, with or without the Commissioner’s recommendation, the plan shall be called the “Revised RBC Plan”.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>“RBC Report” means the report required in § <cite path="§31-2002">31-2002</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>“Total adjusted capital” means the sum of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>An insurer’s statutory capital and surplus; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Such other items, if any, as the RBC Instructions may provide.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>“State” means any of the several states, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the U.S. Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-233" type="History" path="§2">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-233, § 2, 44 DCR 765</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 2802, 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-166" type="History">June 11, 2004, D.C. Law 15-166, § 4(l)(1), 51 DCR 2817</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-311.03">31-311.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-4601.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite>, in par. (1), substituted “31-2002(g)” for “31-2002(c)”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-166">D.C. Law 15-166</cite>, in par. (2), substituted “Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking” for “Commissioner of Insurance and Securities”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2602 of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(l)(1) of Consolidation of Financial Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-381, February 27, 2004,  51 DCR 2653).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
