<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-2502.26b</num>
  <heading>Confidentiality of actuarial opinions, summaries, reports, and workpapers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Statement of Actuarial Opinion shall be provided with the annual financial statement required by § <cite path="§31-1901">31-1901</cite>, in accordance with the appropriate National Association of Insurance Commissioners Property and Casualty Annual Statement Instructions and shall be a public document.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An Actuarial Report, underlying workpapers, or Actuarial Opinion Summary in the possession or control of the Commissioner, and any other material provided by the company to the Commissioner in connection with the Actuarial Report, workpapers, or Actuarial Opinion Summary, shall not be subject to subchapter II of Chapter 5 of Title 2, except a subpoena issued pursuant to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A civil action or an administrative proceeding in which insurance premium rates are an issue; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Oversight by the Council or the federal government.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This section shall not limit the Commissioner’s authority to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Release the documents to the Actuarial Board for Counseling and Discipline if the material is required for the purpose of professional disciplinary proceedings and the Actuarial Board for Counseling and Discipline establishes procedures satisfactory to the Commissioner for preserving the confidentiality of the documents; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Use the documents, materials, or other information in furtherance of any regulatory or legal action brought as part of the Commissioner’s official duties.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner or any person who received documents, materials, or other information while acting under the authority of the Commissioner shall not be permitted or required to testify in any private civil action concerning any confidential documents, materials, or information subject to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>To assist in the performance of the Commissioner’s duties, the Commissioner may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Share documents, materials, or other information, including the confidential and privileged documents, materials, or information subject to subsection (b) of this section with other state, federal, and international regulatory agencies, with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and its affiliates and subsidiaries, and with state, federal, and international law enforcement authorities; provided, that the recipient agrees to maintain the confidentiality and privileged status of the document, material, or other information and has the authority to maintain confidentiality;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Receive documents, materials, or information, including otherwise confidential and privileged documents, materials, or information, from the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and its affiliates and subsidiaries, and from regulatory and law enforcement officials of other foreign or domestic jurisdictions, and shall maintain as confidential or privileged any document, material, or information received with notice or the understanding that it is confidential or privileged under the laws of the jurisdiction that is the source of the document, material, or information; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Enter into agreements governing sharing and use of information consistent with subsections (b) through (d) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>No waiver of any applicable privilege or claim of confidentiality in the documents, materials, or information shall occur as a result of disclosure to the Commissioner under this section or as a result of sharing as authorized in subsection (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Oct. 9, 1940, 54 Stat. 1076, ch. 792, ch. II, § 26b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-289" type="History">as added Mar. 20, 2009, D.C. Law 17-289, § 2, 55 DCR 12619</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-3931.13">31-3931.13</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
