<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-2205</num>
  <heading>Reporting requirements for U.S. Branches of non-U.S. insurers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to other requirements of this chapter, every authorized U.S. Branch shall, not later than the first day of March in each year and 45 days after the end of each of the first 3 calendar-year quarters, file the following with the Commissioner and with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (“NAIC”):</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Annual and quarterly statements of the business transacted within the United States and the assets held by or for it within the United States for the protection of policy holders and creditors within the United States, and of the liabilities incurred against such assets. The forms shall not contain any statement in regard to its assets and business elsewhere. The statements shall be in the same format required of an insurer domiciled in the United States Branch’s state of entry state and licensed to write the same kinds of insurance; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statement of trusteed surplus, in such form as the Commissioner may prescribe, as of the end of the same period covered by the statement filed pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection. The aggregate value of the insurer’s general state deposits and trusteed assets deposited with a trustee in compliance with § <cite path="§31-2204">31-2204</cite>, plus accrued investment income thereon where such interest is collected by the states for trustees, less the aggregate net amount of all of its reserves and other liabilities in the United States as determined in accordance with this section, shall be known as its trusteed surplus in the United States. In determining the net amount of the U.S. Branch’s liabilities in the United States to be reported in the statement of trusteed surplus, the U.S. Branch shall make adjustments to total liabilities reported on the accompanying annual or quarterly statements as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Add back liabilities used to offset admitted assets reported in the accompanying quarterly or annual statement; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Deduct:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Unearned premiums on agent’s balances or uncollected premiums not more than 90 days past due;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Reinsurance on losses with authorized insurers, less unpaid reinsurance premiums;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Reinsurance recoverable on paid losses from unauthorized insurers that are included as an asset in the annual statement, but only to the extent a liability for such unauthorized recoverables is included in the liabilities report in the trusteed surplus statement;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Special state deposits held for the exclusive benefit of policyholders, or policyholders and creditors, of any particular state not exceeding net liabilities reports for that state;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Secured accrued retrospective premiums;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>If a life insurer, the amount of its policy loans to policyholders within the United States, not exceeding the amount of legal reserve required on each such policy, and the net amount of uncollected and deferred premiums; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>Any other nontrusteed asset which the Commissioner determines secures liabilities in a substantially similar manner; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any additional information that the Commissioner may require relating to the total business or assets, or any portion thereof, of the non-U.S. insurer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The annual statement and trusteed surplus statement shall be signed and verified by the United States manager, attorney-in-fact, or a duly empowered assistant United States manager of the U.S. Branch. The items of securities and other property held under trust deeds shall be certified in the trusteed surplus statement by the United States trustee or trustees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Every report on examination of a U.S. Branch shall include a trusteed surplus statement as of the date of examination in addition to the general statement of the financial condition of the U.S. Branch.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-128" type="History">May 24, 1996, D.C. Law 11-128, § 6, 43 DCR 1562</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 45(d), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-4405.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
