<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-2502.12</num>
  <heading>Limitations on exposure to risks or hazards.</heading>
  <text>No company other than a mutual or reciprocal company doing business in the District shall expose itself to any loss on any one risk or hazard, whether located in the District or outside of the District, to an amount exceeding 10% of the sum of its capital stock and surplus. No mutual or reciprocal company shall expose itself to any loss on any one risk or hazard, whether located in the District or outside of the District, to an amount exceeding 10% of its surplus. No portion of any such risk or hazard which shall have been reinsured in a company authorized to do business in the District shall be included in determining limitation of risk; provided, that the provisions of this section shall not apply to the insurance of workmen’s compensation, employers’ liability, marine, or inland marine risks.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 76-3-ch792" path="§12">Oct. 9, 1940, 54 Stat. 1070, ch. 792, ch. II, § 12</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-103" type="History">Apr. 26, 1994, D.C. Law 10-103, § 3, 41 DCR 1005</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-232" type="History">Mar. 8, 2007, D.C. Law 16-232, § 202(b), 54 DCR 368</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Capital and surplus requirements for foreign and alien companies, see § <cite path="§31-2502.22">31-2502.22</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Limitation of risk for companies operating on Lloyd’s plan, see § <cite path="§31-2502.20a">31-2502.20a</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-2502.02">31-2502.02</cite> and § <cite path="§31-3931.06">31-3931.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-1515.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-1315.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-232">D.C. Law 16-232</cite> substituted “any one risk or hazard, whether located in the District or outside of the District” for “any 1 risk or hazard in the District”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Insurance Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 1993 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-76">D.C. Law 10-76</cite>, March 17, 1994, law notification  41 DCR 1626).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Department of Insurance abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§31-2501.03">31-2501.03</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
