<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-2995.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Group health plan” means an employee welfare plan (as defined in section 3(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved September 2, 1974 (88 Stat. 829; 29 U.S.C. § 1002(1)), to the extent that the plan provides medical care and includes items and services paid for as medical care to employees or their dependents (as defined under the terms of the plan) directly or through insurance, reimbursement, or otherwise.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Health insurance coverage” means benefits consisting of medical care (provided directly, through insurance or reimbursement, or otherwise and includes items and services paid for as medical care) under any hospital or medical service policy or certificate, hospital, or medical service plan contract, or health maintenance organization contract offered by a health insurer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Health insurer” means any person that provides one or more health benefit plans or insurance in the District, including an insurer, a hospital and medical services corporation, a fraternal benefit society, a health maintenance organization, a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or any other person providing a plan of health insurance subject to the authority of the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Individual health plan” means a plan offering health insurance coverage offered to individuals other than in connection with a group health plan.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-98" type="History">Dec. 17, 2009, D.C. Law 18-98, § 2, 56 DCR 8530</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
