<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-2231.24</num>
  <heading>Judicial review.</heading>
  <text>If, after any hearing under § <cite path="§31-2231.23">31-2231.23</cite>, the Commissioner does not find a violation of this chapter, an aggrieved person may, within 60 days after the decision has been issued, or later in connection with § <cite path="§31-2231.11">31-2231.11</cite>(a), (b), or (b-1) upon a showing of good cause by a victim of an intrafamily offense, sexual assault, dating violence, or stalking, appeal the decision of the Commissioner to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals. In addition, any person subject to an order of the Commissioner under § <cite path="§31-2231.22">31-2231.22</cite> may obtain a review of the order by filing in the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, within 60 days after the order has been issued, a written petition requesting that the order of the Commissioner be set aside. Except as provided above for the time for filing an appeal, appeals shall be made in accordance with § <cite path="§2-510">2-510</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-265" type="History" path="§124">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-265, § 124, 48 DCR 1225</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-360" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-360, § 202(b), 58 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-360">D.C. Law 18-360</law-cite> substituted “issued, or later in connection with § <cite path="§31-2231.11">31-2231.11</cite>(a), (b), or (b-1) upon a showing of good cause by a victim of an intrafamily offense, sexual assault, dating violence, or stalking, appeal” for “issued, appeal”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 203 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-360">D.C. Law 18-360</law-cite> provided: “Sec. 203. Application. This title shall apply to policies and certificates of insurance that are health benefit plans as defined under section 2(4) of the Health Insurance Coverage for Habilitative Services for Children Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-198">D.C. Law 16-198</law-cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§31-3271">31-3271</cite>(4)), that are issued 90 days after the effective date of this title. This title shall not apply to short-term limited duration health benefit plans.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
