<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-2902</num>
  <heading>Payable benefits.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any individual or group health benefit plan, including Medicaid, shall provide health insurance benefits to cover:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A baseline mammogram for women; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An annual screening mammogram for women.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any individual or group health benefit plan, including Medicaid, shall provide health insurance benefits to cover:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Annual cervical cytologic screening for women; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Cervical cytologic screening for women upon certification by an attending physician that the test is medically necessary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Benefits provided in accordance with this section shall not be subject to an annual or coinsurance deductible.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Benefits provided in accordance with this section shall not be subject to a co-payment except when an enrollee or subscriber elects to have a baseline mammogram, annual screening mammogram, annual cervical cytologic screening, and a cervical cytologic screening certified by an attending physician as being necessary, performed by an out-of-network provider in a preferred provider plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Co-payments and coinsurance may be applicable to the enrollee’s or subscriber’s office visit.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Subsections (d) and (e) of this section shall apply:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To any insurance policy or subscriber contract delivered or issued for delivery in the District more than 120 days after April 5, 2005; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To any insurance policy or subscriber contract renewed, amended, or reissued 120 days after April 5, 2005.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-225" type="History">Mar. 7, 1991, D.C. Law 8-225, § 3, 38 DCR 217</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-312" type="History">June 18, 2003, D.C. Law 14-312, § 401(b), 50 DCR 306</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-291" type="History">Apr. 5, 2005, D.C. Law 15-291, § 2, 52 DCR 1457</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91" type="History">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, § 106, 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-2402.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-312">D.C. Law 14-312</cite>, in subsecs. (a) and (b), substituted “health benefit plan” for “health insurance policy or service”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-291">D.C. Law 15-291</cite> added subsecs. (d), (e), and (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-91">D.C. Law 16-91</cite> made a technical correction that resulted in no change in text.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
