<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-3931.15</num>
  <heading>Revocation, suspension, or fine.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may revoke or suspend the certificate of authority to transact insurance business in the District of a captive insurer, including, if applicable, a protected cell, which:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has failed or refused to comply with any provision or requirement of this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is impaired in capital or surplus;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Is insolvent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Is determined, pursuant to Chapter 21 of this title, to be in such condition that further transaction of business by the company will be hazardous to its policyholders, creditors, or the general public;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Has failed or refused to submit any report or statement required by law or order of the Commissioner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Has failed or refused to comply with any provision of its charter or bylaws;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6A)</num>
      <text>Has violated Chapter 22A of this title [§  31-2231.01 et seq.]; provided, that this paragraph shall apply only to District-domiciled risk retention groups licensed as captive insurers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Has used any method in transacting insurance business pursuant to this chapter which would be detrimental to the operation of the captive insurer or would make its condition unsound with respect to its policyholders or the general public; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Has failed otherwise to comply with the laws of the District or any jurisdiction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may also impose a fine not to exceed $5,000 for each violation by a captive insurer, including, if applicable, a protected cell, of any of the provisions found in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-262" type="History" path="§16">Mar. 17, 2005, D.C. Law 15-262, § 16, 52 DCR 1205</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-203" type="History">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-203, § 2(j), 61 DCR 12572</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-3932.03">31-3932.03</cite> and § <cite path="§31-3932.14">31-3932.14</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-203">D.C. Law 20-203</cite> added “including, if applicable, a protected cell” in the introductory language of (a) and (b); and added (a)(6A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 16 of Captive Insurance Company Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-640, November 30, 2004,  52 DCR 1238).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
