<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-3451.09</num>
  <heading>Foreign health organizations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A foreign health organization shall, upon the written request of the Commissioner, submit to the Commissioner an RBC report as of the end of the previous calendar year upon the later of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The date that an RBC report would be required to be filed by a domestic health organization under this chapter; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Fifteen days after the request is received by the foreign health organization.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A foreign health organization shall, at the written request of the Commissioner, promptly submit to the Commissioner a copy of any RBC plan that is filed with the insurance commissioner of any other state.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If (1) a Company Action Level Event, Regulatory Action Level Event, or Authorized Control Level Event occurs with respect to a foreign health organization as determined under the RBC statute applicable in the state of domicile of the health organization (or, if no RBC statute is in force in that state, under the provisions of this chapter), and (2) the Insurance Commissioner of the state of domicile of the foreign health organization fails to require the foreign health organization to file an RBC plan in the manner specified under that state’s RBC statute (or, if no RBC statute is in force in that state, under § <cite path="§31-3451.03">31-3451.03</cite>), the Commissioner may require the foreign health organization to file an RBC plan with the Commissioner. In such event, the failure of the foreign health organization to file an RBC plan with the Commissioner shall be reason to order the health organization to cease and desist from writing new insurance business in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If (1) a Mandatory Control Level Event occurs with respect to a foreign health organization, and (2) no domiciliary receiver has been appointed with respect to the foreign health organization under the rehabilitation and liquidation statute applicable in the state of domicile of the foreign health organization, the Commissioner may apply to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia as permitted under Chapter 34 of Title 31 or Chapter 13 of Title 31 with respect to the liquidation of property of foreign health organizations found in the District of Columbia. The occurrence of the Mandatory Control Level Event shall be considered adequate grounds for the application.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-312" type="History">June 18, 2003, D.C. Law 14-312, § 109, 50 DCR 306</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§31-3851.09">31-3851.09</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
