<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-3271</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>“Adverse decision” means a utilization review determination by a private review agent, a carrier, or a health care provider acting on behalf of a carrier that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>A proposed or delivered health care service covered under the member’s contract is or was not medically necessary, appropriate, or efficient;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>May result in noncoverage of the health care service; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Does not include a decision concerning a subscriber’s status as a member.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A determination denying a request for habilitative services or denying payment for habilitative services because a condition or disease is not a congenital or genetic birth defect is an adverse decision.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Congenital or genetic birth defect” means a defect existing at or from birth, including a hereditary defect. The term “congenital or genetic birth defect” includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Autism or an autism spectrum disorder; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Cerebral palsy.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Habilitative services” means services, including occupational therapy, physical therapy, and speech therapy, for the treatment of a child with a congenital or genetic birth defect to enhance the child’s ability to function.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>“Health benefit plan” means any accident and health insurance policy or certificate, hospital and medical services corporation contract, health maintenance organization subscriber contract, plan provided by a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or plan provided by another benefit arrangement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The term “health benefit plan” does not mean accident only, credit, or disability insurance; coverage of Medicare services or federal employee health plans, pursuant to contracts with the United States government; Medicare supplemental or long-term care insurance; dental only or vision only insurance; specified disease insurance; hospital confinement indemnity coverage; limited benefit health coverage; coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance, insurance arising out of a workers’ compensation or similar law; automobile medical payment insurance; medical expense and loss of income benefits; or insurance under which benefits are payable with or without regard to fault and that is statutorily required to be contained in any liability insurance policy or equivalent self-insurance.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Health insurer” means any person that provides one or more health benefit plans or insurance in the District of Columbia, including an insurer, a hospital and medical services corporation, a fraternal benefit society, a health maintenance organization, a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or any other person providing a plan of health insurance subject to the authority of the Commissioner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Managed care system” means a method that a health insurer uses to review and preauthorize a treatment plan that a health care practitioner develops for a covered person using a variety of cost containment methods to control utilization, quality, and claims.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-198" type="History" path="§2">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-198, § 2, 53 DCR 8829</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-3013">31-3013</cite>, § <cite path="§31-3163">31-3163</cite>, and § <cite path="§31-3311.10">31-3311.10</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
