<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-3932.09</num>
  <heading>Dividends and distributions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Dividends may be declared by the management of an SPFC if the dividends do not violate the provisions of this subchapter or jeopardize the fulfillment of the obligations of the SPFC or the trustee pursuant to the SPFC insurance securitization agreements, the SPFC contract, or any related transaction documents and other provisions of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An SPFC shall not declare or pay dividends in any form other than in accordance with the insurance securitization transaction agreements and shall not declare or pay dividends which decrease the capital and surplus of the SPFC below $250,000.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An SPFC or protected cell of an SPFC shall not pay dividends out of, or make any other distribution out of, its capital or surplus, or both, unless the SPFC or protected cell has obtained the prior written approval of the Commissioner to make the payment or distribution. After giving effect to the dividends, the assets of the SPFC, including assets held in trust pursuant to the terms of the insurance securitization, shall be sufficient to satisfy the Commissioner that the SPFC can meet its obligations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may approve an ongoing plan for the payment of dividends or other distributions by an SPFC or protected cell of an SPFC. Approval by the Commissioner of an ongoing plan for the payment of dividends or other distribution shall be conditioned upon the retention, at the time of each payment, of capital and surplus equal to or in excess of amounts specified by, or determined in accordance with formulas approved for the SPFC or protected cell by, the Commissioner.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-262" type="History">Mar. 17, 2005, D.C. Law 15-262, ยง 209</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-285" type="History">as added Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-285, ยง 2(b), 54 DCR 944</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
