<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-3311.06</num>
  <heading>Post-claims underwriting and prior approval for rescission, cancellation, or limitation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An insurer shall not rescind an enrollee’s plan or coverage once the enrollee is covered under the plan or coverage involved; provided, that this section shall not apply to a covered individual who has performed an act or practice that constitutes fraud or makes an intentional misrepresentation of material fact as prohibited by the terms of the plan or coverage. The plan or coverage shall not be cancelled without prior notice to the Commissioner as required by subsection (b) of this section and prior notice to the consumer and an opportunity to appeal as required by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, approved March 23, 2010 (124 Stat. 109; scattered sections of the United States Code).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A health carrier shall provide at least 30 days advance written notice to each plan enrollee, or for individual health insurance coverage, primary subscriber, who would be affected by the proposed rescission of coverage before coverage under the plan may be rescinded in accordance with subsection (a) of this section regardless of, in the case of group or only to an individual within the group. The notice shall explain the reason for the rescission, procedures of appealing, and how to contact the Health Care Ombudsman and the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking for further information.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Prior to rescinding the enrollee’s plan or coverage, the insurer shall provide to the Commissioner documentation to support the rescission and the Commissioner shall have 5 business days following receipt of the proposed rescission and supporting documentation to review the documentation to determine if the insurer is complying with the requirements of subsection (a) of this section. The insurer may rescind the plan or coverage after the end of the 5-day period of review unless the Commissioner objects or disapproves the proposed rescission within the 5-day period.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-360" type="History" path="§107">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-360, § 107, 58 DCR 896</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
