<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-3171.10</num>
  <heading>Conflicts of interest.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A member of the executive board or of the staff of the Authority shall not be employed by, a consultant to, a member of the board of directors of, affiliated with, or otherwise a representative of, a health carrier or other insurer, an agent or broker, a health professional, or a health care facility or health clinic while serving on the board or on the staff of the Authority.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A member of the executive board or of the staff of the Authority shall not be a member, a board member, or an employee of a trade association of health carriers, health facilities, health clinics, or health professionals while serving on the board or on the staff of the Authority.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A member of the executive board or of the staff of the Authority shall not be a health professional unless he or she receives no compensation for rendering services as a health professional and does not have an ownership interest in a professional health care practice.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No member of the executive board or of the staff of the Authority shall, for one year after the end of the member’s service on the board or employment by the Authority, accept employment with any health carrier that offers a qualified health benefit plan through the exchanges.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No member of the executive board shall make, participate in making, or in any way attempt to use his or her official position to influence the making of any decision that he or she knows or has reason to know will have a reasonably foreseeable material financial effect, distinguishable from its effect on the public generally, on him or her or a member of his or her immediate family, or on either of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any source of income, other than gifts and other than loans by a commercial lending institution in the regular course of business on terms available to the public without regard to official status, aggregating $250 or more in value provided to, received by, or promised to the member within 12 months prior to the time when the decision is made.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any business entity in which the member is a director, officer, partner, trustee, or employee, or holds any position of management.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-94" type="History" path="§11">Mar. 2, 2012, D.C. Law 19-94, § 11, 59 DCR 213</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
