<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-3171.09a</num>
  <heading>Distribution of individual and small group health benefit plans.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A carrier that offers individual or small group health benefit plans shall offer such plans solely through the American Health Benefit Exchange, as established pursuant to §  31–3171.04(a), subject to the following transition provisions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Individual health benefit plans with plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2014, shall be offered solely through the American Health Benefit Exchange;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On or after January 1, 2014, small group health benefit plans offered to any small business that was not insured as of December 31, 2013, shall be offered and issued solely through the American Health Benefit Exchange;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Small group health benefit plans offered to or renewed by any small business that was insured as of December 31, 2013, may be issued or renewed during calendar year 2014 through existing distribution channels with the same carrier or a new carrier, except that such plans shall meet the qualifications for certification of a qualified health plan as provided in section 10; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Unless the Council acts by October 1, 2014 to change the date that all small group health plans shall be offered, issued, or renewed through the American Health Benefit Exchange, on or after January 1, 2015, all small group health benefit plans shall be offered and issued or renewed solely through the American Health Benefit Exchange.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The requirements of this section shall not apply to grandfathered health plans as defined in section 1251 of the Federal Act.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-94">Dec. 11, 2012, D.C. Law 19-94, §  10a</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-123">as added July 16, 2014, D.C. Law 20-123, § 2(c), 61 DCR 5379</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 days) addition of this section, see § 2(c) of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-22">D.C. Law 20-22</cite>, October 3, 2013,  60 DCR 10880).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2(c) of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-87, June 19, 2013,  60 DCR 9542, 20 DCSTAT 1446).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see §§ 2(c) and 3 of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-170, September 26, 2013,  60 DCR 14742).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2(c) of the Better Prices, Better Quality, Better Choices for Health Coverage Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-335, May 22, 2014,  61 DCR 5375).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
