<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-3705</num>
  <heading>Disclosure standards.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In order to provide for full and fair disclosure in the sale of Medicare supplement policies, no Medicare supplement policy or certificate shall be delivered in the District of Columbia unless an outline of coverage is delivered to the applicant at the time application is made.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall prescribe the format and content of the outline of coverage required by subsection (c) of this section. For purposes of this section, the term “format” means style, arrangements, and overall appearance, including such items as the size, color, and prominence of type and arrangement of text and captions. The outline of coverage shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A description of the principal benefits and coverage provided in the policy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statement of the renewal provisions, including any reservation by the issuer of a right to change premiums, and disclosure of the existence of any automatic renewal premium increases based on the policyholder’s age; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A statement that the outline of coverage is a summary of the policy issued or applied for and that the policy should be consulted to determine governing contractual provisions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may prescribe by regulation a standard form and the contents of an informational brochure for persons eligible for Medicare, which is intended to improve the buyer’s ability to select the most appropriate coverage and improve the buyer’s understanding of Medicare. Except in the case of the direct response insurance policies, the Mayor may require by regulation that the informational brochure be provided to any prospective insured eligible for Medicare concurrently with delivery of the outline of coverage. With respect to direct response insurance policies, the Mayor may require by regulation that the prescribed brochure be provided upon request to any prospective insured eligible for Medicare, but in no event later than the time of policy delivery.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue regulations for captions or notice requirements, determined to be in the public interest and designed to inform prospective insureds that particular insurance coverages are not Medicare supplement coverages, for all accident and sickness insurance policies sold to persons eligible for Medicare, other than:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Medicare supplement policies; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Disability income policies.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue reasonable regulations to govern the full and fair disclosure of the information in connection with the replacement of accident and sickness policies, subscriber contracts, or certificates by persons eligible for Medicare.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-170" type="History" path="§6">Oct. 1, 1992, D.C. Law 9-170, § 6, 39 DCR 5825</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-202" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-202, §§ 2(d)-(f), 43 DCR 6054</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 35(b), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(d) through (f) of the Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-244, April 11, 1996,  43 DCR 2119), § 2(d) through (f) of the Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-396, October 9, 1996,  43 DCR 5684), § 2(d) through (f) of the Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-416, October 28, 1996,  43 DCR 6078), § 2(d) through (f) of the Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-474, December 30, 1996,  44 DCR 198), and see § 2(d) through (f) of the Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-49, March 31, 1997.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§31-3701">§ 31-3701</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-2615.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
