<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-3251</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Commissioner” means Commissioner of the Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Credentialing intermediary” means a person to whom a health insurer has delegated credentialing or recredentialing authority and responsibility.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Health benefit plan” means any accident and health insurance policy or certificate, hospital and medical services corporation contract, health maintenance organization subscriber contract, plan provided by a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or plan provided by another benefit arrangement. The term “health benefit plan” does not mean accident only, credit, or disability insurance; coverage of Medicare services or federal employee health plans, pursuant to contracts with the United States government; Medicare supplemental or long-term care insurance; dental only or vision only insurance; specified disease insurance; hospital confinement indemnity coverage; limited benefit health coverage; coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance, insurance arising out of a workers’ compensation or similar law; automobile medical payment insurance; medical expense and loss of income benefits; or insurance under which benefits are payable with or without regard to fault and that is statutorily required to be contained in any liability insurance policy or equivalent self-insurance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Health care provider” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>An individual who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized to provide health care services by the District of Columbia for a practice set forth under § <cite path="§3-1201.02">3-1201.02</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>An agency, organization, facility, or distinct part of any of them, licensed under subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 44.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Health insurer” means any person that provides one or more health benefit plans or insurance in the District of Columbia, including an insurer, a hospital and medical services corporation, a fraternal benefit society, a health maintenance organization, a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or any other person providing a plan of health insurance subject to the authority of the Commissioner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Provider panel” means providers that contract with a health insurer to provide health care services to the enrollees under a health benefit plan of the health insurer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Uniform credentialing form” means the form designed by the Commissioner, by regulation, for use by a health insurer or its credentialing intermediary for credentialing and re-credentialing of a health care provider for participation on a provider panel.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-96" type="History">Apr. 13, 2002, D.C. Law 14-96, § 101, 49 DCR 991</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-3255">31-3255</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
