<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-3609</num>
  <heading>Incontestability period.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a policy or certificate has been in force for less than 6 months, an insurer may rescind a long-term care insurance policy or certificate or deny an otherwise valid long-term care insurance claim upon a showing of misrepresentation that is material to the acceptance for coverage.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a policy or certificate has been in force for at least 6 months, but less than 2 years, an insurer may rescind a long-term care insurance policy or certificate or deny an otherwise valid long-term care insurance claim upon a showing of misrepresentation that is both material to the acceptance for coverage and which pertains to the condition for which benefits are sought.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>After a policy or certificate has been in force for 2 years, it shall not be contestable upon the grounds of misrepresentations alone. The policy or certificate may be contested only upon a showing that the insured knowingly and intentionally misrepresented relevant facts relating to the insured’s health.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No long-term care insurance policy or certificate may be field unless based on medical or health status.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For purposes of this subsection, the term “field issued” means a policy or certificate issued by an agent or third party administrator pursuant to the underwriting authority granted to the agent or third party administrator by an insurer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If an insurer has paid benefits under a long-term care insurance policy or certificate, the benefit payments may not be recovered by the insurer in the event that the policy or certificate is rescinded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the event of the death of the insured, this section shall not apply to the remaining death benefits of a life insurance policy that accelerates benefits for long term care; except that, in the event of death of the insured, the remaining death benefits under these policies shall be governed by § <cite path="§31-4803">31-4803</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-121" type="History" path="§10">May 23, 2000, D.C. Law 13-121, § 10, 47 DCR 2038</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Long-Term Care Insurance Temporary Amendment Act of 2000 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-147">D.C. Law 13-147</law-cite>, July 18, 2000, law notification  47 DCR 6097).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of § 35-4909.1 1981 Ed., see § 2(c) of the Long-Term Care Insurance Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-312, April 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2738).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of § 35-4909.1 1981 Ed., see § 2(c) of the Long-Term Care Insurance Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-370, July 10, 2000,  47 DCR 5838).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§31-3609.01">31-3609.01</cite>, see § 502(c) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
