<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-3404</num>
  <heading>Powers of health maintenance organizations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The powers of a health maintenance organization include, but are not limited to, the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The purchase, lease, construction, renovation, operation, or maintenance of hospitals, medical facilities, or both, and their ancillary equipment, and such property and equipment as may reasonably be required for its principal office or for such purposes as may be necessary in the transaction of the business of the organization;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Transactions between affiliated entities, including loans and the transfer of responsibility under all contracts (provider, enrollee, etc.) between affiliates or between the health maintenance organization and its parent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The furnishing of health care services through providers, provider associations, or agents for providers which are under contract with or employed by the health maintenance organization;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The contracting with any person for the performance on its behalf of certain functions, such as marketing, enrollment, and administration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The contracting with an insurance company, including Group Hospitalization and Medical Service, Inc., licensed in the District for the provision of insurance, indemnity, or reimbursement against the cost of covered services provided by the health maintenance organization or with optometry services, podiatry services, dental services, pharmaceutical service plans, and other entities authorized to do business in the District for the provision of supplemental health services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The joint marketing of products with an insurance company authorized to do business in the District as long as the company that is offering each product is clearly identified; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Entering into administrative service provider contracts with contracting providers whereby covered services are rendered to enrollees by external providers who have entered into contracts with the contracting provider.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A health maintenance organization shall file notice, with adequate supporting information, with the Commissioner prior to the exercise of any power granted in subsection (a)(1), (2), or (4) of this section which may affect the financial soundness of the health maintenance organization. The Commissioner shall disapprove such exercise of power only if the Commissioner determines it would substantially and adversely affect the financial soundness of the health maintenance organization and endanger its ability to meet its obligations. If the Commissioner does not disapprove within 30 days of the filing of the notice, the exercise of power shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may issue rules and regulations exempting those activities having a de minimis effect from the filing requirement of this subsection.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-235">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-235, § 5, 44 DCR 818</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 46(b), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="31-3411">31-3411</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 35-4504.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
