<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-3311.03a</num>
  <heading>Essential health benefits.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Consistent with federal law, the Commissioner, with the approval of the Executive Board of the Health Benefit Exchange Authority, shall, by rule, select the benchmark plan for the individual and small group market for purposes of establishing the essential health benefits in the District pursuant to section 1302 of the Affordable Care Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the essential health benefits benchmark plan for the individual and small group market does not include all of the benefit categories specified by section 1302 of the Affordable Care Act, or a need exists to add additional benefits, the Commissioner, with the approval of the Executive Board of the Health Benefit Exchange Authority, may, by rule, supplement the benchmark plan benefits as needed so long as the benchmark plan meets the minimum requirements of section 1302 of the Affordable Care Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A health plan offering the required essential health benefits for the individual and small group markets, other than a health plan offered through the federal basic health program or Medicaid, may not be offered in the District unless the Commissioner determines that it is substantially equal to the benchmark plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When making this determination, the Commissioner shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Ensure that the plan covers the essential health benefits categories specified in section 1302 of the Affordable Care Act; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Consider whether the health plan has a benefit design that would create a risk of biased selection based on health status and whether the health plan contains meaningful scope and level of benefits in each of the 10 essential health benefit categories specified by section 1302 of Affordable Care Act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, notwithstanding any other provision of benefits mandated by District law, the benchmark plan adopted by the Commissioner shall be the benefits required in all health benefit plans offered in the individual and small group markets.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Grandfathered health plans, as defined in section 1251 of the Affordable Care Act, shall be exempt from complying with the requirements of the benchmark plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-360" type="History" path="ยง104a">April 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-360, ยง 104a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-265" type="History">as added May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-265, ยง 104(b), 62 DCR 1529</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
