<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-4332</num>
  <heading>Appeals from Commissioner to Mayor.</heading>
  <text>Any appeals to the Mayor from rulings of the Commissioner shall be perfected and filed with the Mayor within 20 days exclusive of Sundays and legal holidays from the date such rulings are communicated to the party at interest.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 19, 1934, 48 Stat. 1142, ch. 672, ch. II, § 33</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(i), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Examiner orders following mayor’s consideration of findings, appeals, see § <cite path="§31-1404">31-1404</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Managing general agent license suspension or revocation, appeal from mayor, see § <cite path="§31-1506">31-1506</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-1404">31-1404</cite> and § <cite path="§31-1506">31-1506</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-432.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-432.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Department of Insurance abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§31-4301">31-4301</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
