<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-4443</num>
  <heading>Effect of merger or consolidation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When a merger or consolidation has been completed, the merging or consolidating companies shall be a single company.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a merger, the single company shall be the 1 designated in the plan as the surviving company and, for a consolidation, shall be the new company described in the plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The separate existence of the merging or consolidating companies shall cease.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The surviving or new company shall have the rights, the privileges, the immunities, and the powers and shall be subject to the duties and liabilities of a life company organized under this subdivision.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The surviving or the new company shall have the rights, the privileges, the immunities, and the franchises of each of the merging or consolidating companies.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All property interests, debts, claims, or other interests belonging to the merging or the consolidating companies shall be transferred automatically to the single company.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Realty interests vested in the merging or the consolidating companies shall not revert or be impaired because of the merger or the consolidation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The surviving or the new company shall be responsible for obligations of the merging or the consolidating companies.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A claim involving 1 of the merging or consolidating companies may be litigated as though the merger or the consolidation had not taken place or with the single company replacing the merging or the consolidating company.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Neither the rights of creditors nor any liens upon the property of a merging or consolidating company shall be impaired by the merger or the consolidation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For a merger, the articles of incorporation of the surviving company shall be considered amended to the extent that the articles of merger described changes in the articles of incorporation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a consolidation, articles of consolidation provisions required or permitted in the articles of incorporation of life companies shall be considered the articles of incorporation of the new company.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The aggregate amount of the net assets of the merging or the consolidating companies available for the payment of dividends immediately before the merger or the consolidation, to the extent that the amount cannot be transferred to stated capital, shall continue to be available for the payment of dividends by the surviving or the new company.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 73-2-ch672" path="§42">June 19, 1934, ch. 672, ch. III, § 42</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-160" type="History">as added Mar. 14, 1985, D.C. Law 5-160, § 3(c), 32 DCR 39</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Fraternal benefit societies, consolidations and mergers, see § <cite path="§31-5311">31-5311</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Hospital and medical services corporations, applicability of this section, see § <cite path="§31-3503">31-3503</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-3503">31-3503</cite> and § <cite path="§31-5311">31-5311</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-640.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
