<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-4303</num>
  <heading>Disposition of excess in fees, charges, or taxes.</heading>
  <text>Whenever it appears to the satisfaction of the Commissioner that, because of some error, mistake, or erroneous interpretation of a statute, a company has paid fees, charges, or taxes in excess of the amount legally chargeable against it, the Commissioner shall, on application of the company, present the matter to the Mayor, with the view of refunding to such company any such excess, or applying the excess or portion thereof toward the payment of fees, charges, or taxes already due from such company.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 73-2-ch672" path="§4">June 19, 1934, 48 Stat. 1131, ch. 672, ch. II, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(i), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Department of Insurance abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§31-4301">31-4301</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-403.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-403.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-3503">31-3503</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Tax refunds, see §§ <cite path="§47-1317">47-1317</cite>, <cite path="§47-1318">47-1318</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Hospital and medical services corporations, applicability of this section, see § <cite path="§31-3503">31-3503</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
