<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-4315</num>
  <heading>Deposit of securities by companies desiring to transact business — Amount; deposits outside District.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Every company desiring to transact business in the District shall, as a prerequisite to the issuance of a certificate of authority, deposit, as herein provided, approved securities of not less than $100,000 market value. In the case of domestic companies, such deposit shall be made in the District as prescribed under § <cite path="§31-4316">31-4316</cite>; provided, that the deposit of every domestic company heretofore organized under the provisions of the laws of the District or other act of Congress may, in the discretion of the Commissioner, be limited: (1) For stock companies, to an amount equal to the capital stock outstanding on June 19, 1934; and (2) for nonstock companies, to such amount as in the opinion of the Commissioner would be required from stock companies of comparable size. In no case shall the deposit of a domestic company be less than $25,000 in value. In the case of foreign or alien companies, the deposit may be made as provided under § <cite path="§31-4316">31-4316</cite>, or may be made with the supervising official of any state, territory, or insular possession of the United States authorized to accept such deposit, which shall be held for the benefit of all policyholders.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In the case of a deposit made with an official outside the District, a certificate of deposit from said official shall be filed with the Commissioner, showing the character of the deposit, before a certificate of authority to transact business in the District may be issued, and, if the securities so deposited are not of the class authorized by this subdivision for investments of companies, the Commissioner may require an additional deposit in approved securities.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 19, 1934, 48 Stat. 1133, ch. 672, ch. II, § 16</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 20, 1940, 54 Stat. 217, ch. 204</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(i), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 24, 1998</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">D.C. Law 12-81, § 22(b), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Reserves, see § <cite path="§31-5201">31-5201</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-415.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-415.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Department of Insurance abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§31-4301">31-4301</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
