<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-4402</num>
  <heading>Formation — Filing, notice and bond requirements.</heading>
  <text>The incorporators shall file such articles with the Commissioner and shall publish in a newspaper of general circulation in the District notice of the filing of such articles and of the intention to form such company. Copy of such notice verified by the oath of the publisher of the newspaper, or his agent, copies of proposed bylaws and forms of subscription for capital stock and of proposed applications for membership and for insurance and of all proposed forms of insurance policies, literature, and advertisements shall be filed with the Commissioner. The incorporators shall also file with the Commissioner a bond payable to the Commissioner and his successors, as trustee, in the sum of $10,000 with approved corporate sureties, and conditioned upon the faithful accounting to the proposed company, on completion of its organization and the receipt of its certificate of authority from the Commissioner, or the stockholders, members, applicants for policies, and creditors, or the trustee, receiver, or assignee of the proposed company, duly appointed in any proceedings in any court or department of competent jurisdiction in the District, in accordance with their respective rights in case the organization of the proposed company shall not be completed and a certificate of authority shall not be procured from the Commissioner.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>June 19, 1934, 48 Stat. 1144, ch. 672, ch. III, § 2</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(k), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 35-602.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 35-502.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Department of Insurance abolished: The Department of Insurance, including the Superintendent, was abolished and the functions thereof transferred to the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia by Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1952. Reorganization Order No. 43, dated June 23, 1953, as amended, established, under the direction and control of a Commissioner, a Department of Insurance headed by a Superintendent. The Order provided for the organization of the Department, abolished the previously existing Department of Insurance, and provided that all functions and positions of the previous Department would be transferred to the new Department of Insurance, including the duties, powers, and authorities of all officers and employees; and that all personnel, property, records and unexpended balances relating to the functions and positions transferred would also be transferred to the new Department. The executive functions of the Board of Commissioners were transferred to the Commissioner of the District of Columbia by § 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967. The functions of the Superintendent of Insurance were transferred to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs by Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1983, effective March 31, 1983. Pursuant to the provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-268">D.C. Law 11-268</cite>, the Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation was established and the duties of the Superintendent of Insurance and the Insurance Administration were assumed by the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities, and the Insurance Administration in the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs was abolished.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
