<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-4316</num>
  <heading>Deposit of securities by companies desiring to transact business — Type of securities allowed; officials responsible for safekeeping; collection of income; substitution; decline in value.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When any company is required by this subdivision to make a deposit in the District, such deposit shall be in securities of the class authorized by this subdivision for investments of companies, and shall be delivered by the company to the Executive Secretary of the District and the Auditor of the District, who shall receive and hold the same subject to the lawful orders of the Commissioner, and who shall be responsible for the safekeeping of all securities deposited or delivered under the authority of this section. The company shall have the right to collect the income on deposited securities so long as it continues solvent and complies with the laws of the United States and of the District, and it shall have the right to substitute for such securities other securities, provided such substituted securities are of the character, amount, and value required by this section, and are approved by the Commissioner; provided, that not less than $25,000 of such deposit shall at all times consist of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness of the United States or of any state of the United States, or of any county or incorporated city of any state of the United States, and that securities of a class different from such bonds or other evidences of indebtedness shall not in any case be accepted for deposit except with the specific approval of and at values determined by the Commissioner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the value of securities deposited by any company shall decline, the Commissioner may require the company to make a further deposit, in order that the amount and value of the deposit required by this subdivision shall at all times be maintained.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 73-2-ch672" path="§17">June 19, 1934, 48 Stat. 1134, ch. 672, ch. II, § 17</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 20, 1940, 54 Stat. 217, ch. 204</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(i), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">Reorganization Order No. 23, dated December 30, 1952, transferred the functions relating to the delivery of securities required to be deposited by insurance companies transacting business in the District of Columbia from the Secretary of the Board of Commissioners and the Auditor of the District to the Internal Audit Officer or his deputy and the Disbursing Officer or his deputy, Department of General Administration. The Disbursing Office was established in the Finance Office of the Department of General Administration by Reorganization Order No. 20, dated November 10, 1952. Reorganization Order No. 20 was superseded by Organization Order No. 121, dated December 12, 1957, which placed disbursing functions in the Treasury Division of the Office of the Finance Officer. Organization Order No. 121 was revoked by Organization Order No. 3, dated December 23, 1967, under Part IVC of which disbursing functions were continued in the Treasury Division of the Finance Office. These functions were subsequently transferred to the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue by Commissioner’s Order No. 69-96, dated March 7, 1969.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-416.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-416.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§31-4315">§ 31-4315</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Reserves, see <cite path="§31-5201">§ 31-5201</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Department of Insurance abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§31-4301">§ 31-4301</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Office of Auditor abolished: The Office of the Auditor of the District of Columbia was abolished and the functions thereof transferred to the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia by Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1952. All functions of the Office of the Auditor including the functions of all officers, employees, and subordinate agencies were transferred to the Director, Department of General Administration by Reorganization Order No. 3 of the Board of Commissioners, dated August 28, 1952. Reorganization Order No. 19, dated November 10, 1952, established in the Department of General Administration an Internal Audit Office headed by an Internal Office Auditor. The executive functions of the Board of Commissioners were transferred to the Commissioner of the District of Columbia by § 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967. Reorganization Orders No. 3 and 19 were revoked by Organization Order No. 3 of the Commissioner of the District of Columbia, dated December 13, 1967. Parts III and IVB of the latter Order established, within the newly created Department of General Administration, an Internal Audit Office headed by an Internal Audit Officer and prescribed the functions thereof. These functions were subsequently transferred to the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue by paragraph 4 of Commissioner’s Order No. 69-96, dated March 7, 1969. Part IVB of Organization Order No. 3 and that portion of paragraph 4 of Commissioner’s Order No. 69-96 pertaining to a transfer of audit functions to the Department of Finance and Revenue, were revoked by Organization Order No. 33, dated July 14, 1972. The latter Order established an Office of Municipal Audit and Inspection and prescribed the functions thereof. Organization Order No. 50, dated December 31, 1974, established the Office of Budget and Management Systems, and transferred to that Office the functions of the Office of Municipal Audit and Inspection. The Office of Budget and Management Systems was replaced by Mayor’s Order 79-5, dated January 2, 1979, which Order established the Office of Budget and Revenue Development.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Office of Secretary to Board of Commissioners abolished: The Office of the Secretary to the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia was abolished and the functions thereof transferred to the Board of Commissioners by Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1952. Reorganization Order No. 41 of the Board of Commissioners, dated June 23, 1953, issued pursuant to that Plan, established as part of the Executive Office of the Board of Commissioners, under the direction and control of the Board, an Office of the Secretary to the Board of Commissioners to perform ministerial duties for the Board. The Order described the purpose and functions of the Office of Secretary, and provided that the functions and positions of the previously existing Office of the Secretary to the Board be transferred to the new Office, and that the previously existing Office of the Secretary be abolished. The executive functions of the Board of Commissioners were transferred to the Commissioner of the District of Columbia by § 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967. Organization Order No. 2 of the Commissioner, dated December 13, 1967, as amended, established within the Executive Office of the Commissioner a Secretariat headed by an Executive Secretary. The Order transferred to the Secretariat certain functions, including the duties, powers, and authorities of all officers and employees performing such functions and assigned to the Office of the Secretary as it existed immediately prior to December 13, 1967, and revoked all other orders inconsistent therewith.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
