<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-4724</num>
  <heading>Access to psychologists or optometrists under group health insurance policy.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No policy of group health insurance shall be delivered or issued in the District of Columbia or be issued or amended to cover any resident of the District of Columbia if it contains a provision which would restrict access to psychologists or optometrists. When a policy relating to group health insurance requires payment or reimbursement for services which may be performed by a duly licensed psychologist or optometrist, any person covered by the policy shall be free to select and have direct access to such psychologist or optometrist without supervision or referral by a practitioner of the healing art and shall be entitled under the policy to have payment or reimbursement made for services performed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No policy of group health insurance shall be delivered or issued in the District or be issued or amended to cover any resident of the District if it does not contain a provision which:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For a policy issued or renewed after April 15, 1995, covers a minor grandchild, niece, or nephew of an employee of the District of Columbia if the minor grandchild, niece, or nephew is under the primary care of the insured, and if the legal guardian of the minor grandchild, niece, or nephew, if other than the insured, is not covered by an accident or sickness policy. For the purposes of this paragraph, the term “primary care” means that the insured provides food, clothing, and shelter, on a regular and continuous basis, for the minor grandchild, niece, or nephew during the time that the District of Columbia public schools are in regular session; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a policy issued or renewed after April 15, 1996, covers a minor grandchild, niece, or nephew under the primary care of the insured, and if the legal guardian of the minor grandchild, niece, or nephew, if other than the insured, is not covered by an accident or sickness policy. For the purposes of this paragraph, the term “primary care” means that the insured provides food, clothing, and shelter, on a regular and continuous basis, for the minor grandchild, niece or nephew during the time that the District of Columbia public schools are in regular session.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 19, 1934, 48 Stat. 1156, ch. 672, ch. V, § 24</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-66" type="History">as added Feb. 11, 1982, D.C. Law 4-66,§ 2(b), 28 DCR 5040</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-158" type="History">Aug. 25, 1994, D.C. Law 10-158, § 3, 41 DCR 4881</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Hospital and medical services corporations, applicability of this section, see § <cite path="§31-3503">31-3503</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-3503">31-3503</cite> and § <cite path="§31-4712">31-4712</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-530.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
