<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-4001</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Insurer” means any individual, partnership, corporation, company, organization, professional association, or other business entity that issues, amends, or renews motor vehicle liability or homeowner’s liability insurance policies or contracts in the District of Columbia (“District”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Child development home” means a child development program provided in a private residence for up to a total of 5 children and infants, with no more than 2 infants in the group. The total of 5 children and infants shall not include the children of the child development home caregiver who are 6 years of age or older if the total number of children of the child development home caregiver between the ages of 6 and 15 years of age does not exceed 3 children, and of those 3 children, no more than 2 are 10 years old or younger.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Child development program” means a program responsive to the stages of physical, emotional, social, and intellectual growth and behavior of infants or children.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Caregiver” means a person whose duties include direct care, supervision, and guidance of infants or children in a child development home.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Infant” means an individual between the ages of birth and 2 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Child” means an individual between the ages of 2 and 15 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Person” means any individual, firm, partnership, company, corporation, trustee, or association.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-140" type="History" path="§2">June 13, 1990, D.C. Law 8-140, § 2, 37 DCR 2651</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(x), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-166" type="History">June 11, 2004, D.C. Law 15-166, § 4(y), 51 DCR 2817</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-2501.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-166">D.C. Law 15-166</law-cite>, in par. (7), substituted “Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking” for “Commissioner of Insurance and Securities”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(y) of Consolidation of Financial Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-381, February 27, 2004,  51 DCR 2653).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
