<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-5234</num>
  <heading>Aggregate limitations on Premium Tax Credits; Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The aggregate amount of Premium Tax Credits that shall be allowed for all Certified Investors under this chapter shall not exceed $50 million. No Certified Capital Company, on an aggregate basis with its Affiliates, shall file Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests in excess of the maximum amount of Premium Tax Credits which may be allowed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A Premium Tax Credit Allocation Request shall be made by a Certified Investor on a form provided by the Commissioner and filed with the Commissioner by a Certified Capital Company on behalf of the Certified Investor. The form shall include the affidavit of the Certified Investor pursuant to which the Certified Investor shall irrevocably commit to invest Certified Capital in the Certified Capital Company in the amount of the Premium Tax Credit allocated to it (even if the amount is less than the amount of the Premium Tax Credit Allocation Request). The maximum amount of Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests which shall be allowed to be filed by any one Certified Investor, on an aggregate basis with its Affiliates, in one or more Certified Capital Companies, shall not exceed the greater of $10 million or 15% of the aggregate limitation as provided in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Premium Tax Credits shall be allocated to Certified Investors in Certified Capital Companies in the order that Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests are filed with the Commissioner by the Certified Capital Companies on their behalf. The Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests may be filed on or after March 10, 2004, and the filings made before such date shall be considered to have been received by the Commissioner on such date. All filings made on the same day shall be treated as having been made contemporaneously. The deadline for submitting Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests shall be the first business day which occurs 90 days after the date on which the Commissioner will begin accepting applications for certification as a Certified Capital Company pursuant to § <cite path="§31-5232">31-5232</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If 2 or more Certified Capital Companies file Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests with the Commissioner on behalf of their respective Certified Investors on the same day, and the amount of the Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests exceeds in the aggregate the limit of available Premium Tax Credits under subsection (a) of this section, Premium Tax Credits shall be allocated among the Certified Investors on a pro rata basis. The pro rata allocation for any one Certified Investor shall be the product of a fraction, the numerator of which is the amount in the Premium Tax Credit Allocation Request filed on behalf of the Certified Investor and the denominator of which is the total of the amounts in all Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests filed on behalf of all Certified Investors, multiplied by the aggregate limitation as provided in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No allocation shall be made to the Certified Investors of a Certified Capital Company unless the Certified Capital Company has filed Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests that are not less than 15% of the Premium Tax Credits available under subsection (a) of this section; provided, that if the allocation process does not result in all Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests having been filled, the 15% minimum shall be reduced to 10% and then 5% until the aggregate of Premium Tax Credits provided in subsection (a) of this section have been allocated or all Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests have been filled.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Within 5 business days after the Commissioner receives a Premium Tax Credit Allocation Request filed by a Certified Capital Company, the Commissioner shall notify the Certified Capital Company of the amount of Premium Tax Credits allocated to each of the Certified Investors in the Certified Capital Company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>At the time of receipt of Certified Capital from Certified Investors, the total cash, cash equivalents, or other assets readily available to the Certified Capital Company to make Certified Investments after deducting the costs and expenses of forming and syndicating the Certified Capital Company shall be an amount equal to or greater than 50% of the total Premium Tax Credit allocated to the Certified Investors under subsection (e) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If a Certified Capital Company does not receive from a Certified Investor an investment of Certified Capital equaling or exceeding the amount of Premium Tax Credits allocated to the Certified Investor within 5 business days of the Certified Capital Company’s receipt of notice of the allocation, the Premium Tax Credits allocated to the Certified Investor shall be forfeited, and the Commissioner, within 5 business days, shall reallocate the Premium Tax Credits among the other Certified Investors in all Certified Capital Companies on a pro rata basis with respect to the Premium Tax Credit Allocation Requests filed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-87" type="History">Mar. 10, 2004, D.C. Law 15-87, § 5, 50 DCR 10982</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-5231">31-5231</cite> and § <cite path="§31-5233">31-5233</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
