<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-5606.05</num>
  <heading>Civil liability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person shall be civilly liable to another person who buys a security if the person:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Offers or sells a security in violation of § <cite path="§31-5602.01">31-5602.01</cite>, § <cite path="§31-5603.01">31-5603.01</cite>, or § <cite path="§31-5605.05">31-5605.05</cite>, of a rule or order under § <cite path="§31-5604.05">31-5604.05</cite> which requires the affirmative approval of sales literature, or of a condition imposed under § <cite path="§31-5603.05">31-5603.05</cite>(g) or (h); or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Offers or sells a security by means of an untrue statement of a material fact or an omission to state a material fact necessary in order to make the statement made, in the light of the circumstances under which made, not misleading, the buyer does not know of the untruth or omission and the offeror or seller does not sustain the burden of proof that the offeror or seller did not know, and in the exercise of reasonable care could not have known, of the untruth or omission.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person shall be civilly liable to another person who sells a security if the person offers to purchase or purchases the security by means of any untrue statement of a material fact or any omission to state a material fact necessary in order to make the statement made, in the light of the circumstances under which it is made, not misleading, the seller does not know of the untruth or omission, and the purchaser does not sustain the burden of proof that the purchaser did not know, and in the exercise of reasonable care could not have known, of the untruth or omission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A person shall be civilly liable to another person if the person:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Acts as an investment adviser or representative in violation of §§ <cite path="§31-5602.02">31-5602.02</cite>, <cite path="§31-5605.02">31-5605.02</cite>, <cite path="§31-5605.05">31-5605.05</cite>(b), or of any rule or order adopted under § <cite path="§31-5604.05">31-5604.05</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Receives directly or indirectly any consideration from the other person for advice as to the value of securities or their purchase or sale or for acting as an investment adviser or representative under § <cite path="§31-5601.01">31-5601.01</cite>(17) or (18), whether through the issuance of analyses, reports or otherwise, and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Employs an device, scheme, or artifice to defraud the other person or engages in an act, practice, or course of business which operates or would operate as a fraud or deceit on the other person.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In an action brought under subsection (a)(1) of this section, a buyer may sue at law or in equity:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To recover the consideration paid for the security, interest at the rate used in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia from the date of payment, costs, and reasonable attorneys’ fees, less the amount of any income received on the security, upon the tender of the security and any income received on it; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For damages if the buyer no longer owns the security. The amount of damages shall be the amount that would be recoverable on a tender less the value of the security when the buyer disposed of it, plus interest at the rate used in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia from the date of disposition.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In an action under subsection (a)(2) of this section, a seller may sue at law or in equity:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>On tender of the consideration paid for the security, to recover the security, the amount of any income received on the security, costs, and reasonable attorneys’ fees; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For damages if the buyer no longer owns the security.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In an action brought under subsection (a)(3) of this section, a person may sue at law or in equity for the rescission of the advisory contract and any damages resulting from the violation, interest at the rate used in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia from the date of payment of the consideration plus costs and reasonable attorney’s fees, less the amount of any income received from such advice.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person who directly or indirectly controls a person liable under subsection (a) of this section; a partner, officer, or director of the person liable; a person occupying a similar status or performing similar functions; an employee of the person liable who materially aids in the conduct giving rise to the liability; and a broker-dealer or agent who materially aids in the conduct shall be liable jointly and severally with, and to the same extent as the person liable, unless her or she is able to sustain the burden of proof that he or she did not know, and in exercise of reasonable care could not have known, of the existence of the facts by reason of which the liability is alleged to exist. There shall be contribution among the several persons so liable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A tender specified in this section may be made at any time before entry of judgment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A cause of action under this chapter shall survive the death of any person who might have been a plaintiff or defendant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person may not sue under subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section after the earlier of 3 years after the contract of sale or purchase, or the time specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An action may not be maintained:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To enforce any liability under subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section unless brought within one year after the violation on which it is based; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To enforce a liability under subsections (a)(1)(B) or (a)(2) of this section unless brought within one year after the discovery of the untrue statement or omission or after the discovery should have been made by the exercise of reasonable diligence.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A person may not sue under subsection (a)(3) of this section after the earlier of 3 years after the date of the advisory contract or the rendering of investment advice, or the expiration of 2 years after the discovery of the facts constituting the violation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>No person may sue under this section if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The buyer received a written offer, before suit and at a time when the buyer owned the security or asset, to refund the consideration paid, and interest at the rate used in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia from the date of payment, less the amount of any income received on the security or asset, and the buyer failed to accept the offer within 30 days of its receipt;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The buyer received such an offer before suit and at a time when the buyer did not own the security or asset, unless the buyer rejected the offer in writing within 30 days of its receipt; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The seller received a written offer from the buyer, before suit, to return the security or asset, together with the amount of any income received on the security, and interest at the rate used by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia from the date of payment, and the seller failed to accept the offer within 30 days of its receipt.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>No person may sue on a contract if the person has made or engaged in the performance of the contract in violation of this chapter or any rule or order adopted under this chapter, or has acquired any purported right under the contract with knowledge of the facts by reason of which its making or performance violated this chapter or a rule or order adopted under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>A condition, stipulation, or provision that binds a person who acquires a security or asset, or receives a investment advice, to waive compliance with a provision of this chapter or a rule or order adopted under this chapter shall be void.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>The rights and remedies provided by this chapter shall be in addition to any other rights or remedies that may exist at law or in equity, but this chapter does not create a cause of action not specified in this section or authorized under the bonding requirements of § <cite path="§31-5602.03">31-5602.03</cite>(h).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-203" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-203, § 605, 47 DCR 7837</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-5608.01">31-5608.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
