<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-5608.01</num>
  <heading>Scope of Chapter.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Sections 31-5602.01, 31-5603.01, 31-5605.01, or 31-5605.02, 31-5605.05, and 31-5606.05 shall apply to a person who sells, or offers to sell, when an offer to sell is made in the District or an offer to purchase is made and accepted in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Sections 31-5602.01, 31-5605.01, or 31-5605.02, and 31-5605.05 shall apply to a person who purchases, or offers to purchase, when an offer to purchase, is made in the District or an offer to sell is made and accepted in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this section, an offer to sell or to purchase is made in the District, whether or not either person is present in the District, if the offer originates in the District, or is directed by the offeror to a destination in the District and received where it is directed or at a post office in the District if the offer is mailed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this section, an offer to purchase or to sell is accepted in the District if the acceptance is communicated to the offeror in the District and has not previously been communicated to the offeror, orally or in writing, outside the District. The acceptance is communicated to the offeror in the District, whether or not either party is then present in the District, when the offeree directs it to the offeror in the District reasonably believing the offeror to be in the District and it is received at the place to which it is directed or at any post office in the District in the case of a mailed acceptance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An offer to sell or purchase is not made in the District when the publisher circulates, or there is circulated on the publisher’s behalf, in the District a bona fide newspaper or other publication of general, regular, and paid circulation which is not published in the District, or which is published in the District, but has had more than 2/3 of its circulation outside the District during the last 12 months, or a radio or television program originating outside the District is received in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-203">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-203, § 801, 47 DCR 7837</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
