<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-5328</num>
  <heading>Suspension; revocation or refusal of license of foreign or alien society.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When the Commissioner, upon investigation, finds that a foreign or alien society transacting or applying to transact business in the District has exceeded its powers; has failed to comply with any of the provisions of this chapter; is not fulfilling its contracts in good faith; or is conducting its business fraudulently or in a manner hazardous to its members, creditors, or the public, the Commissioner shall notify the society of the deficiency or deficiencies and state in writing the reasons for his or her dissatisfaction. The Commissioner shall immediately issue a written notice to the society requiring that the deficiency or deficiencies which exist are corrected. After the notice, the society shall have a 30-day period in which to comply with the Commissioner’s request for correction.  If the society fails to comply, the Commissioner shall notify the society of the findings of noncompliance and require the society to show cause on a date named why its license should not be suspended, revoked, or refused.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If on such date the society does not present good and sufficient reason why its authority to do business in the District should not be suspended, revoked, or refused, the Commissioner may suspend or refuse the license of the society to do business in the District until satisfactory evidence is furnished to the Commissioner that such suspension or refusal should be withdrawn or the Commissioner may revoke the authority of the society to do business in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this section shall be taken or construed as preventing any such society from continuing in good faith all contracts made in the District during the time such society was legally authorized to transact business herein.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-86" type="History">Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-86, § 1229, 45 DCR 1172</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-1258.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
