<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-5107</num>
  <heading>Filing requirements; forms and rates to be approved by Commissioner.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All forms of policies, certificates of insurance, notices of proposed insurance, applications for insurance, binders, endorsements and riders delivered or issued for delivery in the District and the premium rates pertaining thereto shall be filed with the Commissioner by the insurance company, in such manner and together with such supporting information as the Commissioner may reasonably require. In any case where a group policy is made for a group in the District and the policy is neither delivered nor issued for delivery in the District, the form of policy and all other forms and premium rates referred to in the preceding sentence shall be filed with the Commissioner by the insurance company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may, within 30 days after the filing of any form of policy, certificate of insurance, notice of proposed insurance, application for insurance, binder, endorsement or rider, disapprove any such form if the premium rates charged or to be charged appear by reasonable assumptions to be excessive in relation to benefits paid or to be paid, or if the form contains provisions which are unjust, unfair, inequitable, misleading, or deceptive. In determining whether to disapprove any such form the Commissioner may give due consideration to past and prospective loss experience within and outside the District, to underwriting practice and judgment to the extent appropriate, and to all other relevant factors within and outside the District, and he may take into account the experience of the individual company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the Commissioner notifies the insurance company that the form does not comply with the requirements of this chapter, it shall be unlawful thereafter for such insurance company to issue or use such form. In such notice, the Commissioner shall specify the reason for his disapproval and state that a hearing will be granted promptly upon request in writing by the insurance company. No such policy, certificate of insurance, notice of proposed insurance, application for insurance, binder, endorsement, or rider shall be issued or used until the expiration of 30 days after it has been so filed, unless the Commissioner shall give his prior written approval thereto.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may, at any time after a hearing, held after not less than 20-days written notice to the insurance company, withdraw his approval of any such form if it does not meet the requirements of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The insurance company shall not issue such forms or use them after the effective date of such withdrawal of approval.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The insurance company may revise such forms and the premium rates pertaining thereto from time to time, and such revised forms and premium rates shall be filed with the Commissioner and shall be subject to all the preceding requirements of this section, in like manner as though they were original filings with the Commissioner.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 87-686" type="History" path="§7">Sept. 25, 1962, 76 Stat. 582, Pub. L. 87-686, § 7</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(m), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 25(b), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-1007.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-1607.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Department of Insurance abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§31-5102">31-5102</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
