<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-5606.01</num>
  <heading>Investigation; subpoena power.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Make public or private investigations inside or outside of the District as he considers necessary to determine whether a person has violated, or is about to violate, any provision of this chapter, or any rule or order hereunder, to aid in the enforcement of this chapter, or to aid in the prescribing of rules and forms to implement this chapter. The Commissioner may require the person to pay the reasonable costs and expenses of the investigation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Require or permit the person to file a statement in writing, under oath or otherwise as the Commissioner determines, as to all the facts and circumstances concerning the matter to be investigated; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Publish information concerning a violation of this chapter or any rule or order adopted under this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For purposes of an investigation or proceeding under this chapter, the Commissioner may administer oaths and affirmations, subpoena witnesses and compel their attendance, take evidence, and require the production of any books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, agreements, or other documents or records which the Commissioner deems relevant or material to the inquiry.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to, a person, the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, upon application by the Commissioner, may issue to the person an order requiring the person to appear before the Commissioner to produce documentary evidence, or to give evidence touching the matter under investigation or in question. Failure to obey the order of the court may be punished as a contempt of court.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No person shall be excused from attending and testifying or from producing a document or record before the Commissioner, in obedience to the subpoena of the Commissioner, or in any proceeding instituted by the Commissioner, on the ground that the testimony or evidence, documentary or otherwise, required of the person may tend to incriminate the person or subject the person to a penalty or forfeiture; provided, that no individual may be prosecuted or subjected to a penalty or forfeiture for or on account of a specific subject concerning which the individual is compelled, after claiming his privilege against self-incrimination as to the specific subject, to testify or produce evidence, documentary or otherwise; provided further, that the individual testifying shall not be exempt from prosecution and punishment for perjury or contempt committed in testifying.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may issue and apply to enforce subpoenas in the District at the request of a securities agency or administrator of another state if the activities constituting an alleged violation for which the information is sought would violate this chapter if the activities had occurred in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-203" type="History" path="ยง601">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-203, ยง 601, 47 DCR 7837</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in ยง <cite path="ยง31-5607.03">31-5607.03</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
