<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-5238.02</num>
  <heading>Compliance and economic impact.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Information, records, or other data received, prepared, used, or retained by the Commissioner pursuant to this subsection shall not be subject to the disclosure requirements of subchapter II of Chapter 5 of Title 2 to the extent that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The information, records, or other data describe the commercial and financial operations or intellectual property of a business entity or individual;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The information or records have not been publicly disseminated at any time; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Disclosure of the information or records may put the business entity or individual at a competitive disadvantage.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A Certified Capital Company shall receive and consider applications from every business interested in obtaining funds from the Certified Capital Company. The Certified Capital Company shall maintain a registry of all contacts made with every person or business that contacts the Certified Capital Company for the purpose of obtaining funding. The registry shall be made available to the Commissioner for inspection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A Certified Capital Company shall provide, at the Commissioner’s request, the Commissioner with a detailed written explanation explaining its decision to fund or to decline to fund a prospective business. A Certified Capital Company providing a written explanation pursuant to this paragraph shall include a copy of the prospect’s business plan, financial statements, or other documents submitted by the person or business seeking funding. A Certified Capital Company shall also submit to the Commissioner all internal business analysis documents, if any, prepared by the Certified Capital Company that were considered during its decision-making process.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A Certified Capital Company that declines to provide funding to any business shall promptly communicate its decision in writing to the business seeking the funding. The letter shall include a detailed statement describing the reason the Certified Capital Company declined to fund the business. A copy of the letter shall be sent to the Commissioner.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each Qualified Business shall once a year provide the Certified Capital Companies from which it has received a Qualified Investment with a report stating the number and type of jobs created and retained in total and in the District, salaries paid to each employee, taxes paid to the District, money spent with local businesses or persons, including landlords, major suppliers and vendors, accountants, auditors, attorneys, and others, and whether such businesses or persons are located in the District or elsewhere.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each Qualified Businesses shall provide the Certified Capital Company with documents, such as leases, invoices, payroll reports, employment records, tax returns and contracts, in support of the reports required by paragraph (1) of this subsection. The Certified Capital Company shall maintain the reports and supporting documents for a period of not less than 5 years from the date of receipt and shall make this information available to the Commissioner during the annual review.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision in this chapter, the Commissioner shall promptly make available to the Council and its committees, upon their request, any information made available to or otherwise in the possession of the Commissioner pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner shall conduct an Economic Impact Study once a year, beginning with the year ending December 31, 2009, and ending with the year ending December 31, 2014, to determine the economic impact of the Certified Capital Company program on the District’s economy. The Certified Capital Companies shall require its Qualified Businesses to provide all information necessary, as determined by the Commissioner or his or her designee, to complete the study. A detailed written report shall be prepared at the conclusion of the study. The Commissioner may retain consultants, economists, and other experts to conduct the Economic Impact Study. The costs of these experts shall be borne by the Certified Capital Companies in proportion to the amount of Certified Capital invested in each Certified Capital Company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may subject a Certified Capital Company to an administrative penalty not to exceed $25,000 for any violation of this section, subject to the hearing requirements set forth [in] § <cite path="§2-509">2-509</cite>. Prior to imposing a penalty under this section, the Commissioner shall provide the Certified Capital Company with written notice of the violation and at least 30 days to cure the violation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-87" type="History" path="§9a">Mar. 10, 2004, D.C. Law 15-87, § 9a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-181" type="History">as added by May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-181, § 2(e), 57 DCR 3388</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
