<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-5001</num>
  <heading>Purposes of chapter.</heading>
  <text>The purposes of this chapter are:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>To assure stability in the property insurance market for property located in the District of Columbia;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>To assure the availability of basic property insurance and homeowner’s insurance as defined by this chapter;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>To encourage maximum use and utilization, in obtaining basic property insurance and homeowner’s insurance, of the normal insurance market provided by authorized insurers;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>To provide for the equitable distribution among insurers of the responsibility for insuring qualified property in the District of Columbia for which insurance cannot be obtained through the normal insurance market and to authorize the establishment of a joint underwriting association in the District of Columbia to provide for insuring and reinsuring of basic property insurance and homeowner’s insurance without regard to environmental hazards; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>To encourage the delivery of essential property insurance, and the homeowner’s insurance that is provided by the Facility, at the most reasonable cost possible; provided, that insurance pricing by the Facility:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is actuarially self-supporting; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Does not actively compete with insurance pricing in the normal insurance market provided by authorized insurers.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-448" type="History">Aug. 1, 1968, 82 Stat. 567, Pub. L. 90-448, title XII, § 1202</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-251" type="History">Mar. 27, 2003, D.C. Law 14-251, § 2(a), 50 DCR 222</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-1801.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-1701.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-251">D.C. Law 14-251</cite> substituted “basic property insurance and homeowner’s insurance” for “basic property insurance” throughout the section; in par. (3), substituted “maximum use and utilization” for “maximum use”, and made a nonsubstantive change; in par. (4), substituted “District of Columbia to provide for insuring and” for “District of Columbia to provide for”, and made a nonsubstantive change; and added par. (5).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
