<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-5101</num>
  <heading>Short title; applicability of provisions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This chapter regulating credit life insurance and credit accident and health insurance in the District of Columbia may be cited as “The Act for the Regulation of Credit Life Insurance and Credit Accident and Health Insurance.”</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All life insurance and all accident and health insurance in connection with loans or other credit transactions of less than 5 years duration in the District of Columbia shall be subject to the provisions of this chapter. Such insurance written in connection with a loan or other credit transaction of 5 years duration or more shall not be subject to the provisions of this chapter, nor shall such insurance be subject to the provisions of this chapter if the issuance of the insurance is an isolated transaction on the part of the insurer not related to a plan or regular course of conduct for insuring debtors of the creditor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 87-686" type="History">Sept. 25, 1962, 76 Stat. 580, Pub. L. 87-686, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-263" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-263, § 1411(b)(1), 48 DCR 991</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-132" type="History">May 7, 2002, D.C. Law 14-132, § 602(a)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-1001.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 35-1601.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-263">D.C. Law 13-263</cite> added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-132">D.C. Law 14-132</cite> repealed subsec. (c) which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) Sections §§ <cite path="§31-5110.01">31-5110.01</cite>, <cite path="§31-5111">31-5111</cite>, and <cite path="§31-5112">31-5112</cite> shall apply to an insurance plan or program for which an application of approval has been submitted to the Commissioner under § <cite path="§42-836.01">42-836.01</cite>(2)(B).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite> purported to amend subsec. (c) which was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-132">D.C. Law 14-132</cite>, therefore, the amendment was ineffective.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Protections from Predatory Lending and Mortgage Foreclosure Improvements Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-86">D.C. Law 14-86</cite>, March 19, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 2991).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">Section 2 of Act 14-188, the “Protections from Predatory Lending and Mortgage Foreclosure Improvements Emergency Amendment Act”, deemed approved Nov. 27, 2001, without the signature of the Mayor, provided that <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-263">D.C. Law 13-263</cite> shall not apply beginning November 6, 2001, through March 6, 2002.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
