<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-5605.03</num>
  <heading>Manipulation of market.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person shall not, directly or indirectly, in the District:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Quote a fictitious price for a security;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Effect a transaction in a security which involves no change in the beneficial ownership of the security for the purpose of creating a false or misleading appearance of active trading in a security or for the market for the security;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Enter an order for the purchase of a security with the knowledge that an order of substantially the same size and at substantially the same time and price for the sale of the security has been, or will be, entered by or for the same, or an affiliated, person for the purpose of creating a false or misleading appearance of active trading in a security or with respect to the market for the security;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Enter an order for the sale of a security with knowledge that an order of substantially the same size and at substantially the same time and price for the purchase of the security has been or will be entered by or for the same or different parties for the purpose of creating a false or misleading appearance of active trading in a security or with respect to the market for the security; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Employ any other deceptive or fraudulent device, scheme, or artifice to manipulate the market in a security.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A transaction effected in compliance with, or conduct that does not violate, the applicable provisions of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, and the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder, shall not constitute a violation of subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-203">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-203, ยง 503, 47 DCR 7837</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in ยง <cite root="31-5606.04">31-5606.04</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
