<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-5505</num>
  <heading>Powers and duties of the Association.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Association shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be obligated to pay covered claims existing prior to the determination of the insolvency arising within 30 days after the determination of insolvency, or before the policy expiration date if less than 30 days after the determination of insolvency, or before the insured replaces the policy or causes its cancellation, if the insured does so within 30 days of the determination. The obligation shall extend to covered claims reported pursuant to an optional extended period to report claims sold to the insured by the liquidator. The obligation as to covered claims shall be satisfied by paying to the claimant an amount as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The full amount of a covered claim for benefits under a workers’ compensation insurance coverage;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An amount not exceeding $10,000 per policy for a covered claim for the return of unearned premium; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>An amount not exceeding $300,000 per claimant for all other covered claims.</text>
      </para>
      <aftertext>In no event shall the Association be obligated to pay a claimant an amount in excess of the obligation of the insolvent insurer under the policy from which the claim arises. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a covered claim shall not include any claim filed with the Guaranty Fund after the earlier of the final date for the filing of claims against the liquidator or receiver of an insolvent insurer or 18 months after the order of liquidation. The Association shall pay only that amount of each unearned premium which is in excess of $100;</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be deemed the insurer to the extent of its obligation on the covered claims and to such extent shall have all rights, duties, and obligations of the insolvent insurer as if the insurer had not become insolvent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Allocate claims paid and expenses incurred among the 3 accounts separately, and assess member insurers, separately for each account, amounts necessary to pay the obligations of the Association under paragraph (1) of this subsection subsequent to an insolvency, the expenses of handling covered claims subsequent to an insolvency, and other expenses authorized by this chapter. The assessments of each member insurer shall be in the proportion that the net direct written premiums of the member insurer for the calendar year preceding the assessment on the kinds of insurance in the account bears to the net direct written premiums of all member insurers for the calendar year preceding the assessment on the kinds of insurance in the account. Each member insurer shall be notified of the assessment not later than 30 days before it is due. No member insurer may be assessed in any one year on any account an amount greater than 2% of that member insurer’s net direct written premiums for the calendar year preceding the assessment on the kinds of insurance in the account. If the maximum assessment, together with the other assets of the Association in any account, does not provide in any one year in any account an amount sufficient to make all necessary payments from that account, the funds available shall be prorated and the unpaid portion shall be paid as soon thereafter as funds become available. The Association shall pay claims in any order which it deems reasonable, including the payment of claims as they are received from the claimants or in groups or categories of claims. The Association may exempt or defer, in whole or in part, the assessment of any member insurer, if the assessment would cause the member insurer’s financial statement to reflect amounts of capital or surplus less than the minimum amounts required for a certificate of authority by any jurisdiction in which the member insurer is authorized to transact insurance; provided, however, that during the period of deferment, no dividends shall be paid to shareholders or policyholders. Deferred assessments shall be paid when such a payment will not reduce capital or surplus below required minimums. These payments shall be refunded to those companies receiving larger assessments by virtue of such a deferment, or at the election of any company, credited against future assessments. Each member insurer may set off, against any assessment, authorized payments made on covered claims and expenses incurred in the payment of these claims by the member insurer if they are chargeable to the account for which the assessment is made;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Investigate claims brought against the Association and adjust, compromise, settle, and pay covered claims to the extent of the Association’s obligation and deny all other claims. The Association may review settlements, releases, and judgments to which the insolvent insurer or its insureds were parties to determine the extent to which the settlements, releases, and judgments may be properly contested;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Notify those persons the Mayor directs under § <cite path="§31-5507">31-5507</cite>(b)(1);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Handle claims through its employees or through 1 or more insurers or other persons designated as servicing facilities. Designation of a servicing facility is subject to the approval of the Mayor, but the designation may be declined by a member insurer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Reimburse each servicing facility for obligations of the Association paid by the facility and for expenses incurred by the facility while handling claims on behalf of the Association and shall pay the other expenses of the Association authorized by this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Association may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Employ or retain those persons necessary to handle claims and perform other duties of the Association;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Borrow funds necessary to effect the purposes of this chapter in accord with the plan of operation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sue or be sued;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Negotiate and become a party to those contracts necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Perform any other acts necessary or proper to effectuate the purposes of this chapter; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Refund to the member insurers, in proportion to the contribution of each member insurer to that account, that amount by which the assets of the account exceed the liabilities, if at the end of any calendar year, the board of directors finds that the assets of the Association in any account exceed the liabilities of that account as estimated by the board of directors for the coming year.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-51" type="History">Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-51, § 6, 40 DCR 6120</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-5506">31-5506</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-3905.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
