<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-731</num>
  <heading>Formation of a mutual holding company.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A domestic mutual insurance company, upon approval of the Commissioner, may reorganize by directly or indirectly forming an insurance holding company based upon a mutual plan. The reorganized insurance company shall continue, without interruption, its corporate existence as a stock insurance company subsidiary to the mutual insurance holding company or as a stock insurance company subsidiary to an intermediate holding company which is subsidiary to the mutual insurance holding company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner, after a public hearing as provided in § <cite path="§31-703">31-703</cite>(g)(1), if satisfied that the interests of the policyholders are properly protected and that the plan of reorganization is fair and equitable to the policyholders, shall approve the proposed plan of reorganization and may require as a condition of approval such modifications of the proposed plan of reorganization as the Commissioner finds necessary for the protection of the policyholders’ interests. The Commissioner may retain consultants as provided in § <cite path="§31-703">31-703</cite>(g)(3). A reorganization pursuant to this section is subject to § <cite path="§31-703">31-703</cite>(a), (b), and (c). The Commissioner shall retain jurisdiction over a mutual insurance holding company organized pursuant to this section to assure that policyholder interests are protected.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All of the initial shares of the capital stock of the reorganized insurance company shall be issued to the mutual insurance holding company. The membership interests of the policyholders of the reorganized insurance company shall become membership interests in the mutual insurance holding company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Policyholders of the reorganized insurance company shall be members of the mutual insurance holding company in accordance with the articles of incorporation and bylaws of the mutual insurance holding company. The mutual insurance holding company shall at all times own a majority of the voting shares of the capital stock of the reorganized insurance company.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-159" type="History">Sept. 20, 1996, D.C. Law 11-159, § 2, 43 DCR 3714</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 41(a), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-188" type="History">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-188, § 2(a), 45 DCR 7807</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§31-734">31-734</cite> and § <cite path="§31-735">31-735</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-3721.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-119">D.C. Law 12-119</cite>, June 11, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 4036).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of §§ 35-3721 through 35-3728 1981 Ed., see § 2-9 of the Mutual Holding Company Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-288, July 1, 1996,  43 DCR 3707).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of §§ 35-3721 through 35-3728 1981 Ed., see § 2-9 of the Mutual Holding Company Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-368, August 21, 1996,  43 DCR 3721).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary repeal of the Mutual Holding Company Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-288, July 1, 1996,  43 DCR 3707), see § 12 of the Mutual Holding Company Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-368, August 21, 1996,  43 DCR 4633).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-295, March 4, 1998,  45 DCR 1764), § 2(a) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-364, June 5, 1998,  45 DCR 3875), and § 2(a) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-550, December 18, 1998,  46 DCR 512).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
