<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-705</num>
  <heading>Registration of insurers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Every insurer which is authorized to do business in the District and which is a member of an insurance holding company system shall register with the Mayor, except a foreign insurer subject to registration requirements and standards adopted by statute or regulation in the jurisdiction of its domicile which are substantially similar to those contained in the following provisions of this subchapter:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>This section;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Section 31-706(a)(1), (b), and (d); and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Either § <cite root="31-706">31-706</cite>(a)(2) or a provision like the following: “Each registered insurer shall keep current the information required to be disclosed in its registration statement by reporting all material changes or additions within 15 days after the end of the month in which it learns of each change or addition.”</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any insurer which is subject to registration under this section shall register within 15 days after it becomes subject to registration, and annually thereafter by April 30 of each year, unless the Mayor for good cause shown extends the time for registration, and then within the extended time. The Mayor may require any insurer authorized to do business in the District which is a member of a holding company system, and which is not subject to registration under this section, to furnish a copy of the registration statement, the summary specified in subsection (c) of this section or other information filed by the insurance company with the insurance regulatory authority of domiciliary jurisdiction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Every insurer subject to registration shall file the registration statement on a form prescribed by the NAIC, which shall contain the following current information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The capital structure, general financial condition, ownership, and management of the insurer and any person controlling the insurer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The identity and relationship of every member of the insurance holding company system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The following agreements in force, and transactions currently outstanding or which have occurred during the last calendar year between the insurer and its affiliates:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Loans, other investments, or purchases, sales, or exchange of securities of the affiliates by the insurer or of the insurer by its affiliates;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Purchases, sales, or exchange of assets;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Transactions not in the ordinary course of business;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Guarantees or undertakings for the benefit of an affiliate which result in an actual contingent exposure of the insurer’s assets to liability, other than insurance contracts entered into in the ordinary course of the insurer’s business;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>All management agreements, service contracts, and all cost-sharing arrangements;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Reinsurance agreements;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Dividends and other distributions to shareholders; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Consolidated tax allocation agreements;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any pledge of the insurer’s stock, including stock of any subsidiary or controlling affiliate, for a loan made to any member of the insurance holding company system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4A)</num>
      <text>If requested by the Mayor, the insurer shall include financial statements of or within an insurance holding company system, including all affiliates. Financial statements may include annual audited financial statements filed with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (“SEC”) pursuant to the Securities Act of 1933, approved May 27, 1933 (48 Stat. 74; 15 U.S.C. § 77a et seq.), or the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, approved June 6, 1934 (48 Stat. 881; 15 U.S.C. § 78a et seq.). An insurer required to file financial statements pursuant to this paragraph may satisfy the request by providing the Mayor with the most recently filed parent corporation financial statements that have been filed with the SEC;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Other matters concerning transactions between registered insurers and any affiliates as may be included from time to time in any registration forms adopted or approved by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Statements that the insurer’s board of directors oversees corporate governance and internal controls and that the insurer’s officers or senior management have approved, implemented, and continue to maintain and monitor corporate governance and internal control procedures; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Any other information required by the Mayor by rule or regulation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All registration statements shall contain a summary outlining all items in the current registration statement which are different from the prior registration statement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No information need be disclosed on the registration statement filed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section if the information is not material for the purposes of this section. Unless the Mayor by rule, regulation, or order provides otherwise, sales, purchases, exchanges, loans or extensions of credit, investments, or guarantees involving one-half of 1% or less of an insurer’s admitted assets as of the 31st day of December next preceding shall not be deemed material for purposes of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subject to § <cite root="31-706">31-706</cite>(b), each registered insurer shall report to the Mayor all dividends and other distributions to shareholders within 15 business days following their declaration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Any person within an insurance holding company system subject to registration shall be required to provide complete and accurate information to an insurer, where the information is reasonably necessary to enable the insurer to comply with the provisions of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall terminate the registration of any insurer which demonstrates that it no longer is a member of an insurance holding company system.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may require or allow 2 or more affiliated insurers subject to registration to file a consolidated registration statement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may allow an insurer which is authorized to do business in the District and which is part of an insurance holding company system to register on behalf of any affiliated insurer which is required to register under subsection (a) of this section and to file all information and material required to be filed under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall not apply to any insurer, information, or transaction if and to the extent that the Mayor by rule, regulation, or order shall exempt the same from the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>Any person may file with the Mayor a disclaimer of affiliation with any authorized insurer or the disclaimer may be filed by the insurer or any member of an insurance holding company system. The disclaimer shall fully disclose all material relationships and bases for affiliation between the person and the insurer as well as the basis for disclaiming the affiliation. A disclaimer of affiliation shall be deemed to have been granted, unless the Mayor, within 30 days following receipt of a complete disclaimer, notifies the filing party that the disclaimer is disallowed. In the event of disallowance, the disclaiming party may request an administrative hearing, which shall be granted. The disclaiming party shall be relieved of its duty to register under this section if approval of the disclaimer has been granted by the Mayor or has been deemed approved.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k-1)</num>
    <text>The ultimate controlling person of every insurer subject to registration shall also file an annual enterprise risk report. The report shall, to the best of the ultimate controlling person’s knowledge and belief, identify the material risks within the insurance holding company system that could pose enterprise risk to the insurer. The report shall be filed with the lead state commissioner of the insurance holding company system as determined by the procedures within the Financial Analysis Handbook adopted by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>The failure to file a registration statement or any summary of the registration statement or enterprise risk filing required by this section within the time specified for such a filing shall be a violation of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-44">Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-44, § 6, 40 DCR 6027</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-255">May 16, 1995, D.C. Law 10-255, § 32(b), 41 DCR 5193</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 43, 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-235">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-235, § 2(d), 62 DCR 461</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="31-701">31-701</cite>, § <cite root="31-707">31-707</cite>, § <cite root="31-708">31-708</cite>, and § <cite root="31-710">31-710</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 35-3705.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-235">D.C. Law 20-235</cite> added (b)(4A), (b)(6), and (b)(7) and made related changes; rewrote (k); added (k-1); and substituted “statement or enterprise risk filing required” for “statement required” in (l).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Because of the codification of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-159">D.C. Law 11-159</cite> as subchapter II of Chapter 37 of Title 35 [subchapter II of Chapter 7 of Title 31, 2001 Ed.], and the designation of the preexisting text as subchapter I, “subchapter” has been substituted for “chapter” in the introductory language of (a)(1) and in (f).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
