<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-737</num>
  <heading>Limitations of actions.</heading>
  <text>Any action challenging the validity of or arising out of acts taken or proposed to be taken under this subchapter shall be commenced within 30 days after the date of the issuance of any order by the Commissioner pursuant to this subchapter. In any action challenging the validity of or arising out of acts taken or proposed to be taken under this subchapter, or charging that the directors of the mutual insurance holding company or any of its subsidiaries have acted improperly in connection with any aspect of the acts taken or proposed to be taken under this subchapter, the mutual insurance holding company or any of its subsidiaries in whose right such action is brought, or the defendant(s) shall be entitled at any state of the proceedings before final judgment to require the plaintiff(s) to give security for the reasonable expenses, including attorney fees, which may be incurred by the mutual insurance holding company or any of its subsidiaries or any other defendant(s) in connection with such action. Thereafter, the amount of such security, from time to time, may be increased or decreased in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction of such action upon a showing that the security provided has or may become inadequate or excessive.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-159" type="History" path="§8">Sept. 20, 1996, D.C. Law 11-159, § 8, 43 DCR 3714</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-202" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-202, § 4, 43 DCR 6054</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-188" type="History">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-188, § 2(d), 45 DCR 7807</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-3727.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(d) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-119">D.C. Law 12-119</cite>, June 11, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 4036).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">See notes to § <cite path="§35-3721">35-3721</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Mutual Holding Company Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-449, December 10, 1996,  43 DCR 6866), and § 2 of the Mutual Holding Company Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-6, March 3, 1997,  44 DCR 1619).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of § 8 of the Mutual Holding Company Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-290) to conform with this section, see § 11 of the Mutual Holding Company Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-368, August 21, 1996,  43 DCR 4633).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Mutual Holding Company Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-449, December 10, 1996,  43 DCR 6866), and § 2 of the Mutual Holding Company Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-6, March 3, 1997,  44 DCR 1619).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(d) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-295, March 4, 1998,  45 DCR 1764), § 2(d) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-364, June 5, 1998,  45 DCR 3877), and § 2(d) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-550, December 18, 1998,  46 DCR 512).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
