<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-903</num>
  <heading>Approval of the plan of conversion by the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After adoption by the mutual company’s board of directors, the plan shall be submitted to the Commissioner for review and approval. The Commissioner shall approve the plan upon finding that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The provisions of this section have been complied with;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The plan will not prejudice the interests of the members; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The plan’s method of allocating subscription rights is fair and equitable.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner, in his discretion, may order that a hearing on the plan be held, which hearing shall be conducted in accordance with the contested case procedures set forth in <cite path="§2-509">§ 2-509</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-2)</num>
    <text>A decision or order of the Commissioner, after a hearing conducted in accordance with the contested case procedures as set forth in subsection (a-1) of this section, may be reviewed as provided in <cite path="§2-510">§ 2-510</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Prior to the members’ approval of the plan, a mutual company seeking the Commissioner’s approval of a plan shall file the following documents with the Commissioner for review and approval:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The plan of conversion, including the independent evaluation of pro forma market value required by <cite path="§31-906|(f)">§ 31-906(f)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The form of notice required by <cite path="§31-904|(b)">§ 31-904(b)</cite> for eligible members of the meeting to vote on the plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any proxies to be solicited from eligible members pursuant to <cite path="§31-904|(c)">§ 31-904(c)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The form of notice required by <cite path="§31-910|(a)">§ 31-910(a)</cite> for persons whose policies are issued after adoption of the plan but before its effective date; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The proposed articles of incorporation and bylaws of the converted stock company. Once filed, these documents shall be approved or disapproved by the Commissioner within a reasonable time.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>After the members have approved the plan, the converted stock company shall file the following documents with the Commissioner:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The minutes of the meeting of the members at which the plan was voted upon; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The revised articles of incorporation and bylaws of the converted stock company.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may retain, at the mutual company’s expense, any qualified expert not otherwise a part of the Commissioner’s staff to assist in reviewing the plan and the independent evaluation of the pro forma market value which is required by <cite path="§31-906|(i)">§ 31-906(i)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-126" type="History" path="§4">May 24, 1996, D.C. Law 11-126, § 4, 43 DCR 1551</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 43(c), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-214" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-214, § 2(b), 47 DCR 9580</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 19, 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite>, in subsec. (a-2), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-214">D.C. Law 13-214</cite> inserted subsecs. (a-1) and (a-2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-4203.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§31-1371.05">§ 31-1371.05</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
