<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-5205</num>
  <heading>Employees’ compensation corporations or associations to file certain information with Commissioner; disapproval of premium rate or schedule; judicial review.</heading>
  <text>Every insurance corporation or association authorized to transact business in the District of Columbia, which insures employers against liability for compensation under the Employees’ Compensation Act, shall file with the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities [Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking] its manual of classifications and underwriting rules, together with basic rates for each class, and also merit rating plans designed to modify the class rates, none of which shall take effect until the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities [Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking] shall have approved the same as adequate and reasonable for the group of risks to which they respectively apply. The Commissioner of Insurance and Securities [Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking] may withdraw his approval of any premium rate or schedule made by any insurance corporation or association, if, in his judgment, such premium rate or schedule is inadequate or unreasonable; provided, that upon petition of the company or association or any other party aggrieved the opinion of the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities [Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking] shall be subject to review by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia: Provided further, that any petition for review shall be filed with said Court within 30 days after the rendition of opinion by the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities [Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking].</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 854, § 657b</annotation>
      <annotation>April 16, 1934, 48 Stat. 592, ch. 144</annotation>
      <annotation>June 25, 1936, 49 Stat. 1921, ch. 804</annotation>
      <annotation>June 25, 1948, 62 Stat. 991, ch. 646, § 32(b)</annotation>
      <annotation>May 24, 1949, 63 Stat. 107, ch. 139, § 127</annotation>
      <annotation>July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 572, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(c)(36)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(d), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 35-205.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 35-205.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>“The Employees’ Compensation Act,” referred to near the beginning of the first sentence, refers to Chapter 15 of Title 36.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Department of Insurance abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite root="31-5201">31-5201</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
