<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1217.135</num>
  <heading>Bond authorization.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council approves and authorizes the issuance of one or more series of bonds in an aggregate principal amount not to exceed $198 million. The bonds, which may be issued from time to time, in one or more series, shall be tax-exempt or taxable as the Mayor shall determine and shall be payable and secured as provided in <cite path="ยง2-1217.136">ยง 2-1217.136</cite>; provided, that within 60 days prior to the issuance of any bonds, the Chief Financial Officer shall submit to the Mayor and the Council a report to determine the subsidy level needed from the District for the project.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The proceeds of the bonds shall be used as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An amount not to exceed $148 million in 2008 dollars (adjusted for inflation by the Consumer Price Index) may be used for payment of Development Costs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The balance of the proceeds may be used to pay the financing costs incurred by the District and to fund capitalized interest and required reserves.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may pay from the proceeds of the bonds the financing costs and expenses of issuing and delivering the bonds, including, but not limited to, underwriting, legal, accounting, financial advisory, bond insurance or other credit enhancement, marketing and selling the bonds, and printing costs and expenses.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-252" type="History" path="ยง105">Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-252, ยง 105, 55 DCR 9251</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
