<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-137</num>
  <heading>Powers of Inspector of Plumbing.</heading>
  <text>The Inspector of Plumbing and his assistants shall be under the direction of said Mayor of the District of Columbia, and they are hereby empowered, accordingly, to inspect or cause to be inspected, all houses when in course of erection in said District, to see that the plumbing, drainage, and ventilation of sewers, and gas-fittings thereof conform to the regulations hereinbefore provided for; and also at any time, during reasonable hours, under like direction, on the application of the owner, or occupant, or the complaint under oath of any reputable citizen, to inspect or cause to be inspected any house in said District to examine the plumbing, drainage, and ventilation of sewers, and gas-fittings thereof, and generally to see that the regulations hereinbefore provided for are duly observed and enforced.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 52-1-ch53" path="§4">Apr. 23, 1892, 27 Stat. 21, ch. 53, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 3, 1893, 27 Stat. 543, ch. 199</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-727.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1025.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§21-2002">§ 21-2002</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
