<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1431.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|14|C">this unit</code-cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“ADA” means the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, approved July 26, 1990 (104 Stat. 327; 42 U.S.C. § 12101 et seq.).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“ADA Compliance Program” means the program established by <cite path="§2-1431.02">§ 2-1431.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Agency” means all agencies and instrumentalities of the District government.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Disability” means, with respect to an individual:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A physical or mental impairment that substantially limits one or more of the major life activities of such individual;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A record of such an impairment; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Being regarded as having such an impairment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Human Rights Act” means Unit A of this chapter [<cite path="§2-1401.01">§ 2-1401.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Mayor’s Committee on Persons with Disabilities” means the Mayor’s Committee on Persons with Disabilities, established by Mayor’s Order 88-245 (November 16, 1998), and amended by Mayor’s Order 2002-79 (April 15, 2002).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Office” means the Office of Disability Rights established by <cite path="§2-1431.03">§ 2-1431.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Office of Human Rights” means the Office of Human Rights established by <cite path="§2-1411.01">§ 2-1411.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Olmstead Compliance Plan” means a comprehensive working plan, developed in collaboration with individuals with disabilities and with District agencies serving individuals with disabilities, which shall include annual legislative, regulatory, and budgetary recommendations for the District to serve qualified individuals with disabilities in accordance with Olmstead v. L.C., 527 U.S. 581, and in the most integrated setting as provided in 28 C.F.R. Part 35, App. A.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Rehabilitation Act” means the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, approved September 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 355; 29 U.S.C. § 701 et seq.).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-239" type="History" path="§2">Mar. 8, 2007, D.C. Law 16-239, § 2, 54 DCR 404</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 7083 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> repealed Section 10 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-239">D.C. Law 16-239</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Orders">Re-Establishment of the District of Columbia Commission on Persons with Disabilities, see Mayor’s Order 2009-165, September 25, 2009 ( 56 DCR 8093).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
