<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1402.52</num>
  <heading>Records and reports.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Every person subject to this chapter shall preserve any regularly kept business records for a period of 6 months from the date of the making of the record, or from the date of the action which is the subject of the record, whichever is longer; such records shall include, but not be limited to, application forms submitted by applicants, sales and rental records, credit and reference reports, personnel records, and any other record pertaining to the status of an individual’s enjoyment of the rights and privileges protected or granted under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Where a charge of discrimination has been filed against a person under this chapter, the respondent shall preserve all records which may be relevant to the charge or action, until a final disposition of the charge in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All persons subject to this chapter shall furnish to the Office, at the time and in the manner prescribed by the Office, such reports relating to information under their control as the Office may require. The identities of persons and properties contained in reports submitted to the Office under the provisions of this section shall not be made public.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-38" type="History" path="§252">Dec. 13, 1977, D.C. Law 2-38, title II, § 252, 24 DCR 6038</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2262.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2523.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
