<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-218.53</num>
  <heading>Agency reporting requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each agency shall submit a quarterly report to the Department and to the District of Columbia Auditor within 30 days after the end of each quarter, except for the 4th quarter report. The 4th quarter and annual report shall be submitted together. When submitting a quarterly report, the agency shall list each expenditure as it appears in the general ledger from the expendable budget of the agency during the quarter. For each expenditure, the report shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the vendor from which the goods or services were purchased;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The vendor identification number;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A description of the goods or services provided;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Whether the vendor was a small or certified small business enterprise;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The funding source for the expenditure (local, federal, capital, or other);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The date of the expenditure;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The dollar amount of the expenditure; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The percentage of the agency's total dollar amount of expenditures in the quarter to all small business enterprises and certified business enterprises.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>In addition to the report of prime contracting activity required by subsection (a) of this section, each agency shall also submit to the Department and the Office of the District of Columbia Auditor within 30 days of the end of each quarter, a report on a contract basis of payments made by beneficiaries to subcontractors that are certified business enterprises and such payments shall be reported against the amounts included in the approved detailed certified business enterprise subcontracting plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each agency shall submit to the Department and the District of Columbia Auditor, within 30 days of the issuance of the Comprehensive Annual Financial Report, an annual report listing each expenditure as it appears in the general ledger from the expendable budget of the agency during the fiscal year which shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The information required to be included in the quarterly reports (with calculations for the fiscal year);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A description of the activities the agency engaged in, including the programs required by this part, to achieve the goals set forth in <cite path="§2-218.41">§ 2-218.41</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A description of any changes the agency intends to make during the succeeding fiscal year to the activities it engages in to achieve the goals set forth in <cite path="§2-218.41">§ 2-218.41</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department shall monitor agency compliance with the reporting requirements of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Auditor shall review the annual report of each agency to determine whether the planned activities of the agency for the succeeding fiscal year are likely to enable the agency to achieve the goals set forth in <cite path="§2-218.41">§ 2-218.41</cite>. The District of Columbia Auditor shall make recommendations on activities the agency should engage in to meet or exceed the goals set forth in <cite path="§2-218.41">§ 2-218.41</cite>. The District of Columbia Auditor’s recommendations shall be submitted to the agency, the Council, and the Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Department shall review the annual report of an agency to determine whether the planned activities of the agency for the succeeding fiscal year are likely to enable the agency to achieve the goals set forth in <cite path="§2-218.41">§ 2-218.41</cite>. The Department shall make recommendations on activities the agency should engage in to meet or exceed the goals set forth in <cite path="§2-218.41">§ 2-218.41</cite>. The Department’s recommendations shall be submitted to the agency, the Office of District of Columbia Auditor, and the Council within 30 days of the agency’s annual report submission.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History" path="§2353">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2353, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-207" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-207, § 2(n), 55 DCR 6107</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2222(b), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-141" type="History">Apr. 20, 2010, D.C. Law 18-141, § 2(m), 57 DCR 1485</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-159" type="History">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-159, § 2(d), 57 DCR 3006</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-108" type="History">June 10, 2014, D.C. Law 20-108, § 2(ee), 61 DCR 3892</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2222(b) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2222(b) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(m) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-251, January 23, 2008,  55 DCR 1259).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(m) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-156, October 18, 2007,  54 DCR 10919).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2353 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(m) of the Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-96">D.C. Law 17-96</cite>, January 29, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 3403).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> rewrote the introductory paragraph of (a); rewrote (a)(2), (a)(3), (a)(4), and (a)(8); and added (a-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-159">D.C. Law 18-159</cite>, in the lead-in language of subsec. (a), inserted “The 4th quarter and annual report shall be submitted together.”; and rewrote subsec. (a)(8), which had read as follows: “(8) The total expenditure on certified small business enterprises and the percentage the total expenditure on certified small business enterprises is of the total expenditure.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-141">D.C. Law 18-141</cite> rewrote subsecs. (a) and (e); and, in subsec. (b), substituted “the Department and the District of Columbia Auditor” for “the Department”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-207">D.C. Law 17-207</cite>, in subsec. (a)(1)(D), substituted “certified” for “local, small, or disadvantaged”; and, in subsecs. (a)(2)(A), (3)(A), (b)(2)(A), substituted “Certified” for “Local, small, or disadvantaged”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-301.181">§ 1-301.181</cite>, <cite path="§1-301.182">§ 1-301.182</cite>, <cite path="§1-301.184">§ 1-301.184</cite>, <cite path="§2-218.13">§ 2-218.13</cite>, and <cite path="§2-218.54">§ 2-218.54</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7005.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that, except as provided in <cite path="§2-218.46|(f)">§ 2-218.46(f)</cite>, contracts existing or pending as of June 10, 2014, shall not be affected by the provisions of the act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>: Section 4(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that applications pending as June 10, 2014, shall not be subject to the provisions of the act.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
