<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-218.71</num>
  <heading>Triennial review of program and subchapter.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Every 3 years following October 20, 2005, the Department shall submit to the Council and the Mayor the results of an independent evaluation of the certified business enterprise programs. This evaluation shall compare the costs of contracts awarded pursuant to this subchapter to the cost of contracts awarded without use of the set-asides and bid preferences authorized by this subchapter. This evaluation shall also compare economic outcomes such as revenue, tax payments, and employment of District residents for certified business enterprises certified pursuant to <cite path="2|2|IX-A|D">part D of this subchapter</cite> to economic outcomes for similar firms that are not certified pursuant to <cite path="2|2|IX-A|D">part D of this subchapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department shall review the findings in the triennial report and the goals, intents, and purposes of this subchapter. The Department shall transmit to the Council and the Mayor a report setting forth any recommended amendments to this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History" path="§2371">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2371, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20" type="History">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 2062(j), 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-207" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-207, § 2(q), 55 DCR 6107</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-108" type="History">June 10, 2014, D.C. Law 20-108, § 2(kk), 61 DCR 3892</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(p) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-251, January 23, 2008,  55 DCR 1259).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(p) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-156, October 18, 2007,  54 DCR 10919).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2062(j) of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2371 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(p) of the Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-96">D.C. Law 17-96</cite>, January 29, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 3403).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>  substituted “the Council and the Mayor” for “the Council, the Mayor, and the Commission” in (a); substituted “Department” for “Department and the Commission” in the first sentence of (b); and substituted “shall transmit” for “shall, and the Commission may, transmit” in the second sentence of (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-207">D.C. Law 17-207</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “certified” for “small, local, and disadvantaged”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “pursuant to <cite path="2|2|IX-A|D">part D of this subchapter</cite>” for “by the Commission”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7005.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that, except as provided in <cite path="§2-218.46|(f)">§ 2-218.46(f)</cite>, contracts existing or pending as of June 10, 2014, shall not be affected by the provisions of the act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>: Section 4(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that applications pending as of June 10, 2014, shall not be subject to the provisions of the act.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
