<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-507</num>
  <heading>Compilation of rules and regulations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>As soon as practicable after the effective date of this subchapter, the Mayor shall have compiled, indexed, and published in the District of Columbia Register all regulations adopted by the District of Columbia Council and rules adopted by the Mayor and District of Columbia Council and each agency and in effect at the time of such compilation. Such compilations shall be promptly supplemented or revised as may be necessary to reflect new regulations and rules and changes in regulations and rules.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Compilations shall be made available to the public at a price fixed by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor must publish the 1st compilation required by subsection (a) of this section within 1 year after the effective date of this subchapter and no regulations adopted by the District of Columbia Council nor rule adopted by the Mayor or by an agency before the date of such 1st publication which has not been filed and published in accordance with this subchapter and which is not set forth in such compilation shall be in effect after 1 year after the effective date of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-614" type="History" path="§8">Oct. 21, 1968, 82 Stat. 1207, Pub. L. 90-614, § 107, formerly § 8</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-19" type="History">Oct. 8, 1975, D.C. Law 1-19, title I, § 102(g), 22 DCR 2048</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-96" type="History">renumbered, Mar. 29, 1977, D.C. Law 1-96, § 3(a), (c), 23 DCR 3744</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-153" type="History">Mar. 6, 1979, D.C. Law 2-153, § 6(b), 25 DCR 6960</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1507.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1507.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">The Law Effective Date Notice for D.C. Law 1-96, published on April 8, 1977, was incorrect and was corrected on June 3, 1977, and published at 23 DCR 9532b.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§11-1525">§ 11-1525</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 5 of the Uniform Law Commissioners’ Model State Administrative Procedure Act (1961 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“District of Columbia Council”, appearing twice in (a) and once in (c), should probably be “Council of the District of Columbia” or “Council”, in view of <cite path="§1-1502|(1)|(B)" proof="true">§ 1-1502(1)(B)</cite> and the fact that this section refers to current and ongoing Council activity.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
