<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-1055</num>
  <heading>Subpoena power.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When necessary for the discharge of its duties, the Board shall have the authority to issue subpoenas to compel witnesses to appear and testify and to produce books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, documents, or other relevant records.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, subpoenas hall be served personally upon the witness or his or her designated agent, not less than 5 business days before the date the witness must appear or the documents must be produced, by one of the following methods, which may be attempted concurrently or successively:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By a special process server, at least 18 years of age, designated by the Board from among the staff of the Board or any of the offices or organizations represented on the Board; provided, that the special process server is not directly involved in the investigation; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By a special process server, at least 18 years of age, engaged by the Board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If, after a reasonable attempt, personal service on a witness or witness’ agent cannot be obtained, a special process server identified in subsection (b) of this section may serve a subpoena by registered or certified mail not less than 8 business days before the date the witness must appear or the documents must be produced.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a witness who has been personally summoned neglects or refuses to obey the subpoena issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Board may report that fact to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and the court may compel obedience to the subpoena to the same extent as witnesses may be compelled to obey the subpoenas of the court.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-296">Apr. 11, 2003, D.C. Law 14-296, § 2(c), 50 DCR 320</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
