<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-1366</num>
  <heading>Payment of compensation into court; vesting of title.</heading>
  <text>Payment into the registry of the court for the use of the parties entitled of the sum adjudged to be just compensation for the property to be condemned and taken, or for any parcel thereof, or any interest therein, pursuant to this subchapter, constitutes payment of the compensation. Upon the payment, the plaintiff is entitled to an order declaring that the title to the property in respect of which the compensation is so paid is vested in the United States of America. The money so paid into the registry of the court shall be deemed to be vested in the persons owning or interested in the property, according to their respective estates and interest, and the money shall take the place and stand in lieu of the property condemned. The court, upon the application of the plaintiff or of any party in interest, may determine and direct who is entitled to receive payment of the money so paid into the registry, and, in its discretion, order a reference to the auditor of the court or a special master to ascertain the facts on which the determination and direction are to be made.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-241" type="History">Dec. 23, 1963, 77 Stat. 580, Pub. L. 88-241, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, eminent domain powers, see § <cite path="§9-1107.01">9-1107.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§9-1107.01">9-1107.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 16-1366.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 16-1366.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
