<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-1024</num>
  <heading>Penalties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who violates any provision of § <cite path="§16-1022">16-1022</cite> and who takes the child to a place within the District, or detains or conceals the child within the District of Columbia is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to fine not exceeding $250 or performance of community service not exceeding 240 hours, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who violates any provision of § <cite path="§16-1022">16-1022</cite> and who takes the child to a place outside the District or detains or conceals the child outside the District shall be punished as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the child is out of the custody of the lawful custodian for not more than 30 days, the person is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to a fine not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>] or imprisonment for 6 months, or both, except that if the person releases the child without injury in a safe place prior to arrest, the person is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $250, or performance of community service not exceeding 240 hours, or imprisonment not exceeding 30 days, or a combination of all three.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the child is out of the custody of the lawful custodian for more than 30 days, the person is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to a fine of not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>] or imprisonment for 1 year, or both, except that if the person releases the child without injury in a safe place prior to arrest, the person is guilty of a misdemeanor and, on conviction, is subject to a fine not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>] or imprisonment not exceeding 60 days, or both.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-115" type="History">May 23, 1986, D.C. Law 6-115, § 5, 33 DCR 2424</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-231" type="History">May 10, 1989, D.C. Law 7-231, § 25(e), 36 DCR 492</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 281(b), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§23-563">23-563</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 16-1024.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>]” for “not exceeding $1,000” in (b)(1); and in (b)(2), substituted “of not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>]” for “not exceeding $5,000”, and substituted “not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>]” for “not exceeding $500”.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 281(b) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
