<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-1051</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Board” means the Domestic Violence Fatality Review Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Domestic violence fatality” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A homicide under any of the following circumstances:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The alleged perpetrator and victim resided together at any time;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>The alleged perpetrator and victim have a child in common;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>The alleged perpetrator and victim were married, divorced, separated, or had a romantic relationship, not necessarily including a sexual relationship;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>The alleged perpetrator is or was married to, divorced, or separated from, or in a romantic relationship, not necessarily including a sexual relationship, with a person who is or was married to, divorced, or separated from, or in a romantic relationship, not necessarily including a sexual relationship, with the victim;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>The alleged perpetrator had been stalking the victim;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(vi)</num>
        <text>The victim filed a petition for a protective order against the alleged perpetrator at any time;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(vii)</num>
        <text>The victim resided in the same household, was present at the workplace of, was in proximity of, or was related by blood or affinity to a person who experienced or was threatened with domestic violence by the alleged perpetrator; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(viii)</num>
        <text>The victim or the perpetrator was or is a child, parent, sibling, grandparent, aunt, uncle, or cousin of a person in a relationship that is described within this subsection.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A suicide of an individual where there were implications that the individual was the victim of domestic violence prior to his or her suicide, including the following circumstances:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The victim had applied for or received a protection order within the 2-year period preceding the suicide;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>The victim had undergone counseling or treatment as a result of being the victim of domestic violence within the 2-year period preceding the suicide; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>The victim had reported to the police that he or she had been the victim of domestic violence within the 2-year period preceding the suicide.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Protection order” means an injunction or other order, whether temporary or final, issued by a tribunal for the purpose of preventing violent or threatening acts or harassment against, contact or communication with, or physical proximity to, another individual.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-296" type="History">Apr. 11, 2003, D.C. Law 14-296, § 2(c), 50 DCR 320</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
