<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-1332</num>
  <heading>Sale of excess property; restrictions on use; fair market value; disposition of moneys.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia may, with the consent of the Council in accordance with section 10-801, upon completion of public improvements:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>subdivide, and sell, at public or private sale, or exchange, any excess real property acquired pursuant to this subchapter; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>to carry out such purposes, convey any property acquired in excess of that actually needed and which is not essential to the usefulness of the public works —</text>
    </para>
    <aftertext>with such reservations concerning the future use and occupation of the property as, in the Mayor’s discretion, may be necessary to protect the public improvements.</aftertext>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Property sold under this section shall be sold at not less than the fair market value at the time sold, as determined by appraisement of the assessor of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Moneys received from sales or transfers of properties pursuant to this subchapter shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the revenues of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-241">Dec. 23, 1963, 77 Stat. 575, Pub. L. 88-241, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 558, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 145(f)(9)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 4(k), 35 DCR 147</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-96">Mar. 15, 1990, D.C. Law 8-96, § 6, 37 DCR 795</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 10(q), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-1333">16-1333</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 16-1332.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 16-1332.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Disposal of surplus real property: Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-96">D.C. Law 8-96</cite> provided that for the purposes of this act, the term “real property” means land titled in the name of the District of Columbia (“District”) or in which the District has a controlling interest and includes all structures of a permanent character erected thereon or affixed thereto, any natural resources located thereon or thereunder, all riparian rights attached thereto, or any air space located above or below the property or any street or alley under the jurisdiction of the Mayor.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
