<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-1336</num>
  <heading>Condemnation of excess real property by Mayor; payment of awards, damages, and costs; no assessments for benefits.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When, pursuant to this subchapter, excess real property is condemned by the Mayor, the condemnation proceedings for the acquisition of the property shall be in accordance with subchapter II of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Appropriations available for the payment of awards, damages, and condemnation proceedings pursuant to subchapter II of this chapter may be used in the payment of awards, damages, and costs in condemnation proceedings for the acquisition of excess real property, as provided by this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Appropriations available for the payment of awards, damages, and costs in condemnation proceedings pursuant to subchapter II of this chapter may be used in the payment of awards, damages, and costs in condemnation proceedings thereunder for the acquisition of excess real property as provided by this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In all cases where excess real property is condemned, assessments for benefits may not be levied by the jury in respect to the acquisition of the property.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-241" type="History">Dec. 23, 1963, 77 Stat. 576, Pub. L. 88-241, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 558, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 145(f)(7)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-201" type="History">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, § 502, 30 DCR 148</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104" type="History">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 4(l), 35 DCR 147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-68" type="History">Feb. 5, 1994, D.C. Law 10-68, § 20(a), 40 DCR 6311</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 16-1336.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 16-1336.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(l)(3)-(6) of D.C. Law 7-104 purported to substitute “7-213” for “7-214” 1981 Ed., and “7-214” for “7-215” 1981 Ed. in subsection (a), “7-322” for “7-323” 1981 Ed. in subsections (a) and (c), and “7-301” for “7301” 1981 Ed. in subsection (c), apparently without regard to the amendment to this section by D.C. Law 4-201.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">The reference in subsection (b) to “sections referred to by subsection (a)” has been rendered obsolete by amendments made in <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-201">D.C. Law 4-201</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
