<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-2390</num>
  <heading>Jurisdiction.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the court shall have jurisdiction to enter guardianship order and shall retain jurisdiction to enforce, modify, or terminate a guardianship order until a child reaches 21 years of age; provided, that when the child reaches 18 years of age, the child consents and the court finds it is in the best interest of the child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A child who exits foster care to guardianship may not reenter foster care after age 18.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-273" type="History">Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-273, § 3(b), 48 DCR 1637</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-230" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-230, § 502(a), 57 DCR 6951</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-230">D.C. Law 18-230</cite> rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “The court shall retain jurisdiction to enforce, modify, or terminate a guardianship order until the child reaches 18 years of age. If the court finds that it is in the child’s best interest and if the child consents, the court may retain jurisdiction until the child reaches 21 years of age.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of the Adoption and Guardianship Subsidy Temporary Amendment Act of 2010 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 18-208">D.C. Law 18-208</cite>, July 27, 2010, law notification  57 DCR 7547).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of subchapter V, “Permanent Guardianship”, consisting of §§ <cite path="§16-2381">16-2381</cite> to 16-2399, see § 3(b) of the Adoption and Guardianship Subsidy Temporary Amendment Act of 2010 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 18-208">D.C. Law 18-208</cite>, July 27, 2010, law notification  57 DCR 7547).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of the Foster Children’s Guardianship Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-490, December 18, 2000,  48 DCR 63).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 3(c) of Foster Children’s Guardianship Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-4, February 13, 2001,  48 DCR 2254).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of Adoption and Guardianship Subsidy Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-393, May 7, 2010,  57 DCR 4346).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
