<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-2348</num>
  <heading>Parentage records; confidentiality; inspection and disclosure.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except on order of the Family Division, no records in a case over which the Division has jurisdiction under section 11-1101(11) shall be open to inspection by anyone other than the plaintiff, respondent, their attorneys of record, the IV-D agency, or authorized professional staff of the Superior Court. Any inspection shall be subject to the safeguards provided by section 16-925. The Family Division, upon proper showing, may authorize the furnishing of certified copies of the records or portions thereof to the respondent, the other parent, or custodian of the child, a party in interest, or their duly authorized attorneys. Certified copies of the records or portions thereof may be furnished, upon request, to the IV-D agency and the Corporation Counsel for use as evidence in nonsupport proceedings and to the Registrar as provided by section 16-2346(a).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No person shall disclose, receive, or use records in violation of this section. Whoever willfully discloses, receives, makes use of, or knowingly permits the use of information in violation of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>] or imprisoned not more than ninety days, or both. Violations of this section shall be prosecuted by the Corporation Counsel in the name of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-241" type="History">Dec. 23, 1963, 77 Stat. 592, Pub. L. 88-241, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 545, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 121(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-87" type="History">Oct. 1, 1976, D.C. Law 1-87, § 20(g), 23 DCR 2544</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-34" type="History">Oct. 8, 1981, D.C. Law 4-34, § 29(a), 28 DCR 3271</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104" type="History">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 4(s), 35 DCR 147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-269" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-269, § 106(r), 48 DCR 1270</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 281(d), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 16-2348.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 16-2348.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-269">D.C. Law 13-269</cite>, in subsec. (a), added “the IV-D agency,” following “attorneys of record,”; added “Any inspection shall be subject to the safeguards provided by  section 16-925.” following the first sentence and added “the IV-D agency and” following “furnished, upon request, to”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>]” for “not more than $250” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 5(p) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-103">D.C. Law 12-103</cite>, May 8, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 3254).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 5(t) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-210">D.C. Law 12-210</cite>, April 13, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 3832).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 105(t) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-57">D.C. Law 13-57</cite>, March 7, 2000, law notification  47 DCR 1979).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 105(m) of Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-207">D.C. Law 13-207</cite>, March 31, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 3238).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 5(p) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-222, December 23, 1997,  44 DCR 114), and § 5(p) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-309, March 20, 1998,  45 DCR 1923).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">Section 16 of D.C. Act 12-309 provided for the application of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 5(s) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Second Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-439, August 12, 1998,  45 DCR 6110), § 5(s) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-503, October 27, 1998,  45 DCR 8495), and § 5(s) of the Child Support and Welfare Reform Compliance Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-600, January 20, 1999, 46 DCR</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 281(d) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(s) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-104">D.C. Law 7-104</cite> purported to substitute “Director of the Department of Human Services” for “Director of Public Health” in subsection (a) apparently without regard to the amendment of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-34">D.C. Law 4-34</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
