<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-2310.01</num>
  <heading>Separation of young children detained prior to a hearing.</heading>
  <text>The Director of the Department of Human Services and the Director of Social Services shall ensure that each child at risk who is detained, however briefly, pursuant to section 16-2311(a)(2)   or (b)(1) shall be physically separated at all times, except during transportation, from children or other detainees 13 years of age or older, from any child under the age of 13 who has been detained on the ground that there is probable cause to believe the child has committed a crime of violence, as defined in section 23-1331(4)  , or in any other manner deemed to ensure the safety of the child. Neither the Department of Human Services nor the Director of Social Services shall deliver a child under the age of 13 to the custody of the United States Marshals Service. For the purposes of this section, “child at risk” means a child under the age of 13 or any child 13 years of age or older who, because of his or her size or physical stature, is determined to be especially physically or psychologically vulnerable to attacks by other children.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-140" type="History">Aug. 13, 1986, D.C. Law 6-140, § 2(c), 33 DCR 3827</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-2311.01">16-2311.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 16-2310.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(c) of the Juvenile Speedy Trial Equity Temporary Act of 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-139">D.C. Law 17-139</cite>, March 26, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 4470).</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(c) of Juvenile Speedy Trial Equity Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-235, December 27, 2007,  55 DCR 240).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(c) of Juvenile Speedy Trail Equity Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-315, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3408).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 28(c)(2) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> provided that the section designation of § <cite path="§16-2310.1">16-2310.1</cite> of the District of Columbia Official Code is redesignated as § <cite path="§16-2310.01">16-2310.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
