<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-2394</num>
  <heading>Unlawful disclosure.</heading>
  <text>Whoever willfully discloses, receives, makes use of, or knowingly permits the use of information concerning a child or other person in violation of section 16-2393   shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction thereof shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>] or imprisoned for not more than 90 days, or both. A violation of this section shall be prosecuted by the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-273" type="History">Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-273, § 3(b), 48 DCR 1637</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 281(f), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>]” for “not more than $250”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">For temporary (225 day) addition of subchapter V, “Permanent Guardianship”, consisting of §§ <cite path="§16-2381">16-2381</cite> to 16-2399, see § 3(b) of the Adoption and Guardianship Subsidy Temporary Amendment Act of 2010 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 18-208">D.C. Law 18-208</cite>, July 27, 2010, law notification  57 DCR 7547).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of the Foster Children’s Guardianship Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-490, December 18, 2000,  48 DCR 63).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 3(c) of Foster Children’s Guardianship Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-4, February 13, 2001,  48 DCR 2254).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 281(f) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
