<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-2333.01</num>
  <heading>Permitted disclosures of juvenile information.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An official of the Family Court, the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services, or the Metropolitan Police Department may disclose information (but not records) about a juvenile otherwise protected from disclosure under sections 16-2331, 16-2332, and 16-2333 in accordance with this section only if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the professional judgment of the official, disclosing the information will assist in the protection, welfare, treatment, or rehabilitation of the juvenile;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A professional relationship exists between the official and the juvenile; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The general nature of the disclosure, and rationale for making the disclosure, is approved by the official’s supervisor or agency director.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Information disclosed under this section may be disclosed only to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A principal, teacher, or counselor at a school that the juvenile attends or has attended; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A mental health professional as that term is defined in section 7-1201.01(11).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The information that may be disclosed under this section shall be limited to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The juvenile’s name;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Whether the juvenile is or has been on probation or in the custody of the Department;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Whether the juvenile has violated the terms of probation or absconded while in the custody of the Department;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Whether the juvenile has been arrested by the Metropolitan Police Department, or another law enforcement agency, and the charges brought against the juvenile; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The disposition of the charges brought against the juvenile.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Information disclosed pursuant to this section shall be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Kept confidential and shall not be disclosed by the recipient to another individual or entity except in accordance with section 16-2331, 16-2332, or 16-2333; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Limited to the greatest extent possible consistent with its express purpose.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>This section permits the limited disclosure of information contained in records and files otherwise protected from disclosure under sections 16-2331, 16-2332, and 16-2333, but does not authorize disclosure of the records and files.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-284">Mar. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-284, § 3(f), 57 DCR 10477</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-2331">16-2331</cite>, § <cite path="§16-2332">16-2332</cite>, and § <cite path="§16-2333">16-2333</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
