<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-2321</num>
  <heading>Disposition of child with mental illness or a substantial intellectual disability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If no previous examination has been made under section 16-2315 and the Division, after a factfinding but before a dispositional hearing, has reason to believe that a child has a mental illness or a substantial intellectual disability, it may order an examination as provided in section 16-2315.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If as a result of the examination the child is found to have a mental illness or a substantial intellectual disability, the Division may, in lieu of other disposition, direct the appropriate authority to initiate commitment proceedings under Chapter 5 or 11 of Title 21. The Division may order the child detained in suitable facilities pending commitment proceedings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the examination does not indicate that commitment proceedings should be initiated or if the proceedings do not result in commitment, the Division shall proceed to disposition pursuant to this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 536, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 121(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, §§ 20(c)(1), 20(c)(3), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 16-2321.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 16-2321.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> rewrote the section heading, which formerly read: “Disposition of mentally ill or substantially retarded child”; substituted “has a mental illness or a substantial intellectual disability” for “is mentally ill or substantially retarded” in (a); and substituted “have a mental illness or a substantial intellectual disability” for “be mentally ill or substantially retarded” in the first sentence of (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
