<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-2384</num>
  <heading>Motions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A motion for permanent guardianship may be filed by the proposed permanent guardian, the District of Columbia government, or by the child through his or her legal representative.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A motion for a permanent guardianship may be filed any time after a neglect petition is filed pursuant to section 16-2305.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A motion for permanent guardianship shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name, sex, date and place of birth, and current placement of the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The proposed permanent guardian’s name and relationship to the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the child’s parents;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A plain and concise statement of the facts and opinions on which the permanent guardianship is sought;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A description of the child’s mental and physical health;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A statement why permanent guardianship, rather than adoption, termination of parental rights, or return to parent, is in the child’s best interests;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A statement as to the various efforts taken by the moving party to locate the parent of the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>An itemization of the child’s assets;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>A statement of compliance with Chapter 3 of Title 21, if applicable;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The name of proposed successor guardians, if any, and their relationship to the child and proposed permanent guardians;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Information required by Chapter 45 of Title 16; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Written consents, if any, to the permanent guardianship.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>When any facts required pursuant to subsection (c) of this section are not known to the moving party, if he or she shall so state in the motion, or on a motion by any party, the court, for good cause shown, may direct the filing of a bill of particulars to inform the moving party of the precise nature of the allegations of neglect.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-273" type="History">Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-273, § 3(b), 48 DCR 1637</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-2398">16-2398</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of subchapter V, “Permanent Guardianship”, consisting of §§ <cite path="§16-2381">16-2381</cite> to 16-2399., see § 3(b) of the Foster Children’s Guardianship Temporary Act of 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-208">D.C. Law 13-208</cite>, April 4, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 3239).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of the Foster Children’s Guardianship Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-490, December 18, 2000,  48 DCR 63).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 3(c) of Foster Children’s Guardianship Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-4, February 13, 2001,  48 DCR 2254).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
