<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-4208</num>
  <heading>Mediator’s disclosure of conflicts of interest; background.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before accepting a mediation, an individual who is requested to serve as a mediator shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Make an inquiry that is reasonable under the circumstances to determine whether there are any known facts that a reasonable individual would consider likely to affect the impartiality of the mediator, including a financial or personal interest in the outcome of the mediation and an existing or past relationship with a mediation party or foreseeable participant in the mediation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Disclose any such known fact to the mediation parties as soon as is practical before accepting a mediation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a mediator learns any fact described in subsection (a)(1) of this section after accepting a mediation, the mediator shall disclose it as soon as is practicable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>At the request of a mediation party, an individual who is requested to serve as a mediator shall disclose the mediator’s qualifications to mediate a dispute.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person that violates subsection (a), (b), or (g) of this section is precluded by the violation from asserting a privilege under § <cite path="§16-4203">16-4203</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subsections (a), (b), (c), and (g) of this section do not apply to an individual acting as a judge or administrative law judge.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>This chapter does not require that a mediator have a special qualification by background or profession.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A mediator must be impartial, unless after disclosure of the facts required in subsections (a) and (b) of this section to be disclosed, the parties agree otherwise.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-87" type="History">Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-87, § 2(b), 53 DCR 1075</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 9 of the Uniform Mediation Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
