<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-4202</num>
  <heading>Scope.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) or (c) of this section, this chapter applies to a mediation in which:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The mediation parties are required to mediate by statute or court or administrative agency rule or referred to mediation by a court, administrative agency, or arbitrator;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The mediation parties and the mediator agree to mediate in a record that demonstrates an expectation that mediation communications will be privileged against disclosure; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The mediation parties use as a mediator an individual who holds himself or herself out as a mediator or the mediation is provided by a person that holds itself out as providing mediation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The chapter does not apply to a mediation:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Relating to the establishment, negotiation, administration, or termination of a collective bargaining relationship;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Relating to a dispute that is pending under or is part of the processes established by a collective bargaining agreement, except that the chapter applies to a mediation arising out of a dispute that has been filed with an administrative agency or court;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Conducted by a judge who might make a ruling on the case; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Conducted under the auspices of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A primary or secondary school, if all the mediation parties are students;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A correctional institution for youths, if all the mediation parties are residents of that institution; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia or the Mayor, if the mediation arises from a consumer complaint under authority of Chapter 39 of Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code, and one of the mediation parties is the consumer complainant.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the mediation parties agree in advance in a signed record, or a record of proceeding reflects agreement by the parties, that all or part of a mediation is not privileged, the privileges under §§ <cite path="§16-4203">16-4203</cite> through <cite path="§16-4205">16-4205</cite> shall not apply to the mediation or part agreed upon; provided, that §§ <cite path="§16-4203">16-4203</cite> through <cite path="§16-4205">16-4205</cite> shall apply to a mediation communication made by a person that has not received actual notice of the agreement before the communication is made.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-87" type="History">Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-87, § 2(b), 53 DCR 1075</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-4210">16-4210</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 3 of the Uniform Mediation Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
