<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-4602.07</num>
  <heading>Inconvenient forum.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A court of the District which has jurisdiction under this chapter to make a child-custody determination may decline to exercise its jurisdiction at any time if it determines that it is an inconvenient forum under the circumstances and that a court of another state is a more appropriate forum. The issue of inconvenient forum may be raised upon motion of a party, the court’s own motion, or request of another court.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Before determining whether it is an inconvenient forum, a court of the District shall consider whether it is appropriate for a court of another state to exercise jurisdiction. For this purpose, the court shall allow the parties to submit information and shall consider all relevant factors, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Whether domestic violence has occurred and is likely to continue in the future and which state could best protect the parties and the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The length of time the child has resided outside the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The distance between the court in the District and the court in the state that would assume jurisdiction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The relative financial circumstances of the parties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Any agreement of the parties as to which state should assume jurisdiction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The nature and location of the evidence required to resolve the pending litigation, including testimony of the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The ability of the court of each state to decide the issue expeditiously and the procedures necessary to present the evidence; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The familiarity of the court of each state with the facts and issues in the pending litigation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a court of the District determines that it is an inconvenient forum and that a court of another state is a more appropriate forum, it shall stay the proceedings upon condition that a child-custody proceeding be promptly commenced in another designated state and may impose any other condition the court considers just and proper.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A court of the District may decline to exercise its jurisdiction under this chapter if a child-custody determination is incidental to an action for divorce or another proceeding while still retaining jurisdiction over the divorce or other proceeding.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-293" type="History">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-293, § 2(d), 48 DCR 2214</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-4602.01">16-4602.01</cite>, § <cite path="§16-4602.03">16-4602.03</cite>, § <cite path="§16-4602.06">16-4602.06</cite>, and § <cite path="§16-4602.08">16-4602.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 207 of the Uniform Child Custody Jurisdiction and Enforcement Act (1997 Act).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
