<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-4802</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Alternate standby guardian” means a person with all the rights, responsibilities, and qualifications of a standby guardian who acts as the standby guardian if the current or originally designated standby guardian repudiates the designation, becomes incapacitated, or dies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Attending clinician” means a licensed physician or licensed nurse practitioner who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Has primary responsibility for the treatment and care of a designator;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Shares the responsibility for the treatment and care of a designator, or is acting on behalf of the licensed physician or licensed nurse practitioner who has primary responsibility for the treatment and care of the designator; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Is familiar with the designator’s medical condition in cases where no licensed physician or licensed nurse practitioner has the responsibility for the treatment and care of a designator.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Child” means a person under 18 years of age.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Consent” means a written authorization signed by the designator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Court” means the Domestic Relations Branch of the Family Division [Family Court] of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Debilitation” means those periods when a person cannot care for that person’s minor child as a result of a chronic condition caused by physical illness, disease, or injury from which, to a reasonable degree of probability, the designator may not recover.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Designation” means the written naming of a standby guardian by the designator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Designator” means a custodial parent, including a person other than a parent who has physical custody of a child and who has been awarded legal custody or guardianship by a court, who has been diagnosed, in writing, by a licensed clinician to suffer from a chronic condition caused by injury, disease, or illness from which, to a reasonable degree of probability, the designator may not recover.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Determination of incapacity” means a written determination made by the attending clinician that, to a reasonable degree of certainty, a designator is chronically and substantially unable to understand the nature and consequences of decisions concerning the care of a minor child as a result of a mental or organic impairment and is consequently unable to care for the minor child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Incapacity” means a chronic and substantial inability, as a result of a mental or organic impairment, to understand the nature and consequences of decisions concerning the care of a minor child, and a consequent inability to care for the minor child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Parent” means the biological parent or adoptive mother or father of a child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Standby guardian” means a person named by the designator to assume the duties of a legal custodian of a child upon the occurrence of a triggering event.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Triggering event” means any of the following 3 events:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The designator’s debilitation, with the designator’s written acknowledgement of debilitation and consent to commencement of the standby guardianship;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The designator’s incapacity as determined by an attending clinician; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The designator’s death.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-152">June 25, 2002, D.C. Law 14-152, § 2, 49 DCR 4248</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-4806">16-4806</cite> and § <cite path="§16-4810">16-4810</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
