<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-4408</num>
  <heading>Provisional remedies.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before an arbitrator is appointed and is authorized and able to act, the court, upon motion of a party to an arbitration proceeding and for good cause shown, may enter an order for provisional remedies to protect the effectiveness of the arbitration proceeding to the same extent and under the same conditions as if the controversy were the subject of a civil action.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After an arbitrator is appointed and is authorized and able to act:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The arbitrator may issue such orders for provisional remedies, including interim awards, as the arbitrator finds necessary to protect the effectiveness of the arbitration proceeding and to promote the fair and expeditious resolution of the controversy, to the same extent and under the same conditions as if the controversy were the subject of a civil action; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A party to an arbitration proceeding may move the court for a provisional remedy only if the matter is urgent and the arbitrator is not able to act timely or the arbitrator cannot provide an adequate remedy.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A party does not waive a right of arbitration by making a motion under subsection (a) or (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-111" type="History">Feb. 27, 2008, D.C. Law 17-111, § 2(b), 55 DCR 1847</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-4404">16-4404</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 8 of the Uniform Arbitration Act (2000).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
