<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-4423</num>
  <heading>Vacating award.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon motion to the court by a party to an arbitration proceeding, the court shall vacate an award made in the arbitration proceeding if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The award was procured by corruption, fraud, or other undue means;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>There was:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Evident partiality by an arbitrator appointed as a neutral arbitrator;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Corruption by an arbitrator; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Misconduct by an arbitrator prejudicing the rights of a party to the arbitration proceeding;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An arbitrator refused to postpone the hearing upon showing of sufficient cause for postponement, refused to consider evidence material to the controversy, or otherwise conducted the hearing contrary to § <cite path="§16-4415">16-4415</cite>, so as to prejudice substantially the rights of a party to the arbitration proceeding;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An arbitrator exceeded the arbitrator’s powers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>There was no agreement to arbitrate; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The arbitration was conducted without proper notice of the initiation of an arbitration as required in § <cite path="§16-4409">16-4409</cite> so as to prejudice substantially the rights of a party to the arbitration proceeding.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The court may vacate an award made in the arbitration proceeding on other reasonable ground.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A motion under this section shall be filed within 90 days after the movant receives notice of the award pursuant to § <cite path="§16-4419">16-4419</cite> or within 90 days after the movant receives notice of a modified or corrected award pursuant to § <cite path="§16-4420">16-4420</cite>, unless the movant alleges that the award was procured by corruption, fraud, or other undue means, in which case the motion shall be made within 90 days after the ground is known or by the exercise of reasonable care would have been known by the movant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the court vacates an award on a ground other than that set forth in subsection (a)(5) of this section, it may order a rehearing. If the award is vacated on a ground stated in subsection (a)(1) or (2) of this section, the rehearing shall be before a new arbitrator. If the award is vacated on a ground stated in subsection (a)(3), (4), or (6) of this section, the rehearing may be before the arbitrator who made the award or the arbitrator’s successor. The arbitrator shall render the decision in the rehearing within the same time as that provided in § <cite path="§16-4419">16-4419</cite>(b) for an award.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If the court denies a motion to vacate an award, it shall confirm the award unless a motion to modify or correct the award is pending.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-111">Feb. 27, 2008, D.C. Law 17-111, § 2(b), 55 DCR 1847</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-4404">16-4404</cite>, § <cite path="§16-4412">16-4412</cite>, § <cite path="§16-4414">16-4414</cite>, § <cite path="§16-4418">16-4418</cite>, § <cite path="§16-4420">16-4420</cite>, § <cite path="§16-4421">16-4421</cite>, § <cite path="§16-4422">16-4422</cite>, § <cite path="§16-4424">16-4424</cite>, and § <cite path="§16-4425">16-4425</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 23 of the Uniform Arbitration Act (2000).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
