<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>16-4005</num>
  <heading>Beginning and concluding collaborative law process.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A collaborative law process begins when the parties sign a collaborative law participation agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The tribunal may not order a party to participate in a collaborative law process over that party’s objection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A collaborative law process is concluded by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The resolution of a collaborative matter as evidenced by a signed record;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The resolution of a part of the collaborative matter, evidenced by a signed record, in which the parties agree that the remaining parts of the matter will not be resolved in the process; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The termination of the process.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A collaborative law process terminates:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When a party gives notice to other parties in a record that the process is ended; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When a party:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Begins a proceeding related to a collaborative matter without the agreement of all parties; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In a pending proceeding related to the matter:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Initiates a pleading, motion, order to show cause, or request for a conference with the tribunal;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Requests that the proceeding be put on the tribunal’s calendar; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Takes similar action requiring notice to be sent to the parties; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided by subsection (g) of this section, when a party discharges a collaborative lawyer or a collaborative lawyer withdraws from further representation of a party.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A party’s collaborative lawyer shall give prompt notice to all parties in a record of a discharge or withdrawal.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A party may terminate a collaborative law process with or without cause.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the discharge or withdrawal of a collaborative lawyer, a collaborative law process continues, if not later than 30 days after the date that the notice of the discharge or withdrawal of a collaborative lawyer required by subsection (e) of this section is sent to the parties:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The unrepresented party engages a successor collaborative lawyer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In a signed record:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The parties consent to continue the process by reaffirming the collaborative law participation agreement;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The agreement is amended to identify the successor collaborative lawyer; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The successor collaborative lawyer confirms the lawyer’s representation of a party in the collaborative process.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A collaborative law process does not conclude if, with the consent of the parties, a party requests the tribunal to approve a resolution of the collaborative matter or any part thereof as evidenced by a signed record.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>A collaborative law participation agreement may provide additional methods of concluding a collaborative law process.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-125" type="History">May 9, 2012, D.C. Law 19-125, § 2(b), 59 DCR 1928</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 5 of the Uniform Collaborative Law Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
