<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-4014</num>
  <heading>Appropriateness of collaborative law process.</heading>
  <text>Before a prospective party signs a collaborative law participation agreement, a prospective collaborative lawyer shall:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Assess with the prospective party factors the lawyer reasonably believes relate to whether a collaborative law process is appropriate for the prospective party’s matter;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Provide the prospective party with information that the lawyer reasonably believes is sufficient for the party to make an informed decision about the material benefits and risks of a collaborative law process as compared to the material benefits and risks of other reasonably available alternatives for resolving the proposed collaborative matter, such as litigation, mediation, arbitration, or expert evaluation; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Advise the prospective party that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>If, after signing an agreement, a party initiates a proceeding or seeks intervention by the tribunal in a pending proceeding related to the collaborative matter, the collaborative law process terminates;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Participation in a collaborative law process is voluntary and any party has the right to terminate unilaterally a collaborative law process with or without cause; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The collaborative lawyer and any lawyer in a law firm with which the collaborative lawyer is associated may not appear before the tribunal to represent a party in a proceeding related to the collaborative matter, except as authorized by § <cite path="§16-4009">16-4009</cite>(c), § <cite path="§16-4010">16-4010</cite>(b), or § <cite path="§16-4011">16-4011</cite>(b).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-125" type="History">May 9, 2012, D.C. Law 19-125, § 2(b), 59 DCR 1928</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-4020">16-4020</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 14 of the Uniform Collaborative Law Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
