<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-4414</num>
  <heading>Immunity of arbitrator; competency to testify; attorney’s fees and costs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An arbitrator is immune from civil liability to the same extent as a judge of a court of the District of Columbia acting in a judicial capacity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The immunity afforded by this section supplements any immunity under other law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The failure of an arbitrator to make a disclosure required by § <cite path="§16-4412">16-4412</cite> does not cause any loss of immunity under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In a judicial, administrative, or similar proceeding, an arbitrator is not competent to testify, and may not be required to produce records as to any statement, conduct, decision, or ruling occurring during the arbitration proceeding, to the same extent as a judge of a court of the District of Columbia acting in a judicial capacity. This subsection does not apply:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To the extent necessary to determine the claim of an arbitrator against a party to the arbitration proceeding; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To a hearing on a motion to vacate an award under § <cite path="§16-4423">16-4423</cite>(a)(1) or (2) if the movant establishes prima facie that a ground for vacating the award exists.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a person commences a civil action against an arbitrator arising from the services of the arbitrator or if a person seeks to compel an arbitrator to testify or produce records in violation of subsection (d) of this section, and the court decides that the arbitrator is immune from civil liability or that the arbitrator is not competent to testify, the court shall award to the arbitrator reasonable attorney’s fees and other reasonable expenses of litigation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-111" type="History">Feb. 27, 2008, D.C. Law 17-111, § 2(b), 55 DCR 1847</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-4404">16-4404</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 14 of the Uniform Arbitration Act (2000).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
