<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-831.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“De facto parent” means an individual:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Lived with the child in the same household at the time of the child’s birth or adoption by the child’s parent;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Has taken on full and permanent responsibilities as the child’s parent; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Has held himself or herself out as the child’s parent with the agreement of the child’s parent or, if there are 2 parents, both parents; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Has lived with the child in the same household for at least 10 of the 12 months immediately preceding the filing of the complaint or motion for custody;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Has formed a strong emotional bond with the child with the encouragement and intent of the child’s parent that a parent-child relationship form between the child and the third party;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Has taken on full and permanent responsibilities as the child’s parent; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>Has held himself or herself out as the child’s parent with the agreement of the child’s parent, or if there are 2 parents, both parents.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Intrafamily offense” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§16-1001">16-1001</cite>(8).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Legal custody” means legal responsibility for a child, including the right to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Make decisions regarding the child’s health, education, and general welfare;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Access the child’s educational, medical, psychological, dental, or other records; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Speak with and obtain information regarding the child from school officials, health care providers, counselors, or other persons interacting with the child.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Physical custody” means a child’s living arrangements. The term “physical custody” includes a child’s residency or visitation schedule.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Third party” means a person other than the child’s parent or de facto parent.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-21" type="History">Sept. 20, 2007, D.C. Law 17-21, § 2(b), 54 DCR 6835</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 217(b), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-368" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-368, § 4(f), 56 DCR 1338</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in the section designation.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-368">D.C. Law 17-368</cite>, in par. (2), substituted “§ <cite path="§16-1001">16-1001</cite>(8)” for “§ <cite path="§16-1001">16-1001</cite>(5)”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of Safe and Stable Homes for Children and Youth Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-69, July 9, 2007,  54 DCR 6826).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
