<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1521</num>
  <heading>Consumer disclosure requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An entity selling or reselling an interest in a community renewable energy facility shall provide a disclosure to the potential subscriber that includes the following, prior to the sale or resale of that subscription:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A good faith estimate of the annual kilowatt hours to be delivered by the community renewable energy facility based on the size of the subscriber’s interest;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A plain language explanation of the terms under which the bill credits will be calculated;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A plain language explanation of the contract provisions regulating the disposition or transfer of the subscription; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A plain language explanation of the costs and benefits to the potential subscriber based on the subscriber’s current usage and applicable tariff, for the term of the proposed contract.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor or his or her designee may require that any entity engaged in the sale or resale of a subscription in a community renewable energy facility provide additional disclosure to the buyer or lessee, the Mayor, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All contracts for the sale or resale of a subscription in a community renewable energy facility for use in a residential dwelling may be reviewed by the Mayor or his or her designee upon request.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor pursuant to <cite path="2|5|1" proof="true">subchapter 1 of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite> [<cite path="§2-501">§ 2-501</cite> et seq.], may issue rules to carry out the disclosure requirements contained in this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-107" type="History" path="§121">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, § 121</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-47" type="History">as added Dec. 13, 2013, D.C. Law 20-47, § 2(e), 60 DCR 15138</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-47">D.C. Law 20-47</cite> added this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
