<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1511</num>
  <heading>Recovery for public purpose programs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The electric company may make an application to the Commission to recover all costs that have been or will be incurred by the electric company under public purpose programs established by law or ordered by the Commission, including the consumer education program established under <cite path="§34-1504">§ 34-1504</cite>. To the extent the costs are determined by the Commission to be just and reasonable, the Commission shall allow the electric company to recover the costs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In determining whether an electric company should be permitted to recover costs described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission shall ensure that such costs:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Have not been or will not be recovered through rates charged by the electric company;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Have not been or will not be recovered through the sale of any or all of the electric company’s generation assets; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Have not or will not be recovered through a competitive transition charge imposed under <cite path="§34-1510">§ 34-1510</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All costs recoverable under this section may be recovered through a surcharge or other appropriate cost recovery mechanism to be determined by the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-107" type="History" path="§111">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, § 111, 47 DCR 1091</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§34-1509">§ 34-1509</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
