<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-2401.18</num>
  <heading>“Mayor,” “District of Columbia water system” defined.</heading>
  <text>As used in <cite path="§34-2401.17">§ 34-2401.17</cite>, unless the context otherwise requires:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“District of Columbia water system” or “water system” means any and all of the facilities used or to be used for the supply of raw or partly purified water wherever situated and all of the facilities used or to be used for the distribution of purified water situated within the District of Columbia which are operated by the Department of Environmental Services or the Washington Aqueduct Division of the Washington District of the Corps of Engineers, Department of the Army, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 81-2-ch218" path="§1">June 2, 1950, 64 Stat. 195, ch. 218, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">The functions of the Department of Environmental Services were transferred to the Department of Public Works by Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1983, effective March 1, 1984.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 43-1540, referred to in the introductory language of this section, was repealed by the Act of December 24, 1974, 87 Stat. 832, Pub. L. 93-198, § 243(b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-1539.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-1551.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
