<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-802</num>
  <heading>Quorum; investigations; rules and regulations.</heading>
  <text>A majority of the commissioners shall constitute a quorum to do business, and any vacancy shall not impair the right of the remaining commissioners to exercise all the powers of the Commission. Any investigation, inquiry, or hearing within the powers of the Commission may be made or held by any commissioner, whose acts and orders, when approved by the Commission, shall be deemed to be the order of the Commission. The Commission shall have power to adopt and publish rules and regulations for the administration of the provisions of this subtitle, including the conduct of its investigations, inquiries, hearings, and other proceedings.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 62-3-ch150" path="§8|97|(b)">Mar. 4, 1913, 37 Stat. 995, ch. 150, § 8, par. 97(b)</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Dec. 15, 1926, 44 Stat. 921, ch. 8, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">Editor’s Note Section 2 of An Act to alter the personnel of the Public Utilities Commission of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, 44 Stat. 921 former <cite path="§43-404" proof="true">§ 43-404</cite>, 1981 Ed., provided that this section not be construed to invalidate certain acts of the prior Commission including those relating to orders or rules, complaints, inquiries or hearings, actions or proceedings.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-202.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-403.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§34-1314.02">§ 34-1314.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Utility service, valuation and accounts, Commission oversight of individual rates and dividends, see <cite path="§34-1117">§ 34-1117</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Street railways and bus lines, generally, see <cite path="§35-201">§ 35-201</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Rules and regulations, power of Commission to adopt, see <cite path="§34-902">§ 34-902</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public utility accidents, reporting and investigations, see <cite path="§34-401">§ 34-401</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Measurement standards, rules and regulations, <cite path="§34-1120">§ 34-1120</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mayor, council and other officers, police power regulations, see <cite path="§1-303.03">§ 1-303.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Gas and electric meters, inspections, rules and regulations, see <cite path="§34-303">§ 34-303</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Depreciation accounts, see <cite path="§34-1115">§ 34-1115</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Construction oversight and accounts, see <cite path="§34-1116">§ 34-1116</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
