<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-205.51a</num>
  <heading>TANF Universal Service Delivery Model.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By no later than September 30, 2011, the Mayor shall have adopted and fully implemented the TANF Universal Service Delivery Model, as created by the Department of Human Services, which shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Address customer needs based on personal and family circumstances, to the extent feasible;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Require orientation and a detailed assessment and referral to an appropriate array of services and supports, which shall be provided through:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Contract job placement;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Education and training vendors, and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>District agencies;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Emphasize education, training, and skills enhancement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Assist customers in addressing and overcoming challenges that are barriers to employment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Include financial disincentives to customers who without good cause remain unemployed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Provide for participation with the TEP program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Provide for an Individual Responsibility Plan for each customer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Include a system of sanctions for a customer who fails to participate or complete an Individual Responsibility Plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A nonexempt customer who fails to participate or complete an Individual Responsibility Plan shall be subject to a progressive, graduated sanction policy, as established by the Department of Human Services. Each level of sanctions shall reduce further the maximum grant a customer will be eligible to receive.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit a draft plan of the TANF Universal Service Delivery Model to the Council for its review by March 1, 2011.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, ยง 551a</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370">as added Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, ยง 522(e), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Former ยง <cite root="4-205.51a">4-205.51a</cite> has been recodified as ยง <cite root="4-205.51b">4-205.51b</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
