<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-205.55</num>
  <heading>Timely and adequate notice of action to discontinue, etc., assistance.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall give timely and adequate notice in cases of intended action to discontinue, withhold, terminate, suspend, reduce assistance, or make assistance subject to additional conditions, or to change the manner or form of payment to a protective, vendor, or 2-party payment.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Timely” means that the notice is postmarked at least 15 days before the date upon which the action would become effective, except as provided in § <cite root="4-205.54">4-205.54</cite>(d).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Adequate” means that the written notice includes a statement of what action the Mayor intends to take, the reasons for the intended action, the specific law and regulations supporting the action, an explanation of the individual’s right to request a hearing, and the circumstances under which assistance will be continued if a hearing is requested.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may dispense with timely notice, but shall send adequate notice no later than the date upon which the action would become effective when:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor has factual information confirming the death of a recipient or of the TANF or POWER payee when there is no relative available to serve as new payee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor receives a clear written statement signed by a recipient that states that he or she no longer wishes assistance, or that gives information that requires termination or reduction of assistance, and the recipient has indicated, in writing, that he or she understands the consequence of supplying this information;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The recipient’s whereabouts are unknown and mail sent to him or her has been returned by the post office indicating no known forwarding address. (If the recipient’s whereabouts become known during the payment period covered by a returned check, the recipient’s check shall be made available to him or her by the Mayor.);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The recipient has been accepted for assistance in a new jurisdiction and that fact has been previously established by the Mayor; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A special allowance granted for a specific period is terminated and the recipient had been informed in writing at the time the allowance was granted that the allowance shall automatically terminate at the end of the specified period.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>When changes in District of Columbia law require automatic grant adjustments for classes of recipients, timely notice of these grant adjustments shall be given, which shall be deemed “adequate” if it includes a statement of the intended action, the reasons for the intended action, a statement of the specific change in law requiring the action, and a statement of the circumstances under which a hearing may be obtained and assistance continued.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 555, 29 DCR 1060</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-35">Sept. 10, 1985, D.C. Law 6-35, § 2(j), 32 DCR 3778</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-241">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 2(tt), 46 DCR 905</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="4-205.54">4-205.54</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 3-205.55.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(x) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-7">D.C. Law 12-7</cite>, August 1, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 4639).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(x) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-130">D.C. Law 12-130</cite>, July 24, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 6501).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(mm) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-230">D.C. Law 12-230</cite>, April 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 4143).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-25, February 27, 1997,  44 DCR 1778), and § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-77, May 27, 1997,  44 DCR 3181).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Notice Requirement Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-44, March 31, 1997,  44 DCR 2096).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-306, March 20, 1998,  45 DCR 1900).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(tt), § 2(tt) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-372, June 9, 1998,  45 DCR 4270), of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-425, July 31, 1998,  45 DCR 5682), § 2(tt) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-552, December 24, 1998,  46 DCR 521), and § 2(tt) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-19, February 17, 1999,  46 DCR 2492).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
