<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-107</num>
  <heading>Institutional personnel under supervision of Board; duties of superintendent; appointment and discharge of personnel.</heading>
  <text>The superintendents and all other employees engaged in the operation of the institutions enumerated in § <cite path="§4-106">4-106</cite> shall be subject to the supervision of the Board. Each superintendent shall have the management and control of the institution to which he is appointed and shall be subordinate to the Director of Public Welfare. The superintendent and all other employees of each of the institutions enumerated in § <cite path="§4-106">4-106</cite> shall be appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia upon nomination by the Board and shall be subject to discharge by the Mayor upon recommendation of the Board.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 16, 1926, 44 Stat. 209, ch. 58, § 7</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Superintendents of prisons, see § <cite path="§24-201.11">24-201.11</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-107.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 3-107.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Board of Public Welfare abolished: See note to § <cite path="§4-102">4-102</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
