<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-112</num>
  <heading>Submission of plans for new institutions; investigation of institutions.</heading>
  <text>All plans for new institutions shall, before adoption of the same, be submitted to the Board of Public Welfare for suggestion and criticism. The Mayor of the District of Columbia may at any time order an investigation by the Board, or a committee of its members, of the management of any penal, charitable, or reformatory institution in the District of Columbia; and said Board, or any authorized committee of its members, when making such investigation, shall have power to send for persons and papers and to administer oaths and affirmations; and the report of such investigation, with the testimony, shall be made to the Mayor.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 6, 1900, 31 Stat. 664, ch. 807</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 16, 1926, 44 Stat. 210, ch. 58, § 10</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-112.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 3-112.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Board of Public Welfare abolished: See note to § <cite path="§4-102">4-102</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
