<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-110</num>
  <heading>Powers of Board of Charities transferred.</heading>
  <text>The following powers and duties prior to March 16, 1926, imposed by law upon the Board of Charities shall be vested in the Board, and the unexpended balance of all appropriations made for the purpose of discharging such powers and duties shall become available to the Board:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>To provide for the transportation to their respective places of residence of nonresident indigent persons, and to provide for indigent persons, who are legal residents of the District of Columbia, medical care and treatment when necessary, under contracts with such hospitals as are or may be designated by law;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>To provide for the transportation to their respective places of residence of nonresident persons with mental illness and to afford hospital care for indigent persons with mental illness who are legal residents of the District of Columbia in such hospital or hospitals as are or may be designated by law; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>To provide for all other aged, infirm, or needy persons, in the manner authorized by law or by appropriations enacted by the Congress.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 16, 1926, 44 Stat. 210, ch. 58, § 10</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-87" type="History">Oct. 1, 1976, D.C. Law 1-87, § 5, 23 DCR 2544</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 15, 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mentally ill, financial responsibility for care of hospitalized persons, see § <cite path="§21-586">21-586</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mentally ill, nonresidents, see § <cite path="§21-551">21-551</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-110.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 3-110.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite> substituted “persons with mental illness” for “insane persons”, throughout the section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Board of Public Welfare abolished: See note to § <cite path="§4-102">4-102</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
