<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-125</num>
  <heading>Assisting child to leave institution without authority; concealing such child; duty of police.</heading>
  <text>Any person who shall entice or attempt to entice, away from any home or institution, any child legally committed to the Board of Public Welfare and placed by said Board in such home or institution, or any person who shall assist or attempt to assist any such child to leave without permission such home or institution, knowing such child to be an inmate of such institution or to have been placed in such home, or any person who shall harbor, conceal, or aid in harboring or concealing any such child who shall be absent without leave from a home or institution in which he has been placed by the Board of Public Welfare, shall, upon conviction thereof, be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and shall pay a fine of not less than $10 nor more than $100; and any policeman shall have power, and it is hereby made his duty, to take into custody any child, when in his power to do so, who shall be absent without leave from a home or institution in which he has been placed and return him thereto or to the Receiving Home.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 77-2-ch649" path="§2">Jan. 12, 1942, 55 Stat. 883, ch. 649, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Age of majority, see § <cite path="§46-101">46-101</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-126.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 3-127.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5039 of Fiscal Year 2009 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-468, July 28, 2008,  55 DCR 8746).</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Board of Public Welfare abolished: See note to § <cite path="§4-102">4-102</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
