<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1302.02</num>
  <heading>Information to be retained.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There shall be retained in the Child Protection Register the following information concerning each substantiated and inconclusive report:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The recipient of the report, the date and the time of the receipt of the report;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The information required in the report pursuant to <cite path="§4-1321.03">§ 4-1321.03</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The census tract and ward in which the child lives and other demographic information concerning the incident referred to in the report;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The agencies to which the report was referred and the date and the time of the referral;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The agency or agencies making the initial investigation, the summary of the results of the initial investigation and the dates and the times the investigations were begun and terminated;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The agency or agencies making the social investigation, the summary of the results of the social investigation, the dates and the times said investigation was begun and terminated, the services offered and when they were offered;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The agency or agencies to which the referrals were made and the services requested, with the dates of the opening and the closing of the case;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The placements of the child and the dates of each placement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Court actions concerning the child and the dates thereof; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The date the case was closed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>There may be retained in the Child Protection Register other information required for research, planning, evaluation and management purposes pursuant to rules adopted according to <cite path="§2-501">§ 2-501</cite> et seq.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The staff which maintains the Child Protection Register shall review all open cases every 6 months to assure that information in said Register is current and shall request updated information from the appropriate agencies as indicated.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The public agencies responsible for receiving reports, making investigations and providing or securing case management shall be responsible for supplying the information required under this section to the Child Protection Register on a timely basis.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22" type="History" path="§202">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title II, § 202, 24 DCR 3341</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-206" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-206, § 2(h), 49 DCR 7815</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 14-206: Section 16(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-310">D.C. Law 14-310</cite> provided that section 2(a)(2), (4), (5), (6), and (7), (b), (c), (d), (e), (h), (i), (j), (k), and (l) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-206">D.C. Law 14-206</cite> shall apply as of October 1, 2003.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) delay of the applicability of provisions changing the manner in which the Child and Family Services Agency will process reports of child abuse and neglect, see § 3 of Improved Child Abuse Investigations Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-603, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 687).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) delay of the applicability of provisions changing the manner in which the Child and Family Services Agency will process reports of child abuse and neglect, see § 3 of Improved Child Abuse Investigations Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-494, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 9781).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Improved Child Abuse Investigations Technical Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-240">D.C. Law 14-240</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2753).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-206">D.C. Law 14-206</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “concerning each substantiated and inconclusive report:” for “concerning each supported report:”; and repealed subsec. (c). Prior to repeal, subsec. (c) had read as follows: “(c) Information in an unsupported report shall be retained in a separate index in which all information that could identify any person referred to in the unsupported report shall be destroyed.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2112.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2112.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§4-1302.01">§ 4-1302.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
