<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1303.06</num>
  <heading>Confidentiality of records and information.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Information acquired by staff of the Child and Family Services Agency that identifies individual children reported as or found to be abused or neglected or which identifies other members of their families or other persons shall be considered confidential and may be released or divulged only for:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Purposes relating to the identification of abuse or neglect;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The identification of service needs or resources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The securing or provision of treatment or direct services for the child or individual identified;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The investigation or review of child fatalities by representatives of the Child Fatality Review Committee, established pursuant to § <cite path="§4-1371.03">4-1371.03</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of and in accordance with Chapter 2A of Title 7 [§ <cite path="§7-241">7-241</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Persons or agencies who are not covered by confidentiality requirements comparable to those in subsection (a) of this section, to whom information is released pursuant to this section, § <cite path="§4-1302.03">4-1302.03</cite>, or § <cite path="§4-1302.04">4-1302.04</cite> must sign a statement that they will not divulge such confidential information for purposes unrelated to the purposes of treatment, identification or evaluation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22" type="History" path="§306">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title III, § 306</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-29" type="History">as added Oct. 18, 1979, D.C. Law 3-29, § 2, 26 DCR 678</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-136" type="History">June 27, 2000, D.C. Law 13-136, § 201(e), 47 DCR 2850</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4618, 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-69" type="History">Feb. 13, 2002, D.C. Law 14-69, § 2(a), 48 DCR 11072</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-273" type="History">Dec. 4, 2010, D.C. Law 18-273, § 202, 57 DCR 7171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1303.35">4-1303.35</cite>, § <cite path="§4-1371.06">4-1371.06</cite>, and § <cite path="§16-1054">16-1054</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2126.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2136.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-136">D.C. Law 13-136</cite> added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite>, in subsec. (a), inserted “or the investigation or review of child fatalities by representatives of the Child Fatality Review Committee, established pursuant to § <cite path="§4-1317.03">4-1317.03</cite>”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-69">D.C. Law 14-69</cite> repealed subsec. (c) which had read:.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor or the Director of the designated Child and Family Services Agency may disclose to the public the findings or information about a case of child abuse or neglect which has resulted in a child’s fatality or near fatality. Nothing may be disclosed that would likely endanger the life, safety, or physical or emotional well-being of a child or the life or safety of any other person or which may compromise the integrity of a Mayor’s investigation or a civil or criminal investigation or judicial proceeding. If the Mayor denies access to specific information on this basis, the requesting entity may seek disclosure of the information through the Superior Court. The name or any other information identifying the person or entity who referred the child to the Department of Human Services shall not be released to the public.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-273">D.C. Law 18-273</cite> rewrote subsec. (a), which had read as follows: “(a) Information acquired by staff of the Social Rehabilitation Administration of the Department of Human Services which identifies individual children reported as or found to be abused or neglected or which identifies other members of their families or other persons or other individuals shall be considered confidential and may be released or divulged only for purposes relating to the identification of abuse or neglect, the identification of service needs or resources, the securing or provision of treatment or direct services for the child or individual identified, or the investigation or review of child fatalities by representatives of the Child Fatality Review Committee, established pursuant to § <cite path="§4-1371.03">4-1371.03</cite>.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 18 of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-20">D.C. Law 14-20</cite>, September 6, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 9090).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Temporary Repeal of Section For temporary (225 day) repeal of section, see § 2(a) of Public Disclosure of Findings and Information in Cases of Child Fatality or Near Fatality Temporary Amendment Act of 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-215">D.C. Law 13-215</cite>, April 3, 2001, law notification  38 DCR 3457).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Public Disclosure of Findings and Information in Cases of Child Fatality or Near Fatality Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-428, August 14, 2000,  47 DCR 7451).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section, see § 2(a) of the Public Disclosure of Findings and Information in Cases of Child Fatality or Near Fatality Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-491, December 18, 2000,  48 DCR 57).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Public Disclosure of Findings and Information in Cases of Child Fatality or Near Fatality Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-6, February 13, 2001,  48 DCR 2479).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 18 of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-40, April 25, 2001,  48 DCR 5917).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 18 of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-82, July 9, 2001,  48 DCR 6355).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Public Disclosure of Findings and Information in Cases of Child Fatality or Near Fatality Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-191, November 29, 2001,  48 DCR 11233).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Public Disclosure of Findings and Information in Cases of Child Fatality or Near Fatality Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-286, February 25, 2002,  49 DCR 2317).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 202 of Data-Sharing and Information Coordination Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-530, August 6, 2010,  57 DCR 8099).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 202 of Data-Sharing and Information Coordination Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-582, October 20, 2010,  57 DCR 10118).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
