<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1303.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment and purposes.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22" type="History" path="§301">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title III, § 301, 24 DCR 3341</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-227" type="History">Mar. 16, 1995, D.C. Law 10-227, § 2(b), 42 DCR 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-277" type="History">Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-277, § 2(k), 48 DCR 2043</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1301.02">4-1301.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2121.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2131.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) enactments, see §§ 5192, 5193 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-477, August 8, 2006,  53 DCR 7068).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) enactments, see §§ 5192, 5193 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-499, October 23, 2006,  53 DCR 8845).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) enactments, see §§ 5192, 5193 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-1, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1165).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 5192 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</cite> provided that subtitle M of title V of the act may be cited as the “Assessment of District Programs to Prevent Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 2006”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to title XXIII (Section 2352(a)) of Public Law 97-35, the “Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act, to Deliver Social Services Block Grant Funded Homemaker Services for Individuals and Families who are in Need of or Receiving Protective Services”, see Mayor’s Order 97-101, May 28, 1997 ( 44 DCR 3529).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Sections 5192 and 5193 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 5192. Definitions.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“For the purposes of this subtitle, the term:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) ‘Primary prevention’ means activities and services provided to families that are designed to prevent or reduce the prevalence of child abuse and neglect before signs of abuse or neglect may be present.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) ‘Secondary prevention’ means activities and services provided to persons identified by etiological studies because of their propensity to abuse or neglect children in their care. Secondary prevention strategies target children who are identified as being at risk of abuse or neglect and are designed to intervene at the earliest warning signs of abuse or neglect.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 5193. Status of abuse and neglect prevention programs.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) The Mayor shall convene a working group to assess child abuse and neglect prevention programs in the District. The working group shall:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) Take an inventory of all current public and private programs for the prevention of child abuse and neglect, including:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(A) All primary prevention programs servicing the District;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(B) All secondary prevention programs servicing the District;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(C) All sources of local, federal, and private funding for each program; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(D) A determination of whether each program’s services are evaluated for effectiveness; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) Perform a gap analysis to identify where these programs are:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(A) Meeting, or failing to meet, the primary prevention needs of the District;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(B) Meeting, or failing to meet, the secondary prevention needs of the District; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(C) Duplicating services identified in the inventory.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The inventory and gap analysis shall be completed, submitted to the Council, and made available to the public no later than December 31, 2006.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">For applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-277">D.C. Law 13-277</cite>, see note following § <cite path="§4-1303.01a">4-1303.01a</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
