<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-1302.01</num>
  <heading>Duties and responsibilities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is hereby established a Child Protection Register to be maintained by the Agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The purposes of the Register are to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Maintain, in print or in a database, a confidential index of cases of abused and neglected children;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Assist in the identification and treatment of abused and neglected children and their families; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Serve as a resource for the evaluation, management, and planning of programs and services for abused and neglected children.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The staff of the Agency assigned to maintain the Child Protection Register shall maintain 24-hour, 7 day-a-week telephone lines which may be combined with the 24-hour intake components described part C of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Said staff shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Receive reports and information necessary for the operation of the Child Protection Register and make appropriate entries in such Register as required by § <cite path="§4-1302.02">4-1302.02</cite>(a); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Release information contained in the Child Protection Register in a manner consistent with this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit a report to the Council on the Agency’s plan for implementation of the provisions of this part, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-206">D.C. Law 14-206</cite>, no later than January 31, 2003.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title II, § 201, 24 DCR 3341</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-206">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-206, § 2(g), 49 DCR 7815</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1301.02">4-1301.02</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-2111.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 6-2111.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-206">D.C. Law 14-206</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “Agency” for “Division”; in subsec. (b)(1), substituted “Maintain, in print or in a database,” for “Maintain”; in subsec. (c), substituted “Agency” for “Department of Human Services”; and added subsec. (e).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-206">D.C. Law 14-206</cite>, referred to in subsec. (e), is the Improved Child Abuse Investigations Amendment Act of 2002, Oct. 19, 2002,  49 DCR 7815.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
