<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-1303.02a</num>
  <heading>Organization and authority of Child and Family Services Agency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Agency shall be administered by a full-time Director appointed by the Mayor and confirmed by the Council. The Director shall be qualified by experience and training to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director shall report directly to the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Director shall be responsible for all child and family services provided by the Agency, and for monitoring child and family services provided by contract or compact with the Agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Agency shall have sufficient staff, supervisory personnel, and resources to accomplish the purposes of this subchapter, including the capacity to provide emergency and continuing service resources to the children and families covered by this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Staff qualifications, caseload levels, and supervision requirements of the Agency in the public and private delivery of services shall be guided by nationally accepted standards of best practice, such as those developed by the Child Welfare League of America, and shall be published in the District of Columbia Register for public comment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Agency shall be the successor in interest to the Child and Family Services Agency under receivership in the case of LaShawn A., et al. v. Anthony Williams, et al., C. A. No. 89-1754 (TFH), in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia. All real and personal property, Career Service and Management Supervisory Service positions, assets, records, and obligations, and all unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, operations, and administration of the Child and Family Services Agency under receivership in LaShawn A., et al. v. Anthony Williams, et al., shall become the property of the Agency on the date of termination of the receivership. The provisions of this subchapter are intended to be consistent with all outstanding orders of the United States District Court in the LaShawn A, et al. v. Anthony Williams, et al., case.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>All real and personal property, positions, assets, records, and obligations, and all unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, and operations of the Department of Human Services as the “appropriate authority,” under § <cite path="§4-1421">4-1421</cite> for children who have been abused or neglected, shall become the property of the Agency by October 1, 2001.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>All real and personal property, positions, assets, records, and obligations, and all unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, and operations of the Department of Health in regulating child placement agencies and foster and group homes for children who have been abused or neglected shall be transferred to the Agency by October 1, 2001.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>All records and agreed-upon positions, obligations, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions and operations of the Social Services Division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia concerning children who have been abused or neglected shall, subject to any approvals required of the United States Congress, be transferred to the Agency in accordance with the terms and conditions provided in any memorandum of understanding between the Mayor and the Chief Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. This transfer shall be completed on or before October 1, 2001, if possible.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>Expired.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22" type="History">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title III, § 302a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-277" type="History">as added Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-277, § 2(n), 48 DCR 2043</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-94" type="History">Mar. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-94, § 2, 49 DCR 658</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-94">D.C. Law 14-94</cite> added subsec. (j).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Child and Family Services Agency Licensure Exemption of Certain Court Personnel Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-150, October 23, 2001,  48 DCR 10200).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Child and Family Services Agency Licensure Exemption of Certain Court Personnel Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-239, January 28, 2002,  49 DCR 1022).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Pursuant to its own terms, subsec. (j) expired on October 1, 2004.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">For applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-277">D.C. Law 13-277</cite>, see note following § <cite path="§4-1303.01a">4-1303.01a</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7038 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> repealed section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-94">D.C. Law 14-94</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
