<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-1301.06</num>
  <heading>Investigation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The full investigation shall be completed no more than 30 days after the receipt of the first notice of the suspected abuse or neglect.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The investigation shall determine:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The nature, extent, and cause of the abuse or neglect, if any;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If mental injury, as defined in § <cite path="§16-2301">16-2301</cite>(31), is suspected, an assessment of the suspected mental injury by a physician, a psychologist, or a licensed clinical social worker;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the suspected abuse or neglect is determined to be substantiated:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The identity of the person responsible for the abuse or neglect;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The name, age, sex, and condition of the abused or neglected child and all other children in the home;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The conditions in the home at the time of the alleged abuse or neglect;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Whether there is any child in the home whose health, safety, or welfare is at risk; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Whether any child who is at risk should be removed from the home or can be protected by the provision of resources, such as those listed in §§ <cite path="§4-1303.03">4-1303.03</cite> and <cite path="§4-1303.03a">4-1303.03a</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 5 business days after the completion of the investigation, the Agency shall complete a final report of its findings.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Agency shall provide a copy of a report regarding suspected abuse or neglect that addresses possible criminal activity to the Metropolitan Police Department, the Office of the Attorney General, and the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the Agency determines that a report was made in bad faith, the Agency shall refer the report to the Office of the Attorney General, which shall determine whether prosecution of the person making the report in bad faith is warranted.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be read as abrogating the responsibility of the Metropolitan Police Department for criminal investigations.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22" type="History">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title I, § 106, 24 DCR 3341</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-277" type="History">Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-277, § 2(d), 48 DCR 2043</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-341" type="History">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-341,§ 2(c), 52 DCR 2315</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1301.06a">4-1301.06a</cite>, § <cite path="§4-1303.03">4-1303.03</cite>, and § <cite path="§16-2353">16-2353</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2104.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2104.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-277">D.C. Law 13-277</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “with the Agency” for “with the Division” and substituted “either the Agency” for “either the department of Human Services”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-341">D.C. Law 15-341</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">For applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-277">D.C. Law 13-277</cite>, see note following § <cite path="§4-1303.01a">4-1303.01a</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
