<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1303.53</num>
  <heading>Panel procedures; meetings; staff support.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A quorum shall consist of 8 members and the Panel shall develop written bylaws, with the approval of a majority of Panel members, to establish other procedural requirements it considers necessary, including the designation of additional officers.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Panel may establish such committees as it considers necessary, according to rules set forth in the bylaws.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Panel may establish written protocols to guide its work in evaluating the policies, practices, procedures, and performance of the child welfare system.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Panel shall meet not less than once every 3 months, in appropriate meeting space provided by the Agency, at no cost.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Panel meetings shall be open to the public, except that the Panel shall meet in closed session when it is reviewing specific child cases.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any resolution, rule, act, regulation, or other official action is effective only if it is taken, made, or enacted at an open meeting as defined in ยง <cite path="ยง1-207.42">1-207.42</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Panel shall receive staff support from one or more employees of the Agency, as designated by the Director of the Agency.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Agency shall include in its annual performance-based budget submission to the Mayor and Council, beginning in Fiscal Year 2007, an activity-level line item for the Panel, which will include personal services and non-personal services funding.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22" type="History">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title IIIB, ยง 353</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-341" type="History">as added Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-341, ยง 2(m), 52 DCR 2315</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
