<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1362</num>
  <heading>Contracting with private service providers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Private contracts. —</heading>
    <text>Not later than September 30, 1999, CFSA shall enter into contracts with private service providers to perform some of the adoption recruitment and placement functions of CFSA, which may include recruitment, homestudy, and placement services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Competitive bidding. —</heading>
    <text>Any contract entered into pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to a competitive bidding process when required by CFSA contracting policies and procedures.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Performance-based compensation. —</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <heading>In general. —</heading>
      <text>Any contract entered into pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall compensate the winning bidder pursuant to subsection (b) of this section upon completion of contract deliverables.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <heading>Contract deliverables. —</heading>
      <text>In identifying contract deliverables, CFSA shall consider:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of recruitment, receipt of a list of potential adoptive families;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of homestudies, receipt of a completed home-study in a form specified in advance by CFSA; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>In the case of placements, the child is placed in an adoptive home approved by CFSA or the adoption is finalized.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <heading>Types of contracts. —</heading>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent CFSA from entering into contracts that provide for multiple deliverables or conditions for partial payment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <heading>Removal of barriers to adoption. —</heading>
    <text>CFSA shall meet with contractors to address issues identified during the term of a contract entered into pursuant to this subchapter, including issues related to barriers to timely adoptions.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 105-277" type="History" path="§157|(c)">Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681-146, Pub. L. 105-277, § 157(c)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2142.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
