<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1301.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Abused”, when used in reference to a child, shall have the same meaning as is provided in <cite path="§16-2301|(23)">§ 16-2301(23)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Adoption promotion and support services” means services and activities designed to encourage more adoptions of committed children, when such adoptions promote the best interest of the children, including such activities as pre-and post-adoptive services and activities designed to expedite the adoption process and support adoptive families.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2A)</num>
    <text>Except where used in title IV of this act, “Agency” means the Child and Family Services Agency established by <cite path="§4-1303.01a">§ 4-1303.01a</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2A-i)</num>
    <text>“Behavioral health” means a person’s overall social, emotional, and psychological well-being and development.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2A-ii)</num>
    <text>“Behavioral health assessment” means a more thorough and comprehensive examination by a mental health professional of all behavioral health issues and needs identified during an initial behavioral health screening by which the mental health professional shall identify the type and extent of the behavioral health problem and make recommendations for treatment interventions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2A-iii)</num>
    <text>“Behavioral health screening” means a brief process designed to identify youth who are at risk of having behavioral health disorders that warrant immediate attention, or intervention, or to identify the need for further assessment with a more comprehensive examination.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2B)</num>
    <text>“CAC” means Safe Shores, the District of Columbia’s Children’s Advocacy Center.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Case plan” means a written document concerning a child that includes at least the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A description of the type of home or institution in which the child is to be placed, including a discussion of the safety and appropriateness of the placement and how the agency that is responsible for the child plans to carry out the voluntary placement agreement or judicial determination made with respect to the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A plan for assuring that the child receives safe and proper care and that services are available to the parents, child, and foster parents in order to improve conditions in the parents’ home, facilitate return of the child to his or her own safe home or to the child’s permanent placement, and address the child’s needs while a committed child, including the appropriateness of services provided to the child under the plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>To the extent available and accessible, the child’s health and education records;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Where appropriate, for a child 16 years of age or over, a written description of the programs and services which will help the child prepare for the transition from being a committed child to independent living; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>If the child’s permanent plan is adoption or placement in another permanent home, documentation of the steps (including child specific recruitment efforts) taken to accomplish the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Find an adoptive family or other permanent living arrangement, such as with a legal custodian, with a kinship caregiver, or in independent living;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Place the child with an adoptive family, a kinship caregiver, a legal custodian, or in another planned permanent living arrangement; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Finalize the adoption or legal custody or guardianship.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>In the case of a child with respect to whom the permanency plan is placement with a relative and receipt of kinship guardianship assistance payments under <cite path="§16-2399">§ 16-2399</cite>, a description of the:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Steps taken to determine that it is not appropriate for the child to be returned home or adopted;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Reasons for any separation of siblings during placement;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Reasons a permanent placement with a fit and willing relative through a kinship guardianship-assistance arrangement is in the child’s best interests;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>Ways in which the child meets the eligibility requirements for a kinship guardianship-assistance payment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>Efforts made to discuss adoption by the child’s relative foster parent as a more permanent alternative to legal guardianship and, in the case of a relative foster parent who has chosen not to pursue adoption, documentation of the reasons therefore; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(vi)</num>
        <text>Efforts made to discuss with the child’s parent the kinship guardianship-assistance arrangement, or the reasons the efforts were not made; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>A plan for ensuring the educational stability of the child while in foster care, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Assurances that the placement of the child in foster care takes into account the appropriateness of the current educational setting and the proximity to the school in which the child is enrolled at the time of placement; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(I)</num>
          <text>An assurance that the Agency has coordinated with appropriate local educational agencies, as defined under section 9101(26) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, approved January 8, 2002 (115 Stat. 1425;  20 U.S.C. § 7801(26)), to ensure that the child remains in the school in which the child is enrolled at the time of placement; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(II)</num>
          <text>If remaining in the school the child is enrolled in at the time of placement is not in the best interests of the child, assurances by the Agency and the local educational agencies to provide immediate and appropriate enrollment in a new school, with all of the educational records of the child provided to the new school.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Child Protection Register” means the confidential index of all reports established pursuant to <cite path="§4-1302.01">§ 4-1302.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4A)</num>
    <text>“Consumer reporting agency” means a person or entity that assembles or evaluates consumer credit information or other information on consumers for the purpose of furnishing consumer reports and the disclosure of file information to third parties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Credible evidence” means any evidence that indicates that a child is an abused or neglected child, including the statement of any person worthy of belief.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Director” means the Director of the Child and Family Services Agency established by <cite path="§4-1303.01">§ 4-1303.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6A)</num>
    <text>“Domestic partnership” shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§32-701|(4)">§ 32-701(4)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Drug” shall have the same meaning as the term “controlled substance” has in <cite path="§48-901.02|(4)">§ 48-901.02(4)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Drug-related activity” means the use, sale, distribution, or manufacture of a drug or drug paraphernalia without a legally valid license or medical prescription.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Entry into foster care” means the earlier of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The date of the first judicial finding that the child has been neglected; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The date that is 60 days after the date on which the child is removed from the home.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9A)</num>
    <text>“Family assessment” means an evaluation, for the purpose of developing a service plan, to determine:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A family’s strengths and needs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The safety of any children in the home, including assessing whether there exists a risk of abuse or neglect of any child, but excludes a determination as to whether a report of abuse or neglect is substantiated, inconclusive, or unfounded;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A family’s ability to function as a cohesive unit; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>A family’s access to resources.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Family preservation services” means services for children and families who are at risk of abuse or neglect, or in crisis, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Services designed to help children return to families from which they have been removed, or be placed for adoption, where safe and appropriate, with a legal guardian, or, if adoption or legal guardianship is determined not to be safe and appropriate for a child, in another permanent living arrangement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Replacement prevention services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Services which provide follow-up care to families to whom a child has returned after commitment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Respite care services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Services designed to improve parenting skills and abilities.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Family support services” means community-based services to promote the safety and well-being of children and families, and designed to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Increase family strength and stability;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Increase parent confidence and competence;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Afford children safe, stable, and supportive family environments; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Otherwise enhance child development.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Godparent” means an individual identified by a relative of the child by blood, marriage, domestic partnership, or adoption, in a sworn affidavit, to have close personal or emotional ties with the child or the child’s family, which pre-dated the child’s placement with the individual.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Guardian ad litem” means an attorney appointed by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to represent the child’s best interests in neglect proceedings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13A)</num>
    <text>“Inconclusive report” means a report, made pursuant to <cite path="§4-1321.03">§ 4-1321.03</cite>, which cannot be proven to be either substantiated or unfounded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>“Kinship caregiver” means an individual who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is approved by the Division to provide kinship care;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is at least 21 years of age;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Is providing, or is willing to provide for, the day-to-day care of a child; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Either:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Is a relative of the child by blood, marriage, domestic partnership, or adoption; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Is a godparent of the child.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>“Law enforcement officer” means a sworn officer of the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15A)</num>
    <text>“Neglected child” shall have the same meaning as is provided in <cite path="§16-2301|(9)">§ 16-2301(9)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15B)</num>
    <text>“Panel” means the Citizen Review Panel established by <cite path="§4-1303.51">§ 4-1303.51</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15C)</num>
    <text>“Placement disruption” means an unplanned move necessary to protect the safety and well-being of the youth.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>“Police” means the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>“Report” means a report to the police or the Agency of a suspected or known neglected child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(18)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(19)</num>
    <text>“Source” means the person or institution from whom a report originates.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(19A)</num>
    <text>“Substantiated report” means a report, made pursuant to <cite path="§4-1321.03">§ 4-1321.03</cite>, which is supported by credible evidence and is not against the weight of the evidence.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(20)</num>
    <text>“Time-limited family reunification services” means services and activities provided to a committed child and to the child’s parent, guardian, or custodian in order to facilitate the safe, appropriate, and timely reunification of the child during the 15 months following the child’s entry into foster care. Time-limited family reunification services include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Individual, group, and family counseling;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Inpatient, residential, or outpatient substance abuse treatment services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Mental health services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Assistance to address domestic violence;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Services designed to provide temporary child care and therapeutic services for families; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Transportation to or from any of the services and activities described in this paragraph.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(20A)</num>
    <text>“Unfounded report” means a report, made pursuant to <cite path="§4-1321.03">§ 4-1321.03</cite>, which is made maliciously or in bad faith or which has no basis in fact.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(21)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(22)</num>
    <text>“Youth” means an individual under 18 years of age residing in the District and those classified as youth in the custody of the Agency who are 21 years of age or younger.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22" type="History" path="§102">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title I, § 102, 24 DCR 3341</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-87" type="History">Mar. 15, 1990, D.C. Law 8-87, § 3(a), 37 DCR 50</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-136" type="History">June 27, 2000, D.C. Law 13-136, § 201(a), 47 DCR 2850</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-277" type="History">Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-277, § 2(a), 48 DCR 2043</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-206" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-206, § 2(a), 49 DCR 7815</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-341" type="History">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-341, § 2(a), 52 DCR 2315</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 96, 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 20, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 12, 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-162" type="History">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-162, § 2(a), 57 DCR 3029</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-228" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-228, § 2(a), 57 DCR 6926</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-312" type="History">Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-312, § 2(a), 57 DCR 12398</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-141" type="History">June 7, 2012, D.C. Law 19-141, § 505(a), 59 DCR 3083</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“Title IV of this act”, referenced in par. (2A), is title IV of Law 2-22, which is codified to 16-2304, 16-2310, 16-2313, 16-2315, 16-2319, 16-2320, 16-2323 to 16-2338, and 16-2351 to 16-2365.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Supporting Normalcy and Empowering Children in Foster Care Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-333, Mar. 16, 2016,  63 DCR 4306).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Encouraging Foster Children To Have Connections with Siblings Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-240, Dec. 21, 2015,  63 DCR 11).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-228">D.C. Law 18-228</cite>, § 3, see § 7011 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-228">D.C. Law 18-228</cite>, § 3, see § 7011 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, § 601, see § 4112 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, § 601, see § 4112 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-228">D.C. Law 18-228</cite>, § 3, see § 109 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-604, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1045), applicable as of January 10, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-228">D.C. Law 18-228</cite>, § 3, see § 109 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-482, October 12, 2012,  59 DCR 12478).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-586, October 20, 2010,  57 DCR 10136).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-259, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 337).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) delay of the applicability of provisions changing the manner in which the Child and Family Services Agency will process reports of child abuse and neglect, see § 3 of Improved Child Abuse Investigations Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-603, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 687).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) delay of the applicability of provisions changing the manner in which the Child and Family Services Agency will process reports of child abuse and neglect, see § 3 of Improved Child Abuse Investigations Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-494, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 9781).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Adoption and Safe Families Compliance Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-451, November 7, 2000,  47 DCR 9399).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Adoption and Safe Families Compliance Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-383, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 201(a) of the Adoption and Safe Families Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-240, January 11, 2000,  47 DCR 556).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 201(a) of the Adoption and Safe Families Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-178, November 2, 1999,  46 DCR 9714).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 201(a) of the Adoption and Safe Families Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-117, July 28, 1999,  46 DCR 6558).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3 of the Prevention of Child Neglect Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-288, July 22, 1994,  41 DCR 4992).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3 of the Prevention of Child Neglect Emergency Amendment Act of 1993 (D.C. Act 10-100, August 9, 1993,  40 DCR 6141).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Encouraging Foster Children to Have Connections with Siblings Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-85">D.C. Law 21-85</cite>, Mar. 9, 2016,  63 DCR 788).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 402(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-226">D.C. Law 19-226</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 109 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-226">D.C. Law 19-226</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-228">D.C. Law 18-228</cite>, § 3.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-298">D.C. Law 18-298</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(II) If remaining in the school the child is enrolled in at the time of placement is not in the best interests of the child, assurances by the Agency and the local educational agencies to provide immediate and appropriate enrollment in a new school, with all of the educational records of the child provided to the school.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii)(I) An assurance that the Agency has coordinated with appropriate local educational agencies, as defined under section 601(f) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, approved April 11, 1965 (79 Stat. 27;  20 USC § 7801)), to ensure that the child remains in the school in which the child is enrolled at the time of placement; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) Assurances that the placement of the child in foster care takes into account the appropriateness of the current educational setting and the proximity to the school in which the child is enrolled at the time of placement; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(G) A plan for ensuring the educational stability of the child while in foster care, including:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(vi) Efforts made to discuss with the child’s parent the kinship guardianship-assistance arrangement, or the reasons the efforts were not made; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(v) Efforts made to discuss adoption by the child’s relative foster parent as a more permanent alternative to legal guardianship and, in the case of a relative foster parent who has chosen not to pursue adoption, documentation of the reasons therefore; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(iv) Ways in which the child meets the eligibility requirements for a kinship guardianship-assistance payment;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(iii) Reasons a permanent placement with a fit and willing relative through a kinship guardianship-assistance arrangement is in the child’s best interests;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii) Reasons for any separation of siblings during placement;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) Steps taken to determine that it is not appropriate for the child to be returned home or adopted;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F) In the case of a child with respect to whom the permanency plan is placement with a relative and receipt of kinship guardianship assistance payments under D.C. Official Code <cite path="§16-2399">§ 16-2399</cite>, a description of the:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-298">D.C. Law 18-298</cite> added pars. (3)(F) and (G) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-136">D.C. Law 18-136</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(II) If remaining in the school the child is enrolled in at the time of placement is not in the best interests of the child, assurances by the Agency and the local educational agencies to provide immediate and appropriate enrollment in a new school, with all of the educational records of the child provided to the school.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii)(I) An assurance that the Agency has coordinated with appropriate local educational agencies, as defined under section 601(f) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, approved April 11, 1965 (79 Stat. 27;  20 USC § 7801)), to ensure that the child remains in the school in which the child is enrolled at the time of placement; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) Assurances that the placement of the child in foster care takes into account the appropriateness of the current educational setting and the proximity to the school in which the child is enrolled at the time of placement; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(G) A plan for ensuring the educational stability of the child while in foster care, including:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(vi) Efforts made to discuss with the child’s parent the kinship guardianship-assistance arrangement, or the reasons the efforts were not made; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(v) Efforts made to discuss adoption by the child’s relative foster parent as a more permanent alternative to legal guardianship and, in the case of a relative foster parent who has chosen not to pursue adoption, documentation of the reasons therefore; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(iv) Ways in which the child meets the eligibility requirements for a kinship guardianship-assistance payment;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(iii) Reasons a permanent placement with a fit and willing relative through a kinship guardianship-assistance arrangement is in the child’s best interests;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii) Reasons for any separation of siblings during placement;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) Steps taken to determine that it is not appropriate for the child to be returned home or adopted;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F) In the case of a child with respect to whom the permanency plan is placement with a relative and receipt of kinship guardianship assistance payments under D.C. Official Code <cite path="§16-2399">§ 16-2399</cite>, a description of the:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-136">D.C. Law 18-136</cite>, in par. (3), added subpars. (F) and (G) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Improved Child Abuse Investigations Technical Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-240">D.C. Law 14-240</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2753).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Adoption and Safe Families Compliance Temporary Amendment Act of 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-193">D.C. Law 13-193</cite>, October 21, 2000, law notification  47 DCR 8983).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 201(a) of Adoption and Safe Families Temporary Amendment Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-56">D.C. Law 13-56</cite>, March 7, 2000, law notification  47 DCR 1978).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Prevention of Child Neglect Temporary Amendment Act of 1993 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-61">D.C. Law 10-61</cite>, November 20, 1993, law notification  40 DCR 8454).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> added pars. (2A-i), (2A-ii), (2A-iii), (15C), and (22).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-312">D.C. Law 18-312</cite> added pars. (3)(F) and (G).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-228">D.C. Law 18-228</cite> added par. (9A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-162">D.C. Law 18-162</cite> added par. (4A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite> added par. (6A); and, in pars. (12) and (14)(D)(i), substituted “marriage, domestic partnership,” for “marriage,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in par. (15B), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite>, in pars. (13A), (15A), (18), (19A), (20A), and (21), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-341">D.C. Law 15-341</cite> added pars. (2B) and (15B).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-206">D.C. Law 14-206</cite> rewrote par. (1); added pars. (12A), (14A), (18A), and (19A); and repealed pars. (17) and (20).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(6) ‘Division’ means the Child Protective Services Division of the District of Columbia Department of Human Services.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-277">D.C. Law 13-277</cite> added par. (2A) and rewrote par. (6) which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(13) ‘Abused,’ when used with reference to a child, means a child whose parent, guardian or custodian inflicts or fails to make reasonable efforts to prevent the infliction of physical or mental injury upon the child, including excessive corporal punishment, an act of sexual abuse, molestation, or exploitation, or an injury that results from exposure to drug-related activity.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(12) ‘Law enforcement officer’ means a sworn officer of the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(11) ‘Drug-related activity’ means the use, sale, distribution, or manufacture of a drug or drug paraphernalia without a legally valid license or medical prescription.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(10) ‘Drug’ shall have the same meaning as the term ‘controlled substance’ has in <cite path="§33-501|(4)" proof="true">§ 33-501(4)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(9) ‘Unsupported report’ means a report, made pursuant to <cite path="§2-1353" proof="true">§ 2-1353</cite>, which is not supported by credible evidence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(8) ‘Supported report’ means a report, made pursuant to <cite path="§2-1353" proof="true">§ 2-1353</cite>, which is supported by credible evidence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(7) ‘Source’ means the person or institution from whom a report originates.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(6) ‘Report’ means a report to the police or the Division of a suspected or known neglected child.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(5) ‘Police’ means the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(4) ‘Guardian ad litem’ means an attorney appointed by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to represent the child’s best interests in neglect proceedings.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) Except where used in title IV of this act, ‘Division’ means the Child Protective Services Division of the District of Columbia Department of Human Services.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) ‘Credible evidence’ means any evidence which indicates that a child is an abused or neglected child, including the statement of any person worthy of belief.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) ‘Child Protection Register’ means the confidential index of all reports established pursuant to <cite path="§6-2111" proof="true">§ 6-2111</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“For the purposes of this act:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-136">D.C. Law 13-136</cite> rewrote this section, which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2101.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2101.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§2-1402.21">§ 2-1402.21</cite>, <cite path="§4-1301.06b">§ 4-1301.06b</cite>, <cite path="§4-1303.03">§ 4-1303.03</cite>, <cite path="§16-914">§ 16-914</cite>, and <cite path="§42-3505.07">§ 42-3505.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7011 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-228">D.C. Law 18-228</cite>, § 3.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>, § 4112, provided that §§ 302(b)(1)(A) and (C) and 304(b)(1)(D) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> shall apply to public charter schools upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register. Section 302(b)(1)(A) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> added <cite path="§38-203|(i)|(A-i)">§ 38-203(i)(A-i)</cite>; Section 302(b)(1)(C) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> added <cite path="§38-203|(i)|(B-i)">§ 38-203(i)(B-i)</cite>; and Section 304(b)(1)(D) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> added 5 DCMR § A2103(c)(6).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> originally provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite>, § 7004, provided that the applicability of only §§ 302(b)(1), 304, and 502(a) are contingent upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-228">D.C. Law 18-228</cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">For applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-277">D.C. Law 13-277</cite>, see note following <cite path="§4-1303.01a">§ 4-1303.01a</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 14-206: Section 16(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-310">D.C. Law 14-310</cite> provided that section 2(a)(2), (4), (5), (6), and (7), (b), (c), (d), (e), (h), (i), (j), (k), and (l) of D.C. 14-206 shall apply as of October 1, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 7001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 4111 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle K of Title IV of the act may be cited as the “South Capitol Street Memorial Amendment Act of 2013”.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
