<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1301.05</num>
  <heading>Handling of reports — By police.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The police shall, as soon as possible after the receipt of a report of a neglected child other than an abused child, inform the Agency of its contents and any action the police are taking or have taken.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The police may, upon the receipt of a report of an abused child, inform the Agency of its contents and shall, as soon as possible when the report is a substantiated report, inform the Agency of its contents and any action they are taking or have taken.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The police shall immediately after a report is received commence an investigation of the circumstances alleged in the report.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The police shall immediately after a report is received commence an investigation of a case of a neglected child in immediate danger which case was referred from the Agency or reported directly to the police.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Upon the receipt of a report alleging a child is or has been left alone or without adequate supervision, the police shall respond to the report immediately and shall take such steps as are necessary to safeguard the child until a Agency staff member arrives: Provided, however, that if the Agency does not arrive within a reasonable time, the police may transport the child to the Agency. The transporting of a child to the Agency pursuant to this subsection shall not be considered a taking into custody as described in § <cite path="§16-2309">16-2309</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22" type="History" path="§105">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title I, § 105, 24 DCR 3341</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-277" type="History">Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-277, § 2(c), 48 DCR 2043</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-206" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-206,§ 2(b), 49 DCR 7815</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1303.04">4-1303.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2103.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2103.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-277">D.C. Law 13-277</cite> substituted “Agency” for “Division” throughout the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-206">D.C. Law 14-206</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “substantiated report” for “supported report”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Improved Child Abuse Investigations Technical Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-240">D.C. Law 14-240</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2753).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) delay of the applicability of provisions changing the manner in which the Child and Family Services Agency will process reports of child abuse and neglect, see § 3 of Improved Child Abuse Investigations Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-494, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 9781).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) delay of the applicability of provisions changing the manner in which the Child and Family Services Agency will process reports of child abuse and neglect, see § 3 of Improved Child Abuse Investigations Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-603, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 687).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 14-206: Section 16(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-310">D.C. Law 14-310</cite> provided that section 2(a)(2), (4), (5), (6), and (7), (b), (c), (d), (e), (h), (i), (j), (k), and (l) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-206">D.C. Law 14-206</cite> shall apply as of October 1, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">For applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-277">D.C. Law 13-277</cite>, see note following § <cite path="§4-1303.01a">4-1303.01a</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
