<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-1410</num>
  <heading>Authority to charge or receive compensation for services; inability to pay adoption costs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, neither the Mayor nor a child-placing agency authorized to perform services in connection with placement of a child in a family home for adoption may make or receive any charge or compensation for these services.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A child-placing agency may charge an adoptive parent a reasonable fee if the child-placing agency is operating in the District of Columbia exclusively for religious purposes or as a nonprofit organization, pursuant to section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 16, 1954 (68A Stat. 163; 26 U.S.C. § 501(c)), and no part of its net earnings inure to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A child-placing agency providing domestic or international adoption services that is authorized to charge a fee pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall develop a sliding-fee scale based on the per capita income of the applicant and provide each applicant with:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Its fee and refund policy;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An estimate of the agency’s maximum fee for specific services;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Information regarding available public and private subsidies;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Its sliding income fee scale; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>A complete list of the services that it will provide at each stage of the adoption process.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a child-placing agency that charges a fee fails to implement and to maintain a sliding-fee scale as required by this subchapter, or rules issued pursuant to this subchapter, the failure shall be grounds for suspension or revocation of its license.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>In addition to the fee set forth in subsection (b) of this section, a child-placing agency providing domestic or international adoption services that is authorized to charge a fee pursuant to subsection (a) of this section may charge an adoptive parent reasonable fees, but not more than the actual cost, for the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Customary and reasonable legal expenses of the child-placing agency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Costs of locating an absent birthparent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Foster care expenses incurred by the child-placing agency for a period not to exceed 120 days of foster care;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>The living expenses of the birthmother, including food, shelter, and clothing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Transportation costs to obtain medical services, adoption- related services, or costs associated with any required court appearance related to the adoption, including food and lodging expenses;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Expenses for adoption counseling or counseling for the birthparents by an independent mental health professional;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>The birthmother’s legal, hospital, and medical expenses;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(H)</num>
      <text>Legal fees and costs in connection with contested adoption proceedings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(I)</num>
      <text>Expenses incurred by the child-placing agency in connection with an adoption dissolution and alternative placement of a child; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(J)</num>
      <text>Expenses incurred by the child-placing agency in obtaining the documents required to complete the homestudy assessment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except for a reasonable, nonrefundable administrative fee, a child-placing agency shall not retain the fee paid by an adoptive parent unless the child-placing agency has provided the service.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite root="2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this section, including the process for suspension and revocation of the license required to maintain a child-placing agency.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No later than May 31, 2015, the Mayor shall issue rules to implement the provisions of subsection (b-1) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Apr. 22, 1944, ch. 174, § 12</annotation>
      <annotation>June 8, 1954, 68 Stat. 248, ch. 273, § 6</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-59">Apr. 23, 1980, D.C. Law 3-59, § 2(a), 27 DCR 983</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-230">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-230, § 201(e), 57 DCR 6951</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 34, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-269">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-269, § 2(b), 62 DCR 1551</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 32-1011.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 32-790.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-230">D.C. Law 18-230</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated the paragraph designations in (b)(1).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-269">D.C. Law 20-269</cite> added (b-1).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-114">D.C. Law 18-114</cite> rewrote the section to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“Sec. 12. (a) Neither the Mayor nor a child-placing agency authorized to perform services in connection with placement of a child in a family home for adoption may make or receive any charge or compensation for these services; except, that a child-placing agency that is operating in the District of Columbia exclusively for religious purposes or as a nonprofit organization pursuant to  section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 16, 1954 (68A Stat. 163;  26 U.S.C. § 501(c)), and no part of its net earnings inure to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual, may charge an adoptive parent a reasonable fee.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(b)(1) A child-placing agency providing domestic or international adoption services that is authorized to charge a fee pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall develop a sliding fee scale based on the per capita family income size of the applicant and provide each applicant with:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(A) Its fee and refund policy;</annotation>
      <annotation>“(B) An estimate of the agency’s maximum fee for specific services;</annotation>
      <annotation>“(C) Information regarding available public and private subsidies;</annotation>
      <annotation>“(D) Its sliding fee scale; and</annotation>
      <annotation>“(E) A complete list of the services that it will provide at each stage of the adoption process.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(2) The failure of a child-placing agency that charges a fee to implement and to maintain a sliding fee scale as required by this section shall be grounds for suspension or revocation of its license. The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite root="2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this paragraph.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(c) Except for a reasonable, nonrefundable administrative fee, a child-placing agency shall not retain the fee paid by an adoptive parent unless the child-placing agency has provided the service.”</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-114">D.C. Law 18-114</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary provisions requiring, on an emergency basis, criminal background investigations for individuals residing in foster family homes or other homes in which children are placed by order, see §§ 2-15 of the Criminal Background Investigation for the Protection of Children Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-431, September 4, 1998,  45 DCR 5915), and §§ 2-15 of the Criminal Background Investigation for the Protection of Children Legislative Review Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-503, January 27, 1999,  45 DCR 8134).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Private Adoption Fee Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-252, December 17, 2009,  57 DCR 36).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
