<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1501.03</num>
  <heading>Criminal background checks required for certain individuals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section, the following individuals shall apply for criminal background checks in accordance with the requirements of § <cite path="§4-1501.05">4-1501.05</cite> and any regulations issued pursuant to § <cite path="§4-1501.11">4-1501.11</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An applicant who is under consideration for paid employment by a covered child or youth services provider;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An applicant who is under consideration for voluntary service in an unsupervised position by a covered child or youth services provider;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An employee of a covered child or youth services provider; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A volunteer who serves a covered child or youth services provider in an unsupervised position.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An applicant for, or an employee or a volunteer working in, a position at a covered child or youth services provider that will not bring the employee or volunteer in direct contact with children and youth is not required to submit to a criminal background check.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A volunteer at a covered child or youth services provider who has only supervised contact with children or youth is not required to submit to a criminal background check, but may be required to submit to a traffic check pursuant to § <cite path="§4-1501.04">4-1501.04</cite>(b)(2).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An applicant for, or an employee or a volunteer working in, a position at a covered child or youth services provider that will bring the employee or volunteer in direct contact with children and youth is not required to submit to a criminal background check if the applicant, employee, or volunteer has an active federal security clearance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An applicant for a position at a covered child or youth services provider may be offered employment contingent upon receipt of a satisfactory background check, and may begin working in a supervised setting prior to receiving the results.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A volunteer serving any covered child or youth services provider in a position that brings the volunteer in direct contact with children shall not be allowed to begin volunteering in an unsupervised setting until the results of the criminal background check have been received and determined to be satisfactory.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>An employee or unsupervised volunteer shall be required to submit to periodic criminal background checks while employed by or volunteering at any covered child or youth services provider in an unsupervised setting.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-353" type="History" path="§203">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-353, § 203, 52 DCR 2331</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 203 of Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-30, February 17, 2005,  52 DCR 2993).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 203 of Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-630, November 30, 2004,  52 DCR 1143).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 203 of Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-407, March 18, 2004,  51 DCR 3659).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 203 of Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-279, December 18, 2003,  51 DCR 60).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 203 of Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-71, April 16, 2003,  50 DCR 3593).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 203 of Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-3, January 22, 2003,  50 DCR 1426).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 203 of the Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Second Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-319">D.C. Law 15-319</cite>, April 8, 2005, law notification  52 DCR 4708).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 203 of the Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-117">D.C. Law 15-117</cite>, March 30, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 3804).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 203 of the Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-2">D.C. Law 15-2</cite>, May 3, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 3782).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 203 of the Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-164">D.C. Law 14-164</cite>, June 25, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 6500).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1501.05">4-1501.05</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
