<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1704.03</num>
  <heading>LRAP; participation eligibility.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To be eligible to participate in the LRAP, an applicant shall, at the time of application and throughout participation in the LRAP:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Hold, or actively plan to secure, eligible employment; provided, that a participant shall hold eligible employment before any payments may be disbursed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be a resident of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be a lawyer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Have an annual adjusted gross income of less than $75,000, subject to a 3% annual increase beginning on October 1, 2013;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Exhaust all other available avenues for loan repayment assistance, including through participation in any available undergraduate or law school debt-forgiveness programs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Have no current service obligation from scholarships;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Submit a timely and completed application;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Be in satisfactory repayment status on all eligible debt; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Execute a release to allow the Administrator access to records, credit information, and information from lenders necessary to verify eligibility of debt and to determine loan repayments.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A law student attending the David A. Clarke School of Law at the University of the District of Columbia who is in his or her final year of school may apply and be approved for loan repayment assistance if the applicant demonstrates that he or she will meet all eligibility requirements by the time of the first award disbursement.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History" path="§403">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 403</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">as added Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 3002(b), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-320" type="History">June 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-320, § 504(b), 60 DCR 3390</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1704.05">4-1704.05</cite> and § <cite path="§4-1704.06">4-1704.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-320">D.C. Law 19-320</law-cite> substituted “$75,000, subject to a 3% annual increase beginning on October 1, 2013” for “$65,000” in (a)(4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (a)(4), see § 504(b) of the Omnibus Criminal Code Amendments Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-599, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1017).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 504(b) of the Omnibus Criminal Code Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-44, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5381, 20 DCSTAT 1281).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
