<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1704.01</num>
  <heading>LRAP.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Poverty Lawyer Loan Repayment Assistance Program shall provide loan repayment assistance to lawyers working in eligible employment. The LRAP shall be part of and be funded through the Initiative, established pursuant to § <cite path="§4-1702.01">4-1702.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Funding for the LRAP shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amount of funding for the LRAP for each fiscal year shall be specified by an act of the Council and shall not be modified except by a subsequent act of the Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any training or evaluation deemed necessary by the Bar Foundation for purposes of the Initiative shall be permitted as a non-administrative expense, with reasonable expenses for these purposes not restricted to the percentage set aside for administrative expenses under subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Deputy Mayor may serve as Administrator or may designate a nonprofit entity to serve as the Administrator. If the Deputy Mayor designates a nonprofit entity as the Administrator, the Deputy Mayor shall provide funding for the LRAP by awarding a grant to the nonprofit entity. The grant shall be nonlapsing and interest earned by the nonprofit on grant funds shall remain available for use by the Administrator for the purposes of the LRAP, without fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For fiscal year 2012, the Deputy Mayor shall designate the Bar Foundation as the Administrator.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, the Administrator may use up to 15% of the grant funding for reasonable administrative expenses associated with administering the LRAP.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the Deputy Mayor has designated the Bar Foundation as Administrator, the Bar Foundation may, in lieu of using a percentage of LRAP grant funding under paragraph (3) of this subsection, use a portion of funds authorized under § <cite path="§4-1703.01">4-1703.01</cite>(b) for reasonable administrative expenses associated with administering the LRAP.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History" path="§401">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 401</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">as added Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 3002(b), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26 , 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 3032(c), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3032(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3032(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3032(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added (b)(3); added “Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection” in (c)(3); and added (c)(4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1701.01">4-1701.01</cite> and § <cite path="§4-1702.02">4-1702.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
