<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-205.77</num>
  <heading>POWER — Failure to participate in self-sufficiency activities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a POWER recipient who is an adult or minor head of an assistance unit fails, without good cause (as determined by the Mayor) to participate in required activities to promote self-sufficiency, the recipient shall be sanctioned in the same manner as a TANF recipient who fails to comply with the requirements of an individual responsibility plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall promulgate rules defining what constitutes good cause for failure to participate in required self-sufficiency activities, in addition to those grounds described in subsections (c), (d), and (e) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall not sanction a POWER recipient based on the failure of the recipient to participate in self-sufficiency activities if the recipient is a single custodial parent caring for a child under 6 years old, and the recipient proves that the recipient has a demonstrated inability, as determined by the Mayor, to obtain needed child care for one or more of the following reasons:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Appropriate child care within a reasonable distance from the recipient’s home or participation site is unavailable;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Informal child care by a relative or under other arrangements is unavailable or unsuitable; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Appropriate and affordable formal child care arrangements are unavailable.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall not sanction a POWER recipient based on the failure of the recipient to participate in self-sufficiency activities if the Mayor has failed to notify the recipient of the self-sufficiency activities in which the recipient must participate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall not sanction a POWER recipient based on the failure of the recipient to participate in self-sufficiency activities if the Mayor provides the activities but placement in those activities are not yet available to the recipient.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall only apply if the POWER recipient has complied with any other obligations required of POWER applicants or recipients.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History" path="§577">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 577</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-241" type="History">as added Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 4(g), 46 DCR 905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">See notes to § <cite path="§4-205.69">4-205.69</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4(h) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-230">D.C. Law 12-230</cite>, April 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 4143).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-205.77.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
