<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-204.13</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Office of Medicaid Operations Reform.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Office of Medicaid Operations Reform.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall appoint a Director of the Office who shall be responsible for the management and operations of the Office and serve at the pleasure of the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish an External Medicaid Task Force to advise the Director.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall fix the compensation of the Director pursuant to subchapter IX of Chapter 6 of Title 1.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Director is authorized to hire staff in the Career Service, consistent with budgetary authorization, as he or she deems necessary to perform the functions of the Office. The Director may engage qualified volunteers in accordance with District of Columbia law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If spending pressures generated by the Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance programs make it necessary that funds from the Medicaid and Special Education Reform Fund be made available for expenditure by the Department of Human Services, the Child and Family Services Agency, the Department of Mental Health, or the Department of Health, the Director, in accordance with § <cite path="§4-204.55">4-204.55</cite>(a)(2)(A), shall submit to the Mayor either a plan to generate savings comparable to the funds allocated or a performance plan to ensure future reduction of costs and maximization of third-party revenues.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Director shall have the authority to delegate to other employees of the Office any of the Director’s powers and duties.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1503, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 1502(c), 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite>, in subsec. (a), deleted “Public Provider” following “Medicaid”; rewrote subsec. (f) which had read as follows: “(f) If spending pressures generated by the Medicaid program make it necessary that funds from the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund be made available for expenditure by the Department of Human Services or the Child and Family Services Agency, the Director shall submit to the Mayor a plan to generate savings comparable to the funds allocated in accordance with § <cite path="§7-1811.03">7-1811.03</cite>(b)(5)(A)(i).”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1502(c) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1502(c) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
