<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-205.75</num>
  <heading>POWER — Redetermination of eligibility.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A POWER recipient’s eligibility for POWER shall be redetermined at intervals determined by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A POWER recipient, who is determined ineligible for POWER solely because the recipient is no longer incapacitated, or because other factors considered with the recipient’s incapacity no longer substantially precludes the recipient’s ability to work or to participate in job search or job readiness activities, shall be certified as eligible for TANF in a fashion that ensures financial assistance is not disrupted, if the recipient meets all TANF eligibility criteria. The Mayor shall provide adequate and timely notice that the POWER recipient has been determined ineligible for POWER.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A POWER recipient who is determined eligible for continuation of one year due to incapacity under § <cite path="§4-205.72">4-205.72</cite>(b)(2) shall be informed by the Mayor or the Mayor’s designee about the recipient’s potential eligibility for Social Security Disability Insurance (“SSDI”) or Supplemental Security Income (“SSI”). If appropriate, the POWER recipient shall submit an application for SSDI or SSI benefits as part of the recipient’s self-sufficiency plan. The Mayor or the Mayor’s designee shall offer application and advocacy assistance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-241" type="History">as added Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 4(g), 46 DCR 905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 5072(d), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-205.75.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4(h) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-230">D.C. Law 12-230</cite>, April 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 4143).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">See notes to § <cite path="§4-205.69">4-205.69</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5072(d) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5072(d) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5072(d) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
