<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-205.53</num>
  <heading>Reconsideration of grants; modification of amount; duty of recipient to notify Mayor of change of circumstances; grants under General Public Assistance Program for Unemployables.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All public assistance grants made under this chapter shall be reconsidered by the Mayor as frequently as he or she may deem necessary, but in every case the Mayor shall make such reconsiderations at least once in each year. After such further investigation as the Mayor may deem necessary, the amount of public assistance may be changed, or may be entirely withdrawn, if the Mayor finds that any such grant has been made erroneously, or if he or she finds that the recipient’s circumstances have altered sufficiently to warrant such action. If at any time during the continuance of public assistance the recipient becomes possessed of resources in excess of the amount previously reported by the recipient, or if other changes occur in the nonfinancial circumstances previously reported by the recipient that would alter either the recipient’s need or eligibility, it shall be the recipient’s duty to notify the Mayor of this information immediately upon the receipt or possession of the additional resources, or upon the change in circumstances. A recipient shall inform the Mayor whenever the recipient begins to receive earned income, if the recipient did not earn income previously, and whenever the recipient ceases to receive earned income. The recipient shall inform the Mayor as soon as the recipient becomes aware that a change will occur, rather than waiting to inform the Mayor in the periodic report required under § <cite path="§4-205.54">4-205.54</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History" path="§553">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 553, 29 DCR 1060</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-27" type="History">Aug. 17, 1991, D.C. Law 9-27, § 2(h), 38 DCR 4205</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-68" type="History">Feb. 5, 1994, D.C. Law 10-68, § 10(e), 40 DCR 6311</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-60" type="History">Mar. 20, 1998, D.C. Law 12-60, § 701(q), 44 DCR 7378</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-241" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 2(rr), 46 DCR 905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-205.11">4-205.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-205.53.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 101(h) of Omnibus Budget Support Temporary Act of 1991 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 9-19">D.C. Law 9-19</cite>, June 21, 1991, law notification  38 DCR 5786).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(x) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-7">D.C. Law 12-7</cite>, August 1, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 4639).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(q) of General Public Assistance Program Termination Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-21">D.C. Law 12-21</cite>, September 23, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 5760).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 701(q) of Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Temporary Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-59">D.C. Law 12-59</cite>, March 20, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 2094).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(x) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-130">D.C. Law 12-130</cite>, July 24, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 6501).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(rr) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-230">D.C. Law 12-230</cite>, April 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 4143).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 101(h) of the Omnibus Budget Support Emergency Act of 1991 (D.C. Act 9-37, May 17, 1991,  38 DCR 3390).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 101(h) of the Omnibus Budget Support Congressional Recess Emergency Act of 1991 (D.C. Act 9-69, July 24, 1991,  38 DCR 4945).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-25, February 27, 1997,  44 DCR 1778), and see § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-77, May 27, 1997,  44 DCR 3181).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(q) of the General Public Assistance Program Termination Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-72, May 12, 1997,  44 DCR 2989).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 701(q) of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-152, October 17, 1997,  44 DCR 6196), and see § 701(q) of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-239, January 13, 1998,  45 DCR 508).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-306, March 20, 1998,  45 DCR 1900).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(rr) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-372, June 9, 1998,  45 DCR 4270), § 2(rr) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-425, July 31, 1998,  45 DCR 5682), § 2(rr) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-552, December 24, 1998,  46 DCR 521), and § 2(rr) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review  Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-19, February 17, 1999,  46 DCR 2492).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 12-60: Section 2002 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-60">D.C. Law 12-60</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 1997.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
