<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-204.54</num>
  <heading>Purposes of the Fund.</heading>
  <text>The Fund shall be used for the following purposes:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Ensuring adequate resources are available to support District-wide Medicaid costs and revenue shortfalls;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1A)</num>
    <text>Ensuring adequate resources are available to support District-wide Medicare costs and revenue shortfalls;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1B)</num>
    <text>Ensuring adequate resources are available to support District-wide Foster Care and Adoption Assistance costs and revenue shortfalls;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Ensuring adequate resources are available to support District-wide Special Education costs and revenue shortfalls;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Supporting Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance reform activities designed to establish cost-effective, agency-based Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance operations; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Optimizing Medicaid, Medicare, Foster Care and Adoption Assistance and other third-party revenues.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1554, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 1503(c), 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-204.53">4-204.53</cite> and § <cite path="§4-204.55">4-204.55</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</law-cite>, in the introductory language, substituted “The Fund shall be used for the following purposes:” for “The purposes of the Fund shall include:”; added pars. (1A) and (1B); in par. (3), substituted “Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance” for “Medicaid” in two places; and in par. (4), substituted “Medicaid, Medicare, Foster Care and Adoption Assistance” for “Medicaid”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1503(c) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1503(c) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 5142 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 5142 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
