<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-205.66</num>
  <heading>Failure to meet school attendance requirements; notice.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon determination that a pregnant or parenting teen has failed without good cause to meet the school attendance requirements of subsection (b) of this section, the Department shall provide notice which specifies the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That the pregnant or parenting teen has a right to review and copy his or her records at the expense of the pregnant or parenting teen’s school pursuant to Chapter 26 of Title 5 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That prior to any action against the pregnant or parenting teen, he or she has a right to challenge, in writing, the contents of his or her school records pursuant to Chapter 26 of Title 5 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That the pregnant or parenting teen is entitled to a hearing if he or she is not satisfied with the administrative decision pursuant to Chapter 26 of Title 5 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the pregnant or parenting teen, or his or her parent or guardian, does not request a fair hearing pursuant to § <cite path="§4-210.05">4-210.05</cite>, or, if after a fair hearing has been held, the hearing officer finds that the pregnant or parenting teen is not exempt from the school attendance requirements imposed by § <cite path="§4-205.65">4-205.65</cite>(a), the Department shall determine the pregnant or parenting teen ineligible for federally-funded TANF benefits in the next possible payment month.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department of Human Services shall develop an incentive program, in consultation with the District of Columbia Public Schools, to encourage school attendance and recognize those who meet the attendance requirements.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 566</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-72" type="History">as added Oct. 27, 1995, D.C. Law 11-72, § 101, 42 DCR 4728</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-241" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 4(f), 46 DCR 905</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-205.66.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4(d) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-7">D.C. Law 12-7</cite>, August 1, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 4639).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4(d) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-130">D.C. Law 12-130</cite>, July 24, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 6501).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4(f) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-230">D.C. Law 12-230</cite>, April 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 4143).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(d) of the Public Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-25, February 27, 1997,  44 DCR 1778), § 4(d) of the Public Assistance Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-77, May 27, 1997,  44 DCR 3181), and § 4(d) of the Public Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-306, March 20, 1998,  45 DCR 1900).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(f) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-372, June 9, 1998,  45 DCR 4270), § 4(f) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-425, July 31, 1998,  45 DCR 5682),§ 4(f) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-552, December 24, 1998,  46 DCR 521), and § 4(f) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-19, February 17, 1999,  46 DCR 2492).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Expiration of Law</heading>
      <text>Expiration of Law 11-72</text>
      <text>See note to § <cite path="§4-205.01">4-205.01</cite>.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
