<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-204.11</num>
  <heading>Short title.</heading>
  <text>This part may be cited as the “Office of Medicaid Operations Reform Establishment Act of 2002”.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History" path="§1501">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1501, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 1502(a), 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite> deleted “Public Provider” following “Medicaid”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) approval of proposed amendments to the District of Columbia State Plan for Medical Assistance, see § 1902 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For the temporary (90 day) Medicaid State Plan Amendment Approval provisions, see § 1902 of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1502(a) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1502(a) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For the temporary (90 day) Medicaid State Plan Amendment Approval provisions, see § 1902 of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title of title XV of Law 15-39: Section 1501 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite> provided that title XV of the act may be cited as the Medicaid and Tobacco Funding Amendment Act of 2003.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 1902 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</cite> provided: “Pursuant to section 1(a)(2) of An Act To enable the District of Columbia to receive Federal financial assistance under Title XIX of the Social Security Act for a medical assistance program, and for other purposes, approved December 27, 1967 (81 Stat. 744; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§1-307.02">1-307.02</cite>(a)(2)), the Council of the District of Columbia approves the proposed amendments to the District of Columbia State Plan for Medical Assistance to authorize the Medicaid Program to remove the requirement that requires that rates paid to hospitals, nursing facilities, and intermediate care facilities for persons with mental retardation be adjusted annually for inflation; to add provisions that require that payments made to hospitals, nursing facilities, and intermediate care facilities for persons with mental retardation for inflation adjustments in subsequent fiscal years be contingent upon the availability of funds; to increase the pharmacy dispensing fee effective April 1, 2003; and to remove provisions authorizing payment exceptions to the cost ceilings applicable to nursing facilities; and to approve a waiver to the District of Columbia State Plan for Medical Assistance to expand coverage of its Medicaid Program to childless adults 50 to 64 years of age.” Establishment of the Office of Medicaid Public Provider Operations Reform, see Mayor’s Order 2002-101, June 28, 2002 ( 49 DCR 5997).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
