<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-204.55</num>
  <heading>Distribution of funds.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall distribute funds from the Fund only after:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Certifying that the funds are needed by the District of Columbia Public Schools, the Child and Family Services Agency, the Department of Human Services, the Department of Mental Health, or the Department of Health for the purposes described in § <cite path="§4-204.54">4-204.54</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Certifying either that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A savings plan to be submitted by the Director of the Office of Medicaid Operations Reform to the Mayor will generate savings for the Child and Family Services Agency, the Department of Human Services, the Department of Mental Health, or the Department of Health, respectively, comparable to the funds to be allocated to the agency during Fiscal Year 2003 or Fiscal Year 2004; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>If a savings plan that will generate savings comparable to the funds allocated is not possible, a performance plan to be submitted by the Director of the Office of Medicaid Operations Reform to the Mayor will ensure that the agency to which the requested funds are to be allocated will implement policies and procedures and develop the infrastructure necessary to enable the agency to reduce costs and maximize third-party revenues by no later than October 1, 2004; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Certifying that a savings plan to be submitted by the District of Columbia Public Schools will generate savings comparable to the funds allocated to the agency during Fiscal Year 2003 or Fiscal Year 2004; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Providing notification of the distribution to the Mayor and Council.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>A savings plan required under subsection (a)(2)(A)(i) of this section that pertains to the allocation of funds to an agency in Fiscal Year 2003 shall be submitted no later than December 31, 2002. The plan shall commence no later than October 1, 2003, and shall generate savings comparable to the funds allocated to the agency from the Fund in Fiscal Year 2003.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-2)</num>
    <text>A savings plan required under subsection (a)(2)(A)(i) of this section that pertains to the allocation of funds to an agency in Fiscal Year 2004 shall be submitted no later than December 31, 2003. The plan shall commence no later than October 1, 2004, and shall generate savings comparable to the funds allocated to the agency from the Fund in Fiscal Year 2004.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-3)</num>
    <text>A performance plan required under subsection (a)(2)(A)(ii) of this section shall be submitted no later than December 31, 2003, and shall commence no later than October 1, 2004.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-4)</num>
    <text>The savings plan required under subsection (a)(2)(B) of this section that pertains to the allocation of funds to the District of Columbia Public Schools in Fiscal Year 2003 shall be submitted, no later than December 31, 2002, by the District of Columbia Public Schools to the Special Education Task Force established by Chapter 25A of Title 38. The plan shall commence no later than October 1, 2003, and generate savings comparable to the funds allocated to the agency from the Fund in Fiscal Year 2003.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-5)</num>
    <text>The savings plan required under subsection (a)(2)(B) of this section that pertains to the allocation of funds to the District of Columbia Public Schools in Fiscal Year 2004 shall be submitted, no later than December 31, 2003, by the District of Columbia Public Schools to the Special Education Task Force established by Chapter 25A of Title 38. The plan shall commence no later than October 1, 2004, and generate savings comparable to the funds allocated to the agency from the Fund in Fiscal Year 2004.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-6)</num>
    <text>Beginning 3 months following the commencement of any plan submitted pursuant to subsection (a)(2) of this section, or no later than January 2, 2004, the Mayor and the Special Education Task Force shall provide the Council with quarterly reports on the progress made by the Department of Human Services, the Child and Family Services Agency, the Department of Mental Health, the Department of Health, and the District of Columbia Public Schools, in reducing costs associated with the Medicaid, Medicare, Foster Care and Adoption Assistance, and Special Education programs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Total distribution of funds from the Fund to the District of Columbia Public Schools, the Child and Family Services Agency, the Department of Human Services, the Department of Mental Health, or the Department of Health in any given fiscal year shall not exceed the amount appropriated for that agency in that fiscal year for the purposes of § <cite path="§7-1811.03">7-1811.03</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1555, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 1503(d), 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, §§ 12, 84(g), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-204.13">4-204.13</cite> and § <cite path="§7-1811.03">7-1811.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “the Department of Human Services, the Department of Mental Health, or the Department of Health” for “or the Department of Human Services” in par. (1), and rewrote par. (2); added subsecs. (a-1), (a-2), (a-3), (a-4), (a-5), and (a-6); and in subsec. (b), substituted “the Department of Human Services, the Department of Mental Health, or the Department of Health” for “or the Department of Human Services”. Prior to amendment, par. (2) of subsec. (a) had read as follows: “(2) Certifying that a savings plan to be submitted by the Director of the Office of Medicaid Public Provider Operations Reform to the Mayor in accordance with § <cite path="§7-1811.03">7-1811.03</cite>(b)(5)(A)(i), will generate savings comparable to the funds allocated; and”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite>, in subsecs. (a-4) and (a-5), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1503(d) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1503(d) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
