<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-208.05</num>
  <heading>Repayment by GPA recipient.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For any month in which a person who received benefits under the former General Public Assistance (“GPA”) program received both GPA and Supplemental Security Income (“SSI”), the former GPA recipient shall repay to the District of Columbia:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The entire GPA monthly assistance payment if the SSI benefits received equaled or exceeded the GPA payment; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That portion of the GPA monthly assistance payment equal in amount to the SSI benefits received if the SSI benefits received were less than the GPA payment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In order to make repayment in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, a former GPA recipient who applied for SSI must have agreed to have the initial SSI benefit forwarded directly to the Department of Human Services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a former GPA recipient’s initial SSI benefit, the Department shall calculate, in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, the amount of the benefit due to the Department as repayment and the amount, if any, due the former GPA recipient. The Department shall provide the former GPA recipient with a written explanation of this calculation and shall pay any amount due the former GPA recipient, in accordance with 42 U.S.C. § 1383 (g) and SSA Interim Assistance Provisions, 20 C.F.R. § 416.1901 to 416.1922 (1983).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History" path="§805">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 805</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-53" type="History">as added Mar. 14, 1984, D.C. Law 5-53, § 2(d), 30 DCR 6278</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-60" type="History">Mar. 20, 1998, D.C. Law 12-60, § 701(s), 44 DCR 7378</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-241" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 2(ccc), 46 DCR 905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-208.5.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(s) of General Public Assistance Program Termination Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 12-21">D.C. Law 12-21</law-cite>, September 23, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 2760).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 701(s) of Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Temporary Act of 1997 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 12-59">D.C. Law 12-59</law-cite>, March 20, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 2094).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(ccc) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 12-230">D.C. Law 12-230</law-cite>, April 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 4143).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(s) of the General Public Assistance Program Termination Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-72, May 12, 1997,  44 DCR 2989).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 701(s) of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-152, October 17, 1997,  44 DCR 6196), and see § 701(s) of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-239, January 13, 1998,  45 DCR 508).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(ccc) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-372, June 9, 1998,  45 DCR 4270), § 2(ccc) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-425, July 31, 1998,  45 DCR 5682),§ 2(ccc) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-552, December 24, 1998,  46 DCR 521), and § 2(ccc) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-19, February 17, 1999,  46 DCR 2492).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 12-60: Section 2002 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 12-60">D.C. Law 12-60</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 1997.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
