<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-204.53</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Medicaid and Special Education Reform Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing, revolving fund the Medicaid and Special Education Reform Fund into which shall be deposited funds made available for the purposes of Medicaid, Medicare, Foster Care and Adoption Assistance, and Special Education reform described in § <cite path="§4-204.54">4-204.54</cite>. The Fund shall be administered by the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All amounts deposited in the Fund shall be appropriated without fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress. All amounts deposited in the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the purposes of Medicaid, Medicare, Foster Care and Adoption Assistance, and Special Education reform described in § <cite path="§4-204.54">4-204.54</cite>, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1553, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 1503(b), 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-204.52">4-204.52</cite> and § <cite path="§7-1811.03">7-1811.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite>, in subsecs. (a) and (b), substituted “Medicaid, Medicare, Foster Care and Adoption Assistance, and Special Education reform” for “Medicaid and Special Education reform”.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1503(b) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1503(b) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 5142 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 5142 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 5142 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> provided:</text>
      <text>“(a) Beginning on June 1, 2012, unspent funds from Medicaid underenrollment, calculated on a fiscal year basis, shall be set aside in a fund to offset the costs to implement the South Capitol Street Memorial Amendment Act of 2012 effective June 7, 2012 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>;  59 DCR 3083) (‘South Capitol Street Memorial Amendment Act’).</text>
      <text>“(b) This section shall not apply if the South Capitol Street Memorial Amendment Act is fully funded, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer, either by the terms of this section or pursuant to section 10002(3) of the Revised Revenue Estimate Contingency Priority List Act of 2012, passed on 2nd reading on June 5, 2012 (Enrolled version of Bill 19-743).”</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
