<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-210.09</num>
  <heading>Time limit on requests.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A request for a hearing to review adverse action by the Mayor concerning any new application for public assistance or any application or request for a change in the amount, kind, or conditions of public assistance must be made within 90 days following the postmark of the notification to the applicant or recipient, pursuant to § <cite path="§4-210.04">4-210.04</cite>, of such adverse action by the Mayor and of his or her right to a hearing with respect to that action.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A request for a hearing to review a decision by the Mayor to terminate, reduce, or change the amount, kind, or conditions of public assistance benefits, or to take other action adverse to the recipient must be made within 90 days following the postmark of notice from the Mayor of his or her intention to make such change or take such action.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A request for a hearing must be granted by the Mayor. A time and place shall be designated for such hearing and the applicant shall be notified of such time and place within 5 days of this request for a hearing. Hearing shall be held within a reasonably short time following the request, such time not to exceed 45 days following the initial request for a hearing.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 1009, 29 DCR 1060</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-35" type="History">Sept. 10, 1985, D.C. Law 6-35, § 2(o), 32 DCR 3778</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-205.59">4-205.59</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-210.9.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
