<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-210.04</num>
  <heading>Notification of right to request hearing and method of making request.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Written information regarding the right to request a hearing and the method of making such request shall be furnished by the Mayor to each public assistance applicant or recipient at the time of application and whenever the Mayor notifies the applicant or recipient that it intends to take action which may or will adversely affect him or her or his or her benefits, including changes in or terminations of assistance payments. Such written notice shall include information that the claimant has the right to be represented by legal counsel or by a lay person who is not an employee of the District; that he may bring witnesses in his or her behalf; that reasonable expenses related to the hearing, such as transportation costs for the claimant and his or her witnesses, will be paid by the Mayor, and that legal services are available to the claimants.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A copy of the rules relating to hearing procedures will be furnished to all claimants at the time a hearing is requested pursuant to § <cite path="§4-210.05">4-210.05</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 1004, 29 DCR 1060</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-241" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 2(iii), 46 DCR 905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-210.09">4-210.09</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-210.4.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(iii) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 12-230">D.C. Law 12-230</law-cite>, April 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 4143).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(iii) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-372, June 9, 1998,  45 DCR 4270), § 2(iii) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-425, July 31, 1998,  45 DCR 5682),§ 2(iii) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-552, December 24, 1998,  46 DCR 521), and § 2(iii) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-19, February 17, 1999,  46 DCR 2492).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
