<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-212.02</num>
  <heading>Protective or vendor payments on behalf of dependent children.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may authorize protective or vendor payments on behalf of dependent children under the following conditions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>It has been clearly determined that the parent or relative persistently mismanages the assistance payment to the detriment of the child as evidenced by such factors as the improper clothing and feeding of the children, failure to pay rent resulting in repeated evictions, and other similar indications of money mismanagement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The individual selected as payee for the family has demonstrated his or her interest and concern in the welfare of the family, has the ability to establish and maintain a positive relationship and help the family to make proper use of the assistance payment, and is a responsible and dependable person. Members of the staff of the Mayor or persons whose selection might create a conflict of interest, such as grocers or landlords, shall not be selected as payees.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A determination has been made as to what requirements, if any, will be met by vendor payments to persons providing goods and services with, to the extent possible, the participation and consent of the caretaker in the assistance unit.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, with the cooperation of the payee, will undertake and continue special efforts to develop greater ability on the part of the relative to manage funds in such manner as to protect the welfare of the family.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The cases of children for whom protective or vendor payments are being made shall be reviewed at least every 6 months to determine whether there is a need to continue such payments, or, if the relative is considered able to manage funds in the best interest of the children, whether assistance can be resumed as a direct money payment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Provision will be made for termination of protective payments, or payments to a person furnishing goods or services, as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When caretakers are considered able to manage funds in the best interest of the child, there will be a return to money payment status.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When it appears that need for protective payments or payments to a person furnishing goods or services will continue or is likely to continue beyond 1 year because all efforts have not resulted in sufficiently improved use of assistance in behalf of the child, judicial appointment of a guardian, or other legal representative may be sought and such payments will terminate when the appointment has been made.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An opportunity for a fair hearing will be given to the relative of the children with respect to the determination of whether a protective or vendor payment should be made or continued, the selection of the payee, or if foster care should be provided.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 1202, 29 DCR 1060</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-241" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 2(qqq), 46 DCR 905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-212.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(x) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-7">D.C. Law 12-7</cite>, August 1, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 4639).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(x) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-130">D.C. Law 12-130</cite>, July 24, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 6501).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(qqq) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-230">D.C. Law 12-230</cite>, April 20, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 4143).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-25, February 27, 1997,  44 DCR 1778), and § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-77, May 27, 1997,  44 DCR 3181).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-306, March 20, 1998,  45 DCR 1900).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(qqq) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-372, June 9, 1998,  45 DCR 4270), § 2(qqq) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-425, July 31, 1998,  45 DCR 5682), § 2(qqq) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment  Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-552, December 24, 1998,  46 DCR 521), and § 2(qqq) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-19, February 17, 1999,  46 DCR 2492).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
