<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-220.01</num>
  <heading>Nonrevival of previously repealed or superseded laws, acts, regulations, Commissioner’s orders, Commissioners’ orders, and administrative orders; effect of amendments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this subchapter shall not cause the revival of any law, act, regulation, Commissioner’s order, Commissioners’ order, or administrative order (for the purposes of this subchapter and Title XXIII, “public enactment”) previously repealed or superseded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any amendment to a law effected by a law, act, regulation, Commissioner’s order, Commissioners’ order, or administrative order in § 2101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-101">D.C. Law 4-101</cite> to a public enactment not therein contained shall be considered as having been made on the date of the original enactment of such public enactment and shall continue in effect.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Public enactments repealed by § 2101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-101">D.C. Law 4-101</cite> shall be considered to have been in effect from their date of original enactment until April 6, 1982, as provided in title XXIII.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 2102, 29 DCR 1060</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-220.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“Title XXIII,” referred to in subsections (a) and (c) of this section, is Title XXIII of the Act of April 6, 1982, <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-101">D.C. Law 4-101</cite>, which contained a disposition table of prior public enactments regarding public assistance programs. <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-101">D.C. Law 4-101</cite> was an attempt to draw together without substantive change a variety of prior enactments, many of which had never been codified. <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-101">D.C. Law 4-101</cite> repealed the following public enactments: Chapter 2 of Title 4 of the D.C. Code; certain uncodified D.C. Laws which included 1-74, 1-92, 1-108, and  3-3; certain sections of Act 4-133; and all or portions of certain regulations which included 68-20, 68-28, 68-28a, 69-1, 69-3, 69-19, 69-23, 69-24, 69-26, 69-27, 69-29, 69-30, 69-37, 69-40, 69-49, 69-50, 69-58, 69-59, 70-9, 70-12, 70-29, 71-2, 71-24, 71-29, and 72-17.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
