<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-251.04</num>
  <heading>Subsidies.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All subsidies established under this chapter shall be subject to the availability of appropriations. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as creating an entitlement to a subsidy for any person.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to § <cite path="§4-251.06">4-251.06</cite>, the Mayor shall establish by rule the amount of a subsidy a grandparent or relative caregiver is eligible to receive under this chapter; provided, that the subsidy shall be at least 66%, but no more than 105%, of the regular daily rate of the subsidy for a long-term permanent Level 1 guardianship established under § <cite path="§29-6103.3">29-6103.3</cite> of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The amount of a subsidy a grandparent or relative caregiver is eligible to receive under this chapter shall be offset by any amount a grandparent or relative caregiver receives as TANF or Supplemental Security Income for the child.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-69" type="History" path="§104">Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-69, § 104, 53 DCR 54</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-21" type="History">Sept. 20, 2007, D.C. Law 17-21, § 3(b), 54 DCR 6835</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 502, 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-40" type="History">Dec. 15, 2015, D.C. Law 21-40, § 2(c), 62 DCR 13746</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-21">D.C. Law 17-21</law-cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “within 5% (no less than 95% and no more than 105%) of the regular daily rate of the subsidy for a long-term permanent Level 1 guardianship” for “no less than the regular daily rate of the subsidy for a long-term permanent guardianship”; and, in subsec. (c), substituted “receives as TANF or Supplemental Security Income” for “receives from TANF”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</law-cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “that the subsidy shall be at least 66%, but no more than 105%” for “that the subsidy shall be within 5% (no less than 95% and no more than 105%)”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-40">D.C. Law 21-40</law-cite> substituted “grandparent or relative caregiver” for “grandparent” throughout (b) and (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Grandparent Caregivers Program Subsidy Transfer Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-177">D.C. Law 20-177</law-cite>, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 21).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 104 of Grandparent Caregivers Pilot Program Establishment Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-278, February 22, 2006,  53 DCR 1459).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Safe and Stable Homes for Children and Youth Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-69, July 9, 2007,  54 DCR 6826).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 502 of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the Grandparent Caregivers Program Subsidy Transfer Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-508, Dec. 8, 2014, 61 DCR 12717, 20 STAT 4429, 20 STAT 4429).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the Grandparent Caregivers Program Subsidy Transfer Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-33, Mar. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 4540, 21 DCSTAT 870).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of the Grandparent Caregivers Program Subsidy Transfer Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-200, Nov. 23, 2015,  62 DCR 15270).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 501 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</law-cite> provided that subtitle A of title V of the act may be cited as “Grandparent Caregivers Program and Long-Term Permanent Guardianship Subsidies Amendment Act of 2010”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 503 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</law-cite> provided: “Sec. 503. Applicability. This subtitle shall apply as of January 1, 2011.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
