<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-251.03</num>
  <heading>Eligibility.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A grandparent may be eligible to receive subsidy payments under this section if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The grandparent has been the child’s primary caregiver for at least the previous 6 months.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The child has resided in the grandparent’s home for at least the previous 6 months;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The child’s parent has not resided in the grandparent’s home for at least the previous 6 months; provided, that a parent may reside in the home without disqualifying the grandparent from receiving a subsidy if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The parent has designated the grandparent to be the child’s standby guardian pursuant to Chapter 48 of Title 16;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The parent is a minor enrolled in school; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The parent is a minor with a medically verifiable disability under criteria that shall be prescribed by the Mayor pursuant to § <cite path="§4-251.06">4-251.06</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The grandparent, and all adults residing in the grandparent’s home, has submitted to a criminal background check;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The grandparent’s household income is under 200 percent of the federally-defined poverty level;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The grandparent is a resident of the District as defined by § <cite path="§4-205.03">4-205.03</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The grandparent has applied for Temporary Assistance for Needy Families benefits for the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The grandparent has entered into a subsidy agreement that includes a provision that no payments received under the agreement shall inure to the benefit of the child’s parent but shall be solely for the benefit of the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8A)</num>
      <text>The grandparent is not currently receiving a guardianship or adoption subsidy for the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The grandparent has provided a signed statement, sworn under penalty of perjury, that the information provided to establish eligibility pursuant to this section, or any rules promulgated pursuant to § <cite path="§4-251.06">4-251.06</cite>, is true and accurate to the best belief of the grandparent applicant; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The grandparent has met any additional requirements prescribed by the Mayor pursuant to rules issued under § <cite path="§4-251.06">4-251.06</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may waive the eligibility requirements established in subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Agency determines that the child is at risk of removal from the parent, guardian, or custodian pursuant to § <cite path="§4-1301.07">4-1301.07</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The parent, guardian, or custodian permits the grandparent to be the child’s primary caregiver; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The parent, guardian, or custodian permits the child to reside with the grandparent.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall recertify the eligibility of each grandparent receiving a subsidy on at least an annual basis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of the recertification, a grandparent may be required to provide a signed statement, sworn under penalty of perjury, that the information provided to establish continued eligibility pursuant to this section, or any rules promulgated pursuant to § <cite path="§4-251.06">4-251.06</cite>, remains true and accurate to the best belief of the grandparent.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall terminate subsidy payments to a grandparent at any time if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Mayor determines the grandparent no longer meets the eligibility requirements established by this section, or by rules issued under § <cite path="§4-251.06">4-251.06</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>There is a substantiated finding of child abuse or neglect against the grandparent caregiver resulting in the removal of the child from the grandparent’s home.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A grandparent whose subsidy payments are terminated as a result of the removal of the child from the grandparent’s home may reapply if the child has been returned to the grandparent’s home.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Eligibility for subsidy payments under this section may continue until the child reaches 18 years of age.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An applicant whose application for a subsidy has been denied or whose subsidy has been terminated shall be entitled to a hearing under the applicable provisions of Chapter 5 of Title 2; provided that a grandparent shall not be entitled to a hearing if the denial or termination of a subsidy is based upon the unavailability of appropriated funds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Any statement under this section made with knowledge that the information set forth therein is false shall be subject to prosecution as a false statement under § <cite path="§22-2405">22-2405</cite>(a).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-69" type="History">Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-69, § 103, 53 DCR 54</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-21" type="History">Sept. 20, 2007, D.C. Law 17-21, § 3(a), 54 DCR 6835</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-261, § 2, 60 DCR 1296</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-251.05">4-251.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-21">D.C. Law 17-21</cite>, in subsec. (a), rewrote pars. (1) and (3) and added par. (8A); and added subsec. (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-261">D.C. Law 19-261</cite> added (a-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-69">D.C. Law 16-69</cite>, § 103a, concerning transfer of subsidy, see § 2(b) of the Grandparent Caregivers Program Subsidy Transfer Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-177">D.C. Law 20-177</cite>, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 21).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 103 of Grandparent Caregivers Pilot Program Establishment Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-278, February 22, 2006,  53 DCR 1459).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of Safe and Stable Homes for Children and Youth Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-69, July 9, 2007,  54 DCR 6826).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of (a-1), see § 2 of the Grandparent Caregivers Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-571, December 20, 2012,  60 DCR 97.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Grandparent Caregivers Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-37, March 19, 2013,  60 DCR 4659, 20 DCSTAT 520).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-69">D.C. Law 16-69</cite>, § 103a, concerning transfer of subsidy, see § 2(b) of the Grandparent Caregivers Program Subsidy Transfer Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-508, Dec. 8, 2014, 61 DCR 12717, 20 STAT 4429).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-69">D.C. Law 16-69</cite>, § 103a, concerning transfer of subsidy, see § 2(b) of the Grandparent Caregivers Program Subsidy Transfer Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-33, Mar. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 4540, 21 DCSTAT 870).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
