<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-271.01</num>
  <heading>SOAR Pilot Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established within the Department of Human Services (“Department”) a SSI/SSDI Outreach, Access, and Recovery, or SOAR Pilot Program (“Program”) to provide application assistance for individuals applying to receive Supplemental Security Income (“SSI”) and Social Security Disability Insurance (“SSDI”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Department may contract with, or provide a grant to, a qualified community- based nonprofit corporation, organization, or consortia of organizations, with offices located in the District, to operate the Program. The Department shall establish the criteria that an entity must meet to be selected to operate the Program. If the Department is unable to contract with an outside entity that meets the specified criteria, or determines it to not be in the best interest of the District, the Department shall operate the Program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A grant issued under this subsection shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1 [§ <cite path="§1-328.11">1-328.11</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Program shall conduct outreach to homeless individuals to provide intensive assistance and support with completing an SSI or SSDI application with the federal Social Security Administration.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  5132, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this chapter, see § 5142 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this chapter, see § 5132 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this chapter, see § 5132 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
