<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-406</num>
  <heading>Responsibility of Department for payment.</heading>
  <text>The Department shall be responsible for payment of day care fees to:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A child development home, after admission of a particular child, for its part of the appropriate rate for up to 15 consecutive days for that child when absence is caused by illness of the child or a change in the parent’s training status, provided the child is in regular attendance and the parent remains eligible or a space is being reserved;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A child development home or child development center that has contracted with the Mayor to provide day care services and that has documented that services were provided (this payment shall include payment for District and federal holidays and snow days);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>An in-home caregiver, only for those days when the in-home caregiver is present in the home of the mother or caretaker relative and rendering services as agreed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-16">Sept. 19, 1979, D.C. Law 3-16, § 7, 26 DCR 20</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-174">Mar. 15, 1985, D.C. Law 5-174, § 2(a), 32 DCR 743</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-216">Apr. 13, 1999, D.C. Law 12-216, § 2(e), 46 DCR 281</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 3-306.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 3-306.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Day Care Policy Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-72">D.C. Law 12-72</cite>, March 20, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 2107).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(e) of the Day Care Policy Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-207, December 15, 1997,  44 DCR 353), § 2(e) of the Day Care Policy Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-509, November 10, 1998,  45 DCR 8146), and § 2(e) of the Day Care Policy Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-12, February 8, 1999,  46 DCR 2330).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
