<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-503</num>
  <heading>Administration of Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The administration of the Program is hereby designated to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia (“Court”), which shall issue rules and regulations as are necessary to carry out the provisions and purposes of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All records and computer software relating to the functions of the Program as originally established by the Victims of Violent Crime Compensation Act of 1981, effective April 6, 1982 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 4-100">D.C. Law 4-100</cite>; <cite path="§4-531">§ 4-531</cite> et seq.) [repealed], are hereby transferred to the Court for the exclusive purpose of operating the Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Court shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Investigate claims filed pursuant to this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Obtain from an agency or department of the District of Columbia government or the United States government information, data, and assistance that will enable the Court to determine if a crime was committed or attempted and whether the claimant is eligible for compensation under this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Process and maintain claims in the order they are filed, including claims previously filed pursuant to the Victims of Violent Crime Compensation Act of 1981, effective April 6, 1982 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 4-100">D.C. Law 4-100</cite>; <cite path="§4-531">§ 4-531</cite> et seq.) [repealed];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Determine each claim filed pursuant to this chapter and reinvestigate or reopen cases when necessary;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Require and direct medical examination of victims or secondary victims when necessary;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Publicize the existence of the Program and the procedure for obtaining compensation under the Program through the Court and the Crime Victims Compensation Appeals Board (“Board”), the District of Columbia Metropolitan Police Department, the U.S. Attorney’s Office, the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia, and other public or private agencies, organizations, and service providers; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Provide printed informational materials, including brochures and posters, in both English and Spanish.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-243" type="History" path="§4">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-243, § 4, 44 DCR 1142</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“The Victims of Violent Crime Compensation Act of 1981, effective April 6, 1982 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 4-100">D.C. Law 4-100</cite>;  D.C. Code <cite path="§3-401">§ 3-401</cite> et seq.),” referred to in (b) and (c)(3), was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-243">D.C. Law 11-243</cite>, § 20, effective April 9, 1997.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">See note to <cite path="§4-501">§ 4-501</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-423.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
