<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-551</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Domestic violence” means a pattern of abusive behavior in any relationship that is used by one partner to gain or maintain power and control over another intimate partner, dating partner, or family member. The term “domestic violence” includes physical, sexual, emotional, economic, or psychological actions or threats of actions that influence another person. This consists of any behaviors that intimidate, manipulate, humiliate, isolate, frighten, terrorize, coerce, threaten, blame, hurt, injure, or wound someone.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Domestic violence counselor” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§14-310">14-310</cite>(a)(2).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Domestic violence program” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§14-310">14-310</cite>(a)(3).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Hotline” means the Domestic Violence Hotline program established by § <cite path="§4-552">4-552</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Office” means the Office of Victim Services, established by Mayor’s Order 2004-119, issued July 19, 2004 (51 DCR 7997).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 3032, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 3032 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 3032 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <annotation>Section 3031 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle D of Title III of the act may be cited as the “Domestic Violence Hotline Establishment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
