<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-553</num>
  <heading>Task force.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning October 1, 2013, the Office shall establish a task force to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assess staff and technology needs of the Hotline; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Develop mechanisms for administration of the Hotline; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Develop standards that coincide with the standards used by the existing domestic violence first responder line.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The task force shall include representatives from the D.C. Coalition Against Domestic Violence, governmental victim services programs, and domestic violence programs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>By January 30, 2014, the task force shall transmit to the Office and to the Office of the Secretary to the Council a report that includes the assessments and developments completed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 3034, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 3034 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 3034 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 3031 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that Subtitle D of Title III of the act may be cited as the “Domestic Violence Hotline Establishment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite>: Section 11001 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
