<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-561.06</num>
  <heading>Reviews and reporting requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The independent expert consultant shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Prepare, by June 1, 2015, and on a semiannual basis thereafter, a public report that contains:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A description of the work conducted by the independent expert consultant for that period;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The methodology and specific findings for each review conducted, including a general description of the policies and procedures reviewed, the observations of the consultant regarding the MPD’s implementation of those policies and procedures, the training reviewed, and a discussion of any improvements that need to be made;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A determination of whether the MPD’s implementation of reforms made after March 2013 are having a positive effect on the overall investigations of sexual assaults and whether there are any unintended negative consequences of these new policies or reforms;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>A comparison of cases reported to the MPD through the DC SANE Program and MPD case numbers to ensure that all sexual assaults have been documented; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>The Chief of Police’s formal response to the report prepared pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Review the case review plan and process developed pursuant to § <cite path="§4-561.14">4-561.14</cite>(d)(1), making recommendations for improvement as needed.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A draft version of the report shall be provided to the Chief of Police for review before the public issuance of the final report.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Chief of Police shall have 30 days to review the report and prepare a formal response for purposes of a public report issued pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The independent consultant shall, within 45 days of being retained by the OVS, develop a plan and a schedule for conducting the reviews and preparing the report described in subsection (a)(1) of this section, and shall submit this plan to the OVS for review and approval.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The plan established pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include a timeline for submitting any recommendations to the Council or the Mayor regarding proposed legislation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The OVS shall complete a review of the independent expert consultant’s plan developed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section within 30 days from the date of receipt.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-139" type="History" path="§206">Nov. 20, 2014, D.C. Law 20-139, § 206, 61 DCR 5913</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
