<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-561.12</num>
  <heading>Establishment of a Sexual Assault Response Team.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Sexual Assault Response Team.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The SART shall be a partnership of public and private agencies that coordinates a high-quality, multidisciplinary, victim-centered response to sexual assault cases.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Membership on the SART shall consist of the following persons:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director of the OVS, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The SART coordinator, who shall be appointed by the Director of the OVS;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Chief of Police, or his or her designee; provided, that the designee is a member of the Sexual Assault Unit with the rank of Captain or above;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A representative from the MPD Victim Services Branch;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The United States Attorney for the District of Columbia, or his or her designee; provided, that the designee is an attorney assigned to the Sex Offense and Domestic Violence Section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A representative from the Victim Witness Assistance Unit of the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A representative from the United States Park Police;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The Director, or his or her designee, of a private or nonprofit entity that is a member of the DC SANE Program; provided, that the designee is a forensic nurse examiner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The Director, or his or her designee, of a community-based advocacy organization that is providing advocacy services as part of the DC SANE Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>A representative, selected by the OVS, from a community-based organization that is providing post-assault mental health services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>A representative from the designated State Sexual Assault Coalition for the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>The Director of DFS, or his or her designee; provided, that the designee is a forensic scientist;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>The Chief Medical Examiner, or his or her designee; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>A representative from a District of Columbia-based college or university; provided, that the representative holds a position at that institution that provides direct victim services to sexual assault victims.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The SART shall hold its initial meeting within 90 days after November 20, 2014. At the initial meeting, one non-governmental member of the SART shall be elected as Chairperson by a majority of the SART members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Following the SART’s initial meeting, the SART shall meet at least 6 times per calendar year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The SART shall establish its own procedures and requirements with respect to the place and manner in which it will conduct its meetings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Subchapter IV of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-571">2-571</cite> et seq.] does not apply to meetings of the SART.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-139" type="History" path="§212">Nov. 20, 2014, D.C. Law 20-139, § 212, 61 DCR 5913</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
