<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-753.02</num>
  <heading>Eligibility for services within the Continuum of Care.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An individual or family is eligible to receive services within the Continuum of Care if the individual or family:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is a resident of the District, as defined by § <cite path="§4-751.01">4-751.01</cite>(32), except that low-barrier shelters and severe weather shelters operating as low-barrier shelters shall not be required to receive demonstration of residency or prioritize District residents, pursuant to subsection (b) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Meets any additional eligibility requirements that have been established pursuant to § <cite path="§4-754.31">4-754.31</cite> by the provider from whom services are sought.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a)(2) of this section, the Mayor may exclude certain services within the Continuum of Care from the residency requirement; provided, that the Mayor publishes which services are excluded from the requirement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No individual or family may be deemed ineligible for services solely because the individual or family cannot establish proof of homelessness or residency at the time of the individual or family’s application for assistance. The District shall give priority, however, to an individual or family who establishes proof of residency and homelessness at the time of application for assistance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall operate at least one central intake center for families for the purposes of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Assessing the eligibility of families for services within the Continuum of Care and making appropriate referrals for those services; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Serving as a resource center for families who are seeking information about the availability of services within the Continuum of Care.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1A)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall operate an intake center specializing in crisis intervention services and located in close proximity to the Landlord and Tenant Branch of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1B)</num>
      <text>Intake workers shall provide the following for each individual seeking services:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An overview of the shelter’s policies in regards to the protection of residents based upon actual or perceived sexual orientation and gender identity;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The opportunity for the individual to disclose whether he or she requests special placement or care based on safety concerns due to actual or perceived sexual orientation status or gender identity; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The opportunity to disclose, voluntarily and only following a discussion of the shelter’s policies and accommodations for LGBTQ populations and ability to safeguard confidential information, the individual’s sexual orientation and gender identification and expression; provided, that the intake worker and all staff shall conduct this discussion in a culturally competent manner.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1C)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>No later than 180 days after February 26, 2015, the Mayor shall issue a grant to a community-based organization to establish one or more intake and drop-in center for youth, including minors and youth-headed families, for the purposes of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Assessing the eligibility of youth for services within the Continuum of Care and making referrals, including to the Child and Family Services Agency as appropriate; provided, that homelessness alone is not a valid reason for an allegation of abuse or neglect;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Coordinating as necessary with the intake centers for families operated pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Contacting the parent or guardian of an unaccompanied minor within 72 hours of the minor’s request for services within the Continuum of Care; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Tracking outcomes, utilization rates, and turn-aways of youth across service providers.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Grants issued pursuant to this paragraph shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1 [§ <cite path="§1-328.11">1-328.11</cite> et seq.]</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Families who are eligible for services within the Continuum of Care shall receive appropriate referrals to the first available provider based on the chronological order in which they apply for assistance, consistent with any additional eligibility requirements established pursuant to § <cite path="§4-754.32">4-754.32</cite> by the provider from whom services are sought.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any family who is determined to be eligible for services pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(A) of this section, but who is not immediately served due to lack of capacity, shall be placed on one or more waiting lists for the services sought and shall be served in the order in which appropriate referrals become available.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, in determining what is an “appropriate referral,” the Mayor shall consider relevant factors, including prior receipt of services, disability, family size, affordability of housing, age, and whether an individual is an LGBTQ homeless youth, and may use these factors to prioritize a family’s placement in shelter or other service.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall not impose or apply eligibility criteria that exclude or tend to exclude an individual with a disability or any class of individuals with disabilities from fully and equally enjoying any services within the Continuum of Care, unless such criteria are shown to be necessary for the provision of the services.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If eligibility for a family seeking shelter cannot be determined pursuant to subsection (a) of this section on the business day on which the family applies for shelter, the Mayor may place the family in an interim eligibility placement for a period not to exceed 3 days.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may extend an interim eligibility placement no more than 3 times; provided, that an interim eligibility placement shall not exceed a period of 12 days, except as otherwise provided in paragraph (6) of this subsection and § <cite path="§4-754.11">4-754.11</cite>(a)(20).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall issue an eligibility determination pursuant to subsection (a) of this section to a family placed in an interim eligibility placement within 12 days of the start of the interim eligibility placement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the Mayor does not issue an eligibility determination within 12 days of the start of an interim eligibility placement, the interim eligibility placement shall conclude and the family shall be considered eligible for shelter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>If the Mayor determines that a family in an interim eligibility placement is eligible for shelter, the Mayor shall place that family in shelter, subject to the requirements of § <cite path="§4-753.01">4-753.01</cite>(d).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>If the Mayor determines that a family in an interim eligibility placement is ineligible for shelter pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, because the Mayor determines that the family has access to safe housing or for another reason, the interim eligibility placement shall conclude on the date indicated in the written notice issued pursuant to § <cite path="§4-754.33">4-754.33</cite>(b-1), unless the family has filed a timely fair hearing request pursuant to § <cite path="§4-754.41">4-754.41</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may consider a family that was placed in an interim eligibility placement, but was determined to be ineligible for shelter because the family has access to other safe housing, for the same housing and case management services offered by the Department to family shelter residents.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>If the Mayor determines that a family placed in an interim eligibility placement is ineligible for shelter because the family has access to safe housing, and the family subsequently loses access to that safe housing within 14 days of the Mayor’s determination, the Mayor shall place the family in shelter if the Mayor determines that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The family is participating in prevention and diversion services; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The family has no access to other safe housing that complies with paragraph (9) of this subsection.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>For purposes of determining the eligibility of a family in an interim eligibility placement for shelter pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, safe housing, in addition to meeting the definition of “safe housing” set forth in § <cite path="§4-751.01">4-751.01</cite>(32A), shall satisfy the following criteria:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The family shall be expected to have access to the safe housing for at least 14 days; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To the best of the provider’s knowledge, the family’s presence in the safe housing shall not imminently jeopardize the tenancy of any household already occupying the safe housing.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Other than during a hypothermia alert, no provision under this subsection shall be construed to require the Mayor to provide shelter to a family if there is no existing capacity in the shelter system or if the Department has exhausted its appropriation for family shelter services.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall operate a computerized information system to collect, maintain, and distribute up-to-date information regarding the number of beds or units available in shelter and supportive housing in the District, the availability of supportive services, and the current usage and unmet demand for such beds, units, and services.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Intake providers shall enter the information provided pursuant to subsection (c)(1B) of this section in the computerized information system.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History" path="§8">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 8, 52 DCR 8113</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-296" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-296, § 2(f), 54 DCR 1097</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-367" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-367, § 2(c), 58 DCR 987</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-100" type="History">May 3, 2014, D.C. Law 20-100, § 2(e), 61 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 5102(d), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-75" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-75, § 2(c), 63 DCR 257</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-752.02">4-752.02</cite>, § <cite path="§4-754.21">4-754.21</cite>, § <cite path="§4-754.34">4-754.34</cite>, and § <cite path="§4-756.02">4-756.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-296">D.C. Law 16-296</law-cite>, in subsec. (c), added par. (1A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-367">D.C. Law 18-367</law-cite>, in subsec. (a)(2), substituted “§ <cite path="§4-751.01">4-751.01</cite>(32), except that low-barrier shelters and severe weather shelters operating as low-barrier shelters shall not be required to receive demonstration of residency or prioritize District residents, pursuant to subsection (b) of this section; and” for “§ <cite path="§4-205.03">4-205.03</cite>”; added subsec. (a-1); and, in subsec. (b), substituted “for assistance. The District shall give priority, however, to an individual or family who establishes proof of residency and homelessness at the time of application for assistance” for “for assistance”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-100">D.C. Law 20-100</law-cite> added (c)(1B); substituted “housing, age, and whether an individual is an LGBTQ homeless youth” for “housing and age” in (c)(4); and added (d)(2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</law-cite> added (c)(1C).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-75">D.C. Law 21-75</law-cite> added (c-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5102(d) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5102(d) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5102(d) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the Interim Eligibility and Minimum Shelter Standards Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-217, Nov. 30, 2015,  62 DCR 15648).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the Interim Eligibility and Minimum Shelter Standards Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-326, Mar. 3, 2016,  63 DCR 3658).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
