<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-755.01</num>
  <heading>No entitlement to services.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No provision of this chapter shall be construed to create an entitlement (either direct or implied) on the part of any individual or family to any services within the Continuum of Care, other than shelter in severe weather conditions as authorized by <cite path="§4-754.11|(5)" proof="true">§ 4-754.11(5)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No provision of this chapter shall be construed to require the District to expend funds for individuals or families who are eligible for services within the Continuum of Care, beyond the level of the District’s annual appropriation for services within the Continuum of Care.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, a minimum of 10 beds shall be established for LGBTQ homeless youth through a 2-year grant program to establish and maintain facilities for these beds. LGBTQ-identified homeless youth shall have priority preference for the beds established through the 2-year grant program. If beds are not in use by a LGBTQ-identified homeless youth, they may be filled by a non-LGBTQ-identified homeless youth until an LGBTQ-identified homeless youth presents the need for a bed and the non-LGBTQ-identified homeless youth has been transferred pursuant to <cite path="§4-754.34|(a)">§ 4-754.34(a)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Eligibility criteria shall be established to receive a grant. Eligible grantees shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be community organizations based in the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Have expertise in systems of care for LGBTQ homeless youth; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Establish or maintain facilities through these grants that protect the safety of LGBTQ homeless youth through facilities that are specifically for LGBTQ youth and separate from any existing homeless services for the general population.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>At least 30% of the grant funding shall be allocated to support proposals received for social innovation and other demonstration projects that may address the needs of this population with new, promising prevention and service-delivery models; provided, that the number of beds established for LGBTQ youth is no lower than 10.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall expire if the Interagency Council determines that the needs of LGBTQ homeless youth are being met at a rate equal to or higher than the needs of homeless youth in the general population pursuant to <cite path="§4-752.02|(b-1)">§ 4-752.02(b-1)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the Mayor shall fund a minimum of 5 additional shelter beds for homeless youth up to 24 years or age and additional transitional housing capacity for 10 youth 18 to 24 years of age.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Homeless services for youth shall be provided through 2-year grants to eligible community organizations based in the District with expertise in systems of care for homeless youth.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Recipients of grants shall establish, maintain, or expand facilities through these grants that protect the safety of homeless youth through facilities that are specifically for homeless youth and separate from any existing homeless services for the general population.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Grants issued pursuant to this subsection shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of <cite path="1|3">Chapter 3 of Title 1</cite> [<cite path="§1-328.11">§ 1-328.11</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History" path="§28">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 28, 52 DCR 8113</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-100" type="History">May 3, 2014, D.C. Law 20-100, § 2(k), 61 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 5102(e), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-212" type="History">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-212, § 2(d), 61 DCR 13077</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-75" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-75, § 3, 63 DCR 257</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-212">D.C. Law 20-212</cite> provided that the act shall take apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3 of the Interim Eligibility and Minimum Shelter Standards Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-326, Mar. 3, 2016,  63 DCR 3658).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  5102(e) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  5102(e) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  5102(e) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-75">D.C. Law 21-75</cite> repealed the amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-212">D.C. Law 20-212</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-212">D.C. Law 20-212</cite> would have substituted “which shall meet the requirements of this chapter” for “as authorized by <cite path="§4-754.11|(5)" proof="true">§ 4-754.11(5)</cite>” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-100">D.C. Law 20-100</cite> added (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§4-752.02">§ 4-752.02</cite>, <cite path="§4-754.34">§ 4-754.34</cite>, and <cite path="§4-756.02">§ 4-756.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
