<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-754.34</num>
  <heading>Transfer of clients.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A provider may transfer a client to another provider to ensure the client receives the most appropriate services available within the Continuum of Care whenever:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The client consents to the transfer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The provider identifies and secures for the client a placement with another provider that more appropriately meets the client’s medical, mental health, behavioral, or rehabilitative service needs in accordance with the client’s service plan; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The client is a non-LGBTQ-identified youth occupying a bed established pursuant to § <cite path="§4-755.01">4-755.01</cite>(c)(1) and an LGBTQ-identified homeless youth has presented a need for shelter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to the circumstances under which a client may be transferred as described in subsection (a) of this section, a provider may transfer a client when a client fails or refuses to comply with the provider’s Program Rules and the client responsibilities listed in § <cite path="§4-754.13">4-754.13</cite>, or engages in any of the behaviors listed in § <cite path="§4-754.36">4-754.36</cite>(2); provided, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The client has received proper notice of the Program Rules, client responsibilities, and prohibited behaviors, as required by § <cite path="§4-754.33">4-754.33</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The provider has made a good-faith effort to enable the client to comply with the Program Rules so that the client is able to continue receiving services without a transfer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Transfers of clients under this section can be made through direct arrangements with other providers within the Continuum of Care or through coordination with the central intake center established pursuant to § <cite path="§4-753.02">4-753.02</cite>(c)(1). Such efforts shall be documented by the provider in the client’s records.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History" path="§20">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 20, 52 DCR 8113</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-100" type="History">May 3, 2014, D.C. Law 20-100, § 2(j), 61 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-754.11">4-754.11</cite>, § <cite path="§4-754.32">4-754.32</cite>, § <cite path="§4-754.35">4-754.35</cite>, § <cite path="§4-754.36">4-754.36</cite>, § <cite path="§4-754.37">4-754.37</cite>, and § <cite path="§4-755.01">4-755.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-100">D.C. Law 20-100</law-cite> added (a)(3) and made related changes.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
