<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-754.39</num>
  <heading>Mediation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Providers are strongly encouraged to establish internal mediation programs to resolve disputes with clients.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any provider who chooses to establish an internal mediation program shall offer mediation services to any client of the provider, or the client’s representative, who requests them.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon receiving an oral or written request for mediation, the provider shall provide the client or the client’s representative with reasonable written notice of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The time and place of any mediation proceedings; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The client’s right to request a fair hearing for formal review of his or her complaint pursuant to § <cite path="§4-754.41">4-754.41</cite> and his or her right to request administrative review pursuant to § <cite path="§4-754.42">4-754.42</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The provider shall allow the client or the client’s representative to review its records of the client prior to the mediation proceeding.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The provider shall allow the client to be accompanied by a legal or other representative of the client’s choosing in any mediation proceedings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Upon conclusion of the mediation proceedings, the provider shall notify the client of his or her right to request a fair hearing pursuant to § <cite path="§4-754.41">4-754.41</cite>, and the deadline for making such a request, if he or she is not satisfied with the outcome of the mediation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>No member of the provider’s staff who was involved in the incident or incidents at issue in the mediation shall serve as a mediator during the proceedings.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History" path="§25">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 25, 52 DCR 8113</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-754.32">4-754.32</cite>, § <cite path="§4-754.38">4-754.38</cite>, and § <cite path="§4-754.52">4-754.52</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
