<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-754.35</num>
  <heading>Suspension of services.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a client fails or refuses to comply with the provider’s Program Rules and the client responsibilities listed in § <cite path="§4-754.13">4-754.13</cite>, or engages in any of the behaviors listed in § <cite path="§4-754.36">4-754.36</cite>(2), the provider may suspend services to the client for an appropriate period of time in light of the severity of the act or acts leading to the suspension, but in no case for any period longer then 30 days. The suspension may be implemented only when:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The client has received proper notice of the Program Rules, client responsibilities, and prohibited behaviors, as required by § <cite path="§4-754.33">4-754.33</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The provider has made a good-faith effort to enable the client to comply with the Program Rules so that the client is able to continue receiving services without suspension.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Prior to suspension of services, the provider shall make a reasonable effort, given the severity of the situation, to transfer the client to another provider within the Continuum of Care, in accordance with § <cite path="§4-754.34">4-754.34</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A provider may not suspend adult individuals or adult family members in a manner that results in minor children or dependent adults being left unattended in a shelter or supportive housing unit.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 21, 52 DCR 8113</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-754.36">4-754.36</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
