<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-753.05</num>
  <heading>Placement of first-priority homeless families.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When funds that have been allocated for tenant-based assistance under § <cite path="§6-228">6-228</cite> are made available because a family that has been receiving tenant-based assistance no longer requires or has become ineligible for the assistance, the Mayor and the District of Columbia Housing Authority shall use those funds to provide tenant-based assistance to homeless families referred by the Department of Human Services and determined to have first priority to shelter pursuant to 29 DCMR § 2508.01(a)(1). The referrals shall be made in accordance with the special eligibility criteria set forth in 29 DCMR § 2556 through 29 DCMR § 2558.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Funding for tenant-based assistance that has been made available due to reasons other than the circumstances described in subsection (a) of this section shall not be subject to the requirements of subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 8c</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61">as added Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 2092, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-117">June 26, 2014, D.C. Law 20-117, § 2, 61 DCR 2032</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added this section.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-117">D.C. Law 20-117</cite> rewrote this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-236">D.C. Law 19-236</cite> added <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-35">D.C. Law 16-35</cite> § 8c to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“Sec. 8c. Placement of first priority homeless families for the 2012-2013 hypothermia season.</annotation>
      <annotation>“For fiscal year 2013, the Mayor and the District of Columbia Housing Authority may fill vacant Rent Supplement Program tenant-based vouchers, established by section 26c of the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999, effective March 2, 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§6-228">6-228</cite>), with homeless families referred by the Department of Human Services and determined to have first priority to shelter pursuant to  29 DCMR § 2508.01(a)(1), through the end of the 2012-2013 hypothermia season. The referrals shall be made in accordance with the special eligibility criteria set forth in  29 DCMR § 2556 through 29 DCMR § 2558.”</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-236">D.C. Law 19-236</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-35">D.C. Law 16-35</cite>, § 8c, concerning placement of first priority homeless families, see § 2 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Technical Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-56">D.C. Law 20-56</cite>, December 13, 2013,  60 DCR 15165).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-35">D.C. Law 16-35</cite>, § 8c, concerning placement of first priority homeless families for the 2012-2013 hypothermia season, see § 2 of the Local Rent Supplement Program Voucher Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-545, November 16, 2012,  59 DCR 13590).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-35">D.C. Law 16-35</cite>, § 8c, concerning placement of first priority homeless families for the 2012-2013 hypothermia season, see § 2 of the Local Rent Supplement Program Voucher Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-12, February 20, 2013,  60 DCR 3960, 20 DCSTAT 466).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see §§ 2092 and 2093 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-35">D.C. Law 16-35</cite>, § 8c, see §§ 2(a), 2(c), 3(a), and 3(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Technical Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-180, October 4, 2013,  60 DCR 14949).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see §§ 2092 and 2093 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <annotation>Section 2091 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle J of Title II of the act may be cited as the “Local Rent Supplement Sustainment Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-117">D.C. Law 20-117</cite>: Section 18 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-117">D.C. Law 20-117</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
