<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-754.13</num>
  <heading>Client responsibilities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Clients receiving services within the Continuum of Care shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Seek appropriate permanent housing or Housing First, except when the client is residing in severe weather and low barrier shelter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Seek employment, education, or training when appropriate, except when the client is residing in severe weather and low barrier shelter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Refrain from the following behaviors while on a provider’s premises:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The use or possession of alcohol or illegal drugs;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The use or possession of weapons;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Assaulting or battering any individual, or threatening to do so; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Any other acts that endanger the health or safety of the client or any other individual on the premises;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Ensure that children within the client’s family and physical custody are enrolled in school, where required by law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Ensure that the client’s minor children receive appropriate supervision while on the provider’s premises;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Utilize child care services when necessary to enable the adult client to seek employment or housing or to attend school or training, unless the client meets any of the exemptions of <cite path="§4-205.19g">§ 4-205.19g</cite>, or section 5809.4(b)-(e) of Title 29 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, including any subsequent revisions.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Respect the safety, personal rights, and private property of provider staff members and other clients;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Maintain clean sleeping and living areas, including bathroom and cooking areas;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Use communal areas appropriately, with attention to cleanliness and respect for the interests of other clients;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Be responsible for one’s own personal property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Establish and contribute to a savings or escrow account, or other similar savings arrangement, if required by rules established by the Mayor pursuant to <cite path="§4-753.01|(f)">§ 4-753.01(f)</cite> and included in the provider’s Program Rules approved pursuant to <cite path="§4-754.32|(b)">§ 4-754.32(b)</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Follow all Program Rules established by a provider pursuant to <cite path="§4-754.32">§ 4-754.32</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Clients residing in temporary shelter and transitional housing shall participate in the provider’s assessment and case management services.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History" path="§11">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 11, 52 DCR 8113</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5182(d), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 5181 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle Q of Title V of the act may be cited as the “Homeless Services Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5182(d) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5182(d) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added (a)(11); redesignated former (a)(11) as (a)(12); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§4-754.32">§ 4-754.32</cite>, <cite path="§4-754.34">§ 4-754.34</cite>, and <cite path="§4-754.35">§ 4-754.35</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
