<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-752.02</num>
  <heading>Powers and duties of the Interagency Council on Homelessness.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Interagency Council shall provide leadership in the development of strategies and policies that guide the implementation of the District’s policies and programs for meeting the needs of individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In fulfilling the responsibility described in subsection (a) of this section, the Interagency Council shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Coordinate an annual, community-wide needs-assessment and planning process to identify, prioritize, and target needs for services within the Continuum of Care. The needs-assessment shall take into account existing data, including the number of homeless youth and the number of LGBTQ homeless youth in the District, and include input from at least one public hearing, which shall be held at least once each year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At least every 5 years, prepare and publish a strategic plan for services within the Continuum of Care that takes into account existing data and community input;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Prepare an annual plan detailing how the District intends to provide or arrange for services within the Continuum of Care that takes into account existing data and community input, including an assessment of the need for services among subpopulations of homeless individuals or families, including LGBTQ youth;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Review on a regular basis the efforts of each member of the Interagency Council to fulfill the goals and policies of the annual plan prepared pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection, including a review of the number and nature of contracts and grants entered into by each agency to provide services within the Continuum of Care;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Prepare and submit to the Mayor an annual written report evaluating the efforts of each member agency of the Interagency Council to meet the goals and policies of the annual plan prepared pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Direct the Department of General Services to identify vacant public buildings or tax-foreclosed buildings to be used as shelter and supportive housing facilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Provide input into the District’s planning and application for federal funds for services within the Continuum of Care. All applications for federal funds shall take into account the strategic plan developed by the Interagency Council prepared pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Have access to data collected and generated by a computerized information system as set up by the Mayor pursuant to § <cite path="§4-753.02">4-753.02</cite>(d). The data may include the number of beds or units available in the District’s shelter and supportive housing facilities, the availability of supportive services in the District, and the current usage of and unmet demand for such beds, units, and services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>By September 1 of each year, develop a plan, consistent with the right of clients to shelter in severe weather conditions, describing how member agencies will coordinate to provide hypothermia shelter, identifying the specific sites that will be used as hypothermia shelters, and including protocols on how to provide shelter services for unaccompanied minors; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Review reports of the fair hearings and administrative reviews requested or received by clients within the Continuum of Care, which shall include the provider party to the appeal, the subject matter of the appeal, and the final disposition of the appeal.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>Beginning 5 years from May 3, 2014, and every 2 years thereafter, the Interagency Council shall evaluate the service needs of the District’s LGBTQ homeless youth as compared to homeless youth in the general population. If the Interagency Council determines, based on data, that the needs of LGBTQ homeless youth are being met at a rate equal to or higher than the needs of homeless youth in the general population, the provisions of § <cite path="§4-755.01">4-755.01</cite>(c) shall expire.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall, no later than February 1 of each year, make available to all Interagency Council members the District’s proposed budget breakdown of each agency’s appropriations for services within the Continuum of Care. The Interagency Council shall give comments to the Mayor regarding the proposed budget.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Each member agency of the Interagency Council shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Conduct or commission an annual audit of any private entity designated by the agency to approve or allocate any grants or contracts, on behalf of the Mayor, for services within the Continuum of Care, and make available a report of the audit to all Interagency Council members;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Offer training and technical assistance to its employees who directly provide services within the Continuum of Care and to any providers with which the member agency or its designee contracts to deliver the services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Report to the Interagency Council on a quarterly basis currently available data on the number of individuals and families that applied for homeless services and the number of homeless individual or families that were served by the agency and its contractors.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Department of Human Services shall administer the Homeless Prevention Program, established pursuant to Chapter 7B of this title [§  4-771.01], in consultation with the Interagency Council on Homelessness.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History" path="§5">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 5, 52 DCR 8113</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 33(b), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-100" type="History">May 3, 2014, D.C. Law 20-100, § 2(c), 61 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §§  5102(a), 5113, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-754.53">4-754.53</cite> and § <cite path="§4-755.01">4-755.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> substituted “Department of General Services” for “Office of Property Management” in (b)(6).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by D.C. 20-100 substituted “existing data, including the number of homeless youth and the number of LGBTQ homeless youth in the District,” for “existing data” in (b)(1); rewrote (b)(3); and added (b-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> rewrote (b)(9); and added (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> rewrote (b)(9); and added (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  5102(a) and 5123 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  5102(a) and 5113 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  5102(a) and 5113 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 5052 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided: “Sec. 5052. Winter plan report. ”By September 1, 2010, the Department of Human Services shall submit to the Council, along with the annual winter plan required by section 5(b)(9) of Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005, effective October 22, 2005 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-36">D.C. Law 16-36</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§4-752.02">4-752.02</cite>(b)(9)), an evaluation of case management services provided to homeless individuals during the hypothermia season, including a detailed protocol to evaluate residents’ needs to help them emerge from homelessness.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
