<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-1842</num>
  <heading>Training program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Metropolitan Police Department (“MPD”), the Child and Family Services Agency (“CFSA”), and the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services (“DYRS”) shall provide training on human trafficking to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>New law enforcement officers, social workers, and case managers; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Current law enforcement officers, social worker employees, and case managers who have not previously received comparable training.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The training shall be a minimum of 4 hours and shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The nature and dimension of human trafficking;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The legal rights and remedies available to a victim of human trafficking;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The services and facilities available to a victim of human trafficking;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The legal duties imposed on a police officer, social worker, or case manager to enforce the provisions of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-276">D.C. Law 20-276</law-cite>, and to offer protection and assistance to a victim of human trafficking;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Techniques for determining when a person may be a victim of trafficking;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Techniques for handling a human trafficking offense that promotes the safety of the victim; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The particular needs of youth and minor trafficking victims;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>MPD, CFSA, and DYRS shall consult with community organizations that provide training, resources, advocacy, or services to victims of human trafficking for assistance in developing and presenting training on human trafficking.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-239" type="History" path="§112">Oct. 23, 2010, D.C. Law 18-239, §  112</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-276" type="History">as added May 7, 2015, D.C. Law 20-276, § 6(a), 62 DCR 479</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
