<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-1323</num>
  <heading>Obstructing bridges connecting D.C. and Virginia.</heading>
  <text>Effective with respect to conduct occurring on or after August 5, 1997, whoever in the District of Columbia knowingly and willfully obstructs any bridge connecting the District of Columbia and the Commonwealth of Virginia:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Shall be fined not less than $1,000 and not more than $5,000, and in addition may be imprisoned not more than 30 days; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>If applicable, shall be subject to prosecution by the District of Columbia under the provisions of District law and regulation amended by the Safe Streets Anti-Prostitution Amendment Act of 1996.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The fine set forth in this section shall not be limited by § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Pub. L. 105-33" path="§11712|(e)">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 782, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11712(e)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 112(b), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§5-133.17">5-133.17</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-1123.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> added (3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 112(b) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 11721 of title XI of Pub. L. 105-33, 111 Stat. 786, the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, provided that except as otherwise provided in this title, the provisions of this title shall take effect on the later of October 1, 1997, or the day the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority certifies that the financial plan and budget for the District government for fiscal year 1998 meet the requirements of section 201(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, as amended by this title.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “regulation amended by the Safe Streets Anti-Prostitution Amendment Act of 1996,” referred to in (2), is § 5 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 11-130">D.C. Law 11-130</law-cite>, effective May 24, 1996, and found at  43 DCR 1570.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite>: Section 401 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
