<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-1511</num>
  <heading>Fraudulent advertising.</heading>
  <text>It shall be unlawful in the District of Columbia for any person, firm, association, corporation, or advertising agency, either directly or indirectly, to display or exhibit to the public in any manner whatever, whether by handbill, placard, poster, picture, film, or otherwise; or to insert or cause to be inserted in any newspaper, magazine, or other publication printed in the District of Columbia; or to issue, exhibit, or in any way distribute or disseminate to the public; or to deliver, exhibit, mail, or send to any person, firm, association, or corporation any false, untrue, or misleading statement, representation, or advertisement with intent to sell, barter, or exchange any goods, wares, or merchandise or anything of value or to deceive, mislead, or induce any person, firm, association, or corporation to purchase, discount, or in any way invest in or accept as collateral security any bonds, bill, share of stock, note, warehouse receipt, or any security; or with the purpose to deceive, mislead, or induce any person, firm, association, or corporation to purchase, make any loan upon or invest in any property of any kind; or use any of the aforesaid methods with the intent or purpose to deceive, mislead, or induce any other person, firm, or corporation for a valuable consideration to employ the services of any person, firm, association, or corporation so advertising such services.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>May 29, 1916, 39 Stat. 165, ch. 130, § 1</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Food sales, misrepresentation or false advertising, purchase authorization, see § <cite root="37-201.22a">37-201.22a</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Fraud, see § <cite root="22-3221">22-3221</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Proof of intent to defraud, see § <cite root="23-322">23-322</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Theft, see § <cite root="22-3211">22-3211</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="22-1512">22-1512</cite>, § <cite root="22-1513">22-1513</cite>, and § <cite root="37-201.22a">37-201.22a</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 22-1411.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 22-1411.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
