<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-1705</num>
  <heading>Gambling premises; definition; prohibition against maintaining; forfeiture; liens; deposit of moneys in Treasury; penalty; subsequent offenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any house, building, vessel, shed, booth, shelter, vehicle, enclosure, room, lot, or other premises in the District of Columbia, used or to be used in violating the provisions of <cite path="§22-1701">§ 22-1701</cite> or <cite path="§22-1704">§ 22-1704</cite>, shall be deemed “gambling premises” for the purpose of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for any person in the District of Columbia knowingly, as owner, lessee, agent, employee, operator, occupant, or otherwise, to maintain, or aid, or permit the maintaining of any gambling premises.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All moneys, vehicles, furnishings, fixtures, equipment, stock (including, without limitation, furnishings and fixtures adaptable to nongambling uses, and equipment and stock for printing, recording, computing, transporting, safekeeping, or communication), or other things of value used or to be used in:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Carrying on or conducting any lottery, or the game or device commonly known as a policy lottery or policy, contrary to the provisions of <cite path="§22-1701">§  22-1701</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Setting up or keeping any gaming table, bank, or device contrary to the provisions of <cite path="§22-1704">§  22-1704</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Maintaining any gambling premises shall be subject to forfeiture consistent with the standards and procedures set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-278">D.C. Law 20-278</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Whoever violates this section shall be imprisoned not more than 180 days or fined not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>, or both, unless the violation occurs after the person has been convicted of a violation of this section, in which case the person may be imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or fined not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 56-2-ch854" path="§866">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1331, ch. 854, § 866</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 29, 1953, 67 Stat. 95, ch. 159, § 206(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 87-259" type="History">Sept. 21, 1961, 75 Stat. 540, Pub. L. 87-259, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-60" type="History">July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-119" type="History">May 21, 1994, D.C. Law 10-119, § 2(l), 41 DCR 1639</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-151" type="History">Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151, § 105(i), 41 DCR 2608</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-284" type="History">June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-284, § 4, 46 DCR 1328</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 9045, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 201(q), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-278" type="History">June 16, 2015, D.C. Law 20-278, § 305, 62 DCR 1920</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 201(q) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 4 of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-506, November 10, 1998,  45 DCR 45 8139), and § 4 of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-13, February 8, 1999,  46 DCR 2333).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 4 of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization and Street Solicitation for Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-428, August 6, 1998,  45 DCR 5884).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 105(i) of the Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-255, June 22, 1994,  41 DCR 4286).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 13(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-282">D.C. Law 12-282</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-282">D.C. Law 12-282</cite> inserted “designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department or any” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-278">D.C. Law 20-278</cite> rewrote (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>, in (d), substituted the first occurrence of “not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $1,000” and the second occurrence of “not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $2,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “General Fund” for “Treasury of the United States to the credit”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 22-1505.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-1505.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§23-546">§ 23-546</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Search warrants, see <cite path="§23-521">§ 23-521</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Return of property by property clerk, see <cite path="§5-119.16">§ 5-119.16</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-278">D.C. Law 20-278</cite>, referred to in (c)(3), enacted <cite path="41|3">Chapter 3 of Title 41</cite> (<cite path="§41-301">§ 41-301</cite> et seq.), made amendments to the criminal offenses in §§ 48-901.02 and 48-905.02, and made conforming amendments to §§ 7-2507.06a, 8-905, 22-902, 22-1705, 22-2723, 32-1343, 48-905.03, and 50-1501.04.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
