<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-1502</num>
  <heading>Forging or imitating brands or packaging of goods.</heading>
  <text>Whoever wilfully forges, or counterfeits, or makes use of any imitation calculated to deceive the public, though with colorable difference or deviation therefrom, of the private brand, wrapper, label, trademark, bottle, or package usually affixed or used by any person to or with the goods, wares, merchandise, preparation, or mixture of such person, with intent to pass off any work, goods, manufacture, compound, preparation, or mixture as the manufacture or production of such person which is not really such, shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1333, ch. 854, § 879</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-151" type="History">Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151, § 105(e), 41 DCR 2608</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 201(v), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Fraud, see § <cite path="§22-3221">22-3221</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Violations pertaining to registration of containers of milk and beverages composed principally of milk, see §§ <cite path="§36-130">36-130</cite> and <cite path="§36-153">36-153</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Violations pertaining to registration of labor union labels, see § <cite path="§36-203">36-203</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-1402.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 22-1402.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $500”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 105(e) of the Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-255, June 22, 1994,  41 DCR 4286).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 201(v) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
