<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-1341</num>
  <heading>Unlawful entry of a motor vehicle.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It is unlawful to enter or be inside of the motor vehicle of another person without the permission of the owner or person lawfully in charge of the motor vehicle. A person who violates this subsection shall, upon conviction, be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, imprisoned for not more than 90 days, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An employee of the District government in connection with his or her official duties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A tow crane operator who has valid authorization from the District government or from the property owner on whose property the motor vehicle is illegally parked; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A person with a security interest in the motor vehicle who is legally authorized to seize the motor vehicle.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “enter the motor vehicle” means to insert any part of one’s body into any part of the motor vehicle, including the passenger compartment, the trunk or cargo area, or the engine compartment.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-88" type="History" path="§102">Dec. 10, 2009, D.C. Law 18-88, § 102, 56 DCR 7413</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 213(b), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 213(b) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 102 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-227, October 21, 2009,  56 DCR 8668).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 102 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-181, August 6, 2009,  56 DCR 6903).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $500” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§23-581">23-581</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
