<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-2001</num>
  <heading>Definition and penalty; conspiracy.</heading>
  <text>Whoever shall be guilty of, or of aiding or abetting in, seizing, confining, inveigling, enticing, decoying, kidnapping, abducting, concealing, or carrying away any individual by any means whatsoever, and holding or detaining, or with the intent to hold or detain, such individual for ransom or reward or otherwise, except, in the case of a minor, by a parent thereof, shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished by imprisonment for not more than 30 years. For purposes of imprisonment following revocation of release authorized by § <cite path="§24-403.01">24-403.01</cite>, the offense defined by this section is a Class A felony. This section shall be held to have been violated if either the seizing, confining, inveigling, enticing, decoying, kidnapping, abducting, concealing, carrying away, holding, or detaining occurs in the District of Columbia. If 2 or more individuals enter into any agreement or conspiracy to do any act or acts which would constitute a violation of the provisions of this section, and 1 or more of such individuals do any act to effect the object of such agreement or conspiracy, each such individual shall be deemed to have violated the provisions of this section. In addition to any other penalty provided under this section, a person may be fined an amount not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1322, ch. 854, § 812</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 18, 1933, 47 Stat. 858, ch. 103</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-347" type="History">Nov. 8, 1965, 79 Stat. 1307, Pub. L. 89-347, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-302" type="History">June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-302, § 4(g), 47 DCR 7249</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 303(i), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Armed offenses, additional penalty, see §§ <cite path="§22-4501">22-4501</cite> and <cite path="§22-4502">22-4502</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§11-502">11-502</cite>, § <cite path="§22-3152">22-3152</cite>, § <cite path="§22-4001">22-4001</cite>, § <cite path="§23-546">23-546</cite>, and § <cite path="§24-112">24-112</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-2101.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 22-2101.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-302">D.C. Law 13-302</law-cite>, substituted “not more than 30 years” for “life or for any term as the court in its discretion may determine”; and inserted the second sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> added the last sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(g) of the Sentencing Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 13-462, November 7, 2000,  47 DCR 9443).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(g) of Sentencing Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-2, February 2, 2001,  48 DCR 2239).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(g) of Sentencing Reform Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-51, May 2, 2001,  48 DCR 4370).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 303(i) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite>: Section 401 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
