<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-2302</num>
  <heading>Prohibited acts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No person may ask, beg, or solicit alms, including money and other things of value, in an aggressive manner in any place open to the general public, including sidewalks, streets, alleys, driveways, parking lots, parks, plazas, buildings, doorways and entrances to buildings, and gasoline service stations, and the grounds enclosing buildings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No person may ask, beg, or solicit alms in any public transportation vehicle; or at any bus, train, or subway station or stop.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No person may ask, beg, or solicit alms within 10 feet of any automatic teller machine (ATM).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No person may ask, beg, or solicit alms from any operator or occupant of a motor vehicle that is in traffic on a public street.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>No person may ask, beg, or solicit alms from any operator or occupant of a motor vehicle on a public street in exchange for blocking, occupying, or reserving a public parking space, or directing the operator or occupant to a public parking space.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>No person may ask, beg, or solicit alms in exchange for cleaning motor vehicle windows while the vehicle is in traffic on a public street.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>No person may ask, beg, or solicit alms in exchange for protecting, watching, washing, cleaning, repairing, or painting a motor vehicle or bicycle while it is parked on a public street.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>No person may ask, beg, or solicit alms on private property or residential property, without permission from the owner or occupant.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-54" type="History" path="§3">Nov. 17, 1993, D.C. Law 10-54, § 3, 40 DCR 5450</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§22-2304">22-2304</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-3312.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
