<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-2713</num>
  <heading>Premises occupied for lewdness, assignation, or prostitution declared nuisance.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Whoever shall erect, establish, continue, maintain, use, own, occupy, or release any building, erection, or place used for the purpose of lewdness, assignation, or prostitution in the District of Columbia is guilty of a nuisance, and the building, erection, or place, or the ground itself in or upon which such lewdness, assignation, or prostitution is conducted, permitted, or carried on, continued, or exists, and the furniture, fixtures, musical instruments, and contents are also declared a nuisance, and shall be enjoined and abated as hereinafter provided.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Whoever shall erect, establish, continue, maintain, use, own, occupy, or release any building, erection, or place which is resorted to by persons using controlled substances in violation of Chapter 9 of Title 48, for the purpose of using any of these substances or for the purpose of keeping or selling any of these substances in violation of Chapter 9 of Title 48, is guilty of a nuisance, and the building, erection, or place, or the ground itself in or upon which such activity is conducted, permitted, or carried on, continued, or exists, and the furniture, fixtures, and contents thereof, are also declared a nuisance and disorderly house, and shall be enjoined and abated as hereinafter provided.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 63-2-ch16" path="§1">Feb. 7, 1914, 38 Stat. 280, ch. 16, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-127" type="History">June 19, 1998, D.C. Law 12-127, § 2(a), 45 DCR 1304</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 22-2713.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-2713.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§22-2714">22-2714</cite>, § <cite path="§22-2717">22-2717</cite>, and § <cite path="§22-2720">22-2720</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Chief of Police, authority and duty in regard to houses of prostitution, see §§ <cite path="§5-115.06">5-115.06</cite> and <cite path="§5-115.07">5-115.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Action to abate, enjoin, and prevent a drug-related nuisance, where there is reason to believe such exists, see § <cite path="§42-3101">42-3101</cite> et seq.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
