<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-3226.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Applicant” means any individual, sole proprietorship, partnership, association, cooperative, corporation, nonprofit organization, and any other organization required to register with the District to conduct telemarketing in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Certificate of registration” means a document issued by the District government showing that a named individual or business has registered as a telephone solicitor with the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Consumer” means a person who is or may be required to pay for goods or services offered by a telephone solicitor through telemarketing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Goods” or “services” means any real property or any tangible or intangible personal property or services of any kind provided or offered to a consumer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Licensed securities, commodities or investment broker” means a licensed or registered securities, commodities or investment broker.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Seller” means any person, who, in connection with a telemarketing transaction, provides, offers to provide, or arranges for others to provide goods or services to the customer in exchange for consideration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Telemarketing” means a plan, program or campaign which is conducted to induce the purchase of goods or services by use of one or more telephones. Telemarketing does not include a one-time or infrequent transaction unrelated to a pattern of repeated transactions. Telemarketing does not include a telephone call to a consumer:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>As a one-time or infrequent transaction unrelated to a pattern of repeated transactions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>To provide information to a consumer and in which payment for the sale of good or services is not accepted in that telephone call;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>To administer an existing account or service an existing customer (including product safety recalls);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>To respond to a consumer’s request; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>In which payment for the sale of good or services is not accepted in that telephone call.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Telephone solicitor” means a person (acting himself or itself, or through an agent) who initiates a telephone call to a consumer in the District of Columbia as a part of a plan, program, or campaign which is conducted to induce the purchase of goods or services by the use of one or more telephones. A telephone solicitor does not include a person who initiates a telephone call to a consumer:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>As a one-time or infrequent transaction unrelated to a pattern of repeated transactions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>To provide information to a consumer and in which payment for the sale of good or services is not accepted in that telephone call;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>To administer an existing account or service an existing customer (including product safety recalls);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>To respond to a consumer’s request; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Does not accept payment for the sale of good or services in that telephone call.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-164" type="History">Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 126a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-301" type="History">as added June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-301, § 102, 47 DCR 7039</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-42" type="History">Oct. 26, 2001, D.C. Law 14-42, § 18, 48 DCR 7612</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-42">D.C. Law 14-42</cite>, in par. (8)(E), made a nonsubstantive change.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 18 of Technical Amendments Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-108, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7622).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
