<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-3312.03</num>
  <heading>Wearing hoods or masks.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No person or persons over 16 years of age, while wearing any mask, hood, or device whereby any portion of the face is hidden, concealed, or covered as to conceal the identity of the wearer, shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Enter upon, be, or appear upon any lane, walk, alley, street, road highway, or other public way in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Enter upon, be, or appear upon or within the public property of the District of Columbia; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Hold any manner of meeting or demonstration.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The provisions of subsection (a) of this section apply only if the person was wearing the hood, mask, or other device:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>With the intent to deprive any person or class of persons of equal protection of the law or of equal privileges and immunities under the law, or for the purpose of preventing or hindering the constituted authorities of the United States or the District of Columbia from giving or securing for all persons within the District of Columbia equal protection of the law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>With the intent, by force or threat of force, to injure, intimidate, or interfere with any person because of his or her exercise of any right secured by federal or District of Columbia laws, or to intimidate any person or any class of persons from exercising any right secured by federal or District of Columbia laws;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>With the intent to intimidate, threaten, abuse, or harass any other person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>With the intent to cause another person to fear for his or her personal safety, or, where it is probable that reasonable persons will be put in fear for their personal safety by the defendant’s actions, with reckless disregard for that probability; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>While engaged in conduct prohibited by civil or criminal law, with the intent of avoiding identification.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-203" type="History">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-203, § 4, 30 DCR 180</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§22-3312.04">22-3312.04</cite> and § <cite path="§23-581">23-581</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-3112.3.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
