<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-3571.02</num>
  <heading>Applicability of fine proportionality provision.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a sentence to pay a fine under § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> shall be subject to the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a law setting forth the penalty for such an offense specifies a maximum fine that is lower than the fine otherwise applicable under § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> and such law, by specific reference, exempts the offense from the applicability of the fine otherwise applicable under § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, the defendant may not be fined more than the maximum amount specified in the law setting forth the penalty for the offense.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a law setting forth the penalty for such an offense specifies a maximum fine that is higher than the fine otherwise applicable under § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> and such law, by specific reference, exempts the offense from the applicability of the fine otherwise applicable under § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, the defendant may be fined the maximum amount specified in the law setting forth the penalty for the offense.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If a law setting forth the penalty for such an offense specifies no fine and such law, by specific reference, does not exempt the offense from the fine otherwise applicable under § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, the defendant may be fined pursuant to § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If any person derives pecuniary gain from such an offense, or if the offense results in pecuniary loss to a person other than the defendant, the defendant may be fined not more than the greater of twice the gross gain or twice the gross loss.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The court may impose a fine under this subsection in excess of the fine provided for by § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> only to the extent that the pecuniary gain or loss is both alleged in the indictment or information and is proven beyond a reasonable doubt.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>[This chapter and the provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>] shall not apply to any provision of Title 11 of the District of Columbia Official Code.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 102, 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 102 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
