<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-3104</num>
  <heading>Affirmative defenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Under this chapter it shall be an affirmative defense that the defendant in good faith reasonably believed the person appearing in the performance was 18 years of age or over.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, in any prosecution for an offense pursuant to § <cite path="§22-3102">22-3102</cite>(2) it shall be an affirmative defense that the person so charged was:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A librarian engaged in the normal course of his or her employment; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A motion picture projectionist, stage employee or spotlight operator, cashier, doorman, usher, candy stand attendant, porter, or in any other nonmanagerial or nonsupervisory capacity in a motion picture theater.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The affirmative defense provided by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply if the person described therein has a financial interest (other than his or her employment, which employment does not encompass compensation based upon any proportion of the gross receipts) in:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The promotion of a sexual performance for sale, rental, or exhibition;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The direction of any sexual performance; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The acquisition of the performance for sale, retail, or exhibition.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>It shall be an affirmative defense to a charge under § <cite path="§22-3102">22-3102</cite> that the defendant:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Possessed or accessed less than 6 still photographs or one motion picture, however produced or reproduced, of a sexual performance by a minor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Promptly and in good faith, and without retaining, copying, or allowing any person, other than a law enforcement agency, to access any photograph or motion picture:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Took reasonable steps to destroy each such photograph or motion picture; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Reported the matter to a law enforcement agency and afforded that agency access to each such photograph or motion picture.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-173" type="History">Mar. 9, 1983, D.C. Law 4-173, § 5, 29 DCR 5749</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-239" type="History">Oct. 23, 2010, D.C. Law 18-239, § 205(c), 57 DCR 5405</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-2014.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-239">D.C. Law 18-239</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “18” for “16”; and added subsec. (c).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
