<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-3751.01</num>
  <heading>Enhanced penalties for offenses committed against transit operators and Metrorail station managers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person who commits an offense enumerated in § <cite path="§22-3752">22-3752</cite> against a transit operator, who, at the time of the offense, is authorized to operate and is operating a mass transit vehicle in the District of Columbia, or against Metrorail station manager while on duty in the District of Columbia, may be punished by a fine of up to one and 1/2 times the maximum fine otherwise authorized for the offense and may be imprisoned for a term of up to one and 1/2 times the maximum term of imprisonment otherwise authorized by the offense, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Mass transit vehicle” means any publicly or privately owned or operated commercial vehicle for the carriage of 6 or more passengers, including any Metrobus, Metrorail, Metroaccess, or DC Circulator vehicle or other bus, trolley, or van operating within the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Metrorail station manager” means any Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority employee who is assigned to supervise a Metrorail station from a kiosk at that station.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Transit operator” means a person who is licensed to operate a mass transit vehicle.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-307" type="History" path="§2a">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-307, § 2a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-206" type="History">as added July 23, 2008, D.C. Law 17-206, § 2(b), 55 DCR 5168</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§22-3752">22-3752</cite> and § <cite path="§35-261">35-261</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
