<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-3020.52</num>
  <heading>Reporting requirements and privileges.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person who knows, or has reasonable cause to believe, that a child is a victim of sexual abuse shall immediately report such knowledge or belief to the police. For the purposes of this subchapter, a call to 911, or a report to the Child and Family Services Agency, shall be deemed a report to the police.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any person who is or has been a victim of sexual abuse is not required to report pursuant to subsection (a) of this section if the identity of the alleged perpetrator matches the identity of the victim’s abuser.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No legally recognized privilege, except for the following, shall apply to this subchapter:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A lawyer or a person employed by a lawyer is not required to report pursuant to subsection (a) of this section if the lawyer or employee is providing representation in a criminal, civil, or delinquency matter, and the basis for the knowledge or belief arises solely in the course of that representation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The notification requirements of subsection (a) of this subsection do not apply to a priest, clergyman, rabbi, or other duly appointed, licensed, ordained, or consecrated minister of a given religion in the District of Columbia, or a duly accredited practitioner of Christian Science in the District of Columbia, if the basis for the knowledge or belief is the result of a confession or penitential communication made by a penitent directly to the minister if:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The penitent made the confession or penitential communication in confidence;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The confession or penitential communication was made expressly for a spiritual or religious purpose;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The penitent made the confession or penitential communication to the minister in the minister’s professional capacity; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The confession or penitential communication was made in the course of discipline enjoined by the church or other religious body to which the minister belongs.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A confession or communication made under any other circumstances does not fall under this exemption.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section should not be construed as altering the special duty to report by persons specified in § <cite path="§4-1321.02">4-1321.02</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-257" type="History" path="§252">May 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-257, § 252</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-315" type="History">as added June 8, 2013, D.C. Law 19-315, § 4, 60 DCR 1702</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-315">D.C. Law 19-315</cite> added this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
