<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-3225.09</num>
  <heading>Insurance fraud prevention and detection.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 6 months of April 27, 1999, every insurer licensed in the District shall submit to the Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation, an insurance fraud prevention and detection plan (“plan”). The plan shall indicate specific procedures for the accomplishment of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Prevention, detection, and investigation of insurance fraud;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Orientation of employees on insurance fraud prevention and detection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Employment of fraud investigators;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Reporting of insurance fraud to the appropriate authorities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Collection of restitution for financial loss caused by insurance fraud.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may review the plan for compliance with this section and may order reasonable modification or request a summary of the plan. The Commissioner may establish by regulation a fine for an insurer failing to comply with the plan. The plan shall not be deemed a public record for the purposes of any public records or subchapter II of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, an insurer who fails to submit an insurance prevention and detection plan, or the warning provision required by subsection (d) of this section shall be subject to a fine of $500 per day, not to exceed $25,000.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No later than 6 months after April 27, 1999, all insurance application forms and all claim forms shall contain a conspicuous warning in language the same or substantially similar to the following:</text>
    <text>“WARNING: It is a crime to provide false or misleading information to an insurer for the purpose of defrauding the insurer or any other person. Penalties include imprisonment and/or fines. In addition, an insurer may deny insurance benefits if false information materially related to a claim was provided by the applicant.”.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>None of the requirements of this section shall be deemed to apply to reinsurers, reinsurance contracts, reinsurance agreements, or reinsurance claims transactions.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-164" type="History">Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 125i</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-273" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 1999, D.C. Law 12-273, § 2, 46 DCR 1132</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-3825.9.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
