<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-4015</num>
  <heading>Penalties; mandatory release condition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any sex offender who knowingly violates any requirement of this chapter, including any requirement adopted by the Agency pursuant to this chapter, shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, or imprisoned for not more than 180 days, or both. In the event that a sex offender convicted under this section has a prior conviction under this section, or a prior conviction in any other jurisdiction for failing to comply with the requirements of a sex offender registration program, the sex offender shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Compliance with the requirements of this chapter, including any requirements adopted by the Agency pursuant to this chapter, shall be a mandatory condition of probation, parole, supervised release, and conditional release of any sex offender.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-137" type="History" path="§16">July 11, 2000, D.C. Law 13-137, § 16, 47 DCR 797</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 236, 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-801">16-801</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite>, in (a), substituted “not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $1,000” in the first sentence, and for “not more than $25,000” in the second sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 236 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite>: Section 401 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
