<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-4508</num>
  <heading>Transfers of firearms regulated.</heading>
  <text>No seller shall within the District of Columbia deliver a firearm to the purchaser thereof until 10 days shall have elapsed from the date of the purchase thereof, except in the case of sales to marshals, sheriffs, prison or jail wardens or their deputies, policemen, or other duly appointed law enforcement officers, and, when delivered, said firearm shall be transported in accordance with § <cite path="§22-4504.02">22-4504.02</cite>. At the time of purchase, the purchaser shall sign in duplicate and deliver to the seller a statement containing his or her full name, address, occupation, date and place of birth, the date of purchase, the caliber, make, model, and manufacturer’s number of the firearm and a statement that the purchaser is not forbidden by § <cite path="§22-4503">22-4503</cite> to possess a firearm. The seller shall, within 6 hours after purchase, sign and attach his or her address and deliver one copy to such person or persons as the Chief of Police of the District of Columbia may designate, and shall retain the other copy for 6 years. No machine gun, sawed-off shotgun, or blackjack shall be sold to any person other than the persons designated in § <cite path="§22-4514">22-4514</cite> as entitled to possess the same, and then only after permission to make such sale has been obtained from the Chief of Police of the District of Columbia. This section shall not apply to sales at wholesale to licensed dealers.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 8, 1932, 47 Stat. 652, ch. 465, § 8</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 29, 1953, 67 Stat. 94, ch. 159, § 204(e)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-119" type="History">May 21, 1994, D.C. Law 10-119, § 15(g), 41 DCR 1639</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-388" type="History">May 20, 2009, D.C. Law 17-388, § 2(g), 56 DCR 1162</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-170" type="History">Sept. 29, 2012, D.C. Law 19-170, § 3(f), 59 DCR 5691</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-3208.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 22-3208.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-388">D.C. Law 17-388</cite> substituted “firearm” for “pistol”; substituted “10 days” for “48 hours”; and substituted “shall be transported in accordance with § <cite path="§22-4504.02">22-4504.02</cite>” for “shall be securely wrapped and shall be unloaded”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-170">D.C. Law 19-170</cite> in the first sentence, substituted “date of the” for “time of the application for the”; in the second sentence, substituted “time of purchase” for “time of applying for the purchase of a firearm,” substituted “date and” for “color,” substituted “date of purchase” for “date and hour of application,” deleted “to be purchased” following “of the firearm,”; and substituted “purchase” for “such application” in the third sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Inoperable Pistol Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-652, January 6, 2009,  56 DCR 927).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Inoperable Pistol Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-24, March 16, 2009,  56 DCR 2309).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Transfer Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-69, May 13, 2011,  58 DCR 4256).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(f) of Firearms Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-352, May 11, 2012,  59 DCR 5116).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(f) of the Firearms Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-394, July 18, 2012,  59 DCR 8694).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(f) of the Firearms Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-510, October 26, 2012,  59 DCR 12808).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
