<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-404.02</num>
  <heading>Assault on a public vehicle inspection officer.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person commits the offense of assault on a public vehicle inspection officer if that person assaults, impedes, intimidates, or interferes with a public vehicle inspection officer while that officer is engaged in or on account of the performance of his or her official duties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who violates this subsection shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, or be imprisoned for not more than 180 days; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have his or her license or licenses for operating a public vehicle-for-hire, as required by the Commission pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 3 of Title 50 [§ <cite path="§50-301">50-301</cite> et seq.], revoked without further administrative action by the Commission.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>It is neither justifiable nor excusable for a person to use force to resist the civil enforcement authority exercised by an individual believed to be a public vehicle inspection officer, whether or not such enforcement action is lawful.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Commission” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§50-303">50-303</cite>(6).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Public vehicle-for-hire” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§50-303">50-303</cite>(17).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Public vehicle inspection officer” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§50-303">50-303</cite>(19).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 56-2-ch854" path="§806b">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1322, ch. 854, § 806b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-320" type="History">as added June 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-320, § 401, 60 DCR 3390</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-320">D.C. Law 19-320</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 401 of the Omnibus Criminal Code Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-44, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5381, 20 DCSTAT 1281).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of the Act of Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1322, ch. 854, § 806b, concerning assault on a public vehicle inspection officer, see § 401 of the Omnibus Criminal Code Amendments Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-599, January 14, 2013,   60 DCR 1017).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
