<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-4006</num>
  <heading>Duties of the Department of Mental Health.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Agency shall have the authority to notify the Department of Mental Health in writing of those sex offenders in the custody or under the supervision of the Department of Mental Health who are required to register pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>With respect to sex offenders for whom notice has been given pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Department of Mental Health shall inform the Agency when a sex offender:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is first granted unaccompanied access to the hospital grounds or is placed on convalescent leave;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If first conditionally or unconditionally released; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Is on unauthorized leave.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The information provided to the Agency by the Department of Mental Health shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of and other identifying information about a sex offender, including a physical description and photograph, if available;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The action taken under subsection (b) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The date on which the action was taken;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>To the extent known, the address at which the sex offender is living or intends to live, works or intends to work, or attends school or intends to attend school; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Administrative information that may assist the Agency or the Metropolitan Police Department in locating the sex offender.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Agency and the Metropolitan Police Department are authorized to make further disclosures of the information provided by the Department of Mental Health pursuant to this section as necessary to ensure compliance with this chapter and to prosecute violations of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-137" type="History" path="§7">July 11, 2000, D.C. Law 13-137, § 7, 47 DCR 797</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-56" type="History">Dec. 18, 2001, D.C. Law 14-56, § 116(h), 48 DCR 7674</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§22-4012">22-4012</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-56">D.C. Law 14-56</law-cite>, substituted “Department of Mental Health” for “Commission on Mental Health Services” in the heading, and in subsecs. (a), (b), (c), and (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 16(h) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-51">D.C. Law 14-51</law-cite> substituted “Department of Mental Health” for “Commission on Mental Health Services” in the heading; and, in subsecs. (a), (b), (c) and (d), substituted “Department of Mental Health” for “Commission on Mental Health Services”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 19(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-51">D.C. Law 14-51</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 16(h) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-55, May 2, 2001,  48 DCR 4390).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 16(h) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-101, July 23, 2001,  48 DCR 7123).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 116(h) of Mental Health Service Delivery Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-144, October 23, 2001,  48 DCR 9947).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
