<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-4502</num>
  <heading>Additional penalty for committing crime when armed.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person who commits a crime of violence, or a dangerous crime in the District of Columbia when armed with or having readily available any pistol or other firearm (or imitation thereof) or other dangerous or deadly weapon (including a sawed-off shotgun, shotgun, machine gun, rifle, dirk, bowie knife, butcher knife, switchblade knife, razor, blackjack, billy, or metallic or other false knuckles):</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>May, if such person is convicted for the first time of having so committed a crime of violence, or a dangerous crime in the District of Columbia, be sentenced, in addition to the penalty provided for such crime, to a period of imprisonment which may be up to, and including, 30 years for all offenses except first degree murder while armed, second degree murder while armed, first degree sexual abuse while armed, and first degree child sexual abuse while armed, and shall, if convicted of such offenses while armed with any pistol or firearm, be imprisoned for a mandatory-minimum term of not less than 5 years; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shall, if such person is convicted more than once of having so committed a crime of violence, or a dangerous crime in the District of Columbia, or an offense in any other jurisdiction that would constitute a crime of violence or dangerous crime if committed in the District of Columbia, be sentenced, in addition to the penalty provided for such crime, to a period of imprisonment of not less than 5 years and, except for first degree murder while armed, second degree murder while armed, first degree sexual abuse while armed and first degree child sexual abuse while armed, not more than 30 years, and shall, if convicted of such second offense while armed with any pistol or firearm, be imprisoned for a mandatory-minimum term of not less than 10 years.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Shall, if such person is convicted of first degree murder while armed, second degree murder while armed, first degree sexual abuse while armed, or first degree child sexual abuse while armed, be sentenced, in addition to the penalty provided for such crime, to a period of imprisonment of not less than the minimum and mandatory minimum sentences required by subsections (a)(1), (a)(2), (c) and (e) of this section and § <cite path="§22-2104">22-2104</cite>, and not more than life imprisonment or life imprisonment without possibility of release as authorized by § <cite path="§24-403.01">24-403.01</cite>(b-2); § <cite path="§22-2104">22-2104</cite>; § <cite path="§22-2104.01">22-2104.01</cite>; and §§ <cite path="§22-3002">22-3002</cite>, <cite path="§22-3008">22-3008</cite>, and <cite path="§22-3020">22-3020</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For purposes of imprisonment following revocation of release authorized by § <cite path="§24-403.01">24-403.01</cite>(b)(7), the offenses defined by this section are Class A felonies.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any person sentenced pursuant to paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a) above for a conviction of a crime of violence or a dangerous crime while armed with any pistol or firearm, shall serve a mandatory-minimum term of 5 years, if sentenced pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of this section, or 10 years, if sentenced pursuant to paragraph (2) of subsection (a) of this section, and such person shall not be released, granted probation, or granted suspension of sentence, prior to serving such mandatory-minimum sentence.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Subchapter I of Chapter 9 of Title 24 shall not apply with respect to any person sentenced under paragraph (2) of subsection (a) of this section or to any person convicted more than once of having committed a crime of violence or a dangerous crime in the District of Columbia sentenced under subsection (a)(3) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The execution or imposition of any term of imprisonment imposed under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (a) of this section may not be suspended and probation may not be granted.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e-1)</num>
    <text>In addition to any other penalty provided under this section, a person may be fined an amount not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as reducing any sentence otherwise imposed or authorized to be imposed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>No conviction with respect to which a person has been pardoned on the ground of innocence shall be taken into account in applying this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 8, 1932, 47 Stat. 560, ch. 465, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-226" type="History">Dec. 27, 1967, 81 Stat. 737, Pub. L. 90-226, title VI, § 605</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 600, Pub. L. 91-358, title II, § 205</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-166" type="History">Mar. 9, 1983, D.C. Law 4-166, §§ 3-7, 30 DCR 1082</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-69" type="History">Dec. 7, 1985, D.C. Law 6-69, § 9, 32 DCR 4587</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-19" type="History">July 28, 1989, D.C. Law 8-19, § 3(b), 36 DCR 2844</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-120" type="History">May 8, 1990, D.C. Law 8-120, § 3(b), 37 DCR 24</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-119" type="History">May 21, 1994, D.C. Law 10-119, § 15(a), 41 DCR 1639</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-302" type="History">June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-302,§ 6(a), 47 DCR 7249</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-313" type="History">June 19, 2001, D.C. Law 13-313, § 21(b)(1), (2), 48 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-88" type="History">Dec. 10, 2009, D.C. Law 18-88, § 219(a), 56 DCR 7413</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-170" type="History">Sept. 29, 2012, D.C. Law 19-170, § 3(b), 59 DCR 5691</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 310, 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Eligibility for geriatric or medical parole, convictions under this section, see § <cite path="§24-467">24-467</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Institutional and educational good time credit eligibility, minimum sentences under this section, see § <cite path="§24-221.06">24-221.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Minimum sentences, conviction under this section, see § <cite path="§24-403">24-403</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Sentencing, supervised release, and good time credit for conviction of felonies under this section committed on or after August 5, 2000, see § <cite path="§24-403.01">24-403.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-751.01">4-751.01</cite>, § <cite path="§5-113.32">5-113.32</cite>, § <cite path="§22-4513">22-4513</cite>, § <cite path="§23-1322">23-1322</cite>, § <cite path="§24-221.06">24-221.06</cite>, § <cite path="§24-403">24-403</cite>, § <cite path="§24-403.01">24-403.01</cite>, and § <cite path="§24-467">24-467</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-3202.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 22-3202.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-302">D.C. Law 13-302</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), in par. (1), substituted “up to, and including, 30 years for all offenses except first degree murder while armed, second degree murder while armed, first degree sexual abuse while armed, and first degree child sexual abuse while armed imprisonment” for “up to life imprisonment”, in par. (2), substituted “to a period of imprisonment of not less than 5 years and, except for first degree murder while armed, second degree murder while armed, first degree sexual abuse while armed and first degree child sexual abuse while armed, not more than 30 years” for “to a minimum period of imprisonment of not less than 5 years and a maximum period of imprisonment which may not be less than 3 times the minimum sentence imposed and may be up to life imprisonment”, and added pars. (3) and (4); repealed subsec. (b) which had read: “(b) Where the maximum sentence imposed under this section is life imprisonment, the minimum sentence imposed under subsection (a) of this section may not exceed 15 years imprisonment.”; in subsec. (c), deleted “on parole” following “not be released”; and repealed subsec. (d) which had read: “(d) Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, any person sentenced under subsection (a)(2) of this section may be released on parole in accordance with Chapter 4 of Title 24, at any time after having served the minimum sentence imposed under that subsection.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-313">D.C. Law 13-313</law-cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “paragraph (1), (2), or (3)” for “paragraph (1) or (2)”; and, in subsec. (e), in par. (1), inserted “or to any person convicted more than once of having committed a crime of violence or a dangerous crime in the District of Columbia sentenced under subsection (a)(3) of this section”, and in par. (2), substituted “paragraphs (2) or (3)” for “paragraph (2)”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-88">D.C. Law 18-88</law-cite>, in subsec. (a)(2), substituted “Columbia, or an offense in any other jurisdiction that would constitute a crime of violence or dangerous crime if committed in the District of Columbia,” for “Columbia,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-170">D.C. Law 19-170</law-cite> added “or a dangerous crime” following “a crime of violence” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> added (e-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6(a) of the Sentencing Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 13-462, November 7, 2000,  47 DCR 9443).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6(a) of Sentencing Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-2, February 2, 2001,  48 DCR 2239).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6(a) of Sentencing Reform Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-51, May 2, 2001,  48 DCR 4370).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 302(b) of Crime Bill Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-129, June 29, 2009,  56 DCR 5495).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 219(a) of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-181, August 6, 2009,  56 DCR 6903).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 219(a) of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-227, October 21, 2009,  56 DCR 8668).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Firearms Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-352, May 11, 2012,  59 DCR 5116).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of the Firearms Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-394, July 18, 2012,  59 DCR 8694).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (c), see § 3(b) of the Firearms Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-510, October 26, 2012,  59 DCR 12808).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 310 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite>: Section 401 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
