<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-4004</num>
  <heading>Dispute resolution procedures in the Superior Court.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person, other than a person for whom a certification has been made under § <cite path="§22-4003">22-4003</cite>(a), may seek review of a determination by the Agency that the person is required to register or to register for life under this chapter if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The determination depends on a finding or findings which are not apparent from the disposition described in § <cite path="§22-4001">22-4001</cite>(3)(A), including, but not limited to, a finding not apparent from the disposition as to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Whether the victim of an offense was a minor or under 12 year of age;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Whether certain sexual acts or contacts were forcible;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Whether the exemption of § <cite path="§22-4016">22-4016</cite>(b) applies; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Whether the standards under § <cite path="§22-4001">22-4001</cite>(6)(E) or (8)(G) for coverage offenses under the laws of other jurisdictions are satisfied; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The person asserts that the records establishing that he or she was convicted or found not guilty by reason of insanity of a registration offense or offenses or a lifetime registration offense or offenses, or that he or she was determined to be a sexual psychopath as provided in § <cite path="§22-4001">22-4001</cite>(3)(A)(ii), are erroneous.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In order to seek review of a determination, as authorized by paragraph (1) of this subsection, the person shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>At the time the person is first informed by the Agency that it has determined that the person must register as a sex offender or must register as a sex offender for life, provide the Agency with a notice of intent to seek review of the determination; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Within 30 days of providing the notice of intent described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, file a motion in the Court setting forth the facts which he or she disputes and attaching any documents or affidavits upon which he or she intends to rely. The Court shall decide the motion within 60 days of its filing.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If a person fails to follow the procedures set forth in paragraph (2) of this subsection, he or she may nevertheless seek review of a determination, as authorized by paragraph (1) of this subsection, but only for good cause shown and to prevent manifest injustice, by filing a motion within 3 years of the date on which a determination is made by the Agency that the person must register as a sex offender or must register as a sex offender for life. The release and dissemination of information concerning the person, including community notification, as authorized by this chapter for sex offenders will, however, proceed unless and until the Court issues an order that the person is not required to register as a sex offender.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless the motion described in subsection (a) of this section and attached documents and affidavits conclusively show that the person is entitled to no relief, the Court shall cause notice thereof to be served upon the prosecuting attorney.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Court may, in its sole discretion, decide a motion made under subsection (a) of this section on the basis of the motion, affidavits, the files and records of the case, other written documents, proffers of the parties, or an evidentiary hearing. If the Court determines that a hearing is necessary to decide the issue or if the interests of justice otherwise require, the Court shall appoint counsel for the person if he or she is not represented by counsel and meets the financial criteria for the appointment of counsel.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the Court concludes that the person is required to register under this chapter, the Court shall follow the procedures set forth in § <cite path="§22-4003">22-4003</cite>(a) and (b). If the Court concludes that the person is not required to register under this chapter or is not required to register for life under this chapter, the Court shall enter an order certifying that the person is not required to register under this chapter or is not required to register for life under this chapter and shall provide the Agency with a copy of that order.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-137" type="History">July 11, 2000, D.C. Law 13-137, § 5, 47 DCR 797</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§22-4003">22-4003</cite>, § <cite path="§22-4007">22-4007</cite>, § <cite path="§22-4010">22-4010</cite>, § <cite path="§22-4011">22-4011</cite>, and § <cite path="§22-4013">22-4013</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
