<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-4330</num>
  <heading>Seizure of hunting and fishing equipment; sale at public auction and disposal of proceeds; disposal of property not sold at auction; payment of valid liens after sale.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All rifles, shotguns, ammunition, bows, arrows, traps, seines, nets, boats, and other devices of every nature or description used by any person within the District of Columbia when engaged in killing, ensnaring, trapping, or capturing any wild bird, wild mammal, or fish contrary to this chapter or any regulation made pursuant to this chapter shall be seized by any police officer, or any designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department, upon the arrest of such person on a charge of violating any provision of this chapter or any regulations made pursuant thereto, and be delivered to the Mayor. If the person so arrested is acquitted, the property so seized shall be returned to the person in whose possession it was found. If the person so arrested is convicted, the property so seized shall, in the discretion of the court, be forfeited to the District of Columbia, and be sold at public auction, the proceeds from such sale to be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the District of Columbia. If any item of such property is not purchased at such auction, it shall be disposed of in accordance with regulations prescribed by the District of Columbia Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If any property seized under the authority of this section is subject to a lien which is established by intervention or otherwise to the satisfaction of the court as having been created without the lienor’s having any notice that such property was to be used in connection with a violation of any provision of this chapter or any regulation made pursuant thereto, the court, upon the conviction of the accused, may order a sale of such property at public auction. The officer conducting such sale, after deducting proper fees and costs incident to the seizure, keeping, and sale of such property, shall pay all such liens according to their priorities, and such lien or liens shall be transferred from the property to the proceeds of the sale thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-730" type="History">Aug. 23, 1958, 72 Stat. 814, Pub. L. 85-730, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-284" type="History">June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-284, § 5, 46 DCR 1328</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Return of property by property clerk, see § <cite path="§5-119.16">5-119.16</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-1630.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 22-1630.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-282">D.C. Law 12-282</cite> inserted “or any designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department” in the first sentence of (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 13(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-282">D.C. Law 12-282</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary provision, on an emergency basis, making available for a reasonable fee the name, address, date of birth, occupation, and photograph of persons convicted of violation of §§ 22-2701 or 22-2703 1981 Ed., see § 2 of the Safe Streets Anti-Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-252, April 15, 1996,  43 DCR 2139).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(a) of the Safe Streets Anti-Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-252, April 15, 1996,  43 DCR 2139).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 5 of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization and Street Solicitation for Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-428, August 6, 1998,  45 DCR 5884), § 5 of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-506, November 10, 1998,  45 DCR 8139), and § 5 of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-13, February 8, 1999,  46 DCR 2333).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(205) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
