<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-4506</num>
  <heading>Issue of a license to carry a pistol.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department (“Chief”) may, upon the application of a person having a bona fide residence or place of business within the District of Columbia, or of a person having a bona fide residence or place of business within the United States and a license to carry a pistol concealed upon his or her person issued by the lawful authorities of any State or subdivision of the United States, issue a license to such person to carry a pistol concealed upon his or her person within the District of Columbia for not more than 2 years from the date of issue, if it appears that the applicant has good reason to fear injury to his or her person or property or has any other proper reason for carrying a pistol, and that he or she is a suitable person to be so licensed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A non-resident who lives in a state that does not require a license to carry a concealed pistol may apply to the Chief for a license to carry a pistol concealed upon his or her person within the District of Columbia for not more than 2 years from the date of issue; provided, that he or she meets the same reasons and requirements set forth in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For any person issued a license pursuant to this section, or renewed pursuant to § <cite path="§7-2509.03">7-2509.03</cite>, the Chief may limit the geographic area, circumstances, or times of the day, week, month, or year in which the license is effective, and may subsequently limit, suspend, or revoke the license as provided under § <cite path="§7-2509.05">7-2509.05</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The application for a license to carry shall be on a form prescribed by the Chief and shall bear the name, address, description, photograph, and signature of the licensee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § <cite path="§7-2509.05">7-2509.05</cite>(b), any person whose application has been denied or whose license has been limited or revoked may, within 15 days after the date of the notice of denial or notice of intent, appeal to the Concealed Pistol Licensing Review Board established pursuant to § <cite path="§7-2509.08">7-2509.08</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 8, 1932, 47 Stat. 651, ch. 465, § 6</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-119" type="History">May 21, 1994, D.C. Law 10-119, § 15(e), 41 DCR 1639</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-388" type="History">May 20, 2009, D.C. Law 17-388, § 2(f), 56 DCR 1162</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-279" type="History">June 16, 2015, D.C. Law 20-279, § 3(b), 62 DCR 1944</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-3206.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 22-3206.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-279">D.C. Law 20-279</cite> revived and rewrote this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) revival and amendment of this section, see § 3(b) of the License to Carry a Pistol Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-169">D.C. Law 20-169</cite>, March 7, 2015,  61 DCR 11814).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal, see § 2(f) of Inoperable Pistol Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-652, January 6, 2009,  56 DCR 927).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal, see § 2(f) of Inoperable Pistol Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-24, March 16, 2009,  56 DCR 2309).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3(b) of the License to Carry a Pistol Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-447, Oct. 7, 2014,  61 DCR 10765, 20 STAT 4175).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of emergency D.C. Act 20-447, § 4, the act’s applicability clause, see § 2 of the License to Carry a Pistol Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-448, Oct. 7, 2014,  61 DCR 10777, 20 STAT 4187).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) revival and amendment of this section as of September 23, 2014, see § 3(b) of the License to Carry a Pistol Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-564, Jan. 6, 2015,  62 DCR 866, 21 STAT 527).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of emergency D.C. Act 20-447, see § 4(b) of the License to Carry a Pistol Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-564, Jan. 6, 2015,  62 DCR 866, 21 STAT 527).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of temporary D.C. Act 20-169, see § 4(c) of the License to Carry a Pistol Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-564, Jan. 6, 2015,  62 DCR 866, 21 STAT 527).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) revival and amendment of this section, see § 3(b) of the License to Carry a Pistol Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-74, June 4, 2015,  62 DCR 8242, 21 DCSTAT 1451).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
