<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-712</num>
  <heading>Prohibited acts; penalty.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person commits the offense of bribery if that person:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Corruptly offers, gives, or agrees to give anything of value, directly or indirectly, to a public servant; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Corruptly solicits, demands, accepts, or agrees to accept anything of value, directly or indirectly, as a public servant;</text>
    </para>
    <aftertext>in return for an agreement or understanding that an official act of the public servant will be influenced thereby or that the public servant will violate an official duty, or that the public servant will commit, aid in committing, or will collude in or allow any fraud against the District of Columbia.</aftertext>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting concurrence in official action in the course of legitimate compromise between public servants.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any person convicted of bribery shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> or twice the monetary equivalent of the thing of value, whichever is greater, or imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-164" type="History">Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 302, 29 DCR 3976</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, §§ 111(a)(3), 205(v), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§23-546">23-546</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-712.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>, in (c), substituted “not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $25,000,” and “twice” for “3 times”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 111(a)(3) and 205(v) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
