<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-3226.06</num>
  <heading>Unlawful acts and practices.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A telephone solicitor commits the offense of telephone solicitation fraud when engaged in any one of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fails to obtain or maintain a valid certificate of registration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Obtains a certificate of registration through any false or fraudulent pretence or representation in any registration application;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Knowingly fails to have received written consent to use the name of a charitable organization;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Knowingly misrepresents any of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The total cost of the goods or services that are the subject of the telephone solicitation sales call;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Material restrictions, material limitations, or material conditions to the purchase of goods or services that are the subject of a telephone solicitation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Material aspects of the performance, efficacy, nature or characteristics of goods or services that are the subject of a telephone solicitation; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Material aspects of the nature of terms of the telephone solicitor’s refund, cancellation, exchange or repurchase policies;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Induces a consumer to purchase goods or services by means of a false or fraudulent pretense, representation or promise;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Charges a consumer’s checking or savings account without the consumer’s express written authorization; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Procures the services of any professional delivery, courier, or other pickup service to obtain immediate receipt and/or possession of a consumer’s payment unless the goods are delivered with the opportunity to inspect before payment is collected.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who violates any provision of this section shall be subject to the penalties provided in §§ <cite root="22-3226.09">22-3226.09</cite> and <cite root="22-3226.10">22-3226.10</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-164">Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 126f</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-301">as added June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-301, § 102, 47 DCR 7039</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="16-801">16-801</cite>, § <cite root="22-3226.10">22-3226.10</cite>, and § <cite root="22-3226.11">22-3226.11</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
