<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-801</num>
  <heading>Definition and penalty.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Whoever shall, either in the nighttime or in the daytime, break and enter, or enter without breaking, any dwelling, or room used as a sleeping apartment in any building, with intent to break and carry away any part thereof, or any fixture or other thing attached to or connected thereto or to commit any criminal offense, shall, if any person is in any part of such dwelling or sleeping apartment at the time of such breaking and entering, or entering without breaking, be guilty of burglary in the first degree. Burglary in the first degree shall be punished by imprisonment for not less than 5 years nor more than 30 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, whoever shall, either in the night or in the daytime, break and enter, or enter without breaking, any dwelling, bank, store, warehouse, shop, stable, or other building or any apartment or room, whether at the time occupied or not, or any steamboat, canalboat, vessel, or other watercraft, or railroad car, or any yard where any lumber, coal, or other goods or chattels are deposited and kept for the purpose of trade, with intent to break and carry away any part thereof or any fixture or other thing attached to or connected with the same, or to commit any criminal offense, shall be guilty of burglary in the second degree. Burglary in the second degree shall be punished by imprisonment for not less than 2 years nor more than 15 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to any other penalty provided under this section, a person may be fined an amount not more than the amount set forth in § <cite root="22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1323, ch. 854, § 823</annotation>
      <annotation>Dec. 27, 1967, 81 Stat. 736, Pub. L. 90-226, title VI, § 602</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 303(l), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Firearm possession, additional, see § <cite root="22-4502">22-4502</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Theft, see § <cite root="22-3211">22-3211</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Unlawful entry, see § <cite root="22-3302">22-3302</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="11-502">11-502</cite>, § <cite root="22-4001">22-4001</cite>, § <cite root="23-546">23-546</cite>, and § <cite root="24-112">24-112</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 22-1801.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 22-1801.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> added (c).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 303(l) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
