<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 22-2">
  <num type="law">22-2</num>
  <num type="bill">22-142</num>
  <num type="act">22-51</num>
  <heading type="short">Land Disposition Transparency Temporary Amendment Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes to clarify the law on making substantive changes to a land disposition agreement and the administrative requirements for property dispositions that were in progress at the time of the recently enacted changes to the act.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-06-10</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/37530/B22-0142-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 22-2</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 4021</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2017-03-07" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2017-03-07" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2017-04-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-04-24</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Land Disposition Transparency Temporary Amendment Act of 2017".</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 1 of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code ยง 10-801), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b)(9) is amended by striking the phrase "with this resolution, unless" and inserting the phrase "with this resolution in accordance with subsection (b-1)(2) of this section, unless" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new subsection (b-5) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(b-5)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a-1)(4) and (b-2) of this section, for each of the following projects, the Mayor shall hold at least one public hearing on the finding that the real property is no longer required for public purposes before submitting the proposed surplus resolution and proposed disposition resolution to the Council:</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Franklin School (Ward 2);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Grimke School (Ward 1);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Parcel 42 (Ward 6);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Water Front Station II (Ward 6);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>Crummell School (Ward 5);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(F)</num>
            <text>Truxton Circle (Ward 5);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(G)</num>
            <text>MLK Gateway (Ward 8);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(H)</num>
            <text>1125 Spring Road, N.W. (Ward 4);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>200 K Street, N.W. (Parking Deck)(Ward 6); and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(J)</num>
            <text>Northwest One (New Communities)(Ward 6).</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The hearing required by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be held at an accessible evening or weekend time and in an accessible location in the vicinity of the real property. The Mayor shall provide at least 30 days written notice of the public hearing to the affected Advisory Neighborhood Commission and publish notice of the hearing in the District of Columbia Register at least 15 days before the hearing.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง10-801"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602 (c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02 (c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
