<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 22-178">
  <num type="law">22-178</num>
  <num type="bill">22-863</num>
  <num type="act">22-452</num>
  <heading type="short">Campaign Finance Reform and Transparency Temporary Amendment Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Amendment Act of 2011 to enhance the reporting requirements of political action committees and independent expenditure committees during nonelection years and to apply current contribution limitations to political action committees during nonelection years.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2018-06-25</introduced>
    <effective>2018-10-30</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/40503/Signed_Act/B22-0863-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 22-178</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/40503/B22-0863-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-452</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 9567</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0863">
      <vote date="2018-06-26" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-07-10" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-09-06</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Campaign Finance Reform and Transparency Temporary Amendment Act of 2018".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Amendment Act of 2011, effective April 27, 2012 (D.C. Law 19-124; D.C. Official Code § 1-1161.01 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 309(b) (D.C. Official Code § 1-1163.09(b)) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The existing text is designated as paragraph (1).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (2) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>In addition to the reporting requirements in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the treasurer of each political action committee and independent expenditure committee shall file the reports required by subsection (a) of this section on the 10th day of April and October of each year in which there is no election. The reports shall be complete as of the date prescribed by the Director of Campaign Finance, which shall not be more than 5 days before the date of filing.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1163.09"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 333 (D.C. Official Code § 1-1163.33) is amended by adding a new subsection (f-1) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(f-1)</num>
          <text>Limitations on contributions under this section shall apply to political action committees during nonelection years.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1163.33"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
