<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 22-205">
  <num type="law">22-205</num>
  <num type="bill">22-87</num>
  <num type="act">22-504</num>
  <heading type="short">Elections Modernization Amendment Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955 to require the District of Columbia Board of Elections to divide the District into appropriate voting precincts every 5 years, to permit voters to elect to receive a voter guide by electronic means, in lieu of by mail, if such a guide is published by the District of Columbia Board of Elections, to exempt the current Executive Director of the District of Columbia Board of Elections from the domicile requirement, and to repeal the requirement that the District of Columbia Board of Elections publish and display on its website a searchable copy of the list of qualified electors registered to vote; and to amend the State Board of Education Establishment Act of 2007 to allow members of the State Board of Education to serve as certain elected officials of political parties.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2017-01-24</introduced>
    <effective>2019-02-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/37290/B22-0087-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 22-205</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/37290/B22-0087-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-504</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 12361</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0087">
      <vote date="2018-10-02" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-10-16" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-10-31</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, this bill increases the frequency with which the Board of Elections evaluates and determines voting precincts to every 5 years, subject to Council approval and requires that a system be developed to permit registered voters to elect to receive a voter guide by electronic means. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Judiciary and Public Safety</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Elections Modernization Amendment Act of 2018".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 699; D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§1-1001.05">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 5 (D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.05) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(a)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(8)">
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (8) is amended by striking the phrase "Divide the District" and inserting the phrase "Every 5 years, divide the District" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>Divide the District</find>
            <replace>Every 5 years, divide the District</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(12)">
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (12) is amended by striking the phrase "votes therein;" and inserting the phrase "votes therein, including by establishing a system to permit voters to elect to receive a voter guide by electronic means in lieu of by mail, if such a guide is published by the Board;" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>votes therein;</find>
            <replace>votes therein, including by establishing a system to permit voters to elect to receive a voter guide by electronic means in lieu of by mail, if such a guide is published by the Board;</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(e)|(1)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (e)(1) is amended by adding a new subparagraph (B-i) to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="2">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(B)"/>
            <num>(B-i)</num>
            <text>The requirements of subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall not apply to Executive Director Alice Miller, beginning on her hire date of July 6, 2016.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 7(h)(2A) (D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.07(h)(2A)) is repealed.</text>
      <codify:repeal doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1001.07|(h)|(2A)"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 402(e)(1)(C) of the State Board of Education Establishment Act of 2007, effective June 12, 2007 (D.C. Law 17-9; D.C. Official Code § 38-2651(e)(1)(C)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="2">
      <para>
        <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2651|(e)|(1)|(C)"/>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Not hold another elective office, other than as an official of a political party, as described in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1001.01|(1)">section 1(1)</code-cite> through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1001.01|(4)">(4)</cite><span codify:value=""> of the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 699; D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.01(1)-(4))</span>; or</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
