<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 22-213">
  <num type="law">22-213</num>
  <num type="bill">22-112</num>
  <num type="act">22-514</num>
  <heading type="short">Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Compact Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To authorize the Mayor to execute, on behalf of the District of Columbia, an Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Compact for the purpose of regulating designated insurance products, to promote and protect the interest of consumers of individual and group annuity life insurance, disability income, and long-term care insurance products, to develop uniform standards for insurance products covered by the compact, to establish a central clearinghouse to receive and provide prompt review of insurance products covered under the compact and certain advertisements related to insurance products, to create  appropriate uniform standards, to improve coordination of regulatory resources and expertise between state insurance departments regarding the setting of uniform standards and review of the insurance products covered by the compact, to create the Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Commission, and to perform related functions as may be consistent with the state regulation of the business of insurance.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2017-02-07</introduced>
    <effective>2019-02-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/37365/B22-0112-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 22-213</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/37365/B22-0112-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-514</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 12933</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0112">
      <vote date="2018-10-02" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-10-16" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-11-13</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, this bill authorizes the Mayor to execute an Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Compact to protect the interest of consumers of individual and group annuity, life insurance, disability income and long-term care insurance products. The Compact shall develop uniform standards for insurance products covered by the Compact and among other things, create an Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Commission. A compacting state includes any State which has enacted the legislation and has not withdrawn or been terminated.</summary>
      <committee>Committee on Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Compact Act of 2018".</text>
  <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="31|13B" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>I</num>
      <heading>Authority to enter into Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Compact.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert> -->
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="31|13B" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>II</num>
      <heading>Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Compact.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <!-- <codify:recodify-section doc="D.C. Code" path="31|13B" num-value="31-1391" destination-path="31|13B|I" history="false"/> -->
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="31|13B|II" num-value="31-1392.01"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading codify:value="Mayoral Authority."/>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to execute, on behalf of the District of Columbia, an Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Compact in the form substantially as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <container>
        <heading>Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Compact.</heading>
        <text>
          <h3> Article I. Purpose.</h3>
        </text>
        <text>The purpose of the interstate compact, through means of joint and cooperative action among the Compacting States, is to promote and protect the interest of consumers of individual and group annuity, life insurance, disability income, and long-term care insurance products; to develop uniform standards for insurance products covered by the Compact; to establish a central clearinghouse to receive and provide prompt review of insurance products covered under the Compact and, in certain cases, Advertisements related thereto, submitted by insurers authorized to do business in one or more Compacting jurisdictions; to give appropriate uniform standards; to improve coordination of regulatory resources and expertise between state insurance departments regarding the setting of uniform standards and review of the insurance products covered by the Compact; to create the Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Commission; and to perform these and such other related functions as may be consistent with the state regulation of the business of insurance.</text>
        <text>
          <h3>Article II. Definitions.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>"Advertisement" means any material designed to create public interest in a Product, or induce the public to purchase, increase, modify, reinstate, borrow on, surrender, replace, or retain a policy, as more specifically defined in the Rules and Operating Procedures of the Commission.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>"Bylaws" mean those bylaws established by the Commission for its governance, or for directing or controlling the Commission's actions or conduct.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>"Compacting State" means any State that has enacted this Compact legislation and  has  not  withdrawn  pursuant  to  Article  XIV,  paragraphs  (a)  through  (f)  of  the Compact, or been terminated pursuant to Article XIV, paragraphs (g) through (i) of this Compact.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>"Commission" means the Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Commission established by this Compact.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>"Commissioner" means the chief insurance regulatory official of  a  State including, but not limited to, commissioner, superintendent, director, or administrator.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>"Domiciliary  State"  means  the  state  in  which  an  Insurer  is  incorporated  or organized; or, in the case of an alien Insurer, its state of entry.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>"Insurer" means any entity licensed by a State to issue contracts of insurance for any of the lines of insurance covered by this act.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>"Member" means the person chosen by a Compacting State as its representative to the Commission, or his or her designee.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>"Non-compacting State" means any State which is not at the time a Compacting State.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>"Operating Procedures" mean procedures  promulgated  by  the  Commission implementing a Rule, Uniform Standard, or a provision of this Compact.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>"Product" means the form of a policy or contract, including any application, endorsement, or related form that is attached to and made a part of the policy or contract, and any evidence of coverage or certificate, for an individual or group annuity, life insurance, disability income, or long-term care insurance product that an Insurer is authorized to issue.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>"Rule" means a statement of general or particular applicability and future effect promulgated by the Commission, including a Uniform Standard developed pursuant to Article VII of this Compact, designed to implement, interpret, or prescribe law or policy or describing the organization, procedure, or practice requirements of the Commission, which shall have the force and effect of law in the Compacting States.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>"State" means any state, district, or territory of the United States of America.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>"Third-Party  Filer"  means  an  entity  that  submits  a  Product  filing  to the Commission on behalf of an Insurer.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>"Uniform Standard" means a standard adopted by the Commission for a Product line, pursuant to Article VII of this Compact, and shall include all of the Product requirements in aggregate; provided, that each Uniform Standard shall be construed, whether express or implied, to prohibit the use of any inconsistent, misleading, or ambiguous provisions in a Product and the form of the Product made available to the public shall not be unfair, inequitable, or against public policy as determined by the Commission.</text>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article III. Establishment of the Commission and Venue.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The Compacting States hereby create and establish a joint public agency known as the  "Interstate  Insurance  Product  Regulation  Commission."  Pursuant to Article IV, the Commission will have the power to develop Uniform Standards for Product lines, receive and provide prompt review of Products filed therewith, and give approval to those Product filings satisfying applicable Uniform Standards; provided, that it is not intended for the Commission to be the exclusive entity for receipt and review of insurance Product filings. Nothing herein shall prohibit any Insurer from filing its Product in any State wherein the Insurer is licensed to conduct the business of insurance; and any such filing shall be subject to the laws of the State where filed.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>The Commission is a body corporate and politic, and an instrumentality of the Compacting States.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>The  Commission  is  solely  responsible  for  its  liabilities  except  as  otherwise specifically provided in this Compact.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>Venue is proper and judicial proceedings by or against the Commission shall be brought solely and exclusively in a court of competent jurisdiction where the principal office of the Commission is located.</text>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3> Article IV. Powers of the Commission.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall have the following powers:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>To promulgate Rules, pursuant to Article VII of this Compact, which shall have the force and effect of law and shall be binding in the Compacting States to the extent and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>To exercise its rule-making authority and establish reasonable Uniform Standards for Products covered under the Compact, and Advertisement related thereto, which shall have the force and effect of law and shall be binding in the Compacting States, but only for those Products filed with the Commission; provided, that a Compacting State shall have the right to opt out of such Uniform Standard pursuant to Article VII to the extent and in the manner provided in this Compact; provided further, that any Uniform Standard established by the Commission for long-term care insurance products may provide the same or greater protections for consumers as, but shall not provide less than, those protections set forth in the National Association of Insurance Commissioners'("NAIC") Long-Term Care Insurance Model Act and Long-Term Care Insurance Model Regulation, adopted as of 2001. The Commission shall consider whether any subsequent amendments to the NAIC Long-Term Care Insurance Model Act or Long-Term Care Insurance Model Regulation adopted by the NAIC require amending of the Uniform Standards established by the Commission for long-term care insurance products;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>To receive and review in an expeditious manner Products filed with the Commission, and rate filings for disability income and long-term care insurance Products, and give approval of those Products and rate filings that satisfy the applicable Uniform Standard, where such approval shall have the force and effect of law and be binding on the Compacting States to the extent and in the manner provided in the Compact;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>To receive and review in an expeditious manner Advertisement relating to long-term care insurance products for which Uniform Standards have been adopted by the Commission, and give approval to all Advertisement that satisfies the applicable Uniform Standard. For any Product covered under this Compact, other than long-term care insurance products, the Commission shall have the authority to require an Insurer to submit all or any part of its Advertisement with respect to that Product for review or approval prior to use, if the Commission determines that the nature of the Product is such that an Advertisement of the Product could have the capacity or tendency to mislead the public. The actions of Commission as provided in this Article shall have the force and effect of law and shall be binding in the Compacting States to the extent and in the manner provided in the Compact;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>To exercise its rule-making authority and designate Products and Advertisement that may be subject to a self-certification process without the need for prior approval by the Commission.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>To promulgate Operating Procedures, pursuant to Article VII of this Compact, which shall be binding in the Compacting States to the extent and in the manner provided in this Compact;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>To bring and prosecute legal proceedings or actions in its name as the Commission; provided, that the standing of any state insurance department to sue or be sued under applicable law shall not be affected;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(8)</num>
              <text>To issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of evidence;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(9)</num>
              <text>To establish and maintain offices;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(10)</num>
              <text>To purchase and maintain insurance and bonds;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(11)</num>
              <text>To borrow, accept, or contract for services of personnel, including, but not limited to, employees of a Compacting State;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(12)</num>
              <text>To  hire  employees,  professionals,  or  specialists,  and  elect  or  appoint officers, and to fix their compensation, define their duties, and give them appropriate authority to carry out the purposes of the Compact, and determine their qualifications; and to establish the Commission's personnel policies and programs relating to, among other things, conflicts of interest, rates of compensation, and qualifications of personnel;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(13)</num>
              <text>To accept any and all appropriate donations and grants of money, equipment, supplies, materials, and services, and to receive, utilize, and dispose of the same; provided, that at all times the Commission shall strive to avoid any appearance of impropriety;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(14)</num>
              <text>To lease, purchase, accept appropriate gifts or donations of, or otherwise to own, hold, improve or use, any property, real, personal, or mixed; provided, that at all times the Commission shall strive to avoid any appearance of impropriety;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(15)</num>
              <text>To sell, convey, mortgage, pledge, lease, exchange, abandon, or otherwise dispose of any property, real, personal, or mixed;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(16)</num>
              <text>To remit filing fees to Compacting States as may be set forth in the Bylaws, Rules, or Operating Procedures;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(17)</num>
              <text>To enforce compliance by Compacting States with Rules, Uniform Standards, Operating Procedures, and Bylaws;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(18)</num>
              <text>To provide for dispute resolution among Compacting States;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(19)</num>
              <text>To advise Compacting States on issues relating to Insurers domiciled or doing business in Non-compacting jurisdictions, consistent with the purposes of this Compact;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(20)</num>
              <text>To provide advice and training to those personnel in state insurance departments  responsible  for  Product  review,  and  to  be  a  resource  for  state  insurance departments;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(21)</num>
              <text>To establish a budget and make expenditures;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(22)</num>
              <text>To borrow money;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(23)</num>
              <text>To appoint committees, including advisory committees comprising Members, state insurance regulators, state legislators or their representatives, insurance industry and consumer representatives, and such other interested persons as may be designated in the Bylaws;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(24)</num>
              <text>To provide and receive information from, and to cooperate with, law enforcement agencies;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(25)</num>
              <text>To adopt and use a corporate seal; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(26)</num>
              <text>To perform such other functions as may be necessary or appropriate to achieve the purposes of this Compact consistent with the state regulation of the business of insurance."</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article V. Organization of the Commission.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>Each Compacting State shall have and be limited to one Member. Each Member shall be qualified to serve in that capacity pursuant to applicable law of the Compacting State Any Member may be removed or suspended from office as provided by the law of the State from which he or she shall be appointed. Any vacancy occurring in the Commission shall be filled in accordance with the laws of the Compacting State wherein the vacancy exists. Nothing herein shall be construed to affect the manner in which a Compacting State determines the election or appointment and qualification of its own Commissioner.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>Each Member shall be entitled to one vote and shall have an opportunity to participate in the governance of the Commission in accordance with the Bylaws. Notwithstanding any provision herein to the contrary, no action of the Commission with respect to the promulgation of a Uniform Standard shall be effective unless two-thirds (2/3) of the Members vote in favor thereof.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>The Commission  shall, by a  majority of  the  Members,  prescribe  Bylaws to govern its conduct as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes, and exercise the powers, of the Compact, including, but not limited to:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Establishing the fiscal year of the Commission;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Providing reasonable procedures for appointing and electing members, as well as holding meetings, of the Management Committee;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Providing reasonable standards and procedures: (i) for the establishment and meetings of other committees, and (ii) governing any general or specific delegation of any authority or function of the Commission;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Providing reasonable procedures for calling and conducting meetings of the Commission  that  consists  of  a majority of  Commission  members,  ensuring  reasonable advance notice of each such meeting, and providing for the right of citizens to attend each such meeting with enumerated exceptions designed to protect the public's interest, the privacy of individuals, and insurers' proprietary information, including trade secrets. The Commission may meet in camera only after a majority of the entire membership votes to close a meeting en toto or in part. As soon as practicable, the Commission must make public (i) a copy of the vote to close the meeting revealing the vote of each Member with no proxy votes allowed, and (ii) votes taken during such meeting;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>Establishing the titles, duties, and authority of and reasonable procedures for the election of the officers of the Commission;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>Providing reasonable standards and procedures for the establishment of the personnel policies and programs of the Commission. Notwithstanding any civil service or other similar laws of any Compacting State, the Bylaws shall exclusively govern the personnel policies and programs of the Commission;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>Promulgating a code of ethics to address permissible and prohibited activities of Commission members and employees; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(8)</num>
              <text>Providing a mechanism for winding up the operations of the Commission and the equitable disposition of any surplus funds that may exist after the termination of the Compact after the payment and reserving of all of its debts and obligations.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall publish its bylaws in a convenient form and file a copy thereof and a copy of any amendment thereto, with the appropriate agency or officer in each of the Compacting States.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(e)</num>
            <text>A Management Committee comprising no more than fourteen (14) members shall be established as follows:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>One (1) member from each of the six (6) Compacting States with the largest premium volume for individual and group annuities, life insurance, disability income, and long-term care insurance products determined from the records of the NAIC for the prior year;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Four (4) members from those Compacting States with at least two percent (2%) of the market, based on the premium volume described above, other than the six (6) Compacting States with the largest premium volume, selected on a rotating basis as provided in the Bylaws; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Four  (4)  members  from  those  Compacting  States  with  less  than  two percent (2%) of the market, based on the premium volume described above, with one (1) selected from each of the four (4) zone regions of the NAIC as provided in the Bylaws.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(f)</num>
            <text>The Management Committee shall have such authority and duties as may be set forth in the Bylaws, including but not limited to:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Managing the affairs of the Commission in a manner consistent with the Bylaws and purposes of the Commission;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Establishing and overseeing an organizational structure within, and appropriate procedures for, the Commission to provide for the creation of Uniform Standards and Rules, receipt and review of Product filings, administrative and technical support functions, review of decisions regarding the disapproval of a Product filing, and the review of elections made by a Compacting State to opt out of a Uniform Standard; provided, that a Uniform Standard shall not be submitted to the Compacting States for adoption unless approved by two-thirds (2/3) of the members of the Management Committee;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Overseeing the offices of the Commission; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Planning, implementing, and coordinating communications and activities with other state, federal, and local government organizations in order to advance the goals of the Commission.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(g)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall elect annually officers from the Management Committee, with each having such authority and duties as may be specified in the Bylaws.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(h)</num>
            <text>The Management Committee may, subject to the approval of the Commission, appoint or retain an executive director for such period, upon such terms and conditions, and for such compensation as the Commission may deem appropriate. The executive director shall serve as secretary to the Commission, but shall not be a Member of the Commission. The executive director shall hire and supervise such other staff as may be authorized by the Commission.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>A legislative committee comprising state legislators or their designees shall be established to monitor the operations of, and make recommendations to, the Commission, including the Management Committee; provided, that the manner of selection and term of any legislative committee member shall be as set forth in the Bylaws. Prior to the adoption by the Commission of any Uniform Standard, revision to the Bylaws, annual budget, or other significant matter as may be provided in the Bylaws, the Management Committee shall consult with and report to the legislative committee.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(j)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall establish two (2) advisory committees, one comprising consumer representatives independent of the insurance industry and the other comprising insurance industry representatives.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(k)</num>
            <text>The Commission may establish additional advisory committees as its Bylaws may provide for the carrying out of its functions.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(l)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall maintain its corporate books and records in accordance with the Bylaws.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(m)</num>
            <text>The Members, officers, executive director, employees, and representatives of the Commission shall be immune from suit and liability, either personally or in their official capacity, for any claim for damage to or loss of property or personal injury or other civil liability caused by or arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred, or that the person against whom the claim is made had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities; provided, that nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to protect any such person from suit or liability for any damage, loss, injury, or liability caused by the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of that person.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(n)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall defend any Member, officer, executive director, employee, or representative of the Commission in any civil action seeking to impose liability arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, or that the person against whom the claim is made had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities; provided, that nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit that person from retaining his or her own counsel; provided further, that the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from that person's intentional or willful and wanton misconduct.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(o)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall indemnify and hold harmless any Member, officer, executive  director,  employee,  or  representative  of  the  Commission  for  the  amount  of  any settlement or judgment obtained against that person arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission  that occurred  within the scope of Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, or that such person had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, provided, that the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of that person.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article VI. Meetings and Acts of the Commission.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall meet and take such actions as are consistent with the provisions of this Compact and the Bylaws.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>Each Member of the Commission shall have the right and power to cast a vote to which that Compacting State is entitled and to participate in the business and affairs of the Commission. A Member shall vote in person or by such other means as provided in the Bylaws. The Bylaws may provide for Members' participation in meetings by telephone or other means of communication.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall meet at least once during each calendar year. Additional meetings shall be held as set forth in the Bylaws.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article VII. Rules and Operating Procedures: Rulemaking Functions of the Commission and Opting Out of Uniform Standards.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The  Commission  shall  promulgate  reasonable  Rules,  including  Uniform Standards, and Operating Procedures in order to effectively and efficiently achieve the purposes of this Compact. Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the event the Commission exercises its rulemaking authority in a manner that is beyond the scope of the purposes of this act, or the powers granted hereunder, then such an action by the Commission shall be invalid and have no force and effect.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>Rules and Operating Procedures shall be made pursuant to a rulemaking process that conforms to the Model State Administrative Procedure Act of 1981, as amended, as may be appropriate to the operations of the Commission. Before the Commission adopts a Uniform Standard, the Commission shall give written notice to the relevant state legislative committee(s) in each Compacting State responsible for insurance issues of its intention to adopt the Uniform Standard. The Commission in adopting a Uniform Standard shall consider fully all submitted materials and issue a concise explanation of its decision.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>A Uniform Standard shall become effective ninety (90) days after its promulgation  by  the  Commission  or  such  later  date  as  the  Commission  may  determine; provided, that a Compacting State may opt out of a Uniform Standard as provided in this Article. The term "opt out" shall be defined as any action by a Compacting State to decline to adopt or participate in a promulgated Uniform Standard. All other Rules and Operating Procedures, and amendments thereto, shall become effective as of the date specified in each Rule, Operating Procedure, or amendment.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>A Compacting State may opt out of a Uniform Standard, either by legislation or regulation duly promulgated by the insurance department under the Compacting State's administrative procedure act. If a Compacting State elects to opt out of a Uniform Standard by regulation, it must (i) give written notice to the Commission no later than ten (10) business days after the Uniform Standard is promulgated, or at the time the State becomes a Compacting State, and (ii) find that the Uniform Standard does not provide reasonable protections to the citizens of the State, given the conditions in the State. The Commissioner shall make specific findings of fact and conclusions of law, based on a preponderance of the evidence, detailing the conditions in the State that warrant a departure from the Uniform Standard and determining that the Uniform Standard would not reasonably protect the citizens of the State. The Commissioner must consider and balance the following factors and find that the conditions in the State and needs of the citizens of the State outweigh:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The intent of the legislature to participate in, and the benefits of, an interstate agreement to establish national uniform consumer protections for the Products subject to this act; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The presumption that a Uniform Standard adopted by the Commission provides reasonable protections to consumers of the relevant Product.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(e)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Notwithstanding  the  foregoing,  a  Compacting  State  may,  at  the  time  of  its enactment of this Compact, prospectively opt out of all Uniform Standards involving long-term care insurance products by expressly providing for such opt out in the enacted Compact, and such an opt out shall not be treated as a material variance in the offer or acceptance of any State to participate in this Compact. Such an opt out shall be effective at the time of enactment of this Compact by the Compacting State and shall apply to all existing Uniform Standards involving long-term care insurance products and those subsequently promulgated.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>In accordance with subparagraph (1) of this paragraph, the District of Columbia opts out of all existing and prospective uniform standards involving long-term care insurance products in order to preserve the District's statutory requirements governing these insurance products.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(f)</num>
            <text>If a Compacting State elects to opt out of a Uniform Standard, the Uniform Standard shall remain applicable in the Compacting State electing to opt out until such time the opt out legislation is enacted into law or the regulation opting out becomes effective.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(g)</num>
            <text>Once the opt out of a Uniform Standard by a Compacting State becomes effective as provided under the laws of that State, the Uniform Standard shall have no further force and effect in that State unless and until the legislation or regulation implementing the opt out is repealed or otherwise becomes ineffective under the laws of the State. If a Compacting State opts out of a Uniform Standard after the Uniform Standard has been made effective in that State, the opt out shall have the same prospective effect as provided under Article XIV of this Compact for withdrawals.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(h)</num>
            <text>If a Compacting State has formally initiated the process of opting out of a Uniform Standard by regulation, and while the regulatory opt out is pending, the Compacting State may petition the Commission, at least fifteen (15) days before the effective date of the Uniform  Standard,  to  stay  the  effectiveness  of  the  Uniform  Standard  in  that  State.  The Commission may grant a stay if it determines the regulatory opt out is being pursued in a reasonable manner and there is a likelihood of success. If a stay is granted or extended by the Commission, the stay or extension thereof may postpone the effective date by up to ninety (90) days, unless affirmatively extended by the Commission; provided, that a stay may not be permitted to  remain  in  effect  for  more  than  one  (1)  year  unless  the  Compacting  State  can  show extraordinary circumstances that warrant a continuance of the stay, including, but not limited to, the existence of a legal challenge that prevents the Compacting State from opting out. A stay may be terminated by the Commission upon notice that the rulemaking process has been terminated.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Not  later  than  thirty  (30)  days  after  a  Rule  or  Operating  Procedure  is promulgated,  any person  may file  a  petition  for  judicial  review  of  the  Rule  or  Operating Procedure; provided, that the filing of such a petition shall not stay or otherwise prevent the Rule or Operating Procedure from becoming effective unless the court finds that the petitioner has a substantial likelihood  of  success.  The court shall give deference to the actions of the Commission consistent with applicable law and shall not find the Rule or Operating Procedure to be unlawful if the Rule or Operating Procedure represents a reasonable exercise of the Commission's authority.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article VIII. Commission Records and Enforcement.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall promulgate Rules establishing conditions and procedures for  public  inspection  and  copying  of  its  information  and  official  records,  except  such information and records involving the privacy of individuals and insurers' trade secrets. The Commission may promulgate additional Rules under which it may make available to federal and state agencies, including law enforcement agencies, records and information otherwise exempt from disclosure and may enter into agreements with such agencies to receive or exchange information or records subject to nondisclosure and confidentiality provisions.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>Except  as  to  privileged  records,  data,  and  information,  the  laws  of  any Compacting  State  pertaining  to  confidentiality  or  nondisclosure  shall  not  relieve  any Compacting  State  Commissioner  of  the  duty  to  disclose  any  relevant  records,  data,  or information to  the Commission;  provided,  that  disclosure to  the Commission  shall  not  be deemed to waive or otherwise affect any confidentiality requirement; provided further, that, except as otherwise expressly provided in this act, the Commission shall not be subject to the Compacting State's laws pertaining to confidentiality and nondisclosure with respect to records, data, and information in its possession. Confidential information of the Commission shall remain confidential after such information is provided to any Commissioner.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall monitor Compacting States for compliance with duly adopted  Bylaws,  Rules,  including  Uniform  Standards,  and  Operating  Procedures.  The Commission shall notify any non-complying Compacting State in writing of its noncompliance with Commission Bylaws, Rules, or Operating Procedures. If a non-complying Compacting State fails to remedy its noncompliance within the time specified in the notice of noncompliance, the Compacting State shall be deemed to be in default as set forth in Article XIV.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>The Commissioner of any State in which an Insurer is authorized to do business, or is conducting the business of insurance, shall continue to exercise his or her authority to oversee the market regulation of the activities of the Insurer in accordance with the provisions of the State's law. The Commissioner's enforcement of compliance with the Compact is governed by the following provisions:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>With respect to the Commissioner's market regulation of a Product or Advertisement that is approved or certified to the Commission, the content of the Product or Advertisement shall not constitute a violation of the provisions, standards, or requirements of the Compact except upon a final order of the Commission issued at the request of a Commissioner after prior notice to the Insurer and an opportunity for hearing before the Commission.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Before  a  Commissioner  may  bring  an  action  for  violation  of  any provision, standard, or requirement of the Compact relating to the content of an Advertisement not approved or certified to the Commission, the Commission, or an authorized Commission officer or employee, must  authorize  the  action.  However, authorization pursuant to this paragraph does not require notice to the Insurer, opportunity for hearing, or disclosure of requests for authorization or records of the Commission's action on such requests.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article IX. Dispute Resolution.</h3>
        </text>
        <text>The Commission shall attempt, upon the request of a Member, to resolve any disputes or other issues that are subject to this Compact that may arise between two (2) or more Compacting States, or between Compacting States and Non-compacting States.  The Commission shall promulgate an Operating Procedure providing for resolution of such disputes.</text>
        <text>
          <h3>Article X. Product Filing and Approval.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>Insurers  and  Third-Party  Filers  seeking  to  have  a  Product  approved  by  the Commission shall file the Product with, and pay applicable filing fees to, the Commission. Nothing in this act shall be construed to restrict or otherwise prevent an insurer from filing its Product with the insurance department in any State wherein the insurer is licensed to conduct the business of insurance, and such filing shall be subject to the laws of the States where filed.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall establish appropriate filing and review processes and procedures pursuant  to Commission Rules and Operating Procedures.  Notwithstanding any provision herein to the contrary, the Commission shall promulgate Rules to establish conditions and  procedures  under  which  the  Commission  will  provide  public  access  to  Product  filing information. In establishing such Rules, the Commission shall consider the interests of the public in having access to such information, as well as protection of personal medical and financial information and trade secrets, that may be contained in a Product filing or supporting information.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>Any Product approved by the Commission may be sold or otherwise issued in those Compacting States for which the Insurer is legally authorized to do business.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article XI. Review of Commission Decisions Regarding Filings.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>Not later than thirty (30) days after the Commission has given notice of a disapproved Product or Advertisement filed with the Commission, the Insurer or Third Party Filer whose filing was disapproved may appeal the determination to a review panel appointed by the Commission. The Commission shall promulgate Rules to establish procedures for appointing such review panels and provide for notice and hearing. An allegation that the Commission in disapproving a Product or Advertisement filed with the Commission, acted arbitrarily, capriciously, or in a manner that is an abuse of discretion or otherwise not in accordance with the law is subject to judicial review in accordance with paragraph (d), Article III.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall have authority to monitor, review, and reconsider Products and Advertisement subsequent to their filing or approval upon a finding that the Product does not meet the relevant Uniform Standard. Where appropriate, the Commission may withdraw or modify its approval after proper notice and hearing, subject to the appeal process in paragraph (a) of this Article.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article XII. Finance.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall pay or provide for the payment of the reasonable expenses of its establishment and organization. To fund the cost of its initial operations, the Commission may accept contributions and other forms of funding from the NAIC, Compacting States, and other sources. Contributions and other forms of funding from  other  sources  shall  be  of  such  a  nature  that  the  independence  of  the  Commission concerning the performance of its duties shall not be compromised.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall collect a filing fee from each Insurer and Third Party Filer filing a Product with the Commission to cover the cost of the operations and activities of the Commission and its staff in a total amount sufficient to cover the Commission's annual budget.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>The Commission's budget for a fiscal year shall not be approved until it has been subject to notice and comment as set forth in Article VII of this Compact.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall be exempt from all taxation in and by the Compacting States.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(e)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall not pledge the credit of any Compacting State except by and with the appropriate legal authority of that Compacting State.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(f)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall keep complete and accurate accounts of all its internal receipts, including grants and donations, and disbursements of all funds under its control. The internal financial accounts of the Commission shall be subject to the accounting procedures established under its Bylaws. The financial accounts and reports including the system of internal controls and procedures of the Commission shall be audited annually by an independent certified public accountant. Upon the determination of the Commission, but no less frequently than every three  (3)  years,  the  review  of  the  independent  auditor  shall  include  a  management  and performance audit of the Commission. The Commission shall make an annual report to the Governor/Executive and  legislature  of  the  Compacting  States,  which  shall  include  a  report  of  the independent audit. The Commission's internal accounts shall not  be confidential  and such materials  may  be  shared  with  the  Commissioner  of  any  Compacting  State  upon  request; provided, that any work papers related to any internal or independent audit and any information regarding the privacy of individuals and insurers' proprietary information, including trade secrets, shall remain confidential.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(g)</num>
            <text>No Compacting State shall have any claim to or ownership of any property held by or vested in the Commission or to any Commission funds held pursuant to the provisions of this Compact.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article XIII. Compacting States, Effective Date, and Amendment.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>Any State is eligible to become a Compacting State.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>The Compact shall become effective and binding upon legislative enactment of the Compact into law by two (2) Compacting States; provided, that the Commission shall become effective for purposes of adopting Uniform Standards for reviewing and giving approval or disapproval of Products filed with the Commission that satisfy applicable Uniform Standards only after twenty-six (26) States are Compacting States or, alternatively, by States representing greater than forty percent (40%) of the premium volume for life insurance, annuity, disability income, and long-term care insurance products, based on records of the NAIC for the prior year. Thereafter,  it  shall  become  effective  and  binding  as  to  any other  Compacting  State  upon enactment of the Compact into law by that State.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>Amendments to the Compact may be proposed by the Commission for enactment by the Compacting  States.  No amendment shall become effective and binding upon the Commission  and  the  Compacting  States  unless  and  until  all  Compacting  States  enact  the amendment into law.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article XIV. Withdrawal, Default, and Termination.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>Once effective, the Compact shall continue in force and remain binding upon each and every Compacting State; provided, that a Compacting State may withdraw from the Compact ("Withdrawing State") by enacting a statute specifically repealing the statute that enacted the Compact into law.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>The effective date of withdrawal is the effective date of the repealing statute. However, the withdrawal shall not apply to any Product filings approved or self-certified, or any Advertisement of such Products, on the date the repealing statute becomes effective, except by mutual  agreement  of  the  Commission  and  the Withdrawing  State, unless  the  approval  is rescinded by the Withdrawing State as provided in paragraph (e) of this Article.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>The  Commissioner  of  the  Withdrawing  State  shall  immediately  notify  the Management Committee in writing upon the introduction of legislation repealing this Compact in the Withdrawing State.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>The Commission shall notify the other Compacting States of the introduction of such legislation within ten (10) days after its receipt of notice thereof.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(e)</num>
            <text>The Withdrawing State is responsible for all obligations, duties, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of withdrawal, including any obligations, the performance of which extend beyond the effective date of withdrawal, except to the extent those obligations may have been released or relinquished by mutual agreement of the Commission and the Withdrawing State. The Commission's approval of Products and Advertisement prior to the effective date of withdrawal shall continue to be effective and be given full force and effect in the Withdrawing State, unless formally rescinded by the Withdrawing State in the same manner as provided by the laws of the Withdrawing State for the prospective disapproval of Products or Advertisement previously approved under the State's law.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(f)</num>
            <text>Reinstatement following withdrawal of any Compacting State shall occur upon the effective date of the Withdrawing State reenacting the Compact.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(g)</num>
            <text>If  the  Commission  determines  that  any  Compacting  State  has  at  any  time defaulted ("Defaulting State") in the performance of any of its obligations or responsibilities under this Compact, the Bylaws, or duly promulgated Rules or Operating Procedures, then, after notice and hearing as set forth in the Bylaws, all rights, privileges, and benefits conferred by this Compact on the Defaulting State shall be suspended from the effective date of default as fixed by the  Commission.  The  grounds  for  default  include,  but  are  not  limited  to, the failure  of  a Compacting  State  to  perform  its  obligations  or  responsibilities and  any  other  grounds designated in Commission Rules. The Commission shall immediately notify the Defaulting State in writing of the Defaulting State's suspension pending a cure of the default. The Commission shall stipulate the conditions and the time period within which the Defaulting State must cure its default. If the Defaulting State fails to cure the default within the time period specified by the Commission,  the  Defaulting  State  shall  be  terminated  from  the  Compact  and  all  rights, privileges, and benefits conferred by this Compact shall be terminated from the effective date of termination.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(h)</num>
            <text>Product approvals by the Commission or Product self-certifications, or any Advertisement in connection with such Product, that are in force on the effective date of termination shall remain in force in the Defaulting State in the same manner as if the Defaulting State had withdrawn voluntarily pursuant to paragraphs (a) through (f) of this Article.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Reinstatement following termination of any Compacting State requires a reenactment of the Compact.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(j)</num>
            <text>The Compact dissolves effective upon the date of the withdrawal or default of the Compacting State that reduces membership in the Compact to one Compacting State.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(k)</num>
            <text>Upon the dissolution of this Compact, the Compact becomes null and void and shall be of no further force or effect, and the business and affairs of the Commission shall be wound up and any surplus funds shall be distributed in accordance with the Bylaws.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article XV. Severability and Construction.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The provisions of this Compact shall be severable. If any phrase, clause, sentence, or provision is deemed unenforceable, the remaining provisions of the Compact shall be enforceable.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>The provisions of this Compact shall be liberally construed to effectuate its purposes.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <text>
          <h3>Article XVI. Binding Effect of Compact and Other Laws.</h3>
        </text>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>Nothing herein prevents the enforcement of any other law of a Compacting State, except as provided in paragraph (b) of this Article.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>For any Product approved or certified to the Commission, the Rule, Uniform Standard, or other  requirement  of  the  Commission  shall  constitute  the  exclusive provisions  applicable  to  the  content,  approval,  and  certification  of  such  Product.  For Advertisement that is subject to the Commission's authority, the Rule, Uniform Standard, or other requirement of the Commission that governs the content of the Advertisement shall constitute  the  exclusive  provision  that  a  Commissioner  may  apply  to  the  content  of  the Advertisement.  Notwithstanding the foregoing, no action taken by the Commission shall abrogate or restrict:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The access of any person to state courts;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Remedies available under state law related to breach of contract, tort, or other laws not specifically directed to the content of the Product;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>State law relating to the construction of insurance contracts; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>The authority of the attorney general of the State, including, but not limited to, maintaining any actions or proceedings, as authorized by law.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>All insurance Products filed with individual States shall be subject to the laws of those States.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>All  lawful  actions  of  the  Commission,  including  all  Rules  and  Operating Procedures promulgated by the Commission, are binding upon the Compacting States.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(e)</num>
            <text>All agreements between the Commission and the Compacting States are binding in accordance with their terms.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(f)</num>
            <text>Upon the request of a party to a conflict over the meaning or interpretation of Commission actions and a majority vote of the Compacting States, the Commission may issue advisory opinions regarding the meaning or interpretation in dispute.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(g)</num>
            <text>In the event any provision of this Compact exceeds the constitutional limits imposed  on  the  legislature  of  any  Compacting  State,  the  obligations,  duties,  powers,  or jurisdiction sought to be conferred by that provision upon the Commission shall be ineffective as to that Compacting State and those obligations, duties, powers, or jurisdiction shall remain in the Compacting State and shall be exercised by the agency thereof to which those obligations, duties, powers, or jurisdiction are delegated by law in effect at the time this Compact becomes effective.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </container>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="31|13B|II" num-value="31-1392.02"/>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading codify:value="Commissioner Designated."></heading>
    <text>The Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking is designated to serve as the representative of the District to the Interstate Insurance Product Regulation Commission.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code  1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code  1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
