<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 22-52">
  <num type="law">22-52</num>
  <num type="bill">22-563</num>
  <num type="act">22-200</num>
  <heading type="short">Government Employer-Assisted Housing Temporary Amendment Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Amendment Act of 1999 to provide that Employer-Assisted Housing Program participants who settle on the purchase of a housing unit in Fiscal Year 2018 and are not provided funds at the time of settlement in the amounts that they are eligible to receive under the act shall be retroactively compensated by the Department of Housing and Community Development, and to require the department to provide written notice describing the act's provisions to any person who has begun the application process for the program, all program participants, and the community-based organizations charged with the program's implementation.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2018-01-27</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/39168/B22-0563-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 22-52</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/39168/B22-0563-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-200</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 12551</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2017-11-07" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2017-11-21" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-12-07</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Government Employer-Assisted Housing Temporary Amendment Act of 2017".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 4 of the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Amendment Act of 1999, effective May 9, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-96; D.C. Official Code ยง 42-2503), is amended by adding new subsections (e) and (f) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subject to the availability of funds, if, at the time of a Participant's settlement in Fiscal Year 2018, the Department does not provide the Participant all of the matching contributions under section 5(b), or, if the Participant is a first responder, all of the matching contributions under section 5(b-1) and a grant of up to $10,000 under section 6a, which the Participant was eligible to receive under this act at the time of settlement, the Department shall compensate the Participant retroactively after settlement in the amount that the Participant should have received but did not receive.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>This subsection shall apply as of October 1, 2017.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>Within 5 days after the effective date of the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Emergency Amendment Act of 2017, passed on emergency basis on November 7, 2017 (Enrolled version of Bill 22-562), the Department shall provide written notice describing the provisions of this act to any person who has begun the application process for the Program, all Participants, and the community-based organizations charged with the Program's implementation.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง42-2503"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง l-206.02(c)(l)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
