<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 22-63">
  <num type="law">22-63</num>
  <num type="bill">22-550</num>
  <num type="act">22-224</num>
  <heading type="short">Department of Health Care Finance Independent Procurement Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To provide the Department of Health Care Finance with independent procurement authority, which exempts the agency from the Procurement Practices Reform Act, the Chief Procurement Officer's Authority, and the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005 for the specific purpose of issuing a contract to a company to manage and operate the United Medical Center.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2017-11-02</introduced>
    <effective>2018-02-17</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/39128/Signed_Act/B22-0550-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 22-63</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/39128/B22-0550-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-224</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 11</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0550">
      <vote date="2017-11-21" reading="Amendments"/>
      <vote date="2017-11-21" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2017-12-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-12-29</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of Health Care Finance Independent Procurement Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2017".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 105(c) of the Procurement Practices Reform Act of 2010, effective April 8, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-371; D.C. Official Code § 2-351.05(c)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (18) is amended by striking the word "and" at the end.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (19) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phase "; and" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (20) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(20)</num>
          <text>The procurement of services by the Department of Health Care Finance ("Department") for the management and operation of the United Medical Center; provided, that:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The procurement is conducted through a competitive process, as determined by the Department, producing not less than 2 responsive proposals; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Sections 202, 401a, 415, and Title X of this act shall apply.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-351.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 2351 of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-218.51), is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a), (a-1), and (b) of this section, the subcontracting requirements of section 2346 may be waived by the Director of the Department of Health Care Finance for a procurement solicited pursuant to section 105(c)(20) of the Procurement Practices Reform Act of 2010, effective April 8, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-371; D.C. Official Code § 2-351.05(c)(20)).</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-218.51"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
