<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 22-78">
  <num type="law">22-78</num>
  <num type="bill">22-96</num>
  <num type="act">22-249</num>
  <heading type="short">Electric Vehicle Public Infrastructure Expansion Amendment Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002 to establish an Electric Vehicle Charging Station Pilot Program, to require the District Department of Transportation to install at least 15 electric vehicle charging stations, to require the District Department of Transportation to collect data related to the electric vehicle charging stations, to require the District Department of Transportation to submit an annual report to the Council analyzing the Electric Vehicle Charging Station Pilot Program, and to require the District Department of Transportation to publish on its website a map showing the location of the electric vehicle charging stations.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2018-03-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/37348/B22-0096-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 22-78</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/37348/B22-0096-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-249</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 1560</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2017-12-05" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-01-09" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-02-06</enacted>
      <summary>This legislation establishes the Electric Vehicle Charging Station Pilot Program which will place at least 15 publically-available electric vehicle charging stations in the District by January 1, 2019. The bill requires DDOT to transmit a publicly-available report to the Council regarding the results of the program and issuing recommendations based on its findings by January 1, 2020. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Transportation and the Environment</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Electric Vehicle Public Infrastructure Expansion Amendment Act of 2018".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective May 21, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-137; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§50-921.01a|(a)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2a (D.C. Official Code § 50-921.01a) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(1)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (1) is redesignated as paragraph (1B).</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="num" count="1">
          <find>(1)</find>
          <replace>(1B)</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>New paragraphs (1) and (1A) are added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert before="(1B)"/>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>"Electric vehicle" means a vehicle that is propelled by an electric motor and is capable of being recharged from an external source of electricity.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <codify:insert before="(1B)"/>
            <num>(1A)</num>
            <text>"Electric vehicle charging station" means a publically accessible facility or equipment that is located on public property, including any public space in the District, and is used to charge the battery or other energy storage device of an electric vehicle.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <codify:not-funded-anno applicability-path="§3"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new section 2o is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <codify:insert path="50|9A|I" after="§50-921.22" num-value="50-921.23" history-prefix="as added"/>
          <num>2o</num>
          <heading>Electric Vehicle Charging Station Pilot Program.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>There is established an Electric Vehicle Charging Station Pilot Program ("Pilot Program"), which shall be administered by DDOT.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>By January 1, 2019, DDOT shall install at least 15 electric vehicle charging stations, including at least one electric vehicle charging station in each ward. Each electric vehicle charging station shall have the capacity to charge more than one vehicle simultaneously.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>DDOT shall, through a competitive bidding process, enter into an agreement with one or more private entities or public utilities to operate and maintain the electric vehicle charging stations.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>All electric vehicle charging stations installed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be capable of collecting and transmitting data in real time to DDOT, including:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The amount of energy consumed at the electric vehicle charging stations;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The location, time of day, and length of time of each use of an electric vehicle charging station; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>How customers paid for the use of an electric vehicle charging station.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>Beginning January 1, 2020, and on an annual basis thereafter, DDOT shall submit to the Council and make publically available an annual report that:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Analyzes the data collected pursuant to subsection (c) of this section; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Makes recommendations regarding:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Whether to continue any agreements entered into pursuant to subsection (b)(2) of this section;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Improving access to electric vehicle charging stations;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Additional locations where electric vehicle charging stations should be installed;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>The level of power the electric vehicle charging stations should provide; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Other policies or programs that could encourage the use of electric vehicles.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(e)</num>
            <text>DDOT shall publish on its website a map identifying the location of all electric vehicle charging stations. DDOT shall update the map, at a minimum, on a quarterly basis.</text>
          </para>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History" path="§9o">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, §  9o</annotation>
      <codify:not-funded-anno path="§50-921.23" applicability-path="§3" action="creation of"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <!-- <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 22-78" path="§2|(a)|(2)" date="2018-08-15" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 22-78" path="§2|(b)" date="2018-08-15" history="false"/> -->
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
