<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>19-1505</num>
  <heading>Power to disclaim; general requirements; when irrevocable.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person may disclaim, in whole or part, any interest in or power over property, including a power of appointment. A person may disclaim the interest or power even if its creator imposed a spendthrift provision or similar restriction on transfer or a restriction or limitation on the right to disclaim.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except to the extent a fiduciary’s right to disclaim is expressly restricted or limited by another statute of the District of Columbia or by the instrument creating the fiduciary relationship, a fiduciary may disclaim, in whole or part, any interest in or power over property, including a power of appointment, whether acting in a personal or representative capacity. A fiduciary may disclaim the interest or power even if its creator imposed a spendthrift provision or similar restriction on transfer or a restriction or limitation on the right to disclaim, or an instrument other than the instrument that created the fiduciary relationship imposed a restriction or limitation on the right to disclaim.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To be effective, a disclaimer must:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be in a writing or other record;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Declare the disclaimer;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Describe the interest or power disclaimed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Be signed by the person making the disclaimer; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Be delivered or filed in the manner provided in § <cite path="§19-1512">19-1512</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>“Record” means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>“Signed” means, with present intent to authenticate or adopt a record, to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Execute or adopt a tangible symbol; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Attach to or logically associate with the record an electronic sound, symbol, or process.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A partial disclaimer may be expressed as a fraction, percentage, monetary amount, term of years, limitation of a power, or any other interest or estate in the property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A disclaimer becomes irrevocable when it is delivered or filed pursuant to § <cite path="§19-1512">19-1512</cite> or when it becomes effective as provided in §§ <cite path="§19-1506">19-1506</cite> through <cite path="§19-1511">19-1511</cite>, whichever occurs later.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A disclaimer made under this chapter is not a transfer, assignment, or release.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-205" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-205, § 2(b), 53 DCR 9063</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 5 of the Uniform Disclaimer of Property Interests Act (1999).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
