<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>19-1307.06</num>
  <heading>Removal of trustee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The settlor, a cotrustee, or a beneficiary may request the court to remove a trustee, or a trustee may be removed by the court on its own initiative.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The court may remove a trustee if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The trustee has committed a serious breach of trust;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Lack of cooperation among cotrustees substantially impairs the administration of the trust;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Because of unfitness, unwillingness, or persistent failure of the trustee to administer the trust effectively, the court determines that removal of the trustee best serves the interests of the beneficiaries; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>There has been a substantial change of circumstances or removal is requested by all of the qualified beneficiaries, the court finds that removal of the trustee best serves the interests of all of the beneficiaries and is not inconsistent with a material purpose of the trust, and a suitable cotrustee or successor trustee is available.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Pending a final decision on a request to remove a trustee, or in lieu of or in addition to removing a trustee, the court may order such appropriate relief under section 19-1310.01(b) as may be necessary to protect the trust property or the interests of the beneficiaries.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-104">Mar. 10, 2004, D.C. Law 15-104, § 2(b), 51 DCR 208</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§19-1310.01">19-1310.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 706 of the Uniform Trust Code.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
