<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>19-1513</num>
  <heading>When disclaimer barred or limited.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A disclaimer is barred by a written waiver of the right to disclaim.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A disclaimer of an interest in property is barred if any of the following events occur before the disclaimer becomes effective:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The disclaimant accepts the interest sought to be disclaimed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The disclaimant voluntarily assigns, conveys, encumbers, pledges, or transfers the interest sought to be disclaimed or contracts to do so; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A judicial sale of the interest sought to be disclaimed occurs.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A disclaimer, in whole or part, of the future exercise of a power held in a fiduciary capacity is not barred by its previous exercise.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A disclaimer, in whole or part, of the future exercise of a power not held in a fiduciary capacity is not barred by its previous exercise unless the power is exercisable in favor of the disclaimant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A disclaimer is barred or limited if so provided by law other than this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A disclaimer of a power over property which is barred by this section is ineffective. A disclaimer of an interest in property which is barred by this section takes effect as a transfer of the interest disclaimed to the persons who would have taken the interest under this chapter had the disclaimer not been barred.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-205" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-205, § 2(b), 53 DCR 9063</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§19-1516">19-1516</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 13 of the Uniform Disclaimer of Property Interests Act (1999).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
