<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>19-1307.04</num>
  <heading>Vacancy in trusteeship; appointment of successor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A vacancy in a trusteeship occurs if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person designated as trustee rejects the trusteeship;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person designated as trustee cannot be identified or does not exist;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A trustee resigns;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A trustee is disqualified or removed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A trustee dies; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A guardian or conservator is appointed for an individual serving as trustee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If one or more cotrustees remain in office, a vacancy in a trusteeship need not be filled. A vacancy in a trusteeship must be filled if the trust has no remaining trustee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A vacancy in a trusteeship of a noncharitable trust that is required to be filled must be filled in the following order of priority:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By a person designated pursuant to the terms of the trust to act as successor trustee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By a person appointed by unanimous agreement of the qualified beneficiaries; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By a person appointed by the court.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A vacancy in a trusteeship of a charitable trust that is required to be filled must be filled in the following order of priority:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By a person designated pursuant to the terms of the trust to act as successor trustee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By a person selected by the charitable organizations expressly designated to receive distributions under the terms of the trust if the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia concurs in the selection; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By a person appointed by the court.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Whether or not a vacancy in a trusteeship exists or is required to be filled, the court may appoint an additional trustee or special fiduciary whenever the court considers the appointment necessary for the administration of the trust.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-104" type="History">Mar. 10, 2004, D.C. Law 15-104, § 2(b), 51 DCR 208</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§19-1301.08">19-1301.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 704 of the Uniform Trust Code.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
