<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>19-1512</num>
  <heading>Delivery or filing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “beneficiary designation” means an instrument, other than an instrument creating a trust, naming the beneficiary of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An annuity or insurance policy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An account with a designation for payment on death;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A security registered in beneficiary form;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A pension, profit-sharing, retirement, or other employment-related benefit plan; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Any other nonprobate transfer at death.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsections (c) through (l) of this section, delivery of a disclaimer may be effected by personal delivery, first-class mail, or any other method likely to result in its receipt.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In the case of an interest created under the law of intestate succession or an interest created by will, other than an interest in a testamentary trust:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A disclaimer must be delivered to the personal representative of the decedent’s estate; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If no personal representative is then serving, it must be filed with a court having jurisdiction to appoint the personal representative.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In the case of an interest in a testamentary trust:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A disclaimer must be delivered to the trustee then serving, or if no trustee is then serving, to the personal representative of the decedent’s estate; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If no personal representative is then serving, it must be filed with a court having jurisdiction to enforce the trust.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>In the case of an interest in an inter vivos trust:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A disclaimer must be delivered to the trustee then serving;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If no trustee is then serving, it must be filed with a court having jurisdiction to enforce the trust; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the disclaimer is made before the time the instrument creating the trust becomes irrevocable, it must be delivered to the settlor of a revocable trust or the transferor of the interest.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>In the case of an interest created by a beneficiary designation which is disclaimed before the designation becomes irrevocable, the disclaimer must be delivered to the person making the beneficiary designation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>In the case of an interest created by a beneficiary designation which is disclaimed after the designation becomes irrevocable:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The disclaimer of an interest in personal property must be delivered to the person obligated to distribute the interest; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The disclaimer of an interest in real property must be recorded with the Recorder of Deeds.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>In the case of a disclaimer by a surviving holder of jointly held property, the disclaimer must be delivered to the person to whom the disclaimed interest passes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>In the case of a disclaimer by an object or taker in default of exercise of a power of appointment at any time after the power was created:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The disclaimer must be delivered to the holder of the power or to the fiduciary acting under the instrument that created the power; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If no fiduciary is then serving, it must be filed with a court having authority to appoint the fiduciary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>In the case of a disclaimer by an appointee of a nonfiduciary power of appointment:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The disclaimer must be delivered to the holder, the personal representative of the holder’s estate, or to the fiduciary under the instrument that created the power, or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If no fiduciary is then serving, it must be filed with a court having authority to appoint the fiduciary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>In the case of a disclaimer by a fiduciary of a power over a trust or estate, the disclaimer must be delivered as provided in subsection (c), (d), or (e) of this section, as if the power disclaimed were an interest in property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>In the case of a disclaimer of a power by an agent, the disclaimer must be delivered to the principal or the principal’s representative.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-205">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-205, § 2(b), 53 DCR 9063</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-230">Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-230, § 3(a), 59 DCR 13606</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="19-1505">19-1505</cite> and § <cite root="19-1515">19-1515</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-230">D.C. Law 19-230</cite>, in (f), substituted “which is disclaimed before” for “made before the time” and substituted “the disclaimer” for “a disclaimer”; and rewrote (g).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 12 of the Uniform Disclaimer of Property Interests Act (1999).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
