<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>19-604.17</num>
  <heading>Optional form of revocation.</heading>
  <text>The following form may be used to create an instrument of revocation under this subchapter. The other sections of this subchapter govern the effect of this or any other instrument used to revoke a transfer on death deed.</text>
  <text>
    <center>
      <strong>(front of form)</strong>
      <br/>
      <strong>REVOCATION OF TRANSFER ON DEATH DEED</strong>
    </center>
  </text>
  <text>NOTICE TO OWNER</text>
  <text>This revocation must be recorded before you die or it will not be effective. This revocation is effective only as to the interests in the property of owners who sign this revocation.</text>
  <text>IDENTIFYING INFORMATION</text>
  <text>Owner or Owners of Property Making This Revocation:</text>
  <text>........................................................................</text>
  <text>Printed name  Mailing address</text>
  <text>........................................................................</text>
  <text>Printed name  Mailing address</text>
  <text>Legal description of the property:</text>
  <text>........................................................................</text>
  <text>REVOCATION</text>
  <text>I revoke all my previous transfers of this property by transfer on death deed.</text>
  <text>SIGNATURE OF OWNER OR OWNERS MAKING THIS REVOCATION</text>
  <text>.................................................. [(SEAL)] ......................</text>
  <text>Signature  Date</text>
  <text>.................................................. [(SEAL)] ......................</text>
  <text>Signature  Date</text>
  <text>ACKNOWLEDGMENT</text>
  <text>(insert acknowledgment here)</text>
  <text>
    <center>
      <strong>(back of form)</strong>
      <br/>
      <strong>COMMON QUESTIONS ABOUT THE USE OF THIS FORM</strong>
    </center>
  </text>
  <text>How do I use this form to revoke a Transfer on Death (“TOD”) deed? Complete this form. Have it acknowledged before a notary public or other individual authorized to take acknowledgments. Record the form in the public records in the Office of the Recorder of Deeds. The form must be acknowledged and recorded before your death or it has no effect.</text>
  <text>How do I find the “legal description” of the property? This information may be on the TOD deed. It may also be available in the Office of the Recorder of Deeds. If you are not absolutely sure, consult a lawyer.</text>
  <text>How do I “record” the form? Take the completed and acknowledged form to the Office of the Recorder of Deeds. Follow the instructions given by the Recorder of Deeds to make the form part of the official property records.</text>
  <text>I am being pressured to complete this form. What should I do? Do not complete this form under pressure. Seek help from a trusted family member, friend, or lawyer.</text>
  <text>I have other questions about this form. What should I do? This form is designed to fit some but not all situations. If you have other questions, consult a lawyer.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-230" type="History">Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-230, § 2(b), 59 DCR 13606</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
