<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>19-604.13</num>
  <heading>Effect of transfer on death deed at transferor’s death.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in the transfer on death deed, in this section, or in § <cite path="§16-910">16-910</cite>, § <cite path="§18-308">18-308</cite>, § <cite path="§19-320">19-320</cite>, § <cite path="§19-502">19-502</cite>, or in Chapter 1 of Title 19, on the death of the transferor, the following rules apply to property that is the subject of a transfer on death deed and owned by the transferor at death:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Subject to paragraph (2) of this section, the interest in the property is transferred to the designated beneficiary in accordance with the deed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The interest of a designated beneficiary is contingent on the designated beneficiary surviving the transferor. The interest lapses if a designated beneficiary fails to survive the transferor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Subject to paragraph (4) of this section, concurrent interests are transferred to the beneficiaries in equal and undivided shares with no right of survivorship.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the transferor has identified 2 or more designated beneficiaries to receive concurrent interests in the property, the share of one which lapses or fails for any reason is transferred to the other, or to the others in proportion to the interest of each in the remaining part of the property held concurrently.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A beneficiary takes the property subject to all conveyances, encumbrances, assignments, contracts, mortgages, liens, and other interests to which the property is subject at the transferor’s death. For purposes of this subsection, the recording of the transfer on death deed is deemed to have occurred at the transferor’s death.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a transferor is a joint owner and is survived by one or more other joint owners, the property that is the subject of a transfer on death deed belongs to the surviving joint owner or owners with right of survivorship.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a transferor is a joint owner and is the last surviving joint owner, the transfer-on death-deed is effective.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A transfer on death deed transfers property without covenant or warranty of title even if the deed contains a contrary provision.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-230" type="History">Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-230, § 2(b), 59 DCR 13606</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
