<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>19-602.12</num>
  <heading>Rights at death.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, on death of a party sums on deposit in a multiple-party account belong to the surviving party or parties. If 2 or more parties survive and one is the surviving spouse or surviving domestic partner of the decedent, the amount to which the decedent, immediately before death, was beneficially entitled under section 19-602.11 belongs to the surviving spouse or surviving domestic partner. If 2 or more parties survive and none is the surviving spouse or surviving domestic partner of the decedent, the amount to which the decedent, immediately before death, was beneficially entitled under section 19-602.11 belongs to the surviving parties in equal shares, and augments the proportion to which each survivor, immediately before the decedent’s death, was beneficially entitled under section 19-602.11, and the right of survivorship continues between the surviving parties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In an account with a POD designation:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>On death of one of 2 or more parties, the rights in sums on deposit are governed by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On death of the sole party or the last survivor of 2 or more parties, sums on deposit belong to the surviving beneficiary or beneficiaries. If 2 or more beneficiaries survive, sums on deposit belong to them in equal and undivided shares, and there is no right of survivorship in the event of death of a beneficiary thereafter. If no beneficiary survives, sums on deposit belong to the estate of the last surviving party.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Sums on deposit in a single-party account without a POD designation, or in a multiple-party account that, by the terms of the account, is without right of survivorship, are not affected by death of a party, but the amount to which the decedent, immediately before death, was beneficially entitled under section 19-602.11 is transferred as part of the decedent’s estate. A POD designation in a multiple-party account without right of survivorship is ineffective. For the purposes of this section, designation of an account as a tenancy in common establishes that the account is without right of survivorship.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The ownership right of a surviving party or beneficiary, or of the decedent’s estate, in sums on deposit is subject to requests for payment made by a party before the party’s death, whether paid by the financial institution before or after death, or unpaid. The surviving party or beneficiary, or the decedent’s estate, is liable to the payee of an unpaid request for payment. The liability is limited to a proportionate share of the amount transferred under this section, to the extent necessary to discharge the request for payment.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-292" type="History">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-292, § 302(b), 48 DCR 2087</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-79" type="History">Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-79, § 5(r), 53 DCR 1035</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§19-602.03">19-602.03</cite>, § <cite path="§19-602.13">19-602.13</cite>, § <cite path="§19-602.14">19-602.14</cite>, § <cite path="§19-602.15">19-602.15</cite>, and § <cite path="§19-602.22">19-602.22</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-79">D.C. Law 16-79</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “surviving spouse or surviving domestic partner” for “surviving spouse”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 212 of the Uniform Nonprobate Transfers on Death Act (1991 Act).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
