<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-1212</num>
  <heading>Answer to a notice of violation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person shall answer a notice of violation within 14 calendar days of the date the notice of violation was issued.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To answer a notice of violation, a person issued a notice may:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Admit the violation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Admit the violation, but with an explanation; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Deny the violation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No response other than those listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be regarded as an answer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person admitting a violation shall, at the time the person submits an answer, pay the applicable civil fine in person or by mail.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person denying the violation shall receive from the Office of Administrative Hearings within 30 days of the office’s receipt of the answer a notice with information about a hearing date.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a person to whom a notice of violation has been issued fails to respond to the notice within 14 calendar days of the date the notice was issued, the person shall be found liable for the civil violation and in default and shall be assessed both the civil fine for the violation and an additional penalty equal to the amount of that civil fine.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-126" type="History" path="§202">July 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-126, § 202, 61 DCR 3482</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3062 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3062 of the FY 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 DCSTAT 3696).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
