<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-172">
  <num type="law">12-172</num>
  <heading type="short">Prince Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1998-10-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-172.pdf">D.C. Law 12-172</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 5195</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0590">
      <narrative>Law 12-172, the “Prince Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-590, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 2, 1998, and June 16, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 8, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-415 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-172 became effective on October 16, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S 5 kwiktag 062 324 479 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-172 "Prince Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-590, on first and second readings, June 2, 1998 and June 16, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 8, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-415, and published in the August 7, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 5195) and transmitted to Congress on July 29, 1998 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-172, effective October 16, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July Sept. Oct. 29,30,31 8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24,25,28,29,30 1,2,5,6,7,8,9,13,14,15 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C, ACT 12-415 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 8. 1998 CodificaKon D~i~ of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code to designate real property owned by the Pri ~ce Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation as tax exempt and to provide equitable real property tax relief to the Prince Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation for such property from December 5, 1997, through March 31, 1998. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Prince Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents to the chapter is amended by adding a new section designation "§ 47-1045. Prince Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation, lot 0826 in square 0333 b) A new section 47-1045 is added to read as follows § 47-1045. Prince Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation, lot 0826 in square 0333 Certain property located in the District of Columbia described as lot 0826 in square 0333 situated at 1000 "U" Street, N.W together with improvements thereon and furnishings therein, with equitable ar cl legal title in the name of the Prince Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation, i hereby exempt from all taxation so long as the same is used in carrying on the purposes and activities of the Prince Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation and is not used for exclusively commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ 47-1005, 47-1007, and 47-1009 Sec. 3. The Council of the District of Columbia orders that all real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against the Prince Hall Freemason and Eastern Star Charitable Foundation, on real property located at 1000 U Street, N.W Washington, D.C lot 0826 in square 0333, for the period December 5, 1997, through March New Section 47-1045 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 31, 1998, be forgiven, and that any payments already made for this period, as of the effective date of this act, be refunded. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 5. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Re Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: July 8, 1998 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12-590Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST READI~IG, 6-2’98 APPROVED ABSENT CATANIA, CHAVOUS AND THOMAS [ J ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Counci|memDer Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Na) NV AB Chmn. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson Councilmember I Aye Nay AB Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas. St. L//Secretary to the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV Present not Voting Date A~OPTED FINAL READING, 6-16-98 APPROVED ABSENT [ I ROLL CALL VOTE Result CHAVOUS Chron. Cropp Alien Ambrose Brazil Mason Catania Patterson ’~’~ X- indicates Vote ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Aye Nay NV AB Councilmeraber Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nat NV AB Chavous I Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT j ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson X Indicates Vote AB Absent Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. ’ NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Counc Dale</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
