<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-164">
  <num type="law">12-164</num>
  <heading type="short">Correctional Treatment Facility Temporary Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-164.pdf">D.C. Law 12-164</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 12-164, the “Correctional Treatment Facility Temporary Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-578. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 3, 1998, and April 7, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 20, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-335 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-164 became effective on October 10, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 325 542 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-164 "Correctional Treatment Facility Temporary Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-578, on first and second readings, March 3, 1998 and April 7, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 20, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-335 and published in the May 15, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 2937) and transmitted to Congress on May 19, 1998 for a 60-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(2) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 60-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-164, effective October 10, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 60-day Congressional Review Period: May July Sept. Oct. 19,20,21,22 1,2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 14,15,16,17,20,21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30,31, 8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24,25,28,29,30 1,2,5,6,7,8,9 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D, C, ACT 12-335 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APRIL 20, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend, on a temporary basis, the Correctional Treatment Facility Act of 1996 to authorize the use of force and use of weapons by correctional officers employed by the operator of any private prison facility housing inmates in the District of Columbia for the District of Columbia Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau &amp;amp;Prisons, in addition to the Correctional Treatment Facility. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Correctional Treatment Facility Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The Correctional Treatment Facility Act of 1996, effective June 3, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-276; D.C. Code § 24-495.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 24-495.1) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (4) is amended to read as follows 4 Private correctional officer" means any full-time or part-time employee of the private operator of the Correctional Treatment Facility or any other privately-operated prison facility housing inmates in the District for the District of Columbia Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons, or the subcontractor of any private operator housing inmates in the District of Columbia for the District of Columbia Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons, whose primary responsibility is the supervision, protection, care, and control of inmates assigned to the Correctional Treatment Facility or any other privately-operated prison facility in the District 2) Paragraph (5) is amended to read as follows 5 Private operator" means any individual, partnership, corporation, or incorporated association bound by contract with the District or the United States to operate the Correctional Treatment Facility or any other prison facility housing inmates in the District for the District of Columbia Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons b) Subsection 3(a D.C. Code § 24-495.2(a is amended to read as follows a) A private correctional officer may carry firearms provided by the private operator only in the following situations: Note, Section 24-495.1 Note, Section 24-495.2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1) While patrolling the perimeter grounds at the CTF or any other privately- operated prison facility 2) While transporting inmates assigned to the CTF or any other privately- operated prison facility 3) While pursuing inmates assigned to the CTF or any other privately-operated prison facility who have escaped from the custody of the Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons; and 4) During a state of emergency as determined by the Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons c) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 24-495.3) is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) An inmate confined in any privately-operated prison facility established pursuant to Subtitle C of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, approved August 5, 1997 (111 Star. 712; P.L. 105-33 shall be deemed to be at all times in the legal custody of the Federal Bureau of Prisons. Only the Federal Bureau of Prisons shall have authority to transfer or assign inmates into or out of the privately-operated prison facility. All laws and regulations governing conduct of inmates in Federal Bureau of Prisons facilities shall apply to inmates confined in any privately-operated prison facility during such time as the prison facility is operated by a private operator. All laws and regulations establishing penalties for offenses committed against correctional officers or other correctional employees shall apply wherever applicable to offenses committed against any private correctional officer or other employee of the private operator Sec. 3. The enactment of this act will have no adverse fiscal impact, and has the potential for favorable fiscal impact because it will allow the District to be considered by the Federal Bureau of Prisons as a location of a new privately-operated prison facility for at least 2,200 District inmates, a project which would generate jobs and increase District revenues. Sec. 4 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116: D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Note, Section 24-495.3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) This ac~expire after 225 ~s of its having taken effect C~o~f~i:fthe District o olu/~l’a/ APPROVED: April 20, 1998 ITEM ON CONSENT CALFNDA.R ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12.578 Docket NO. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 3-3-98 J~ VOICE ~OTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT AP~OVED CHAVOUS AND THOMAS ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania I Aye AB Councilmem her se Chasous Es ans {Jarvis Mason Patterson AB [ Councilmember Schw’artz Smith, Jr. Thomas. Sr ’~ X h~dicates XoIe ~U Xb,ent N Present not X ] gecretar)tO the o~il ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ’,,o T~ ADOPTED FINAL READING, 4-7-98 VOICE VOI’E RECORDED OTE ON REQI APPROVED ALL PRESENT I J ROLl ’ALL VOTE Result iuncilmember .A)e Na) N\ AB ounedmembcr ¢ Na B Councilmemher A)e Na? [ N 1~ Chron. Cropp Cha~ ous Schss artz Allen [ E~ans Smith. Jr. 1 Ambrose .lar~ i~ Thomas, St. Brazil Mason Catania Patterson X Indicates ore XB-xh~ent NV-Prcsent not XotlnR o I~e ouncd Dale I I] F~NSENT (L~LENDAR ] A(’TION &amp;amp; DATE VOI(’E VOTE RI (ORI)ED VOTE IN REOI:EST ABSENT [ I ROLL ALL O’I’E Result t ouncilmemt~e: A)e Na7¯ Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates Vote Evans Jar~is Mason Patterson c [ %a V AB Councilmember Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. I A) e Na? N~ AB t.B Sbsen! NV. Present not otin ER1 IFICAI’ION RECORD Sccrctar to the (’ouncil Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp, To amend, on a temporary basis, the Correctional Treatment Facility Act of 1996 to authorize the use of force and use of weapons by correctional officers employed by the operator of any private prison facility housing inmates in the District of Columbia for the District of Columbia Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons, in addition to the Correctional Treatment Facility. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Correctional Treatment Facility Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The Correctional Treatment Facility Act of 1996, effective June 3, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-276; D.C. Code § 24-495.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 24-495.1) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (4) is amended to read as follows 4 Private correctional officer" means any full-time or part-time employee of the private operator of the Correctional Treatment Facility or any other privately-operated prison facility housing inmates in the District for the District of Columbia Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons, or the subcontractor of any private operator housing inmates in the District of Columbia for the District of Columbia Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons, whose primary responsibility is the supervision, protection, care, and control of inmates assigned to the Correctional Treatment Facility or any other privately-operated prison facility in the District 2) Paragraph (5) is amended to read as follows 5 Private operator" means any individual, partnership, corporation, or incorporated association bound by contract with the District or the United States to operate the Correctional Treatment Facility or any other prison facility housing inmates in the District for the District of Columbia Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons b) Subsection 3(a D.C. Code § 24-495.2(a is amended to read as follows a) A private correctional officer may carry firearms provided by the private operator only in the following situations: Note, Section 24-495.1 Note, Section 24-495.2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1) While patrolling the perimeter grounds at the CTF or any other privately- operated prison facility 2) While transporting inmates assigned to the CTF or any other privately- operated prison facility 3) While pursuing inmates assigned to the CTF or any other privately-operated prison facility who have escaped from the custody of the Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons; and 4) During a state of emergency as determined by the Department of Corrections or the Federal Bureau of Prisons c) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 24-495.3) is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) An inmate confined in any privately-operated prison facility established pursuant to Subtitle C of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, approved August 5, 1997 (111 Stat. 712; P.L. 105-33 shall be deemed to be at all times in the legal custody of the Federal Bureau of Prisons. Only the Federal Bureau of Prisons shall have authority to transfer or assign inmates into or out of the privately-operated prison facility. All laws and regulations governing conduct of inmates in Federal Bureau of Prisons facilities shall apply to inmates confined in any privately-operated prison facility during such time as the prison facility is operated by a private operator. All laws and regulations establishing penalties for offenses committed against correctional officers or other correctional employees shall apply wherever applicable to offenses committed against any private correctional officer or other employee of the private operator Sec. 3. The enactment of this act will have no adverse fiscal impact, and has the potential for favorable fiscal impact because it will allow the District to be considered by the Federal Bureau of Prisons as a location of a new privately-operated prison facility for at least 2,200 District inmates, a project which would generate jobs and increase District revenues. Sec. 4 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116: D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Note, Section 24-495.3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) This act sha~ expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. ¯ o District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
