<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-133">
  <num type="law">12-133</num>
  <heading type="short">Eastern Market Open Air Retailing Temporary Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-133.pdf">D.C. Law 12-133</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 12-133, the “Eastern Market Open Air Retailing Temporary Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-573. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 3, 1998, and April 7, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 20, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-333 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-133 became effective on July 24, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 325 513 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-133 "Eastern Market Open Air Retailing Temporary Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 4 l 2 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-573, on first and second readings, March 3, 1998 and April 7, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 20, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-333 and published in the May 15, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 2933) and transmitted to Congress on May 19, 1998 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-133, effective July 24, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: May June July 19,20,21,22 1,2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 14,15,16,17,20,21,22,23 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-333 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APRIL 20, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To permit, on a temporary basis, the interim continuation of non-food open air retailing in the exterior space at Eastern Market that is not otherwise leased. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Eastern Market Open Air Retailing Temporary Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Consistent with past practices of a Saturday Arts and Crafts Festival and Sunday Flea Market in the North Hall of Eastern Market and the adjacent public space exterior to the North Hall, as designated in the April 29, 1982, April 16, 1987, and December 27, 1995, space sub-assignments from the Commission on Arts and Humanities Sub-assignments the Department of Administrative Services may permit open air non-food retailing activities in the same manner and under the same limits and rules as these activities existed as of November 30, 1997. No open air retailing shall be permitted in the interior or exterior space that is designated in the 1966 lease between Eastern Market Corporation and the Department of Administrative Services without the agreement of the lessee, Eastern Market Corporation. Sec. 3. For purposes of this act, the premises described in the Sub-assignments include 1) The 4,500 square feet of space on the ground floor of the North end of Eastern Market; and (2) The grounds adjacent to the North end of Eastern Market (part of Lot 800 in Square 872, reference number 914.3021 which extend from the Seventh Street curb on the east to the building line, from the North Carolina curb line on the north to the building line, and from the alley curb line on the west to the building line. Sec. 4. This act shall have no fiscal impact. Note, Sections 10-138, 47-2002.1 Note, Sections 10-138, 47-2002.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 5 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203 (a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act sh~ expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: April 20, 1998 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLtTMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD "FWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Ooeket ~o B12-573 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 3-3-98 I~ VOICE OTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST .ABSENT APPROVED CHAVOUS AND THOMAS ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember A)e Chron. Cropp Alien Ambrose Brazil j Catania ] Councilmember Cha~ous Esans tarx is Mason PaCterson %be v tO Ihe ouncll 1 ITEm__gENT ~ALENDAR iAB (ouncilmember r Schw’artz Smith. Jr. Thomas, St. I~ A(’TION &amp;amp; D TE t t.Hlll-I{ IION RI’L(ORI i ADOPTED FINAL READING, 4-7-98 VOICE VOlE RECORDED %OTE ON REQtES1 APPROVED ABSENT ALL PRESENT ROLL CAI.L VOI’E Resul| (’ouncilmember A.~e Na) N% SB Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Cha~ous Esans ,larx is Mason ] I]EM ON CONSENT (’ALEND-%R i£R 1 I1-1(\11 Rf RI) i Councilmemher A}e Na N% [ SB Schsvartz Smith. Jr. Thomas, St, I A{’TION &amp;amp; DAI’E 01(1£ VOTE RE(ORDED VO[E ON REQt Egl I I ROI.L CALIJVOTE Resul! Chmn. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose darvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson X Indicates S’ot¢ AB Absent ]SchwartzC°Uncilmember Smith, Jr. Thomas. Sr A)e Na N% AB NV Present not otinR (’ER IIFIC~TION RE( ORD Secretary tO the (’ouneH Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To permit, on a temporary basis, the interim continuation of non-food open air retailing in the exterior space at Eastern Market that is not otherwise leased. BE IT ENACTED BY TIlE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Eastern Market Open Air Retailing Temporary Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Consistent with past practices of a Saturday Arts and Crafts Festival and Sunday Flea Market in the North Hall of Eastern Market and the adjacent public space exterior to the North Hall, as designated in the April 29, 1982, April 16, 1987, and December 27, 1995, space sub-assignments from the Commission on Arts and Humanities Sub-assignments the Department of Administrative Services may permit open air non-food retailing activities in the same manner and under the same limits and rules as these activities existed as of November 30, 1997. No open air retailing shall be permitted in the interior or exterior space that is designated in the 1966 lease between Eastern Market Corporation and the Department of Administrative Services without the agreement of the lessee, Eastern Market Corporation. Sec. 3. For purposes of this act, the premises described in the Sub-assignments include 1) The 4,500 square feet of space on the ground floor of the North end of Eastern Market; and (2) The grounds adjacent to the North end of Eastern Market (part of Lot 800 in Square 872, reference number 914.3021 which extend from the Seventh Street curb on the east to the building line, from the North Carolina curb line on the north to the building line, and from the alley curb line on the west to the building line. Sec. 4. This act shall have no fiscal impact. Note, Sections 10-138, 47-2002.1 Note, Sections 10-138, 47-2002.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 5 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act sh~ expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. ¯ of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia l ITEM ON CONSENT CALFNDAR I)0 ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Ix~q VOICE OTE RECORDED VOTE O%REQt’EST ABSENT COUNCIL PERIOD IM¢ELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COt"~CIL VOTE Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, AP~ROVED CHAVOUS AND THOMAS B12,.573 3-3-98 ROLL CALL VOTE Resu|t Cbmn. Cropp Atien Cha~ou~ Ambrose Brazil Catania I~I~ ITEM ONI~NSENT ~ALEND~R Ja r~ i~ t I-.HllI-I llI)\ Hf(ORI) ACTION &amp;amp; DA1E Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas. Sr. ADOPTED FINAL READING, 4-7-98 VOICE VOlE RECL~RI)ED OTE N REO! APPROVED ALL PRESENT [ I ROLl ALL VOlT Result Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Cha~ou tRIltI 1 to\ Rt( Sch~artz Smith. Jr. Thomas. Sr. ] I 011"I IE Ri.(I)RDE|) VOFE O\ REOI ESI AB.~t:\T I I ROLL ALl. VOTE Resull Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Chavous Mason Patterson B Sb~enl Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas. St ’ER I IFI(~TIO% RE(’ORD</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
