<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-191" flag="true">
  <num type="law">12-191</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-191.pdf">D.C. Law 12-191</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 322 473 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-191 "Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing Temporary Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-689, on first and second readings, July 7, 1998 and September 22, 1998, respectively. Following the signature oft he Mayor on October 2, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-465 and published in the November 6, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 7832) and transmitted to Congress on January 25, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-191, effective March 26, 1999. LINDA W CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 2,3,4,8,9,10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-465 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 2, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, to establish a mandatory drug and alcohol testing policy for certain employees of the District of Columbia Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services, to ensure that care for residents at the District’s secured and residential facilities for juveniles and persons with mental illness is provided in a safe and secure environment. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-601.1 et seq is amended by adding a new title XX-B to read as follows TITLE XX-B "MANDATORY DRUG AND ALCOHOL TESTING OF CERTAIN EMPLOYEES OF THE DEPARTMENT OF HUMAN SERVICES AND THE COMMISSION ON MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES Sec. 2021. Definitions For the purposes of this title, the term 1 Applicant" means a person who has filed a written employment application form to work for the Department of Human Services or the Commission on Mental Health Services, or has been tentatively selected for employment by either the Department or CMHS, to work as a high potential risk employee 2 CMHS" means the Commission on Mental Health Services 3 Department" or "DHS" means the Department of Human Services. Note, New Section 1-621.21 ENROLLED ORIGINAL a) alcohol use 4 High Potential Risk employee" or "HPR employee" means any Department or CMHS employee who has resident care or custody responsibilities in secured facilities or who works within a residential facility 5 Post-accident employee" means any Department or CMHS employee who, while on duty, was involved in a vehicular or other type of accident resulting in personal injury or property damage, or both 6 Random testing" means drug or alcohol testing taken by Department or CMHS employees at an unspecified time for the purposes of determining whether or not any Department or CMHS employees have used drugs or alcohol and as a result are unable to satisfactorily perform their employment duties 7 Probable cause" means a belief by a supervisor that an employee is under the influence of an illegal substance or alcohol such that the employee’s ability to perform his or her job is impaired 8 Probable cause referral" means a referral, based on probable cause, for testing by the Department or CMHS for drug or alcohol use 9 Residential facility" means a facility that provides a supervised, sheltered living environment for individuals who need such an environment because of their mental, familial, social, or other circumstances 10 Secured facility" means a hospital or institution, leased or owned, and operated by the District government that is equipped and qualified to provide in-resident or in- patient care to detained or committed youth or persons suffering with mental illness Sec. 2022. Employee testing. The following Department and CMHS employees shall be tested for drug and employee; and 1) An applicant for a position that would qualify the applicant as a HPR 2) An employee who has had a probable cause referral 3) A post-accident employee, as soon as reasonably possible after an accident 4) A HPR employee b) Only HPR employees shall be subject to random testing c) Employees shall be given written notice, issued at least 30 days after the effective date of this title, that the Department and CMHS will implement a drug and alcohol testing program d) No employee may be tested for drug or alcohol use prior to receiving the notice required by subsection (c) of this section e) Conditions giving rise to "probable cause" must be observed and documented. Supervisors shall be trained in substance abuse recognition and shall receive a second opinion from another supervisor prior to making a probable cause referral. 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL f) An employee shall be given one opportunity to seek treatment following a positive test result g) The Department and CMHS shall procure a testing vendor and testing shall be implemented pursuant to this title Sec. 2023. Testing methodology a) Testing shall be performed by an outside contractor. The contractor shall be a laboratory certified by the United States Department of Health and Human Services HHS to perform j ob related drug and alcohol forensic testing b) For random testing, the contractor shall come on-site to the Department or CMHS institutions and shall collect urine specimens and split the samples c) The contractor shall perform enzyme-multiplied-immunoassay technique EMIT testing on one sample and store the other sample. Any positive EMIT test shall then be confirmed by the contractor using gas chromatography/mass spectrometry GCMS methodology d) Any Department or CMHS employee found to have a confirmed positive urinalysis shall be notified of the result. The employee may then authorize the stored sample to be sent to another HHS certified laboratory of his or her choice, at his or her expense, for secondary GCMS confirmation e) Probable cause and post-accident testing shall follow the same procedures set forth in subsections (a) through (d) of this section. In such cases, the employee shall be escorted by a supervisor to the contractor’s test site for specimen collection or breathalyzer f) A breathalyzer shall be deemed positive by the Department’s or CMHS’s testing contractor if the contractor determines that 1 milliliter of the employee’s breath (consisting of substantially alveolar air) contains .48 micrograms or more of alcohol Sec. 2024. Motor vehicle operators Any Department or CMHS employee who operates a motor vehicle in the District of Columbia shall be deemed to have given his or her consent, subject to conditions in this title, to the testing of the employee’s urine or breath, for the purpose of determining drug or alcohol content, whenever a supervisor has probable cause or a police officer arrests such person for a violation of the law and has reasonable grounds to believe such person to have been operating or in physical control of a motor vehicle within the District while that person’s breath contains. 10 percent or more, by weight, of alcohol, or while under the influence of an intoxicating liquor or any drug or any combination thereof, or while the ability to operate a motor vehicle is impaired by the consumption of intoxicating liquor Sec. 2025. Procedure and employee impact a) The drug and alcohol testing policy shall be issued in advance of program implementation to inform employees and allow them the opportunity to seek treatment. An employee shall be allowed only one opportunity to seek treatment following their first positive test result. Thereafter, any confirmed positive drug test, or positive breathalyzer test, or a OFFICE OF THE BUDGET IBill Numl~r: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA ENROLLED OR+G.+AL FISCAL IMPACT STATEMENT IType: Emergency x Temporary x Permanent I Date Reported: Subject/Short Title Deparb’nent of Human Services Employee Mandatory Drug and Alcohol Testing Temporary Act of 1998" 1.It will impact spending If ’Yes,’ complete Section 1 in the F’~sca~ Estimate Wod(sheet a) It will affect IocaJ expenditures. b) It will affect federal expenditures. c) It will affect private/other expendtures. d) It will affect intra-District expenditures. YES NO (x x x x x) 2. It will impact revenue If ’Yes,’ complete Section 2 in the Rscal Estimate Worksheet a) It will impact local revenue. b) It will impact federal revenue. c) It will impact private/other revenue. d) It will impact intra-District revenue x x x x x) 3. The bill will have NO or little fiscal impact on spending or revenue If ’Yes,’ explain below x) ExplanaUon for NO fiscal impact: If you check "Yes" for each question, please explain on separate sheet. 1. It will affect an agency and/agencies in the District. 2. Will there be performance measures/output for this bill? 3. Will it have results/outcome, i.e what would happen if this bill is enacted or not enacted? 4. Will the Budget and Financial Plan be affected by this bill? 5. The bill will have NO performance or outcome impact. YES NO (x x x) Sources of information: Services D.C. Department of Human Councilmember: Sandra Allen, Chair, Committee on Human Services Staff Person &amp;amp; Tel: Michael Battle 724-8045 Reviewed by Budget Director: Budget Office Tel: 202-724-8139 OFFICE OF THE BUDGET COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA I Bill Number: I Type: Emergency Temporaw( x ENROLLED ORIG] Z ,L FISCAL ESTIMATE WORKSHEET Permanent ] Date Reported: I EXPENDITURE Personal Services Regular Pay Regular Pay Other Additiona~ Gross Pay Fdnge Benefits SUBTOTAL Non-Personal Services Supplies &amp;amp; Materials Utilities Communications Rent Other Ser~f, ces &amp;amp; Charges Subsidies &amp;amp; Transfers Depreciation &amp;amp; Land Equipment Debt Service &amp;amp; Other SUBTOTAL TOTAL OBJ. CODE CURRENT FISCAL YR OUT I~ OUT YEAR 1 t YEAR 2 l (oo) OUT YEAR 3 (ol) 11 16,288 12 13 14 3,420 19,708 65,154 13,682 78,836 65,154 13,682 78,836 65,154 13,682 2O 30A 30B 30C 4O 50 6O 70 8O 12,320 12,320 32,028 49,280 49,840 49,280 49,840 128,116 128,676 50,400 129,236 Assumptions, Concerns: 2 DS-11 drug testing monitors at $32,577 in salary plus $6,841 in fringe benefits FY 98 expenses for 3 months cost of testing $28 per test: YSA CMHS fy 98 50 3~ fyO0 220 1,560 fy 01 240 t,560 fy 02 26O 1,560 440 x 28.00=$12,320 1,760 x 28.00 49,280 1,780 x 28.00 49,840 1,800 x 28.00 50,400 1,820x 28.00 50,960 OUT YEAR 4 (02) 65,154 13,682 78,836 50,960 50,960 129,796 ENROLLED ORIGINAL refusal to submit to a drug or breathalyzer test shall be grounds for termination of employment in accordance with this act b) The program shall cover all DHS and CMHS employees, including management, and shall be implemented as a single Department or CMHS program c) The results of a random test may not be turned over to any law enforcement agency without the employee’s written consent Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement The fiscal impact statement is attached. Sec. 4. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3 (a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Council of the District of District of Columbia ][ APPROVED: October 2, 1998 4 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION a DATE VOICE vOT RECORDED VOTE ON REOUEST COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLIJMBLA COUNCIL PERIOD "I~’ELVE RECORD OF OFFICLAL COUNCIL VOTE Docke,,’o. B12-689 ADOP~ FIRST READING, 7-7-98 APPROVED ABSENT THOMAS ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmcmber Aye Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson x Indicates Vote ’ retary to the Council 1~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Na) NX AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas. Sr. AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV Present not Voting ADOPTED FINAL READING, 9-22’98 APPROVED MASON ROLL CALf, VOTE Result Councilmeraber Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates Vote IAye Nay NV AB Councihnember Aye Na) NV ]AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Mason Patterson Y~Yrweta~to the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV=Present nOt votin j Y r .ACTION &amp;amp; DATE [ [ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councfimember [ Aye Nay NV AB Cotmcilmember Ave Nay j NV AB Councilmember Ave Nav Chron. Cropp ] Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania [ Patterson X Indicates Vote I I AB Absent Schwartz Smith Ir. Thomas, Sr. NV AB I NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Governmen(Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, to establish a mandatory drug and alcohol testing policy for certain employees of the District of Columbia Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health SerVices, to ensure that care for residents at the District’s secured and residential facilities for juveniles and persons with mental illness is provided in a safe and secure environment. BE IT ENACTED BY THE ~OUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-601.1 etseq is amended by adding a new title XX-B to read as follows TITLE XX-B "M~iNDATORY DRUG AND ALCOHOL TESTING OF CERTAIN EMPLOYEES OF THE DEPARTMENT OF HUMAN SERVICES AND THE COMMISSION ON MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES Sec. 2021. Definitions For the purposes of this title, the term 1 Applicant" means a person who has filed a written employment application form to work for the Department of Human Services or the Commission on Mental Health Services, or has been tentatively selected for employment by either the Department or CMHS, to work as a high potential risk employee 2 CMHS" means the Commission on Mental Health Services 3 Department" or "DHS" means the Department of Human Services. Note, New Section 1-621.21 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4 High Potential Risk employee" or "HPR employee" means any Department or CMHS employee who has resident care or custody responsibilities in secured facilities or who works within a residential facility 5 Post-accident employee" means any Department or CMHS employee who, while on duty, was involved in a vehicular or other type of accident resulting in personal injury or property damage, or both 6 Random testing" means drug or alcohol testing taken by Department or CMHS employees at an unspecified time for the purposes of determining whether or not any Department or CMHS employees have used drugs or alcohol and as a result are unable to satisfactorily perform their employment duties 7 Probable cause" means a belief by a supervisor that an employee is under the influence of an illegal substance or alcohol such that the employee’s ability to perform his or her job is impaired 8 Probable cause referral" means a referral, based on probable cause, for testing by the Department or CMHS for drug or alcohol use 9 Residential facility" means a facility that provides a supervised, sheltered living environment for individuals who need such an environment because of their mental, familial, social, or other circumstances 10 Secured facility" means a hospital or institution, leased or owned, and operated by the District government that is equipped and qualified to provide in-resident or in- patient care to detained or committed youth or persons suffering with mental illness Sec. 2022. Employee testing a) The following Department and CMHS employees shall be tested for drug and alcohol use 1) An applicant for a position that would qualify the applicant as a HPR employee; and 2) An employee who has had a probable cause referral 3) A post-accident employee, as soon as reasonably possible after an accident 4) A HPR employee b) Only HPR employees shall be subject to random testing c) Employees shall be given written notice, issued at least 30 days after the effective date of this title, that the Department and CMHS will implement a drug and alcohol testing program d) No employee may be tested for drug or alcohol use prior to receiving the notice required by subsection (c) of this section e) Conditions giving rise to "probable cause" must be observed and documented. Supervisors shall be trained in substance abuse recognition and shall receive a second opinion from another supervisor prior to making a probable cause referral. 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL f) An employee shall be given one opportunity to seek treatment following a positive test result g) The Department and CMHS shall procure a testing vendor and testing shall be implemented pursuant to this title Sec. 2023. Testing methodology a) Testing shall be performed by an outside contractor’. The contractor shall be a laboratory certified by the United States Department of Health and Human Services HHS to perform job related drug and alcohol forensic testing b) For random testing, the contractor shall come on-site to the Department or CMHS institutions and shall collect urine specimens and split the samples c) The contractor shall perform enzyme-multiplied-immunoassay technique EMIT testing on one sample and store the other sample. Any positive EMIT test shall then be confirmed by the contractor using gas chromatography/mass spectrometry GCMS methodology d) Any Department or CMHS employee found to have a confirmed positive urinalysis shall be notified of the result. The employee may then authorize the stored sample to be sent to another HHS certified laboratory of his or her choice, at his or her expense, for secondary GCMS confirmation e) Probable cause and post-accident testing shall follow the same procedures set forth in subsections (a) through (d) of this section. In such cases, the employee shall be escorted by a supervisor to the contractor’s test site for specimen collection or breathalyzer f) A breathalyzer shall be deemed positive by the Department’s or CMHS’s testing contractor if the contractor determines that 1 milliliter of the employee’s breath (consisting of substantially alveolar-air) contains .48 micrograms or more of alcohol Sec. 2024. Motor vehicle operators Any Department or CMHS employee who operates a motor vehicle in the District of Columbia shall be deemed to have given his or her consent, subject to conditions in this title, to the testing of the employee’s urine or breath, for the purpose of determining drug or alcohol content, whenever a supervisor has probable cause or a police officer arrests such person for a violation of the law and has reasonable grounds to believe such person to have been operating or in physical control of a motor vehicle within the District while that person’s breath contains. 10 _percent or more, by weight, of alcohol, or while under the influence of an intoxicating liquor or any drug or any combination thereof, or while the ability to operate a motor vehicle is impaired by the consumption of intoxicating liquor Sec. 2025. Procedure and employee impact a) The drug and alcohol testing policy shall be issued in advance of program implementation to inform employees and allow them the opportunity to seek treatment. An employee shall be allowed only one opportunity to seek treatment following their first positive test result. Thereafter, any confirmed positive drug test, or positive breathalyzer test, or a OFFICE OF THE BUDGET Bill Num~r: CuUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA ENROLLED FISCAL IMPACT STATEMENT J Type: Emergency x Temporary x Permanent I Date Reported: I Subject/Short TP,.le Department of Human Se~ces Employee Mandatory Drug and Alcohol Testing Temporary Act of 1998’ 1.It will impact spending If ’Yes,’ complete Section 1 in the FLa.,a] Estimate Worksheet a) It will affect Ioca~ expenditures. b) It will affect federal expenditures. c) It will affect private/other expendtures. d) It will affect intra-Distdct expenditures. 2.It will impact revenue If ’Yes,’ complete $eclJon 2 in the Rscal EslJtnate Worksheet a) It will impact local revenue. b) It wig impact federal revenue. c) It will impact private/other revenue. d) It will impact intra-District revenue. 3. The bill will have NO or little fiscal impact on spending or revenue If ’Yes,’ explain below YES NO (x x x x x x x x x x x) Explanation for NO fiscal impact: If you check "Yes" for each question, please explain on separate sheet. 1. It will affect an agency and/agencies in the District. 2. Will there be performance measures/output for this bill? 3. Will it have results/outcome, i.e what would happen if this bill is enacted or not enacted? 4. Will the Budget and Financial Plan be affected by this bill? 5. The bill will have NO pedormance or outcome impact. YES NO (x x x) Sources of information: Services D.C. Department of Human Councilmember: Sandra Allen, Chair, Committee on Human Services Staff Person &amp;amp; Tel: Michael Battle 724-8045 Reviewed by Budget Director: Budget Office Tel: 202-724-8139 OFFICE OF THE BUDGET ENROLLED ORIG]t L COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA FISCAL ESTIMATE WORKSHEET IBill Number Type: Emergency Temp°raP x Petma"~nt I Date Rep°rted: I OBJ. CURRENT OUT I OUT OUT OUT E X P E N D I T U R E CODE FISCAL YR YEAR 1 YEAR 2 YEAR 3 YEAR 4 98 99 IX] 01 02) Personal Services Regular Pay Regular Pay Other Additional Gross Pay -Fringe Benefits SUBTOTAL Non-Personal Services Supplies &amp;amp; MateriaJ Utilibes Communications Rent Other Services &amp;amp; Cha~ges Subsidies &amp;amp; Transfers Deprecial~on &amp;amp; Land Equipment Debt Service &amp;amp; Other S U BTOTAL TOTAL 11 12 13 14 16,288 65,154 65,154 65,154 65,154 3,420 19,708 13,682 78,836 13,682 78,836 13,682 78,836 13,682 78,836 20 30A 30B 30C 40 50 60 70 8O 12,320 49,280 t 49,840 50,400 50,960 12,320 49,280 49,840 50,400 50,960 32,028 128,116 128,676 129,236 129,796 Assumpbons, Concerns: 2 DS-11 drug testing monitors at $32,577 in saJary plus $6,841 in fringe benefits FY 98 expenses for 3 months cost of testing $28 per test: YSA CMHS 98 50 3g0 1y99 2oo I,S6O ~00 22O 1,560 fy 01 240 I,S60 fy O2 26O 1,560 440 x 28.00 12,320 1,760 x 28.00 49,280 1,780 x 28.00 49,840 1,800 x 28.00 50,400 1,820 x 28.00 50,960 ENROLLED ORIGINAL refusal to submit to a drug or breathalyzer test shall be grounds for termination of employment in accordance with this act b) The program shall cover all DHS and CMHS employees, including management, and shall be implemented as a single Department or CMHS program c) The’results of a random test may not be turned over to any law enforcement agency without the employee’s written consent Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement The fiscal impact statement is attached. Sec. 4. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the vetc0, approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect u~nr~i?onf the District o-f Colu~bia/ Mayor District of Columbia 4 I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I ACI’ION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE ¯ RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLIYMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIE VOTE D,,e, No. B12-689 ADOPT FIRST READING. 7-7-98 APPROVED ABSENT THOMAS { { ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councdmember Aye Nay N AB Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania ] X Indicates Vote F-re to the Councii I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE l VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQtiEST ABSENT iCouncilmemberChavous Evans I Aye [ NV AB Councilmembcr Aye Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas. Sr.Jarvis Mason Patterson AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD ADOPTED FINAL READING, 9-22-98 APPROVED MASON ROLL CALL VOTE Result ,Councdmember Chron. Cropp Allen [ Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicsfes Vote Council I ITEM ON CON~ENT CALENDAR Aye Na NV AB Couneilmember Ave I Na~ NX" I AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Evans Jarvis t Mason Patterson AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Schwartz Smith. Jr. 1 Thomas. St. NV-Present not VOtln~ I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDEI) VOTE ON REQUEST .gBSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councihmember Aye Na NV AB CouncilmemDer Ave Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Cropp Chavous Schwartz Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil [ I Mason Catania [ Patterson X Indicates Vote Smith. Jr. i Thomas. Sr. AB Ab!lent N~,’ Present not ~ollne CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the COuncil Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
