<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-190">
  <num type="law">12-190</num>
  <heading type="short">Office of the Inspector General Law Enforcement Powers Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1999-03-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-190.pdf">D.C. Law 12-190</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 7814</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0622">
      <narrative>Law 12-190, the “Office of the Inspector General Law Enforcement Powers Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-622, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 7, 1998, and September 22, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 2, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-461 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-190 became effective on March 26, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 089 898 372 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-190 "Office of the Inspector General Law Enforcement Powers Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-622, on first and second readings, July 7, 1998 and September 22, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 2, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-461 and published in the November 6, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 7814) and transmitted to Congress on January 25, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. LINDA W CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 2,3,4,8,9,10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C ACT 12-461 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 2, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Snpp. To amend the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 and An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes to allow investigators employed by the Office of the Inspector General to carry firearms, to make arrests if a felony violation is being committed in the presence of the investigator, and to apply for and execute search warrants. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, that this act may be cited as the "Office of the Inspector General Law Enforcement Powers Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 208 of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1182.8 is amended by adding a new subsection (f-l) to read as follows f-l) An employee of the Office of the Inspector General who, as part of his or her official duties, conducts investigations of alleged felony violations, shall possess the following authority while engaged in the performance of official duties 1) To carry a firearm within the District of Columbia or a District government facility located outside of the District, provided that the employee has completed a course of training in the safe handling of firearms and the use of deadly force, and is qualified to use a firearm according to the standards applicable to officers of the Metropolitan Police Department. The employee may not carry a firearm in the course of official duties unless designated by the Inspector General in writing as having the authority to carry a firearm. The Inspector General shall issue written guidehnes pertaining to the authority to carry firearms, the appropriate use of firearms, firearms issuance and security, and the use of force 2) To make an arrest without a warrant if the employee has probable cause to believe that a felony violation of a federal or District of Columbia statute is being committed in his or her presence, provided that the arrest is made while the employee is engaged in the performance of his or her official duties within the District of Columbia or a District government facility located outside of the District; and Section 1-1182.8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3) To serve as an affiant for, to apply to an appropriate judicial officer for, and execute a warrant for the search of premises or the seizure of evidence if the warrant is issued under authority of the District of Columbia or of the United States upon probable cause Sec. 3. Section 5(a) of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Star. 651; D.C. Code § 22-3205(a is amended by inserting the phrase "including criminal investigators &amp;amp;the Office of the Inspector General, designated in writing by the Inspector General, while engaged in the performance of their official duties after the phrase "duly appointed law-enforcement officers Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the Committee Report on Bill 12-622 as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(3 Sec. 5. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203 (a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 .gtat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Reg~ Council of the District of Columbia Section 22-3205 DMi~tYr~2t of Columbia APPROVED: October 2, 1998 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Docke,~o. B12-622 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 7-7-98 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEffI ABSENT APPROVED ALL PRESENT [ J ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Conncilmember Aye N~ty Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil NV [ AB Catania x Indicates Vote ’S~cr r o e Co..c’, I Councilmember Aye [ Nay Chavous Evans I Jarvis Mason Patterson AB Absen! CERTIFICATION RECORD ACTION &amp;amp; DATE NV AB Councilmember I Aye Na N’~ AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. I Thomas, Sr. NV Present not Vonn~ Dale ADOPTED F I NAL READ I NG, 9’22-98 [~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON I~E(~UEST ABSENT APPROVED MASON ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron, Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay I X Indicates Vote ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE NV AB Councilmember Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Council Aye I Nu [ NV AB AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD j NV-Presfnt not volin c 8 Date VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT { I ROI~L CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councdmember Aye Nay NV AB Counci|member Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. Mason Patterson X Indicates Vote AB Absent NV Present not Votin~ CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretory to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
