<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-182">
  <num type="law">12-182</num>
  <heading type="short">Public School Nurse Assignment Temporary Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-182.pdf">D.C. Law 12-182</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 12-182, the “Public School Nurse Assignment Temporary Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-739. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 30, 1998, and September 22, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 1, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-453 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-182 became effective on March 26, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LMENT(S) kwikta[ 062 323 671 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-182 "Public School Nurse Assignment Temporary Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-739, on first and second readings, July 30, 1998 and September 22, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 1, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-453 and published in the October 16, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 7449) and transmitted to Congress on January 25, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-182, effective March 26, 1999. LINDA W CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 2,3,4,8,9,10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-453 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER I, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987 to indicate the level of medical coverage required at District of Columbia Public School varsity and non-varsity interscholastic football games held in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public School Nurse Assignment Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 See. 2. Section 2(e)(1)(A) of the District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987, effective December 10, 1987 (D.C. Law 7-45; D.C. Code § 31-2421(e)(1)(A is amended to read as follows A) For varsity football, a licensed medical doctor and for non-varsity football, a licensed medical doctor or certified athletic trainer Sec. 3. This act shall have no fiscal impact. Sec. 4 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Cotmcil to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Note, Section 31-2421 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. nc~i~f the District of Columb~-ia/ 2 [ ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12.739 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 7 30-98 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED CATANIA, SMITH AND. THOMAS ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson x Indicates Vote e Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT MASON AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Councilmerabcr Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St j NV yreseut not Voting ADOPTED FINAL READING, 9-22’98 APPROVED ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV Chmn. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans~ Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson X Indicates Vote AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD ~Secretiry to the Council [ [ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. n Date I I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson x IndicateS Vote Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
