<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-197">
  <num type="law">12-197</num>
  <heading type="short">Sex Offender Registration Risk Assessment Clarification and Convention Center Marketing Service Contracts Temporary Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-197.pdf">D.C. Law 12-197</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 12-197, the “Sex Offender Registration Risk Assessment Clarification and Convention Center Marketing Service Contracts Temporary Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-699. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 7, 1998, and September 22, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 8, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-474 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-197 became effective on March 26, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-197 "Sex Offender Registration Risk Assessment Clarification and Convention Center Marketing Service Contracts Temporary Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-699, on first and second readings, July 7, 1998 and September 22, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 8, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-474 and published in the November 13, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 7997) and transmitted to Congress on January 28, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-197, effective March 26, 1999. I2INDA W CRO P Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 2,3,4,8,9,10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C. ACT 12-474 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 8, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend, on a temporary basis, the Sex Offender Registration Act of 1996 to provide for risk assessments and determinations of all offenders who are required to register under the Act so that appropriate notification to community entities, institutions, organizations, and members can be made; and to amend the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994 to require that additional marketing service contracts be submitted to the Council. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Sex Offender Registration Risk Assessment Clarification and Convention Center Marketing Service Contracts Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 18 of the Sex Offender Registration Act of 1996, effective June 3, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-274; D.C. Code § 24-1117 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c) Notwithstanding any other provision of this act, and subject to the availability of funds, the Court may at any time 1) Direct the Advisory Council to make an assessment and recommendation concerning any offender who is required to register under this act 2) Order a mental examination of any offender who is required to register under this act, for the purpose of assessing risk under the provisions of this act; and 3) Make the determinations described in section 6(3)(D in conformity with section 6(3)(A C Sec. 3. Section 208a of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective August 12, 1998 (D.C. Law 12-142; to be codified at D.C. Code § 9-809.1 is amended by adding a new subsection (g) to read as follows g) Any marketing contracts that exceed the specified dollar amounts contained in section III.A. 1 or section 3(a)(1) of the Washington Convention Center Contract Nos. 1-99, 2- 99, 3-99, and 4-99, as approved by the Council, shall be submitted to the Council for a 60-day Note, Section 24-1117 Note, Section 9-809.1 1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL period of review and approval. No additional marketing contracts shall be approved by the Authority without Council review and approval Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council expects the adoption of section 2 of this act to require the expenditure of funds for the mental health assessments which could vary from a few hundred to several thousand dollars per offender, for an estimated total of $200,000 per year. Funding for the mental health aspect of this program is being contemplated through a reprogramming. In the meantime, and to the extent that funding is available, the Forensic Services Administration, Bureau of Legal Services will conduct court-ordered mental health evaluation of sex offenders although it will require additional time to complete them. Priority will be given to offenders who are released or will be released in the near future. Sec. 5. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3 (a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor l District of Columbia APPROVED: October 8, 1998 2 ] I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE 1~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD "I~’ELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIl. VOTE OoeketNo. B12-699 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 7-7-98 APPROVED THOMAS ROLL CALL VOTE Result Couneilmember Aye Nay Chmn. Cropp IAB Councilmernbcr Aye Nay [ NV AB Couocilmember Chavous [ Schwartz Aye N AB Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson X [4~dicate$ Vote ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV Present not oting ADOPTED FINAL READING, 9’22-98 APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT MASON ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Alien Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson x Indicates Vote Aye Nay NV AB-Absem ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE CERTIFICATION RECORD AB Councilmember Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Aye Nay N~,’ .AB I NV-Present not VOtln~ Date [ I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST .ABSENT ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates Vote NV ] AB Councilmember Aye Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Nty NV AB Absent AB Cnuncilmember Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas. St. Aye Nav NV AB NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend, on a temporary basis, the Sex Offender Registration Act of 1996 to provide for risk assessments and determinations of all offenders who are required to register under the Act so that appropriate notification to community entities, institutions, organizations, and members can be made; and to amend the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994 to require that additional marketing service contracts be submitted to the Council. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Sex Offender Registration Risk Assessment Clarification and Convention Center Marketing Service Contracts Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 18 of the Sex Offender Registration Act of 1996, effective June 3, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-274; D.C. Code § 24-1117 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c) Notwithstanding any other provision of this act, and subject to the availability of funds, the Court may at any time 1) Direct the Advisory Council to make an assessment and recommendation concerning any offender who is required to register under this act 2) Order a mental examination of any offender who is required to register under this act, for the purpose of assessing risk under the provisions of this act; and 3) Make the determinations described in section 6(3)(D in conformity with section 6(3)(A C Sec. 3. Section 208a of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective August 12, 1998 (D.C. Law 12-142; to be codified at D.C. Code § 9-809.1 is amended by adding a new subsection (g) to read as follows g) Any marketing contracts that exceed the specified dollar amounts contained in section III.A.1 or section 3(a)(1) of the Washington Convention Center Contract Nos. 1-99, 2- 99, 3-99, and 4-99, as approved by the Council, shall be submitted to the Council for a 60-day Note, Section 24-1117 Note, Section 9-809.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL period of review and approval. No additional marketing contracts shall be approved by the Authority without Council review and approval Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council expects the adoption of section 2 of this act to require the expenditure of funds for the mental health assessments which could vary from a few hundred to several thousand dollars per offender, for an estimated total of $200,000 per year. Funding for the mental health aspect of this program is being contemplated through a reprogramming. In the meantime, and to the extent that funding is available, the Forensic Services Administration, Bureau of Legal Services will conduct court-ordered mental health evaluation of sex offenders although it will require additional time to complete them. Priority will be given to offenders who are released or will be released in the near future. Sec. 5. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3 (a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. lrman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia 2 I ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I~ vOICE VOTE ¯ RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE D.~e, No. B12-699 ADOPTED FIRST READIN6. 7-7-98 APPROVED ABSENT THOMAS ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Na N AB Counedmember Aye Na NV AB Councilmembcr IChavous I Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas. Sr. Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson X dicates Vote v. VF etsry to t~e Counci ITEM ON CONSEN~ CALENDAR A~OS &amp;amp T~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Aye Na~ t ’1 NV Present not otm~ ADOPTED FINAL READING, 9-22-98 APPROVED ABSENT MASON ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania ’ IAye Na) NV AB Councilmember Aye Na NV t AB Councdmember Ave Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB-Absem CERTIFICATION RECORD Uouncil Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas. St. ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I [ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST .aBSENT [ ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmembcr Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Ave Nay NV AB CouncilmemDer Aye Nay Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith..Jr. Thomas. Sr.Jarvis Mason Patterson AB Absent NV AB NV. Present not ~ottne CE~i JVlCATION RECORD Secretary. to the Council Dale</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
