<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-116">
  <num type="law">12-116</num>
  <heading type="short">Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-116.pdf">D.C. Law 12-116</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0426">
      <narrative>Law 12-116, the “Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-426, which was referred to the Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 3, 1998, and March 3, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 17, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-313 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-116 became effective on June 6, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-116 "Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 Amendment Act of 1998 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-426, on first and second readings, February 3, 1998 and March 3, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on March 17, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-313, and published in the April 3, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page1959) and transmitted to Congress on March 31, 1998 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-116, effective June 6, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Mar. Apr. May June 31 1,21,22,23,24,27,28,2930 1,4,5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,18,19,20,21,22 1,2,3,4,5 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12’3!3 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MARCH 17, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 to clarify certain requirements of the act and to conform certain definitions to federal law; the District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982 to exempt mortgage lenders and mortgage brokers from the requirements of that act; and An Act To regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms, and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real estate brokers in the District of Columbia to add certain exemptions. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996, effective September 9, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-155; D.C. Code § 26-1001 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 26-1001) is amended as follows: Section (1) Paragraph (9) is amended to read as follows: 26-1ool 9 Loan application" means the submission of a borrower’s financial information in anticipation of a credit decision, whether written or computer-generated, relating to a mortgage loan. If the submission does not state or identify a specific property, the submission is an application for a pre-qualification and not an application for a mortgage loan. The subsequent addition of an identified property to the submission converts the submission to an application for a mortgage loan 2) Paragraph (11)(A)(i) is repealed b) Section 3(1 D.C. Code § 26-1002(1 is amended to read as follows: Section 1) Any bank, trust company, savings bank, savings and loan association, or 26-1002 credit union incorporated or chartered under the laws of the United States, any state or territory of the United States, or the District, and any other financial institution incorporated or chartered under the laws of the District or of the United States, that accepts deposits and is regulated ENROLLED ORIGINAL under Title 26 of the District of Columbia Code, and subsidiaries and affiliates of such entities which maintain their principal office or a branch office in the District of Columbia and in which the lender, subsidiary, or affiliate is subject to the general supervision or regulation of, or subject to audit or examination by, a regulatory body or agency of the United States, any state or territory of the United States, or the District c) Section 4(b)(3 D.C. Code § 26-1003(b)(3 is amended by striking the word "having" and inserting the word "maintaining" in its place wherever it appears. Section 26-1003 Sec. 3. Section 1~2 of the District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-209; D.C. Code § 45-1931 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the word "or b) Paragraph (8) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase or" in its place c) A new paragraph (9) is added to read as follows 9) Any person who is licensed by the District of Columbia as a mortgage lender or mortgage broker, or who is exempt from licensure under section 3 of the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996, effective September 9, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-155; D.C. Code § 26- 1002 Section 45-1931 Sec. 4. Section 10(a) of An Act To regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms, and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real estate brokers in the District of Columbia, approved February 4, 1913 (37 Star. 660; D.C. Code § 26-710(a is amended by inserting the phrase "any person exempt from licensure under section 3 of the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 if the activity involves making or brokering a mortgage after the phrase "licensed mortgage lenders Section 26-710 Sec. 5. This act will have no fiscal impact. Sec. 6. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule ENROLLED ORIGINAL Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia/~egister. Council of the District of Columbia District ofColumbia APPROVED: March 17, 1998 |TEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DA’IE COl. NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL MBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COL’NCIL VOTE Doc o, No. B12-426 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 2-3-98 1 vOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED THOMAS [ I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Coun¢ilmember Chron. Cropp Chavous Allen E~ans Ambrose [ Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania i Palterson x Indicates Vole v 0 e~r to the Council I Aye Nay NV [ AB Councilmrmber X)e Nay NV AB (’~uncilmernber ~ll bsent (ER I I F I( IION RI-X’ORD Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR IXI AC[ION &amp;amp; DATE ADOPTED FINAL READING, 3-3-98 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST .ABSENT A_P_PROVED EVANS [ ] ROLl ALl. VOTE Resul¢ Councilmember Aye Nay N~*’ AB (’ounci|memhcr Chron. Cropp Cha~ous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Pallerson X Iti ~ieales Vole J tar)’ to the (’ouncil ] II’EM ON CONSENT(’ALENDAR ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE IR | IF I( A I ION RE(ORI) Councilmember Aye Na} NV AB Schwarlz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. I I VOICE VOTE RE(’ORDED YOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I } ROLL CALL VOTE Resul ’ouncilmember Chron. Cropp Chavous Alien Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson A~e Na) NV AB (’ouncilmrmher X)c Na) N’~ AB Councilmember Aye Na NV AB X Indicates Vote Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas, Sr. AB Absent NV Present not Voting (’ERTIEICATION RECORD Secretary to the Cozzncil Dale ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA CodificationDisO.ict of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 to clarify certain requirements of the act and to conform certain definitions to federal law; the District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982 to exempt mortgage lenders and mortgage brokers from the requirements of that act; and An Act To regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms, and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real estate brokers in the District of Columbia to add certain exemptions. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996, effective September 9, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-155; D.C. Code § 26-1001 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 26-1001) is amended as follows: Se~ion (1) Paragraph (9) is amended to read as follows: 26-1001 9 Loan application" means the submission of a borrower’s financial information in anticipation of a credit decision, whether written or computer-generated, relating to a mortgage loan. If the submission does not state or identify a specific property, the submission is an application for a pre-qualification and not an application for a mortgage loan. The subsequent addition of an identified property to the submission converts the submission to an application for a mortgage loan 2) Paragraph (11)(A)(i) is repealed b) Section 3(1 D.C. Code § 26-1002(1 is amended to read as follows: Section 1) Any bank, trust company, savings bank, savings and loan association, or 26-1002 credit union incorporated or chartered under the laws of the United States, any state or territory of the United States, or the District, and any other financial institution incorporated or chartered under the laws of the District or of the United States, that accepts deposits and is regulated ENROLLED ORIGINAL under Title 26 of the District of Columbia Code, and subsidiaries and affiliates of such entities which maintain their principal office or a branch office in the District of Columbia and in which the lender, subsidiary, or affiliate is subject to the general supervision or regulation of, or subject to audit or examination by, a regulatory body or agency of the United States, any state or territory of the United States, or the District c) Section 4(b)(3 D.C. Code § 26-1003(b)(3 is amended by striking the word "having" and inserting the word "maintaining" in its place wherever it appears. Section 26-1003 Sec. 3. Section 12 of the District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-209; D.C. Code § 45-1931 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the word "or b) Paragraph (8) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase or" in its place c) A new paragraph (9) is added to read as follows 9) Any person who is licensed by the District of Columbia as a mortgage lender or mortgage broker, or who is exempt from licensure under section 3 of the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996, effective September 9, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-155; D.C. Code § 26- 1002 Section 45-1931 Sec. 4. Section 10(a) of An Act To regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms, and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real estate brokers in the District &amp;amp;Columbia, approved February 4, 1913 (37 Star. 660; D.C. Code § 26-710(a is amended by inserting the phrase "any person exempt from licensure under section 3 of the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996 if the activity involves making or brokering a mortgage after the phrase "licensed mortgage lenders Section 26-710 Sec. 5. This act will have no fiscal impact. Sec. 6. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia/Register. C~r~an Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia I I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR IN ACTION &amp;amp; DA’IE VOICE VOTI: RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD I~,’E[ VE RECORD OF OFI:ICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Do~e, No. B12-426 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 2-3-98 APPROVED THOMAS ROLL CALL VOI"E Resal! Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania I A~ N N SB (ouncilnlemher ] | Chavous Jarvi~ Mason Palter~on ir~l; Io !he {o. n¢,l ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR A(+PION &amp;amp; DATE Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas. St u} XB EB 11} I I10% ADOPTED FINAL READING, 3-3-98 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ~BSENT APPROVED EVANS ROLL (’ALL VOTE Result CouneHmember Aye Nay Nx. AB ouncilmcmhrr Chron. Cropp Cha~ous Allen Evans Ambrose Janis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson X Indicates Vote ITEM N CONSENT (’ALENDAR ERIII’I 110% RE( ORD Ct~uncilmember A)r Na~ XV AB Sch~vartz Smith. Jr. Thomas. Sr. [ ¯ I ’ Date I x("rloN &amp;amp; DATE } VOI(’E VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUES’[ ABSENT I } ROLl. CALL VOTE Re~ull Councilmemher Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania A)e Na) NV ~B X Indica;es Vote Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB Absenl Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas, Sr. Aye Na NV AB NV Presen{ nol Votin ’ERi’IEICATION RECORD</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
