<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-132">
  <num type="law">12-132</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Federal Conformity Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1998-07-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-132.pdf">D.C. Law 12-132</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 2931</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0415">
      <narrative>Law 12-132, the “District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Federal Conformity Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-415, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 3, 1998, and April 7, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 20, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-332 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-132 became effective on July 24, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S 5 kwiktag s 089 896 644 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-132 "District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Federal Conformity Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-415, on first and second readings, March 3, 1998 and April 7, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 20, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-332 and published in the May 15, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 2931) and transmitted to Congress on May 19, 1998 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-132, effective July 24, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: May July 19,20,21,22 1,2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 14,15,16,17,20,21,22,23 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C, ACT 12-332 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APRIL 20, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act to include provisions permitting the sharing of information with the National Directory &amp;amp;New Hires to comply with requirements of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Federal Conformity Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 13(0 of the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act, approved August 28, 1935 (49 Stat. 946; D.C. Code § 46-114(0 is amended in the third sentence by inserting after the phrase "Public Welfare of the government of any state the following text or the National Directory of New Hires established pursuant to section 316(f) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, approved August 22, 1996 (110 Stat. 2209; 42 U.S.C. §653a) or any District of Columbia State Directory of New Hires established pursuant to section 313(b) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 Sec. 3. Fiscal impact a) General statement. The proposed legislation amends the District of Columbia’s Unemployment Compensation Act to comply with the requirements of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Act of 1996. First, the legislation requires Department of Employment Services DOES to share information with U.S. Department of Health and Human Services for entry in the National Directory of New Hires, and with any District of Columbia State Directory of New Hires that may be established. These directories will identify individuals who are working and are delinquent on child support payments b) Quantitative estimate of the expenditure needed to implement the measure. Implementation of the legislation will require DOES’s data center performing data interfacing and cross matching for the National Directory. The data center will incorporate a one Section 46-114 ENROLLED ORIGINAL time $60,000 cost for the National Directory. The data center will interface data reported to the Directory of New Hires with the agency’s unemployment compensation benefit system. After the first year implementation costs, the annual cost will be $26,000 for computer tapes and processing for the National Directory. First Year Cost 86,000 Second Year Cost 26,000 (c) Identification of revenue and funds currently available from existing revenue source to implement the measure. No current revenue or funds are available to implement the proposed changes to the legislation d) Extent to which current appropriations are available to finance the implementation of the measure during the current fiscal year. There is no fiscal impact on the current appropriation for DOES to finance the implementation of this proposed legislative change e) Identification of the specific source of revenue to be recommended in the forthcoming fiscal years to implements this measure. The $60,000 start-up cost and $26,000 tape and processing cost for the National Directory of New Hires will be reimbursed by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203 (a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code §47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act approved December 2~4, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and District of Columbia Re~i~ter J publication in the Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: Apr±l 20, I998 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE vOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENF COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL. VOTE Docket No. B12-415 ADOPIED FIRST READING, 3-3-98 APPROVED [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember [ Aye Na~ N% AB Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania ouncilmernher Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patlerson A(~PION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQ|EST ’~,e %a} %V [ AB (ouncilrnemher Sch~’artz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Absent ER I IFI( x FII Rk(’ORD Date’ ADOPTED FINAL READING, 4-7-98 APPROVED %BSENT ALL PRESENT I I ROLL ILl. VOTE Result Ciluncilmem bet A)e Na? Chmn. Cropp Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates i Secr~r~ to the (tiuncil I rFE%I ON CONSENT (’ALENDAR AB ouncilmember Chasous .I a r~ is Mason Patterson x;,e Na N B (Touncilmembcr Schsvartz Smith. Jr. Thomas. Sr. i %11 b~enl ERIIFI( gll()\ RtL( ORI) NV-Present not sotin2 I CFION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RE(’ORI)ED VOFE ON BSEN’F ROLL CALL VOTE Result (’ouncilmembcr Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania |  Na} X B (ouncilmember I ’~,t Na? N; AB Councilmember A)e Na~ NV All Chavoas Schwartz X Indicates Vote Evans Smith. Jr. Jan’is Thomas. St. Mason Patterson B- Absen! NV Present not %otin.o (’ERFIFI(’ATION RECORD Secreta to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act to include provisions permitting the sharing of information with the National Directory &amp;amp;New Hires to comply with requirements of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Federal Conformity Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 13(0 &amp;amp;the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act, approved August 28, 1935 (49 Stat. 946; D.C. Code § 46-114(f is amended in the third sentence by inserting after the phrase "Public Welfare of the government of any state the following text or the National Directory of New Hires established pursuant to section 316(f) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, approved August 22, 1996 (110 Stat. 2209; 42 U.S.C. §653a) or any District of Columbia State Directory of New Hires established pursuant to section 313(b) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 Sec. 3. Fiscal impact a) General statement. The proposed legislation amends the District of Columbia’s Unemployment Compensation Act to comply with the requirements &amp;amp;the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Act of 1996. First, the legislation requires Department of Employment Services DOES to share information with U. S, Department of Health and Human Services for entry in the National Directory of New Hires, and with any District of Columbia State Directory of New Hires that may be established. These directories will identify individuals who are working and are delinquent on child support payments b) Quantitative estimate of the expenditure needed to implement the measure. Implementation of the legislation will require DOES’s data center performing data interfacing and cross matching for the National Directory. The data center will incorporate a one Section 46-114 ENROLLED ORIGINAL time $60,000 cost for the National Directory. The data center will interface data reported to the Directory of New Hires with the agency’s unemployment compensation benefit system. After the first year implementation costs, the annual cost will be $26,000 for computer tapes and processing for the National Directory. First Year Cost 86,000 Second Year Cost 26,000 (c) Identification of revenue and funds currently available from existing revenue source to implement the measure. No current revenue or funds are available to implement the proposed changes to the legislation d) Extent to which current appropriations are available to finance the implementation of the measure during the current fiscal year. There is no fiscal impact on the current appropriation for DOES to finance the implementation of this proposed legislative change e) Identification of the specific source of revenue to be recommended in the forthcoming fiscal years to implements this measure. The $60,000 start-up cost and $26,000 tape and processing cost for the National Directory of New Hires will be reimbursed by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code §47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District o fColumbiaRe 2~ter 7~d -Cha~j~a’n Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTIO amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE O~ REQUEST ABSENF COUNCIL PERIOD FWLLVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL. VOTE Docke! A.OP. ED FIRST READING, APPROVED B12-415 3-3-98 ROLL C/*LL VOTE Resuh t Chmn. Cropp Cha us Allen E~,ans Ambrose Ja ts Brazil Mason Catanta Patterson [ ecre~rv ro ~e (ounc~i I~ ITEM O~ CO~SEXT CALEXDAR I ION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE REC~I)ED VOTE ON ~B h~ent EHIIFI 11t1% RF ORD oun¢llmcmhcr $chwarlz smith, Jr. Thomas. St. t CI [)al~’ I ADOPTED FINAL READING. 4-7-98 APPROVED ALL PRESENT I I ROLl ’,,ILl. VOTE rrsull Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Cha~ou~ E~ans .Jar, l~ Mason Catania rl to the liun¢il I ITL:%I (iN CONSENT (’~[.END.%R i:Rlll-l( Ill(l\ RI(ORI B Councilmember Sch~artz Smith. Jr. Thomas. St. I %CI’10 amp VOICE %OTE REf’ORliED %r()[t N RI’:QI l:~l ABSENT I I ROLL CALl. VOTE Result (’uunolmemDtr Chmn. Cr0pp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates Oft oun¢ilmemhrr Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson B b~cnl Councilmember Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas, St. A~¢ Nay N% All N%’ Present no ollng (’ER rlFl( ATION RE(’ORD Secretary’ Io the onnl:il Dale</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
