<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-253">
  <num type="law">12-253</num>
  <heading type="short">RETIRED POLICE OFFICER REDEPLOYMENT AMENDMENT ACT OF 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1999-04-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-253.pdf">D.C. Law 12-253</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 1274</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0239">
      <narrative>Law 12-253, the ‘Retired Police Officer Redeployment Amendment Act of 1998,‘ was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-239, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 1, 1998 and December 15, 1998, respectively.  Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-601 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.  D.C. Law 12-253 became effective on April 20, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 328 842 (5) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-253 "Retired Police Officer Redeployment Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill 12-239 on first and second readings, December 1, 1998 and December 15, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 29, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act the bill became Act 12-601 and it was published in the February 19, 1999 edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 46, page 1274 The Act was transmitted to Congress on February 10, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired, and the Act is now D.C. Law 12-253, effective April 20, 1999 c/~F ’ LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Da~’s Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 Apr. 12,13,14,15,19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL ANACT D,C, ACT 12-601 IN THECOUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 29, 1998 Cod~c~aon District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the Retired Police Officer Redeployment Amendment Act of 1992, to authorize the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department to rehire a retired member of the Metropolitan Police Department without liability for annuity offset or negative impact on the unfunded liability of the District of Columbia Police Officers and Firefighters Retirement Fund. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Retired Police Officer Redeployment Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The Retired Police Officer Redeployment Amendment Act of 1992, effective September 29, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-163; D.C. Code § 4-618.1 passim is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 4-618.1) is amended by adding a new subsection (g) to read as follows g) The provisions of this section shall apply to any police officer hired after September 29, 1992 b) Section 6(b D.C. Code § 4-618.1 note and § 4-629 note) is repealed. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in Section 4-618.1 Note, Section 4-618.1, 4 -629 ENROLLED ORIGINAL section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §,1~233(c)(1 and pub~cation in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia ~Distn.ct of Columbia APPROVED: December 29, 1998 2 rrE~ ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OFTHE DISTRICI" OF COI UMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIl. VOTE D.kctNo. Bi2~239 ADOPTED F I RST READ ING, 12;0i:98 APPROVED ABSENT I ROLL CALL VOTE Resolt Cnuncitmembtr Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember ALL PRESENT Aye Nay NV AB AB- Absent Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St Chmn. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson iomczJ~.s. Vnt_e tbe Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR 1~ A~ION &amp;amp; DATE I~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST CERTIFICATION RECORD ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12±15L98 APPRO-VED ABSENT ] I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result AI [. RRESENT Councilmcmber Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania ¯ X- Indi~tes Vote e to the Council I ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Aye Nay NV AB Counciimember Aye Nay Chavons Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson A.B-Ahsent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV AB Councihnember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. NV-Preseot not vottnlZ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED OTE ON REQUEST .ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp Alien Ambrose Brazil Catania Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Counciimember .Aye Nay NV AB indicates Vole Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. AB Absent N~,’ Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to Ihe Coun¢i| Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
