<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-224">
  <num type="law">12-224</num>
  <heading type="short">Public School Nurse Assignment Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1999-04-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-224.pdf">D.C. Law 12-224</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 483</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0722">
      <narrative>Law 12-224, the “Public School Nurse Assignment Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-722, which was referred to the Committee on Education, Libraries, and Recreation. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 11, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-542 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-224 became effective on April 13, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMEN (S) ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C. ACT 12’542 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 11, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987 to indicate the level of medical coverage required at District of Columbia Public School varsity and non- varsity interscholastic football games. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public School Nurse Assignment Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 2(e)(1)(A) of the District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987, effective December 10, 1987 (D.C. Law 7-45; D.C. Code § 31-2421(e)(1)(A is amended to read as follows A) For varsity football, a licensed medical doctor and for non-varsity football, a licensed medical doctor or certified athletic trainer Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Section 31-2421 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia ~Register. Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 11, 1998 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORDOF OFF,C~L COUNC,L VOTE B!2-722 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST, READING, 11-10’98 [~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED MASON, SCHWARTZ SMITH AND THOMAS I ] ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Couneilmember Chron. Cropp Ambrose Brazil Aye Nay, NV AB Couneilmember Aye Nay NV AB Counciimember Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. Mason Catania Patterson ¯ x Indicates Vote AB Abseut Secretary to the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE NV Present not Voting ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12,,01’98 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED ALL PRESENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Couacilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Aye Nay NV AB Couuci|membtr Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr 1 X Indicates Vote AB-Absent ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE NV-Preseut not votine I.I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I I ROI’.I’, CALL VOTE Ruolt Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Couo¢ilmember Aye Nay NV AB I Chavous Schwar~ Evan~ Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. Mason Patterson X Indicates Vote AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
