<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-21" flag="true">
  <num type="law">12-21</num>
  <heading type="short">General Public Assistance Program Termination Temporary Amendment Act of 1997</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-21.pdf">D.C. Law 12-21</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 12-21, the “General Public Assistance Program Termination Temporary Amendment Act of 1997,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-169. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 6, 1997, and June 3, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 18, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-98 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-21 became effective on September 23, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ELLMENT(S 5) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-21 "General Public Assistance Program Termination Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-169, on first and second readings, May 6, 1997 and June 3, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 18, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-98, and published in the July 18, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 4028) and transmitted to Congress on July 11, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-21, effective September 23, 1997. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July Aug. Sept. 11,14,15,16,17,21,22,23,24,25,28,29,30,31 1 2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C, ACT 12-98 IN THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 18, 1997 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia General Public Assistance Act of 1982 to terminate the General Public Assistance program. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "General Public Assistance Program Termination Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code § 3-201.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 101(4 D.C. Code § 3-201.1(4 is repealed b) Section 201(3 D.C. Code § 3-202.1(3 is repealed c) A new section 201a is added to read as follows Sec. 201 a. Termination of General Public Assistance Effective May 1, 1997, the General Public Assistance GPA program shall be terminated. No person shall be eligible to receive GPA benefits after May 1, 1997 d) Section 401 (D.C. Code § 3-204.1) is amended by striking the phrase and GPA and inserting the word "and" before the phrase "Aid to the Blind e) Section 502 (D.C. Code § 3-205.2) is amended by striking the phrase "GPA f) Section 508 (D.C. Code § 3.205.8) is repealed g) Section 513 (D.C. Code § 3-205.13) is amended by striking the phrase "except GPA h) Section 514 (D.C. Code § 3-205.14) is repealed i) Section 533(a D.C. Code §3-205.33(a is repealed j) Section 534 (D.C. Code § 3-205.34) is repealed k) Section 536 (D.C. Code § 3-205.36) is amended by striking the phrase "or GPA 1) Section 542(2 D.C. Code § 3-205.42(2 is repealed m) Section 542a (D.C. Code § 3-205.42a) is repealed. Note, Section 3-201.1 Note, Section 3-202.1 Note, Section 3-202.1 Note, Section 3-204.1 Note, Sections 3-205.2, 3-2058, 3-205.13 Note, Sections 3-205.14, 3-205.33, 3-205.34 Note, Section 3-205.36 Note, Sections 3-205.42, 3-205.42a ENROLLED ORIGINAL (n) Section 549(c D.C. Code § 3-205.49(c is amended by striking the phrase "or General Public Assistance o) Section 549(d D.C. Code § 3-205.49(d is amended by striking the phrase "or GPA p) Section 550(c D.C. Code § 3-205.50(c is repealed q) Section 553(b c) and (d D.C. Code § 3-205.53(b c) and (d is repealed r) Section 801(a D.C. Code § 3-208.1(a is amended by striking the phrase "GPA or" and "of GPA or" in the second sentence s) Section 805(d D.C. Code § 3-208.5(d is repealed t) Section 1002(c D.C. Code § 3-210.2(c is amended by striking the phrase GPA u) Section 1019(a D.C. Code § 3-210.19(a is repealed v) Section 1101 (D.C. Code § 3-211.1) is amended by striking the phrase GPA w) Section 1103(a D.C. Code § 3-211.3) is amended by striking the second sentence x) Section 1203(g D.C. Code § 3-212.3(g is amended by striking the second sentence y) Section 1705(a)(1 D.C. Code § 3-217.5(a)(1) is repealed. Sec. 3. Section 3a(3)(G) of the District of Columbia Right to Overnight Shelter Initiative of 1984, effective March 6, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-197; D.C. Code § 3-602(c)(7 is amended by striking the phrase"General Public Assistance Sec. 4. Section 15-712(b) of the District of Columbia Code is amended by striking the phrase "General Public Assistance" and inserting the phrase "General Assistance for Children" in its place. Sec. 5. Section 7 of the Medical and Geriatric Parole Act of 1992, effective May 15, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-271; D.C. Code § 24-266 is amended as follows a) Subsection is amended by striking the phrase "general or b) Subsection (c) is repealed. Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement a) The average GPA caseload for Fiscal Year 1997 is projected to be 1,536 cases. Elimination of the GPA program effective May 1, 1997, would result in projected saving of $1.9 million in FY 97 and $4.5 million annually in District funding. Sec. 7. This act shall apply as of May 1, 1997. Sec. 8 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of Note, Section 3-205.49 Note, Sections 3-205.49, 3-205.50 Note, Section 3-205.53 Note, Section 3-208.1 Note, Section 3-208.5 Note, Section 3-210.2 Note, Sections 3-210.19, 3-211.1, 3-211.3, 3-212.3, 3-212.3 Note, Section 3-217.5 Note, Section 3-602 Note, Section 15-712 Note, Section 24-266 ENROLLED ORIGINAL veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: June 18, 1997 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12-169 Docket No. AD, OPTED FIRST READING, 05-06-97 vo,c,~VOTE APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENrl" THOMAS I ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result I Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Cropp Evans Allen Jarvis Am brose Mason Brazil Patterson Chavous Schwartz V Secretary to the Council I~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE AB -Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV Present not Voting l~at¢ ADOPTED FINAL READING, 06-03-97 [~ VOICE VOTERECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED ALL PRESENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous X-indie~ no ¯ [ ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [ ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Counciimember Aye Nay NV AB Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. Mason Patterson Schwartz An-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV-Present not voting [ ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmembcr Chron. Cropp Evans Allen Jarvis Am brose Mason Brazil Patterson Chavous Schwartz x Indicates Vote Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. AB Absent NV Pre~ent not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
