<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-257">
  <num type="law">12-257</num>
  <heading type="short">Criminal Records Check for the Protection of Children Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1999-04-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-257.pdf">D.C. Law 12-257</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 1309</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0694">
      <narrative>Law 12-257, the “Criminal Records Check for the Protection of Children Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-694, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 1, 1998, and December 15, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-608 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-257 became effective on April 20, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ~’ 062 322 495 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-257 "Criminal Records Check for the Protection of Children Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill 12-694 on first and second readings, December 1, 1998 and December 15, 1998, respectively. Following the signature oft he Mayor on December 29, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act the bill became Act 12-608 and it was published in the February 19, 1999 edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 46, page 1309 The Act was transmitted to Congress on February 10, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired, and the Act is now D.C. Law 12-257, effective April 20, 1999. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Days Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. Mar. 10,11,12,22,23,24,25 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 12,13,14,15,19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-608 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 29, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code to require criminal records checks for individuals seeking to become adoptive parents of children and for individuals residing in foster family homes or other homes in which children are placed by court order, require that fees be paid for criminal records checks, and to provide penalties for individuals who disclose confidential information under the act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Criminal Records Check for the Protection of Children Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by adding a new Chapter 50 to read as follows Chapter 50. Criminal Records Check Sec 16-5001. Definitions 16-5002. Criminal records check required for certain individuals 16-5003. Request for criminal records check 16-5004. Payment of fees 16-5005. Confidentiality of information to be maintained 16-5006. Effect of failure to request criminal records check 16-5007. Penalties for violations of act 16-5008. Rules § 16-5001. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Adult" means an individual who has attained 18 years of age 2 Director" means the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Human Services, or his designee 3 Division" means the Family Division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia 4 Foster family home" means a home described in Title XVII of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code New Chapter 50, Title 16 New Section 16-5001 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Code § 3-217.1 et seq or any other foster family home in the District of Columbia established by law 5 Licensed child-placing agency" means an individual or entity defined as such in section 2 of An Act To regulate the placing of children in family homes, and for other purposes, approved April 22, 1944 (58 Star. 193; D.C. Code § 32-1002 3 16-5002. Criminal records check required for certain individuals a) The following individuals shall apply for a criminal records check in accordance with § 16-5003 1) An individual who seeks to become an adoptive parent of a child under Chapter 3 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code 2) An adult, other than a parent of the child, but including a relative of the child, who resides in the home of an individual described in paragraph (1) of this section 3) Upon order of a judicial officer, an individual with whom a child is placed under § 16-2320(a)(2) or (a)(3)(C 4) Upon order of a judicial officer, an adult who resides in the home of an individual with whom a child is placed under § 16-2320(a)(2) or (a)(3)(C including a parent or other relative of the child; and 5) An adult who resides in a foster family home in which a child is placed, including a relative of the child, and, upon order of a judicial officer, a parent of the child b) A criminal records check under this act must be conducted in accordance with section 471(a)(20) of the Social Security Act, approved June 17, 1980 (94 Stat. 501; 42 U.S.C. § 671(a)(20 § 16-5003. Request for criminal records check a) Within the time stated in subsection (b) of this section, an individual described in § 16-5002 shall submit to the Metropolitan Police Department MPD for transmittal to the Federal Bureau of Investigation FBI a complete set of legible fingerprints on a fingerprint card in a form approved by the FBI. The MPD shall request the FBI to conduct a criminal records check of the individual and shall request that the FBI forward the results to the Director. After receiving the results of the criminal record check, the Director shall forward them to the Division at the request of the Division b) The time in which the request must be made to the FBI pursuant to subsection (a) of this section is as follows 1) For an individual described in § 16-5002(a)(1 A) Before the individual files a petition for adoption pursuant to § 16- 305; and B) If the child has been found to be neglected under Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code, or has been relinquished to a licensed child-placing agency, before the child is placed in the individual’s home 2) For an individual described in § 16-5002(a)(2 New Section 16-5002 New Section 16-5003 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL A) Before the individual described in § 16-5002(a)(1) files a petition for adoption; and B) Before the child is placed in the individual’s home 3) For any individual who becomes a resident of the home of the individual described in § 16-5002(a)(1) after the filing of the petition for adoption, within 10 calendar days after the individual becomes a resident of the home 4) For an individual described in § 16-5002(a)(3) or (4) who is a foster parent, before the child is placed in the individual’s home, and, for any other individual described in § 16-5002(a)(3) or (4 within 2 business days of entry of the judicial order placing the child in the home 5) For an individual described in § 16-5002(a)(5 before the placement of a child in the foster family home, unless, within 1 year of the placement of the child in the home, the Director has received the results of a criminal records check and considers the results satisfactory 6) For any individual described in § 16-5002(a)(5) who was not a resident of the foster family home when the child was placed in the home, within 10 days after the individual becomes a resident of the home 7) For an individual described in § 16-5002(a)(4) or (5) who was not a resident of the foster family home when the child was placed in the home, within 10 calendar days after the individual becomes a resident of that home; and 8) For an individual described in § 16-5002, who was not subject to this act solely because the individual was a minor, but who becomes an adult while the child is residing in the same home, within 90 calendar days after the individual becomes an adult § 16-5004. Payment of fees a) Except as otherwise provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Director shall pay the fees charged by the FBI and the MPD for processing a request for a criminal records check from funds made available to the District of Columbia under Title IV, Part E of the Social Security Act, approved June 17, 1980 (94 Stat. 501; 42 U.S.C. § 670 etseq to the extent permitted by that Act, or, otherwise, from other available funds b) The Division shall pay the fees described in subsection (a) of this section for an individual described in § 16-5002(a)(3) or (4 in a case in which a child is found to be neglected for physical or sexual abuse, from funds made available to the District of Columbia under Title IV, Part E of the Social Security Act, approved June 17, 1980 (94 Stat. 501; 42 U.S.C. § 670 et seq to the extent permitted by that Act, or, otherwise, from other available funds c) The following individuals shall pay the fees described in subsection (a) of this section 1) An individual described in § 16-5002(a)(1) who is seeking to become an adoptive parent of a child, other than a child found to be neglected under Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code or a child with respect to whom parental rights have been New Section 16-5004 ENROLLED ORIGINAL relinquished to the District of Columbia under section 6 of An Act To regulate the placing of children in family homes, and for other purposes, approved April 22, 1944 (58 Star. 194; D.C. Code 8 32-1007 and 2) An adult who resides in the home of an individual described in paragraph (1) of this subsection 8 16-5005. Confidentiality of information to be maintained a) No employee of the Department of Human Services or other agency of the District of Columbia shall disclose information obtained as a result of a request submitted pursuant to 8 16-5003(a) to any unauthorized individual or entity b) This act does not authorize the disclosure of information concerning an individual who was not an adult, or prosecuted as an adult, at the time to which the information pertains if the disclosure of such information is prohibited by other law 8 16-5006. Effect of failure to request criminal records check a) If an individual described in 8 16-5002(a)(1) fails to request a criminal records check as required by this act, the Division may deny or dismiss the petition for adoption b) If an individual described in § 16-5002(a)(2) fails to request a criminal records check as required by this act, the Division may dismiss the petition for adoption c) If an individual described in 8 16-5002(a)(3) fails to request a criminal records check as required by this act, the Division may refuse to place the child in the individual’s home, remove the child from the home, or take other appropriate action to ensure the health, welfare, or safety of the child d) If an individual described in § 16-5002(a)(4) fails to request a criminal records check as required by this act, the Division may remove the child from the home or take any other appropriate action to ensure the health, welfare, or safety of the child e) If an individual described in 8 16-5002(a)(5) fails to request a criminal records check as required by this act, the Division may remove the child from the foster family home or take any other appropriate action to ensure the health, welfare, and safety of the child f) If an individual described in 8 16-5002(b)(6) fails to request a criminal records check as required by this act, the Division may take the applicable action described in subsection (b d or (e) of this section 8 16-5007. Penalties for violations of act a) An individual who discloses confidential information in violation of section 6 is guilty of a criminal offense and, upon conviction, is subject to a fine not to exceed $1,000 or a term of incarceration of not more than 180 days, or both b) Prosecutions for violation of this act shall be brought in the name of the District of Columbia upon information by the Corporation Counsel 8 16-5008. Rules The Mayor shall promulgate rules to carry out the purposes of this act New Section 16-5005 New Section 16-5006 New Section 16-5007 New Section 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia ~District of Columbia APPROVED: December 29, 1998 I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR IX ~ctton &amp;amp; DAtE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD T~’ELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B 12 6 9 4 Docket No. ADOPTED. F IRST..READING, i2.L.OiL98 VOICE VOTE APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ALL .PRESENT I ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Couueilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Counciimember Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Brazil Mason Catania Patterson i~ Indicates Ve.te¯ I AB-A.u, N P,e.otuot,ot.~j X- CERTIFICATION RECORD¯ i t~m on consent cak~n~ar o ADOPTED. FINAL .READING 12;!5:18 iX VOICE VOTERECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVF_D THOMAS. ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania I Ave I Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson X Indicates Vote the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR AB-Absen! f Aye Nay NV AB NV.Preseat not votiol Dale I I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE vOICE X’OTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I ] RoLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. AB Absent NV Present not ~rotillg CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification Distn’ct of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code to require criminal records checks for individuals seeking to become adoptive parents of children and for individuals residing in foster family homes or other homes in which children are placed by court order, require that fees be paid for criminal records checks, and to provide penalties for individuals who disclose confidential information under the act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Criminal Records Check for the Protection of Children Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by adding a new Chapter 50 to read as follows Chapter 50. Criminal Records Check Sec 16-5001. Definitions 16-5002. Criminal records check required for certain individuals 16-5003. Request for criminal records check 16-5004. Payment of fees 16-5005. Confidentiality of information to be maintained 16-5006. Effect of failure to request criminal records check 16-5007. Penalties for violations of act 16-5008. Rules § 16-5001. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Adult" means an individual who has attained 18 years of age 2 Director" means the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Human Services, or his designee 3 Division" means the Family Division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia 4 Foster family home" means a home described in Title XVII of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code New Chapter 50, Tire 16 New Sea~n 16-5001 ENROLLED ORIGINAL § 3-217.1 et seq or any other foster family home in the District of Columbia established by law 5 Licensed child-placing agency" means an individual or entity defined as such in section 2 of An Act To regulate the placing of children in family homes, and for other purposes, approved April 22, 1944 (58 Star. 193; D.C. Code § 32-1002 § 16-5002. Criminal records check required for certain individuals a) The following individuals shall apply for a criminal records check in accordance with section 4 1) An individual who seeks to become an adoptive parent of a child under Chapter 3 of Tkle 16 of the District of Columbia Code 2) An adult, other than a parent of the child, but including a relative of the child, who resides in the home of an individual described in paragraph (1) of this section 3) Upon order of a judicial officer, an individual with whom a child is placed under section 16-2320(a)(2) or (a)(3)(C) of the District of Columbia Code 4) Upon order of a judicial officer, an aduk who resides in the home of an individual with whom a child is placed under section 16-2320(a)(2) or (a)(3)(C) of the District of Columbia Code, including a parent or other relative of the child; and 5) An aduk who resides in a foster family home in which a child is placed, including a relative of the child, and, upon order of a judicial officer, a parent of the child b) A criminal records check under this act must be conducted in accordance with section 471(a)(20) of the Social Security Act, approved June 17, 1980 (94 Stat. 501; 42 U.S.C. § 671(a)(20 § 16-5003. Request for criminal records check a) Within the time stated in subsection (b) of this section, an individual described in section 3 shall submit to the Metropolitan Police Department MPD for transmittal to the Federal Bureau of Investigation FBI a complete set of legible fingerprints on a fingerprint card in a form approved by the FBI. The MPD shall request the FBI to conduct a criminal records check of the individual and shall request that the FBI forward the results to the Director. After receiving the results of the investigation, the Director shall forward them to the Division at the request of the Division b) The time in which the request must be made to the FBI pursuant to subsection (a) of this section is as follows 1) For an individual described in section 3(a)(1 A) Before the individual files a petition for adoption pursuant to section 16-305 of the District of Columbia Code; and B) If the child has been found to be neglected under Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code, or has been relinquished to a licensed child-placing agency, before the child is placed in the individual’s home 2) For an individual described in section 3(a)(2 New Section 16-5002 New Section 16-5003 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL A) Before the individual described in section 3(a)(1) files a petition for adoption; and B) Before the child is placed in the individual’s home 3) For any individual who becomes a resident of the home of the individual described in section 3(a)(1) after the filing of the petition for adoption, within 10 calendar days after the individual becomes a resident of the home 4) For an individual described in section 3(a)(3) or (4) who is a foster parent, before the child is placed in the individual’s home, and, for any other individual described in section 3(a)(3) or (4 within 2 business days of entry of the judicial order placing the child in the home 5) For an individual described in section 3(a)(5 before the placement of a child in the foster family home, unless, within 1 year of the placement of the child in the home, the Director has received the resuks of a criminal records check and considers the results satisfactory 6) For any individual described in section 3(a)(5) who was not a resident of the foster family home when the child was placed in the home, within 10 days after the individual becomes a resident of the home 7) For an individual described in section 3(a)(4) or (5) who was not a resident of the foster family home when the child was placed in the home, within 10 calendar days after the individual becomes a resident of that home; and 8) For an individual described in section 3, who was not subject to this act solely because the individual was a minor, but who becomes an adult while the child is residing in the same home, within 90 calendar days after the individual becomesan adult § 16-5004. Payment of fees a) Except as otherwise provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Director shall pay the fees charged by the FBI and the MPD for processing a request for a criminal records check from funds made available to the District of Columbia under Tire IV, Part E of the Social Security Act, approved June 17, 1980 (94 Star. 501; 42 U.S.C. § 670 etseq to the extent permitted by that Act, or, otherw, ise, from other available funds b) The Division shall pay the fees described in subsection (a) of this section for an individual described in section 3(a)(3) or (a)(4 in a case in which a child is found to be neglected for physical or sexual abuse, from funds made available to the District of Columbia under Title IV, Part E of the Social Security Act, approved June 17, 1980 (94 Star. 501; 42 U.S.C. § 670 et seq to the extent permitted by that Act, or, otherwise, from other available c) The following individuals shall pay the fees described in subsection (a) of this section 1) An individual described in section 3(a)(1) who is seeking to become an adoptive parent of a child, other than a child found to be neglected under Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code or a child with respect to whom parental rights have been New Section 16-5004 ENROLLED ORIGINAL relinquished to the District of Columbia under section 6 of An Act To regulate the placing of children in family homes, and for other purposes, approved April 22, 1944 (58 Star. 194; D.C. Code § 32-1007 and 2) An adult who resides in the home of an individual described in paragraph (1) of this subsection § 16-5005. Confidentiality of information to be maintained a) No employee of the Department of Human Services or other agency of the District of Columbia shall disclose information obtained as a result of a request submitted pursuant to section 4(a) to any unauthorized individual or entity b) This act does not authorize the disclosure of information concerning an individual who was not an adult, or prosecuted as an adult, at the time to which the information pertains if the disclosure of such information is prohibited by other law § 16-5006. Effect of failure to request criminal records check a) If an individual described in section 3(a)(1) fails to request an investigation as required by this act, the Division may deny or dismiss the petition for adoption b) If an individual described in section 3(a)(2) fails to request an investigation as required by this act, the Division may dismiss the petition for adoption c) If an individual described in section 3(a)(3) fails to request an investigation as required by this act, the Division may refuse to place the child in the individual’s home, remove the child from the home, or take other appropriate action to ensure the health, welfare, or safety of the child d) If an individual described in section 3(a)(4) fails to request an investigation as required by this act, the Division may remove the child from the home or take any other appropriate action to ensure the health, welfare, or safety of the child e) If an individual described in section 3(a)(5) fails to request an investigation as required by this act, the Division may remove the child from the foster family home or take any other appropriate action to ensure the health, welfare, and safety of the child f) If an individual described in section 4(b)(6) fails to request an investigation as required by this act, the Division may take the applicable action described in subsection (b d or (e) of this section § 16-5007. Penalties for violations of act a) An individual who discloses confidential information in violation of section 6 is guilty of a criminal offense and, upon conviction, is subject to a free not to exceed $1,000 or a term of incarceration of not more than 180 days, or both b) Prosecutions for violation of this act shall be brought in the name of the District of Columbia upon information by the Corporation Counsel § 16-5008. Rules The Mayor shall promulgate rules to carry out the purposes of this act New Section 16-5005 New Section 16-5006 New Section 16-5007 New Se~n 16-5008 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia 5 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD "U~’ELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12-694 ADOPTED. FIRST .READING, 12~0iL98 VOICE VOTE APPROVED RECORDEDVOTEON REQUEST ABSENT ALL .PRESENT ] } ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Couneilmembcr Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania I~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I’~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Aye Nay NV AB Counciimember Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson X Iodicatcs Vote AB Absent e(a~to the Council Aye Nay NV AB Councilmcmber Aye Nu3 NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas. St. NV Present nol Voling ADOPTED. FINAL .READING, i2~i5L98 [~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED ¯ THOMAS. ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chron. Cropp Allen .L Ave [ Na~ NV AB Councdlmember Ave Na~ NV AB Councilmember A’,e Nay NV All Chavous Schwartz Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates ~’otr ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB-AbscO! CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV-Present not voting DIIe I I CTION &amp;amp; DATE vOICE VOTE RECORDED ’,’OTE ON REQUEST ABSENT } ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmcmt~er Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil X Indicates Vote Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay I NV ABAve Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. Mason Patterson AB Absent NV Presel~t nol ~voling CERTIFICATION RECORD Sccrelltry tO the Counci Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
