<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-226">
  <num type="law">12-226</num>
  <heading type="short">Mental Health Services Client Enterprise Establishment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1999-04-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-226.pdf">D.C. Law 12-226</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 500</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0593">
      <narrative>Law 12-226, the “Mental Health Services Client Enterprise Establishment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-593, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 11, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-547 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-226 became effective on April 13, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-226 "Mental Health Services Client Enterprise Establishment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-593, on first and second readings, November 10, 1998 and December 1, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 11, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-547 and published in the January 22, 1999, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 46 page 500) and transmitted to Congress on February 3, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-226, effective April 13, 1999 j. S LINDA W CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 3,4,8,9,10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 Apr. 12 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C. ACT 12’547 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 11, 1998 Codifiea~on District of Columb~ Code 1999 Supp. To authorize the Mayor to establish client enterprise projects to enable clients of the Commission on Mental Health Services to acquire community work skills by authorizing them to cam profits from their participation in the program. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Mental Health Services Client Enterprise Establishment Act of 1998 Sec. 2 a) The Mayor is authorized to establish an enterprise program at St. Elizabeths Hospital to promote the rehabilitation and employment of clients of the Commission on Mental Health Services with the intended purpose of assisting clients of the Commission on Mental Health Services to acquire community work skills in preparation for independent living b) Purchases and sales of merchandise which may be made by clients and the payment of any wages to clients or any other expenses of the program may be paid from funds derived from the day to day operation of the enterprise program but shall not be subject to the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1181.1 etseq c) The Mayor, or during a control year as defined in section 305 of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 152; D.C. Code § 47-393 the Mayor or the Chief Financial Officer, is authorized to establish a revolving fund to be used for the collection and disbursement of funds for any enterprise program established pursuant to this act and shall supervise all collections and disbursements from the fund for the purposes set forth in this act d) Any business operations conducted pursuant to this act shall be subject to the oversight of the District of Columbia Auditor pursuant to section 455 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 803; D.C. Code § 47-117 Sec. 3. The Mayor may issue rules to implement the provisions of this act in accordance with Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, Subehapter III, Chapter 6, Title 32 New Section 32-631 New Section 32-632 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code § 1-1501 etseq Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 5. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 11, 1998 2 I I ITeM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I~ ALI’ION &amp;amp; DATE [~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12-593 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11’10’98 APPROVED AMBROSE, MASON ANDTHOMAS I I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen A ro brose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmcmber Aye Na NV AB Chavous Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thoroas, Sr. X o Indic,~tes Vote AB Absent NV Present not Voting ff Secreturyto the Council t. ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ALL PRESENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councdmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye ] Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chmn. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr X Indicates Vote AB-Absent NV-Present not Secretary. to the Council CERTIFICATION RECORD ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I I VOJCE OTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I I ROI~L CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB CouncilmemDer Aye Nay ~r AB Cuuncilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Cropp Chavous Schwartz Allen Evans Smith, Jr. Ambrose Jarvis Thoroas, St. Brazil Mason Catania Patterson X Indicates Volt AB Absent NV Present not Votilie, CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary. to the Council Dale</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§44-921"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§44-922"/>
  </section>
</document>
