<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-233">
  <num type="law">12-233</num>
  <heading type="short">Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1999-04-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-233.pdf">D.C. Law 12-233</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 564</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0380">
      <narrative>Law 12-233, the “Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-380, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 16, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-553 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-233 became effective on April 20, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag e 062 324 330 (5 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-233 "Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill 12-380 on first and second readings, November 10, 1998 and December 1, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 16, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act the bill became Act 12-553 and it was published in the January 22, 1999 edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 46, page 564 The Act was transmitted to Congress on February 10, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired, and the Act is now D.C. Law 12-233, effective April 20,1999 f J LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Days Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: 10,11,12,22,23,24,25 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 12,13,14,15,19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C. ACT 12’553 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 16, 1998 To amend the Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Act of 1993 to require that the Foundation for the National Capital Region temporarily serve as the fiduciary agent of the Trust Fund, to allow the Trust Fund to hold and distribute funds for other organizations, eliminate the requirement of retained assets, eliminate the requirement that the Director of the Mayor’s Youth Initiative Office serve as a member of the Board, and permit the expansion of the Board membership and length of service. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Act of 1993, effective November 20, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-56; D.C. Code § 6-2131 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 6-2132) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (d) is repealed 2) A new subsection(d-1) is added to read as follows d-l) The Trust Fund may hold and distribute funds for other organizations. Auditing procedures shall be established by the Board 3) Subsection (f) is repealed b) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 6-2133) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended as follows A) Strike the third sentence and insert the sentence "The D.C. Treasurer and the Director of the Department of Human Services shall serve as members of the Board of Directors in its place B) Add a new sentence at the end to read as follows Through its by- laws, the Board of Directors may expand the number of members of the Board to include a business representative 2) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL b) The D.C. Treasurer and the Director of the Department of Human Services shall serve terms as members of the Board of Directors for the same duration as the terms of their office 3) Subsection (f) is amended by striking the last sentence. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement Enactment of the Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Amendment Act of 1998 will have no negative fiscal impact. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: December 16, 1998 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR VOICE VOTE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12--380 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11’10’98 APPROV.ED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOT£ -Resnit Conncilmemher Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania the Council I ITEM ON CONSENT CALEND^r I~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT AMB.ROSE AND MASON Aye Nay NV AR Councilmember Aye Nay I NV AB Councilmember Aye Na NV AB= Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORU NV Present not %oting Dale ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-01’98 PPRDVED ALL PRESENT I I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Cuuacilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania I Patterson X Indicates Vote tn t~ Cnu~il I I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Aye [ Nay NV AB Counciimembee Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. AB-Absent ’CERTIFICATION RECORD N~,’-Pfescnt not volin~ f I | Dire ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I I ROi~L CALL VOTE Result CouncilmemDer Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB CounciJmember Aye Nly ~’ AB Councilmemtwr Aye Ntv NV AB X Indicates Vote Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB Absent Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Act of 1993 to require that the Foundation for the National Capital Region temporarily serve as the fiduciary agent of the Trust Fund, to allow the Trust Fund to hold and distribute funds for other organizations, eliminate the requirement of retained assets, eliminate the requirement that the Director of the Mayor’s Youth Initiative Office serve as a member of the Board, and permit the expansion of the Board membership and length of service. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Act of 1993, effective November 20, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-56; D.C. Code § 6-2131 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 6-2132) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (d) is repealed 2) A new subsection(d-1) is added to read as follows d-l) The Trust Fund may hold and distribute funds for other organizations. Auditing procedures shall be established by the Board 3) Subsection (f) is repealed b) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 6-2133) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended as follows A) Strike the third sentence and insert the sentence "The D.C. Treasurer and the Director of the Department of Human Services shall serve as members of the Board of Directors in its place B) Add a new sentence at the end to read as follows Through its by- laws, the Board of Directors may expand the number of members of the Board to include a business representative 2) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL b) The D.C. Treasurer and the Director of the Department of Human Services shall serve terms as members of the Board of Directors for the same duration as the terms of their office 3) Subsection (f) is amended by striking the last sentence. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement Enactment of the Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Amendment Act of 1998 will have no negative fiscal impact. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia 2 I I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE .ECORD OF OF.CIAt CO~’.C ’OTE B12’380 Docket No. ADOPTED F I RST READ I NG, 11’10’98 APPROVED ] ROLL CALL VOTE Resul! Councillembcr Chron. Cropp Alien Ambrose Brazil AMBROSE AND MASON Aye Nay NV AB Couocilmember Ave Nay NV AB Councilmeatber Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. Mason Ca~a~ Patterson ’~ X dicatcs Vote ~thc Council AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV Present not Votmg Date ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12L01~98 APPRDVED I~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I~g] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REOUEST ABSENT ALL PRESENT [ I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Cnuucnimembcr Aye Nay NV AB Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Councilmember Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson X Indicates Vote ’ to the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I IAye [ Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Dale I I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I I ROlL CALL VOTE Councilmembcr Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmembcr Aye Nay NV AB Councilmembcr Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. AB Absenl NV Present not ~oting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Dste ENROLLED ORIGINAL e) The assessment for each cartier and self-insurer for the preceding fiscal year shall be redetermined, subsequent to each fiscal year, based upon the actual total amount of compensation and medical payments paid and the administrative costs incurred that year. Adjustments for differences between the beginning year assessment and the year end actual determination, if any, shall be made to the next ensuing assessment f) The Mayor shall assess each carrier and self-insurer for its pro rata share of the total amount of costs to administer this act in the fiscal year pursuant to this section, and shall give written notice by certified or registered mail to each carrier or self-insurer of the assessment against it g)(1) Assessments shall be paid within the time prescribed by the Mayor 2) For a period not to exceed 12 months following the effective date of the Workers’ Compensation Amendment Act of 1998, the Mayor may permit payment of the assessment of each cartier or self-insured in quarterly installment payments h) If a deficit is projected to occur in the administration of the fund created pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, prior to the end of the fiscal year, the Mayor is authorized to implement an emergency assessment in an amount deemed necessary to avoid the deficit. Self- insurers and carriers, on behalf of their policyholders, shall remit the emergency assessment within 30 calendar days of receipt of the assessment i) The Mayor is authorized to promulgate rules deemed necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including provisions for making and preserving appropriate records, paying of assessments, inspecting these records, and the submission by carriers and self-insurers of reports prescribed by the Mayor j) If a carder or self-insurer fails to pay the assessment referred to in subsection (f) or (h) of this section, or to make and preserve records in the form and manner required by the Mayor, to file a report in the form and manner required by the Mayor, or to allow the Mayor to inspect records required by rules issued pursuant to this section, the Mayor may suspend or revoke the authorization of a carrier to insure for workers’ compensation or a self-insurer to act as a self-insurer pursuant to this act 1) Section 44 (D.C. Code § 36-343) is amended as follows 1) The existing text is designated as subsection (a 2) New subsections (b c and (d) are added to read as follows Co) The Mayor shall study and report to the Council on a proposal to reclassify Office of Workers’ Compensation Hearing Examiners as Administrative Law Judges ALJs and to raise their level of compensation c) The Mayor shall develop performance measures and qualifications for the ALJs for the Office of Workers’ Compensation and recommend compensation levels within 90 days after the effective date of the Workers’ Compensation Amendment Act of 1998. See~on 36-343</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
