<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-231">
  <num type="law">12-231</num>
  <heading type="short">Adult Education Designation Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1999-04-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-231.pdf">D.C. Law 12-231</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 487</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0775">
      <narrative>Law 12-231, the “Adult Education Designation Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-775, which was referred to the Committee on Education, Libraries, and Recreation. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 11, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-544 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-231 became effective on April 20, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EL N (S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-231 "Adult Education Designation Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill 12-775, on first and second readings, November 10, 1998 and December 1, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 11, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act the bill became Act 12-544 and it was published in the January 22, 1999 edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 46, page 487 The Act was transmitted to Congress on February 10, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired, and the Act is now D.C. Law 12-231, effective April 20, 1999. LINDA W CROPP Chairman of the Council Days Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 Apr. 12,13,14,15,19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C, ACT 12-544 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER !I, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act to designate the University of the District of Columbia as the agency responsible for supervision of the adult education program in public schools; to transfer all duties, functions, powers, and funding relating to adult education to the Board of Trustees, to allow UDC to charge fees and waive any fees for District residents, and to authorize the Board of Trustees to set educational and health policies for the adult education program. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Adult Education Designation Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act, approved October 26, 1974 (88 Star. 1423; D.C. Code § 31-1501 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 206 (D.C. Code § 31-1516) is amended by adding new paragraphs (17) and (18) to read as follows 17) Establish or approve policies and procedures governing admissions, curricula, educational and vocational programs, and graduation for the adult education program, and operate an adult education program which shall provide services and instruction for adults who A) Lack sufficient mastery of basic educational skills to enable them to function effectively in society B) Do not have a certificate of graduation from a school providing secondary education and who have not achieved an equivalent level of education; or C) Have limited ability in speaking, reading, writing, or understanding the English language and whose native language is a language other than English 18) Establish health policies and procedures for adult students as provided in the Student Health Care Act of 1985, effective December 3, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-66; D.C. Code § 31-2401 et seq Section 31-1516 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) A new section 212 to is added read as follows Sec. 212. Supervision of the adult education program a) Notwithstanding any other provision of District law, the University of the District of Columbia shall be the state agency responsible for supervision of adult education in public schools. All functions, powers, duties, and funding of the Board of Education and the District of Columbia Public Schools regarding adult education shall be vested in the Trustees. All rules, orders, obligations, determinations, and understandings of the Board of Education or the District of Columbia Public Schools relating to adult education shall remain in effect until lawfially amended, repealed, or modified by the Trustees b) The University with the approval of the Trustees, shall submit to the Mayor, the Council, and the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority, the Consensus Commission, and the appropriate congressional committees, a long-term reform plan, as provided in section 2101 of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Code § 31-2853.1 The plan shall include a description of how the University will accomplish the implementation of a comprehensive and an effective adult education and literacy program c) The University shall apply for federal funds as provided in the Adult Education Act, approved April 28, 1988 (102 Star. 302, 20 U.S.C. § 1201 d)(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the University is authorized to charge fees for all adult education courses. The amount to be charged to each adult shall be fixed annually by the University as the amount necessary to cover the expense of instruction, cost of textbooks and school supplies, and other operating costs associated with each course offered, provided that the amount and changes in the amount fixed by this subsection are set by the University in accordance with section 6 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (88 Stat. 1206; D.C. Code § 1-1506 Following the final adoption of such amount, the University shall transmit a copy to the Mayor and the Council 2) All amounts received by the University pursuant to this section shall be paid to the D.C. Treasurer and accounted for in the General Fund as a separate revenue source allocable to provide authority for the offering of select adult education courses for which fees will be charged 3) Waivers, in whole or in part, of fees for select adult education courses may be granted by the University only to District residents New Seelion 31-1520.1 Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register t of Columbia APPROVED: December ii, 1998 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12-775 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST, READING, II-10-98 ]~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED MASON, SCHWARTZ SMITH AND THOMAS ROLL CALL VOTE -Reautt Coulgilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Coon¢ilmember Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson Aye Nny NV AB X indicates Vote AB ADsem NV Present not Voting ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR A~ION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED ALL PRESENT [ I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Aye Nay NV ABCouncilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania x Indicates Vote Councilmcmber Aye Nay NV I AB Conncilmembcr Aye Nay NV AB Chavoas Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis ¯ Thomas, St. Mason Patterson AB-Air~ent NV*Present not votinl~ CERTIFICATION~RECORD Date I ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I l OICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I I ROi~L CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania x. Indicates Vote Couucilmember Aye Nay NV AR Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB Absent Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Nv Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
