<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-252">
  <num type="law">12-252</num>
  <heading type="short">Hazardous Duty Compensation for Metropolitan Police Department Scuba Divers Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1999-04-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-252.pdf">D.C. Law 12-252</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 1127</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0142">
      <narrative>Law 12-252, the “Hazardous Duty Compensation for Metropolitan Police Department Scuba Divers Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-142, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 1, 1998 and December 15, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-593 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-252 became effective on April 20, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 324 905 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-252 "Hazardous Duty Compensation for Metropolitan Police Department Scuba Divers Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill 12-142 on first and second readings, December l, 1998 and December 15, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 29, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act the bill became Act 12-593 and it was published in the February 12, 1999 edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 46, page 1127 The Act was transmitted to Congress on February 10, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired, and the Act is now D.C. Law 12-252, effective April 20, 1999 f/{4 J LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Days Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 Apr. 12,13,14,15,19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C. ACT 12-593 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER29,1998 Cod~fwation District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Police and Firemen’s Salary Act of 1958 to authorize hazardous duty compensation for Metropolitan Police Department scuba divers. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Hazardous Duty Compensation for Metropolitan Police Department Scuba Divers Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 202 of the District of Columbia Police and Fireman’s Salary Act of 1958, approved August 1, 1958 (72 Stat. 483; D.C. Code § 4-408 is amended as follows a) The section heading is amended to read as follows Sec. 202. Additional compensation for helicopter pilot, bomb disposal, or scuba diving duty b) A new sentence is added after the first sentence to read as follows Further, each officer or member of the metropolitan police force assigned on or after August 29, 1972 to the Harbor Patrol division within the Metropolitan Police Department as scuba divers shall receive in addition to his or her scheduled rate of basic compensation 2,710.00 per annum so long as he or she remains in such assignment Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect upon its approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) oft he Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in Section 4-408 ENROLLED ORIGINAL section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: December 29, 1998 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR +ORION DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Doc.tNo. B12,142 ADOPTED. FIRST ,READING, 12;.01:98 VOICE VOTE APPROVED .ECORDED VOTE ON.EQ.EST ALL,PRESENT ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmembee Aye Nay NV AB Councitmembcr Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Thomas, St.Jarvis Mason Patterson X -Indicates Vote AB Abscnt CI~RTIFICATION RECORD~ lhe Council ACTION &amp;amp; DATE _L Aye Nay NV AB NV Present not Voting ADOPTED. FINAL .READING i2Li5L98 VO,CEVOTE APPR£1VF.B ’ RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT THOMAS I I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Aye I Nay NV AB Councilmember Chron. Cropp ] Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson AB-Absent’ ’ CERTIFICATION RECORD e~cretary tO the COuocd J ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Aye Nay NV AB Counciimember Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St L Aye Nay NV AB NV-Present not voting Date I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE vOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT. I I RoLL CALL VOTE esntt Coua¢ilmembec Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmembcr Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. AB Absent NV Present not ~roting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
