<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-22">
  <num type="law">12-22</num>
  <heading type="short">Washington Convention Center Authority Collective Bargaining Amendment Act of 1997</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1997-09-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-22.pdf">D.C. Law 12-22</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 4168</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0173">
      <narrative>Law 12-22, the “Washington Convention Center Authority Collective Bargaining Amendment Act of 1997,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-173. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 6, 1997, and June 3, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 18, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-99 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-22 became effective on September 23, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN L EN (S 5) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-22 "Washington Convention Center Authority Collective Bargaining Amendment Act of 1997 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-173, on first and second readings, May 6, 1997 and June 3, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 18, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-99, and published in the July 25, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 4168) and transmitted to Congress on July 11, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-22, effective September 23, 1997. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July Aug. Sept. 11,14,15,16,17,21,22,23,24,25,28,29,30,31 1 2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-99 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 18, 1997 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994 to provide for coverage of the Washington Convention Center employees by the Public Employee Relations Board and by the labor-management relations title of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Washington Convention Center Authority Collective Bargaining Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. Section 216 of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective September 28, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-188; D.C. Code § 9-817 is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase except that titles V and XVII of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 22-139; D.C. Code §§ 1-605.1 etseq, and 1-618.1 etseq shall apply in its place. Sec.3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Section 9-817 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §~blication in the District of Columbia Register. Acing Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: June 18, 1997 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Docket No. B12-173 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 05-06-97 l~ VOICEVOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVFn ALL PRESENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Cooncilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chmn. Cropp Evans Smith, Jr. Allen Jarvis Ambrose Mason Brazil Patterson Thomas, Sr. Chavous ’’’ ~/rcta~y to the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST Schwartz AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ABSENT ADOPTED FINAL READING, 06-03-97 APPROVED ALL PRESENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Coencilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous X-indicltes no I I I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye i Nay NV AB Conn©ilmember Aye Nay NV AB Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson Schwartz AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV-Present not voting U Dn|e- VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson Schwartz X Indicates Vote AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
