<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-254">
  <num type="law">12-254</num>
  <heading type="short">Food Stamp Trafficking and Public Assistance Fraud Control Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1999-04-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-254.pdf">D.C. Law 12-254</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 1276</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0520">
      <narrative>Law 12-254, the “Food Stamp Trafficking and Public Assistance Fraud Control Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-520, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 1, 1998, and December 15, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-602 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-254 became effective on April 20, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMEN (S) kwikta 062 329 501 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-254 "Food Stamp Trafficking and Public Assistance Fraud Control Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill 12-520 on first and second readings, December 1, 1998 and December 15, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 29, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act the bill became Act 12-602 and it was published in the February 19, 1999 edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 46, page 1276 The Act was transmitted to Congress on February 10, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired, and the Act is now D.C. Law 12-254, effective April 20, 1999 LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Days Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: 10,11,12,22,23,24,25 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 12,13,14,15,19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-602 IN TI-IE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 29, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982 to clarify that intent is an element of the crime in cases of public assistance fraud, to grant the Corporation Counsel the power to issue subpoenas to aid in prosecuting public assistance fraud, to authorize the punishment of the crime of food stamp trafficking as a misdemeanor, and to grant the Mayor the authority to suspend, revoke, or deny a business license or permit to anyone who is convicted of food stamp trafficking. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Food Stamp Trafficking and Public Assistance Fraud Control Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code § 3-201.1 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 1801(a D.C. Code § 3-218.1(a is amendedby inserting the phrase "with the intent to defraud" after the phrase "Any person who b) Anew section 1804 is added to read as follows See. 1804. Prosecutions; subpoenas; witness fees; perjury; compulsion of obedience to subpoena; oaths a) In addition to any power to bring criminal or civil actions or otherwise carry out the duties under this act, the Corporation Counsel shall have the authority to issue subpoenas for a witness to appear and testify or to produce all books, records, papers, or documents in any investigation into alleged violations of this act b) A wimess, other than those employed by the District of Columbia, summoned under subsection (a) of this section shall be paid the same fees and mileage that a witness is paid in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia Superior Court but the fees need not be tendered to the witness before he or she appears and testifies or produces books, records, papers, or documents c) Any willful false swearing on the part of any witness testifying about a material fact pursuant to a subpoena issued under subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to prosecution 3-218.1 New Section 3-218.4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL pursuant to the DisWict of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code § 22-2511 etseq d) If any witness, who has been personally summoned, neglects or refuses to obey the subpoena, the Corporation Counsel may report this fact to the Superior Court. The Superior Court may compel obedience to the subpoena to the same extent as a witness may be compelled to obey the subpoenas of that court e) The Corporation Counsel may administer oaths to any witness summoned in any investigation under subsection (a) of this section c) A new section 1805 is added to read as follows See. 1805. Penalties a) Any person who knowingly uses, transfers, acquires, alters, purchases, possesses, or transports one or more food stamp coupons or access devices in a manner not authorized by the Food Stamp Act of 1964, approved August 31, 1964 (78 Stat. 703; 7 U.S.C. § 2011 etseq Food Stamp Act or by regulations issued pursuant to that Act, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be fined no more than $1,000 or imprisoned for not more than 180 days, or both b) In addition to the penalty in subsection (a) of this section, any person convicted of a misdemeanor under this section shall be subject to suspension by the Superior Court from participation in the District of Columbia food stamp program for a period of 1 year consecutive to that period of suspension mandated by section 6(b)(1) of the Food Stamp Act (7 U.S.C. § 2015(b)(1 c) Prosecution under this act shall be conducted in the Superior Court by the Corporation Counsel d) For purposes of this section, the term 1 Access device" means any card, plate, code, account number, or other means of access, which can be used, alone or in conjunction with another access device, to obtain payments, allotments, benefits, money, goods, or other things of value, or which can be used to initiate a transfer of funds under the Food Stamp Act or regulations issued pursuant to this Act 2 Food stamp coupon" means a coupon issued by the United States Department of Agriculture pursuant to the Food Stamp Act or regulations issued pursuant to that Act 3 Person" means an individual, firm, partnership, group, corporation, institution, agency, or other entity, public or private d) A new section 1806 is added to read as follows Sec. 1806. Suspension, revocation, or denial of a business license or permit a) The Mayor is authorized to suspend, revoke, or deny the issuance or renewal of any business license or permit of any person or entity convicted of food stamp wafficking under this act, the Food Stamp Act, or regulations issued pursuant to that Act. New Section 3-~18.5 New Section 3-]18.6 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "Co) Prior to the suspension, revocation, or denial of any business license or permit, the affected party shall be given notice, and shall be offered an opportunity to present evidence, and to be heard concerning the proposed action c) In any hearing pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, a conviction shall create a presumption that the person or entity convicted of food stamp trafficking is unfit to hold the business license or permit at issue Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Respomibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 publication in the District of Columbia Register.Stat. 813; D.C.~c 3(C)(1 and ~J Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: December 29, 1998 3 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE vOICE VOTE RECOimED VOT~ ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COI,,UMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICLA, L COUNCIL VOTE D.,e,~o. B!?’520 ADOPTED FIRST P~ADING. 12.01a98 APPROVED A~ENT ALL PRESENT I ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Couuei|member Aye Nuy NV AB Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Chavous A||en Evans Ambrose JarvJs Brazil Mason Catania Patterson Aye Nay NV AB Connei|member Aye Nu~ 1 NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St CERTI,ICATION RECORD the Council ~EM ON C~NSENT CALENUAR ON" DATE ADOPTED F INAL READING, 12,15L98 APPROVEDVOICE VOTE BECOROED VOTE ON REQUEST A~SENT THOMAS I I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil 1 Catania x In~catcs vote etary to the Council [ ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB-Absent CERTiFICAtION Rr.’~ORD CouttciSmembcr Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. I Thomas, Sr. NV-Presen! not voting Date i | ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmeml~er Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Chavoos Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson x Indicates Vote Nay NV AB Countilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982 to clarify that intent is an element of the crime in cases of public assistance fraud, to grant the Corporation Counsel the power to issue subpoenas to aid in prosecuting public assistance fraud, to authorize the punishment of the crime of food stamp trafficking as a misdemeanor, and to grant the Mayor the authority to suspend, revoke, or deny a business license or permit to anyone who is convicted of food stamp trafficking. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Food Stamp Trafficking and Public Assistance Fraud Control Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code § 3-201.1 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 1801 (a D.C. Code § 3-218.1 (a is amended by insexXing the phrase "with the intent to defraud" after the phrase "Any person who b) A new section 1804 is added to read as follows Sec. 1804. Prosecutions; subpoenas; witness fees; perjury; compulsion of obedience to subpoena; oaths a) In addition to any power to bring criminal or civil actions or otherwise carry out the duties under this act, the Corporation Counsel shall have the authority to issue subpoenas for a witness to appear and testify or to produce all books, records, papers, or documents in any investigation into alleged violations of this act b) A witness, other than those employed by the District of Columbia, summoned under subsection (a) of this section shall be paid the same fees and mileage that a witness is paid in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia Superior Court but the fees need not be tendered to the witness before he or she appears and testifies or produces books, records, papers, or documents c) Any willful false swearing on the part of any witness testifying about a material fact pursuant to a subpoena issued under subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to prosecution Section 3-218.1 New Section 3-218.4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL pursuant to the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code § 22-2511 etseq d) If any witness, who has been personally summoned, neglects or refuses to obey the subpoena, the Corporation Counsel may report this fact to the Superior Court. The Superior Court may compel obedience tO the subpoena to the same extent as a witness may be compelled to obey the subpoenas of that court e) The Corporation Counsel may administer oaths to any witness summoned in any investigation under subsection (a) of this section c) A new section 1805 is added to read as follows Sec. 1805. Penalties a) Any person who knowingly uses, transfers, acquires, alters, purchases, possesses, or transports one or more food stamp coupons or access devices in a manner not authorized by the Food Stamp Act of 1964, approved August 31, 1964 (78 Stat. 703; 7 U.S.C. § 2011 etseq Food Stamp Act or by regulations issued pursuant to that Act, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be freed no more than $1,000 or imprisoned for not more than 180 days, or both b) In addition to the penalty in subsection (a) of this section, any person convicted of a misdemeanor under this section shall be subject to suspension by the Superior Court from participation in the District of Columbia food stamp program for a period of 1 year consecutive to that period of suspension mandated by section 6(b)(1) of the Food Stamp Act (7 U.S.C. § 2015(b)(1 c) Prosecution under this act shall be conducted in the Superior Court by the Corporation Counsel d) For purposes of this section, the term 1 Access device" means any card, plate, code, account number, or other means of access, which can be used, alone or in conjunction with another access device, to obtain payments, allotments, benefits, money, goods, or other things of value, or which can be used to initiate a transfer of funds under the Food Stamp Act or regulations issued pursuant to this Act 2 Food stamp coupon" means a coupon issued by the United States Department of Agriculture pursuant to the Food Stamp Act or regulations issued pursuant to that Act 3 Person" means an individual, firm, partnership, group, corporation, institution, agency, or other entity, public or private d) A new section 1806 is added to read as follows Sec. 1806. Suspension, revocation, or denial of a business license or permit a) The Mayor is authorized to suspend, revoke, or deny the issuance or renewal of any business license or permit of any person or entity convicted of food stamp trafficking under this act, the Food Stamp Act, or regulations issued pursuant to that Act. New Section 3-218,5 New Section 3-218.6 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL b) Prior to the suspension, revocation, or denial of any business license or permit, the affected party shall be given notice, and shall be offered an opportunity to present evidence, and to be heard concerning the proposed action c) In any hearing pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, a conviction shall create a presumption that the person or entity convicted of food stamp trafficking is unfit to hold the business license or permit at issue Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-,7,~3(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTIO amp; OAT~ votct VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COIIITMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE o. B 520 ADOPTED FIRST RgADING. 12-01,98 APPROVED ABSENT ALL PRESENT I I ROLL CALL VOTE R~ult Councilntl.mlJer Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Cataaia Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Chavous Evalls Jarvis Mason Patterson 1 Nay NV AB Counciimember Aye Na N% AB Schwartz Smith, Jr Thomas, Sr X indicnll VOll. AB Al~S~ot ff’ IV PreSenl not lung J l Io lie Coilil DIll ITEM ON CIINSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICEVOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ADOPTED FINAL READING 12-15L98 APPROVED A~ENT THOMAS I I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmeml~er Chmn. Cropp j Alien Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates VOle ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember A.ve Nay NV AB Chavous Evans Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. CERTIFICATION RECORD Ai|’Absl.nl x NV.Preseot not vOIOnl~ Dill’ I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT CALL VOTE Councilml.meer Chron. Cropp Ambrose Brazil Aye Na~ NV AB Councilmembcr A~¢ Nay NV AB Councilstuber Aye Nay NV AB J Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. Mason Catania Patterson X Indieutr$ Votl. AB -Abseut ’~V. Prl.sl.nt not ~onng CERTIFICATION RECORD Secrelary IO the CollIOI Date District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Washington, D.C. Via Facsimile January 20, 1999 Ms. Phyllis Jones Secretary to the Council Council of the District of Columbia One Judiciary Square Building 441 Fourth Street, NW Suite 716 Washington, D.C. 20001 DC Act 12-602 "’Food Stam Tr and Public Assistance Fraud Control _Amendment Act of 1998’" Dear Ms. Jones: This is to advise you that the Authority, having reviewed the above,captioned Act does not disapprove the Act or have any recommendations for modifications to it Sincerely yours, Mark Goldstein Director of Policy and Planning One Thomas Circle, NW ¯ Suite 900 ¯ Washington, DC 20005 Phone (202) 504-3400 ¯ Fax (202) 504-3431</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
