<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-211">
  <num type="law">12-211</num>
  <heading type="short">Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-211.pdf">D.C. Law 12-211</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 12-211, the “Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-773. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 22, 1998, and October 22, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 5, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-512 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-211 became effective on April 13, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN L N (S) kwiktag 062 328 534 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-211 "Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-773, on first and second readings, September 22, 1998 and October 6, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 5, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-512 and published in the December 18, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 9045) and transmitted to Congress on February 3, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-211, effective April 13, 1999. LINDA W CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 3,4,8,9,10,11,12,22,23,24,25 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 12 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C. ACT 12-512 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 5, 1998 To amend, on a temporary basis, the School Based Budgeting and Accountability Emergency Act of 1998 and the School Based Budgeting and Accountability Act of 1998 to change the date the Superintendent is required to submit the implementation plan for reforms from September 15, 1998 to October 15, 1998; to amend the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department Small Purchase Authority Emergency Act of 1998 and the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department Small Purchase Authority Act of 1998 to add a sunset provision of September 30, 1999; and to amend Title XIX of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1998 and Title XXIII of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Act of 1998 to change from mandatory to discretionary the establishment of a disability income protection program for Executive Service employees. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 706 of the School Based Budgeting and Accountability Emergency Act of 1998, signed by the Mayor on June 23, 1998 (D.C. Act 12-401 is amended by striking the phrase "September 15, 1998" and inserting the phrase "October 15, 1998" in its place. Sec. 3. Section 1106 of the School Based Budgeting and Accountability Act of 1998, signed by the Mayor on June 23, 1998 (D.C. Act 12-399 is amended by striking the phrase "September 15, 1998" and inserting the phrase "October 15, 1998" in its place. Sec. 4. The Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department Small Purchase Authority Emergency Act of 1998, signed by the Mayor on June 23, 1998 (D.C. Act 12-401 is amended by adding a new section 1204 to read as follows Sec. 1204. This title shall expire on September 30, 1999 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 5. The Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department Small Purchase Note, New Section Authority Act of 1998, signed by the Mayor on June 23, 1998 (D.C. Act 12-399 is amended by 1-11s3.22 adding a new section 1604 to read as follows Sec. 1604. This title shall expire on September 30, 1999 Sec. 6. Section 1901(c) of Title XIX of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1998, signed by the Mayor on June 23, 1998 (D.C. Act 12-401 is amended by striking the word "shall" after the phrase "The Mayor" and inserting the word "may" in its place. Note, New Section 1-611.61 Sec. 7. Section 2301(c) of Title XXIII of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Act of 1998, signed by the Mayor on June 23, 1998 (D.C. Act 12-399 is amended by striking the word "shall" after the phrase "The Mayor" and inserting the word "may" in its place. Note, New Section 1-611.61 Sec. 8. This act will have no fiscal impact. Sec. 9 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Council of the District of Crlumbia District of Columbia APPROVED: November 5, 1998 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR AC’rlON &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B 12 773 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 9-22-98 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED MASON ROLL CALL VOTE Result Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV AB NV Present not Voting Date ADO.PTED FINAL READING, 10-6’98 Councilmember Chron. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans Am brose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson x Indicates Vote AB Absent i r/r~Wl L, CERTIFICATION RECORD I I ~M ON COGENT CALENWAR ]~ A~ION &amp;amp; DATE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT MASON AND SMITH [ ROLL CALL VOTE Result Coun¢ilmemDer Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV Chmn. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, x Indicates Vote V A S~t~ry tO the Conncil l/ ITEM ON CONSENT CALI~DAR AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD [ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE NV-Present not voting VOICE VOTE .RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Coun¢ilmembcr Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania x Indicates Vote Aye Nay NV AB I Cont~cilmember Aye Nay NV AB Co~meilm~mbtv Aye Nay Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason PaHerson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. AB Absent NV AB NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
