<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-37">
  <num type="law">12-37</num>
  <heading type="short">Real Property Tax Sale Amendment Act of 1997</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-10-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-37.pdf">D.C. Law 12-37</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 4850</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0178">
      <narrative>Law 12-37, the “Real Property Tax Sale Amendment Act of 1997,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-178, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 17, 1997, and July 1, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 17, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-139 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-37 became effective on October 23, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwikta 062 326 069 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-37 "Real Property Tax Sale Amendment Act of 1997 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-178, on first and second readings, June 17, 1997 and July 1, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 17, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-139, and published in the August 22, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 4850) and transmitted to Congress on September 3, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-37, effective October 23, 1997 L1NDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Sept. 3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,26, 29,30 Oct. 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,20,21,22 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-139 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 17, 1997 To amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code to prevent owners of real property with delinquent real property taxes from participating in real property tax sales. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Real Property Tax Sale Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. Chapter 13 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents for the chapter is amended by adding the phrase "47-1320. Delinquent taxpayers bidding at tax sales prohibited b) A new section 47-1320 is added to read as follows § 47-1320. Delinquent taxpayers bidding at tax sales prohibited a) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, an owner of real property with delinquent real property taxes shall not bid on, or purchase, any other real property sold at tax sale in accordance with § 47-1303 or § 47-1314 b) An owner of real property with delinquent real property taxes that is being sold pursuant to § 47-1303 or § 47-1314 may bid on, or purchase, the real property if the owner pays all delinquent taxes, applicable penalties, and costs assessed against the real property c) The Mayor is authorized to develop procedures and promulgate rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section Sec. 3. This act shall ta_ke effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- ENROLLED ORIGINAL Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and puhl~i~9~ in t~District of Columbia Register Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: duly 17, i997 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE D.ke, No. B12--178 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 06-17-97 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST APPROVED ABSEN]~ ROLL CALL VOTE Result ALL PRESENT Councilmember Aye Na) N AB Counciimcmbcr Aye NUy N~*r AB Councilmember Aye NU&amp;gt; N~ AB Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz AB AbsentCERTIFICATION RECORD v i’ ¢ret.ry. totheC i ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV Present not Voting Date ADOPTED FINAL READING, 07-01-97 VOICE VOTE APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT JARV I S [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Counciimember Aye Na) NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous X-indicates no Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD I cgrct~ry. to the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Aye Nay NV AB NV-Present not voting I I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote AB Absent NV Present Itot Voting’ CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
