<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-55">
  <num type="law">12-55</num>
  <heading type="short">Public Assistance Fair Hearing Procedures Amendment Act of 1997</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1998-02-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-55.pdf">D.C. Law 12-55</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 6068</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0257">
      <narrative>Law 12-55, the “Public Assistance Fair Hearing Procedures Amendment Act of 1997,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-257, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 1, 1997, and September 22, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 3, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-172 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-55 became effective on February 27, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 328 922 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-55 "Public Assistance Fair Hearing Procedures Amendment Act of 1997" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-257, on first and second readings, July 1, 1997 and September 22, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 3, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-172, and published in the October 24, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 6068) and transmitted to Congress on October 23, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-55, effective February 27, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Oct. Nov. Jan. Feb. 23,24,27,28,29,30,31 3,4,5,6,7,10,12,13 27,28,29 2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,23,24,25,26 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-172 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 3, 1997 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend the Public Assistance Act of 1982 to change the requirement that a verbatim written transcript be prepared for every fair heating and to require recorded testimony instead, and to authorize transcripts when requested by a claimant, if ordered by the hearing officer or for purposes of judicial review, with costs of transcription to be borne by the Mayor. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public Assistance Fair Hearing Procedures Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. Title X of the Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code § 3-210.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 1010 (D.C. Code § 3-210.10) is amended in the second sentence by striking the phrase "taken down and transcribed" and inserting the word "recorded" in its place b) Section 101 l(a D.C. Code § 3-210.11 (a is amended as follows 1) By striking the phrase "A verbatim transcript of" in the third sentence and inserting the word "Recorded" in its place; and (2) By adding a new sentence at the end to read as follows Hearings shall be transcribed if requested by the claimant, if ordered by the hearing officer, or for purposes of judicial review. All costs of transcription shall be borne by the Mayor Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to ovelTide the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the Section 3-210.10 Section 3-210.11 ENROLLED ORIGINAL District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(c a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December~4, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia/~egister 1 1 ~t’/o~S’̄ ’ bia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 3, 1997 2 I { lION D-S’I’I IX ’%OI(E VOIERI’ ORDI’~D %01E O% Rl’ l EN l { OI \{ I1 1}t llll I)I~IRI( I I)P Oil XllJl x lt;11 1 IL PERI(II} 1 tl t; RI]( ORll (IF OI=FI(’I-Xl 01 X(II IOTE o lt lt;o B12-257 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 07-01-97 ROLL (’ALL rE R~ult BRAZ!L~ EVANS~-JARV!S~ SCHWARTZ AND THOMAS ouncihnember A~e N’a} %\ &amp;amp;ll (’ouneilmemher Chmn. Cropp Evans Allen Jarvis Ambrose Mason Brazil Patterson Chavous Schwartz c \a B ouncilmember c \a I Smith. Jr. Thomas. St. ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR lt lt ADOPTED F I NAL READ I NG, 09-22-97 APPROVEDVOI(’E VOTE RECORDED X’OTE ON REQUEST %IISENT DIXON. JARVIS AND THOMAS ROLL (ALL VOTE Result ouncihnendler A.~e Na} N%’ AB Councilmember Chron. Cropp Dixon Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Chavous Patterson A)e Na) NV %B (’ouncilmember Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas. St. ¯ "l X-ind]ales- no to lhe Council I ITE%I ON CONSENT (’ALENDAR AB-Absen! CERTIFICATION RECORD t NV-Presenl not votinl~ 7 I 4(’TIO\ &amp;amp; I)ATE i VOIt:E VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST %IISEN’I I ROll CAll vo’rE Result { uun¢ilmember e Na) Cbmn. Cropp Ambrose Brazil Chavous x Indicales o|e NV AB Councilmember Dixon Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson NV AB Councilmemher Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas, St ER IIFI I1()\ RE(ORI ecretar~ 1o Ihe (uuncil Dale ENROLLED ORIGINAL A RESOLUTION 11-515 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA October 1, 1996 To confirm the appointment of Mr. William B. Johnson as an alternate to the Water and Sewer Authority Board of Directors. RESOLVED, BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this resolution may be cited as the "Water and Sewer Authority Board of Directors Alternate Member William B. Johnson Confirmation Resolution of 1996 Sec. 2. The Council of the District of Columbia confirms the appointment of: Mr. William B. Johnson 2520 36th Street, S.E. Washington, D.C. 20020 (Ward 7) as an alternate member of the Board of Directors of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, established by section 204 of the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996, effective April 18, 1996 (D.C. Law 11- 111; D.C. Code § 43-1674 for a 4-year term. Sec. 3. The Council of the District of Columbia shall transmit a copy of this resolution, upon its adoption, each to the nominee and to the Office of the Mayor. Sec. 4. This resolution shall take effect immediately. COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eleven RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Docket No Action &amp;amp; Date PRII-798 Resolution No ADOPTED, i0-i-96 RII-5i5 [ ] Item on Consent Calendar [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Aye Nay NV AB Cotmcilmember Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Evans Ray X Indicates Vote Aye Nay NV AB Absent AB Coundlmember SmRh, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington Aye Nay NV AB NV Present not Voting [ X] VOICE VOTE Result Absent APPROVED LIGHTFOOT AND THOMAS Recorded vote (on request) CERTIFICATE OF RECORD ~ecrettn’y to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
