<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-52">
  <num type="law">12-52</num>
  <heading type="short">Nuisance Repairs Amendment Act of 1997</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1998-02-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-52.pdf">D.C. Law 12-52</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 6226</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0174">
      <narrative>Law 12-52, the “Nuisance Repairs Amendment Act of 1997,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-174, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 8, 1997, and September 22, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 3, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-169 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-52 became effective on February 27, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LLMEN (S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-52 "Nuisance Repairs Amendment Act of 1997" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-GovemJnent and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-174, and first and second readings, September 8, 1997 and September 22, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 3, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-169, and published in the October 31, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 6226) and transmitted to Congress on October 23, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-52, effective February 27, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Oct. 23,24,27,28,29,30,31 Nov. 3,4,5,6,7,10,12,13 Jan. 27,28,29 Feb. 2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,23,24,25,26 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C. ACT 12-169 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 3, 1997 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend section 1 of An Act To provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, to require owners of real property that have become a nuisance to pay fair market value for repairs made to the property by the District of Columbia government. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Nuisance Repairs Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. Section l(a) of An Act To provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes, approved April 14, 1906 (34 Stat. 114; D.C. Code § 5-513(a is amended by striking the phrase "assess the cost of correcting such condition" and inserting the phrase "assess the fair market value of the correction of the condition or the actual cost of the correction, whichever is higher in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. As before, the cost of correcting the nuisance will be paid by the owner, presumably, so there is no added cost to the District. It can be expected, however, that there will be an increase in litigation costs preceding the District’s effort to abate the nuisances. The legislation does not address who pays this cost, but it can be presumed that it will be added to the cost of abating the nuisance itself. The revenue to be raised by correcting the nuisances will be offset by an equal amount of cost to the agency doing the correcting. Currently, there isn’t any historical data which will predict how many nuisances will reach this level, so the amount of potential cost and revenue to and for that agency cannot be estimated. The Financial Plan and Budget will be impacted by a like amount of revenues and expenditures if the proposed legislation is implemented to the letter, however, neither can be quantified at this time. Section 5-513 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication inthe District ot~er.Q~a~n i j J~ Council of the District of Colum ~a District of Columbia APPROVED: October 3, 1997 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR AC’TION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST BSENT I ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result COl’N( IL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUSlBIA COUNCIE PERIOD rELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL colrNcIE VOTE ~o o. B12-174 ADOPTED FIRST READING~ 09-Q8-97 APPRQVF~ ALL PRESENT Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Aye Nay NV AB Councihnember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember A) Na NV AB Dixon Smith. Jr. Evans Thomas, Jarvis Mason Chavous o the Council ITEM ON CONSENT (’AI.ENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DAIE VOICE RECORDEI) VOTE ON REQEEST Patterson AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV Present not Voting ADOPTED FINAl READING, 09-22-97 APPROVED ABSENT DIXON, JARVIS AND THOMAS ROLL CALl. ’*’()rE Result Couacilmember Chron. Cropp A||e~ Ambrose Brazil Chavous X-indicate[ no [ t ITE~I ON (’O~SEN1 C-~LE~DAR I I ACTION DATE Nay N S,B Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember A)e Nay NV AB Dixon Schwartz Evans Smith. Jr. Jarvis Thomas. St. Mason Patterson AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD t NV-Present not s’otin~ Date I VOI(’E VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQL EST ABSENT I I ROLL (’ALL VOTE Result Councilmember A.~e Nay NV AB Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous X Indicates Vote Councilmember .Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Dixon Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas. Sr. Mason Patterson AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
