<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-66">
  <num type="law">12-66</num>
  <heading type="short">Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Health and Life Insurance Clarification Amendment Act of 1997</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1998-03-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-66.pdf">D.C. Law 12-66</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 343</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0229">
      <narrative>Law 12-66, the “Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Health and Life Insurance Clarification Amendment Act of 1997,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-229, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 7, 1997, and November 4, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 21, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-205 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-66 became effective on March 20, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 328 798 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-66 "Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Health and Life Insurance Clarification Amendment Act of 1997" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-229, on first and second readings, October 7, 1997 and November 4, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 21, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-205, and published in the December 12, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 7486) and transmitted to Congress on December 18, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-66, effective March 20, 1998. Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. Mar. 27,28,29 2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,23,24,25,26,27 2,3,4,5,6,9,10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,fi, ACT 12-205 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 21, 1997 Codifica6on D~wia of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to clarify eligibility for continuation of health and life benefits for certain employees of the District government first employed after September 30, 1987. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Health and Life Insurance Clarification Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective October 1, 1987 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-601.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2103(1 D.C. Code § 1-622.3(1 is amended to read as follows 1 Annuitant" means A) An employee first employed by the District after September 30, 1987, who has subsequently retired pursuant to any of the following i) Teachers’ Retirement System (D.C. Code §§ 31-1201 to 31- 1252 ii) Police and Fire Retirement System (D.C. Code §§ 4-607 to 4-630 1571 or iii) Judges’ Retirement System (D.C. Code §§ 11-1561 to 11 iv) Teachers’ Insurance and Annuity Association programs; or B) An employee first employed by the District after September 30, 1987, who has subsequently separated pursuant to the District Retirement Benefit Program (Sections 2603 through 2614 of this act) after any of the following i) Reaching 57 years of age and having completed 25 years of creditable District service in a law enforcement position ii) Becoming entitled to retirement benefits under the Social Security Act; or Section 1-622.3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Act iii) Becoming entitled to disability benefits under the Social Security (b) Section 2204(1 D.C. Code § 1-623.4(1 is amended to read as follows 1 Annuitant" means A) An employee first employed by the District after September 30, 1987, who has subsequently retired pursuant to any of the following i) Teachers’ Retirement System (D.C. Code §§ 31-1201 to 31- 1252 ii) Police and Fire Retirement System (D.C. Code §§ 4-607 to 4-630 1571 or iii) Judges’ Retirement System (D.C. Code §§ 11-1561 to 11 iv) Teachers’ Insurance and Annuity Association programs; or B) An employee first employed by the District after September 30, 1987, who has subsequently separated pursuant to the District Retirement Benefit Program (Sections 2603 through 2614 of this act) after any of the following i) Reaching 57 years of age and having completed 25 years of creditable District service in a law enforcement position ii) Becoming entitled to retirement benefits under the Social Security Act; or iii) Becoming entitled to disability benefits under the Social Security Act Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the Committee report on Bill 12-229 as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 913; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Section 1-623.4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: November 21, 1997 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COt NCIL OF "IIIE DIS IRICT OF (O1.| MBIA COUNCIL PERIOD T~VELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COt’NCIL VOIE ~oc~.No. B12-229 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 10-07-97 APPROVED ABSENT ALL PRESENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result (ooncilmember Aye Nay I NV Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous f~ X lndica~tes Set ~ry tO the Council 1~ ITEM ON (’ONSEN [ (’AI.ENDAR I~ A(~ION &amp;amp; DATE AB [ Councilm~mber Dixon Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson I B [ (ouncdmember Aye Na~ N Schv, artz mll h, Jr. ’~B- khsent Thomas. St. ’ ¯ Present not nlin~ ADOPTED FINAL READING, 11-04-97 vOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED JARVIS Jarvis Mason Patterson I ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result (’ouncdmcmher .A)e Nay NV B Cnuncilmemi~cr Chron. Cropp Dixon Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous X-indicates A’oIe ~’ to the Conncil ITEM ON CONSENT C-~LENDAR ~B--Xbsenl ouncllmrmher A)e Na~ N B Sch~aartz [Smith. Jr. Thomas. St. NV-Present not voting CERTIFICATION RECORI) I ~CFION &amp;amp; DATE 1 x’Ol(’E VOTE ¯ RECORDED X OTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chmn. Cropp Allen Am brose Brazil Chasous A~e Na~ NV X Indicates Vote AB Councdmember Dixon Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Aye I Na~ NV Absent AB (ouncilmember Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Aye Nay NV AB CERTIFICATION RECORD Secrela~ to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
