<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-89">
  <num type="law">12-89</num>
  <heading type="short">Life Insurance Special Contingency Reserve Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1998-04-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-89.pdf">D.C. Law 12-89</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 1306</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0162">
      <narrative>Law 12-89, the “Life Insurance Special Contingency Reserve Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-162, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1997, and January 6, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 26, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-262 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-89 became effective on April 29, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LL NT(S) kwiktag 062 326 003 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-89 "Life Insurance Special Contingency Reserve Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-162, on first and second readings, December 4, 1997 and January 6, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on January 26, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-262, and published in the March 13, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 pagel306) and transmitted to Congress on February 27, 1998 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-89, effective April 29, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. Mar. Apr. 27 2,3,4,5,6,9,10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26 27,30,31 1,21,22,23,24,27,28 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, Afil 12-262 THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JANUARY 26, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to authorize the transfer of a special contingency reserve from one life insurance policy to a successor life insurance policy. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Life Insurance Special Contingency Reserve Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 2213 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-623.13 is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) When a policy purchased pursuant to section 2205 is replaced by a successor policy, either by a new policy under a contract with the same life insurance company or by a policy under a new contract with another life insurance company, any balance remaining in the special contingency reserve shall be transferred to the special contingency reserve for the new policy Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact report in the Committee report on Bill 12-162 as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 913; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(3 Sec. 4. The provisions of section 2 of this act shall apply as of May 30, 1995. Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203 (a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in Section 1-623.13 Note, Section 1-623.13 ENROLLED ORIGINAL section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1=233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia May,or District of Columbia APPROVED: January 26, 1998 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE COUNCIL OF ]’lie DISTRICT OF COLtTMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORDO~O~,C,ALCO,’NCILVOTE B12’162 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST RFADINC 2-4’97 APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmcmbcr Aye Nay NV Chron. Cropp Allen A m brose Brazil Catania ALL PRESENT Councilmcmbcr Chavous Evans Jar~is Mason Palterson AB Counci|member Aye Na) NV B Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St X -’ ~ndicates Vote ~B bscnl NV Present not oting ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR o ADOPTED F! NAL READ ING. 1-6’98 vo o~ APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT 1 I ROLl ALL VOTE Result Councilmembcr Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicalcs Vote ar.v to the (’ouncil ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE ALL _P_R_ES ENT Aye Nay NV AB (’ouncilmemhrr sc Xa AB Councilmcmber Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas. St. Mason Patterson (ER I I1~1 I ION Rl-~{ NV-Prescnt not vuting I .I VOICE VOTE RE(’ORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result ouncilmerabcr Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Cropp Allen A m brose Brazil Catania L Councilmcmhcr jr Na) NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Evans Jar~’is Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. X Indicates Vote AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
