<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-92">
  <num type="law">12-92</num>
  <heading type="short">Defined Contribution Transition Vesting Clarification Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1998-04-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-92.pdf">D.C. Law 12-92</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 1314</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0407">
      <narrative>Law 12-92, the “Defined Contribution Transition Vesting Clarification Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-407, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1997, and January 6, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 26, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-265 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-92 became effective on April 29, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S 5 kwiktag COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-92 "Defined Contribution Transition Vesting Clarification Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-407, on first and second readings, December 4, 1997 and January 6, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on January 26, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-265, and published in the March 13, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 1314) and transmitted to Congress on February 27, 1998 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(t) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-92, effective April 29, 1998. L1NDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 27 Mar. 2,3,4,5,6,9,10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26 27,30,31 Apr. 1,21,22,23,24,27,28 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-265 Codifica~on D~i~ of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JANUARY 26, 1998 To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to allow District government employees, whose participation in the District Defined Contribution Plan ceases as a result of the implementation of provisions of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, to credit their continuous service with the District of Columbia courts after September 30, 1997 and service with certain employers that provide the services previously performed by the District government toward the vesting requirement of the Defined Contribution Plan; and the Defined Contribution Transition Vesting Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 to clarify that District government employees also include nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia courts. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Defined Contribution Transition Vesting Clarification Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 2604(1) of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective October 1, 1987 (D.C. Law 7-27; D.C. Code § 1-627.4(1 is amended as follows a) The existing language is designated as subparagraph (A b) A new subparagraph (B) is added to read as follows B) For purposes of vesting pursuant to section 2610(b creditable service for employees whose participation in the District Defined Contribution Plan ceases as a result of the implementation of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, approved August 5, 1997 (Pub. L. No. 105-33 shall also include continuous service performed by nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia courts after September 30, 1997, or service performed for a successor employer that provides the services previously performed by the District government toward the vesting requirement of the Defined Contribution Plan Section 1-627.4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. There is no fiscal impact because this legislation does not cause the District to make any further contributions to the employee’s defined contribution plan after the employee is employed by the successor employer. Therefore, it causes no adverse fiscal impact and thus is consistent with the existing District budget and financial plan. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Re Council of the District of Columbia M~yor¯ District of Columbia APPROVED: January 26, 1998 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLI!MBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12-407 Docket No. ADOPTED F!RST READING, 12-4:97 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVEB ALL PRESENT [ [ ROLL CALL VOTE Result Coun¢ilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Na) NV AB Chavoiis E~ans Jarvis Mason Patterson x Ind/ales.%’ote I ’ r ’’ ’h ’ I tTE~t ON CONSENT C,~LEnD ACX;OS x~ i %B- Sb~rnt tLRIIII( tltO~ REI ORI) AB Counciimember Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. ADOPTED FINAL READING, 1’6-98 I~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED ALL PRESENT { I ROLl ALl, VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Na) NV AB lun¢ilnlembtr Chron. Cropp Chaxous Allen Exans Ambrose Jar~ i~ Brazil Mason Catania Patterson X Indicatt,s/’ote fl J 1 ’re is r y lh e ou. eli 1 1 ’TICMO~CONSENTC, LENDAR (t-R I !t II t I |{ )\ tiE(ORI) ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Councilmember Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St Aye Na? N%’ AB NV-Present not otin~ VOTE RECORDEI) VOTE On REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result (’oun¢ilmenibtr Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania A)e Na NV .I,B Councilmrmtwr Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson X Indicates Vote AB Absenl Councilmember Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Aye Nay NV AB N%’ Present not Voting CERTIFICATIOn RECORD Secretary’ to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
