<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-163">
  <num type="law">10-163</num>
  <heading type="short">Motor Vehicle Tinted Window Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-08-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-163.pdf">D.C. Law 10-163</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 4886</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0422">
      <narrative>Law 10-163, the “Motor Vehicle Tinted Window Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-422, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and the Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 7, 1994, and June 21, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 8, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-276 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-163 became effective on August 26, 1994.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S 5) to~iktag 03 24~ g~ COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D,C. LAW 10-163 Motor Vehicle Tinted Window Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-422 on first and second readings, June 7, 1994, and June 21, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 8, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-276, and published in the July 22, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol.41 page 4886) and transmitted to Congress on July 15, 1994 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-163 effective August 26, 1994. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July August 1 5,1 8,1 9,20,21,22,25,26,27,28,29 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 AN ACT D.C. ACT i0-276 Enrolled Original ,od c tior IN THE COUNCII, OF TIlE DISTRICT OF COI, UMBIA JULY 8, 1994 To amend the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, and title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations to regulate the tinting of motor vehicle windows. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Motor Vehicle Tinted Window Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. The District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Code § 40-701 et seq is amended by adding a new section lla to read as follows Sec. lla. Tinted windows prohibited a) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, no motor vehicle may be operated or parked upon the public streets or spaces of the District of Columbia with 1) A front windshield or front side windows that allow less than 70% light transmittance; or 2) A rear windshield or rear side windows that allow less than 50% light transmittance b) A motor vehicle may be operated or parked upon the public streets of the District of Columbia with a front windshield that allows less than 70% light transmittance above the AS-1 line, or within 5 inches from the top of the windshield c) Any person who operates or parks a motor vehicle in violation of subsection (a) of this section shall be issued a $50 citation d)(1) Except as provided by subsection (f) of this section, any motor vehicle found to violate subsection (a) of this section shall be required to be inspected at an official District Inspection Station within 5 business days after the finding 2) If the motor vehicle is not brought into compliance with subsection (a) of this section by the end of the 5-day period, the owner of the vehicle shall be fined not more than $1,000 e)(1) Except as provided by subsection (f) of this section, any motor vehicle found to violate subsection (a) of this section on a second or subsequent occasion shall be required to be inspected at an official District Inspection Station within 5 business days after the second or subsequent finding. New Section 40-718.1 Enrolled Original 2) If the motor vehicle is not brought into compliance with subsection (a) of this section by the end of the 5-day period, the owner of the vehicle may be fined not more than $5,000 f) Any police officer or other authorized government agent of the District may order the immediate removal of a motor vehicle from the public streets to an official District Inspection Station if the police officer or other authorized government agent determines that the health and safety of the public is at risk due to window tinting in violation of subsection (a) of this section g) No person shall install window tinting on a motor vehicle, which is not exempt pursuant to subsection (h) of this section, in the District of Columbia which would cause the motor vehicle to violate subsection (a) of this section if-the vehicle were operated or parked on the public streets of the District of Columbia h) Limousines, ambulances, buses and hearses, meeting the requirements of 18 DCMR 413.10, church-owned vehicles, and all official government vehicles, shall be exempt from the requirements of this section i) Nothing in this act shall be construed to modify or affect any federal law concerning the window tinting of motor vehicles that is applicable to manufacturers, importers, dealers, or motor vehicle repair businesses for new or used motor vehicles and equipment See. 3. Section 734 of title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal l~egulations is amended by adding new subsections 734.8 to 734.19 to read as follows 734.8 Except as provided in subsection 734.9, no motor vehicle may be operated or parked upon the public streets or spaces of the District of Columbia with A) A front windshield or front side windows that allow less than 704 light transmittance; or B) A rear windshield or rear side windows that allow less than 504 light transmittance 734.9 A motor vehicle may be operated or parked upon the public streets of the District of Columbia with a front windshield that allows less than 704 light transmittance above the AS-1 line, or within 5 inches from the top of the windshield 734.10 Any person who operates or parks a motor vehicle in violation of subsection 734.8 shall be issued a $50 citation 734.11 Any motor vehicle found to violate subsection 734.8 shall be required to be inspected at an official District Inspection Station within 5 business days after the finding 734.12 If the motor vehicle described in subsection 734.11 is not brought into compliance with subsection 734.8 by the end of the 5-day period, the owner of the vehicle shall be fined not more than $1,000 734.13 Any motor vehicle found to violate subsection 734.8 on a second or subsequent occasion shall be required to be inspected at an official District Inspection Station within 5 business days after the second or subsequent finding 734.14 If the motor vehicle described in subsection 734.13 is not brought into compliance with subsection 734.8 by the end of the 5-day period, the owner of the vehicle may be fined not more than $5,000 or the motor vehicle may be forfeited. Enrolled Original "734.15 No person shall install window tinting on a motor vehicle, which is subject to the provisions of this section, in the District of Columbia with a front windshield tinted below the AS-1 line, or 5 inches from the top of the windshield, or with rear side windows and rear windshield that allow less than 504 light transmittance 734.16 Any person who violates subsection 734.15 shall be fined not more than $1,000 734.17 Any person who violates subsection 734.15 on a second or subsequent occasion shall be fined not more than $5,000 734.18 Notwithstanding subsections 734.11 and 734.13, any police officer or other authorized government agent of the District may order the immediate removal of a motor vehicle from the public streets to an official District Inspection Station if the police officer or other authorized government agent determines that the health and safety of the public is at risk due to window tinting in violation of subsection 734.8 734.19 Limousines, ambulances, buses and hearses, meeting the requirements of 18 DCMR 413.10, church-owned vehicles, and all official government vehicles, shall be exempt from the requirements of subsections 734.8 734.18 See. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in. section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-G0vernment and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia lZegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia. Municipal l~egulations Ch man ¯ Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: July 8, 1994 COUNCIL OF DISTRICT OF COLlegIA CC~mcLl Pe~ied Ten RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Item on Consent Calendar ACT1ON &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE ecorcIed vote on re(:]L~esi ~bser~t LL CALL VOTE ESULT COUNC1LMEMBER AYE NAY N.V. Bill i0-422 Adopted First Reading, 6-7-94 Approved Chavous ~UNC~L MEMBER ¯ ~YE NAY i N.V¯ [ A.a. ] COUNCIL MEMBER ’ 1 ;ON ’ NV Present. not volln(~A.B Absent i Item on Consent Calendar ~2 ACTION &amp;amp; DATE vOICE VOTE: Recor~e(3 vole on r~uest AD LL CALL VOT RESULT [ CO~CIL MEMBER AYE I NAY NV. CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CERTIFiCATiON RECORD ate Adopted Final Reading, 6-21-94 Approved Smith CROPP f I X Incl~cates Vote w lne Council A.B. I COUNCIL, MEMBER RAY. i S.M.I TH JR. BA:,RRY Item on Corm~nl Calendir ACTION &amp;amp; DAT VOICE VOTe: RecoKled ~te u ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT Cq~,NCIL MEMeER AYE NAY ~N.V.A.8. CHMN. CLARKE BRAZIL L.CHAVOUS i CROPP COUNCIL MEMBER AYE FVAN£ qARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A.B Absem NAY i N.V. i N.V Present. not vouncJ Date CERTIFICATION RECORD X Indicates Vole CObNCIL MEMBER EVANS JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHAN~ON A.8 Ab~ AYE NAY N.V. ’A.B. N.V Present, not voan(:j ¯CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCILMEMBER tAYE ’"RAY ’,~MITH: j’R. THOMA~ SR. } NAY I N.V, Secre~a~/to tr~e Councd COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 The Honorable Sharon Pratt Kelly Mayor of the District of Columbia 441 4th Street, N.W llth Floor Washington, D.C. 20001 Re: Transmittal of Bill 10-422 Motor Vehicle Tinted Window Amendment Act of 1994 Date of Council Action: 06-21 -94 Dear Mayor Kelly: The above named enacted bill is hereby transmitted in accordance with Section 404(e) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to th~s bill, for your information, is the report of the Council’s standing committee with jurisdiction over this matter erel y d Cl arke Chairman of the Council Enclosure AN ACT Enrolled Original Codiflc t or IN TtIE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, and title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations to regulate the tinting of motor vehicle windows. BE IT ENACTED BY TtIE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Motor Vehicle Tinted Window Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. The District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved Mareh 3, 1925 (43 Star. 1119; D.C. Code § 40-701 e~ seq is amended by adding a new section lla to read as follows Sec. lla. Tinted windows prohibited a) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, no motor vehicle may be operated or parked upon the public streets or spaces of the District of Columbia with i) A front windshield or front side windows that allow less than 70% light transmittance; or 2) A rear windshield or rear side windows that allow less than 50% light transmittance b) A motor vehicle may be operated or parked upon the public streets of the District of Columbia with a front windshield that allows less than 70% light transmittance above the AS-1 line, or within 5 inches from the top of the windshield c) Any person who operates or parks a motor vehicle in violation of subsection (a) of this section shall be issued a $50 citation d)(1) Except as provided by subsection (f) of this section, any motor vehicle found to violate subsection (a) of this section shall be required to be inspected at an official District Inspection Station within 5 business days after the finding 2) If the motor vehicle is not brought into compliance with subsection (a) of this section by the end of the 5-day period, the owner of the vehicle shall be fined not more than $1,000 e)(1) Except as provided by subsection (f) of this section, any motor vehicle found to violate subsection (a) of this section on a second or subsequent occasion shall be required to be inspected at an official District Inspection Station within 5 business days after the second or subsequent finding. Section 40-718.1 Enrolled Original 2) If the motor vehicle is not brought into compliance with subsection (a) of this section by the end of the 5-day period, the owner of the vehicle may be fined not more than $5,000 f) Any police officer or other authorized government agent of the District may order the immediate removal Of a motor vehicle from the public streets to an official District Inspection Station if the police officer or other authorized government agent determines that the health and safety of the public is at risk due to window tinting in violation of subsection (a) of this section g) No person shall install window tinting on a motor vehicle, which is not exempt pursuant to subsection (h) of this section, in the District of Columbia which would cause the motor vehicle to violate subsection (a) of this section if the vehicle were operated or parked on the public streets of the District of Columbia h) Limousines, ambulances, buses and hearses, meeting the requirements of 18 DCMlZ 413.10, church-owned vehicles, and all official government vehicles, shall be exempt from the requirements of this section i) Nothing in this act shall be construed to modify or affect any federal law concerning the window tinting of motor vehicles that is applicable to manufacturers, importers, dealers, or motor vehicle repair businesses for new or used motor vehicles and equipment Sec. 3. Section 734 of title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal I~egulations is amended by adding new subsections 734.8 to 734.19 to read as follows 734.8 Except as provided in subsection 734.9, no motor vehicle may be operated or parked upon the public streets or spaces of the District of Columbia with A) A front windshield or front side windows that allow less than 70~ light transmittance; or B) A rear windshield or rear side windows that allow less than 50~o light transmittance 734.9 A motor vehicle may be operated or parked upon the public streets of the District of Columbia with a front windshield that allows less than 70% light transmittance above the AS-1 line, or within 5 inches from the top of the windshield 734.10 Any person who operates or parks a motor vehicle in violation of subsection 734.8 shall be issued a $50 citation 734.11 Any motor vehicle found to violate subsection 734.8 shall be required to be inspected at an official District Inspection Station within 5 business days after the finding 734.12 If the motor vehicle described in subsection 734.11 is not brought into compliance with subsection 734.8 by the end of the 5-day period, the owner of the vehicle shall be fined not more than $1,000 734.13 Any motor vehicle found to violate subsection 734.8 on a second or subsequent occasion shall be required to be inspected at an official District Inspection Station within 5 business days after the second or subsequent finding 734.14 If the motor vehicle described in subsection 734.13 is not brought into compliance with subsection 734.8 by the end of the 5-day period, the owner of the vehicle may be fined not more than $5,000 or the motor vehicle may be forfeited. Enrolled Original "734.15 No person shall install window tinting on a motor vehicle, which is subject to the provisions of this section, in the District of Columbia with a front windshield tinted below the AS-1 line, or 5 inches from the top of the windshield, or with rear side windows and rear windshield that allow less than 50% light transmittance 734.16 Any person who violates subsection 734.15 shall be fined not more than $1,000 734.17 Any person who violates subsection 734.15 on a second or subsequent occasion shall be fined not more than $5,000 734.18 Notwithstanding subsections 734.11 and 734.13, any police officer or other authorized government agent of the District may order the immediate removal of a motor vehicle from the public streets to an official District Inspection Station if the police officer or other authorized government agent determines that the health and safety of the public is at risk due to window tinting in violation of subsection 734.8 734.19 Limousines, ambulances, buses and hearses, meeting the requirements of 18 DCMTL 413.10, church-owned vehicles, and all official government vehicles, shall be exempt, from the requirements of subsections 734.8 734.18 ’ See. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Keorganization Act, approved December 24, 1,973 (87 star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations Chairman Council of the District of Cohimbia Mayor District of Columbia Item on Consent CT]GN &amp;amp; OATE vOIC~ VOTE: CO~CIL OF DIsTrIcT OF CC~n’~i ±ccl Ten RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE ~3CCKET NO: Bill 10-422 Adopted First Reading, 6-7-94 Approved sent: Chavous VOTE F~ESULT COUNCIL MEMSER CHMN L~RKE i ’ I EVANS BARRY CHAVOUS X nQ=cates vole NAY i N.V i A.a. I COUNC:L MEME]E wE NAY N 2 ~MASQN iNATHANSON i ’ 1 Aa A~sent NV Preset, not votln SMITH~ JR. i Item on Consent CalenOar ACTION &amp;amp; OATE VOICE VOTE. i~e~of(:l~ vOt~ 011 rEN~lUe~t Smith Absent: U O a~e Ādopted Final Readin~ 6-21-94 Approved ROLL CALL VOTE RESUL COU~CILMEMBERcHMN. CLARKE AYE INAY BARRY I i ~ARViS BRAZIL I 1 kIGHTFQOT CHAVOUS I MA~QN CROPP i i NATHANSON X InO~cates Vote A.B Absent Item on Com~t S~ITH~ JR THOMAS, AYE i NAY N.V A ’:AYE NAY NV, I A.8. COUI~C, IL MEMBER RA~ N.V Present n~ vo0n(I U AC11ON &amp;amp; OAT vOiCE VOl Ab~’ \ RO~ CALL VO RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ~N,V, A.B. C~MN. CLARKE BX’RRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. EVANS RAY JARVIS SMITH~ JR. LIGHTFOOT THOMAS, SR. MASON NATHANSQN A.B AOSe~t N.V Present. n~ CERTIFICATION RECORD Secrmary to me Councd</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
