<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-132">
  <num type="law">10-132</num>
  <heading type="short">Fuels Technology Temporary Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-06-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-132.pdf">D.C. Law 10-132</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 10-132, the “Fuels Technology Temporary Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-591. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 1, 1994, and April 12, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 28, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-231 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-132 became effective on June 28, 1994.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C, LAW 10-132 "Fuels Technology Temporary Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. I0-591 on first and second readings, March l, 1994, and April 12, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 28 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. I0-231, and published in the May 13, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol.41 page 2590) and transmitted to Congress on May 5, 1994 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law I0-132, effective June 28, 1994 Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: May 5,6,9,10,II,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26 June 8, 9,10,13,14,15,16,17,20,21,22,23,24,27 AN ACT D,C, ACT i0-231 Enrolled Original Codification District of Columbia Code 1994 Supplement} IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APRIL 28, 1994 To amend, on a temporary basis, the Alternative Fuels Technology Act of 1990 to delete certain provisions dependent upon the issuance of rules. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Fuels Technology Temporary Amendment Act of 1994 Sec. 2. Section 4 of the Fuels Technology Act of 1990, effective March 8, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-293; D.C. Code § 40-2003 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is repealed b) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase pursuant to rules issued by the Mayor Sec. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. NOte, Section 40-2003 Enrolled Original (b) effect. This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken j~@ I ’ h~air man ~Council of the District o£ Columbia D ct of Colu~"ia APPROVED; Api~J] 28~ 1994 COUNCIL OF TEE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Ten RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO tlem on Consent ~C~dar ACTION &amp;amp; DA Adopted First :E VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on st Absent: C~opp and ~vans ROLL CALL 0~ RESULT CHMN CLARKE } I EVf~N£JARVTSL BARRY i i:,’ ’[BRAZIL I LIGHTFhnT ’ CHAVOUS i 1 MASON L_CROPP i NATHA.NSON X ’~~tes Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not votin~ CERTIFICATION RECORD era on ~nsem C~ar ~ACT~N &amp;amp; DATE O~f Fi~l ~di 4-12-94 vOiCE VOTE V ecord~ vote on r~ BI0-591 COUNCIL MEMBER RAY SMIT~ JR.I,T~OMASTSR. Date Absent ROLL CALL VO’SE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS r CROPP X m~cates Vote tCOUINCILMEMBEREVAN£ ’ LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A.B Absent AYE NAY INV. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER F~AY- SMITH, JR. THQMAS. SR. Date AYE NAY N.V. ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE Recorded vote on r~ Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ~Y NV. i A.B -CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL _CHAVOUS ’..CRQPP X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. I A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.Y. EVANS RAY JARV I S .SM.I TH ’~ R LIGHTFObT THOMAS, SR. M_ASON I NATHANSON A.B Absent N.V Present. not votin~ CERTIFICATION RECORD Secr,s~tary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
