<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-137">
  <num type="law">10-137</num>
  <heading type="short">EMERGENCY ASSISTANCE PROGRAM AMENDMENT ACT OF 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-07-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-137.pdf">D.C. Law 10-137</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 3008</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0223"/>
    <search-text>ENRO N (S) kwiktag 062 313 200 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE DLC~ LAW 10-137 "Emergency Assistance Program Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. P. L~ 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. I0-223 on first and second readings. April 12, 1994, and May 3, 1994. respectively~ Following the signature of the Mayor on May 18 1994. this legislation was assigned Act No, I0-242, and published in the May 27. 1994. edition of the D~C~ Register (Vol~41 page 3008) and transmitted to Congress on May 23. 1994 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D,C, Law I0-137 effective J Dates Counted During the 30,day Congressional Review Period: May June July 23,24,25,26 8,9.10,13.14.15,16.17.20.21,22,23,24,27.28.29,30 12.13,14,15,18,19.20,21.22 AN ACT D,C, 10-242 Enrolled Original Codification Dlstrlct of Co~urnbla Code 1994 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Emergency Assistance Program Act of 1988 to change the number of days within which the Mayor shall provide emergency assistance, to clarify that either mailing a cheek or a confirmation letter from the Mayor to the vendor tolls the running of the time under the statute and to require the issuance of an expedited cheek in certain circumstances. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTI~ICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Emergency Assistance Program Amendment Act of 1994 Sec. 2. Section 5(a) of the Emergency Assistance Program Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-221; D.C. Code § 3-1004(a is amended as follows a) By striking the number "8" and inserting the number "12" in its place; and (b) By adding a new sentence at the end of the subsection to read as follows For purposes of this subsection a direct vendor payment has been made if the Mayor has paid cash or mailed a check for needed services to the appropriate vendorI or mailed a confirmation letter to a vendor ~Si~0vin~ paymen{~ [or needed services. In the event that a vendor refuses to accept a confirmation letter, the Mayor shall take all reasonable steps to provide payment to the vendor within a time-frame appropriate to avert the crisis Section 3-I004 Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 Enrolled Original and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations f the District of Columbia APPROVED: May 18, 1994 2 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on reaues[ Absent: COUNCIL OF T~E DISTRICT OF COLI/M~I~ COuncil Period Ten RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: BI0-223 Adopted First Reading. 4-12-94 Approved Barry, Chavous, and Jarvis ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT I COUNCILME~BER AYE !NAY N.V. IA.B. COUNCIL MEMBER t ~YE I NAY CHMN..’CLARKE BARRY _BRAZIL i I IIT~TPnnT ’CHAVOUS J { iMASON CROPP i ] INATHANSON x no~cates Vote A.8 Absent N.Y. N.V Present, not voting COUNC=LMEMBER YE NAY i i ’" ISMITH, JR. THOMAS~ SR. ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: RecordeO vote on reoueet Adopted Final Approved Reading, 5-3-94 Absent: Jarvis ROLL CALLVOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. CHMN, CLARKE BARRY BRAZIi CHAVOUS CROPP 1 t X Indicates Vote Item on J~:Z~et~c,J(:It? A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C~un6il FVAN£ JARV; LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER RAt S~ITH~ JR I THOMAS, N.V Present. n~ volin~ AYE I NAY N.V. i ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. L C~MN. CLARKE ;BARRY BRAZIL ~CHAVOUS CROPP X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER EVANS JARVlS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A,B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B, N.V Present. no~ vot~n~j CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER RAY SMITH JR THOMAS~ SR AYE NAY N,V, A,B, Secretary to t~e Councd Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
