<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-194">
  <num type="law">10-194</num>
  <heading type="short">Repeat Offender Life Without Parole Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-10-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-194.pdf">D.C. Law 10-194</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 4283</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0478">
      <narrative>Law 10-194, the “Repeat Offender Life Without Parole Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-478, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 7, 1994, and June 21, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 21, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-254 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-194 became effective on October 7, 1994.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENR kwiktag ¯ 062 313 610 L EN (S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C~ LAW 10-194 "Repeat Offender Life Without Parole Amendment Act of Igg4 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. I0-478 on first and second readings, June 7, 1994 and June 21, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 21, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. I0-254, and published in the July l, 1994, edition of the D,C. Register (Vol.41 page 4283) and transmitted to Congress on June 22, 1994 for a 60-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(2) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 60-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law I0-194 effective October 7, 1994 ’~Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 60-day Congressional Review Period: June July August September October 22,23,24, 27,28, 29,30, 12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,25,26,27,28,29 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,II,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,26 12,13,14,15,16,19,20,21,22,23,26,27,28,29,30 3,4,5,6 Enrolled Original AN ACT D,C, ACT i0-254 Godlfication District of Columbia Code I 1995 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 21, 1994 To amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to permit persons convicted of 3 crimes of violence to be sentenced to life without parole, and to amend the Assault Weapon Manufacturing Strict Liability Act of 1990 to include machine guns. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTIZlCT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Kepeat Offender Life Without Parole Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. Section 907A of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved July 29, 1970 (84 Star. 599; D.C. Code § 22-104a is amended to read as follows a)(1) If a person is convicted in the District of Columbia of a felony, having previously been convicted of 2 prior felonies not committed on the same occasion, the court may in lieu of any sentence authorized, impose such greater term of imprisonment as it deems necessary, up to and including life 2) If a person is convicted in the District of Columbia of a crime of violence as defined by section 1 of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Star. 650; D.C. Code § 22-3201 having previously been convicted of 2 prior crimes of violence not committed on the same occasion, the court may in lieu of any sentence authorized, impose a term of imprisonment of life without possibility of parole b) For the purposes of this section 1) A person shall be considered as having been convicted of a felony if the person was convicted of a felony by a court of the District of Columbia, any state, or the United States or its territories 2) A person shall be considered as having been convicted of a crime of violence if the person was convicted of a crime of violence as defined by section 1 of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Stat. 650; D.C. Code § 22-3201 by a court of the District of Columbia, any state, or the United States or its territories. Section 22-i04a c)(1) A person shall be considered as having been convicted of 2 felonies if the person has been convicted of a felony twice before on separate occasions by courts of the District of Columbia, any state, or the United States or its territories 2) A person shall be considered as having been convicted of 2 crimes of violence if the person has twice before on separate occasions been convicted of a crime of violence as defined by section 1 of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Star. 650; D.C. Code § 22-3201 by courts of the District of Columbia, any states, or the United States or its territories d) No conviction or plea of guilty with respect to which a person has been pardoned shall be taken into account in applying this section Sec. 3. The Assault Weapon Manufacturing Strict Liability Act of 1990, effective March 6, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-263; D.C. Code § 6-2391 e~ seq is amended as follows a) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 6-2392) is amended by inserting the phrase "or machine gun" after the phrase "assault weapon" wherever it appears b) Section 6 (D.C. Code § 36-2391, note) is amended by striking the period at the end of the section and inserting the phrase and to the discharge of a machine gun that is manufactured, imported, or distributed after the effective date of the l~epeat Offender Life Without Parole Amendment Act of 1994 in its place. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 60-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Keorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and Section 6-2392 Note Section 6-2391 Enrolled Original publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District o£ Columbia Municipal Regulations ohuainrc~f the District o; Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: June 21, 1994 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recoraed vote on request Absenl: COUNCIL OF TIIE DISTRICT OF COLI.IMB COuncil Period Ten RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Bill DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 6-7-94 10-478 Approved Brazil, Chavous and Lightfoot ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE BARRY _BRAZI L CHAVOUS CRQPP AYEINAY1N.V.A.B. COUNCILMEMBER I~YE NAY ’il EVANS i I ITGHTFOOT I I MASON I i ] NATHANSON I IN’V’IIA’B" COUNCIL MEMBER ’IAYE NAY ,i N.V i A.B I RAY. l l, l { I SMITH~ JR i THOMAS. SR I i X nolcales Vote A.8 Absent N.V Presen~ v I Secre CSonc Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: CERTIFICATION RECORD Adopted Final Approved Recorde~ vote on reuuest Absent: Date Readinq 6-21-94 Liqhtfoot, Barry and Smith ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN, CLARKE FVAN~ BARRY JARVi~ BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CHAVOUS CROPP ] IMASONNATHANSON [ X Ind~c~es Vote A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. AB. 1 N.V Present. not voting ICOUNCILMEMBERRA SMITH, JR. THOMAS. SR CERTIFICATION RECORD Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vole on recluest Absent: ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CRQPP AYE NAY I N.V. A.B. 1 X Indicates Vote Secretary to the Councd COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. EVANS JARVIS LIGHTFOOT M.ASON NATHAN$ON A.B Absent N.V Present not voI~n(J CERTIFICATION RECORD {.~J COUNCIL MEMBER RAY SMITH JR. THOMAS~ SR AYE NAY N.V Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
