<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-102">
  <num type="law">10-102</num>
  <heading type="short">Patient Counseling Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-04-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-102.pdf">D.C. Law 10-102</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 1002</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0376">
      <narrative>Law 10-102, the “Patient Counseling Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-376, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on January 4, 1994, and February 1, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 17, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-190 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-102 became effective on April 26, 1994.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwik~g 062 331 247 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-102 "Patient Counseling Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-376 on first and second readings, January 4, 1994, and February I, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on February 17, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-190, and published in the March 4, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 41 page 1002) and transmitted to Congress on February 25, 1994 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act, The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D;C Law 10-102, effective Apri 1994, i x;;’ ’\-~DAVID A, CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30,day Cong.ressional Review Period: February March April 25,28 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24 12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,25 AN ACT ACT 10-190 Enrolled Original Codif|c~tio~ District of Co!umbia Code 19 9 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA FEBRUARY 17, 1994 To amend the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 to establish patient counseling requirements for pharmacists providing prescription services to medical assistance recipients or their caregivers. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Patient Counseling Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. The District of Columbia Itealth Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Code § 2-3301.1 et seq is amended by adding a new section 1006a to read as follows Sec. 1006a. Pharmacist consultation, with medical assistance recipient or caregivers; records a) A pharmacist who provides prescription services to medical assistance recipients shall offer to discuss with each medical assistance recipient or caregiver who presents a prescription order for outpatient drugs any matter which, in the exercise of the pharmacist’s professional judgment, the pharmacist deems significant, which may include the following 1) The name and description of the medication 2) The dosage form, dosage, route of administration, and duration of drug therapy 3) Special directions, precautions for preparation, administration, and use by the patient 4) Common severe side or adverse effects or interactions and therapeutic contraindications that may be encountered, including their avoidance, and the action required if they occur 5) Techniques for self-monitoring drug therapy 6) Proper storage 7) Prescription refill information; and 8) Action to be taken in tt~e event of a missed dose b) The offer to discuss may be made in the manner determined by the professional judgment of the pharmacist, which may include any 1 or a combination of the following 1) A face-to-face communication with the pharmacist or the pharmacisCs designee 2) A sign posted in such a manner that it can be seen by patients; New Section 2-3310.6a Enrolled Original 3) A notation affixed to or written on the bag in which the prescription is to be dispensed 4) A notation contained on the prescription container 5) Communication by telephone; or 6) Any other manner prescribed by rule c) Nothing in this section shall be construed as requiring a pharmacist to provide consultation if the medical assistance recipient or caregiver refuses the consultation. These refusals shall be noted in the profile maintained in accord with subsection (d) of this section for a medical assistance recipient d) A pharmacist shall make a reasonable effort to obtain, record, and maintain, at the individual pharmacy, the following minimal information regarding a medical assistance recipient receiving a prescription 1) Name, address, telephone number, date of birth or age, and gender 2) Individual patient history when significant, including known allergies and drug reactions, and a comprehensive list of medications and relevant devices; and 3) Pharmacist comments relevant to the individual’s drug therapy, which may be recorded either manually or electronically in the patient’s profile, including any failure to accept the pharmacist’s offer to counsel e) This section shall apply only to medical assistance recipients presenting prescriptions for covered outpatient drugs f) The requirements of this section do not apply to refill prescriptions g) The Mayor may adopt regulations implementing the provisions of this section to assure compliance with federal medical assistance requirements See. 3. If any provision of this act or the application thereof to any health care provider is deemed improper and would therefore cause the denial of any portion of the federal share of payment for Medical Assistance expenditures by the United States Department of Health and Human Services, then that provision shall be declared invalid, but the invalidity shall not affect other provisions or any other application of this act which can be given effect without the invalid provision or application. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia l~egister, the District Note, New Section 2-3310.6a Enrolled Original of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal l~egulations. Chaimman Council of the District of Columbi~ I~ayor District of Columbia APPROVED February 17, 1994 COUNCIL OF T~E DISTRICT OF COLLEMB[A Council Period Ten RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO [[ Item on Consen~ C~endar ~x~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on rec~uest Absent: Adopted Approved Evans Bill 10-376 First Reading, 1-4-94 ROLL COUNCIL MEMBER CHIN CLARKE BARRY ,BRAZIL -CHAVOUS CROPP ;ALL VOTE RESULT AYE I NAY, N:V t A.B. CouNCIL M. EMBER 1 I I EVANS I [ I ]J Rv s I I MASONJ i i i NATHANSON X in(~cates Vote AB Absent Item on Consent Catendar ACT(ON &amp;amp; OATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request N V Present. not votm£ CERTIFICATION RECORO Absent: COUNCIL MEMBER 1 AYE I NAY N V t A,8, SMITH~IIJR. L] ,] THOMAS~-SR. j 5ate Adopted Final Reading, 2-1-94 Approved Barry. Liqhtfoot. Smith and Thomas ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE EVANS BARRY QIARViS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CHAVOUS l ’ MASON ROPP i NATHANSdN X indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N,V, A.B. N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER SMITH, JR THOMAS ’ i CERTIFICATION RECORD i S~fetaryto t.e Council Item’on Consent Calendar I I ’ /4 AYE NAY I N.V. ACTION &amp;amp; DAT~ C VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE EVANS ’ BAR’RY JARV[ S "BRAZIL L [..G. HTF00T CHAVOUS ,MASON ~CROPP ’ NATHANSON X indicates ~ote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. I~AY .SMITH JR; THOMAS SR A.Bo Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
