<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-179">
  <num type="law">10-179</num>
  <heading type="short">Professional License Fee Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-09-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-179.pdf">D.C. Law 10-179</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 5210</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0083">
      <narrative>Law 10-179, the “Professional License Fee Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-83, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 21, 1994, and July 5, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 26, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-304 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-179 became effective on September 24, 1994.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag" 103 221 127 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OFFICE OF THE GENERAL COUNSEL WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 TRANSMITTAL OF ENROLLED LEGISLATION Professional License Fee Amendment Act of 1994Short Title: Bill #10-83 Act Date Transmitted to LSD: Received by LSD: Chairman Clarke Codification Counsel cc: cc: RECEIVED JIJL-7 P4:18 (with attachment with attachment) Please notify me of any error/comment within 24 hours. II. Office of the ~tary Date Date III. CLEARANCE OF CORRESPONDENCE BY LSU Letter(s) to the Mayor Date Letter(s) to Congress Rev. 12/22/92 Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D~C. LAW 10-179 "Professional License Fee Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. I0-83 on first and second readings, June 21, 1994 and July 5, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 26, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. I0-304, and published in the August 5, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol.41 page 5210) and transmitted to Congress on August l, 1994 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act, The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D,C, Law I0-179 effective Septembg~ 24, 1994, DAVID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: August 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,26 September 12,13,14,15,16,19,20,21,22,23 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 10-304 DiWlet of Co mbta Code L l| ’ ’ t~L 19,,95 IN THE COUNCIL OF TttE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 26, 1994 To amend the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 to exempt certain attorneys engaged in pro bono and indigent legal services from the professional license requirements. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act [nay be cited as the "Professional License Fee Amendment Act of 1994 Sec. 2. Section la(b) of title XIV of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947, effective September 10, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-145; D.C. Code § 47-1814.1a(b is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the word "and" after the semicolon b) Paragraph (2) is mended to read as follows 2) An attorney who is an inactive member of the District of Columbia bar, a judge, or a retired judge eligible for temporary judicial assignment, who applies for and. is granted an exemption from the license required pursuant to section 1 of this title in accordance with the rules issued by the Mayor pursuant to section 1 of title XVI and who is not otherwise required to obtain a Heense pursuant to subsection (a) of this section; and c) A new paragraph (3) is added to read as follows 3) An attorney who is engaged in the provision of legal services, on a pro bono basis solely or in combination with government service in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection, or an attorney who is engaged in th.e provision of legal services solely as an employee or an affiliate of a nonprofit organization located in the District of Columbia that provides legal services for indigent clients without fee or for a nominal processing fee, who applies for and is granted an exemption from the license required pursuant to section 1 of this title in accordance with the rules issued by the Mayor pursuant to section. 1 of title XVI and. who is not otherwise required to obtain a license pursuant to subsection (a) of this section Section 47-1814. la See. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval, by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, Enrolled Original approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia I~egister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council oI~ the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: July 26, 1994 COL~’NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA C~mcil io:t tern on Consent Cmencla~ AClqGN &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE ecorcea vo~e on ~e~ues[ mOsent: RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOI"E DOCKET NO: Bill 10-83 Adopted First Reading, 6-21-94 Approved Barry, Lightfoot and Smith ACTION &amp;amp; OATE NA,V iNV’"[A.B. Present, not votm vOICE VOTE~ Approved ~ecorOe~ vote On re(3’uest Brazil and Thomas ADsent ROLL CALL VOT RESULT I CHIN,t COUNCILI BARRY MEMBERcLARKEi{iAYE!i NAY i~vli ’;tAB’I COUNCIL Vote I ~’ r" Item on Consem~ Calemctar N.V Present. not vot~nSI CERTIFICATION RECORD ACTION vOiCE vOl"&amp;amp; Recor(:led vote on re¢lue~l Abse ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIl. MEMBER _CHMN. CLARKE BARRy .BRAZ,IL CHAVOUS CROPP AYE NA,Y iN,V A.B. COUNCIL I~EMBER EVANS ’JARV I S L[GHTF~OOT M, ASON 1 ’ NATHANSON x In~iCates Vote A.B CERTIFICATION RECORD Se(:r~al~/to me C’OUNCIL MEMBER RAY NAY N,V. A.B. JR. T!OMAS R. Oa~e AN ACT 10-83 Dl~ct of Co~urnbia Cod Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 to exempt certain attorneys engaged in pro bone and indigent legal services from the professional license requirements. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF TttE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Professional License Fee Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. Section la(b) of title XIV of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947, effective September 10, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-145; D.C. Code § 47-1814.1a(b is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the word "and" after the semicolon b) Paragraph (2) is amended to read as follows 2) An attorney who is an inactive member of the District of Columbia bar, a judge, or a retired judge eligible for temporary judicial assignment, who applies for and is granted an exemption from the license required pursuant to section 1 of this title in accordance with the rules issued by the Mayor pursuant to section 1 of title XVI and .who is not otherwise required to obtain a license pursuant to subsection (a) of this section; and c) A new paragraph (3) is added to read as follows 3) An attorney who is engaged in the provision of legal services, on a pro bone basis solely or in combination with government service in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection, or an attorney who is engaged in the provision of legal services solely as an employee or an affiliate of a nonprofit organization located in the District of Columbia that provides legal services for indigent clients without fee or for a nominal processing fee, who applies for and is granted an exemption from the license required pursuant to section 1. of this title in accordance with the rules issued by the Mayor pursuant to section 1 of title XVI and who is not otherwise required to obtain a license pursuant to subsection (a) of this section Section 47-1814.1a See. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, Enrolled Original approved December 24, 1.973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations hairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia 2 COL~CTL OF TIIE DISTRICT OF COLb~EBI RECORD OF ~F~CIAL C~UNC~L VO CC~ NO: COUNCIL MEMIBEF~ i AYE CHMN SLAR,KE Bill 10-83 BARRY ’BRAZIL CHA,~OJS ’’ i’ OPP ’ Adopted First Reading, 6-21-94 Approved Barry, Lightfoot and Smith I FVANS } RAY APdT I ’, S,~IT JR. ’i THbMAS S’R’ m’" I" ’, ’ MA~O ’ i N6T~ANSON A Abs~t N V mresent. no~ vo~n~ CE~F~CAT~ON mECORD ~IAY Approved Brazil and Thomas (j Da" ’ COUNCI~’~EMBEB kYF EVA’NS. NAY I N,V A.B, JARVIS i I’CIGHf’FOOT I M~ASO’N’ ’ I NATHANSON J X Im~cale vote A ADhere N.V Present, no~ vo~n CERTIFICATIC)N RECORD COUNC;C RAY SMITH JR~ I THOMAS~ SR the Council D~</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
