<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-198">
  <num type="law">10-198</num>
  <heading type="short">Recreation Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-03-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-198.pdf">D.C. Law 10-198</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 10-198, the “Recreation Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-741, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Youth Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 19, 1994, and October 4, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 13, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 10-393 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-198 became effective on March 23, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 221 384 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-198 "Day Care Policy Temporary Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-722 on first and second readings, July 19, 1994 and October 4, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 21, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-335, and published in the November 4, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol.41 page 7172 and transmitted toCongress on January 27, 1995, for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactmen~as D.C. Law 10-198 effective March 14, 1995 i DAVID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. Mar. 27,30,31 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT i0-335 Codific tion Dbtrict of Co!umbia Cods IN THE COUNCIL OF TtIE DISTKICT OF COLUMBIA OCT OBER 1994 To amend, on a temporary basis, the Day Care Policy Act of 1979 to authorize the Mayor to establish differential payment rates for child care services based on the age of the child. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Day Care Policy Temporary Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. The Day Care Policy Act of 1979, effective September 19, 1979 (D.C. Law 3-16; D.C. Code § 3-301 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 10(a)(1 D.C. Code § 3-309(1 is amended by adding a new subparagraph (E) to read as follows E) The Mayor shall, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1204; D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq issue rules to establish differentiated payment rates for child development centers that reflect variations in the costs of providing services to children of different age groups b) Section ll(a D.C. Code § 3-310) is amended by adding a new subsection (a-l) to read as follows a-l) The Mayor shall, pursuant to title 1 o[ the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq issue rules to establish differentiated payment rates for child development homes and in-home caregivers that reflect variations in the costs of providing services to children of different age groups Sec. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Note, Section 3-309 Note, Section 3-310 ENROLLED ORIGINJkL (b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 21, 1994 2 COLqWCIL OF TIlE DISTRICT OF COLb~IBI~ Council Period Ten RECORD OF OFRCIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO Item on Consent Calendar ACT;ON &amp;amp; DATE E VOICE VOTE ecordea vote on ;eauest ADsent: Z ROLL CALL VOTE R~SULT I COUNCIL X indicates VOte Item on Consen! C~en(:lar ,3~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE vOICE VOTE ~ecoraea vote. on reauest ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE J NAY NV A.B.C.OU NCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP X Indicates Vote Item on Con~nt Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; OAT VOICE VOTE: RecorOe¢l vote on re&amp;lt;luest Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY I N,V. A.B. C~iMN ’. CLARKE BARRY i BRAZIL ,CHAVOUS CR, QpP I X InOicates Vote BI0-722 Adopted First Reading, 7-19-94 Approved Barry and Evans COUNCIL MEMBER SON A.B Absent N.V Present. not votzn~ CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBEF~ AYE NAY N V t.I,&amp;lt I; 7 /¯ D ate Adopted Final Reading, I0-4-94 Approved Barry, Brazil, Chavous, Evans, Jarvis and Ray COUNCILMEMB~REVAN£ AYE NAY iN.V.A.8, iCOUNCILMEMBERRA&amp;amp AR I i S~ITH~ JR LIGHTFOOT I THOM~S~ j MASQN I’NATHANSON I A.S Absent N.V Present, not vo~n~ CERTIFtCATICN RECORD Date COUNCILMEMBER AYE NAY N.V, A.B. COUNCILMEMBER AYEINAY[.N.V EVANS. RAY JARVlS ~MITH~ JR. L.!GHTFOOT THOMAS, SR. MASON ~ATHAN$’QN A.B Absem N.V Presem. n~ vo~ CERTIFICATION RECORD SecretaW to tt~e Councd Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
