<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-149">
  <num type="law">10-149</num>
  <heading type="short">Hacker’s License Requirements Amendment Act of 1984 Temporary Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-08-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-149.pdf">D.C. Law 10-149</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 4485</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0646">
      <narrative>Law 10-149, the “Hacker’s License Requirements Amendment Act of 1984 Temporary Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-646. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 3, 1994, and June 7, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 23, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-262 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-149 became effective on August 17, 1994.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LMENT(S) kwiktag~ 103 221 684 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D~C. LAW 10-149 "Hacker’s License Requirements Amendment Act of 1984 Temporary Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. I0-646 on first and second readings, May 3, 1994, and June 7, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 23, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. I0-262, and published in the July 8, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol.41 page 4485) and transmitted to Congress on June 27, 1994 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law I0-149 effective August 17, 1994~ Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Oune July August 27,28,29,30 12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,25,26,27,28,29 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,II,12,15,16 Enrolled Original AN ACT ~o~i~t~Ion D. C. 10-262 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 23, 1994 To amend, on a temporary basis, An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the I~ist { o£ Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes, to increase the hacker’s license training course from a 12- to a 24-hour course, to increase the fee from $25 to a fee of not less than $100 per person, and to direct the University of the District of Columbia to resume teaching this course by July 1, 1994. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Hacker’s License l~equirements Amendment Act of 1984 Temporary Amendment Act of 1994" Sec. 2. Paragraph 11 of section 7 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes, approved July 1, 1902 (32 Star. 626; D.C. Code § 47-2829(e)(2)(A is amended as follows a) By striking the first 3 sentences and inserting the following Completion of the hacker’s license training course consisting of not less than 24-hours administered by any person authorized by the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission for a fee of not less than $100 for each applicant. Upon completion of the course, a certificate of completion shall be issued to include the date of completion and shall be presented to the Office of Taxicabs with the application for a license. Prior to issuing the certificate, each applicant shall pass a test consisting of the subject matters taught in the course and in evaluation of the applicant’s English communication skills. The certificate of completion shall be issued only when an applicant has attended every session of the 24-hour course Scion 47-2829 Sec. 3. The University of the District of Columbia shall resume teaching the hacker’s license training course by July 1, 1994. Sec. 4 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section. 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental I~eorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 Enrolled Original and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect or upon the effective date of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985 end~ Act of 1994, whichever occurs first. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: June 23, 1994 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: RecorQeo vote on request Absent: COUNCIL OF T~E DISTRICT OF COLLEMBL~ Council Period Ten RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: BI0-646 Adopted First Reading, 5-3-94 Approved Barry, Chavous, Jarvis, Thomas and Brazil ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE CHHN CLARKE i IJARVT~BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP x Indicates Vote A.8 Absent INAY N.V. i A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER I AYE 1 RAY I I I SMITH JR. ’ I I i THOMAS~ SR N.V Present. not voting Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted F:h’~l Reading, 6 94 Date~ VOICE VOTE proved Recorded vote on reduesI Absent: ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT CO~ClLMEMBER AYE NAYIN.V.A.B. CHMN LARKEIi BARRY BRAZIl CHAVOUS CR~PP X Indicates Vote Item on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.8. FV#N~ LIGHTFOOT MASON A.8 Absent N.V Present. not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE I NAY N.V. A.B. RAY S,M.ITH~ JR. I I THOMAS. SR. I I Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE ’_ vOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL .CHAVOUS -CROPP AYE NAY I N.V. A.8. 1 X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER EVANS JARVIS LIGHTF00T MASON ~ATHANSON A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present. not voan(:j CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE RAY SMITH. JR. THOMAS~ SR NAY N.V. Secretary/to tl~e Councd Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
