<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-201">
  <num type="law">10-201</num>
  <heading type="short">Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1995-03-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-201.pdf">D.C. Law 10-201</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 7178</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 10-201, the “Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-658, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and the Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 5, 1994, and October 4, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 21, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-338 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-201 became effective on March 14, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 221 166 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-201 "Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-658 on first and second readings, July 5, 1994 and October 4, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 21, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-338, and published in the November 4, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol.41 page 7178 and transmitted to Congress on January 27, 1995, for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law10-201effective March14,1995 Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Jan. 27,30,31 Feb. 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 Mar. 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT Codifleatio~ D,C. ACT i0- 338 District of Co, umbia Code C !9 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 21, 1994 To amend the Alternative Fuels Technology Act of 1990 and title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal l~egulations to conform District law and regulations to the requirements of title II of the Clean Air Act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. The Alternative Fuels Technology Act of 1990, effective March 8, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-243; D.C. Code § 40-2001 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 40-2001) is amended by adding a new subsection (d} to read as follows d) Section 246 of the Clean Air Act requires that the District develop a state implementation plan revision that manages harmful emissions from motor vehicles by establishing a clean fuel fleet program that is consistent with federal law and regulations. As part of a multi-jurisdiction ozone nonattainment area encompassing portions of the District and the states of Maryland and Virginia, the District must implement a clean fuel fleet program b) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 40-2002) is amended to read as follows See. 3. Definitions For the purpose of this act, the term 1 Alternative fuel" means methanol, ethanol, or other alcohols (including any mixture of gasoline or other fuels containing 85~o or more by volume of alcohol natural gas, liquefied petroleum gas, propane, or electricity 2 Alternative-fuel vehicle" means a dedicated, flexible-fueled, bi-fueled, or dual-fueled vehicle that operates on an alternative fuel 3 Bi-fuel vehicle" means a motor vehicle that is equipped to operate on either a clean-burning alternative fuel or a conventional fuel, including gasoline or diesel fuel. Section 40-2001 Section 40-2002 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4 Capable of being centrally fueled" means a fleet, or that part of a fleet, consisting of vehicles that can be refueled 1004 of the time at a location that is owned, operated, or controlled by the covered fleet operator, or is under contract with the covered fleet operator 5 Centrally fueled" means a fleet, or that part of a fleet, consisting of vehicles that are fueled 1004 of the time at a location that is owned, operated, or controlled by the covered fleet operator or is under contract with the covered fleet operator, including any vehicle that under normal operations is garaged at a personal residence at night, but that is centrally fueled 1004 of the time 6 Clean Air Act" means the Clean Air Act, approved December 17, 1963 (77 Star. 392; 42 U.S.C. 7401 e~ seq as amended 7 Clean fuel" means any fuel, including methanol, ethanol, or other alcohols (including any mixture thereof containing 854 or more by volume of alcohol with gasoline or other fuel reformulated gasoline, diesel, natural gas, liquefied petroleum gas, hydrogen, or power source (including electricity) used in a clean-fuel vehicle that complies with standards and requirements applicable to such vehicle when using such fuel or power source 8 Clean-fuel fleet vehicle" or "CFFV" means a clean-fuel vehicle operated by a covered fleet operator 9 Clean-fuel vehicle" means a motor vehicle which has been certified to meet, for any mode] year, a set of emission standards that classifies it as a clean-fuel vehicle, in accordance with this act 10 Contract fueling" means that a fleet vehicle is required to be refueled at a service station or other facility with which the fleet operator has entered into a contract for such refueling purposes. Commercial fleet service cards which are provided to fleet operators by any leasing or vehicle management company do not constitute contract fueling 11 Converted vehicle" means a conventionally fueled vehicle that is converted to operate on a clean fuel in accordance with federal regulations and meets the emission standards set forth for that class of clean-fuel vehicle 12 Covered area" means any part of the District that is included in an ozone nonattainment area classified under subpart 2 of part D of title I of the Clean Air Act as serious, severe, or extreme based on data for the calendar years 1987, 1988, and 1989 13 Covered fleet" means any fleet of 10 or more covered fleet vehicles owned, operated, leased, used, maintained, or otherwise controlled by a person. The term "covered fleet" does not include motor vehicles exempt under section 5 14 Covered fleet operator" means a person who operates a fleet of at least 10 covered fleet vehicles that is operated in the covered area 15 Covered fleet vehicle" means any motor vehicle which is in a vehicle class for which emission standards are applicable under section 8 and in a covered fleet which is centrally fueled or capable of being centrally fueled. The term "covered fleet vehicle" does not include motor vehicles exempt under section 5 16 Credit" means a credit for the acquisition of a clean-fuel vehicle pursuant to section 246(f) of the Clean Air Act. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 17 Dedicated vehicle" means a vehicle that operates solely on a clean alternative fuel 1(18) 11Dual-fuel vehicle" means a motor vehicle that operates on 2 fuel sources 19 IEmergency vehicleI~ means any vehicle that is legally authorized by a governmental authority to exceed the speed limit to transport people and equipment to and from situations in which speed is required to save lives or property, including a rescue vehicle, fire truck, or ambulance. 11(20 ’ederal fleet" means any fleet owned or operated by the United States government. 11(21} 11~’lexible-fueled vehicle" means a vehicle that is capable of operating on either or any combination of 2 fuels 22 l~uel provider" means any person that provides fuel to a covered fleet. 1I(23 Garaged under normal operations at a personal residenceI~ means a vehicle that, when it is not in use, is normally parked at the personal residence of the individual who usually operates it, rather than at a central refueling, maintenance, or business location. These vehicles are not considered to be capable of being centrally fueled and are exempt from the program unless they are, in fact, centrally fueled 1004 of the time. 11(24 lHeavy duty vehicle" or 11HDV" means a vehicle weighing more than 8,501 pounds GVWIL but less than 26,000 pounds GVWtL. 11(25 High-Occupancy Vehicle lanes1I means transportation control measures which restrict a vehicle’s access to certain roadway lanes based on the number of occupants in the vehicle. I~(26 IInherently low-emission vehicle" or I~ILEV" means any light-duty motor vehicle, light-duty truck, or heavy-duty vehicle that is certified as a low-emission vehicle pursuant to emission standards promulgated by the Environmental Protection Agency. I~(27 Law enforcement vehicle~ means any vehicle that is primarily operated by a civilian or military police officer or sheriff, enforcement agency of the federal government, state highway patrols, municipal law enforcement, or other similar law enforcement agency, and that is used for the purpose of law enforcement activities, including chase, apprehension, surveillance, or patrol of people engaged in, or potentially engaged in, unlawful activities. 11(28 Light duty truck" or "LDT’ means a truck weighing 8,500 pounds GVWtL or less. 11(29 Light duty vehicle" or "LDV" means a vehicle weighing 8,500 pounds GVWtL or less 30) 11Location11 means any building, structure, facility, or installation, that is owned or operated by a person, or is under the control of a person, located on 1 or more contiguous properties, and contains, or could contain, a fueling pump or pumps for the use of the vehicles owned or controlled by that person. The term "location" includes all of the facilities of the fleet operator in a single covered area, in their entirety. The term "location~ is not meant to be interpreted narrowly, such as a single refueling pump 31 Low-emission vehicle" or ’LEV~ means a vehicle that meets the LEV emission standards promulgated under the Clean Air Act. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 32 Model Year" means the period between September 1 and August 31 of the preceeding calendar year 33 Motor vehicle" means any motor vehicle, as defined in section l(a) of title IV of the District of Columbia l~evenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Star. 679; D.C. Code § 40-101(1 34 Nonroad vehicle" means a vehicle that is powered by a nonroad engine and that is not a motor vehicle, or a vehicle used solely for competition 35 Partially covered fleet" means any fleet that contains 10 or more covered fleet vehicles, but also contains exempt vehicles including law enforcement and emergency vehicles 36 Person" means an individual, partnership, corporation, association, or any agency, instrumentality, or department of any government 37 Purchase" or "acquisition" includes a lease 38 Qualified second market vehicle" means a vehicle that A) Has been in use for at least 18 months, but not more than 36 months B) Has 50% or more of its useful life remaining C) Is owned or operated by a private covered fleet operator that operates fleets in the District; or D) Is a ULEV, ILEV or ZEV 39 Ultra low-emission vehicle" or "ULEV" means a vehicle that is certified as meeting the ULEV emission standards promulgated under the Clean Air Act 40 Zero-emission vehicle" or "ZEV" means a vehicle that is certified as meeting the ZEV emission standards promulgated under the Clean Air Act c) Section 4(a) and (b D.C. Code § 40-2003(a) and (b is amended to read as follows a)(1) Pursuant to rules issued by the Mayor pursuant to section 6, operators of all covered fleets shall register with the Mayor within 120 days after the effective date of the rules. In the case of fleets which become covered fleets after the effective date of the rules, the fleet operator shall register with the Mayor within 90 days of becoming a covered fleet 2) Accurate records shall be maintained by covered fleet operators to verify compliance with this act. All records shall be maintained for the current model year and the previous model year. For purposes of enforcement of this act, officers and employees of the District, duly designated by the Mayor as inspectors, shall be authorized to inspect the records of a covered fleet operator. All records provided by covered fleet operators shall be treated as confidential and proprietary trade secrets b)(1) Of the new covered fleet vehicles purchased each year by a covered fleet operator in Model Year 1998 and thereafter, at least a specified percentage of the vehicles shall be clean-fuel vehicles as provided in this subsection. These vehicles shall use a clean fuel when operating in the covered area 2) Clean-fuel vehicles shall be purchased according to the following percentages in Model Year 1998: Section 40-2003 ENROLLED ORIGINAL A) 30% of light duty vehicles LDVs and light duty trucks LDTs under 6,000 pounds gross vehicle weight rating (GVWK B) 30% of LDTs between 6,000 pounds and 8,500 pounds GVWK; and C) 50% of heavy duty vehicles HDVs over 8,500 pounds and less than 26,000 pounds GVWR 3) Clean-fuel vehicles shall be purchased according to the following percentages in Model Year 1999 A) 50% of LDTs and LDVs less than 6,000 pounds GVWK B) 50% of LDTs and LDVs between 6,000 pounds and 8,500 pounds GVWR; and C) 50% of HDVs more than 8,500 pounds and less than 26,000 pounds GVWP 4) Clean-fuel vehicles shall be purchased according to the following percentages in Model Year 2000 and every Model Year thereafter A) 70% of LDTs and LDVs less than 6,000 pounds GVWK B) 70% of LDTs and LDVs between 6,000 pounds and 8,500 pounds GVWI and C) 50% of HDVs more than 8,500 pounds and less than 26,000 pounds GVW] d) Section 5 (D.C. Code § 40-2004) is amended to read as follows Sec. 5. Exemptions a) Except as otherwise provided in this act, the following vehicles are exempt from the purchase requirements contained in this act 1) Any vehicle more than 26,000 pounds GVWI 2) Emergency or law enforcement vehicles 3) Nonroad vehicles, including farm and construction vehicles 4) Vehicles in fleets operating in the covered area with fewer than 10 vehicles 5) Vehicles in a covered fleet not capable of being centrally fueled 6) Vehicles which are garaged under normal operations at a personal residence 7) Vehicles leased or rented to the general public 8) New car demonstration vehicles; and 9) Vehicles used for product demonstrations and tests b) The fact that 1 or more vehicles in a fleet is not centrally fueled does not exempt an entire fleet from the purchase requirements contained in this act e) A new section 5a is added to read as follows Sec. 5a. The Mayor, on or before March 1 of each year, shall submit to the Council a report detailing the following a) The total number of alternative-fuel vehicles purchased by the District in the previous fiscal year, by agency b) The total number of alternative-fuel vehicles owned by the District, by agency c) The total number of vehicles owned by the District, by agency; Section 40-2004 New, Section 40-2004.1 |ttlIOLLED OI iGINkL d) The percentage of alternative-fuel vehicles, by agency e) A plan to purchase additional alternative-fuel vehicles in the upcoming fiscal year and subsequent fiscal years; and f) A plan to comply with the purchase requirements mandated by this act f) Section 6 (D.C. Code § 40-2005) is amended to read as follows Sec. 6. l~ules The Mayor shall, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1204; D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq issue rules to implement the provisions of this act g) New sections 8 through 16 are added to read as follows Sec. 8. Emission standards a) Any clean-fuel vehicle purchased pursuant to the requirements of this act shall meet the emission standard for its respective vehicle class and category as contained in sections 243-245 of the Clean Air Act and regulations promulgated under these sections by the Environmental Protection Agency b) Clean-fuel vehicle emission standards may only be amended by the Mayor to the extent necessary to conform with revisions promulgated after the enactment of the Clean Air Act by the Environmental Protection Agency Sec. 9. Vehicle conversions a) The requirements of this act may be met through conversion of existing or new gasoline or diesel-powered vehicles to clean-fuel vehicles which comply with the applicable requirements of this act. For purposes of such provisions, the conversion of a vehicle to a clean-fuel vehicle shall be treated as a purchase. Nothing in this act shall be construed to provide that any covered fleet operator subject to the requirements of this act shall be required to convert existing or new gasoline or diesel-powered vehicles to clean-fuel vehicles or to purchase converted vehicles b) Manufacturers of conversion kits, as well as installers, shall, on request of any fleet operator, the District, or the EPA, demonstrate that vehicles converted to clean-fuel vehicles have a configuration that complies with the emission standards contained in the Clean Air Act, any regulations promulgated by the Environmental Protection Agency, and any regulations promulgated by the Mayor in accordance with this act Sec. 10. Fuel provider requirements Pursuant to section 246(e) of the Clean Air Act, fuel providers shall make clean fuels available to covered fleet operators at locations at which covered fleet vehicles are fueled Sec. 11. Choice of fuels The choice of clean-fuel vehicles and clean fuels shall be made by the covered fleet operators subject to the requirements of this act Sec. 12. Labeling The Mayor shall issue regulations establishing labeling requirements for clean-fuel vehicles operated by fleets in the covered area Sec. 13. Civil penalty a) Each person who fails to comply with any of the provisions of this act, prevents any inspection authorized by this act, or keeps false records shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $5,000. Section 40-2005 New, Section 40-2007 New, Section 40-2008 New, Section 40-2009 New, Section 40-2010 Note~ Section 40-2007 New~ Section 40-20~ 6 ENROLLED ORIGINAL b) Each violation of, or failure to comply with, this act shall constitute a separate offense and the penalties described in subsection (a) of this section shall be applicable to each separate offense See. 14. Emission credit trading program a) Covered fleet operators may meet the fleet vehicle purchase requirements of this act by purchasing clean-fuel vehicles, whether new, used, or converted vehicles, converting existing gasoline or diesel-powered vehicles to clean-fuel vehicles, or by trading and banking clean-fuel fleet vehicle credits b) Clean-fuel fleet vehicle credits may be earned by a covered fleet operator for any of the following qualifying purchases 1) Purchase of a clean-fuel vehicle during any period after March 1, 1993, but before September I, 1997, if the purchase meets all other clean-fuel fleet vehicle requirements applicable to such purchase, including the requirement to use only the fuel on which the vehicle was certified 2) Purchase of a greater number of clean-fuel fleet vehicles than is required under this act 3) Purchase of a clean-fuel fleet vehicle that meets more stringent emission standards than required under this act (ULEVs, ZEVs and ILEVs 4) Purchase of a clean-fuel fleet vehicle in an exempt vehicle category by the operator of a covered or partially-covered fleet; or 5) Purchase of a clean-fuel fleet vehicle by a fleet operator who voluntarily opts-in to the clean fuel fleet program, and who thereafter shall be subject to the requirements of this act as if the operator were a covered fleet operator c) The Mayor shall, to determine the feasibility of providing the trading of credits between mobile and stationary sources and between jurisdictions within the same nonattainment area or the District, study and promulgate a report within 2 years after the enacement of the Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994 Sec. 15. Operational incentives for clean-fuel fleets a) Clean-fuel vehicles operated by covered fleet operators shall be exempt from measures which restrict vehicle usage based primarily on temporal considerations, such as time-of-day and day-of-week restrictions and commercial vehicle bans. This exemption does not include access to High-Occupancy Vehicle lanes, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section b) A fleet vehicle which has been certified by the Environmental Protection Agency as an ILEV, is operated by a covered fleet, and continues to be in compliance with applicable ILEV emission standards shall be exempt from High-Occupancy Vehicle lane restrictions c) The Mayor may issue any regulations the Mayor considers necessary for implementing the exemptions provided for in this section within 45 days after the effective date of the Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994. The exemptions shall be available to covered fleet vehicles upon the adoption of such regulations Sec. 16. Financial and operational incentives for use of alternative fuels. New, Section .40-2012 New, Section 40-2013 New, Sectioz 40-2014 ENROLLED ORIGINAL a) Not later than 180 days after the effective date of the Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994, the Mayor, where feasible, shall submit to the Council proposed legislation, regulations, or a combination thereof, that provides for financial and operational incentives for the commercial fleet use of alternative fuels b) Where feasible, as determined by the Mayor, the proposal shall include the following 1) Income tax credits for alternative fuels vehicles and certain fueling property that A) Are based on section 179A of the United States Internal Revenue Code; and B) Are comparable to similar credits allowed by 1 or more states adjacent to the District 2) A motor fuel tax exception for alternative fuel vehicles that is comparable to similar credits allowed by 1 or more states adjacent to the District 3) Preferential parking or loading use on District owned parking lots and curbside parking spaces (to be known as "green curb parking and loading areas for covered fleet using alternative fuels 4) Requirements that the District purchase qualified second market vehicles to help establish a long term viable market for alternative fuel vehicles; and 5) The creation of a fund by the District to ensure competitive resale values of used alternative fuel vehicles, the funds for which would derive from gifts and other contributions c) The incentives shall be structured and administered so as to qualify for recognition by the EPA for air quality standards attainment purposes. Sec. 3. Chapter 9 of title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (Environment) is amended as follows a} New sections 905 through 914 are added to read as follows 905 FLEET REGISTRATION AND RECORDKEEPING "905.1 Operators of all covered fleets shall register with the Mayor within one hundred twenty (120) days after the effective date of Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994. l~leets which become covered fleets after this effective date because of an increase in fleet size or central fueling capabilities shall register with the Mayor within ninety (90) days of becoming a covered fleet 905.2 Covered fleets shall register on a form to be prescribed by the Mayor, which shall require the following information: name of fleet operator, address of fleet operator, number of fleet vehicles 905.3 Accurate records must be maintained by covered fleets to verify compliance with this chapter. All records shall be maintained for the current model year plus the previous model year. For purposes of enforcement of this chapter, officers or employees duly designated by the Mayor, upon presenting appropriate credentials, are authorized to inspect such records of a covered fleet operator. All records provided by covered fleets to the Mayor or the Mayor’s designee shall be treated as confidential and proprietary trade secrets 905.4 The records that must be maintained by covered fleet operators as provided in subsection 905.3 shall be limited to: 8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL a) The number of clean-fuel vehicles acquired for the applicable model years b) The make, model, weight classification, and fuel type of each fleet vehicle acquired pursuant to this chapter c) The type of clean-fuel vehicle (i.e dedicated, flexible-fueled, bi-fueled, dual-fueled, original equipment manufacturer, converted d) The vehicle identification number; and e) Purchase records or clean fuel purchases on a monthly basis 906 CLEAN FUEL FLEET VEHICLE ACQUISITION REQUIREMENTS "906.1 Of the new covered fleet vehicles purchased each pear by a covered fleet operator beginning in Model Year 1998 and thereafter, at least a specified percentage of such vehicles shall be clean-fuel vehicles, as provided in this section. Such vehicles shall operate on clean fuels when operating in the covered area. The required new vehicle purchase percentages for each vehicle type shall be those set forth in table 906.1 DVo L~d ~D2’o ~de 000 1~o Ill l I I b~he o o O,S 2bo i I ii ~Vs ~e: 8,S00 ~e ~d ~lov 3i,OOO 1be II i i i SOt SOt 30t SOt S0~ 14C:)DT Ot $04 ¯ ENROLLED ORIGINAL "906.2 Any clean-fuel vehicle purchased pursuant to the requirements of subsection 906.1 of this chapter shall meet the emission standard for its respective vehicle class and category as contained in subsection 906.3 and as may be amended by the Mayor to the extent necessary to conform with revised emission standards promulgated after the date of enactment of the Clean Air Act by the Environmental Protection Agency 906.3 Emission tables: CO, g/mL 3.4 4.4 3.4 ]’;S 0 S?|O LW &amp;amp;S’ISO .LDT SO00 s, ST|O TW 0.3,1 0.3,~S 4.4 I.O 0 1.3, 7O ENROLl.Eli "ORIGINAL DT~6000 LDT ~6000 LDT ~000 "’LDT ss~so 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 TABI,,E ~O6.S I ~C NOx I e I:~||ZO~| t,y~ I z.s I I I~|~XO~| W I s W II II ¯ i/z llX~l I o.o W o.o f I 11 £NROLLED ORiGJHAL "906.4 The clean-fuel vehicle purchase requirements applicable to covered fleet operators under this chapter may be satisfied by: ’~(a) Converting existing vehicles to clean-fuel vehicles b) Purchasing new vehicles which shall be converted to clean-fuel vehicles c) Purchasing Original Equipment Manufacturer clean-fuel vehicles; or d) Acquiring credits under section 912 of this chapter 906.5 A covered fleet operator may satisfy the purchase requirements of this section by acquiring dual-fueled, bi-fueled, or flexible-fueled vehicles as long as the operator can demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Mayor that such vehicles are only operated on the clean fuel within the covered area 906.6 Federal fleets shall use, to the extent possible, only Original Equipment Manufacturer vehicles in complying with the purchase requirements of this chapter 907 VEHICLE CONVERSIONS "907.1 Covered fleet operators shall ensure that converted vehicles, conversion kits, and conversion installations shall conform to the requirements of the Environmental Protection Agency for vehicle conversions as found in 40 CFR parts 86 and 88 907.2 A vehicle converted to a clean-fuel vehicle shall be eligible to generate credits only if the conversion kit installer provides the covered fleet operator a clean-fuel vehicle certificate of conformity issued by EPA 907.3 No person shall convert a gasoline or diesel-powered vehicle to a clean-fuel vehicle unless such conversion complies with the rules for conversions as promulgated in this chapter and pursuant to section 247 of the Clean Air Act and regulations promulgated by the Environmental Protection Agency under section 247. Any person performing conversions that do not comply with this chapter, section 247, or regulations promulgated pursuant to section 247, will be considered in violation of federal anti-tampering laws and subject to the penalties provided in the Clean Air Act 907.4 Any person who converts a vehicle to a clean-fuel vehicle shall issue a vehicle or engine warranty for any such conversion done by that person. The warranty and the warranty period shall meet the specifications stated in section 207(i) of the Clean Air Act 907.5 The person who converts a vehicle to a clean-fuel vehicle is responsible for the recall and repair of such vehicles, as specified in section 207 of the Clean Air Act, if at any time there is found to be an inherent or developed problem associated with such conversion or installation 908 EXEMPTIONS "908.1 The following vehicles are exempt from the purchase requirements contained in this chapter a) Any vehicle greater than 26,000 pounds GVWP b) Emergency or law enforcement vehicles c) Nonroad vehicles (farm and construction vehicles d) Vehicles in fleets operating in the covered area with fewer than 10 vehicles e) Vehicles in a covered fleet not capable of being centrally fueled f) Vehicles which are garaged under normal operations at a personal residence g) Vehicles leased or rented to the general public h) New car demonstration vehicles; and i) Vehicles used for product demonstrations and tests 909 VEHICLE LABELING AND IDENTIFICATION I~EQUII~EMENTS "909.1 The Mayor shall issue a clean fuel identification sticker to any vehicle that meets the clean-fuel vehicle emission standards contained in subsection 906.3 of this chapter that has passed inspection in the District 909.2 The clean-fuel vehicle identification sticker is void if removed 909.3 The Mayor shall issue an alternative fuel identification sticker to any clean-fuel vehicle that is powered by an alternative fuel and has passed inspection in the District 909.4 The alternative fuel identification sticker is void if removed 910 FUEL AVAILABILITY REQUIREMENT "910.1 Fuel providers shall make clean fuels available to covered fleet operators at locations at which covered fleet vehicles are fueled 911 FUEL CHOICE "911.1 The choice of clean-fuel vehicles and clean fuels shall be made by the covered fleet operators subject to the requirements of this chapter 912 CREDIT PROGRAM IMPLEMENTATION "912.1 Credits will only be generated when a covered fleet operator acquires above and beyond the required amount and type of vehicles for compliance with the purchase requirements contained in subsection 906.1 of this chapter 912.2 Credits can be generated by a covered fleet operator in the covered area if the vehicles acquired meet all of the requirements of this chapter 912.3 Credits may be used by covered fleets as substitutes for vehicle acquisitions to meet the acquisition requirements 912.4 Conversions to clean-fuel vehicles shall earn credits in the same manner as other acquired vehicles 912.5 Covered fleet operators will meet the fleet vehicle purchase requirements of this act by purchasing clean-fuel vehicles, whether a new, used, or converted vehicle, or by trading and banking clean-fuel fleet vehicle credits for vehicle purchases 912.6 All credit-generating vehicles must meet the applicable emission standards and other requirements contained in section 906 of this chapter 912.7 While in a covered area, a dual-fuel, bi-fuel, or flexible-fuel vehicle purchased by a fleet operator to comply with fleet purchase requirements must be operated at all times on the fuel or fuels on which it was certified as a clean-fuel fleet vehicle. If the fleet operator receives credit for a dual-fuel, bi-fuel, or flexible-fuel vehicle purchase, the vehicle must operate at the same emission level for which the vehicle generated clean-fuel fleet credit 912.8 All covered fleets are eligible to generate credits. ENROLLED ORIGINAL "912.9 Credits may be traded or sold for use in the covered area 912.10 Trading of credits among all subclasses of LDVs and LDTs is permitted. Credit trading is not allowed between the LDT/LDV classes and HDV classes 912.11 Clean-fuel fleet vehicle credits may be earned by a covered fleet operator for any of the following qualifying purchases a) Purchase of a clean-fuel vehicle during any period subsequent to July 15, 1994, but prior to September 1, 1997, if the purchase meets all other clean-fuel fleet vehicle requirements applicable to such purchase, including the statutory requirement to use only the fuel on which the vehicle was certified b) Purchase of a greater number of clean-fuel fleet vehicles than is required under this chapter c) Purchase of a clean-fuel fleet vehicle that meets more stringent emission standards than required under this chapter (ULEVs, ZEVs, and ILEVs d) Purchase of a clean-fuel fleet vehicle in an exempt vehicle category by the operator of a covered or partially-covered fleet; or el Purchase of a clean-fuel fleet vehicle by a noncovered fleet operator 912.12 For LDVs and LDTs, credit values shall be determined in accordance with tables 912.1, 912.2, and 912.3 912.13 For HDVs, credit values shall be determined in accordance with tables 912.4, 912.5, and 912.6 912.14 Credit values shall be calculated to two decimal places 912.15 Credits shall be designated as follows a) Credits generated by the purchase of a qualifying clean-fuel fleet LDV or LDT shall be designated at the time of issuance as light-duty clean-fuel fleet vehicle credits b) Credits generated by the purchase of a qualifying clean-fuel fleet HDV shall be designated at the time of issuance as heavy-duty clean-fuel fleet vehicle credits; and c} Credits generated by the purchase of light heavy-duty or a medium heavy-duty qualifying clean-fuel fleet vehicle shall be designated at the time of issuance as light heavy-duty or medium heavy-duty credits, respectively. ENROLLED ORIGINAL "912.16 Credits tables: TABLE 913.1 LIGHT DUTY VEHICLE CREDIT GENERATION~ MORE amp;(O00 G 00 S3";SO .NOx LVW III 1.00 I 1.=0 I 1.43~ GVI WHR ss?so ~s?so 5 1.S4 1.00 1.03 1.43 1.29 1.47 1.93 2.23 TAELE 112.2 LIGHT DUTY VEHICLE CREDIT GENERATION: 1~000 GVk~ lU40G 137S0 ¯ I~5 LVW I 0.00 i 30 I i DT S.6000 Z,DT )S000 Z,DT s, S000 Z,D? s, i000 ;vlrA s?so ss?so 55( 0.00 0.00 .S7 .71 I I III|I 0.00 0.00 I ¯ ENROLLED ORJGJNAL "912.17 All credits generated in accordance with this regulation may be freely traded or banked for later use, subject to the provisions contained in this chapter, without discount or depreciation 912.18 Duplication of credit vouchers by anyone other than the Mayor is prohibited 912.19 Once a credit voucher is sold or traded, the holder of the sold or traded voucher must return it to the administrative authority. A new voucher will then be issued to the individual or company who received the sold or traded credit voucher 912.20 A covered fleet operator desiring to demonstrate full or partial compliance with covered fleet purchase requirements by the redemption of credits shall surrender sufficient credits as established in this section. In lieu of purchasing a clean-fuel fleet vehicle, a fleet operator shall surrender credits equal to the credit calculation method used in that area from the tables found in this section 912.21 Credits earned within the boundaries of the covered area may be traded within those boundaries whether or not that area encompasses parts of more than one state 912.22 Credits earned within the boundaries of an attainment area may not be used to show compliance for a covered fleet operator in a nonattainment area 912.23 Credits generated by the purchase of LDVs and LDTs of 8,500 pounds GVWI~ or less may be used to demonstrate compliance with covered fleet purchase requirements applicable to LDVs or LDTs of 8,500 pounds GVWl~ or less 912.24 Credits generated by the purchase of vehicles of more than 8,500 pounds GVWR may not be used to demonstrate compliance with requirements for vehicles weighing 8,500 pounds GVWR or less 912.25 Credits generated by the purchase of vehicles of 8,500 pounds GVWR or less may not be used to demonstrate compliance with requirements for vehicles weighing more than 8,500 pounds GV~ql 912.26 Credits generated by the purchase of a HDV of a particular weight subclass may be used to demonstrate compliance with required heavy-duty vehicle purchases for the same or lighter weight subclasses. These credits may not be used to demonstrate compliance with required HDV purchases for vehicles of heavier weight subclasses than the weight subclass of the vehicle that generated the credits. r’913 TRANSPORTATION CONTROL MEASUI~E EXEMPTIONS "913.1 Clean-fuel vehicles operated by covered fleets shall be exempt from measures which restrict vehicle usage based primarily on temporal considerations, such as time-of-day and day-of-week restrictions and commercial vehicle bans. This exemption does not include access to High-Occupancy Vehicle lanes, except as provided in subsection 913.2 of this section 913.2 A fleet vehicle which has been certified by the Environmental Protection Agency as an ILEV, is operated by a covered fleet, and continues to be in compliance with applicable ILEV emission standards shall be exempt from High-Occupancy Vehicle lanes. This exemption shall not apply if, by regulation, it is determined that it would create a clear and direct safety hazard 913.3 The exemptions provided under this section shall be available to covered fleet vehicles upon the adoption of these regulations. ENROLLED ORIGINAL "913.4 Transportation control measure exemptions are subject to the following conditions a) The exemptions shall not be effective outside of the covered area b) The exemptions shall not be transferable among vehicles in the same fleet; and c) Covered fleet operators may not buy, sell, or trade such exemptions 913.5 The transportation control measure exemptions provided to covered fleet vehicles under this section shall remain in effect only if the subject vehicle is in compliance with the clean-fuel vehicle emission standards contained in this chapter 914 FINES AND PENALTIES "914.1 Each person who fails to comply with any of the provisions of this chapter, prevents any inspection authorized by this chapter, or keeps inaccurate records shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $5,000 914.2 Each violation of, or failure to comply with, this chapter shall constitute a separate offense and the penalties described in subsection 914.1 shall be applicable to each separate offense b) Section 999 is amended to read as follows 999 DEFINITIONS AND ABBREVIATIONS "999.1 When used in this chapter, and in forms prescribed under this chapter, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed Alternative fuel" means methanol, ethanol, or other alcohols (including any mixture of gasoline or other fuels containing 85% or more by volume of alcohol natural gas, liquefied petroleum gas, propane, or electricity Alternative-fuel vehicle" means a dedicated, flexible-fueled, bi-fueled, or dual-fueled vehicle that operates on an alternative fuel Bi-fuel vehicle" means a motor vehicle that is equipped to operate on either a clean-burning alternative fuel or a conventional fuel, including gasoline or diesel fuel Capable of being centrally fueled" means a fleet, or that part of a fleet, consisting of vehicles that can be refueled 100% of the time at a location that is owned, operated, or controlled by the covered fleet operator, or is under contract with the covered fleet operator Centrally fueled" means a fleet, or that part of a fleet, consisting of vehicles that are fueled 100% of the time at a location that is owned, operated, or controlled by the covered fleet operator or is under contract with the covered fleet operator. Any vehicle that under normal operations is garaged at a personal residence at night but that is centrally fueled 100% of the time shall be considered to be centrally fueled for the purpose of this definition Clean Air Act" means the Clean Air Act, approved December 17, 1963 (77 Star. 392; 42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq as amended Clean fuel" means any fuel, including methanol, ethanol, or other alcohols (including any mixture thereof containing 85% or more by volume of alcohol with gasoline or other fuel reformulated gasoline, diesel, natural gas, liquefied petroleum gas, hydrogen, or power source (including electricity) used in a clean-fuel vehicle that complies with standards and requirements applicable to such vehicle when using such fuel or power source. 18 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Clean-fuel fleet vehicle" or "CFFV" means a clean-fuel vehicle operated by a covered fleet operator Clean-fuel vehicle" means a motor vehicle which has been certified to meet, for any model year, a set of emission standards that classifies it as a clean-fuel vehicle in accordance with this act Contract fueling" means that a fleet vehicle is required to be refueled at a service station or other facility with which the fleet operator has entered into a contract for such refueling purposes. Commercial fleet service cards which are provided to fleet operators by any leasing or vehicle management company do not constitute contract fueling Converted vehicle" means a conventionally fueled vehicle that is converted to operate on a clean fuel in accordance with federal regulations and meets the emission standards set forth for that class of clean-fuel vehicle Covered area" means any part of the District that is included in an ozone nonattainment area classified under subpart 2 of part D of title I of the Clean Air Act as serious, severe, or extreme based on data for the calendar years 1987, 1988, and 1989 Covered fleet" means any fleet of ten (10) or more covered fleet vehicles owned, operated, leased, used, maintained, or otherwise controlled by a person. The term "covered fleet" does not include motor vehicles exempt under section 5 Covered fleet operator" means a person who operates a fleet of at least ten (10) covered fleet vehicles that is operated in the covered area Covered fleet vehicle" means any motor vehicle which is in a vehicle class for which emission standards are applicable under section 8 and in a covered fleet which is centrally fueled or capable of being centrally fueled. The term "covered fleet vehicle" does not include motor vehicles exempt under section 5 Credit" means a credit for the acquisition of a clean-fuel vehicle pursuant to section 246(f) of the Clean Air Act Dedicated vehicle" means a vehicle that operates solely on a clean alternative fuel Dual-fuel vehicle" means a motor vehicle that operates on two fuel sources Emergency vehicle’t means any vehicle that is legally authorized by a governmental authority to exceed the speed limit to transport people and equipment to and from situations in which speed is required to save lives or property, including a rescue vehicle, fire truck, or ambulance Federal fleet" means any fleet owned or operated by the United States government t~lexible-fueled vehicle" means a vehicle that is capable of operating on either or any combination of two (2) fuels ]~uel provider" means any person that provides fuel to a covered flee t Garaged under normal operations at a personal residence" means a vehicle that, when it is not in use, is normally parked at the personal residence of the individual who usually operates it, rather than at a central refueling, maintenance, or business location. Such vehicles are not considered to be capable of being centrally fueled and are exempt from the program unless they are, in fact, centrally fueled 100% of the time. 79 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Heavy duty vehicle" or "HDV" means a vehicle weighing above 8,501 pounds GVWP~ but below 26,000 pounds GVWIt High-Occupancy Vehicle lanes" means transportation control measures which restrict a vehicle’s access to certain roadway lanes based on the number of occupants in the vehicle Inherently low-emission vehicle" or ~ILEV" means any light-duty motor vehicle, light-duty truck, or heavy-duty vehicle that is certified as a low-emission vehicle pursuant to emission standards promulgated by the Environmental Protection Agency Law enforcement vehicle" means any vehicle that is primarily operated by a civilian or military police officer or sheriff, enforcement agency of the federal government, state highway patrols, municipal law enforcement, or other similar law enforcement agency, and that is used for the purpose of law enforcement activities, including chase, apprehension, surveillance, or patrol of people engaged in, or potentially engaged in, unlawful activities Light duty truck" or "LDT" means a truck weighing 8,500 pounds GVWR or less Light duty vehicle" or "LDV" means a vehicle weighing 8,500 pounds GVWR or less Location" means any building, structure, facility, or installation, that is owned or operated by a person, or is under the control of a person, located on one or more contiguous properties, and contains, or could contain, a fueling pump or pumps for the use of the vehicles owned or controlled by that person. This definition is meant to encompass all of the facilities of the fleet operator in a single covered area, in their entirety. The term "location" is not meant to be interpreted narrowly, such as a single refueling pump Low-emission vehicle" or "LEV" means a vehicle that meets the LEV emission standards promulgated under the Clean Air Act Model Year" means the period between September 1 and August 31 of the proceeding calendar year Motor vehicle" means any motor vehicle, as defined in section l(a) of title IV of the District of Columbia ttevenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Star. 679; D.C. Code § 40-101(1 Nonroad vehicle" means a vehicle that is powered by a nonroad engine and that is not a motor vehicle, or a vehicle used solely for competition Partially covered fleet" means any fleet that contains ten (10) or more covered fleet vehicles, but also contains exempt vehicles including law enforcement and emergency vehicles Person" means an individual, partnership, corporation, association, or any agency, instrumentality, or department of any government Purchase" or "acquisition" includes a lease Qualified second market vehicle" means a vehicle that A) Has been in use for at least eighteen (18) months, but not more than thirty-six (36) months B) Has 504 or more of its useful life remaining C) Is owned or operated by a private covered fleet operator that operates fleets in the District; or VV(D) Is a ULEV, ILEV, or ZEV. 20 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Ultra low-emission vehicle" or "ULEV" means a vehicle that is certified as meeting the ULEV emission standards promulgated under the Clean Air Act Zero-emission vehicle" or "ZEV" means a vehicle that is certified as meeting the ZEV emission standards promulgated under the Clean Air Act 999.2 When used in this chapter, the following abbreviations shall have the meanings ascribed: AFV Alternative Fuel Vehicle BHP-hr Brake horse power-hour CFFV Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle CFF Clean Fuel Fleet g/mi Grams per mile GWVR Gross Vehicle Weight Rating EPA Environmental Protection Agency HDV Heavy Duty Vehicle HOV High Occupancy Vehicle ILEV Inherently Low Emissions Vehicle LDV Light Duty Vehicle LEV Low Emission Vehicle LDT Light Duty Truck LVW Loaded Vehicle Weight LW Loaded Weight M~ Model Year NMHC Non-Methane Hydrocarbon NMOG Non-Methane Organic Gas NOx Nitrogen Oxides OEM -Original Equipment Manufacture TW Total Weight ULEV Ultra Low Emission Vehicle U.S United States VIN Vehicle Identification Number WMATA Washington Metropolitan Transit Authority ZEV Zero Emissions Vehicle Sac. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 21 ENROLLED ORIGINAL and publication in the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 21, 1994 22. @ CO~CIL OF DIST~CT OF COLUMB~ C.c~il ~ricd Ten ]tern on Consent Caenaar ACTIGN &amp;amp; DATE: VOICEE P~oraea vote ~n ~eaues[ ADsent: RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL. VOTE DOCKEr NO F.irst. Readinq 7-5 94 Approved Barry, Liqhtfoot ,and Thomas BI0-658 CSL CALL vOTE RESULT CHMN CLARkE{ i ’ I "’ IEVANR’ BARRY ’ ’jARVT~ } BRAZIL ’ ’ ’ t iIr~aTF~hT CHAVOus i f HASON CROPPl I 1 i INATHANSON. 1 NAY I N.V. I A.S. I COIJNC:I. MEMS~B i &amp;amp;Y~ NAY THOMAS. SR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE X,vo~CE VOTE R O~ vote A.B Ab~ N.V -1 res~t not voen CB~FtCA~ON REC~O 0ate ~lopted Final Re,ling, 10-4-94 Approved "’ -ROU.CAU.VOre--RESULT COdNCILMEMI~R AYEINAY A C@UNC|LMF..MBE AYE CHMN. CLARKE I FVAN~ BARRY ’ JARViS BR&amp;amp;Z[L LIGHTFOOT .CHA.VOUS KROPP NAY’ N.V I SMITH, jR THOMAS R [" J ’i COUNCIL M~MB~R ~’ ’AYE NAY N.V. L&amp;amp; COUNCIL MEMBI AYE EVAN RAY JARVIS SMITH JR. LIGHTFOOT THOMAS. SR ~ASO NATHANSO.N Item o~ Co~I~ C C AC~ON &amp;amp T vo~S VO s R~~I C~L vo RESULT NAY N.V A.8 Atm~M N.Y x CIB:ITIFICATION RI=CORO C~UNCIL.MEMBE, R AYE NAY I N.:V. A.8. CHMN. CLARXE ¯ BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS ,I C~.QPP X IrltlCal~ Vole</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
