<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-234">
  <num type="law">10-234</num>
  <heading type="short">Budget Spending Reduction Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-03-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-234.pdf">D.C. Law 10-234</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 28</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0763">
      <narrative>Law 10-234, the “Budget Spending Reduction Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-763, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-377 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-234 became effective on March 21, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN kwikta 062 312 309 MEN (S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10- 234 "Budget Spending Reduction Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-763 on first and second readings, November 1, 1994 and December 6, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 27, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-377, and published in the January 6, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 28) and transmitted to Congress on Feburary 3, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-234, effective March 21, 1995 DAVID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Confessional Review Period: Feb. 3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 Mar. 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,17,20 AN ACT D,C, ACT 10-377 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Code 1 9_5, Supplement} IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 27, 1994 To amend An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three and for other purposes to authorize the imposition of a fee for special events; and to repeal the Law School Clinical Programs Funding Authorization Act of 1978. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Budget Spending l~eduction Amendment Act of 1994 Sec. 2. Special events a) Paragraph 26 of section 7 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three and for other purposes, approved July 1, 1902 (47 Star. 554; D.C. Code § 47-2826 is amended as follows 1) By designating the existing text as subsection (a and (2) By adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) The Mayor may adjust the license fee set in subsection (a) of this section to cover the costs to the District of providing police, fire, and other public services that are necessary to protect public health and safety b) The Mayor shall establish by rule a schedule of license fees for special events held on public space to cover the costs to the District of providing police, fire, and other public services that are necessary to protect public health and safety. See. 3. Law school clinical program repeal. The Law School Clinical Programs Funding Authorization Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-143; D.C. Code § 31-1901 et seq is repealed. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District Section 47-2826 Section 31-1901 ENROLLED ORIGINAL of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 27, 1994 CO~,’NCIE O~’ DI~A"9,XC"I’ O~’ COLEIJ[BIA CommA.1. L:’e=icxt Ten RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE ~CC,KE’r NO: item on C~nsem Camncl CTICN &amp;amp; DATE: VOTE BI 0-763 Adopted First Reading, ii-i-94 Approved Aoser~t O~N~IL MEMSEFI { AYE NAY ,N V A,&amp;amp C~LJNC:L MEMeE~ ’ ~v~ CLARKE VAN~ BARRY ’ JARVT BRAZIL T~HT~nnT CHAVOUS CR~PP Xvo~cE vol"&amp;amp; Al~lt ROLL CAU. VOTE RESULT JR THOMAS, SR. ’ NATHANSON RAY N.v ’ A.&amp;amp; ’ C~UNC:L MEMBE~ AYE v ¯ 5. I Adopted Final Reading, 12-6-94 Approved NAY I N.V. NAY A ROt.A. CALL VOT RESULT. COUNCIl. MEMEER CHMN. CLARKE ’BARRY BRAZIL "CHAVOUS CROPP AYE NAY N.V. x mat .es vote ~OUNCIL EVANS JARV~S L.;GHTFOQT MASON NATHAN~ON’ AYE NAY N.VI’ AS. COUN~IZ EMeEFI’ AYE I NAY N.V. RAY SMITH~ JR. THOMAS SR. Se¢.-ma me C~c~ Dam AN ACT ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Code { 1995 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three and for other purposes to authorize the imposition of a fee for special events; and to repeal the Law School Clinical Programs Funding Authorization Act of 1978. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Budget Spending Reduction Amendment Act of 1994 Sec. 2. Special events a) Paragraph 26 of section 7 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three and for other purposes, approved July 1, 1902 (47 Star. 554; D.C. Code § 47-2826 is amended as follows 1) By designating the existing text as subsection (a and (2) By adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) The Mayor may adjust the license fee set in subsection (a) of this section to cover the costs to the District of providing police, fire, and other public services that are necessary to protect public health and safety b) The Mayor shall establish by rule a schedule of license fees for special events held on public space to cover the costs to the District of providing police, fire, and other public services that are necessary to protect public health and safety. See. 3. Law school clinical program repeal. The Law School Clinical Programs Funding Authorization Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-143; D.C. Code § 31-1901 et seq is repealed. See. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District Sect ion 47-2826 Section 31-1901 ENROLL£O ORIGINAL of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia COt~’NCIL OF "THE DIST~CT OF COLUMBL C.~ur l ’ericd Ten R~-CORD OF OFFiCiAL COUNCIL VO7 CC~I" B10-763 Adopted First Reading, 11-i-94 ¯ prpv, ed ¯ csert 0’ CAtJ. VOTE aESULT CHMN. CLARKE] ’ VAN~ ’ ’’; RA 5ARRY ’ ’ QARV[S ’SH.[TH, jR ’ ¯ I RAZ~L GHTFOOT THOM R CHAVOUS ,MASON ’ i NATHANS~ I 1r.R~PO ’ ’ ’ ACI~ON &amp;amp; OAI vC~CE v01 F~L CALL VOTE CHMN. CLARKE I EVANS BARRY JARV[~ BRAZ[ L I LIGHTFQOT CHAVOUS I MASON CROPP { T ’ NATHABSQN THOMAS~ SR=’ I i CERTIFICATION ~CCRO S me Co~’ Dam</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
