<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-202">
  <num type="law">10-202</num>
  <heading type="short">Medicaid Benefits Protection Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1995-03-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-202.pdf">D.C. Law 10-202</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 7704</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 10-202, the “Medicaid Benefits Protection Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-584, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 4, 1994, and November 1, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 22, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-340 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-202 became effective on March 14, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 The Honorable Sharon Pratt Kelly Mayor of the District of Columbia 441 4th Street, N.W llth Floor Washington, D.C. 2000] Re: Transmittal of Bill 10-584 Medicaid Benefits Protection Act of 1994 Date of Council Action: II -01 -94 Dear Mayor Kelly: The above named enacted bill is hereby transmitted in accordance with Section 404(e) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to this bill, for your information, is the report of the Council’s standing committee with jurisdiction over this matter. Sincerely avia A. Clarke Chairman of the Council Enclosure AN ACT ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Code Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To bring the District of Columbia Medicaid program into compliance with new federal requirements imposed by the Omnibus Budget Keconcilation Act of 1993. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTKICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Medicaid Benefits Protection Act of 1994 See. 2. Insurer obligations a) No insurer may deny coverage or withhold payments under its plan for any enrollee, subscriber, policyholder, or certificateholder on the basis that such enrollee, subscriber, policyholder, or certificateholder is eligible for Medicaid pursuant to a Medicaid state plan adopted by the District of Columbia or any other jurisdiction pursuant to section 1902 of the Social Security Act, approved January 2, 1968 (79 Star. 344; 42 U.S.C. 1396a b) No insurer may deny enrollment of a child under the health plan of the child’s parent on the grounds that 1) The child was born out of wedlock 2) The child is not claimed as a dependent on the parent’s Federal income tax return; or (3) The child does not reside with the parent or in the insurer’s service area c) Where a child has health coverage through an insurer of a noncustodial parent, the insurer shall 1) Provide such information to the custodial parent as may be necessary for the child to obtain benefits through such coverage 2) Permit the custodial parent (or the provider, with the custodial parent’s approval) to submit claims for covered services without the approval of the noncustodial parent; and (3) Make payments on claims submitted in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection directly to the custodial parent, the provider, or the District of Columbia Medicaid agency d) Where a parent is required by a court or administrative order to provide health coverage for a child, and the parent is eligible for family health coverage, the insurer shall 1) Permit the parent to enroll, under the family coverage, a child who is otherwise eligible for the coverage without regard to any enrollment season restrictions; New Section 1-359.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (2) Enroll the child under family coverage upon application by the child’s other parent, or by the District of Columbia agency administering either the Medicaid program or the child support enforcement program pursuant to Title IV-D of the Social Security Act, approved January 4, 1975 (88 Star. 2351; 42 U.S.C. 652 through 669 if the employed parent is enrolled but fails to make application to obtain coverage of the child; and (3) Not disenroll (or eliminate coverage of) the child unless the insurer is provided satisfactory written evidence that A) The court or administrative order is no longer in effect; or (B) The child is or will be enrolled in comparable health coverage through another insurer which will take effect not later than the effective date of disenrollment e) An insurer may not impose requirements on a District of Columbia agency, which has been assigned the rights of an individual eligible for medical assistance under Medicaid and covered for health benefits from the insurer, that are different from requirements applicable Lo an agent or assignee of any other individual so covered f) For purposes of this section, the term "insurer" includes a group health plan, as defined in section 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved April 7, 1986 (100 Star. 231; 29 U.S.C. 1167(1 a public or private organization which is a qualifying health maintenance organization under federal regulations, or a hospital and medical service plan as defined in section 2 of the Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association Act of 1992, effective July 22, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-129; D.C. Code § 35-1941(8 Sec. 3: Employer obligations. Where a parent is required by a court or administrative order to provide health coverage, which is available through the parenUs employer, the employer shall 1) Permit the parent to enroll under family coverage any child who is otherwise eligible for coverage without regard to any enrollment restrictions 2) Enroll the child under family coverage upon application by the child’s other parent, or by the District of Columbia agency administering either the Medicaid program or the child support enforcement program pursuant to Title IV-D of the Social Security Act, approved January 4, 1975 (88 Star. 2351; 42 U.S.C. 651 through 669 if the parent is enrolled but fails to make application to obtain coverage of the child 3) Not disenroll or eliminate coverage of any such child unless the employer is provided satisfactory written evidence that A) The court order is no longer in effect B) The child is or will be enrolled in comparable coverage which will take effect no later than the effective date of disenrollment; or (C) The employer has eliminated family health coverage for all its employees; and (4) Withhold from the employee’s compensation the employee’s share (if any) of premiums for health coverage and to pay this amount to the insurer, except that the maximum amount so withheld may not exceed the maximum amount to be withheld under section 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act, approved May 29, 1988 (82 Star. 163; 15 U C. 1673(b See. 4. tLecoupment of amounts spent on child medical care a) The Mayor may garnish wages, salary, or other employment income of, and intercept, in accordance with procedures set forth in section 2 of the Prelect Set-Off Liability Act of 1982, effective September 18, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-154; D.C. Code § 47-1812.11 any amounts from District of Columbia tax payable to, any person who 1) Is required by court or administrative order to provide coverage of the cost of health services to a child who is eligible for Medicaid and (2) Has received payment from a third party for the costs of such services, but has not used the payments to reimburse eLther the other parent or guardian of the child or the provider of the services b) A garnishment or tax intercept effectuated pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be effected only to the extent necessary to reimburse the District of Columbia Medicaid agency for its cost under the state plan, but claims for current and past due child support shall take priority over these claims. See. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council o£ the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal ILegulations i Chairman ¯ Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia @ CO[,,’NCIL 0~’ DI~"T~CT OF COLt~’5[BL~ RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOl CC~ET ,NO: BI0-584 Adopted First Reading, 10-4-94 Approved Barry, Evans and Thomas OLL C~L C’r ESLJLT CHiN CLARKE LEVAN ’ RAY BARRY ]ARvT gt SHITH, JR ’ BRAZIL ’I [GHT~T THOMAS SR. CHAVOUS mASON cROPP gt;~ATHANSON X mmcales ~ole B s V mres~I oI vo~n Ca~e AC~ON &amp;amp; OATE Adopted Final Reading, II-I-94 ~voIcEvoTE Approved ~eCor~l~ vO~ on re(~ue mou. CAu. vo’r ESULT IICOU~_NCILMEMBER AY’ N.Y N,V ~AB..qHMN. CLARKE ARRY X m~m~ Vmm A.B Ab t~ O Ac’rION &amp;amp; OA VOlCE vo’r mOLL. CALL VOTE RESULT .CHMN. CLARKE EVANS .[ BARRY JARVI S. I BR.AZ [ L L I GHT F.OOT ~CHAVOUS 1 MASON CROPP I t NATHAN$ON I CER~FICA~QNmC--CORO AYE NAY N.V. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER ,AYE RAY SMITH, JR~ THOMAS, SR. COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-202 "Medicaid Benefits Protection Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-584 on first and second readings, October 4, 1994 and November 1, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 22, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-340, and published in the December 2, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol.41 page 7704 and transmitted to Congress on January 27, 1995, for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-202 effective March 14, 1995 DAVID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Jan. 27,30,31 Feb. 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 M 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13 AN ACT D,C, ACT i0-340 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification Distdct of Columbia Code t 19 9 5 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOV[NB[R 1994 To bring the District of Columbia Medicaid program into compliance with new federal requirements imposed by the Omnibus Budget Reconcilation Act of 1993. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Medicaid Benefits Protection Act of 1994 See. 2. Insurer obligations a) No insurer may deny coverage or withhold payments under its plan for any enrollee, subscriber, policyholder, or certificateholder on the basis that such enrollee, subscriber, policyholder, or certificateholder is eligible for Medicaid pursuant to a Medicaid state plan adopted by the District of Columbia or any other jurisdiction pursuant to section 1902 of the Social Security Act, approved January 2, 1968 (79 Star. 344; 42 U.S.C. 1396a b) No insurer may deny enrollment of a child under the health plan of the child’s parent on the grounds that 1) The child was born out of wedlock 2) The child is not claimed as a dependent on the parent’s Federal income tax return; or (3) The child does not reside with the parent or in the insurer’s service area c) Where a child has health coverage through an insurer of a noncustodial parent, the insurer shall 1) Provide such information to the custodial parent as may be necessary for the child to obtain benefits through such coverage 2) Permit the custodial parent (or the provider, with the custodial parent’s approval) to submit claims for covered services without the approval of the noncustodial parent; and (3) Make payments on claims submitted in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection directly to the custodial parent, the provider, or the District of Columbia Medicaid agency d) Where a parent is required by a court or administrative order to provide health coverage for a child, and the parent is eligible for family health coverage, the insurer shall 1) Permit the parent to enroll, under the family coverage, a child who is otherwise eligible for the coverage without regard to any enrollment season restrictions; New Section 1-359.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (2) Enroll the child under family coverage upon application by the child’s other parent, or by the District of Columbia agency administering either the Medicaid program or the child support enforcement program pursuant to Title IV-D of the Social Security Act, approved January 4, 1975 (88 Star. 2351; 42 U.S.C. 652 through 669 if the employed parent is enrolled but fails to make application to obtain coverage of the child; and (3) Not disenroll (or eliminate coverage of) the child unless the insurer is provided satisfactory written evidence that A) The court or administrative order is no longer in effect; or (B) The child is or will be enrolled in comparable health coverage through another insurer which will take effect not later than the effective date of disenrollment e) An insurer may not impose requirements on a District of Columbia agency, which has been assigned the rights of an individual eligible for medical assistance under Medicaid and covered for health benefits from the insurer, that are different from requirements applicable to an agent or assignee of any other individual so covered f) For purposes of this section, the term "insurer" includes a group health plan, as defined in section 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved April 7, 1986 (100 Star. 231; 29 U.S.C. 1167(1 a public or private organization which is a qualifying health maintenance organization under federal regulations, or a hospital and medical service plan as defined in section 2 of the Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association Act of 1992, effective July 22, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-129; D.C. Code § 35-1941(8 Sec. 3. Employer obligations here a parent is required by a court or administrative order to provide health coverage, which is available through the parent’s employer, the employer shall 1) Permit the parent to enroll under family coverage any child who is otherwise eligible for coverage without regard to any enrollment restrictions 2) Enroll the child under family coverage upon application by the child’s other parent, or by the District of Columbia agency administering either the Medicaid program or the child support enforcement program pursuant to Title IV-D of the Social Security Act, approved January 4, 1975 (88 Star. 2351; 42 U.S.C. 651 through 669 if the parent is enrolled but fails to make application to obtain coverage of the child 3) Not disenroll or eliminate coverage of any such child unless the employer is provided satisfactory written evidence that A) The court order is no longer in effect B) The child is or will be enrolled in comparable coverage which will take effect no later than the effective date of disenrollment; or (C) The employer has eliminated family health coverage for all its employees; and (4) Withhold from the employee’s compensation the employee’s share (if any) of premiums for health coverage and to pay this amount to the insurer, except that the maximum amount so withheld may not 2 EttI OLLE OiliGittl L exceed the maximum amount to be withheld under section 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act, approved May 29, 1988 (82 Star. 163; 15 U.S.C. 1673(b See. 4. Recoupment of amounts spent on child medical care a) The Mayor may garnish wages, salary, or other employment income of, and intercept, in accordance with procedures set forth in section 2 of the Project Set-Off Liability Act of 1982, effective September 18, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-154; D.C. Code § 47-1812.11 any amounts from District of Columbia tax payable to, any person who 1) Is required by court or administrative order to provide coverage of the cost of health services to a child who is eligible for Medicaid; and (2) Has received payment from a third party for the costs of such services, but has not used the payments to reimburse either the other parent or guardian of the child or the provider of the services b) A garnishment or tax intercept effectuated pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be effected only to the extent necessary to reimburse the District of Columbia Medicaid agency for its cost under the state plan, but claims for current and past due child support shall take priority over these claims. See. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal l%egulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Di;t;ict of 21umbia APPROVED: November 22, 1994 Item on Consem Calendar ~AC’TqCN &amp;amp; 0ATE [ ’,"Die E VOTE: CO~’NCIL OF TI~ DISI’BICT OF COLUMBI~ Cc~r~J_]. 9eriod RECORO OF OFRClAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, I0.4-94 Approved Barry, Evans and Thomas ~ec0rCed vote CLL CALL ORE RESULT COLJNCtL MEMBER!!AYE i NAY NV i A.B. i COUNC’,L= MEMBEN i Y NAY iNV. CHMN CLARKE I EVANS BARRY i ’I ~BRAZ!L i ~I GHTFNNT ~HAVOUS 1 MASON CROPP [ NATHANSON X naIca, les qole ltI’~m Se to me Counc, on Comsat Caveat ACTION &amp;amp; DATE. ¯ voice VOTE. Recor0~l vet? on BI0-584 BRAZIL CHAVOUS RCLL CALLVOT mESULT COU~CILMEMBER AYE INAY N.V CHMN. CLARKE BARRY i 1I ACTION SMITH, JR¯ THOMAS SR vOiCE VOTE Recor~e(l vote A A~:sent NV Present. not vOt;nC~ CERTIFICATION RECORD AdoptedFinal Reading, Ii-i-94 Approved COUNCIL MEMBER A.&amp;amp; COUNCIL MEMBER i AYE i ,NAY N.V FRAY- I i SM.I TH, J R i i FV#N£ gARY’5 ~IGHTFQQT MASON COUNCILMEMBER ±C~MN. CLARKE A.B Al3sent N.V Pr~ent. not volta CERTIFtCAlqON RECORD { O~e BARRY BRAZIL FCHAVOUS :CROPP AIrShip: ROLL CALL VOT RESULT, AYE NAY t N.V. A.B. X InO~cates Vote J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.8. COUNClL MEMBER AYE i NAY N.V. IAB. EVANS RAY JARVIS .SMITH JR. LIGHTF00T THOMAS, SR. MASON NATHANSON I I A.B Al3sent N.V Pre~flt r~ voa.L~ CERTIFICATION RECORD S~:rm~ty t~ me Courted Dale</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-307.41"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-307.42"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-307.43"/>
  </section>
</document>
