<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-211">
  <num type="law">10-211</num>
  <heading type="short">Charitable Gift of Life Insurance Proceeds Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1995-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-211.pdf">D.C. Law 10-211</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 8027</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0033">
      <narrative>Law 10-211, the “Charitable Gift of Life Insurance Proceeds Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-348, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 15, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-348 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-211 became effective on March 16, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwikta~ ® 062 313 878 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-211 "Charitable Gift of Life Insurance Proceeds Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-33 on first and second readings, November 1, 1994 and December 6, I994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 15, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-348, and published in the December 23, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 41 page 8027) and transmitted to Congress on January 31, 1995, for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-211, effective March 16, 1995 lrm Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: 31 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15 AN ACT D,C, ACT 10-348 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Code 1995 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 15, 1994 To amend the Life Insurance Act to allow charitable and other benevolent institutions to acquire an insurable interest in the life of a person who chooses to provide for charitable needs by designating a charity as the beneficiary in a life insurance policy. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Charitable Gift of Life Insurance Proceeds Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. Section 16 of chapter 5 of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1934 (48 Star. 1175; D.C. Code §35-521 is amended as follows a) The existing text is designated as subsection (a b) New subsections (b) and (c) are added to read as follows b) A charitable, benevolent, educational, governmental, or religious institution that is described in section 501(c)(3) or section 170(b 1 A) of the Internal l~evenue Code or a trust for the benefit of the institution that is qualified as a charitable remainder trust under section 664 or a pooled income fund under section 642(c)(5) of the Internal l~evenue Code may acquire an insurable interest in the life of an individual if 1) The institution or trust is designated irrevocably as the beneficiary of the insurance proceeds or designated as the owner of the life insurance policy, or both 2) The application for the insurance contract is procured and signed by the individual whose life is to be insured; and 3) Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the insured pays the premiums for the insurance policy for at least 3 years following the issuance of the policy c) Subsection (b) of this section does not prohibit the insured from retaining all ownership rights conferred by the insurance policy, except the right to loan or borrow value during the premium-paying period or at maturity Sec. 3. This act shall be applied retroactively, thereby validating any insurance contract authorized under this act if the individual on whose life the insurance contract was taken is alive on the effective date of this act, even though the insurance contract was entered into before the effective date of this act and the beneficiary or owner of the policy continues to pay the premiums until maturity. S e ct ion 35-521 Note, Section 35-521 ENROLLED ORIGINAL See. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental tLeorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columb tLegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or~he Distrig(f~ Columbia Municipal Chairman Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 15, 1994 @ CO~’NCIX. O~ T~ D~ST~CT OF COt.UMBI RE~ORO OF O~qCIAL COUN~L VOI CCKEr Item on Cot~ Callao XC~CN &amp;amp; OA VOIC~ VO ecor o~e on ues[ B10-33 Adopted FirstRead/mg, 11-1-94 S( CERTIFICATION RECC}RO ate Adopted Final l~eadinqr 12-6-94 ROLl. CALl. VOTE RESULT. CHIN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS £ROPP C ~t~mo Camera’ C Ac’rI()N Al’r¢ vOiCE vo~ R A CA~ vo S~T COUNCIL MEMBEI~ C~MN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL "CHAVOU CROPP AYE NAY COUNCIl. MEM~R AYE NAY N.V. A[~ COUNCIL _u._cH_.@_~ AYE EVANS RAY JARVIS SMITH. JR. LIGHTFOQT THOMAS R. MASON NATHANSON aS. A AI N.V P C~RI"IFICA 1"ION RECORO</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
