<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-221">
  <num type="law">10-221</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Select Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Courses Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1995-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-221.pdf">D.C. Law 10-221</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 8047</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0656">
      <narrative>Law 10-221, the “District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Select Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Courses Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-656, which was referred to the Committee on Education and Libraries. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 15, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-358 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-221 became effective on March 16, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 221 159 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-221 "District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Select Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Courses Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-656 on first and second readings, November 1, 1994 and December 6, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 15, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-358, and published in the December 23, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 41 page 8047) and transmitted to Congress on January 31, 1995, for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-221, effective March 16, 1995 Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. Mar. 31 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15 AN ACT D.C, ACT I0-358 ENROLLED ORiGiNAL Codification District of Columbia Code 995 Supplement) New Chapter IA, Title 31 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 15, 1994 To authorize the District of Columbia Board of Education to charge fees for select adult, community, and continuing education courses. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Select Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Courses Act of 1994 Sec. 2. Definitions. For purposes of this act, the phrase "Select Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Course" means an adult, community, and continuing education course which is either recreational or vocational in nature. Sec. 3. Fees for select District of Columbia Board of Education adult, continuing, and community education courses a) The District of Columbia Board of Education Board of Education is authorized to charge fees for select adult, community, and continuing education courses, provided that no fees shall be charged for Adult Basic Education, Adult Secondary Education Diploma Programs or General Education Development Programs, and Adult English as a Second Language Programs, Levels I through IV b) The amount which shall be charged with respect to each seIect adult, community, and continuing education course shall be fixed annually by the Board of Education as the amount necessary to cover the expense of instruction, cost of textbooks and school supplies, and other operating costs associated with each course offered: Provided, that such an amount and changes in the amount fixed by this subsection are set by the Board of Education in accordance with section 6 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1206; D.C. Code § 1-1506 Following the final adoption of such amounts, the Board of Education shall transmit a copy to the Mayor and a copy to the Council of the District of Columbia c) All amounts received by the Board of Education under this section shall be paid to the D.C. Treasurer and accounted for in the General Fund as a separate revenue source allocable to provide authority for the offering of select adult, community, and continuing education courses for which fees will be charged d) As part of its fiscal year 1995 Supplemental Budget, the Board of Education shall request that an amount equal to the fees collected and New Section 31-131 New Section 31-132 £tll OLLE ORIGIltJ L deposited into the General Fund pursuant to this act, be appropriated to the Board of Education for the purpose of paying for instructors’ salaries, textbooks and supplies, and other operating costs associated with offering select adult, community, and continuing education courses e) Waivers, in whole or in part, of fees for select adult, community, and continuing education courses may be granted by the Board of Education only to District residents, regardless of an individual’s or a student’s employment status with the Board or the District of Columbia Public Schools. Sec. 4. Accountability for funds received. The District of Columbia Board of Education shall account for all funds received pursuant to this act. See. 5. Rulemaking. The Board of Education, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1204; D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia New Section 31-133 Note, New Section 31-131 District of Columbia APPROVED: December 15, 1994 CO~qNCTL OF TEE DISTINCT OF COLiTM~L&amp;amp; Couzlck.1 eriocl Ten RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: BI0-656 Adopted First Reading, 11-1-94 Approved Barry N V I A I CO.UNC:L MEMBEB i ~v I NAY NV. I A COUNC:L MEMeER YE NAY N ’z 5. Adopted Final Approved Barry Readinq, 12-6-94 ROLL CALL VOT RESULT OU__NCILMEMBERcHMN. CLARKE AYE !NAY INV [A’B’, BARRY CHAVOUS CRDPP I x inecales Vote ACTION COUNCIL MEMBER AYE EVAN~ QARViS 41GHTFQQT MA~Q~ NATHANSON I NAY N.V.A.8. ICOUNCIL MEMBER AYE i, NAY" I I SM,,ITH, JR, THOMAS R CEFIITIRCATION R~CORO vOiCE VOT ROu.cAu.vo RSSULT COUNCILMEMBER LC~MN. CLARKE LBARRY I BRAZIL ~CHAVOUS CROPP AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCILMEMBER AYE NAY N.V 8. COUNCILMEMBER AYE ,EVANS RAY JARVIS SMITH~ JR. LIGHTFOOT THOMAS, SR. MASON NATHAN$ON x m v(} tAY N.V. A,S. A.B Al~enl N.V Present v CERTIFICATION RECORD S~.retaty to me Council Dam</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-1001"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-1002"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-1003"/>
  </section>
</document>
