<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-242">
  <num type="law">10-242</num>
  <heading type="short">Clean Air Compliance Fee Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-03-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-242.pdf">D.C. Law 10-242</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 86</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0610">
      <narrative>Law 10-242, the “Clean Air Compliance Fee Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-610, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 28, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-387 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-242 became effective on March 21, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN L MEN (S) kwil~:ag ® 103 221 $63 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10- 242 "Clean Air Compliance Fee Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-610 on first and second readings, November 1, 1994 and December 6, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 28, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-387, and published in the January 6, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 86) and transmitted to Congress on Feburary 3, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-242, effective March 21, 1995. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 Mar. 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,17,20 AN ACT D.C. ACT 10-387 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Code Supplement IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTIZlCT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 28, 1994 New Subchapter IV Chapter 27, Title 47 To comply with the emissions requirements of the Clean Air Act by discouraging single-occupant vehicle home-to-work travel and by encouraging car pools and transit use through the establishment of a fee at a rate of $20 per month per space on employment parking spaces that are not subject to the collection of parking sales and use taxes for the service of parking and to amend the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act and the District of Columbia Use Tax Act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTltlCT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Clean Air Compliance Fee Act of 1994 See. 2. Findings. The Council of the District of Columbia finds that 1) Air pollution impairs the health and welfare of the citizens of the District of Columbia 2) Single-occupant automobile traffic is a substantial source of this pollution and the use of single-occupant automobiles for home-to-work travel has been increasing according to data from the Council of Governments 3) Despite the general availability of public transit and car pools, many individuals drive to work because free or subsidized parking is available 4) Pursuant to the federal Clean Air Act, the District of Columbia is a serious non-attainment jurisdiction and the government of the District of Columbia is required to reduce, eliminate, and control sources of air pollution; and (5) By requiring payment from employment parking that is not subject to the parking sales and use tax and by allocating the revenues to the transit component of the District of Columbia’s Clean Air tLegulatory Program the District of Columbia will simultaneously discourage the use of single-occupancy vehicles for home-to-work travel while encouraging the use of car pools and transit, thereby reducing air pollution in compliance with requirements under the Clean Air Act. Sec. 3. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Employment parking" means the use of a parking space by a person, including owners, partners, employers, proprietors, New, Section 47-2731 New, Section 47-2732 [HBOLLE O IG]HAL employees, and independent contractors, to park to have access to employment, in association with their home-to-work travel 2 Employment parking space" means a parking space, whether or not the parking space is identified or reserved for employment parking, in which employment parking by a motor vehicle occurs more than 2 days per week. Sec. 4. Clean Air Act Compliance Fee a) Pursuant to the federal Clean Air Act, which requires non-attainment jurisdictions such as the District of Columbia to reduce emissions of volatile organic compounds and nitrogen oxides to meet federal ambient air quality standards, there is hereby levied a fee on real property in the District of Columbia at a rate of $20 per month per employment parking space for which sales and use tax for the service of parking is not collected pursuant to section 125(1) of the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Star. 115; D.C. Code § 47-2002(1 or section 212(1) of the District of Columbia Use Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Stat. 126; D.C. Code § 47-2202(1 b) Owners of real property subject to the fee imposed by subsection (a) of this section may seek reimbursement of the fee from the users of employment parking spaces. See. 5. Registration of employment parking spaces a) Owners of real property in the District of Columbia shall register employment parking spaces on their property or on public space over which they control access in accordance with procedures established by the Mayor b)(1) The Mayor may require persons referred to in subsection (a) of this section to supply the following information A) the total number of parking spaces owned or controlled B) the total number of employment parkings spaces; and (C) the total number of employment parking spaces for which sales and use tax for the service of parking is not collected pursuant to section 125(1) of the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Star. 115; D.C. Code § 47-2002(1 or section 212(1) of the District of Columbia Use Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Star. 126; D.C. Code § 47-2202(1 2) The Mayor may establish procedures to require persons referred to in subsection (a) of this section to produce or maintain records c) Registration shall occur semiannually. Sec. 6. Exemptions. The following shall be exempt from the Clean Air Act Compliance Fee established in section 4 and the registration requirement established by section 5 1) Employment parking spaces used by members of the Senate unless the President Pro Tempore of the Senate notifies the Mayor, in writing, that the members of the Senate shall be subject to the fee 2) Employment parking spaces used by members of the House of tLepresentatives unless the Speaker of the House of Representatives New Section 47-2733 New Section 47-2734 New Section 47-2735 ENROLLED OI]]GINAL notifies the Mayor, in writing, that the members of the House of Representatives shall be subject to the fee 3) Employment parking spaces owned or controlled by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority and used by its patrons to obtain access to the transit system 4) Employment parking spaces regulated by meters owned by the District of Columbia 5) Employment parking spaces owned or controlled by foreign governments and used for legation purposes; and (6) l~eal property containing not more than 1 employment parking space. See. 7. t~ules of construction. Nothing in this act shall be construed to impede upon the President’s discretion under section 118 of the Clean Air Act, approved November 15, 1990 (104 Stat 2409; 42 U.S.C. 7418 See. 8. Special agreements with the federal government. The Mayor is authorized to enter into agreements with the legislative, judicial, and executive branches of the federal government regarding compliance and enforcement where issues of national security would otherwise preclude enforcement of this act. Sec. 9. Payment. The fee established in section 4 shall be due and payable semiannually, as prescribed by the Mayor. See. 10. Penalties and enforcement a) Failure to register an employment parking space shall subject the property to a penalty of $240 per employment parking space per 6-month registration period b) If the fee is not paid within the time prescribed by the Mayor, there shall be added to the fee a penalty of 104 of the unpaid amount plus interest of 14 per month or portion of a month until the payment is made. The amount of the unpaid fee plus any penalties and interest due shall constitute a lien against the property from the time it is due and payable, having priority over other liens, secured or otherwise, and shall also constitute a personal debt of the real property owner c) The Mayor, for purposes of determining the total number of employment parking spaces owned or controlled by an owner of real property and for determining the amount of fees due from a real property owner, shall have authority to require a property owner to provide and maintain books and records, may examine any relevant books, papers, records, or memoranda of any person that bear upon the matters required to be included in the registration and may summon any person to appear and produce books, records, papers, or memoranda that bear upon the matters to be included in the registration and give testimony or answer interrogatories under oath 1) The Mayor may administer the oath to any person summoned to give testimony or answer interrogatories. The summons may be served by any member of the Metropolitan Police Department 2) If any person who was personally summoned neglects or refuses to obey the summons, the Mayor may report the fact to the New Section 47-2736 New Section 47-2737 New Section 47-2738 New Section 47-2739 3 ENROLLED Superior Court of the District of Columbia Court and the Court may compel obedience to the summons to the same extent that a witness may be compelled to obey a subpoena of that Court d) The Mayor may enforce the provisions of this act pursuant to the District of Columbia Air Pollution Control Act of 1984, approved March 15, 1985 (D.C. Law 5-165; D.C. Code § 6-905) against any real property owner who produces or maintains false records, or who fails to pay the fee or maintain and produce records as required by the Mayor authorized under this act. See. 11. Allocation of Clean Air Compliance Fee. All fees, interest, penalties, and other charges collected pursuant to this act shah be used to defray the cost of the transit component of the District of Columbia’s Clean Air Regulatory Program. See. 12. Rulemaking. Pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedures Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, § 1-1501 et seq the Mayor is authorized to issue any rules that may be necessary to implement the provisions of this act. The Council requests that the Mayor amend the District of Columbia State Implementation Plan to ensure that the District receives credit for reductions in volatile organic compounds and nitrogen oxides, in fulfillment of the District’s federally mandated requirement to reduce ozone creating pollutants. See. 13. Conforming amendment. Section 2(b)(2) of the Stable and Reliable Source of Revenues for WMATA Act of 1982, effective April 30, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-103; D.C. Code § 1-2466 is amended by adding a new subparagraph (H) to read as follows H) Section 4 of the Clean Air Act Compliance Fee Act of 1994 Sec. 14. Sales and use tax amendments a) Section 114(a)(17) of the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Stat. I13; D.C. Code § 47-2001(n)(1)(Q is amended by inserting the phrase "or the delivery of any newspapers" after the word "issued b) Section 201(a)(15) of the District of Columbia Use Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Stat. 124; D.C. Code § 47-2201(a)(1)(O is amended by inserting the phrase "or the delivery of any newspapers" after the word "issued Sec. 15. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of a veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in § 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Keorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of New Section 47-2740 Note Section 47-2731 Section 1-2466 Section 47-2001 Section 47-2201 Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia /M@o District of Columbia APPROVED: December 28, 1994 5 COL~’NCIL OF TKE DLSTRICT OF COL~’MBIA l~em on Consent CaJena ACT/ON 8= DATE ’JOICE VOTE ecor~ vole on r~UeSl Absent: RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOC}&amp;lt;ET NO: BI0-610 Adopted Fi rst Reading, 7-5-94 Approved Barry and Thomas CLL CALL VOTE ESULT AYE I NAY COUNCIL MEMBER S( CF..RTIRCATION RECORD Counc|l Item on Consem ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE voicE VOT~ Ab~n ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT, CQU_NCIL MEMBER AYE I NAY N.V.A.B. I CHMN. CLARKE BARRY I BRAZIL CHAVOUS x In=cams Vole VOICE VO~ C CA~ VO RESULT COUNCIL AYE i NAY t N~V CHMN. CLARKE :BARRY BRAZIL RCHAVOUS CROPP Adopted Final Reading, 12-6-94 Approved ~prry, Jarvis~ Ray and Thorres COUNCI ’,.B. LMEMBER I AYE i NAV ~N.V i I RA I I S_MITHI JR I. i ’i !THOMAS R i i COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ~WAY l N.V. EVAN~ JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MA~C)I NATHAN50N A AI3~ N.V CERTI.CATION ~ECORO P,~m 1~ COUNCIL MIIMBER RAY SMITH ’JR. ’ THOMAS, SR AYE I NAY I N.V.COUNCIL MEMBER’ AYE’ I~AY N.V. EVANS ’ JARVIS L I GHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A.B A__l~t_ N.V Pr n~l voW, C~J~rlFtCATION RECORO I</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
