<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-235">
  <num type="law">10-235</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-03-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-235.pdf">D.C. Law 10-235</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 30</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 10-235, the “District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-689, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-378 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-235 became effective on March 21, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN L MENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10- 235 "District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-689 on first and second readings, November 1, 1994 and December 6, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 27, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-378, and published in the January 6, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 30) and transmitted to Congress on Feburary 3, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-235, effective March 21, 1995. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Confessional Review Period: Feb. 3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 Mar. 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,17,20 ENI OLLED ORI IttAL AN.ACT Codification D, C, ACT IO- 378 District of ColurnDia Code 1995 SupPlementl IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT O]? COLUMBIA DECEMBER 27, 1994 To amend section 7 of the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Element Amendment Act of 1984 to exempt from zoning, governmental uses that were either existent or substantially planned, documented, or invested in prior to May 23, 1990, and to exempt from zoning, the governmental use that exists at the residential treatment and special education facility located at 3050 R Street, N.W and to amend section 6 of the Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Element Amendment Act of 1984 to revise permit issuance restrictions affecting universities and other institutions subject to the campus plan process. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Amendment Act of 1994 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Element Amendment Act of 1984, effective May 23, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-129; D.C. Code § 1-247 et seq is amended as follows 1) Section 7(a D.C. Code § 1-250(a is amended to read as follows a)(1) Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the government shall be subject to zoning 2) Any governmental land uses that were either existent or substantially planned, documented, and invested in prior to May 23, 1990, shall not be subject to zoning 3) The use of government-owned property on Lot 276 in Square 1282, which is located at 3050 R Street, N.W as a residential treatment and special education facility for not more than 24 emotionally disturbed children, ages 6 to 12 years, and as a treatment and special education facility for not more than 15 emotionally disturbed children, ages 6-12, who do not reside at the facility, shall not be subject to zoning 2) Section 6(c D.C. Code § 1-249(c is amended to to read as follows c) When a major new building proposed for a college or university campus, and included in its campus plan, is instead moved off campus, the college or university must submit the plans for the review and approval of the Board of Zoning Adjustment as a specific amendment to its campus plan, limited to review of the change affecting that specific Section 1-250 Section 1-249 ENROLLED ORIGINAL site, before the college or university may substitute another major new building for that campus plan site. ]?or purposes of this subsection, a major new building is defined as one specifically identified in the campus plan. Further, in order for the community to know as quickly as possible the substitute plans for the site, the review and approval of the new plans are to be done on an expedited basis. If the campus plan site is to remain vacant, or if the existing uses on that site are to remain, then the college or university is required to provide each affected advisory neighborhood commission with written notice of that decision within 30 days of the college’s or university’s decision for movement. In such event, no further review by the Board of Zoning and Adjustment is required Sec. 3. In response to the resolution adopted by the National Capital Planning Commission on November 3, 1994, which certified finding of federal interest impact of the Comprehensive Plan Amendments Act of 1994, effective October 6, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-193; 41 DCtt 5536 ef seq the Council, pursuant to section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental l~eorganization Act of 1973, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 779; D.C. Code § 1-2002(a amends section 2(a)(1)(G)(ii) of the Comprehensive Plan Amendments Act of 1994, which amends the definition of "Central Employment Area" in section 107 of the Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital, as follows 1) By striking the phrase "19th Street, N.W north along 19th Street, N.~q to ]? Street, N.~q west on F Street, N.~q to 20th Street, N north along 20th Street, N.N to Pennsylvania Avenue, N.V west along Pennsylvania Avenue, hi.h to 21st Street, N.W and 2) By inserting in its place the phrase "23rd Street, N.W north along 23rd Street, N.~q to Virginia Avenue, N.W southeast along Virginia Avenue, N.~q to 22nd Street, N.W to the northern lot line of 2121 Virginia Avenue, N.W east along the northern lot line of 2121 Virginia Avenue, N.W to the eastern lot line of 2121 Virginia Avenue, N.W south along the eastern lot line of 2121 Virginia Avenue, N.W to E Street, N.W east along E Street, N.W to 21st Street, N.W north along 21st Street, N.W to the northern edge of the rear lot line of the American Red Cross Building on Lot 834 in Square 104, east along the rear lot line of the American Ked Cross Building to 20th Street, N.I4 south along 20th Street, N.W to the northern edge of the rear lot line of the Associated General Contractors of America AGC building on Lot 835 in Square 122, east along the rear lot line of the AGC building to 19th Street, N.W north along 19th Street, N.W to F Street, N.W west on ]? Street, N.~q to 20th Street, N.W north along 20th Street, N.W to Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W west along Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W to 22nd Street, N.W north along 22nd Street, N.I4. to K Street, N.W east along K Street, N.W to 21st Street, N.I4 See. 4 a) Section 7(c) of the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984, effective October 6, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-193; 41 DCR 5914}, is amended by striking the number "60" and inserting the number "210" in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) Section 7(b) of the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Element Amendment Act of 1984, effective October 6, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-193; 41 DCR 5916) is amended by striking the phrase "1 year" and inserting in its place the phrase "16 months See. 5. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Colu~nbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the Digtr~dt of Columbia Municipal Chairmlln ’ ’ Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 27, 1994 CoI.rMcII. OF DISTgJ~CI’ OF COL5,343I L.l. 9er:Lod ¢P_n RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET’ NO: X’_ Item on Consem Calendar XE ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: XE VOICE VOTE: F~ecor(:Iecl vote on ;eauest Absent F~OLL CALL VOTE ESULT Adopted First Approve~ Barry BI0-689 ReadinQ. I]-i-94 COUNCIL MEMBER AYE i NAY I’~Y j NAY j N.V. CHMN CLhR~E i ’ BARRy I BRAZIL i CHAVOUS I i i MASON i l -CRQPP i, I INATHANSON I i i I X Ino,cmTa~ VOle A.B Absem NV Pr~ v~n t n Cons~Ca~ar INV. A.B. JCO.UNCZLMEMBE I~VANS i NTFnnT iA.B. I COUNCIL MEMBER ¯RAY ’!SNITH, JR.THOMAS SR ACT~ON&amp;amp;OAT~ Adopted Final Read,inq, 1,2-6-94 vOiCE VOT Approved Recor(teO vote on re(iuest Thomas C ROLL CAU. VOT RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE f NAY NIV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY CHMN. CLARKE FVAN~ BARRY QARV~ BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT I CH.A..VOUS I ,i i MASON CR(]PP t NATHANSON I x Incltcates Vote A.B Absent N.V, C ~t C ACTION &amp;amp; OAT VOK:E V01~ r’; ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE!NAY N.V, A.B. CHMN. CLA’RKE BARRY ’ ’ BRAZ~IL CHAVbUS CROPP C0UNCILMEMBER LAYE EVANS JARVIS NAY t COUN£1L MEMBER AYE NAY !N.V. I RAY l SMITH JR- THOMAS. X Ircticates Vote LIGHTFOOT ASON NATHANSQN A.B Abs~ N.V es~t n vo~’~ ’ ’ CERTIFICA~ON RECORD N.V, A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V ’ RAY SMITH JR. THOMAS, SR. Secrermy to me Courted ’Dam</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
