<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-226">
  <num type="law">10-226</num>
  <heading type="short">Parks Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-226.pdf">D.C. Law 10-226</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 1</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 10-226, the “Parks Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-443, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Youth Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Deemed approved without the signature of the Mayor on December 28, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-367 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-226 became effective on March 16, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN kwiktag ® 103 228 984 MEN (S) ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT i0-367 District of i 1995 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 28, 1994 To amend An Act To vest in the Commissioners of the District of Columbia control of street parking in said District to authorize the Director of the Department of Recreation and Parks to regulate use of the parks under the control of the District and the Metropolitan Police Department to enforce the regulations. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Parks Amendment Act of 1994 Sec. 2. An Act To vest in the Commissioners of the District of Columbia control of street parking in said District, approved July 1, 1898 (30 Star. 570; D.C. Code § 8-106 et seq is amended by adding a new section 6a to read as follows Sec. 6a. Authority of the Director of the Department of Recreation and Parks Department to regulate District parks a) The Council finds that, in order to protect the public health and safety, environmental and scenic values, natural or cultural resources, equitable allocations and use of District park facilities, and to alleviate conflict among park visitors, it is necessary to implement management responsibilities for District parks b) The Director of the Department may 1) Establish a reasonable schedule of hours for the operation of parks 2) Impose limits, conditions, and restrictions on the public use of parks 3) Close all or a portion of a park area to public use or to a specific use or activity; or 4) Terminate a limit, condition, restriction or any other decision made pursuant to the subsection c)(1) Except in emergency situations, the Director of the Department shall inform the public of closures, designations, use restrictions or conditions, or the termination or relaxation of such, which is of a nature, magnitude and duration that will result in a significant alteration in the public use pattern of the park area, adversely affect the park’s natural, aesthetic, scenic or cultural values, require a long-term or significant modification in the resource management objectives of the unit, or is of a highly controversial nature, by publishing such changes as rulemaking in the District of Columbia Register and a major Washington, D.C. metropolitan newspaper. Not e Sect±on 8-137.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2) Except in emergency situations, prior to implementing or terminating a restriction, condition, public use limit or closure, the Director of the Department shall prepare a written determination justifying the action. That determination shall set forth the reasons why the restriction, condition, public use limit or closure authorized by subsection (b) of this section has been established, and an explanation of why less restrictive measures will not suffice, or in the case of a termination of a restriction, condition, public use limit or closure previously established under subsection (b) of this section, a determination as to why the restriction is no longer necessary and a finding that the termination will not adversely impact park resources. This determination shall be available to the public upon request d) To implement a public use limit, the Director of the Department may establish a permit, registration, or reservation system. Permits shall be issued in accordance with, or in exception to, the criteria in subsection (b) of this section. Applications for use permits may be sent to the Director of the Department, 30 days in advance of the event, by writing a letter which describes the event including the date, day, starting and ending time of the event, a description of what the event will be, and approximately how many people are expected e) Violating a closure, designation, use or activity restriction or condition, schedule of visiting hours, or public use limit is prohibited. The District of Columbia Metropolitan Police Department may enforce the provisions contained in subsection (b) of this section. Any person violating the provisions of subsection (b) of this section may be punished by a fine of not more than $100 or by imprisonment for not more than 90 days, or both Sec. 3. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental l~eorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and ENROLLED ORIGINAL publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal P~egulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia DEEMED APPROVED WITHOUT SIGNATURE UPON EXPIRATION OF IO-DAY MAYORAL REVIEW PERIOD. NOT SIGNED Mayor District of Columbia December 28, 1994 @ Item on Consent CaJenclat ~ACTION &amp;amp; 0ATE VOICE VOTE COL"~’wcn- 0~’ D~C’I’ 0~’ COLB"~J~I_4. Ozc=:L1. 9e ocl Ten RECORD OF OFRClAL COUNCIL VOTE CCKET NO: Adopted First l~ading, 11-1-94 Approved BI0-443 ~OsenI ROLL CALL "IOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE I NAY I N.V MEMBER ~v A.B. COUNC:L MEMBER JwYE ,NAY ~n(31cales V Ole Iter~ on Consent Calend ’:(ACTION ,I OATE Adopted Final Reading, 12-6-94 ~vOICE VOTE Recor(:l~:l vote on RO~ CA~ VO RESULT ’COU~CILM~BER AYE I NAY I N.V lAB. CHMN C~RK BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP I It AYE NAY N.V.COUNCIL MEMBER FVANq LIGHTFOOT J NATHANSON l A~S~rlI N.V Pre~e~t nOt volln CERTIRCATION RECORD JCOUNCI.L MEMBER AYE S~l TH J R THOMAS R_ { iNAY ACTION vQcE VOTE ROLL CALL VOT RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. ±CI:IMN CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL r. CHAVOUS CROPP l I I X I.Q(:ale~ Vote COUNCIL MEMBER EVANS JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHAN~QN AYE NAY N.V. COIJNClLMEMBB AYE NAY N.V. RAY SMITH JR. T.HOMAS, SR. A.B A_Meqt_ N.V Prese.t not CERTIFICATION RECORD o me Council Dale COUNCIL O~IC Or ~H G~N~.RAL COUNS~.L WASSmNGTON, D.C. 2009 C-8 P3.~9 TRANSMITTAL OF ENROLLED LEGISLATION Short Title: Parks Amendment Act of Bill #10-443 Act Date Transmitted to LSD: Received by LSD: cc: cc: Councilmember Lightfoot Codification Counsel (with attachment with attachment) Please notify me of any error/comment within 24 hours. II ARANCE OF ENROLLED LEGISLATION ~gislative Counsel CFification Counsel Office of~ Secretary Date Date Date III. CLEARANCE OF CORRESPONDENCE BY LSU Letter(s) to the Mayor Date Letter(s) to Congress Rev. 12/22/92 Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON. D.C. 20004 DEC. I The Honorable Sharon Pratt Kelly Mayor of the District of Columbia 441 4th Street, N.W llth Floor Washington, D.C. 20001 Re: Transmittal of Bill I0-443 Parks Amendment Act of 1994" Date of Council Action: 12-06-94 Dear Mayor Kelly: The above named enacted bill is hereby transmitted in accordance with Section 404(e) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to this bill, for your information, is the report of the Council’s standing committee with jurisdiction over this matter. Since re~.y 6avid Cl~rke Chairman of the Council Enclosure AN ACT EHROLLEO ORIGINAL District of Columbia i 1995 SuPp[e.~lent] IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTKICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act To vest in the Commissioners of the District of Columbia control of street parking in said District to authorize the Director of the Department of Reereat|on and Parks to regulate use of the parks under the control of the District and the Metropolitan Police Department to enforce the regulations. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTKICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Parks Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. An Act To vest in the Commissioners of the District of Columbia control of street parking in said District, approved July 1, 1898 (30 Star. 570; D.C. Code § 8-106 et seq is amended by adding a new section 6a to read as follows See. 6a. Authority of the Director of the Department of l{eereation and Parks Department to regulate District parks a) The Council finds that, in order to protect the public health and safety, environmental and scenic values, natural or cultural resources, equitable allocations and use of District park facilities, and to alleviate conflict among park visitors, it is necessary to implement management responsibilities for District parks b) The Director of the Department may 1) Establish a reasonable schedule of hours for the operation of parks 2) Impose limits, conditions, and restrictions on the public use of parks 3) Close all or a portion of a park area to public use or to a specific use or activity; or 4) Terminate a limit, condition, restriction or any other decision made pursuant to the subsection c)(1) Except in emergency situations, the Director of the Department shall inform the public of closures, designations, use restrictions or conditions, or the termination or relaxation of such, which is of a nature, magnitude and duration that will result in a significant alteration in the public use pattern of the park area, adversely affect the park’s natural, aesthetic, scenic or cultural values, require a long-term or significant modification in the resource management objectives of the unit, or is of a highly controversial nature, by publishing such changes as rulemaking in the District of Columbia Register and a major Washington, D.C. metropolitan newspaper. Not e Section 8-137.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2) Except in emergency situations, prior to implementing or terminating a restriction, condition, public use limit or closure, the Director of the Department shall prepare a written determination Justifying the action. That determination shall set forth the reasons why the restriction, condition, public use limit or closure authorized by subsection (b) of this section has been established, and an explanation of why less restrictive measures will not suffice, or in the case of a termination of a restriction, condition, public use limit or closure previously established under subsection (b) of this section, a determination as to why the restriction is no longer necessary and a finding that the termination will not adversely impact park resources. This determination shall be available to the public upon request d) To implement a public use limit, the Director of the Department may establish a permit, registration, or reservation system. Permits shall be issued in accordance with, or in exception to, the criteria in subsection (b) of this section. Applications for use permits may be sent to the Director of the Department, 30 days in advance of the event, by writing a letter which describes the event including the date, day, starting and ending time of the event, a description of what the event will be, and approximately how many people are expected e) Violating a closure, designation, use or activity restriction or condition, schedule of visiting hours, or public use limit is prohibited. The District of Columbia Metropolitan Police Department may enforce the provisions contained in subsection (b) of this section. Any person violating the provisions of subsection (b) of this section may be punished by a fine of not more than $100 or by imprisonment for not more than 90 days, or both Sec. 3. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and EHROLLEO ORIGINAL publication in either the Di§trict of Columbia Register, the District Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal l~egulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia CO~,’NCTL OF TH~ D~CY OP COLU~J~BT.A It~m on Consem Calenaa¢ I~C~(}N &amp;amp; 0AI’ VCIC~ VOW: RE’CORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIl. VOTE DccIIL~r NO: Adopted First ~cj, 11-1-94 BI0-443 Barry ACTION &amp;amp; OATE ~VOICE VOTE ~ecOr~ vOt~ on r~ Ab 0~ CA~ VO ESULT C BTIFtCATION ~COFIO 3a~e Adopted Final iReading, 12-6-94 ~ARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CRI3PP I X In¢llcall~ VO~ NATHANSQN ACTION &amp;amp; OAI vOK~E VOTE POLL CALL VOI SULT LCHMN. CLARKE ’I-’ ’ _BARRY ,BRAZIL I EVANS" JARVIS LIGHTF, OOT, NAY N.V. AS COUNClL M~=MI~,ER AYE ~AY V. RAY SMITH: JR THOMAS, SR CHAVOU$ MASON CROPR. i" I i NATHANSON [ ’ 1 ¯ x ca~ vo~ A&amp;amp A v Prelim x CERTIF~CA’nON me Coutcw Oam "</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
