<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-214">
  <num type="law">10-214</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Retirement Board Judicial Appointment Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1995-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-214.pdf">D.C. Law 10-214</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 8034</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0613">
      <narrative>Law 10-214, the “District of Columbia Retirement Board Judicial Appointment Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-613, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 15, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-351 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-214 became effective on March 16, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENRO LMENT(S) kwiktag® 103 221 571 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-214 "District of Columbia Retirement Board Judicial Appointment Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-613 on first and second readings, November 1, 1994 and December 6, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 15, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-351, and published in the December 23, 1994, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 41 page 8034) and transmitted to Congress on January 31, 1995, for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-214, effective March 16, 1995 A Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-da_v Congessional Review Period; 31 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15 AN ACT D,C. ACT i0-351 EHROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Code | 1 Supplernent~ IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 15, 1994 To amend the District of Columbia Retirement P~eform Act to provide for alternate representation for judges on the District of Columbia Retirement Board. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTKICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Retirement Board Judicial Appointment Amendment Act of 1994 Sec. 2. Section 121(b)(1)(A)(vii) of the District of Columbia Retirement l~eform Act, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Star. 870; D.C. Code § 1-711(b)(1)(A)(vii is amended to read as follows vii) One senior judge and an alternate senior judge appointed by the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration of the District of Columbia Section 1-711 Sec. 3. This act shall take eJ~fect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 15, 1994 @ Item on Consent CalenO&amp;amp;r R ACT1CN &amp;amp; E)AT vOIC~ VOTE ecor~ecl vo{e on OLL CALL VOTE ESULT ;COUNCIL MEMBER I AYE I NAY N V CHMN CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP I COUNCIL OF THE DISTItICT OF COLEHBL4. RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 11-1-94 BI0-613 Approved I FVANS 1 i 1. [ r~HT~nr)T MASON ,{ NATHANSON COUNC:L MEMBER i ¥E .NAY I SMITH, JR. THOMAS~ SR. ’ X n(l~cates vote A AI3seflt N. V lires~nt.,nOt votln t F’°’~’~° z item Consul Ci~ar Adopted Final Readinq, 12-6-94 CROPP ACTION &amp;amp; OAT vO~E VOT~ AbS~m: ROLL CALL VOTe RESULT C09NCIL MEMBER _CHMN.’CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL ~CHAVOUS CROPP AYE NAY [,N.V. A.B. i X Ir~lic~t~ vote COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. E’B. COUNCIL~EMBER AYE NAY’ I~.V. EVANS ’ RAY JARV,IS SMITH. JR. LIGHTFOOT T,HOMAS, SR. MASON NATHANSQN A.B A__l’~mi_ N.V Preset, it rl ’ ’ ’ CERTIFICATION RECORD Sec ary ~o me Council Dale</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
