<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-78">
  <num type="law">10-78</num>
  <heading type="short">Alternative Fuels Technology Amendment Act of 1993</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-03-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-78.pdf">D.C. Law 10-78</citation>
      <citation type="register">40 DCR 8464</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0047">
      <narrative>Law 10-78, the “Alternative Fuels Technology Amendment Act of 1993,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-47, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and the Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 5, 1993, and November 2, 1993, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 17, 1993, it was assigned Act No. 10-151 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-78 became effective on March 17, 1994.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwikta 062 313 944 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-78 "Alternative Fuels Technology Amendment /tct of 1993" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-47 on first and second readings, October 5, 1993, and November 2, 1993, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 17, 1993, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-151, published in the December 10, 1993, edition of the D.C R_egi.ster Vol. 40 page 8464) and transmitted to Congress on November 24, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-78, eff~ective March 17 1994 lli&amp;gt;i ¯ t }/i’ Ol~airman of the Council Dates Counted Durin~ the 30-dayCon gressional Review Period: November 24,26 January 25,26 February 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,22,23,24,25,28 March 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16 AN ACT D,C, ACT i0-151 1994 Enrolled Original Codiflca iort District of Co mbia Code Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 17, 1993 To amend the Alternative Fuels Technology Act of 1990 to extend the deadline for the submission of an exemption report by the Mayor, the submission of a comprehensive plan by each owner or operator of a commercial fleet, the requirement that an owner or operator of a commercial fleet utilize by conversion or procurement a percentage of motor vehicles powered by clean alternative fuels, and issuance of the rules to implement the provisions of the act, for 2 years beyond the present requirements. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Alternative Fuels Technology Amendment Act of 1993 See. 2. The Alternative Fuels Technology Act of 1990, effective March 8, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-243; D.C. Code 40-2001 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3(b D.C. Code § 40-2002(2 is amended by striking the year "1991" and inserting the year "1993" in its place b) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 40-2003) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the year "1992" and inserting the year "1994" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended as follows A) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the year "1993" and inserting the year "1995" in its place (B) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the year "1994" and inserting the year "1996" in its place (C) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the year "1995" and inserting the year "1997" in its place (D) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the year "1996" and inserting the year "1998" in its place (E) Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the year "1997" and inserting the year "1999" in its place (F) Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the year "1998" and inserting the year "2000" in its place (G) Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the year "1999" and inserting the year "2001" in its place (H) Paragraph (8) is amended by striking the year "2000" and inserting the year "2002" in its place Note. Sectio 40-2002 Note. Section 40-2003 Enrolled Original (c) Section 6 (D.C. Code § 40-2005) is amended by striking the year "1991" and inserting the year "1993" in its place. Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations Council of the District of Columbia Note. Section 40-2005 z/Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED ¯ November 17, 1993 2 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COUNCIL OF T~E DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, Bill 10-47 10-5-93 X VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on. request Absent: Approved all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. CHMN CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPp A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE EVANS ,]ARVTS I_IGHTF~OT MASON N~THANSON NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER P~Y SMITH, JR. THOMAS’~-SR. AYE j NAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting Itemln C o r caa’rYe tn°d t;e COuncit ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: CERTIFICATION RECORD D~te Adopted Final Reading, 11-2-93 Approved VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Barry and Mason ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIl CHAVOUS CROPP X Indicates Vote []ltemton conS;e~ t~etcaalrYe t~°dt;e Council COUNCIL MEMBER EVAN-£ ’ JARV LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. t A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE RAY- SMITH, JR. THOMAS. SR. Date NAY t N.V. i [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE BARRY F’BRAZIL ,CHAVOUS CROPP X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER EVANS JARVIS LIGHTF00T MASON ~ATHANSON A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER RAY .SMI i’H JR. THOMASI SR Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
