<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-79">
  <num type="law">10-79</num>
  <heading type="short">Privatization Procurement and Contract Procedures Amendment Act of 1993</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-03-19</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-79.pdf">D.C. Law 10-79</citation>
      <citation type="register">40 DCR 8696</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0285">
      <narrative>Law 10-79, the “Privatization Procurement and Contract Procedures Amendment Act of 1993,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-285, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 21, 1993, and November 2, 1993, respectively. Vetoed by the Mayor on November 19, 1993, Council overrode the veto on December 7, 1993, and the Bill was assigned Act No. 10-153 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-79 became effective on March 19, 1994.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwikta 062 312 166 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-79 "Privatization Procurement and Contract Procedures Amendment Act of 1993 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-285 on first, amended first and second readings, September 21, 1993, October 5, 1993 and November 2, 1993, respectively. On November 19, 1993, Bill No. 10-285 was vetoed by the Mayor. The Council overrode the Mayor’s veto on December 7, 1993. As a result of the Council’s override, Bill No. 10-285 was re-enacted and assigned Act No. 10-153. The Act was published in the December 24 1993, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 40 page 8696) and and transmitted to Congress on December 17, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-79, effective March 19, 1994. DAVIB A. CLARKE C’hairman of the Council Dates Counted Durin~ the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January 25,26 February 1,2,3,a,7,8,9,10,11,22,23,24,25,28 March 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18 Enrolled Original Codification AN ACT Dlstrlet of Columbia Code D, C, ACT 10-153 1994 Supplemem) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 7, 1993 To amend the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 and the Nursing Home and Community Residence Facility Residents’ Protection Act of 1985 to establish policies and procedures for any contract, including any lease or other agreement for privatization or contracting-out, with the private sector to provide goods or services to or on behalf of the District of Columbia that currently are provided by employees, departments, or agencies of the District government. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Privatization Procurement and Contract Procedures Amendment Act of 1993 See. 2. The District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1181.1 ef seqo is amended as follows a) Section 104(a D.C. Code § 1-1181.4(a is amended as follows 1) By striking the word "Nothing" and inserting in its place the phrase "Except as provided in this subsection, nothing and (2) By adding at the end of the subsection the following sentence to read as follows Any contract, including a lease or other agreement, or any contracting policies and procedures relating to such contracts, to provide goods and services to or on behalf of the District government that currently are provided by employees, agencies, or branches of the District government shall comply with the privatization contracts and procedures requirements of section 105b b) A new section 105b is added to read as follows Sec. 105b. Privatization contracts and procedures requirements a) Any contract, including a lease or other agreement, or any contracting policies and procedures relating to such contracts, to provide goods and services to or on behalf of the District government that currently are provided by employees, departments, or agencies of the District government shall provide that 1) A cost analysis comparing the in-house costs of providing the service with the costs associated with contracting for the service shall be completed for each contract proposed pursuant to this section 2) Contracting out will provide savings over the duration of the contract of at least 10 Section 1-1181.4 New Section i-i181.5b Enrolled Original 3) Any contractor who is awarded a contract that displaces District government employees shall offer comparable employment to the displaced employees at rates of wages and benefits comparable to the wages and benefits paid to District government employees 4) Any solicitation for proposed contracts issued pursuant to this section shall include information concerning the procedure by which current District government employees may exercise the right to bid on the contracts 5) An assessment of the economic impact on the District shall be completed for each contract proposed pursuant to this section 6) Prior notification shall be provided to affected District government employees 6 months prior to any adverse impact on the employees or on the date the contract is signed, whichever is sooner; and 7) For these contracts which provide services essential to the health or safety of District residents, a determination and findings that the contracting out will not adversely affect the recipients b) The Mayor shall submit to the Council the cost analysis comparing the in-house costs of providing goods and services with the costs associated with any contract for goods and services for any contract described in subsection (a)(1) of this section made by any agency of the District government which is subordinate to the Mayor c) The Mayor shall submit to the Council any assessment of the economic impact on the District made pursuant to subsection (a)(5) of this section d) Prior to the award of any contract, and unless otherwise prohibited by statute or the District Charter, the Mayor, and all independent agencies and entities of the District government, shall submit to the Council any contract, including a lease or other agreement, or any other contracting policies and procedures relating to such contracts, to provide goods and services to or on behalf of the District that currently are provided by employees, departments, or agencies of the District government for a 45-day review period, during which the Council may approve or disapprove the contract. If the Council takes no action during the 45-day review period, the contract will be deemed approved e) No cost analysis or economic impact assessment shall be submitted to the Council under this section during any time that the Council is on recess, according to its rules, nor shall any time period provided in this section or in the Council’s rules continue to run during any time that the Council is on recess See. 3. The Nursing Home and Community l~esidence Facility Kesidents’ Protection Act of 1985, effective February 24, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-108; D.C. Code § 32-1401 et seq is amended by adding a new section 501a to read as follows Sec. 501a. Privatization contracts, leases, provider agreements, and procedures requirements a) Any contract, lease, or provider agreement relative to any facility covered by this act, or any policies or procedures relating to such contracts, leases, or provider agreements, to provide goods and services to or on behalf of the District of Columbia that currently are provided by employees, departments, or agencies of the District of Columbia shall provide that New Section 32-1462 2 Enrolled Original 1) A cost analysis comparing the in-house costs of providing the service with the costs associated with contracting for the service shall be completed for each contract proposed pursuant to this section 2) Contracting out will provide savings over the duration of the contract of at least 10 3) Any contractor who is awarded a contract that displaces District government employees shall offer comparable employment to the displaced employees at rates of wages and benefits comparable to the wages and benefits paid to District government employees 4) Any solicitation for proposed contracts issued pursuant to this section shall include information concerning the procedure by which current District government employees may exercise the right to bid on the contracts 5) An assessment of the economic impact on the District shall be completed for each contract proposed pursuant to this section 6) Prior notification shall be provided to affected District government employees 6 months prior to any adverse impact on the employees or on the date the contract is signed, whichever is sooner; and 7) For those contracts which provide services essential to the health or safety of District residents, a determination and findings that the contracting out will not adversely affect the recipients b) The Mayor shall submit to the Council the cost analysis comparing the in-house costs of providing goods and services with the costs associated with any contract for goods and services for any contract described in subsection (a)(1) of this section made by any agency of the District government which is subordinate to the Mayor c) The Mayor shall submit to the Council any assessment of the economic impact on the District of Columbia for any contract that is described in subsection (a)(5) of this section made by any agency which is subordinate to the Mayor d) Prior to the award of any contract, and unless otherwise prohibited by statute or the District Charter, the Mayor, and all independent agencies and entities of the District government, shall submit to the Council any contract, including a lease or other agreement, or any other contracting policies and procedures relating to such contracts, to provide goods and services to or on behalf of the District that currently are provided by employees, departments, or agencies of the District government for a 45-day review period, during which the Council may approve or disapprove the contract. If the Council takes no action during the 45-day review period, the contract will be deemed approved e) No cost analysis or economic impact assessment shall be submitted to the Council under this section during any time that the Council is on recess, according to its rules, nor shall any time period provided in this section or in the Council’s rules continue to run during any time that the Council is on recess Sec. 4 a) The District of Columbia Village Expenditure Prohibition Emergency Act of 1993, Council override of Mayoral veto July 13, 1993 (D.C. Act 10-45; 40 DClZ 5444 is repealed b) The District of Columbia Expenditure Prohibition Temporary Act of 1993, Council override of Mayoral veto July 21, 1993 (D.C. Act 10-60; 40 DClZ 5506 is repealed. Enrolled Original Sec. 5. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia VETOED Mayor District of Columbia November 19, 1993 COUNCIL OVERRIDE, 12-7-93 Item on Consent Calendar ’~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill 10-285 Adopted First Reading, 9-21-93 Approved Evans 1 of 2 ROLL CALL VOTE: RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE BARRY ’_,B.RAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP AYE NAY N.V. A.B. X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER EVANS J~RVTS I IGHTFNNT MASON NATHANSON A.B Absent tAYE Se~tary to the Council Item on Consent Calendar NAY I N.V. ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER RAY SMITH JR. THOMAS~ SR AYE NAY N.V. Date Adopted Amended First Reading, 10-5-93 VOICE VOTE: Approved, Brazil voted no Recorded vote on request Absent: Cropp and Smith @ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP X Indic~es Vote I ’ COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.COUNCILMEMBER EVAN£ jARV LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting SM,ITU: JR. THOMAS. SR ’i i Sec ret~’~.o~i e [] Item on Consent Calendar I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: CERTIFICATION RECORD Council Date Adopted Final Reading, 11-2-93 ApprovedVOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Lightfoot [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B CHMN.,CLARKE BARRY "BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP X Indicates Vote Council COUNCILMEMBER EVANS JARV[S L!GHTF00T MASON NATHANSON A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY N.V. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER RAY ~MITH~ JR. THOMAS~ SR. N.V Present, not voting Date AYE NAY N.V. Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF T[[E DISTRICT OF COLU~BL4 Council Period RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Council Override, 12-7-93 Bill 10-285 Approved Recordedvoteonrequest Absent: Barry, Chavous, Cropp, Nathanson, Smith and 2 of 2 Thomas ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHHN CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP AYE NAY N.V. A.B. X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER I AYE NAY iNV. I A.B. EVANS t JARyIS I ITGHTFQQT MASON NATHANSON A.8 Absent N.V Present, not voting Item on Consent Calendar CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER RAY SMITH, JR. THOMAS SR. AYE NAY N.V, Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: C VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent q ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP X Indicates Vote COUNCILMEMBER ARVi~ LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER RAm SMI~t JR. THOMAS- SR AYE NAY N.V. Secretary to tl~e Council C] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Date Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCILMEMBER CHMN CLARKE &amp;gt;BARRY "BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP AYE NAY I N.V, A.B. X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER EVANS JARVIS LIG~TFO~T ~ASON NATHAN{ON A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J ’ I COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. RAY SMITH~ JR. THOMAS~ SR AoB. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
