<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-251</num>
  <heading>Remaining powers, duties, and functions of Comptroller transferred to Superintendent of Banking and Financial Institutions.</heading>
  <text>Any powers, duties, and functions of the Comptroller of the Currency with respect to building associations and building and loan associations operating in the District of Columbia which are not transferred to the Federal Home Loan Bank Board by the specific statutory amendments herein contained are also hereby transferred from the Comptroller of the Currency to the Federal Home Loan Bank Board. After April 11, 1986, the powers, duties, and functions referred to in this section shall reside in the Superintendent of Banking and Financial Institutions [now Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking].</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 82-1-ch404" path="§4">Sept. 15, 1951, 65 Stat. 324, ch. 404, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-63" type="History">Nov. 23, 1985, D.C. Law 6-63,§ 106(e)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-107" type="History">as added Apr. 11, 1986, D.C. Law 6-107, § 2(k), 33 DCR 1168</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 26-404a.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 26-505.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§26-710">§ 26-710</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">The words “specific statutory amendments,” referred to in the section, means the amendments made by §§ 1 to 3 of the Act of September 15, 1951, 65 Stat. 324, ch. 404.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">The “Home Loan Bank Board,” formerly referred to throughout this section, was changed to “Federal Home Loan Bank Board” by § 109(a)(3) of the Act of August 11, 1955, 69 Stat. 640. Subsequently, the Federal Home Loan Bank Board was abolished. For provisions relating to the abolition of the Federal Home Loan Bank Board and the transfer of functions, personnel and property of that agency, see §§ 401 to 406 of Pub. L. 101-73, set out as a note under  12 U.S.C. § 1437.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
