<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-154">
  <num type="law">15-154</num>
  <heading type="short">Elimination of Outdated Crimes Amendment Act of 2003</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2004-04-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-154.pdf">D.C. Law 15-154</citation>
      <citation type="register">50 DCR 10996</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0079">
      <narrative>Law 15-154, the “Elimination of Outdated Crimes Amendment Act of 2003”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-79, which was referred to Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 7, 2003, and November 4, 2003, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 2003, it was assigned Act No. 15-255 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-154 became effective on April 29, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act For the promotion of anatomical science and to prevent the desecration of graves in the District of Columbia, An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, The Act of Parliament, 9 Anne, c. 14, § 8, An act to prevent cruelty to children or animals in the district of Columbia, and for other purposes, An Act To prohibit the business of debt adjusting in the District of Columbia except as an incident to the lawful practice of law as an activity engaged in by a nonprofit corporation or association, the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953, An Act To further regulate banking, banks, trust companies, and building and loan associations in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, An Act To provide that all persons employing female help in stores, shops, or manufactories in the District of Columbia shall provide seats for the same when not actively employed, An Act For the relief of street- car motormen, Chapter 29 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code, and the District of Columbia Traffic Act of 1925 to repeal outdated and unnecessary criminal provisions. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Elimination of Outdated Crimes Amendment Act of 2003 Sec. 2. Section 8 of An Act For the promotion of anatomical science and to prevent the desecration of graves in the District of Columbia, approved April 29, 1902 (32 Stat. 175; D.C. Official Code § 3-208 is repealed. Sec. 3. An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1189; D.C. Official Code § 4-118 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 809 (D.C. Official Code § 22-101) is repealed b) Section 874 (D.C. Official Code § 22-201) is repealed c) Section 822 (D.C. Official Code § 22-304) is repealed d) Section 852 (D.C. Official Code § 22-1302) is repealed e) Section 853 (D.C. Official Code § 22-1303) is repealed f) Section 854 (D.C. Official Code § 22-1304) is repealed g) Section 869a (D.C. Official Code § 22-1709) is repealed h) Section 869b (D.C. Official Code § 22-1710) is repealed i) Section 869c (D.C. Official Code § 22-1711) is repealed j) Section 869d (D.C. Official Code § 22-1712) is repealed k) Section 825 (D.C. Official Code § 22-3304) is repealed l) Section 1 (D.C. Official Code § 45-401) is amended as follows: Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2004 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Repeal § 3-208 Repeal §§ 22-101, 22-201, 22-304, 22-1302, 22-1303, 22-1304, 22-1709, 22-1710, 22-1711, 22-1712, 22-3304 Amend ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 1) Designate the existing language as subsection (a 2) A new subsection (b) is added to read as follows: “(b) The repeal of a criminal statute in the District of Columbia that is declaratory of or in abrogation of a common law crime shall not reinstate the common law crime.” m) section 1289 (D.C. Official Code § 46-407) is repealed n) Section 1290 (D.C. Official Code § 46-408) is repealed. Sec. 4. The Act of Parliament, 9 Anne, c. 14, § 8 (1710; D.C. Official Code § 22-408 is repealed. Sec. 5. Section 5 of An act to prevent cruelty to children or animals in the district of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved June 25, 1892 (27 Stat. 61; D.C. Official Code § 22-1014 is repealed. Sec. 6. An Act To prohibit the business of debt adjusting in the District of Columbia except as an incident to the lawful practice of law as an activity engaged in by a nonprofit corporation or association, approved May 22, 1970 (84 Stat. 264; D.C. Official Code § 22- 1201 is repealed. Sec. 7. Section 214 of the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953, approved June 29, 1953 (67 Stat. 99; D.C. Official Code § 22-1602 is repealed. Sec. 8. Section 7 of An Act To further regulate banking, banks, trust companies, and building and loan associations in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved March 4, 1933 (47 Stat. 1567; D.C. Official Code § 26-108 is repealed. Sec. 9. An Act To provide that all persons employing female help in stores, shops, or manufactories in the District of Columbia shall provide seats for the same when not actively employed, approved March 2, 1895 (28 Stat. 964; D.C. Official Code §§ 32-831 and 832 is repealed. Sec. 10. An Act For the relief of street-car motormen, approved March 3, 1905 (33 Stat. 1001; D.C. Official Code § 35-205 is repealed. Sec. 11. Chapter 29 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase "47-2905. Posting of price scale and insert the phrase "47-2905. Posting of price scale. [Repealed]" in its place 2) Strike the phrase "47-2906. Penalty for failure to post price scale and insert the phrase "47-2906. Penalty for failure to post price scale. [Repealed]" in its place b) Section 47-2905 is repealed c) Section 47-2906 is repealed. Sec. 12. Section 11 of the District of Columbia Traffic Act of 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1124; D.C. Official Code § 50-2207.01 is repealed. § 45-401 Repeal § 46-407 Repeal § 46-408 Repeal § 22-408 Repeal § 22-1014 Repeal § 22-1201 Repeal § 22-1602 Repeal § 26-108 Repeal § 32-831 Repeal § 32-832 Repeal § 35-205 Repeal § 47-2905 Repeal § 47-2906 Repeal § 50-2207.01 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Sec. 13. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 14. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
