<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-156">
  <num type="law">15-156</num>
  <heading type="short">Interim Disability Assistance Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2004-05-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-156.pdf">D.C. Law 15-156</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 3393</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0608">
      <narrative>Law 15-156, the “Interim Disability Assistance Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-608, which was referred to Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 3, 2004, and March 2, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 18, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-391 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-156 became effective on May 18, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend section 407 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982 to require that applications for Interim Disability Assistance be processed with reasonable promptness, to authorize the Mayor to establish rules for the application process, and to establish that the monthly grant amount shall be the same as that for a family size of one for an individual or 2 for a couple under the Temporary Assistance to Needy Families program. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Interim Disability Assistance Amendment Act of 2004 Sec. 2. Section 407 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 13-252; D.C. Official Code § 4-204.07 is amended as follows a) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows b) Applications for IDA shall be approved or disapproved by the Mayor with reasonable promptness. Other aspects of the application process, including good-cause exceptions to the application-processing standard, shall be determined by rules established by the Mayor. The monthly grant amount shall be the same as that for a family size of one for an individual or 2 for a couple under the Temporary Assistance to Needy Families program, as determined under section 552 b) Subsection (d) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1)(C) is amended by striking the phrase "applicable to the TANF program" and inserting the phrase "established by the Mayor" in its place 2) Paragraph (2) is amended as follows A) Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the word "and" at the end B) Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the phrase "number and inserting the phrase "number; and" in its place C) A new subparagraph (D) is added to read as follows D) As a condition of eligibility, an applicant for or recipient of IDA Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2004 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 4-204.07 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. shall cooperate with an entity designated by the Mayor to provide case management and legal advocacy in the SSI application and appeal process Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
