<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-195">
  <num type="law">15-195</num>
  <heading type="short">Eastern Market Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2004-12-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-195.pdf">D.C. Law 15-195</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 7590</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0316">
      <narrative>Law 15-195, the “Eastern Market Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-316, which was referred to the Subcommittee on Human Rights, Latino Affairs and Property. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 1, 2004, and June 29, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 19, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-469 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-195 became effective on December 7, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Eastern Market Real Property Asset Management and Outdoor Vending Act of 1998 to eliminate term limitations for Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee members that are subject to them and to change the composition of the Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee by eliminating the Eastern Market Tenants Council member, by giving a full vote both to the food market inside vendor and the representative from the farmers’ line, by keeping the member from the Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which Eastern Market is sited and eliminating the other Advisory Neighborhood Commission member, by giving the Mayor’s representative a vote, by requiring the Ward 6 Councilmember’s representative to be a resident in the ward and giving the Ward 6 Councilmember’s representative a vote, and to require the Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee to conform its bylaws to these amendments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Eastern Market Amendment Act of 2004”. Sec. 2. Section 12 of the Eastern Market Real Property Asset Management and Outdoor Vending Act of 1998, effective April 16, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-228; D.C. Official Code § 37-111 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is repealed 2) Paragraph (5) is amended to read as follows: “(5) One member who shall be a resident of Ward 6 and who is appointed by the Ward 6 member of the Council, to serve as a voting member;” 3) Paragraph (6) is amended to read as follows: “(6) One member appointed by the Mayor, to serve as a voting member;” 4) Paragraph (7) is repealed 5) Paragraph (8) is amended to read as follows: “(8) Two food market vendors, one from the merchants in the South Hall and the Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2004 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 37-111 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. other from the farmer’s line, and one non-food market vendor to be selected by those market vendors, respectively, each of whom serves as a voting member.” b) Subsection (c) is amended to read as follows: “(c) Members of the EMCAC shall serve for 2-year terms, except that the representative from ANC 6B shall not serve for any period longer than his or her service as a Commissioner. ANC 6B shall identify the EMCAC representative within 45 days after April 16, 1999. To create staggered terms, the initial non-ANC members shall determine by lot that half shall serve for one year.” c) Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase “With the exception of the non- voting representative of the Tenants Council and the voting representatives of the food market vendors and non-food market vendors,” and inserting the phrase “With the exception of the voting representatives of the food market vendors and non-food market vendors,” in its place d) Subsection (f) is amended by adding a sentence at the end to read as follows: “Within 90 days after the effective date of the Eastern Market Amendment Act of 2004, passed on second reading on June 29, 2004 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-316 the EMCAC shall revise its bylaws to be consistent with the act.” e) Subsection (i)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “and one member to represent the Tenants Council as a non-voting member on the EMCAC”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.2(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
