<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-107">
  <num type="law">15-107</num>
  <heading type="short">BOARD OF VETERINARY EXAMINERS AMENDMENT ACT OF 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2004-03-30</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-107.pdf">D.C. Law 15-107</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 1338</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0149"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Veterinary Practice Act of 1982 to reduce the size of the Board of Veterinary Examiners from 7 members to 5 members. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Board of Veterinary Examiners Amendment Act of 2004”. Sec. 2. Section 6 of the Veterinary Practice Act of 1982, effective March 9, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-171; D.C. Official Code § 3-505 is amended as follows a) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows: “(b) The Board shall consist of 5 members appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council. Four members of the Board shall be licensed veterinarians and one member shall be a consumer. No full-time or part-time officer or member of any school of veterinary medicine shall be eligible for appointment to the Board.” b) Subsection (f) is amended to read as follows: “(f) Of the members first appointed to the Board under the Board of Veterinary Examiners Amendment Act of 2004, passed on 2nd reading on January 6, 2004 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-149 2 licensed members shall be appointed to serve terms of 3 years. The 2 licensed members and one consumer member whose nominations to the Board were deemed approved by the Council on January 13, 2003, shall continue to serve the remainder of their 3-year terms after the effective date of the Board of Veterinary Examiners Amendment Act of 2004.” c) Subsection (h) is repealed. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement contained in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2004 Spring Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 3-505 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
