<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-18">
  <num type="law">15-18</num>
  <heading type="short">Presidential Primary Election Amendment Act of 2003</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2003-06-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-18.pdf">D.C. Law 15-18</citation>
      <citation type="register">50 DCR 3389</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0081">
      <narrative>Law 15-18, the “Presidential Primary Election Amendment Act of 2003”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-81, which was referred to Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 4, 2003, and April 1, 2003, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 15, 2003, it was assigned Act No. 15-65 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-18 became effective on June 21, 2003.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend AN ACT To regulate the election of delegates representing the District of Columbia to national political conventions, and for other purposes, to change the dates for holding elections to allow the District of Columbia to hold the first Presidential primary election every 4 years. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Presidential Primary Election Amendment Act of 2003 Sec. 2. AN ACT To regulate the election of delegates representing the District of Columbia to national political conventions, and for other purposes, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 699; D.C. Official Code §1-1001.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 5(b)(1 D.C. Official Code §1-1001.05(b)(1 is amended by striking the phrase “1st Tuesday in May” and inserting the phrase “2nd Tuesday in January” in its place b) Section 10(a D.C. Official Code §1-1001.10(a is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended to read as follows: “(a)(1) The election of the officials referred to in section 1(1) shall be held on the 1st Tuesday after the 2nd Monday in September of each presidential election year. The elections of the officials referred to in section 1(2) and (3 and of officials designated pursuant to section 1(4 and the primary under section 5(b) shall be held on the 2nd Tuesday in January of each presidential election year.” (2) Paragraph (3)(A) is amended by striking the phrase “on the1st Tuesday in May of each even-numbered year which is a presidential election year, and in other even- numbered years, on the 1st Tuesday after the 2nd Monday in September” and inserting the phrase “on the 1st Tuesday after the 2nd Monday in September of each even-numbered year” in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2003 Supp. West Group Publisher Amend §1-1001.05 Amend §1-1001.10 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D. C. Official § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02 (c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
