<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-152">
  <num type="law">15-152</num>
  <heading type="short">Government Employer-Assisted Housing Program Teacher, Police Officer, Firefighter, and Emergency Medical Technician Incentive Amendment Act of 2003</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2004-04-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-152.pdf">D.C. Law 15-152</citation>
      <citation type="register">50 DCR 9827</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0130">
      <narrative>Law 15-152, the “Government Employer-Assisted Housing Program Teacher, Police Officer, Firefighter, and Emergency Medical Technician Incentive Amendment Act of 2003”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-130, which was referred to Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 8, 2003, and October 7, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 24, 2003, it was assigned Act No. 15-199 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-152 became effective on April 24, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Amendment Act of 1999 to include Emergency Medical Technicians in the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Program, and to amend the Employer-Assisted Housing Program regulations. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Government Employer-Assisted Housing Program Teacher, Police Officer, Firefighter, and Emergency Medical Technician Incentive Amendment Act of 2003”. Sec. 2. Section 4 of the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Amendment Act of 1999, effective May 9, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-96; D.C. Official Code § 42-2503 is amended by adding the phrase “emergency medical technician,” after the phrase “firefighter,” wherever it appears. Sec. 3. Chapter 36 of Title 14 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations is amended as follows a) Subsection 3602.3(e) is amended by adding the phrase “emergency medical technicians,” after the phrase “firefighters,” b) Subsection 3603.1 is amended by adding the phrase “emergency medical technicians,” after the phrase “firefighters,” c) Subsection 3605.4 is amended by adding the phrase “emergency medical technicians,” after the phrase “firefighters,” d) Subsection 3607.1 is amended as follows 1) Add the phrase “emergency medical technicians,” after the phrase “firefighters,” in the paragraph defining the term "Applicant 2) Add the following paragraph after the paragraph defining the term "Downpayment Matching Funds “Emergency Medical Technician: defined to include all civilian personnel of the District of Columbia Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department who have fulfilled prescribed requirements by a credentialing agency to practice the art and science of out-of-hospital medicine in conjunction with medical direction, through the performance of assessments and the provision of medical care for emergency patients in the out-of-hospital setting and the expeditious transport to an appropriate care facility.”. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2003 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 42-2503 DCMR ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
