<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-207">
  <num type="law">15-207</num>
  <heading type="short">District Government Reemployed Annuitant Offset Elimination Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2004-12-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-207.pdf">D.C. Law 15-207</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 8779</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0567">
      <narrative>Law 15-207, the “District Government Reemployed Annuitant Offset Elimination Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-567, which was referred to the Committee of Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 29, 2004, and July 13, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 2, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-489 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-207 became effective on December 7, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to treat former District government employees who are federal annuitants the same as former federal government employees who are federal annuitants by eliminating the reduction in pay of a former District government employee who is a reemployed federal annuitant. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “District Government Reemployed Annuitant Offset Elimination Amendment Act of 2004”. Sec. 2. The second sentence of section 1103(b) of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-611.03(b is amended by adding the phrase “5 U.S.C. § 8331,” after the phrase “received by the reemployed individual pursuant to”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Spring Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 1-611.03 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
