<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-258">
  <num type="law">15-258</num>
  <heading type="short">Ceremonial Funds Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2005-03-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-258.pdf">D.C. Law 15-258</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 1176</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0718">
      <narrative>Law 15-258, the “Ceremonial Funds Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No 15-718, which was referred to Committee of Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 5, 2004, and November 9, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 30, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-633 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-258 became effective on March 17, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act To authorize funds for ceremonies in the District of Columbia to authorize the appropriation of not more than “$100,000 annually for funds for ceremonies in the District by the Mayor and the Council, and to authorize the Mayor and the Council to accept, administer, and use gifts or donations for this purpose. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Ceremonial Funds Amendment Act of 2004”. Sec. 2. Section 1 of An Act To authorize funds for ceremonies in the District of Columbia, approved July 11, 1947 (61 Stat. 314, D.C. Official Code § 1-333.09 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase “$25,000” and inserting the phrase “$100,000” in its place b) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase “$25,000” and inserting the phrase “$100,000” in its place c) A new subsection (b-1) is added to read as follows: “(b-1) The Mayor and Council may accept, administer, and use gifts or donations for the purpose of aiding, facilitating, and promoting the conduct of ceremonies in the District, including personal services, for the reception and entertainment, including ceremonial gifts, of officials of foreign, state, local, or federal governments and other dignitaries and eminent persons visiting or returning to the District, or for the reception or entertainment of officials of foreign, state, local, or federal governments when the Mayor is visiting any other jurisdiction in his or her official capacity.”. Sec. 3. This act shall be subject to the availability of appropriations. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 1-333.09 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813, D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
