<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-279">
  <num type="law">15-279</num>
  <heading type="short">Towing Regulation and Enforcement Authority Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2005-04-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-279.pdf">D.C. Law 15-279</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 841</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0364">
      <narrative>Law 15-279, the “Towing Regulation and Enforcement Authority Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-364, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 9, 2004, and December 7, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-670 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-279 became effective on April 5, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to authorize the Mayor to promulgate rules governing the business of furnishing towing services for motor Vehicles, to require that the proposed rules be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period or review, to provide that if the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed regulations, in whole or in part, by resolution, within this 45-day review period, the proposed regulations shall be deemed disapproved, and to authorize criminal and civil penalties for violating the District’s regulations governing towing service for motor vehicles. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Towing Regulation and Enforcement Authority Act of 2004”. Sec. 2. Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents for Chapter 28 is amended by adding the phrase “47-2850. Rules and Regulations Governing the Business of Furnishing Towing Serviced for Motor Vehicles.” b) A new section 47-2850 is added to read as follows: “§ 47-2850. Rules governing the business of furnishing towing services for motor vehicles a) The Mayor is authorized, in accordance with Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq to 1) Promulgate rules to govern the business of furnishing towing services for motor vehicles; and 2) Amend or repeal any provision of chapter 4 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations governing the business of furnishing towing services for motor vehicles b) Rules proposed pursuant to this section shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 47-2850 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed regulations, in whole or in part, by resolution, within this 45-day review period, the proposed regulations shall be deemed disapproved. “(c)(1) Any person who violates any of the rules promulgated pursuant to this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction, shall be subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 per violation, imprisonment for not more that 90 days, or both. “(2) All prosecutions for violations of any rule or regulation issued pursuant to this section shall be in the Criminal Division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the name of the District of Columbia by information signed by the Attorney General or one of his or her assistants. “(3) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the rules issued pursuant to this section, pursuant to Chapter18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infractions shall be pursuant Chapter 18 of Title 2.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602 (c)(3) of the Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02 (c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602 (c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02 (c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
