<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-291">
  <num type="law">15-291</num>
  <heading type="short">Cancer Prevention Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2005-04-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-291.pdf">D.C. Law 15-291</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 1457</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0875">
      <narrative>Law 15-291, the “Cancer Prevention Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-875, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 9, 2004, and December 7, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-686 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-291 became effective on April 5, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Cancer Prevention Act of 1990 to provide that benefits provided are not subject to co-payments and coinsurance and to clarify that the coinsurance or co-payments are applicable to the office visit not the baseline mammogram, annual screening mammogram, annual cervical cytologic screening, and cervical cytologic screening certified by an attending physician as being necessary. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Cancer Prevention Amendment Act of 2004 Sec. 2. Section 3 of the District of Columbia Cancer Prevention Act of 1990, effective March 7, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-225; D.C. Official Code § 31-2902 is amended by adding new subsections (d e and (f) to read as follows d) Benefits provided in accordance with this section shall not be subject to a co- payment except when an enrollee or subscriber elects to have a baseline mammogram, annual screening mammogram, annual cervical cytologic screening, and a cervical cytologic screening certified by an attending physician as being necessary, performed by an out-of-network provider in a preferred provider plan e) Co-payments and coinsurance may be applicable to the enrollee's or subscriber's office visit. “(f) Subsections (d) and (e) of this section shall apply: “(1) To any insurance policy or subscriber contract delivered or issued for delivery in the District more than 120 days after the effective date of the Cancer Prevention Amendment Act, passed on 2nd reading on December 7, 2004 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-815 and “(2) To any insurance policy or subscriber contract renewed, amended, or reissued 120 days after the effective date of the Cancer Prevention Amendment Act, passed on 2nd reading on December 7, 2004 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-815).”. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 31-2902 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
