<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-304">
  <num type="law">15-304</num>
  <heading type="short">Distracted Driving Safety Revised Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2005-04-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-304.pdf">D.C. Law 15-304</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 1694</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0981">
      <narrative>Law 15-304, the “Distracted Driving Safety Revised Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-981, which was referred to the Committee on Public works and Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 9, 2004, and December 7, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-701 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-304 became effective on April 8, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Distracted Driving Safety Act of 2004 to clarify that no points shall be assessed for a violation of this act that does not contribute to an accident. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Distracted Driving Safety Revised Amendment Act of 2004 Sec. 2. Section 6(b) of the Distracted Driving Safety Act of 2004, effective March 30, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-124; D.C. Official Code § 50-1731.06(b is amended to read as follows: “(b) A violation of the provisions of section 3, 4, or 5 shall be processed and adjudicated under the provisions applicable to moving violations set forth in Title II of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2302.01 et seq provided, that no points shall be assessed for a violation of this act that does not contribute to an accident Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 50-1731.06 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
