<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-51">
  <num type="law">15-51</num>
  <heading type="short">Make a Difference Amendment Act of 2003</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2003-12-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-51.pdf">D.C. Law 15-51</citation>
      <citation type="register">50 DCR 8982</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0071">
      <narrative>Law 15-51, the “Make a Difference Amendment Act of 2003”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-71, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 8, 2003, and September 16, 2003, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 6, 2003, it was assigned Act No. 15-164 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-51 became effective on December 9, 2003.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Make a Difference Selection Committee Establishment Act of 1998 to increase the number of yearly honorees from 10 to 25. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Make a Difference Amendment Act of 2003 Sec. 2. Section 4(d) of the Make a Difference Selection Committee Establishment Act of 1998, effective April 30, 1998 (D.C. Law 12-98; D.C. Official Code § 9-1215.03(d is amended by striking the phrase “10 persons” and inserting the phrase “25 persons” in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c 3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2003 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Note, § 9-1215.03</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
