<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-179">
  <num type="law">11-179</num>
  <heading type="short">Juvenile Detention and Speedy Trial Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-179.pdf">D.C. Law 11-179</citation>
      <citation type="register">43 DCR 4243</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0475">
      <narrative>Law 11-179, the “Juvenile Detention and Speedy Trial Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-475, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 19, 1996, and July 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 22, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-329 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-179 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 318 301 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-179 "Juvenile Detention and Speedy Trial Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-475 on first and second readings, June 19, 1996 and July 3, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 22, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-329, and published in the August 9, 1996, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 43 page 4243) and transmitted to Congress on January 10, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-179, effective April 9, 1997 ARVIS Chairman Pro Tempore of the Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,24,25,26,27,28 Mar. 3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21 Apr. 7,8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT ii-329 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 22, 1996 Codij ication District o) Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To amend title 16 of the District of Columbia Code to limit the len~h of time a juvenile remains in secure detention. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Juvenile Detention and Speedy Trial Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 16-2310 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) Fact finding hearings for children placed in secure detention shall be held within the time limits provided in this subsection 1) Except as provided in this subsection, whenever a child has been placed in secure detention prior to a fact finding hearing pursuant to D.C. Code §§ 16-2310 through 16- 2313, the fact finding hearing set forth in D.C. Code § 16-2316 shall commence not later than 30 days from the date at which the Division authorized the child to be detained pursuant to D.C. Code § 16-2312, unless the child is charged with murder, assault with intent to kill, first degree sexual abuse, burglary in the first degree, or robbery while armed, in which case the fact finding hearing shall commence not later than 45 days from the date at which the Division authorized the child to be securely detained 2) Upon motion of the Corporation Counsel, for good cause shown, or by or on behalf of the child consistent with the Rules of the Superior Court, the fact finding hearing of a child securely detained may be continued, and the child continued in secure detention for additional periods not to exceed 30 days each 3) In determining whether good cause has been shown as required by paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Division shall take into account, among other appropriate matters, and shall state its findings on the record, as to whether A) There has been or will be a delay resulting from other proceedings concerning the child, including, but not limited to, examinations to determine the mental competency or physical capacity of the child; from a hearing with respect to other charges against the child; from any interlocutory or expedited appeal; from the making, or consideration by the Division, of any pretrial motions; and from any proceeding relating to the transfer of the Section 16-2310 ENROLLED ORIGINAL child pursuant to D.C. Code § 16-2307 B) Any essential witness is absent or unavailable. For purposes of this subparagraph, an essential witness shall be considered absent when his or her whereabouts are unknown or cannot be determined by due diligence and shall be considered unavailable when his or her presence for the hearing cannot be obtained by due diligence C) Despite the exercise of due diligence, necessary autopsies, medical examinations, fingerprint examinations, ballistic tests, drug analysis, or other scientific tests have not been completed; or D) The ends of justice served by continuing the period of detention outweigh the interests of the child and public in a speedy trial 4) Upon motion by or on behalf of the child, a child in secure detention shall be released from custody if the fact finding hearing is not commenced within the time period set forth in this subsection Sec. 3. Applicability date. The provisions of this act shall be applicable 120 days after the effective date of this act. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Office of the Corporation Counsel and the Superior Court of the District of Columbia have stated that implementation of this act will cost at least $300,000 for Fiscal Year 1997. However, the Council approved an additional $150,000 for each agency in their respective FY 1997 budgets to cover the costs of implementing this act. Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(c and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1- 233 (c)(1 and publication}n the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia DMi of Co lumbia @ APPROVED: July 22, 1996 ~’ COUNCIL OF TI~ DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD I~LEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B 11" 4 7 5 Docket No ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ADOPTED FIRST READING, 06-19-96 ACTION &amp;amp; DATE APPROVEDVOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT CHMN. CLARKE, BRAZIL, JARVIS AND WHITTINGTON ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councflmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB Counctimember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington X- lax~¢zt~s V~z AB Absent NV Present not Voling C CERTIFICATION RECORD Da!e(9 the Co~I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE AD 0 P TED F I NAL READ I NG, 7- 3 9 6APPROVED VOICE VOTE RECO~E~ VO~E ON ABSENT [ I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result EVANS, RAY, SMITH AND THOMAS .C Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay AB Coundlmember Aye Nay AB Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray to the Council X-indicar no ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB-Absent NV-Present not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ACTION &amp;amp; DATE ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTEONREQLTEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE. R~ult Comlcilm~nber Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Jarvis I, X Indicates Vote Light foot Mason Patterson Ray Aye Nay AB Absent NV AB Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington Present not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
