<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-182">
  <num type="law">11-182</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 Conformity Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-182.pdf">D.C. Law 11-182</citation>
      <citation type="register">43 DCR 4251</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0633">
      <narrative>Law 11-182, the “District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 Conformity Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-633, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 4, 1996, and July 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 22, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-333 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-182 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 062 319 295 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C, ACT ii-333 Codi ication District o Columbia Code 1997 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 22, 1996 To amend the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 to provide for greater conformity with federal income tax law. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 Conformity Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 4(bb-l) of title I of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947, approved July 16, 1947 (61 Stat. 335; D.C. Code § 47-1801.4(28A is amended to read as follows bb-1) The term "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" means the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (100 Stat. 2085; 26 U.S.C. 1 et seq as amended through April 11, 1995. The provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be effective on the same dates that they are effective for federal tax purposes, except that section 162(I) shall only apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 1994 Sec. 3 Fiscal impact statement The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203 (a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Section 47-1801.4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. ’ i: ’:J Ix, Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: July 22, 1996 2 oN c~ CALg~CDAIt ACTION &amp;amp; DATg VOtCg VOTg ggCOm)gl) VOTE ON ItEQUE~-W cot CIL oft T~E DISTa.ICT OP COLL,’M~IA COUNCIL l~g~IOO gLgVKq ILgCOgD Oft Ot~IqCXAL COt~CIL VOTg BII-633 ADOPTED FIRST READING~ 6-4-9~ APPROVED EVANS AND CHAVOUS Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans ROLL CALL VOTE ¯ Result Aye Nay NV AB Counddmember Aye Nay AIt Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray v~ [~ ITEM ON CONSF~NT CALgNDAR I~ A~ON &amp;amp; DA~ {~ vOiCE v co~ vo~ o u CHAVOUS [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE. Remit CERTIFICATION agCORD ADOPTED F I NAL READ I N APPROVED Coea~r Aye Nay AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington 7-3-96 £ Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Ray I ITEM ON CONSE~NT CALgINDAR [ I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE [ ] VOlC’g VOTg Aye Nay NV AB Comlclkllembeg Ay~e Nay NV A~ CA~sc~lt~dt~ Ay~ Nay NV AB Jarv~ Sum Jr. Lighffoot Thomm, St. Ma~on Whitttagtoa Patterson CERTIFICATION i~gCORD RECORDED voTg ON REQUEST [ I ROLL CALL VOTE Counc/h~emb~ Chran. Clarke Braz~ Chavo~ Cropp Eva~ Aye Nay AB X Iadicatm vet Cmmcflmemb~ Aye .Nay AB Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray AB- Al~mg Comu:t~memlm’ Aye Nay NV AB Smitk, Jr. Thomas, Sr N Prmast mt Vet~| CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Coundl Dam</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
