<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-109">
  <num type="law">11-109</num>
  <heading type="short">DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA BOARD OF REAL PROPERTY ASSESSMENTS AND APPEALS MEMBERSHIP SIMPLIFICATION ACT OF 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1996-03-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-109.pdf">D.C. Law 11-109</citation>
      <citation type="register">43 DCR 526</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0470"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 318 275 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA D.C. LAW 11-109 "District of Columbia Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals Membership Simplification Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-470 on first and second readings, December 5, 1995 and January 4, 1996 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on January 26, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-197 and published in the February 9, 1996, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 43 page 526) and transmitted to Congress on February 15, 1996 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-109, effective March 29, 1996. DAVID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 15,16,20,21,22,23,26,27,28,29 March 1,4,5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,25,26,27,28 ENROLLED ORIGINAL D,C, AN ACT ACT 11-197 Codification District of Columbia Code 1996 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JANUARY 26, 1996 To amend the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Act Revision Act of 1974 to simplify the requirements for Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals membership. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals Membership Simplification Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 426a of theDistrict of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, effective January 5, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-241; D.C. Code § 47-825.1 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a)(l)(A) is amended to read as follows A) The Board shall be comprised of 18 members, all of whom shall be residents of the District of Columbia District Board members shall be active members of the District of Columbia Bar with real estate experience, District certified general real estate appraisers, District licensed residential real estate appraisers, certified public accountants, mortgage bankers, licensed District real. estate brokers, or persons possessing significant real property experience b) Subsection (a)(1)(E) is repealed. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1- 233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(c and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Section 47-825.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Government and Governmental Reorgar~ation Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publica~ji~a in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia COUNCIL PERIOD EL~’VF~N RECORD OF oFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE D.&amp;lt t~o. BII-470~x ,TE ON CO.,SEN~ CALE.’~ARADoPTED F I RST READ I NG, 12--5--95 [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE APPROVED RECOP,.DED %t)]’E ON REt~F3T ALL PRESENT ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VO|CE VOTE Nay \V B Cotul,ahnenlber ~ye i ~ay NV AB Coun~Jmember Jarv~ Smith. Lightfoot Thom Mason Whittin~on Patterson Ray ~B- Absent ~ERTIFICATION RECO~ the C~mn~l ADOPTED FINAL READING, APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ALL PRESENT Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Ray X-indte~t o ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Ave Nay NV AB C omt ¢ahneml r Ave Nay NV AB Com’.ciht~m~r Jarvis Smith, AB-Abs~tt CERTIFICATION RECORD Lightfoot Mason Patterson Thomas, Sr. Whittington .kCTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT { ROLL CALL VOTE- Result C otmcilmembet- Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lighffoot Chavous Mason Cropp I [ Patter-ran Evans Ray ¯ X ¯ [ndi~tt~ Vote AB Ah~nt Nay AB Cotmc~lawq~.r ye Nay NV AB Cotmcilmemb~r Aye le ’,i ] Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington NV ao C ERI]FICATION RECORD Secretary to tl~ Ce~m,-a Dat~</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
