<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-185">
  <num type="law">11-185</num>
  <heading type="short">Business Corporation Two-Year Report Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-185.pdf">D.C. Law 11-185</citation>
      <citation type="register">43 DCR 4510</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0580">
      <narrative>Law 11-185, the “Business Corporation Two-Year Report Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-580, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 19, 1996, and July 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 22, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-338 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-185 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LMEN (S) kwiktag 062 319 012 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 11-338 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 22, 1996 Codi) ication District o) Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Business Corporation Act of 1954 to provide for the filing of a 2-year report instead of a 5-year report, and to make conforming amendments to the sections governing a proclamation of revocation. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Business Corporation Two-Year Report Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Business Corporation Act, approved June 8, 1954 (68 Stat. 179; D.C. Code § 29-301 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 98 (D.C. Code § 29-398) is amended as follows: Section (1) By striking in subsection (a) the phrase "shall file with the Mayor, on or 29-398 before April 15th of each 5th year from the date of incorporation, if there has been no change in material facts, a 5-year" and inserting in its place the phrase "incorporated before April 15, 1996, shall file with the Mayor on or before April 15, 1997, and on or before April 15th of each 2nd year thereafter, if there has been no change in material facts, a 2) By adding a new subsection (a-l) to read as follows a-l) Each corporation incorporated after April 14, 1996, shall file with the Mayor on or before April 15th of the year after its incorporation, and on or before April 15th of each 2nd year thereafter, if there has been no change in material facts, a report setting forth the information specified in subsection (a) of this section 3) By striking in subsection (b) the phrase "5-year" and inserting the phrase "2- year" in its place. Section (b) Section 112 (D.C. Code § 29-399.13) is amended as follows: 29-399.13 (1) By striking in subsection (a) the phrase "shall file on or before April 15th of each fifth year from the date of authorization to do business in the District of Columbia, if there has been no change in material facts, a 5-year" and inserting the phrase "shall file on or before April 15, 1997, and on or before April 15th of each 2nd year thereafter, if there has been no change in materials facts, a" in its place; ENROLLED ORIGINAL (2) By adding a new subsection (a-l) to read as follows a-l) Each foreign corporation authorized to transact business in the District beginning after April 15, 1997, shall file on or before April 15th of the year after such authorization and on or before April 15th of each 2nd year thereafter, if there has been no change in material facts, a report setting forth the information specified in subsection (a) of this section 3) By striking in subsection (b) the phrase "Such 5-year report" and inserting the phrase "Such 2-year report" in its place c) Section 115 (D.C. Code § 29-399.16) is amended as follows: Section 29-399.16 (1) By striking in subsection (a)(6) the phrase "5-year" and inserting the phrase "2-year" in its place; and (2) By striking in subsection (b)(2) the phrase "5-year" and inserting the phrase "2-year" in its place d) Section 121 (D.C. Code § 29-399.22) is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (d) is amended as follows: 29-399.22 (A) By striking the phrase "a 5-year report fee of $500" and inserting the phrase "a 2-year report fee of $200" in its place; and (B) By striking the phrase "the 5-year report" and inserting the phrase "the 2-year report" in its place 2) Subsection (e) is amended by striking the phrase "5-year" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "2-year" in its place. Section (e) Section 122 (D.C. Code § 29-399.23) is amended as follows: 29-399.23 (1) By striking the phrase "5-year" in the title and wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "2-year" in its place; and (2) By striking the phrase "for 2 consecutive years" wherever it appears f) Section 123(a D.C. Code § 29-399.24(a is amended as follows: section 29-399.24 (1) By striking the phrase "refused to pay any annual report fee" and inserting the phrase "refused to pay any report fee" in its place; and (2) By striking the phrase "refused to file any 5-year report as required by this act for 2 consecutive years" and inserting the phrase "refused to file any report as required by this act for a report period" in its place g) Section 125 (D.C. Code § 29-399.26) is amended as follows: Section (1) By striking the phrase "refused to pay any 5-year report fee or file any 5- 29-399.26 year report for 2 consecutive years" and inserting the phrase "refused to pay report fees or file report for a reporting period" in its place; and (2) By striking the phrase "refusing to pay 5-year report fees" and inserting the phrase "refusing to pay report fees" in its place. Section(h) Section 128 (D.C. Code §29-399.29) is amended by striking the phrase "5-year" in29-399.29 the title and wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "2-year" in its place i) Nothing in this act shall be construed or interpreted as repealing or affecting anyNote, Sections 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL requirement of a domestic or foreign corporation to prepare and submit annual tax forms, or to pay any appropriate District or federal taxes, as provided in accordance with the laws of the District of Columbia or the United States. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 of Congressional review as prc Government and Governmenta 813; D.C. Code § 7233~c)(1 Chairman Council of the District of Columbia 109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and a 30-day period vided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. a~blication in the District of Columbia Register. 29-398 29-399.13 29-399.16 29-399.22 29-399.23 29-399.24 29-399.26 29-399.29 Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: July 22, 1996 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF TH~ DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN ~co~oFo~o~o~ BII-580 Dack~ N~0 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 06-19-96 APPROVED A~E~ | ROLL CALL VOTE. R~sdit Councilmcmber Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans CHMN, CLARKE, BRAZIL, JARVIS AND WHITTINGTON Aye Nay ]¢V AB ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR &amp;amp;CTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Councihnember Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, St. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV. Presmt not Voting k/ I bu ’- ADOPTED FINAL READING, 07-03-96 APPROVED CHAVOUS [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Councilmember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Lighffoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X.indicates no Council Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmeraber Aye Nay NV AB Cotmcilmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB-Abseat NVoPresent not vot~g CERTIFICATION RECORD ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Com~cilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB Cmmcilmembtr Aye Nay X Indicates Vote Jarvis Lighffoot Mason Patterson Ray AB. Absent NV AB Cotmcilmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. ] Thomas, St. Whittington NV- Print not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
