<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-156">
  <num type="law">11-156</num>
  <heading type="short">Excepted Service Positions Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1996-09-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-156.pdf">D.C. Law 11-156</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 11-156, the “Excepted Service Positions Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-685. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 7, 1996, and June 4, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 17, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-284 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-156 became effective on September 20, 1996.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LLMENT(S) kwiktag ¯ 062 330 036 (5) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-156 "Excepted Service Positions Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Coluxnbia adopted Bill 11-685 on first and second readings, May 7, 1996 and June 4, 1996 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 17, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act 11-284 and published in the July 19, 1996 edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 43 page 3695) and transmitted to Congress on July 10, 1996 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30oday Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-156, effective September 20, 1996. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July Aug. Sept. 10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,26,29,30,31 1,2 3,4,5,6,9,10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C. ACT 11-284 Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 17, 1996 To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, to allocate up to an additional 40 Excepted Service positions subject to appointmem by the Mayor to the Office of the Inspector General and, during a control year, up to an additional 20 Excepted Service positions to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, and to repeal the requirement that lists of Excepted Service positions and incumbents in those positions be published in the District of Columbia Register. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Excepted Service Positions Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 903 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-610.3 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a)(2) is amended by adding the following phrase after the word "District except that up to an additional 40 positions subject to appointment by the Mayor shall be allocated to and designated by the Office of the Inspector General and, in a control year, up to an additional 20 positions subject to appointment by the Mayor shall be allocated to and designated by the Office of the Chief Financial Officer b) Subsection (c) is repealed. Sec. 3. The act will have no adverse fiscal impact. Agencies will continue to operate under the FTE ceilings and within budget constraints. Sec. 4 a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the Note, Section 1-610.3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after the 225th day of its having taken effect or on the effective date of the Excepted Service Positions Designation Amendment Act of 1996, whichever occurs first Y6 Tempore ouncil of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: June 17, 1996 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF "I’HX DISTR~c’r OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Bl1’685 Dock~,t No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 5,7’96 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ASSENT ROLL CALL VOTE- Rmult APPROVED JARVIS, LIGHTFOOT, RAY ANDTHOMAS Councilnlember ~ye Na NV AB Councilmember Chmn. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lighffoot Chavous Mason Cropp [ Patterson E~ans ] Ray x [n~dicates Vote the Council A,~e Nay N~V AB Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington AB Absent NV Present no~ Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD F~-EM ON CONSENT CALENDAR X xCTION &amp;amp; DATE X |cE VOI’E ADOPTED FINAL READING, 6-4’96 APPROVED REC~)RDED VOTE ON REQUEST ALL PRESENT RIH.I_ C LL ~OTE Result ve Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Coun~ilmemfler Aye Nay NW AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, Sr. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray AB-Absent NV-Pr~ent not vo~ing i (hmn. Ctarke i terazil r’qH~ i’ 1~ aa X -in d i no [ [’E~I o\ CONSENT CALENDAR kCTIt)N &amp;amp; D~TE CERTIFICATION RECORD OICE OTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST kBSENT i ROLL CALL VOTE- R~ult Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Light foot Chavoas Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray x Indicat¢~ Vote Aye Nay NW AB Counrqmember Aye Nay NW AB Coundlmemb~r Ay¢ Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB AbSent NV Pr ent not YoUng CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
