<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-237">
  <num type="law">11-237</num>
  <heading type="short">Uniform Commercial Code Negotiable Instruments Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-237.pdf">D.C. Law 11-237</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 920</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0573">
      <narrative>Law 11-237, the “Uniform Commercial Code Negotiable Instruments Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-573, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-497 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-237 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN M NT(S) kwikl:ag" 103 224 976 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT ii-497 Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Suppo 1N THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 24, 1996 To amend Article 3 of the Uniform Commercial Code by adding a provision concerning lost, destroyed, or stolen cashier’s checks, teller’s checks, or certified checks. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Commercial Code Negotiable Instruments Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Article 3 of Subtitle I of Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The analysis of Article 3 is amended by inserting, after the listing of § 28:3-311, a new listing to read as follows 28:3-312. Lost, destroyed, or stolen cashier’s check, teller’s check, or certified check b) A new section 28:3-312 is added to read as follows § 28:3-312. Lost, destroyed, or stolen cashier’s check, teller’s check, or certified check a) For the purposes of this section, the term 1 Check" means a cashier’s check, teller’s check, or certified check 2 Claimant" means a person who claims the right to receive the amount of a cashier’s check, teller’s check, or certified check that was lost, destroyed, or stolen 3 Declaration of loss" means a written statement, made under penalty of perjury, to the effect that (i) the declarer lost possession of a check ii) the declarer is the drawer or payee of the check, in the case of a certified check, or the remitter or payee of the check, in the case of a cashier’s check or teller’s check iii) the loss of possession was not the result of a transfer by the declarer or a lawful seizure, and (iv) the declarer cannot reasonably obtain possession of the check because the check was destroyed, its whereabouts cannot be determined, or it is in the wrongful possession of an unknown person or a person that cannot be found or is not amenable to service of process 4 Obligated bank" means the issuer of a cashier’s check or teller’s check or the acceptor of a certified check. New Section 28:3-312 ENROLLED ORIGINAL b) A claimant may assert a claim to the amount of a check by a communication to the obligated bank describing the check with reasonable certainty and requesting payment of the amount of the check, if (i) the claimant is the drawer or payee of a certified check or the remitter or payee of a cashier’s check or teller’s check ii) the communication contains or is accompanied by a declaration of loss of the claimant with respect to the check iii) the communication is received at a time and in a manner affording the bank a reasonable time to act on it before the check is paid, and (iv) the claimant provides reasonable identification if requested by the obligated bank. Delivery of a declaration of loss is a warranty of the truth of the statements made in the declaration. If a claim is asserted in compliance with this subsection, the following rules apply 1) The claim becomes enforceable at the later of(i)the time the claim is asserted, or (ii) the 90th day following the date of the check in the case of a cashier’s check or teller’s check, or the 90th day following the date of the acceptance in the case of a certified check 2) Until the claim becomes enforceable, it has no legal effect and the obligated bank may pay the check or, in the case of a teller’s check, may permit the drawee to pay the check. Payment to a person entitled to enforce the check discharges all liability of the obligated bank with respect to the check 3) If the claim becomes enforceable before the check is presented for payment, the obligated bank is not obliged to pay the check 4) When the claim becomes enforceable, the obligated bank becomes obliged to pay the amount of the check to the claimant if payment of the check has not been made to a person entitled to enforce the check. Subject to § 28:4-302(a)(1 payment to the claimant discharges all liability of the obligated bank with respect to the check c) If the obligated bank pays the amount of a check to a claimant under subsection (b)(4) of this section and the check is presented for payment by a person having rights of a holder in due course, the claimant is obliged to (i) refund the payment to the obligated bank if the check is paid, or (ii) pay the amount of the check to the person having rights of a holder in due course if the check is dishonored d) If a claimant has the right to assert a claim under subsection (b) of this section and is also a person entitled to enforce a cashier’s check, teller’s check, or certified check which is lost, destroyed, or stolen, the claimant may assert rights with respect to the check either under this section or § 28:3-309 Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Managemem Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 09 Star, 116; D!C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmemal Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and ~ublication in the District of Col .uyn~i~’~g’(ster. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 24, 1996 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLULMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE D.,No. Bli-573 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-7-96 ] voIcEVOTE APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST THOMASABSENT { I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X Indicates Vote [X] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Aye Nay AB Councflmember Aye Nay AB Councflmember Aye Nay NT AB Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV. Presmt not Voting ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-3-96 [ I VOICE VOTE APPROVEDRECO"~ED VOT~ ON REQu~ ABSE RAY [ I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Cotmciimember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X-inc~cates ’~ Secretary to the Council [ [ ITEM ON CONSF~NT CALENDAR [ ] ACTION &amp;amp;DATE Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray AB-Abs~t CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV.Present not voting [ I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay AB Counciimember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB Absent NV Present net Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT CodificationDistrict of Colutnbia Code 1997 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Article 3 of the Uniform Commercial Code by adding a provision concerning lost, destroyed, or stolen cashier’s checks, teller’s checks, or certified checks. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Commercial Code Negotiable Instruments Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Article 3 of Subtitle I of Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The analysis of Article 3 is amended by inserting, after the listing of§ 28:3-311, a new listing to read as follows 28:3-312. Lost, destroyed, or stolen cashier’s check, teller’s cheek, or certified cheek b) A new section 28:3-312 is added to read as follows § 28:3-312. Lost, destroyed, or stolen cashier’s check, teller’s check, or certified check a) For the purposes of this section, the term 1 Check" means a cashier’s check, teller’s check, or certified check 2 Claimant" means a person who claims the right to receive the amount of a cashier’s check, teller’s check, or certified check that was lost, destroyed, or stolen 3 Declaration of loss" means a written statement, made under penalty of perjury, to the effect that (i) the declarer lost possession of a check ii) the declarer is the drawer or payee of the check, in the case of a certified check, or the remitter or payee of the check, in the case of a cashier’s check or teller’s check iii) the loss of possession was not the result of a transfer by the declarer or a lawful seizure, and (iv) the declarer cannot reasonably obtain possession of the check because the check was destroyed, its whereabouts cannot be determined, or it is in the wrongful possession of an unknown person or a person that cannot be found or is not amenable to service of process 4 Obligated bank" means the issuer of a cashier’s check or teller’s check or the acceptor of a certified check. New Section 28:3-312 ENROLLED ORIGINAL b) A claimant may assert a claim to the amount of a check by a communication to the obligated bank describing the check with reasonable certainty and requesting payment of the amount ofthe cheek, if(i) the claimant is the drawer or payee of a certified cheek or the remitter or payee of a cashier’s check or teller’s check ii) the communication contains or is accompanied by a declaration of loss of the claimant with respect to the cheek iii) the communication is received at a time and in a manner affording the bank a reasonable time to act on it before the cheek is paid, and (iv) the claimant provides reasonable identification if requested by the obligated bank. Delivery of a declaration of loss is a warranty of the truth of the statements made in the declaration. If a claim is asserted in compliance with this subsection, the following rules apply 1 The claim becomes enforceable at the later of(i) the time the claim is asserted, or (ii) the 90th day following the date of the cheek in the case of a cashier’s cheek or teller’s check, or the 90th day following the date of the acceptance in the case of a certified check 2) Until the claim becomes enforceable, it has no legal effect and the obligated bank may pay the check or. in the case of a teller’s check, may permit the drawee to pay the check. Payment to a person entitled to enforce the cheek discharges all liability of the obligated bank with respect to the check 3) If the claim becomes enforceable before the check is presented for payment, the obligated bank is not obliged to pay the check 4) When the claim becomes enforceable, the obligated bank becomes obliged to pay the amount of the check to the claimanl if pa~nent of the check has not been made to a person entitled to enforce the check. Subject to § 28:4-302(a)(1 payment to the claimant discharges all liability of the obligated bank ~vith respect to the cheek c) If the obligated bank pays the amount of a check to a claimant under subsection (b)(4) of this section and the check is presented for pa~nent by a person having rights of a holder in due course, the claimant is obliged to (il refund the payment to the obligated bank if the check is paid, or (ii) pay the amount of the check to the person having rights of a holder in due course if the check is dishonored d) Ifa claimant has the right to assert a claim under subsection (b) of this section and is also a person entitled to enforce a cashier’s check, tel Icr’s check, or certified check which is lost. destroyed, or stolen, the claimant ma.v assert rights with respect to the check either under this section or § 28:3-309.’. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required bv section 602~c t(3 o f the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. approved l)eccmbcr 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OFFICE OF THE GENERAL COUNSEL WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 TRANSMITTAL OF ENROLLED LEGISLATION Short Title: Uniform Commercial Code Negotiable Instruments Amendment Act of 1996 Bill #11-573 "96 OEC 11 A9:53 Date Transmitted to LSD: cc: Councilmember Ray cc: Codification Counsel (with attachment with attachment) Please notify me of any error/comment within 24 hours. II. CLEARANCE OF ENROLLED LEGISLATION ative Counsel ~j~-ification Counsel Office ~’~t~/I/Secretar3’ Date 2-/’o Date Date III. CLEARANCE OF CORRESPONDENCE BY LSD Letter(s) to the Mavor Date Letter(s) to Congress Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D~C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved Decemt~er 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813;D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Colurr}~ia ~gister. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia ON CONSF~N~ CALF-N’DAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL,’MBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RF.CORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE No. B11-573 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-7-96 [ ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED THOMAS [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chin. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X Indicates Vote [~ ITEM ON CONSEN~f CALF.N~DAR [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DA~ Aye Nay N%’ AB I Councflmember Aye Nay N’V AB CmmciLmember Aye Nay N3 AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. [ AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Light foot Mason Patterson Ray Whittington ~’ Present not Votiag ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-3-96 vOICE VOTE APPROVEDRECORDED VOTE ON REQU~T A~E~T RAY [ ROLL CALL VOTE Result Coundlmember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Aye Nay NV AB Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Counciimmnber Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, Sr. Mason Whittington Cropp Evans Ray x.,7=les no I t" S~c~etal’y. to the Coral I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I ~L~ION &amp;amp; DATE Patterson AB-Abs~t~t CERTIFICATION RECORD NV.Present not veting Date VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Cum:cilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB Cotmcilmember Aye Nay NV AB Counc~lnoJnber Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray AB Absent Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington N’V. pr-~nt not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary. to the Cotm~l Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
