<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-26">
  <num type="law">11-26</num>
  <heading type="short">Revolving Credit account Late Fee Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-07-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-26.pdf">D.C. Law 11-26</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 2565</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0043">
      <narrative>Law 11-26, the “Revolving Credit account Late Fee Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-43, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 4, 1995 and May 2, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 15, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-54 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-26 became effective on July 14, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENR MENT(S) kwiktag 062 3~9 57’t COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11- 26 "Revolving Credit Account Late Fee Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Govemment and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-43 on first and second readings, April 4, 1995 and May 2, 1995, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on May 15, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-54 and published in the May 26, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 2565) and transmitted to Congress on May 19, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: May July 19,22,23,24,25,26 5,6,7,8,9,12,13,14,15,16,19,20,21,22,23,26,27,28 29,30 10,11,12,13 AN ACT ACT 11-54 ENROLLED ORIGINAL i Codification 131strict of Columbia I "| "1996 Supplement} IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MAY 15, 1995 To amend section 28-3702 of the District of Columbia Code to permit a seller or financial institution to charge a late fee on a revolving credit account when the minimum payment is not made within 10 days of the due date. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Revolving Credit Account Late Fee Act of 1995 Sec. 2. Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) By amending the table of contents for Chapter 37 by inserting the phrase late fees" after the phrase "§28-3702. Amount and computation of credit service charge and (b) By amending section 28-3702 by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows d)(1) In addition to the credit service charge permitted in subsection (b) of this section, a seller or financial institution may impose a late fee, delinquency charge, or any similar assessment on each minimum payment not paid in full within 10 days after the date the minimum payment is due. The late fee, delinquency charge, or any similar assessment shall not exceed $15 for any one minimum payment not made within 10 days of the date the minimum payment was due 2) Notwithstanding the terms of any revolving credit account or any other provision of law, a seller or financial institution may impose a late fee, delinquency charge, or other similar assessment pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection provided that the seller or financial institution mails a written notice of the change to each affected buyer at least 30 days before the date of the effected change, and that the seller or financial institution shall permit each affected buyer to repay, under the existing terms, any debt incurred prior to the effective date of the change, unless the buyer incurs additional debt on or after that date or otherwise asserts in writing to the changes 3) The notice required by paragraph (2) of this subsection shall clearly set forth the new terms, the corresponding existing terms, and the effective date of the change; shall appear on a single document that contains no other information except the charged revolving account agreement or other material directly related to the change; and shall be in plain language Section 28-3702 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602 (c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Regis/t, er, the Di~ct of Columbia Statues-At-Large, or the District of Columbia Mun~ Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: May 15, 1995 0 rrgM ON CONSENT CALENDA~ I Xl ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B11-43 Adopted Fi rst Reading, 4-4-95 I Xl vOICE VOTg ggc.om)m) VOTK ON Approved al I present ROLL CALL vo’rg it,remit Ay~ Nmy NV AB Ay~ Nmy NV Am Ay~ Nay NV AB CIlMN BP JL CHAVOU~ CROPP EVANS x-~v~i I M CONS~ I~ A~ON &amp;amp; DA~ I~ V~V~ JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ’rIIOMAS, S~ MASON PA’rr~soN RAY AB. AIm~t CERTWICATION IV. Pmllmt m s’, Adopted F:inal Reading, 5-2-95 Approve d CO~VO~ON r a] I present I I ROLL CALL VOTE. Rmllt Comlcilmmsdl~ Aye Nay NV AB CmlmcMm~mb~ Aye Nay NV AB Aye Nay NV AB CHMN. CLAR~g JARVIS BRAZIL LIGWrFOOT CHAVOUS MASON CROi~ PAI"I’gi~ON EVANS RAY AB- AIImlt Co~IICEiITIFICATION ~OiID I I 0~I CONSENT CALEN~)AR I I AC-’YION &amp;amp; DATg I I VOICK VOTIg I I ROLL CALL VOTE. Resslt Colm4dimmllk~ Aye Nay NV A8 ColmdksMlmb~ Aye Nay NV AB C~mc:~mIIIIMW Ay~ Nay NV AB ClIMN. C"L~ggg JARVIS BRAZIl, LIGH’rFooT CIIAVOUS MA~ON CRO[~ PATTgilSON KVAN~ RAY X ¯ v~e AB AIl~mlt CERTIFICATION ~gCO~</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
