<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-225">
  <num type="law">11-225</num>
  <heading type="short">Insurers’ Records Access and Control Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-225.pdf">D.C. Law 11-225</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 122</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0605">
      <narrative>Law 11-225, the “Insurers’ Records Access and Control Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-605, which was referred to the Committee Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 1, 1996, and November 7, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 27, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-452 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-225 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROL N (S) kwiktag 062 319 204 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-225 "Insurers’ Records Access and Control Amendment Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-605, on first and second readings, October 1, 1996 and November 7, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 27, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-452, and published in the January 10, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 122) and transmitted to Congress on January 23, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-225, effective April 9, 1997. ENE DREW JARVIS Chairman Pro Tempore of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,24,25,26,27,28 3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21 7,8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 11-452 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 27, 1996 Codi) ication District o) Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To amend the Law on Examinations Act of 1993 to clarify that an insurer may use reliable electronically stored data or other process which accurately reproduces or forms a durable medium for storing records and under what circumstances the original may be destroyed. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Insurers’ Records Access and Control Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 4 of the Law on Examinations Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-49; D.C. Code § 35-3603 is amended by adding a new subsection (g) to read as follows g 1) Any insurer, agent, or broker may cause its accounts, records, documents, and files described in subsection (b) of this section to be created, recorded, copied, or reproduced by any photographic, photostatic, microfilm, microcard, miniature photographic, optical disk, electronic imaging, electronic data processing, electronically transmitted facsimile, printout, or reproduction of electronically stored data or other process which accurately reproduces or forms a durable medium for the reproduction of an account, record, document, or file 2) If the items so stored are not the original but accurately represent the original, the original may be destroyed unless held in a custodial or fiduciary capacity, but only if the data is easily accessible to the department in readable form and readable reproduced copies are obtainable 3) A record so stored and accurately reproduced is admissible in evidence as the original in any judicial or administrative proceeding whether the original is in existence or not. The introduction of a reproduced record does not preclude admission of the original. This shall not be construed to exclude from evidence any document or copy thereof which is otherwise admissible under the rules of evidence Section 35-3603 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.2(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in ~olumbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia D~strtct of Columbia APPROVED: November 27, 1996 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE. RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF TH~ DISTRICT OF COLUMBLA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE BII-605 ADOPTFD FIRSI READING, 10.1’_96 APPftOVED LIGHTFOOT Aye Nay NV AB Councflmember Aye Nz? NV AB X- ] ~dicates Vote Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray CERTIFICATION ILECORD Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington Pre~ent not Voting [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Councflmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans I~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE [~ VOICE VOTE ¯ ¯ RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST to the Council | Date ADOPTED FINAL READING, IILZL96 APPROVED ABSENT THOMAS [ [ ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Councilmember Aye Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X-indicates no ~o the Coundl Jarvis Lighffoot Mason Patterson Ray Nzy NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember [ Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB-Abs~tt NV-Present not votlBg ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR AC~fION &amp;amp; DATE CERTIFICATION RECORD [ ] VOICEVOTE RECORDED VO~FE ON REQUEST ABSENT ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X Indicates Vote Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Court dlmember Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, Sr. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD See~ry to the Coundl Aye Nay NV AB NV~ Present not Voting Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
