<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-255">
  <num type="law">11-255</num>
  <heading type="short">Second Technical Amendments Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-255.pdf">D.C. Law 11-255</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 1271</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0905">
      <narrative>Law 11-255, the “Second Technical Amendments Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-905, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-519 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-255 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 089 899 075 (5) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-255 "Second Technical Amendments Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-905, on first and second readings, November 7, 1996 and December 3, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 24, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-519 and published in the March 7, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 1271) and transmitted to Congress on January 31, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Apri ~K~Chairman Pro Tempore of the Council6 HARLENE DREW JARVIS ¢ Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. Mar. Apr. 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,24,25,26,27,28 3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21 7,8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT ii-519 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 24, 1996 Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative Act of 1979 to correct a grammatical error; to amend the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 to correct a grammatical error; to amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to add clarifying language and to correct a punctuation error; to amend the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 to add clarifying language; to amend the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955 to make a stylistic change and to correct a punctuation error; to amend the Business Regulatory Reform Commission Act of 1994 to correct a grammatical error; to amend the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982 to make a stylistic correction and to delete extraneous language; to amend the Day Care Policy Act of 1979 to correct a section reference; to amend the District of Columbia Right to Overnight Shelter Act of 1984 to add clarifying language; to amend the District of Columbia Policeman’s and Fireman’s Retirement Disability Act to make grammatical corrections and to correct subsection references; to amend the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1994 to delete extraneous language; to amend the District of Columbia Environmental Policy Act of 1989 to correct a punctuation error and to delete extraneous language; to amend the Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act of 1978 to add clarifying language and to delete extraneous language; to amend the District of Columbia Solid Waste Management and Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988 to correct a grammatical error; to amend the Solid Waste Facility Permit Act of 1994 to correct a grammatical error; to amend An Act to Authorize an increased share of the cost of certain transportation prqiects in the District of Columbia for fiscal years 1995 and 1996, and for other purposes to add clarifying language; to amend Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code to make grammatical, stylistic, and clarifying corrections; to amend title 20 of the District of Columbia Code to make grammatical, stylistic, and clarifying corrections; to amend Title 21 of the District of Columbia Code to make grammatical, stylistic, and clarifying corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Alcoholic Beverage Control Act to correct a grammatical error and make a stylistic correction; to amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to correct a paragraph designation and grammatical error; to amend An Act Regulating ENROLLED ORIGINAL corporations doing a banking business in the District of Columbia to correct a grammatical error; to amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to correct grammatical errors; to amend the District of Columbia Savings and Loan Acquisition Amendment Act of 1988 to make a stylistic correction; to amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to make a stylistic correction; to amend Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code to make grammatical, stylistic, and clarifying corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Business Corporation Act to make grammatical, stylistic, and clarifying corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act to make a grammatical correction; to amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Limited Liability Company Act of 1994 to make a grammatical and clarifying correction; to amend An Act Making appropriations for the government of the District of Columbia and other activities chargeable in whole or in part against the revenues of said District for fiscal year ending September 30, 1995, and for other purposes to make a stylistic and clarifying correction; to amend An Act for the retirement of public-school teachers in the District of Columbia to make a grammatical correction; to amend the District of Columbia Public Education Reorganization Act to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Education of the Deaf Act of 1986 to make a stylistic and clarifying correction; to amend the Education of the Deaf Act of 1986 to make a clarifying correction; to amend the Drag Paraphernalia Act of 1982 to make a grammatical correction; to amend chapter III of the Life Insurance Act to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Fire and Casualty Act to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Life Insurance Act to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Risk Retention Act of 1993 to make a clarifying correction; to amend the Law on Credit for Reinsurance Act of 1993 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Holding Company System Act of 1993 to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Uniform Disposition of Unclaimed Property Act of 1980 to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996 to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Cable Television Communications Act of 1981 to make grammatical, stylistic, and clarifying corrections; to amend the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 to make a clarifying correction; to amend the Horizontal Property Act of the District of Columbia to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Condominium Act of 1976 to make grammatical and clarifying corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Act to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to make grammatical and stylistic corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act to correct punctuation errors, to add clarifying language, and to delete extraneous language; to amend the Tax Anticipation Notes Act of 1996 to delete extraneous language; to amend the Drug Paraphernalia 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Amendment Act of 1996 to add clarifying language; to amend the Omnibus Sports Consolidation Act of 1994 Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 to add clarifying language; to amend the Budget Support Act of 1995 to correct D.C. Law, D.C. Code, and D.C. Register references and to add clarifying language; to amend the Cable Television Amendment Act of 1996 to make a stylistic and clarifying correction; and to amend the Modified Reduction-in-Force Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 to correct a title reference. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Second Technical Amendments Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Section 7(a) of the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979, effective March 10, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-17l; D.C. Code § 1-116(a is amended by striking the word "commission" and adding the word "Commission" in its place. Sec. 3. Section 7(c) of the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984, effective April 10, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-76; D.C. Code § 1-246(c is amended by striking the word "sections" and adding the word "section" in its place. Sec. 4. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-601.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 301 (D.C. Code § 1-603.1) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (13A) is amended by striking the phrase Nonschool-based personnel and inserting the phrase "The term "nonschool-based personnel in its place 2) Paragraph (15A) is amended by striking the phrase School administrators and inserting the phrase "The term "school administrators" in its place b) Section 2310(a D.C. Code § 1-624.10(a is amended by striking the phrase "subsection (a-l of this section" and adding the phrase "subsection (a-l) of this section in its place. Sec. 5. Section 208(a) of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1182.8(a is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1)(A) is amended by adding in the second sentence the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "subparagraph (B b) Paragraph (1)(B)(iii) is amended by striking the phrase "clause (ii and adding the phrase "sub-subparagraph (ii) of this subparagraph" in its place c) Paragraph (2)(B) is amended by adding the phrase "of this paragraph" after the Section 1-116 Section 1-246 Section 1-603.1 Section 1-624.10 Section 1-1182.8 3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL phrase "subparagraph (A d) Paragraph (3)(G) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraph (4 e) Paragraph (3)(H) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraph (4 f) Paragraph (4)(A) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraph (3)(H g) Paragraph (4)(B) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraph (3)(G Sec. 6. The District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 699; D.C. Code § 1-1301 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 9(h D.C. Code § 1-1313(h is amended by striking in both places the seaio 1-1313 phrase "1-1312(i and adding the phrase "§ 1-1321(i in its place b) Section 17(e)(1 D.C. Code § 1-1321(e)(1 is amended by striking the colon and smiol, adding a semicolon in its place. 1-1321 Sec. 7. Section 2(2)(H) of the Business Regulatory Reform Commission Act of 1994, effective March 16, 1995 (D.C. Law 10-212; D.C. Code § 2-4101(2)(H is amended by striking the word "businesses" and adding the word "business" in its place. Section 2-4101 Sec. 8. The District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code § 3-205.1 et seq is amended as follows (a) Section 511(a)(5)(A-1 D.C. Code § 3-205.11(a)(5)(A-1 is amended by strikingseaio,,3-205.11 the figure "50 and adding the phrase "50 cents" in its place b) Section 1404(a)(5)(A-1 D.C. Code § 3-214.04 (a)(5)(A-1 is amended by striking the phrase "funeral service" in the second sentence. 3-214.o4 Sec. 9. Section 10(a)(3) of the Day Care Policy Act of 1979, effective September 19, 1979 (D.C. Law 3-16; D.C. Code § 3-309(a)(3 is amended by striking the phrase "established by paragraph (1)(A) through (D) and subsection (h)(2 and adding the phrase "established pursuant to subsections (a)(1) and (h)(2 in its place. Section 3-309 Sec. 10. Section 6(a) of the District of Columbia Right to Overnight Shelter Act of 1984, effective March 14, 1985 D.C. Law 5-146; D.C. Code § 3-605.1(a is amended by adding in the third sentence the word "may" after the word "be Section 3-605.1 Sec. 11. Section 12(m) of the District of Columbia Policeman’s and Fireman’s Retirement Disability Act, approved August 21, 1957 (71 Stat. 397; D.C. Code § 4-624 is Section 4-624 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL amended as follows a) Subsection (c-2)(1) is amended by striking the phrase "paragraph (3A) of this subsection" and adding the phrase "subsection (c-1) of this section" in its place b) Subsection (c-2)(1)(A) is amended by striking the phrase "paragraph (3A) of this subsection" and adding the phrase "subsection (c-l) of this section" in its place and by striking the phrase "1 per centum" and adding the figure "1 in its place c) Subsection (c-2)(1)(B) is amended by striking the phrase "paragraph (3A) of this subsection" and adding "subsection (c-l) of this section" in its place and by striking the phrase "1 per centum" and adding the figure "1 in its place d) Subsection (c-2)(2)(A) is amended by striking the phrase the figure "1 in its place e) Subsection (c-2)(2)(B) is amended by striking the phrase the figure "1 in its place 1 per centum" and adding "1 per centum" and adding Sec. 12. Section 13(a) of the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1994, effective March 21, 1995 (D.C. Law 10-243; D.C. Code § 5-131(a is amended by striking the phrase "in effect on March 21, 1995" after the word "States Sec. 13. Section 7(a) of the District of Columbia Environmental Policy Act of 1989, effective October 18, 1989 (D.C. Law 8-36; D.C. Code § 6-986(a is amended as follows a) Subsection (a)(7) is amended by striking the word "or" at the end b) Subsection (a)(8) is amending by striking the period and adding the phrase or" in its place. Sec. 14. The Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-137; D.C. Code § 6-190l et seq is amended as follows a) Section 309(a)(7 D.C. Code § 6-1929(a)(7 is amended by striking the phrase "Director of the facility" wherever it appears and adding the phrase "Department of Human Services" in its place b) Section 411(a)(4 D.C. Code § 6-1951(a)(4 is amended by striking the phrase "no longer" Sec. 15. Section 16(f) of the District of Columbia Solid Waste Management and Multi- Material Recycling Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-226; D.C. Code § 6- 3415(f is amended by striking the word "Envioronmental" and adding the word "Environmental" in its place. Sec. 16. Section 5(a) of the Solid Waste Facility Permit Act of 1994, effective March 23, 1995 (D.C. Law 10-251; D.C. Code § 6-3454(a is amended by striking the word Section 5-/31 Section 6-986 Section 6-1929 Sectioll 6-1951 Section 6-3415 Sectio~l 6-3454 5 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "reasonable" and adding the word "reasonably" in its place. Sec. 17. An Act to Authorize an increased share of the costs of certain transportation projects in the District of Columbia for fiscal years 1995 and 1996, and for other purposes, approved August 4, 1995 (109 Stat. 257; D.C. Code § 7-134.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3(c)(4 D.C. Code § 7-134.2(c)(4 is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase 3 b) Section 4(d D.C. Code § 7-134.3(d is amended by striking the word "authority" and adding the phrase "Authority established pursuant to section 101 (a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat 116; D.C. Code § 47-391.1(a in its place. Section 7-134.2 Section 7-134.3 Sec. 18. Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 16-401(4)(B) is amended by striking the words "right" and "act" and adding the words "rights" and "chapter" respectively, in their places. 16.4Ol (b) Section 16-402(b) is amended by striking the figure 10,000 and adding the figure 16-402 10,000" in its place c) Section 16-909.1 is amended as follows 1) The section heading is amended by striking the word "acknowledgement"~6-9o9.1 and adding the word "acknowledgment" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "acknowledgement" and adding the word "acknowledgment" in its place d) Section 16-911(a-2) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (2)(A) is amended by striking the word "subsection" and adding16-9al the word "chapter" in its place 2) Paragraph (2)(B) is amended by striking the phrase "this subsection" and adding the phrase "subsection (a) of this section" in its place 3) Paragraph (6)(A) is amended by striking the word "interests" and adding the word "interest" in its place e) Section 16-916.1 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase gross income and 16-916.1 adding the phrase "the term "gross income in its place 2) Subsection (1)(5) is amended by striking the phrase "obligations. A temporary" and adding the phrase "obligations; a temporary" in its place 3) Subsection (n)(3) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase 2)(B f) Section 16-2309(a)(7) is amended by striking the word "By" and adding the word s~aio by" in its place. 16-23o~Section (g) Section 16-2320 is amended as follows 6-23~0 6 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (1) Subsection (c)(1) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (a 2) Subsection (c-l) is amended by striking the symbol "§" and adding the word "section" in its place h) Section 16-2331(b) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (c i) Section 16-2345 is amended by striking the word "acknowledgement" and adding the word "acknowledgment" in its place and by adding a period at the end of the second sentence. Section 16-2331 Section 16-2345 Sec. 19. Title 20 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 20-101 (d)(2)(A) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after Section the phrase "paragraph (1 20.101 (b) Section 20-324(a) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phraseseaio,,20-324 "paragraph (3 c) Section 20-701.1(b) is amended by striking the phrase "Time for distribution Section 20-701.1(d) Section 20-704 is amended as follows: seaio 1) Subsection (b)(3) is amended by striking the phrase "representative at the 20-704 end of the paragraph and adding the phrase "representative in its place 2) The undesignated text following subsection (b)(4) is amended by striking the phrases "The personal" and "this subsection" and adding the phrases b-1) The personal" and "subsection (b) of this section" respectively, in their place 3) Subsection (b-l) is amended by striking the phrase b-l and adding the phrase b-2 in its place 4) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the word "Except" and adding the word "except" in its place and by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsections (a) and (b wherever it appears. Section(e) Section 20-713 (a) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase 2o-713 "subsection (c f) Section 20-724(a)(2) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraph (1 20.724 (g) Section 20-73 l(a) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (b 2o-731 (h) Section 20-732(a) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase Section "subsection (c 20-732 (i) Section 20-735(c) is amended by striking the phrase "The Certificate" and adding the phrase "The Certificate of Completion" in its place. 20-735 (j) Section 20-736(1) is amended by striking the phrase "60 day" and adding the phrase "60-day" in its place. 20-736 Section (k) Section 20-91 l(b)(1) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. 2o-~11 7 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (1) Section 20-1301(b)(A) is amended by striking the phrase "the Certificate" and adding s~tion 20-1301 the phrase "the Certificate of Completion" in its place. Sec. 20. Title 21 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 21-320(3) is amended by striking the word "the" and adding the word "The" in its place b) Section 21-501 is amended as follows 1) By striking the word administrator and adding the phrase 1 Administrator in its place 2) By striking the phrase chief of service and adding the phrase 2) Chief of service in its place 3) By striking the word Commission and adding the phrase 3 Commission in its place; By striking the word court and adding the phrase 4 Court in its(4) place 5) By illness in its place 6) By "Mentally-ill person 7) By in its place; striking the phrase mental illness and adding the phrase 5 Mental striking the phrase mentally ill person and adding the phrase 6) in its place; striking the word physician and adding the phrase 7 Physician 8) By striking the phrase private hospital and adding the phrase 8 Private hospital in its place 9) By striking the phrase public hospital and adding the phrase 9 Public hospital in its place; and (10) By striking the phrase qualified psychologist and adding the phrase 10 Qualified psychologist in its place c) Section 21-1201(3)(A) is amended by striking the colon at the end and adding a semicolon in its place d) Section 21-1708 is amended by striking the word "fiducuary" and adding the word "fiduciary" in its place e) Section 21-2205(e) is amended by striking the phrase "executed prior to March 16, 1989" and adding the phrase "for health care executed prior to March 16, 1989 in its place. Sec. 21. The District of Columbia Alcoholic Beverage Control Act, approved January 24, 1934 (48 Stat. 319; D.C. Code § 25-101 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 8(a)(3 D.C. Code § 25-108(a)(3 is amended by adding the word "or" at the end b) Section 31 (D.C. Code § 25-131) is amended by adding the word "issued" after the Section 21-320 Section 21-501 Section 21-1201 Section 21-1708 Section 21-2205 Section 25-108 Section 21-131 8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL phrase "dates of permits" in the first sentence. Sec. 22. Section 714(c)(3) of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Star. 1303; D.C. Code § 26-102(c)(3 is amended by redesignating paragraph (3) as subsection (d by striking the phrase "That after" and adding the phrase "After" in its place, and by striking the phrase "this subsection" and adding the phrase "subsection (c) of this section" in its place. Sec. 23. Section 1 (a)(2) of An Act Regulating corporations doing a banking business in the District of Columbia, approved April 26, 1922 (42 Stat. 500; D.C. Code § 26-103(a)(2 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Section 26-102 Section 26-103 Sec. 24. An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1303; D.C. Code § 26-401 et seq is amended as follows: Section (a) Section 715(2 D.C. Code § 26-401(2 is amended by adding the word "or" at the 26-401 end. Section (b) Section 716(4 D.C. Code § 26-404(4 is amended by adding the word "and" at the26-404 end. end c) Section 721(4 D.C. Code § 26-409(4 is amended by adding the word "and" at the seaio,,26-409 (d) Section 691a(a)(4)(A D.C. Code § 26-506(a)(4)(A is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. 26-so6 Sec. 25. Section 6(g)(4) of the District of Columbia Savings and Loan Acquisition Amendment Act of 1988, effective October 12, 1988 (D.C. Law 7-175; D.C. Code § 26- 905(g)(4 is amended by striking the phrase 4)(A and adding the phrase A in its place. Sec. 26. Section 670 of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1295; D.C. Code § 27-114 is amended by striking the phrase "one mile and a half" and adding the phrase "one and one-half miles" in its place. Sec. 27. Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 28-2103 is amended by striking the phrase "His asset" and adding the phrase "His assent" in its place b) Section 28-2711 is amended as follows 1) The section heading is amended by striking the word "Saving" and adding the word "savings" in its place 2) The text is amended by striking the word "saving" and adding the word "savings" in its place. Section 26-905 Section 27-114 Section 28-2103 Sectiol~ 28-2711 9 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (c) Section 28-3106 is amended as follows: Smion 28-3106 (1) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the word "subsection" and adding the word "section" in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the word "subsection" and adding the word "section" in its place d) Section 28-3307 is amended in the section heading and text by striking the phrase Section "District of Columbia Council" and adding the phrase "Council of the District of Columbia" in 28-3307 its place and by striking the phrase "chapter 37 of title 38 and adding the phrase "Chapter 37 of Title 38 in its place e) Section 28-3308(c) is amended by striking the phrase "this section of’ and addingSection the phrase "this section if’ in its place. 28-3308 (f) Section 28-3309 is amended in the section heading and text by striking the phase Section 28-3309 "District of Columbia Council" and adding the phrase "Council of the District of Columbia" in its place g) Section 28-3312(5) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end. Section 28-3312(h) Section 28-3314 is amended in the lead-in language by striking the phrase "recoverSection or obtain" and adding the phrase "recover, or obtain" in its place. 28-3314 (i) Section 28-3504 is amended by striking the phrase "acknowledgement or promise" and adding the phrase "acknowledgment, or promise in its place and by striking the phrase "isSection28-3504 sufficient" and adding the phrase "is not sufficient" in its place j) Section 28-3701 is amended as follows: Section (1) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase "loss and adding the phrase 28-3701 "loss, and" in its place 2) Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the word Financial" and adding the word financial" in its place k) Section 28-3702(a) is amended as follows: Section (1) Paragraph (2) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the 28-3702 phrase "paragraph (1 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraph (2 and by striking the phrase "size or contrasting" and adding the phrase "size, or contrasting" in its place. Section (1) Section 28-3802 is amended as follows: 28-3802 (1) Paragraph (2)(A) is amended by striking the word "pereson" and adding the word "person" in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the word "chapter" and adding the word "Chapter" in its place m) Section 28-3803(3) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after theSmion 28-3803 phrase "paragraph (2 Section (n) Section 28-3805(a) is amended by striking the phrase § 28-3701 and adding the 28-380s 10 ENROLLED ORIGINAL phrase section 28-3701 in its place o) Section 28-3806 is amended by striking the word "loans" and the phrase "consumersmio, i 28-3806 or" and adding the word "loan" and the phrase "consumer of" respectively, in their places p) Section 28-3810 is amended by striking the word "lesses" and adding the word "lessees" in its place s-381o (q) Section 28-3811 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the 28-3~11 phrase "subsection (f 2) Subsection (e) is amended by striking the word "writen" and adding the word "written" in its place r) Section 28-3817 is amended as follows: Section28-3817 (1) Subsection (c)(4)(B) is amended by striking the phrase "paragraph (A and adding the phrase "subparagraph (A) of this paragraph" in its place 2) Subsection (c)(4)(C) is amended by striking the phrase "paragraph (B and adding the phrase "subparagraph (B) of this paragraph" in its place 3) Subsection (c)(4)(D) is amended by striking the phrase "paragraph (4 and adding the phrase "subparagraph (C) of this paragraph" in its place 4) Subsection (c)(4)(E) is amended by striking the phrases "paragraph (D and "paragraph (C and adding the phrases "subparagraph (D) of this paragraph and "subparagraph (C) of this paragraph respectively, in their places 5) Subsection (d)(2) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (b 6) Subsection (d)(3) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (c 7) Subsection (d)(4) is amended by striking the word "paragraph" and adding the word "subsection" in its place 8) Subsection (e)(1) is amended by adding a comma after the phrase "against the surety 9) Subsection (e)(2) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (f 10) Subsection (e)(3) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (f 11) Subsection (g) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (e)(3 12) Subsection (h) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (e)(3 s) Section 28-3818 is amended as follows: s~t~o 1) Subsection (a)(1) is amended by adding a comma after the words "used" and "family 11 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (2) Subsection (a)(3) is amended by striking the phrase "plan: Provided and adding the phrase "plan; provided in its place 3) Subsection (b) is amended by adding a comma after the word "clear t) Section 28-3819 is amended as follows: Section 28-3819 (1) Subsection (2) Subsection customer 3) Subsection phrase "subsection (c u) Section 28-3901 is s~ctio 1) Subsection 28.390~ word "section" in its place 2) Subsection (b)(2) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end v) Section 28-3902(e) is amended by striking the phrase "section 103 of the Section Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985" and adding the28.3902 phrase "section 6-2703" in its place w) Section 28-3903 is amended as follows: s~aio,,28-3903 (1) Subsection (a)(10) is amended by striking the phrase "D.C. Code, secs. 1- 1503 1-1507" and adding the phrase "sections 1-1501 et seq in its place 2) Subsection (c)(2)(D) is amended by adding a comma after the word "publishes" and by adding the word "or" at the end x) Section 28-3904 is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (r)(4) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. 28-3904 (2) Subsection (r)(5) is amended by adding a comma after the word "illiteracy 3) Subsection (y) is amended by striking the phrase "D.C. Code, sec and adding the word "section" in its place 4) Subsection (z) is amended by striking the phrase "D.C. Code, sec and adding the word "section" in its place and by striking the period at the end and adding a semicolon in its place 5) Subsection (z-l) is amended by striking the period at the end and adding a semicolon in its place 6) Subsection (aa) is amended by striking the period at the end and adding a semicolon in its place 7) Subsection (cc) is amended by striking the word "and" and adding the word "or" in its place y) Section 28-3905 is amended as follows: seaio 1) The undesignated text following subsection (b)(2) is amended as follows:28-39os (A) By striking the phrase "In carrying" and adding the phrase b-l) In carrying" in its place a)(4) is amended by adding a comma after the word "apartment c)(1) is amended by adding a comma after the phrase "potential (d)(3) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the amended as follows a 12) is amended by striking the symbol "§" and adding the 12 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (B) By striking the phrase "such investigation"and adding the phrase "an investigation" in its place; and (C) By adding the phrase "pursuant to subsection (b) of this section" after the word "determination 2) Subsection (d)(2) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraph (1 3) Subsection (d)(5) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end 4) The undesignated text following subsection (d)(6) is amended by striking the phrase "The Director" and adding the phrase d-l) The Director" in its place and by striking the phrase "such reasons" and adding the phrase "the reasons stated in subsection (d) of this section 5) Subsection (e) is amended by striking the phrase "subsection (d wherever its appears and adding the phrase "subsection (d-l in its place 6) Subsection (e)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "paragraph (2) of this subsection" and adding the phrase "subsection (h)(2) of this section" in its place 7) Subsection (f) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (h 8) Subsection (g)(5) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end 9) Subsection (h)(1) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrases "subsection (d and "subsection (f 10) Subsection (h)(1)(D) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end 11) Subsection (h)(3) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraph (1 12) Subsection (i)(1)(A) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (f 13) Subsection (i)(1)(B) is amended by striking the phrase "subsections (d) or (e and adding the phrase "subsection (d) or (e in its place 14) Subsection (i)(1)(C) is amended by striking the word "paragraph" and adding the word "subsection" in its place 15) The undesignated text following subsection (i)(l)(C) is amended by striking the phrase "such appeals" and adding the phrase IA) Such appeals" in its place and by striking the phrase "D.C. Code, sec and adding the word "section" in its place 16) Subsection (i)(2) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (j 17) Subsection (i)(3)(A)(i) is amended by striking the phrase "paragraph (g)(3 and adding "subsection (g)(3) of this section" in its place 18) Subsection (i)(3)(A)(ii) is amended by striking the phrase "subsections (f g) or (j and adding the phrase "subsection (f g or (j) of this section" in its place and by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (h 13 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (19) Subsection (i)(3)(B) is amended as follows A) By adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (h B) By striking the phrase "subsections (f g) or (j and adding the phrase "subsection (t g or (j) of this section" in its place; and (C) By adding a comma after the word "preliminary 20) Subsection (j) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (f 21) Subsection (k)(3) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (f 22) Subsection (p) is amended as follows A) By adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (a B) By striking the phrase "subsections (f g) or (j and adding the phrase "subsection (t g or (j) of this section" in its place; and (C) By striking the word "subparagraph" and adding the word "subsection" in its place 23) Subsection (q) is amended by striking the phrase "subsections (f) of (j and adding the phrase "subsection (f) or (j) of this section" in its place 24) Subsection (r) is amended by striking the phrase "D.C. Code z) Section 28-3907(b)(3) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end aa) Section 28-4001 is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (9) is amended by striking the phrase "section 4" and adding the phrase "section 28-4003" in its place 2) Paragraph (10) is amended by adding a comma after the phrase "hire- purchase bb) Section 28-4005(a)(9)(B) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end cc) Section 28-4006(c) is amended by striking the phrase "this act" wherever it appears and adding the phrase "this chapter" in its place and by striking the phrase "titles I-Ill of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985" and adding the phrase "chapter 27 of Title 6" in its place dd) Section 28-4506 is amended as follows h B) By "section" in its place; and (C) By place 1) Subsection (k) is amended as follows A) By adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection striking the phrase "D.C. Code, sec and adding the word striking the word "Except" and adding the word "except" in its Section 28-3907 Section 28-4001 Section 28-4005 Section 28-4006 Secfiol~ 28-4506 14 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (2) Subsection (1) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (k ee) Section 28-4507 is amended as follows: sectio 28-4507 (1) Subsection (c)(1) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (b 2) Subsection (c)(2) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (b and by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraph (1 ft) Section 28-4602(a)(2) is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (a)(2) is amended by adding the word "by" after the word 28.46o2 "prescribed 2) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase "this act" wherever it appears and adding the phrase "this chapter" in its place gg) Section 28-4603 is amended as follows: Smio 1) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "section 5" and adding the ~8-46o3 phrase "§ 28-4604" in its place 2) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the designations i ii and iii and adding subparagraph designations A B and C respectively, in their place 3) Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the phrase "this act" wherever it appears and adding the phrase "this chapter" in its place 4) Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the phrase "this act" wherever it appears and adding the phrase "this chapter" in its place hh) Section 28-4608 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended as follows; Section28-4608 (A) By striking the phrase "Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act APA approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq and adding the phrase "subchapter I of Chapter 15 of Title 1" in its place B) By striking the phrase "this act" and adding the phrase "this chapter and (C) By striking the phrase "title 1 of the APA (D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq and adding the phrase "subchapter I of Chapter 15 of Title 1" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase "not limited" and adding the phrase "not be limited to" in its place 3) Subsection (c) is amended by adding the word "for" after the word "effective ii) Section 28:1-105(2) is amended by striking the phrases "28:2A-105" and "§ 28:6-s,aio 106" and adding the phrases "28:2A-104" and "§ 28:6-102" respectively, in their places. 28:1-los (jj) Section 28:1-201 is amended as follows: Section (1) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase "2-208" and adding the 28:1-2ol 15 ENROLLED ORIGINAL phrase "28:2-208" in its place 2) Paragraph (44) is amended by striking the phrase "28:4-208 and 28:4-209" and adding the phrase "28:4-210 and 28:4-211" in its place kk) Section 28:2-209 is amended in the section heading by striking the word Section 28:2-209 "rescission" and adding the word "recission" in its place 11) Section 28:2-328 is amended by striking the word "action" and adding the word Section "auction" in its place. 28:2-328 (mm) Section 28:2-513 is amended by striking the period at the end and adding a colon Section in its place. 28:2..q3 (nn) Section 28:2-615 is amended as follows: Section 28:2-615 (1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the word "Delay" and adding the word "delay" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "Where" and adding the word "where" in its place 3) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the word "The" and adding the word "the" in its place oo) Section 28:2-724 is amended by striking the word "prepartion" and adding the word "preparation" in its place. 28:2-724 (pp) Section 28:2A-214 is amended as follows: s~aio 1) Subsection (c) is amended in the introductory language by striking the 28:2A-214 comma and adding a colon in its place 2) Subsection (c)(1) is amended by striking the word "Unless" and adding the word "unless" in its place 3) Subsection (c)(2) is amended by striking the word "If" and adding the word "if" in its place 4) Subsection (c)(3) is amended by striking the word "An" and adding the word "an" in its place. Section(qq) Section 28:2A-405 is amended as follows: 28:2A-4O5 (1) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the word "subsection" and adding the word "section" in its place 2) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the word "subsection" and adding the word "section" in its place 3) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the word "subsection" and adding the word "section" in its place rr) Section 28:2A-501(d) is amended by striking the phrase "of this article" and adding Sectio the phrase "or this article" in its place. 28:2A-S01 (SS) Section 28:3-407(c) is amended by striking the word "an" and adding the word "on" in its place. 28:3-407 Section(tt) Section 28:5-101 is amended by striking the word "The" and adding the word "This" 16 ENROLLED ORIGINAL in its place uu) Section 28:5-113 is amended as follows: Sectio. 28:5-113 (1) Paragraph (2)(a) is amended by striking the word "explicity" and adding the word "explicitly" in its place 2) Paragraph (2)(b) is amended by striking the word "explicity" and adding the word "explicitly" in its place vv) Section 28:7-102(2) is amended by striking the phrase Duty negotiate and Section adding the phrase Duly negotiated in its place. 2s 0 ww) Section 28:7-301(4) is amended by striking the phrase "be adding" and adding theSection phrase "by inserting" in its place. 2s:7-30 xx) Section 28:7-308(1) is amended by striking the phrase "in bloc" and adding the Sectionphrase "en bloc" in its place. 2s:7-3os (yy) Section 28:8-102 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b)(1) is amended by striking the phrase "§ 28:8-301" and addingSection the phrase "§ 28:8-302" in its place. 2s:s-102 (2) Subsection (b)(11) is amended by striking the phrase "§ 28:9-105" and adding the phrase "§ 28:9-104" in its place zz) Section 28:8-313(a)(4) is amended by striking the phrase "purchaser and addingSectio. the phrase "purchaser in its place aaa) Section 28:9-112 is amended in the introductory language by striking the phrase Section "section 28:9-504(1 and adding the phrase "section 28:9-504(2 in its place. 2s:9 2 (bbb) Section 28:9-114(3)(a) is amended by striking the phrase "indicated and addingsection 28:9-114 the phrase "indicated in its place ccc) Section 28:9-203(1) is amended by striking the phrase "§ 28:4-208" and adding section the phrase "§ 28:4-210" in its place. 2s:9-:os Section (ddd) Section 28:9-302(1)(f) is amended by striking the phrase section 28:4-208 and2s:9-302 adding the phrase section 28:4-210 in its place eee) Section 28:9-312(1) is amended by striking the phrase "section 28:4-208" and Section 28:9-312 adding the phrase "section 28:4-210" in its place fff) Section 28:9-313(2) is amended by striking the word "not" and adding the wordSection "no" in its place. 28:9-313 (ggg) Section 28:9-314 is amended by striking the word "taxes" and adding the word Section "takes" in its place. 28:9-314 (hhh) Section 28:9-403(2) is amended by striking the phrase "expiration the five" and Sectio. 28:9-403 adding the phrase "expiration of the five" in its place. Sec. 28. The District of Columbia Business Corporation Act, approved June 8, 1954 (68 Stat. 179; D.C. Code § 29-301 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 5(3 D.C. Code § 29-305(3 is amended by adding the word "or" at the Section 2%305 17 ENROLLED ORIGINAL end b) end c) end d) the end e) end. the end g h) the end. Section Section Section Section Section 7(2 D.C. Code § 29-307(2 is amended by adding the word "or" at the Section 29-307 8(3 D.C. Code § 29-308(3 is amended by adding the word "and" at the Sectio. 29-308 9(a)(5 D.C. Code § 29-309(a)(5 is amended by adding the word "or" at Section 29-309 10(1 D.C. Code § 29-310(l is amended by adding the word "and" at thesection 29-310 13(b)(4 D.C. Code § 29-313(b)(4 is amended by adding the word "and"atSection 29-313 Section 14 (D.C. Code § 29-314) is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (a)(6) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. 29-314 (2) Subsection (d)(3) is amended by adding the word "and" at theend. SectionSection 18(a)(3 D.C. Code § 29-318(a)(3 is amended by adding the word "or" at 29-318 (i) Section 20(d)(3 D.C. Code § 29-320(d)(3 is amended by adding the word "and" at Section the end. 29-320 (j) Section 48(a)(2 D.C. Code § 29-348(a)(2 is amended by adding the word "and" at Section the end. 29-348 (k) Section 72(a)(1 D.C. Code § 29-372(a)(1 is amended by striking the word Section filed and adding the word Filed in its place. 29-372 S ec. 29. Section 101 (1) of the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act, approved August 6, 1962 (76 Stat. 303; D.C. Code § 29-599.3(1 is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and adding a period in its place. Sec. 30. Section 574(3) of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1280; D.C. Code § 29-801(1 is amended by striking the comma at the end. Sec. 31. Section 72 of the Limited Liability Company Act of 1994, effective July 23, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-138; D.C. Code § 29-1371 is amended as follows a) Subsection (c)(1) is amended by striking the word "work" and adding the word "word" in its place b) Subsection (f) is amended by striking the phrase "subsection (d and adding the phrase "subsection (c in its place. Section 29-599.3 Section 29-801 Section 29-1371 18 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 32. Section 143 of An Act Making appropriations for the government of the District of Columbia and other activities chargeable in whole or in part against the revenues of said District for fiscal year ending September 30, 1995, and %r other purposes, approved September 30, 1994 (108 Stat. 2594; D.C. Code § 31-104.2 is amended as follows a) Subsection (b) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (a b) Subsection (c) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrases "subsection (a and "subsection (b)(1 2) Paragraph (2) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (a c) Subsection (d)(2) is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraph (1 31-104.2 Sec. 33. Section 21(b-1)(2)(B)(i) of An Act for the retirement of public-school teachers in the District of Columbia, October 24, 1962 (76 Stat. 1236; D.C. Code § 31-1241(b- 1)(2)(B)(i is amended by adding the word "or" before the word "before Section 31-1241 Sec. 34. Section 513(b)(6) of the District of Columbia Public Education Reorganization Act, effective February 24, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-177; D.C. Code § 31-1553(b)(6 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Sectioii 31-1553 Sec. 35. The Education of the Deaf Act of 1986, approved August 4, 1986 (100 Stat. 781; D.C. Code § 31-1841.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 104(a)(1)(B) and (C D.C. Code § 31-1841.3a(a)(1)(B) and (C is amended Sectio 31-1841.3a by adding the phrase "of this paragraph" after the phrase "subparagraph (A b) Section 201(3 D.C. Code § 31-1842.2a(3) is amended by adding the phrase "of this Section paragraph" after the phrase "subparagraph (F 31-1842.2a (C) Section 203 (D.C. Code § 31-1842.3) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (c)(2)(B) is amended by adding the phrase "of this paragraph" Sectio,~31-1842.3 after the phrase "subparagraph (A 2) Subsection (c)(2)(C) is amended by adding the phrase "of this paragraph" after the phrase "subparagraph (B Sec. 36. Section 210(c)(1) of the Education of the Deaf Act of 1986, October 16, 1992 (106 Stat. 2163; D.C. Code § 31-1842.10(c)(1 is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (b Section 31-1842.10 19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 37. Section 4a(b) and (e) of the Drug Paraphernalia Act of 1982, effective March 25, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-252; D.C. Code § 33-603.1(b) and (e is amended by striking the word "individual" and adding the word "individuals" in its place. Section 33-603.1 Sec. 38. Section 41(g)(2) of chapter III of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 12, Sectio 1960 (74 Stat. 218; D.C. Code § 35-639(g)(2 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. 35-a39 Sec. 39. Section 22(8) of the Fire and Casualty Act, approved October 9, 1940 (54 Stat. Section 1074; D.C. Code § 35-1526(8 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. 35-15~ Sec. 40. Section 6(a)(2) of the Life Insurance Act, approved May 20, 1948 (62 Stat. 245; D.C. Code § 35-1206(a)(2 is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Section 35-1206 Sec. 41. Section 11 of the Risk Retention Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-46; D.C. Code § 35-2910 is amended by adding the word "Liability" before the word "Risk Sectiol~ 35-2910 Sec. 42. Section 2(a)(5) of the Law on Credit for Reinsurance Act of 1993, effective October 15, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-36; D.C. Code § 35-3301(a)(5 is amended by adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase 4 Sec. 43. Section 6(a)(1)(C) of the Holding Company System Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-44; D.C. Code § 35-3705(a)(1)(C is amended by striking the word "Each" and adding the word Each" in its place and by striking the word "addition and adding the word "addition in its place. Section 35-3301 Section 35-3705 Sec. 44. The Uniform Disposition of Unclaimed Property Act of 1980, effective March 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-160; D.C. Code § 42-201 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 104(4)(A D.C. Code § 42-204(4)(A is amended by striking the word "or"Se~tio at the end. 42-204 (b) Section 108(1 D.C. Code § 42-208(1 is amended by adding the word "and" at thesection end. 4z-zo8 Sec. 45. Section 203 of the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996, effective April 18, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-111; D.C. Code § 43-1673 is amended as follows a) Paragraphs (10 22 26 and (28) are amended by striking the period at the end and adding a semicolon in its place b) Paragraph (30) is amended by striking the period at the end and adding the phrase Sectio~ 43-1673 20 ENROLLED ORIGINAL and" in its place. Sec. 46. The Cable Television Communications Act of 1981, effective August 21, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-142; D.C. Code § 43-1801 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 43-1802) is amended as follows: Section 43-1802 (1) Paragraph (19) is amended by adding the word "also" after the word "shall" in the last sentence 2) Paragraph (33) is amended by striking the phrase "cable service" and adding the phrase "cable services" in its place b) Section 47 (D.C. Code § 43-1846) is amended by adding the phrase "and above" s~aion after the word "herein 43-1846 Sec. 47. Section 501(c) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980, effective September 10, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-86; D.C. Code § 45-1651(c is amended by striking the phrase "Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Extension and Amendment Act of 1995" and adding the phrase "Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment Extension and Amendment Act of 1995" in both places. Section 45-1651 Sec. 48. The Horizontal Property Act of the District of Columbia, approved December 21, 1963 (77 Stat. 449; D.C. Code § 45-1701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(14)(C D.C. Code § 45-1702(14)(C is amended by adding the word s~aion 45-1702 "and" at the end b) Section 9(a)(3 D.C. Code § 45-1709(a)(3 is amended by adding the word "and" section at the end. 45-1:o9 (c) Section 14(a)(7 D.C. Code § 45-1714(a)(7 is amended by adding the word "and"s~aion at the end. 45-1714 Sec. 49. The Condominium Act of 1976, effective March 29, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-89; D.C. Code § 45-1801 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 102(18 D.C. Code § 45-1801(18 is amended by striking the word "means" and adding the phrase "shall mean" in its place b) Section 403 (D.C. Code § 45-1863) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a)(6) is amended by striking the word "and" at the end 2) Subsection (a)(7) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Sec. 50. Section 301(15) of the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Act, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-135; D.C. Code § 45-2121(15 is amended by adding the word "or" before the word "sell Section 45-1801 Section 45-1863 Section 45-2121 21 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 5l. The Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Code § 45-2501 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 202(a)(1 D.C. Code § 45-2512(a)(1 is amended by striking the word section 45-2512 "amd" and adding the word "and" in its place b) Section 205 (D.C. Code § 45-2515) is amended as follows: seaio 1) Subsection (a)(3)(C) is amended by striking the word "and" at the end. 45-2515 (2) Subsection (a)(3)(D) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end 3) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase 10)(A and adding the phrase a 10 A c) Section 221(b D.C. Code § 45-2529.2(b is amended by adding the phrase "of this Section subsection" after the phrase "subsection (c 45-2529.2 Sec. 52. The District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act, approved August 28, 1935 (49 Stat. 946; D.C. Code § 46-101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 7 (D.C. Code § 46-108) is amended as follows: Section46-108 (1) Subsection (g)(3)(A) is amended by striking the word "and" at the end 2) Subsection (g)(3)(B) is amended by striking the period and adding the phrase and" in its place 3) Subsection (i)(1)(A)(i)(I) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end 4) Subsection (i)(1)(A)(ii)(ll) is amended by striking the period and adding the phrase mad" in its place b) Section 9(8 D.C. Code § 46-110(8 is amended by adding the word "and" at the sectio end. 46-110 (c) Section 10(d D.C. Code § 46-11 l(d is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (d)(1)(B) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end. 4~-nl (2) Subsection (d)(2) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end. Sec. 53. Section 17 the Tax Revenue Anticipation Notes Act of 1996, effective August 5, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-373; 43 DCR 4786 is amended by striking the phrase "and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register Sec. 54. The Drug Paraphernalia Amendment Act of 1996, signed by the Mayor on August 9, 1996 (D.C. Act l 1-391; 43 DCR 4986 is amended by striking in the long title the word "suspended" and adding the word "revoked" in its place. 22 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 55. The Budget Support Act of 1995, effective March 5, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-98; 43 DCR 5 is amended as follows a) Section 1101(e) is amended by striking the phrase "Section 2705(a)(1) and (2 D.C.scctJo 1-628.5 Code § 1-628.5(a)(1) and (2 and adding the phrase "Section 2705(a)(2) and (3 D.C. Code § 1-628.5(a)(2) and (3 in its place b) Section 1201 is amended in the lead-in text by striking the phrase D.C. Law 10- seaJo 220; D.C. Code § 31-132 and adding the phrase D.C. Law 10-221; D.C. Code § 31-132(a 31-132 in its place. Sec. 56. Section 2(f)(2) of the Cable Television Amendment Act of 1996, signed by the Mayor on August 6, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-386; 43 DCR 4702 is amended to read as follows 2) Subsection (d)(2) is amended to read as follows d)(2) Coordinate, manage, and oversee the use of all municipal and educational channels Section 43-1806 Sec. 57. Section 2(g)(1) of the Modified Reduction-in-Force Temporary Amendment Act of 1996, signed by the Mayor on July 26, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-363; 43 DCR 5427 is amended by striking the phrase "title XVI" and inserting the phrase "title XV" in its place. Note, Section 1-625.7 Sec. 58. Section 6 of the District of Columbia Air Pollution Control Act of 1984, Section 6-906effective March 15, 1985 (D.C. Law 5-165; D.C. Code § 6-906 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c) The Mayor may also issue or amend any rule needed to implement the provisions of this act pursuant to Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq Rules issued pursuant to this subsection are not subject to the 45-day Council review period prescribed in subsection (b) of this section Sections Sec. 59. Sections 101,102, 103(a and 106 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act 4s-gz3, of 1996, enacted July 26, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-360; 43 DCR 4569 are repealed. 47-9113,47-1812.7, 47-3905 Sec. 60. The act makes technical amendments to existing legislation and therefore has no fiscal impact. Sec. 61. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of 23 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Congressional review as provided i/~7~ection 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Self- 8G1 e;n. cm.e ~t0 d~ GlO_~3r~ c~i~n l~J~r g aniicZaattiioO~ jAn a pD~tOr~td oDf ~c~ ln~ bmebri2a elg9i7st3e~!7 Stat. Council of the District of Columbia M~yor District of Columbia APPROVED: December 24, 1996 24 { ] [TF~M ON CONSENT CALENDAR I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE t~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF DISTRICT OF COLL,’MBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVE~N RECORD OF OFlrICIAL COUNCIL VOTE BII-905Docket No ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-7-96 APPROVED THOMAS [ I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Ray x IndiTtes V~e [~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay N AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, Sr. Mason Whittington Patterson AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD ~’t~d NV- Preset no~ Voting [~ ACTION&amp;amp;DATF~ ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-3-96 vo,cE VOTE APP ROVFII A~ENT RAY [ ] POLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans "¢%"0 X-inlicates" no ~ry to the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ] ACTION&amp;amp;DATE C Aye Nay NV AB Cotmcilmember Aye Nay NV AB. Cotm~raemb~r Aye Nay N- AB Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington NV-Presem not ve~ing Date [ ] VOICEVOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councihnember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Light foot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X Indicates Vote AB Absent Coun~lmember Aye Nay N%’ AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington 3 Preset not vetmg CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary, to the Council Date 220; D.C. Code § 31-132 and adding the phrase D.C. Law 10-221; D.C. Code § 31-132(a 1 in its place. 2 Sec. 73. Section 2(d)(2) of the Cable Television Amendment Act of 1996, signed by the3 Mayor on August 6, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-386; 43 DCR is amended to read as follows: 4 2) Subsection (d)(2) is amended to read as follows: 5 d)(2) Coordinate, manage, and oversee the use of all municipal and educational 6 channels 7 Sec. 74. Section 2(g)(1) of the Modified Reduction-in-Force Temporary Amendment Act8 of 1996, signed by the Mayor on July 26, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-363; 43 DCR is amended by 9 striking the phrase "title XVI" and inserting the phrase "title XV" in its place. 10 Sec. 75. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of11 veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial 12 Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the 13 District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, 14 approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and a 60-day period of 15 Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the I)istrict of Columbia Self- 16 Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813;17 D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. 18 43</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
