<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-244">
  <num type="law">11-244</num>
  <heading type="short">Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-244.pdf">D.C. Law 11-244</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 1155</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0693">
      <narrative>Law 11-244, the “Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-693, which was referred to the Committee on the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-504 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-244 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENR LLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 330 051 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-244 "Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-693, on first and second readings, November 7, 1996 and December 3, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 24, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-504, and published in the February 28, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 1155) and transmitted to Congress on January 24, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-244, effective April 9, 1997. Chairman Pro Tempore of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,24,25,26,27,28 Mar. 3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21 Apr. 7,8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 11.504 Codification DisO’ict of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 24, 1996 To amend the Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Act of 1985 to require the driver and all passengers in a motor vehicle to wear a properly adjusted and fastened safety belt while the driver is in control of the vehicle, to provide an exemption for passengers in a vehicle if all seating positions with seat belts in the vehicle are occupied by other persons, provided that the driver shall insure that children 16 years of age and under shall have preference to seating positions with seat belts, to provide for an enforcement date, to provide that efforts to educate the public about the requirements and purpose of this act shall be multi-lingual and in alternative formats, to increase the monetary fine for a violation, to provide for primary enforcement, to provide for the assessment of 2 points to the driving record of a driver found in violation, to make the driver of the vehicle, except the operator of a passenger vehicle for hire, responsible for ensuring that passengers comply with this act; to amend Title 31 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations to establish a mandatory seatbelt usage signage requirement for passenger vehicles for hire; and to provide for a $100 fine for drivers of public vehicles for hire who fail to comply with the signage requirement. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. The Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Act of 1985, effective December 12, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-73; D.C. Code § 40-1601 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 40-1602) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows a) Except as provided in the Child Restraint Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-194; D.C. Code § 40-1201 et seq the driver and all passengers in a motor vehicle shall wear a properly adjusted and fastened safety belt while the driver is in control of the vehicle 2) Subsection (b)(1) is amended by striking the word "or 1 Section 40-1602 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (3) Subsection (b)(2) is amended by striking the and inserting in its place or and (4) A new subsection (b)(3) is added to read as follows 3) Riders who are passengers in a vehicle if all seating positions with seat belts in the vehicle are occupied by other persons. The driver shall insure that children 16 years of age and under have preference to seating positions with seat belts over persons more than 16 years of age b) Section 6 (D.C. Code § 40-1605) is amended to read as follows For the first 6 months after its effective date, the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall educate the public about the requirements and the purpose of the Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996. The efforts to educate the public shall be multi-lingual and in alternative formats c) Section 7 (D.C. Code § 40-1606) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "this act" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "the Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996" in its place; and (2) Subsection (b)(1) is amended to read as follows b)(1) The penalties provisions in paragraph (2) of this subsection and subsection (d) of this section shall not be enforced until 6 months after the effective date of the Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996. The Mayor shall issue rules consistent with the purpose and regulatory scheme created by this act. The Mayor shall issue the rules pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1203; D.C. Code § 1-1501 etseq 3) Subsection (b)(2) is amended to read as follows b)(2) The penalty imposed by the Mayor for violating this act shall be $50, although the Mayor may subsequently increase the amount of the penalty 4) Subsection (c) is repealed 5) Subsection (d) is amended to read as follows d) The Department of Public Works shall assign 2 points pursuant to 18 DCMR 303 to the driving record of a driver found in violation of this act and (6) Subsection (f) is amended to read as follows f) The driver of the vehicle, except operators of passenger vehicles for hire, shall be responsible for ensuring that passengers comply with this chapter Sec. 3. Title 31 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (Taxicabs and Public Vehicles for Hire 31 DCMR) is amended as follows 1) Section 607 of Chapter 6 (Seatbelts 31 DCMR 607) is amended by adding a new subsection 607.2 to read as follows 607.2 All passenger vehicles for hire shall contain a sign which states the following: Section 40-1605 Section 40-1606 DCMR 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "District law requires mandatory use of seat belts. There is a $50 penalty for non- compliance 2) Section 825 of Chapter 8 (Civil Fines for Taxicab Infractions 31 DCMR 825) is amended by adding to the list of fines after the fine for "Loitering the following language Mandatory use of seat belts signage Failure to have $100.00 Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 5. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor. action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17. 1995 (109 Stat. 116: D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(l) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(1 ao0 l~u~lication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 24, 1996 3 [ ] ITF_~M ON CONSENT CALENDAR [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL.~ABIA COUNCIl, PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-7-96 APPROVFD; BRAZ!L VnTF_n NO THOMAS [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NW AB Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray xi md~c~tp vote Secretary. to the Cotmeii AB- Abs~t CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington Cropp Evans 1 1~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-3-96 NV. Preset~t not Voting VOICE VOTE APP R(IVFII RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST RAY ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result C~mncilmember Aye Nay ~T AB Cotmdimember Chmn. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X-i~icales ao Se~re~ry to [he Council [ ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [ ] ACTION &amp;amp;DATE Aye Nay NV AB Coun~ilmember Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB-Abs~tt CERTIFICATION RECORD Aye Nay NW AB C NV-Present net young [ ] VOICEVOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALl, VOTE Result Counci|member Chmn. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray x Indicates Vote Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember [ Aye Nay ] NV AB Coundlmembtr Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB Absent Aye Nay AB Present CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary. to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
