<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-223">
  <num type="law">11-223</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Moratorium on the 1997 Real Property Assessments for Real Property Tax Year 1998 Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-223.pdf">D.C. Law 11-223</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 111</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0847">
      <narrative>Law 11-223, the “District of Columbia Moratorium on the 1997 Real Property Assessments for Real Property Tax Year 1998 Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-847, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 1, 1996, and November 7, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-442 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-223 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwikta 062 321 010 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-223 "District of Columbia Moratorium on the 1997 Real Property Assessments for Real Property Tax Year 1998 Amendment Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-847, on first and second readings, October 1, 1996 and November 7, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 25, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-442, and published in the January 10, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 111) and transmitted to Congress on January 23, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-223, effective April 9, 1997. Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. Mar. Apr. 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,24,25,26,27,28 3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21 7,8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 11-442 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. NOVEMBER 25, 1996 To amend the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974 to provide that the Mayor shall publish in the District of Columbia Register the proposed 1997 real property tax rates on the third Friday following the date the 1997 real property assessment roll is certified and to provide that the assessed value of all real property located in the District of Columbia for real property tax year 1998 shall be the assessed value for real property tax year 1997 and the valuation date for real property tax year 1998 real property assessments shall be January 1, 1997. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Moratorium on the 1997 Real Property Assessments for Real Property Tax Year 1998 Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. Title IV of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, approved September 3, 5974 (88 Stat. 1051; D.C. Code § 47-805 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 413 (D.C. Code § 47-815) is amended by adding a new subsection (a-3) to read as follows a-3) Notwithstanding the first sentence of subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall publish in the District of Columbia Register the proposed 1997 real property tax rates by the third Friday following the date the 1997 real property assessment roll is certified b) Section 421 (D.C. Code § 47-820) is amended by adding new subsections (a-l) and (a-2) to read as follows a-1) Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the real property tax year 1998 assessed value of all real property, subject to appeal pursuant to section 426a of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, effective March 17, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-241; D.C. Code § 47-825.1 shall be the real property tax year 1997 assessed value; provided, that for the purposes of appeal, the valuation date for real property tax year 1998 real property assessments shall be January 1, 1997. For purposes of determining the real property tax year Section 47-815 Section 47-820 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1998 assessment, the 1997 assessment with the latest date shall be the final 1997 assessment by the Mayor unless the assessment was otherwise revised by the Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals or the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. In the case of a revision, the 1997 assessment shall be the assessment as determined by the Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals or the Superior Court a-2) Subsection (a-l) of this section shall not affect the authority of the Mayor pursuant to section 5(b) of Title IX of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved May 16, 1938 (52 Stat. 373; D.C. Code § 47-829 to conduct a supplemental assessment of any property located in the District and shall not affect the right of a real property owner pursuant to ¯ section 5(c) of Title IX of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved May 16, 1938 (52 Star. 373; D.C. Code § 47-830 to appeal from the supplemental assessment to the Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall apply on the effective date of the District of Columbia Moratorium on the 1997 Real Property Assessments for Real Property Tax Year 1998 Amendment Act of 1996. Sec. 5. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- ENROLLED ORIGINAL Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: November 25, 1996 3 ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PKRIOD ELEVF~ REcoRDoFo~co~voTE BIIL847 Docket No. ADOPTED F.IRST READING, i0~1296 APPROVED ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result L!GHTFOOT Councilmember Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavoas Cropp Evans X In~licates Vote the Coun~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Aye Nay NT AB Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington Aye Nay NV AB AB Ab~t NV ¯ Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ADOPTED FINAL READING, 11=7’96 APPROVED ABSENT [ [ ROLL CALL VOTE- gesu|t Councilmember Chmn. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lighffoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X-indicateis no THOMAS Aye Nay AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB AB-Abs~t CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV-Pre~t not voting Date VOICES¢OTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALLVOTE- Result Councilmember Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB X- Indicates Vote Cotmdlmember Aye Nay NV AB Couneflm~nber Aye Nay NV AB Jarvb L~htfoot Mason Pa~erson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. WhiRington AB-Ah~nt net v~g CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Coundl</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
