<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-250">
  <num type="law">11-250</num>
  <heading type="short">BNA Washington, Inc., Real Property Tax Deferral Amendment Act of 1996</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-04-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-250.pdf">D.C. Law 11-250</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 1253</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0818">
      <narrative>Law 11-250, the “BNA Washington, Inc., Real Property Tax Deferral Amendment Act of 1996,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-818, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-514 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-250 became effective on April 9, 1997.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LMENT(S) 062 3~9 403kw~k’~g ® COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11-250 "BNA Washington, Inc Real Property Tax Deferral Amendment Act of 1996 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-818, on first and second readings, November 7, 1996 and December 3, 1996, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 24, 1996, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-514 and published in the March 7, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 1253) and transmitted to Congress on January 31, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-250, effective April 9, 1997. CHARLENE DREW JARVIS Chairman Pro Tempore of the Co i/1/ Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,24,25,26,27,28 3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21 Apr. 7,8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT ii-514 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 24, 1996 Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To amend the real property tax deferral procedure to provide for the deferral of real property taxes on certain real property. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "BNA Washington, Inc Real Property Tax Deferral Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, approved September 3, 1974 (88 Stat. 1051; D.C. Code § 47-801 passim is amended by adding a new section 435a to read as follows Sec. 435a a) Notwithstanding any other law or regulation, the Mayor may enter into an agreement with The Bureau of National Affairs, Inc BNA and BNA Washington, Inc BNAW to defer, up to 10 years, any real property tax liability on property located on Lot 109 and Lot 883 of Square 24, popularly known as 1227-1231 25th Street, N.W Washington, D.C or any property in the District of Columbia acquired for headquarters and principal operations as an addition to, or substitute for, the 25th Street address during the term of any deferral agreement b) The Mayor is authorized to enter into a written agreement Agreement with BNA and BNAW on such terms and conditions as the Mayor deems to be in the best interest of the District, the purpose of which is to provide BNA and BNAW with incentives to continue their current occupancy and usage of the real property specified in subsection (a) of this section, or any similar District property substituted therefor, for which real property tax relief is to be granted and in which BNA and BNAW maintain their headquarters and principal operations, including, but not limited to, production, editorial, home office sales, and home office operations, and to expand their business operation by committing to the lease or purchase of an additional 95,000 square feet of office space in the District of Columbia. New Section 47-845.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL c) The amount of real property tax owed during an approved deferment period shall not constitute delinquent taxes nor shall BNA and BNAW be assessed any interest or penalty for the deferment period. The deferral shall be prospective and shall apply only to the specified tax years d) Taxes, including penalty and interest thereon, deferred under this section shall constitute a preferential lien upon the real property which shall be payable immediately by the seller, transferor, or conveyor whenever the real property is sold, transferred, or conveyed in any manner, to an entity other than BNAW or a wholly-owned subsidiary of BNA or whenever additional co-owners (other than BNA or a wholly-owned subsidiary of BNA) are added to the real property e) In no event shall the deferral granted pursuant to this section be transferable f) As a condition to the grant of tax benefits under this section, BNA and BNAW shall submit to the Mayor by March 31st of each tax year an affidavit, signed under penalty of perjury. The affidavit shall contain the following averments or documentation of same establishing that after reasonable investigation, the undersigned have determined that BNA and BNAW 1) Have met and intend to continue to meet the requirements applicable to the receipt of the real property tax defela’al pursuant to the Agreement 2) Are in compliance with the terms of all public benefit agreements entered into with the District 3) Have recorded as an obligation all unpaid taxes on the subject property in their financial statements 4) Are not now receiving and do not now have pending any other application for forgiveness of the obligation to pay any taxes, or for the abatement of real property tax liability imposed by the District, except as provided in section 426a and subsection (i) of this section 5) Are not delinquent in the payment of taxes, assessments, fees, or other indebtedness to the District; and 6) Are not in violation of the laws and regulations of the District g) The Mayor shall make an annual determination of the compliance by BNA and BNAW with the requirements of this section and the Agreement under this section 1) If the Mayor determines that BNA and BNAW are in compliance, the Mayor shall issue to BNA and BNAW and to the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue Director a certificate of compliance 2) If the Mayor determines that BNA and BNAW are not in compliance, and after the Mayor gives to BNA and BNAW written notice and a reasonable time to cure the noncompliance or default and BNA and BNAW fail to cure the noncompliance or default, the Mayor shall issue to BNA and BNAW and to the Director a certificate of noncompliance and 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL shall direct that BNA and BNAW be billed for the assessment based on the accumulated tax liability as if the deferment had not been approved. The Mayor may waive, in whole or in part, interest and penalties, when, in his or her judgment, such waiver would be in the public interest h) Any assessment pursuant to a determination of noncompliance shall be due and payable by March 31st following the end of the tax year in which the certificate of noncompliance was issued i)(1) ff BNA and BNAW are aggrieved by any assessment of accumulated real property tax, penalty, and interest on real property owned by BNA or BNAW covered by the Agreement and this section, BNA and BNAW may appeal from the assessment in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in section 426a and in sections 3 and 4 of Title IX of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved May 16, 1938 (52 Stat. 371; D.C. Code §§ 47-3303 and 47-3304 provided, however, that the deferred real property taxes need not first be paid 2) At the termination of the 10-year deferral period, BNA and BNAW shall be responsible for the payment of the deferred real property tax notwithstanding the pendency of any administrative or judicial challenge to a real property tax levy or assessment j) The Mayor is authorized to develop the necessary forms and procedures, and to promulgate regulations, necessary to carry out the provisions of this section Sec. 3. Section 5 of Title IX of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved May 16, 1938 (52 Stat. 372; D.C. Code § 47-3305 is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) ff BNA and BNAW are aggrieved by any assessment of real property tax, penalty, and interest on the subject real property made in pursuance of section 435a(h) of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974 (as added by Bill 11-818 BNA and BNAW may within 6 months after notice of said assessment, appeal from the assessment in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in sections 3 and 4 of title IX of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved May 16, 1938 (52 Stat. 371; D.C. Code §§ 47-3303 and 47-3304 Sec. 4 a) The Mayor shall submit to the Council, not later than March 25, 1997, proposed legislation to establish comprehensive standards for the provision of incentives by the District government to maintain existing employers in the District and to attract new employers to the District b) The proposed economic development incentives legislation shall be structured to meet the following goals 1) Provide substantial employment and training opportunities for District residents; Section 47-3305 Note, Section 47-845.1 3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL decisions; and (2) Allow the District to be competitive with other jurisdictions in the region 3) Be attractive enough to employers to affect their retention or relocation (4) Operate in a manner that is as revenue-neutral or revenue-positive as is feasible c) The proposed legislation may include, but not be limited to, the following components 1) Tax credits for new hires of a specified minimum number of District residents, within a certain time period, which could be applied against the employer’s franchise tax; provided, the tax credits should be allowed in all areas of the District, but the amount of the tax credit should be greater in targeted, economically depressed areas 2) Customized free industrial work force training of District residents 3) A restructured and expanded state enterprise zone program 4) Special incentives for employers that establish or operate a foreign trade zone and hire District residents; and 5) A mechanism within the office of the Assistant City Administrator for Economic Development mandated to A) Compile and maintain a list, and usage-related data base, of all public and private incentives available in the District B) Publicize and market the incentives available to employers C) Design a cost-benefit analysis model for assessing incentive proposals; and (D) File an annual report to the Mayor and Council on economic development incentives in the District and legislative recommendations for improvements in this area. Sec. 5 a) Notwithstanding any other law, if the Mayor does not submit the proposed legislation outlined in section 4 on or before March 25, 1997, the Mayor, until the proposed legislation is submitted by the Mayor and received in the Office of the Secretary to the Council, shall not reduce or defer the tax liability, including interest and penalties, or negotiate, or enter into, an agreement for the reduction or deferment of any tax liability, including interest and penalties, of any taxpayer liable to the District for the payment of any tax, including interest and penalties b) Notwithstanding any other law, if the Mayor does not submit the proposed legislation outlined in section 4 on or before March 25, 1997, one position in the Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Economic Development shall be abolished by May 26, 1997, and the savings from the abolishment shall be allocated to the District’s accumulated budget deficit. Note, Section 47-845.1 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (c) Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to the tax deferment provided by section 435a of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974 (as added by Bill 11- 818 Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by § 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1- 233(c)(3 Sec. 7. The provisions of this act shall apply to the tax year beginning October 1, 1996, and ending September 30, 1997, and for each tax year thereafter through September 30, 2007. Sec. 8. The BNA Washington, Inc Real Property Tax Deferral Temporary Amendment Act of 1996, approved October 18, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-433; 43 DCR 6176) is repealed. Sec. 9. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental R~r~,anization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 an~t l~blication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman~ Council of the District of Columbia Note, Sections 47-845.1, 47-3305 DMi~fi:i ;i Columbia APPROVED: December 24, 1996 5 IN ITEM ON CONSENT CALF~NDAR [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE {~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL,’MBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE N~ BII-818 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-7-96 APPROVFD THOMAS ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Aye Nay N~ AB Councfimember Aye Nay AB Councilmemb~r Jarvis Smith, Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, St. Mason Whittington Cmm¢~m~mb~r Chmn. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Patterson Evans ] R,ay x Indicates Vote to the Council | ] |TEM ON CONSF~NT CALENDAR CERTIFICATION RECORD ACTION &amp;amp; DATE ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-3-96 Aye Nay N3,’ AB NV. Pt~s~t net Voting [~ VOICE VOTERECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ 1 ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lighffoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson ¯ Evans Ray X.indicates no AB-Abscnt I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR APPRDVFD LIGHTFOOT SON AND THOMAS Aye Nay NT AB Counctlmm~r Aye Nay AB Co~cilm~mber Aye Nty AB I Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE- R~sult Cmmcilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavons Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB JarvisC°Uncilmember Aye Nay Light foot Mason Patterson Ray x o Indicates Vote AB Absent NV AB Couneiimember Smith, Jr. Thomas. Sr. Whittington Aye Nay AB N’v Pr~*nt lint Votiag CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL A_N ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DIST~CT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To amend the real property tax deferral procedure to provide for the deferral of real property taxes on certain real property. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "BNA Washington, Inc Real Property Tax Deferral Amendment Act of 1996 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, approved September 3, 1974 (88 Stat. 1051; D.C. Code § 47-801 passim is amended by adding a new section 435a to read as follows Sec. 435a a) Notwithstanding any other law or regulation, the Mayor may enter into an agreement with The Bureau of National Affairs, Inc. CBNA and BNA Washington, Inc. CBNAW to deter, up to 10 years, any real property tax liability on property located on Lot 109 and Lot 883 of Square 24, popularly known as 1227-1231 25th Street, N.W Washington, D.C or any property in the District of Columbia acquired for headquarters and principal operations as an addition to, or substitute for, the 25th Street address during the term of any deferral agreement b) The Mayor is authorized to enter into a written agreement Agreement with BNA and BNAW on such terms and conditions as the Mayor deems to be in the best interest of the District, the purpose of which is to provide BNA and BNAW with incentives to continue their current occupancy and usage of the real property specified in subsection (a) of this section, or any similar District property substituted therefor, for which real property tax relief is to be granted and in which BNA and BNAW maintain their headquarters and principal operations, including, but not limited to, production, editorial, home office sales, and home office operations, and to expand their business operation by committing to the lease or purchase of an additional 95,000 square feet of office space in the District of Columbia. New Section 47-845.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL c) The amount of real property tax owed during an approved deferment period shall not constitute delinquent taxes nor shall BNA and BNAW be assessed any interest or penalty for the deferment period. The deferral shall be prospective and shall apply only to the specified tax years d) Taxes, including penalty and interest thereon, deferred under this section shall constitute a preferential lien upon the real property which shall be payable immediately by the seller, transferor, or conveyor whenever the real property is sold, transferred, or conveyed in any manner, to an entity other than BNAW or a wholly-owned subsidiary of BNA or whenever additional co-owners (other than BNA or a wholly-owned subsidiary of BNA) are added to the real property e) In no event shall the deferral granted pursuant to this section be transferable f) As a condition to the grant of tax benefits under this section, BNA and BNAW shall submit to the Mayor by March 31st of each tax year an affidavit, signed under penalty of perjury. The affidavit shall contain the following averments or documentation of same establishing that after reasonable investigation, the undersigned have determined that BNA and BNAW 1) Have met and intend to continue to meet the requirements applicable to the receipt of the real property tax deferral pursuant to the Agreement 2) Are in compliance with the terms of all public benefit agreements entered into with the District 3) Have recorded as an obligation all unpaid taxes on the subject property in their financial statements 4) Are not now receiving and do not now have pending any other application for forgiveness of the obligation to pay any taxes, or for the abatement of real property tax liability imposed by the District, except as provided in section 426a and subsection (i) of this section 5) Are not delinquent in the payment of taxes, assessments, fees, or other indebtedness to the District; and 6) Are not in violation of the laws and regulations of the District g) The Mayor shall make an annual determination of the compliance by BNA and BNAW with the requirements of this section and the Agreement under this section 1) If the Mayor determines that BNA and BNAW are in compliance, the Mayor shall issue to BNA and BNAW and to the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue Director a certificate of compliance. ¯ 2) If the Mayor determines that BNA and BNAW are not in compliance, and after the Mayor gives to BNA and BNAW written notice and a reasonable time to cure the noncompliance or default and BNA and BNAW fail to cure the noncompliance or default, the Mayor shall issue to BNA and BNAW and to the Director a certificate of noncompliance and 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL shall direct that BNA and BNAW be billed for the assessment based on the accumulated tax liability as if the deferment had not been approved. The Mayor may waive, in whole or in part, interest and penalties, when, in his or her judgment, such waiver would be in the public interest h) Any assessment pursuant to a determination of noncompliance shall be due and payable by March 31 st following the end of the tax year in which the certificate of noncompliance was issued i)(1) If BNA and BNAW are aggrieved by any assessment of accumulated real property tax, penalty, and interest on real property owned by BNA or BNAW covered by the Agreement and this section, BNA and BNAW may appeal from the assessment in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in section 426a and in sections 3 and 4 of Title IX of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved May 16, 1938 (52 Stat. 371; D.C. Code §§ 47-3303 and 47-3304 provided, however, that the deferred real property taxes need not first be paid 2) At the termination of the 10-year deferral period, BNA and BNAW shall be responsible for the payment of the deferred real property tax notwithstanding the pendency of any administrative or judicial challenge to a real property tax levy or assessment j) The Mayor is authorized to develop the necessary forms and procedures, and to promulgate regulations, necessary to carry out the provisions of this section Sec. 3. Section 5 of Title IX of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved May 16, 1938 (52 Stat. 372; D.C. Code § 47-3305 is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) If BNA and BNAW are aggrieved by any assessment of real property tax, penalty, and interest on the subject real property made in pursuance of section 435a(h) of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974 (as added by Bill 11-818 BNA and BNAW may within 6 months after notice of said assessment, appeal from the assessment in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in sections 3 and 4 of title IX of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved May 16, 1938 (52 Stat. 371; D.C. Code §§ 47-3303 and 47-3304 Sec. 4 a) The Mayor shall submit to the Council, not later than March 25, 1997, proposed legislation to establish comprehensive standards for the provision of incentives by the District government to maintain existing employers in the District and to attract new employers to the District b) The proposed economic development incentives legislation shall be structured to meet the following goals 1) Provide substantial employment and training opportunities for District residents; Section 47-3305 Note, Section 47-845.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL decisions; and (2) Allow the District to be competitive with other jurisdictions in the region 3) Be attractive enough to employers to affect their retention or relocation (4) Operate in a manner that is as revenue-neutral or revenue-positive as is feasible c) The proposed legislation may include, but not be limited to, the following components 1) Tax credits for new hires of a specified minimum number of District residents, within a certain time period, which could be applied against the employer’s franchise tax; provided, the tax credits should be allowed in all areas of the District, but the amount of the tax credit should be greater in targeted, economically depressed areas 2) Customized free industrial work force training of District residents 3) A restructured and expanded state enterprise zone program 4) Special incentives for employers that establish or operate a foreign trade zone and hire District residents; and 5) A mechanism within the office of the Assistant City Administrator for Economic Development mandated to A) Compile and maintain a list, and usage-related data base, of all public and private incentives available in the District B) Publicize and market the incentives available to employers C) Design a cost-benefit analysis model for assessing incentive proposals; and (D) File an annual report to the Mayor and Council on economic development incentives in the District and legislative recommendations for improvements in this area. Sec. 5 a) Notwithstanding any other law, if the Mayor does not submit the proposed legislation outlined in section 4 on or before March 25, 1997, the Mayor, until the proposed legislation is submitted by the Mayor and received in the Office of the Secretary to the Council, shall not reduce or defer the tax liability, including interest and penalties, or negotiate, or enter into, an agreement for the reduction or deferment of any tax liability, including interest and penalties, of any taxpayer liable to the District for the payment of any tax, including interest and penalties b) Notwithstanding any other law, if the Mayor does not submit the proposed legislation outlined in section 4 on or before March 25, 1997, one position in the Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Economic Development shall be abolished by May 26, 1997, and the savings from the abolishment shall be allocated to the District’s accumulated budget deficit. Note, Sectimt 47-845.1 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (c) Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to the tax deferment provided by section 435a of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974 (as added by Bill 11- 818 Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by § 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1- 233(c)(3 Sec. 7. The provisions of this act shall apply to the tax year beginning October 1, 1996, and ending September 30, 1997, and for each tax year thereafter through September 30, 2007. Sec. 8. The BNA Washington, Inc Real Property Tax Deferral Temporary Amendment Act of 1996, approved October 18, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-433; 43 DCR 6176) is repealed. Sec. 9. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reprj(anization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 7an~ I~blication in the District of ColumbiaRegister. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Note, Sect|oils 47-845.1, 47-3305 Mayor District of Columbia ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE P~CORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF DISTRICT OF COLL,’M~IA cOUNCI~ PER/OD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE N~ BII-818 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-7-96 APPROVFD THOMAS [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Counr.flmember Chnm. Clarke Brazil Cbavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NW AB X Indicates Vote ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NT AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. AB Absi~t CERTIFICATION RECORD Light foot Mason Patterson Ray Whittington NV. Preseat aet Votiag¯ ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-3-96 {~ VOICE VOTERECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result APPROVFD LIGHTFOOT, MASON AND THOMAS Coundlmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Aye Nay NT AB Councflmember Aye Nay NV AB Ceaadhaembcr Aye Nay N’V AB Evans ] ITEM ON CONSF_NT CALENDAR ] ACTION &amp;amp;DATE X-indicates no Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray AB-Abs~t CERTIFICATION RECORD the Council Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV.Pt~seat not vettng { I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT { ] ROLL CALl, VOTE- Result Cmmalmember Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Nay NV AB Cotmcflmember Aye Nay AB CmmdlmemberAye Nay AB X Indicates Vote Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas. Sr. Whittington AB Absent N’V Pr~n am Ymmg CERTIFICATION REcoRD Secretary. to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
