<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-3">
  <num type="law">11-3</num>
  <heading type="short">Prevention of the Spread of the Human Immunodeficiency Virus and Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-04-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-3.pdf">D.C. Law 11-3</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 1070</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0038">
      <narrative>Law 11-3, the “Prevention of the Spread of the Human Immunodeficiency Virus and Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-38, which was retained by council. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on January 17, 1995, and February 7, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 17, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-10 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-3 became effective on April 7, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENRO MENT(S) kwiktag 062 319 557 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT ACT 11 0 Codification District of Columbia Code 1996 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA FEBRUARY 1995 To amend the Drug Paraphernalia Act of 1982 to ensure that the needle exchange program in the District of Columbia is accessible to injecting drug users in the District of Columbia to help prevent the spread of the Human Immunodeficiency Virus and Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Prevention of the Spread of the Human Immunodeficiency Vires and Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. Section 4a of the Drug Paraphernalia Act of 1982, effective March 25, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-252; D.C. Code § 33-603.1 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows a) The Mayor is authorized to establish within the Department of Human Services a Needle Exchange Program Program which may provide clean hypodermic needles and syringes to injecting drug users. Counseling on substance abuse addiction and information on appropriate referrals to drug treatment programs shall be made available to each person to whom a hypodermic needle and syringe is provided. Counseling and information on the Human Immunodeficiency Vires HIV and appropriate referrals for HIV testing and services shall be made available to each person to whom a hypodermic needle and syringe is provided b) Subsection (g)(5)(A) through (D) is amended to read as follows A) Annual HIV infection rates among injecting drug users entering drug. treatment programs in the District B) Estimates of the HIV infection rate among injecting drug users in the District at the start of the Program year as compared to the rate at the end of the third Program year C) The annual number of HIV-positive mothers giving birth in the District D) Annual estimates of the HIV infection rate among newborns; and c) Subsection (h) is amended by striking the phrase "pre-or post-admittance Section 33-603.1 See. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia MunicipalRegulations Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: February 17, 1995 2 ITgM ON CONSgNT CALgNDAR ACTION ¯ DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCI~ PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCI~ VOTE D,~m N~ BI 1-38 Adopted First Reading, 1-17-95 vmc~ vors ¯ ffrove KCOKD~D VOl11 ON ~J~U~ Jarv|s and Lightfoot I I ROL~ CALL VOTg C.~mmctlmmml~w Aye Nsy CIIAVOUS ~VANS I~0 ITgM ON CONSglCT CALKNDAil I~X) VOIC~ VOT~ Adopted Fi nal Readi ncl. 2"7-95 Approved al I present I I ROLL CALL VOTE RIIdt Ce~mmlM~r A~ Ney NV A~ CHMN. CLAR.K~ JARV~ B G~ C~V~S M~ I I PA~i ~ANS ~Y I I AC~ION&amp;amp;DATK I l VOIC~ VOTg I l ilOLLCALJ.VOTE.RIIMI ~IIMN JARVlS B~.I~ LIGRT~OOT CKAVOUS MASON C~OI~ PA~T~P~ON ~VAN$ PAY X la~lkat~ V~~ CERTIFICATION i~.CO~D</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
