<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-42">
  <num type="law">11-42</num>
  <heading type="short">Nonprofit Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-09-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-42.pdf">D.C. Law 11-42</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 3285</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0052">
      <narrative>Law 11-42, the “Nonprofit Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-52, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 2, 1995, and June 6, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 19, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-77 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-42 became effective on September 8, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENRO MEN (S kwiktag ® 062 319 603 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 11- 42 Nonprofit Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-52 on first and second readings, May 2, 1995 and June 6, 1995, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 19, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-77 and published in the June 30, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 3285) and transmitted to Congress on June 22, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-42, effective September 8, 1995. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: June July Aug. 22,23,26,27,28,29,30 10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28,31 1,2,3,4 Sept. 5,6,7 AN ACT D.C. ACT 11-77 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Code i 99 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 19, 1995 To amend the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act to provide for the filing of a 5-year report instead of an annual report, and to increase the fees associated with filings by nonprofit corporations. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Nonprofit Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act, approved August 6, 1962 (76 Stat. 265; D.C. Code § 29-501 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 83 (D.C. Code § 29-584) is amended as follows: section 29-584 (1) By striking the word "Annual" as it appears in the title to the section and inserting the phrase "Five-year" in its place 2) By striking in subsection (a) the phrase "prepare an annual report" and inserting the phrase "prepare and submit every 5 years, if there has been no change in material facts, a report" in its place; and (3) By striking in subsection (b) the phrase "Such annual report" and inserting the phrase "The 5-year report"in its place b) Section 84 (D.C. Code § 29-585) is amended by amending the first sentence to readSection 29-585 as follows The report of a domestic or foreign corporation shall be delivered to the Mayor on or before the 15th day of April in the 5th year in which its certificate of incorporation or certificate of authority, as the case may be, was issued by the Mayor c) Section 85 (D.C. Code § 29-586) is amended to read as follows: Section "If any corporation incorporated under this act, or any corporation which has elected to 29-5s6 accept this act, or any foreign corporation having a certificate of authority issued under this act, shall fail or refuse to pay any report fee or fees payable under this act, or fail to file an report as required by this act, then, in the case of a domestic corporation, the articles of incorporation shall be void and all powers conferred upon the corporation shall be inoperative, and in the case of a foreign corporation, the certificate of authority shall be revoked and all ENROLLEO ORIGINAL powers conferred pursuant to it shall be inoperative d) Section 86(a D.C. Code § 29-587(a is amended by striking the phrase "any annual section report" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "the 5-year report" in its place 29-587 (e) Section 88 (D.C. Code § 29-589) is amended to read as follows: Section "Whenever it is established to the satisfaction of the Mayor that any corporation named29-589 in the proclamation issued in accordance with section 86 has not failed or refused to pay the 5-year report fee or any report filing fees, or has been inadvertently included in the list of corporations as failing or refusing to pay the 5-year report fee or any report filing fees, the Mayor is authorized to correct the mistake by issuing a proclamation to that effect and restoring the articles of incorporation or certificate of authority, as the case may be, to good standing with like effect as if the proclamation or revocation, as to the corporation, was not issued f) Section 90(a D.C. Code § 29-591(a is amended in the first sentence by striking the section word "annual" wherever it appears. 29-591 (g) Section 91 (D.C. Code § 29-592) is amended to read as follows: Section "Sec. 91. Penalties for failure to file 5-year report. 29-592 "Each corporation, domestic or foreign, that fails or refuses to file its 5-year report within the time prescribed by this act shall be subject to a penalty of $75 to be assessed by the Mayor h) Section 92 (D.C. Code § 29-593) is amended as follows: sectio 1) By striking the word "annual" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase29-593 "5-year" in its place 2) By in its place 3) By in its place; in its place 4) By (5) By 30" in its place; and (6) By 100" in its place i) Nothing in this act shall be construed or interpreted as repealing or affecting any requirement of a domestic or foreign corporation to prepare and submit annual tax forms, or to pay any appropriate District or federal tax, as provided in accordance with the laws of the District of Columbia or the United States. striking the figure 1" wherever its appears and inserting the figure 20" striking the figure 2" wherever its appears and inserting the figure 20" striking the figure 5" wherever its appears and inserting the figure 25" striking the figure 10" wherever its appears and inserting the figure striking the figure 25" wherever its appears and inserting the figure Note. Section 29-584 Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602 (c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 2 ENROLLED 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-2~3(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbi~Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia MunicipalRegulations Chairman Council of the District of Columbia oN ¢ONSK’~ CAL&amp;amp;~AIt ACTION &amp;amp; D&amp;amp;TE CO~CIL OF TI~ DI ’~ICT Oil’ COLLM:BIA CO¢~CIL P~JOD O~D O Oi~IClAL C~,’NCIL VO~ B11-52 Adopted First Reading, 05-02-95 I~ vo~g VOT J?,CO~gD voTg ON ~U~Q[~’T A~SENT Approved al i present ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Cotmc’.dm~ber Aye Nay NV AB Chnm. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Cotmcilmemb~r Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray Nay N~V AB Cotmoimember Aye Nay N B Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. X ¯ Indl~ptes Vote AB b~nt ~CERTIFICATIONRECORD | ITEM ON CONSENT CALEndAR ~CTION &amp;amp; DATE N ¯ Pr~nt not Voting y Date Adopted Final Reading, 06-06-95 votc~ VOTE ’Approved RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ,t~sE~ Brazi I and Thomas ROI L CALL VOTE. Result Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous ’ropp Evans X-tndtc~ no a NV ~B Cotmalmember Aye Nay N%’ AB Couacflmeml~r Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB-Ab~t NV-Presem not voting { ITF2,I ON CONSF~’~’r CALENDAR [ I AC£1ON &amp;amp; DATE CERTIFICATION RECORD { I ~VO~O ’~ST ROIA, CALL VOTg. Real* L Aye Nay NV AB Colmilme~m. Aye Nay N’V AB I Aye Nay NV AB Clmm. Clarke Jarvi~ Brszil Lighffeot Chavou~ Mason Cropp P~tterso~ Evans Ray Smith, Jr. Tbonm, St. CF.~TIFICATION KECOI~D COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 JUN 2 2 1995 The Honorable Albert Gore, Jr. President of the Senate United States Senate Room S-212 United States Capitol Washington, D. C. 20510 Re: Transmittal of D.C. ACT 11-77 Nonprofit Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995 Date of Council Action: 06-06-95 Dear Mr. President: The above named act is hereby transmitted in Accordance with section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to this act, for your information, is the report of the Council’s standing committee with jurisdiction over this matter. To begin the count of the 30-day review by Congress, please acknowledge receipt of this document on the copy attached S~incer~ely ] David Clarke Chairman of the Council Enclosure Receipt Acknowledged: Name PLEASE PlaINT Signatuee Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 The Honorable Newt Gingrich Speaker of the House U. S. House of Representatives Room H-209 United States Capitol Washington, D. C. 20515 JUN ,2 2 1995 Re: Transmittal of D.C. ACT 11-77 Nonprofit .Corporation Five-year Report Amendment Act of 1995 Date of Council Action: 06-06-95 Dear Mr. Speaker: The above named act is hereby transmitted in Accordance with section 602(c)(1) the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to this act, for your information, is the report of the Council’s standing committee with jurisdiction over this matter. To begin the count of the 30-day review by Congress, please acknowledge receipt of this document on the copy attached. Sincerel Chairman of the Council Enclosure Receipt Acknowledged: Name PLEASE PRINT Signa~[’~e Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 The Honorable Newt Gingrich Speaker of the House U. S. House of Representatives Room H-209 United States Capitol Washington, D. C. 20515 JUN ;Z 1995 Re Transmittal of D.C. ACT 11-77 Nonprofit Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995 Date of Council Action: 06-06-95 Dear Mr. Speaker: The above named act is hereby transmitted in Accordance with section 602(c)(1) the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to this act, for your information, is the report of the Council’s standing committee with jurisdiction over this matter. To begin the count of the 30-day review by Congress, please acknowledge receipt of this document on the copy attached. Enclosure Receipt Acknowledged: Name PLEASE PRINT Sincerel O~i~ ATClarke Chairman of the Council Signature Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 JUN 22 !995 The Honorable Thomas M. Davis Chairman, Subcommittee on the District of Columbia United States House of Representatives B349A Rayburn House Office Building Washington, D. C. 20515 Re Transmittal of D,C. ACT 11-77 Nonprofit Corporation Five-Year Report Amendment Act of 1995 Date of Council Action: 06-06-95 Dear Mr. Chairman: The above named act is hereby transmitted for your information. A copy of the enclosed act has been transmitted to the Speaker of the House ncer Chairman of the Council Enclosure</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
