<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-44">
  <num type="law">11-44</num>
  <heading type="short">Prevention of Transmission of the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Temporary Amendment Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-44.pdf">D.C. Law 11-44</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 11-44, the “Prevention of Transmission of the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Temporary Amendment Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-311. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 6, 1995, and June 20, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 28, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-82 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-44 became effective on September 16, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN kwikta 062 317 37~ L N (S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA D.C. LAW 11- 44 "Prevention of Transmission of the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-311 on first and second readings, June 6, 1995 and June 20, 1995, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 28, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-82 and published in the July 7, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 3456) and transmitted to Congress on June 30, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-44, effective September 16, 1995. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: June July Aug. 30 10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28,31 1,2,3,4 Sept. 5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Code 1,9~,6 Supplement} IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 28, 1995 To amend, on a temporary basis, the Drug Paraphemalia Act of 1982 to allow qualified community based organizations or other qualified individuals specifically designated by the Commissioner of Public Health, to operate the Needle Exchange Program in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Prevention of Transmission of the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 Sec. 2. Section 4a of the Drug Paraphemalia Act of 1982, effective March 25, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-252; D.C. Code § 33-603.1 is amended as follows a) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows b) The Program authorized by subsection (a) of this section shall be administered by the Commission of Public Health in the Department of Human Services. Only qualified medical officers, registered nurses, counselors, community based organizations, or other qualified individuals specifically designated by the Commissioner of Public Health shall be authorized to exchange hypodermic needles and syringes under the provisions of subsections (c) through (i) of this section b) Subsection (e) is amended to read as follows e) The District of Columbia, its officers, or employees shall not be liable for any injury or damage resulting from use of, or contact with, any needle exchanged as part of the Program authorized by subsection (a) of this section c) A new subsection (e-l) is added to read as follows e-1) A community based organization or other qualified individual designated by the Commissioner on Public Health under subsection (b) of this section shall not be liable for any injury or damage resulting from the Use of, or contact with, any needle exchanged as part of the Note, Section 33-603.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Program authorized by subsection (a) of this section, unless such injury or damage is a direct result of the gross negligence or intentional misconduct of such community based organization or other qualified individual Sec. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect or upon the effective date of the Prevention of Transmission of the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Amendment Act of 1995, whichever occurs first Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: June 28, 1995 | ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE [~ VOICE VOTERECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL Ol~ THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD 01~ OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE BII-311 ADOPTED FIRST READING; 06-06=95 APPROVED BRAZIl EVANS, LIGHTFOOT AND RAY ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Counciimember Aye Nay AB Jarvis Smith, Jr. Light foot Mason Patterson Thomas, Sr. Whittington Evans Ray X Indicates ~Vote [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE [~ VOICE VOTERECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST AB Absent NV Pteseat not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ~{ ’~ }Date A~ FINAL READING~ 06-20-q5 APPROVED ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X-hadicat~ no ~e Council ] [TEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ALL PRE£ENT Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay N3r AB Cotmcflmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington AB.Abs~mt CERTIFICATION RECORD NV-Present not voting Date [ ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE [ ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ] ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result. Councilmcmber Aye Nay NV AB Councflmember Chmn. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray I X Indicates Vote Aye Nay NV AB Councihnember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB Absent NV Present not Vo~ng CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
