<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-73" flag="true">
  <num type="law">11-73</num>
  <heading type="short">Commercial Piracy Protection and Deceptive Labeling Amendment Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-10-31</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-73.pdf">D.C. Law 11-73</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 3277</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0125">
      <narrative>Law 11-73, the “Commercial Piracy Protection and Deceptive Labeling Amendment Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-125, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 2, 1995, and June 6, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 19, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-74 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-73 became effective on October 31, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) AN ACT D,C, ACT ii- 74 [NROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Code I 996 ’-’ SupPfement~ IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 19, 1995 To amend the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982 to clarify that the provisions are not intended to preempt federal copyright law, to require that sound recordings and audiovisual works contain the true name and address of the manufacturer, and to prohibit the unauthorized operation of a recording device in a movie theater. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Commercial Piracy Protection and Deceptive Labeling Amendment Act of 1995 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code § 22-3801 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 114 (D.C. Code § 22-3814) is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) This section does not apply to any sound recording initially fixed on or after February 15, 1972 b) Two new sections, 114a and 114b, are added to read as follows Sec. 114a. Deceptive labeling a) For the purposes of this section, the term 1 Audiovisual works" means material objects upon which are fixed a series of related images which are intrinsically intended to be shown by the use of machines or devices such as projectors, viewers, or electronic equipment, now known or later developed, together with accompanying sounds, if any, regardless of the nature of the material objects, such as films or tapes, in which the works are embodied 2 Manufacturer" means the person who authorizes or causes the copying, fixation, or transfer of sounds or images to sound recordings or audiovisual works subject to this section 3 Sound recordings" means material objects in which sounds, other than those accompanying a motion picture or other audiovisual work, are fixed by any method now known or later developed, and from which the sounds can be perceived, reproduced, or otherwise communicated, either directly or with the aid of a machine or device b) A person commits the offense of deceptive labeling if, for commercial advantage or private financial gain, that person knowingly advertises, offers for sale, resale, or rental, or sells, Section 22-3814 New Section 22-3814.1 [NROLLED ORIGINAL resells, rents, distributes, or transports, or possesses for such purposes, a sound recording or audiovisual work, the label, cover, or jacket of which does not clearly and conspicuously disclose the true name and address of the manufacturer thereof c) Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit 1) Any broadcaster who, in connection with, or as part of, a radio or television broadcast transmission, or for the purposes of archival preservation, transfers any sounds or images recorded on a sound recording or audiovisual work; or 2) Any person who, in his own home, for his own personal use, and without deriving any commercial advantage or private financial gain, transfers any sounds or images recorded on a sound recording or audiovisual work d)(1) Any person convicted of deceptive labeling involving less than 1,000 sound recordings or less than 100 audiovisual works during any 180-day period shall be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both 2) Any person convicted of deceptive labeling involving 1,000 or more sound recordings or 100 or more audiovisual works during a 180-day period shall be fined not more than $50,000 or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both e) Upon conviction under this section, the court shall, in addition to the penalties provided by this section, order the forfeiture and destruction or other disposition of all sound recordings, audiovisual works, and equipment used, or attempted to be used, in violation of this section Sec. 114b. Unlawful operation of a recording device in a motion picture theater a) For the purposes of this section, the term 1 Motion picture theater" means a theater or other auditorium in which a motion picture is exhibited 2 Recording device" means a photographic or video camera, audio or video recorder, or any other device not existing, or later developed, which may be used for recording sounds or images b) A person commits the offense of unlawfully operating a recording device in a motion picture theater if, without authority or permission from the owner of a motion picture theater, or his or her agent, that person operates a recording device within the premises of a motion picture theater c) Any person convicted of unlawfully operating a recording device in a motion picture theater shall be fined not more than $300 or imprisoned for not more than 90 days, or both d) A theater owner, or an employee or agent of a theater owner, who detains or causes the arrest of a person in, or immediately adjacent to, a motion picture theater shall not be held liable for detention, false imprisonment, malicious prosecution, defamation, or false arrest in any proceeding arising out of such detention or arrest, if 1) The person detaining or causing the arrest had, at the time thereof, probable cause to believe that the person detained or arrested had committed, or attempted to commit, in that person’s presence, an offense described in this section 2) The manner of the detention or arrest was reasonable 3) Law enforcement authorities were notified within a reasonable time; and New Section 22-3814.2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4) The person detained or arrested was released within a reasonable time of the detention or arrest, or was surrendered to law enforcement authorities within a reasonable time Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 60-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-2/33(c)(2 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of~olnmbia,~Itatutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Chairman Council of the District of Columbia APPR0V[D: dune 19, 1995 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNC[L OF DESTRICT OF COLL~BL~ COUNCIL PERIOD ELEV KN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COL~CIL VO’I~ Docket N o. Adopted Fi rst Reading, BI1-125 05-02-95 Ann [~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQCEST BSENT Cha vo 1 ROLLCALL OTE- R~ult Cocci/member ye Na~ NV ~B Coun~Jmember Aye Chmn. Clarke t Jar~’~ Brazil Li~htfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray Absent CERTIFICATION RECOIl) ITEM tin CONSENT CALENDAR XCTION &amp;amp; D VOICE V(}TE Adopted Final ApproVed AB Ctmncilmember Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Aye Nay NV AB NV Present not Voting :Readinq, 06-06-95 RECORDED trrE x REQUE.VF ,BSE,T Brazil and Thomas [ R()LI. C’~LL OTE Result Chron. Clarke Brazil Ch~tvous Cropp Evans Ray X.indieatea no f ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Jar~is Light foot Mason Patterson NV AB Comwalmember Smith, Jr. Thomas. Whittington AB-Absent Nay NV AB NV-Present not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Date t ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE R~ult [ Cot~cilme~ber Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evaas IAye Nay K In~ti~ate~ Vote NV AB Coundlmember Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Aye Nay NV AB .L C olin cilmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington Preumt not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to tl~ Coundl Dam AN ACT £NROLff.D ORIGINAL Codlficatlon District of Columbia Code L ~996 SupPlement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982 to clarify that the provisions are not intended to preempt federal copyright law, to require that sound recordings and audiovisual works contain the true name and address of the manufacturer, and to prohibit the unauthorized operation of a recording device in a movie theater. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Commercial Piracy Protection and Deceptive Labeling Amendment Act of 1995 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code § 22-380l et seq is amended as follows a) Section 114 (D.C. Code § 22-3814) is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) This section does not apply to any sound recording initially fixed on or after February 15, 1972 b) Two new sections, 114a and 114b, are added to read as follows Sec. 114a. Deceptive labeling a) For the purposes of this section, the term 1 Audiovisual works" means material objects upon which are fixed a series of related images which are intrinsically intended to be shown by the use of machines or devices such as projectors, viewers, or electronic equipment, now known or later developed, together with accompanying sounds, if any, regardless of the nature of the material objects, such as films or tapes, in which the works are embodied 2 Manufacturer" means the person who authorizes or causes the copying, fixation, or transfer of sounds or images to sound recordings or audiovisual works subject to this section 3 Sound recordings" means material objects in which sounds, other than those accompanying a motion picture or other audiovisual work, are fixed by any method now known or later developed, and from which the sounds can be perceived, reproduced, or otherwise communicated, either directly or with the aid of a machine or device b) A person commits the offense of deceptive labeling if, for commercial advantage or private financial gain, that person knowingly advertises, offers for sale, resale, or rental, or sells, Section 22-3814 New Section 22-3814.1 resells, rents, distributes, or transports, or possesses for such purposes, a sound recording or audiovisual work, the label, cover, or jacket of which does not clearly and conspicuously disclose the true name and address of the manufacturer thereof c) Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit 1) Any broadcaster who, in connection with, or as part of, a radio or television broadcast transmission, or for the purposes of archival preservation, transfers any sounds or images recorded on a sound recording or audiovisual work; or 2) Any person who, in his own home, for his own personal use, and without deriving any commercial advantage or private financial gain, transfers any sounds or images recorded on a sound recording or audiovisual work d)(1) Any person convicted of deceptive labeling involving less than 1,000 sound recordings or less than 100 audiovisual works during any 180-day period shall be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both 2) Any person convicted of deceptive labeling involving 1,000 or more sound recordings or 100 or more audiovisual works during a 180-day period shall be fined not more than $50,000 or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both e) Upon conviction under this section, the court shall, in addition to the penalties provided by this section, order the forfeiture and destruction or other disposition of all sound recordings, audiovisual works, ’and equipment used, or attempted to be used, in violation of this section Sec. 114b. Unlawful operation of a recording device in a motion picture theater a) For the purposes of this section, the term 1 Motion picture theater" means a theater or other auditorium in which a motion picture is exhibited 2 Recording device" means a photographic or video camera, audio or video recorder, or any other device not existing, or later developed, which may be used for recording sounds or images b) A person commits the offense of unlawfully operating a recording device in a motion picture theater if without authority or permission from the owner of a motion picture theater, or his or her agent, that person operates a recording device within the premises of a motion picture theater c) Any person convicted of unlawfully operating a recording device in a motion picture theater shall be fined not more than $300 or imprisoned for not more than 90 days, or both d) A theater owner, or an employee or agent of a theater owner, who detains or causes the arrest of a person in, or immediately adjacent to, a motion picture theater shall not be held liable for detention, false imprisonment, malicious prosecution, defamation, or false arrest in any proceeding arising out of such detention or arrest, if 1) The person detaining or causing the arrest had, at the time thereof, probable cause to believe that the person detained or arrested had committed, or attempted to commit, in that person’s presence, an offense described in this section 2) The manner of the detention or arrest was reasonable 3) Law enforcement authorities were notified within a reasonable time; and New Section 22-3814.2 £NROLLED ORIGINAL 4) The person detained or arrested was released within a reasonable time of the detention or arrest, or was surrendered to law enforcement authorities within a reasonable time Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 60-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-2/33(c)(2 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of ~olumbia~tatutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia VI’EM ON COY~SEN’T CALENDAR VO[CE VOTE RECORDED VO~E kBSENT COUNCIL OF THg DIb"I’g/CT Of COLL,-MBD~ COUNCIL PERIOD ELgVEN RECORD OF oFFICIAL CO CIL VOTE D~kct No. Adopted Fi rst Readi ng, B11-125 05-02-95 Approved ’ i ROLLC~I,L%OTE-Result Chavous Chron. Clarke Brazil Cropp Ray X [c’E .Iarvks Lighffoot Mason Patterson C nc~lmember Aye Nay N~ i xB Smith, Jr. Thomas. Sr. Adol~ed Fi nal Readinq, 06-06-95 ApprOQed REt I)RD| D V [’E O\ xt r Brazil and Thomas Counc~Imember Smith. Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington Lig~tfoot ,Mason Patterson Ray CERTIFICATION RECOPd3 | NV¯Pr~enf. not votang DaI~ t ~Ct~Iro amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON I~gQUEST ABSENT ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Cmmcilmember [ Aye Nay NnV i.AB Com~c£1member Aye B~aza ] L~hff~t Chavo~ M~n Cropp Pa~n Eva~ Ray Nay ~’V AB Cmmcilmeml~r Smith. Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB- Al~.nl Aye Nay’ NV AB CERTIFICATION RECORD</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
