<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-82">
  <num type="law">11-82</num>
  <heading type="short">Uniform Premarital Agreement Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1996-02-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-82.pdf">D.C. Law 11-82</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 6770</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0227">
      <narrative>Law 11-82, the “Uniform Premarital Agreement Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-227, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 10, 1995, and November 7, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 27, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-159 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-82 became effective on February 9, 1996.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 062 312 878 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA D.C. LAW 11-82 "Uniform Premartial Agreement Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-227 on first and second readings, October 10, 1995 and November 7, 1995 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 22, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-159 and published in the December 8, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 6770) and transmitted to Congress on December 8, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-82, effective February 9, 1996 D~VID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Dec. 8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,27 Jan. 3,4,5,8,9,22,23,24,25,26,29,30,31 Feb. 1,2,5,6,7,8 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 11-159 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 27, 1995 Codification District of Columbia Code 1996 Supp. To enact the Unifonr~ Premarital Agreement Act in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Premarital Agreement Act of 1995 Sec. 2. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Premarital agreement" means an agreement between prospective spouses made in contemplation of marriage and to be effective upon marriage 2 Property" means an interest, present or future, legal or equitable, vested or contingent, in real or personal property, including income and eamings. Sec. 3. Formalities. A premarital agreement must be in writing and signed by both parties. It is enforceable without consideration. Sec. 4. Content a) Parties to a premarital agreement may contract with respect to 1) The rights and obligations of each of the parties in any of the property of either or both of them whenever and wherever acquired or located 2) The right to buy, sell, use, transfer, exchange, abandon, lease, consume, expend, assign, create a security interest in, mortgage, encumber, dispose of, or otherwise manage and control property 3) The disposition of property upon separation, marital dissolution, annulment, death, or the occurrence or nonoccurrence of any other event 4) The modification or elimination of spousal support 5) The making of a will, trust, or other arrangement to carry out the provisions New Chapter IA Title 30 New Section 30-141 New Section 30-142 New Section 30-143 ENROLLED ORIGINAL of the agreement 6) The ownership rights in, and disposition of, the death benefit from a life insurance policy 7) The choice of law governing the construction of the agreement; and (8) Any other matter, including their personal rights and obligations, not in violation of public policy or a statute imposing a criminal penalty b) The right of a child to support may not be adversely affected by a premarital agreement. Sec. 5. Effect of man’iage. A premarital agreement becomes effective upon marriage. Sec. 6. Amendment; revocation. After marriage, a premarital agreement may be amended or revoked only by a written agreement signed by the parties. The amended agreement or the revocation is enforceable without consideration. Sec. 7. Enforcement a) A premarital agreement is not enforceable if the party against whom enforcement is sought proves that 1) That party did not execute the agreement voluntarily; or (2) The agreement was unconscionable when it was executed and, before execution of the agreement, that party A) Was not provided a fair and reasonable disclosure of the property or financial obligations of the other party B) Did not voluntarily and expressly waive, in writing, any right to disclosure of the property or financial obligations of the other party beyond the disclosure provided; and (C) Did not have, or reasonably could not have had, an adequate knowledge of the propel"ty or financial obligations of the other party b) If a provision of a premarital agreement modifies or eliminates spousal support and that modification or elimination causes one party to the agreement to be eligible for support under a program of public assistance at the time of separation or marital dissolution, a court, notwithstanding the terms of the agreement, may require the other party to provide support to the extent necessary to avoid that eligibility c) An issue of unconscionability of a premarital agreement shall be decided by the court as a matter of law. Sec. 8. Void marriage. If a marriage is determined to be void, an agreement that would otherwise have been a premarital agreement is enforceable only to the extent necessary to avoid an inequitable result, New Section 30-144 New Section 30-145 New S ectioll 30-146 New Section 30-147 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL unless the agreement expressly provides that it shall be enforceable in the event that the marriage is later determined to be void. Sec. 9. Limitation of actions. Any statute of limitations applicable to an action asserting a claim for relief under a premarital agreement is tolled during the marriage of the parties to the agreement. However, equitable defenses limiting the time for enforcement, including laches and estoppel, are available to either party. Sec. 10. Applicability. This act applies to any premarital agreement executed on or after the effective date of this act. Sec. 11. Application and construction. This act shall be applied and construed to effectuate its general purpose to make uniform the law with respect to the subject of this act among states enacting it. Sec. 12. Fiscal impact. This act will have no fiscal impact. Sec. 13. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(c and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Co~mbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPR0~/EI November 27, 1995 3 New Section 30-148 New Secti~ 30-149 New Section 30-150 ~co~ oF OF~C,A CO~’NCIL vo~ BII--227 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 10-10-95 [ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [X ACTION &amp;amp; DATE APPROVEDI~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST RAYABSENT I ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Cotmcflmenlber Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Councilmember Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray X h~dical~s ’ote AB- Absent CERTIFICATION RECC)RD ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Councilmembe~r Smith, Jr Thomas, Sr N Present not Voting ADOPTED FINAL READING, 11-7-95 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED SMITH [ I ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans X-indicates 1¥~ ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ] ACT1ON &amp;amp; DATE A?e Na? NV AB Councilmember A)e Nay NV AB Cotmcilmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB-Absent NV-Present not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ [ ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Councilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans .C Aye Nay NW AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay N ’ AB X Indicates Vote Jarvis Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB- Absent Present not Volang CERTIFICATION RECOI~D Secretary. to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§46-501"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§46-502"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§46-503"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§46-504"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§46-505"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§46-506"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§46-507"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§46-508"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§46-509"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§46-510"/>
  </section>
</document>
