<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-85">
  <num type="law">11-85</num>
  <heading type="short">Uniform Foreign Money Claims Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1996-02-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-85.pdf">D.C. Law 11-85</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 6791</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B11-0230">
      <narrative>Law 11-85, the “Uniform Foreign Money Claims Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-230, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 10, 1995, and November 7, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 28, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-164 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-85 became effective on February 10, 1996.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LLME T(S) kwiktag 062 312 896 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA D.C. LAW 11-85 "Uniform Foreign Money Claims Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-230 on first and second readings, October 10, 1995 and November 7, 1995 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 28, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-164 and published in the December 8, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 6791) and transmitted to Congress on December 12, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-85, effective February 10, 1996 D A CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Dec. 12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,27 Jan. 3,4,5,8,9,22,23,24,25,26,29,30,31 Feb. 1,2,5,6,7,8,9 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT Coai~caaou District of Columbia D, C, ACT ii- 164 coe 1996 Supp. 1N THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 28, 1995 To enact the Uniform Foreign Money Claims Act in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this New act may be cited as the "Uniform Foreign Money Claims Act of 1995 Chapter 9,Title 15 Sec. 2. Title 15 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents at the beginning of the title is amended by adding at the end "9. Uniform Foreign Money Claims §§ 15-901 15-914 b) A new chapter 9 is added to read as follows Chapter 9. Uniform Foreign Money Claims Sec 15-901 15-902 15-903 15-904 15-905 15-906 15-907 15-908 15-909 15-910 15-911 15-912 15-913 15-914. Definitions. Variation by agreement. Determining money of the claim. Determining amount of the money of certain contract claims. Asserting and defending a foreign money claim. Judgments and awards on foreign money claims; times of money conversion; form of judgment. Conversions of foreign money in distribution proceeding. Prejudgment and judgment interest. Enforcement of foreign judgments. Determining United States dollar value of foreign money claims for limited purposes. Effect of currency revalorization. Supplementary general principles of law. Applicability. Uniformity of application and construction. ENROLLED ORIGINAL "§ 15-901. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Action" means a judicial proceeding or arbitration in which a payment in money may be awarded or enforced with respect to a foreign-money claim 2 Bank-offered spot rate" means the spot rate of exchange at which a bank will sell foreign money at a spot rate 3 Conversion date" means the banking day next preceding the date on which money, in accordance with this act, is A) Paid to a claimant in an action or distribution proceeding B) Paid to the official designated by law to enforce a judgment or award on behalf of a claimant; or C) Used to recoup, set off, or counterclaim in different moneys in an action or distribution proceeding 4 Distribution proceeding" means a judicial or nonjudicial proceeding for the distribution of a fund in which one or more foreign-money claims is asserted and includes an accounting, an assignment for the benefit of creditors, a foreclosure, the liquidation or rehabilitation of a corporation or other entity, and the distribution of an estate, trust, or other fund 5 Foreign money" means money other than money of the United States of America 6 Foreign-money claim" means a claim upon an obligation to pay, or a claim for recovery of a loss, expressed in, or measured by, a foreign money 7 Money" means a medium of exchange for the payment of obligations or a store of value authorized or adopted by a government or by an intergovernmental agreement 8 Money of the claim" means the money determined as proper pursuant to section 15-904 9 Person" means an individual, corporation, government or governmental subdivision or agency, business trust, estate, trust, joint venture, partnership, association, 2 or more persons having a joint or common trust, or any other legal or commercial entity 10 Rate of exchange" means the rate at which money of one country may be converted into money of another country in a free financial market convenient to, or reasonably usable by, a person obligated to pay or to state a rate of conversion. If separate rates of exchange apply to different kinds of transactions, the term means the rate applicable to the particular transactions giving rise to the foreign-money claim 11 Spot rate" means the rate of exchange at which foreign money is sold by a bank or other dealer in foreign exchange for immediate or next day availability or for settlement by immediate payment in cash or equivalent, by charge to an account, or by an agreed delayed settlement not exceeding 2 days 12 State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or a territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States. New Section 15-901 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "§ 15-902. Variation by agreement a) The effect of this act may be varied by agreement of the parties made before or after commencement of an action or distribution proceeding or the entry of judgment b) Parties to a transaction may agree upon the money to be used in a transaction giving rise to a foreign-money claim and may agree to use different moneys for different aspects of the transaction. Stating the price in a foreign money for one aspect of a transaction does not alone require the use of that money for other aspects of the transaction § 15-903. Determining money of the claim a) The money in which the parties to a transaction have agreed that payment is to be made, is the proper money of the claim for payment b) If the parties to a transaction have not otherwise agreed, the proper money of the claim, as in each case may be appropriate, is the money 1) Regularly used between the parties as a matter of usage or course of dealing 2) Used at the time of a transaction in international trade, by trade usage or common practice, for valuing or settling transactions in the particular commodity or service involved; or 3) In which the loss was ultimately felt or will be incurred by the party claimant § 15-904. Determining amount of the money of certain contract claims a) If an amount contracted to be paid in a foreign money is measured by a specified amount of a different money, the amount to be paid is determined on the conversion date b) If an amount contracted to be paid in a foreign money is to be measured by a different money at the rate of exchange prevailing on a date before default, that rate of exchange applies only to payments made within a reasonable time after default, not exceeding 30 days. Thereafter, conversion is made at the bank-offered spot rate on the conversion date c) A monetary claim is neither usurious nor unconscionable because the agreement on which it is based provides that the amount of the debtor’s obligation to be paid in the debtor’s money, when received by the creditor, must equal a specified amount of the foreign money of the country of the creditor. If, because ofunexcused delay in payment of a judgment or award, the amount received by the creditor does not equal the amount of the foreign money specified in the agreement, the court or arbitrator shall amend the judgment or award accordingly § 15-905. Asserting and defending a foreign-money claim a) A person may assert a claim in a specified foreign money. If a foreign-money claim is not asserted, the claimant makes the claim in United States dollars b) An opposing party may allege and prove that a claim, in whole or in part, is in a different money than that asserted by the claimant c) A person may assert a defense, set-off, recoupment, or counterclaim in any money without regard to the money of other claims. New Section 15-902 New Section 15-903 New Section 15-904 New Section 15-905 3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL d) The determination of the proper money of the claim is a question of law § 15-906. Judgments and awards on foreign-money claims; times of money conversion; form of judgment a) Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a judgment or award on a foreign-money claim must be stated in an amount of the money of the claim b) A judgment or award on a foreign-money claim is payable in that foreign money or, at the option of the debtor, in the amount of United States dollars which will purchase that foreign money on the conversion date at a bank-offered spot rate c) Assessed costs must be entered in United States dollars d) Each payment in United States dollars must be accepted and credited on a judgment or award on a foreign-money claim in the amount of the foreign money that could be purchased by the dollars at a bank-offered spot rate of exchange at or near the close of business on the conversion date for the payment e) A judgment or award made in an action or distribution proceeding on both a defense, set-off, recoupment, or counterclaim and the adverse party’s claim, must be netted by converting the money of the smaller into the money of the larger, and by subtracting the smaller from the larger, and specifying the rates of exchange used f) A judgment substantially in the following from complies with subsection (a) of this section IT IS ADJUDGED AND ORDERED, that Defendant (insert name) pay to Plaintiff (insert name) the sum of (insert amount in the foreign money) plus interest on that sum at the rate of interest pursuant to section 15-908 or, at the option of the judgment debtor, the number of United States dollars which will purchase the (insert name of foreign money) with interest due, at a bank-offered spot rate at or near the close of business on the banking day next before the day of payment, together with assessed costs of (insert amount) United States dollars g) Ira contract claim is of the type covered by section 15-904(a) or (b the judgment or award must be entered for the amount of money stated to measure the obligation to be paid in the money specified for payment or, at the option of the debtor, the number of United States dollars which will purchase the computed amount of the money of payment on the conversion date at a bank-offered spot rate h) A judgment must be filed and indexed in foreign money in the same manner as other judgments and has the same effect as a lien. It may be discharged by payment § 15-907. Conversions of foreign money in distribution proceeding The rate of exchange prevailing at or near the close of business on the day the distribution proceeding is initiated governs all exchanges of foreign money in a distribution proceeding. A foreign-money claimant in a distribution proceeding shall assert its claim in the named foreign money and show the amount of United States dollars resulting from a conversion as of the date the proceeding was initiated. New Section 15-906 New Section 15-907 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "§ 15-908. Prejudgment and j udgment interest a) With respect to a foreign-money claim, recovery of prejudgment or pre-award interest and the rate of interest to be applied in the action or distribution proceeding, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, are matters of the substantive law governing the right to recovery under the conflict of laws rules of the District b) The court or arbitrator shall increase or decrease the amount of prejudgment or pre- award interest otherwise payable in a judgment or award in foreign money to the extent required by the law of the District governing a failure to make or accept an offer of settlement or an offer of judgment, or to the extent required by the law of the District governing conduct by a party or its attorney causing undue delay or expense c) A judgment or award on a foreign-money claim bears interest at the rate applicable to judgments of the District § 15-909. Enforcement of foreign judgments a) If an action is brought to enforce a judgment of another jurisdiction expressed in a foreign money and the judgment is recognized in the District as enforceable, the enforcing judgment must be entered as provided in section 15-907, whether or not the foreign judgment confers an option to pay in an equivalent amount of United States dollars b) A foreign judgment may be filed in accordance with any rule or statute of the District providing a procedure for its recognition and enforcement c) A satisfaction or partial payment made upon the foreign judgment, on proof thereof, must be credited against the amount of foreign money specified in the judgment, notwithstanding the entry ofjudgrnent in the District d) A judgment entered on a foreign-money claim only in United States dollars in another state must be enforced in the District in United States dollars only § 15-910. Determining United States dollar value of foreign-money claims for limited purposes a) Computations under this section are for the limited purposes of this section and do not affect computation of the United States dollar equivalent of the money of the judgment for the purpose of payment b) For the limited purpose of facilitating the enforcement of provisional remedies in an action, the value in United States dollars of assets to be seized or restrained pursuant to a writ of attachment, garnishment, execution, or other legal process, the amount of United States dollars at issue for assessing costs, or the amount of United States dollars involved for a surety bond or other court-required undertaking, must be ascertained as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section c) A party seeking process, costs, bond, or other undertaking under subsection (b) of this section shall compute in United States dollars the amount of the foreign money claimed from a bank-offered spot rate prevailing at or near the close of business on the banking day next preceding the filing of a request or application for the issuance of process or for the New Section 15-908 New Section 15-909 New Section 15-910 5 ENROLLED ORIGINAL determination of costs, or an application for a bond or other court-required undertaking d) A party seeking the process, costs, bond, or other undertaking under subsection (b) of this section shall file with each request or application an affidavit or certificate executed in good faith by its counsel or a bank officer, stating the market quotation used and how it was obtained, and setting forth the calculation. Affected court officials incur no liability, after a filing of the affidavit or certificate, for acting as if the judgment were in the amount of United States dollars stated in the affidavit or certificate § 15-911. Effect of currency revalorization a) If, after an obligation is expressed or a loss is incurred in a foreign money, the country issuing or adopting that money substitutes a new money in place of that money, the obligation or the loss is treated as if expressed or incurred in the new money at the rate of conversion the issuing country establishes for the payment of like obligations or losses denominated in the former money b) If substitution under subsection (a) of this section occurs after a judgment or award is entered on a foreign-money claim, the court or arbitrator shall amend the judgment or award by a like conversion of the former money § 15-912. Supplementary general principles of law Unless displaced by particular provisions of this act, the principles of law and equity, including the law merchant, and the laws relative to capacity to contract, principal and agent, estoppel, fraud, misrepresentation, duress, coercion, mistake, bankruptcy, or other validating or invalidating causes supplement the provisions of this act § 15-913. Applicability a) This act applies only to a foreign-money claim in an action or distribution proceeding b) This act applies to foreign money issues even if other law, under the conflict of laws rules of the District of Columbia, applies to other issues in the action or distribution proceeding § 15-914. Uniformity of application and construction This act shall be applied and construed to effectuate its general purpose to make uniform the law with respect to the subject of this act among states enacting similar legislation Sec. 3. Fiscal impact. This act will have no fiscal impact. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia New Section 15-911 New Section 15-912 New Section 15-913 New Section 15-914 6 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(c and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approve~l~ecember 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the Dis~ctrf ~o\umbia Register. Chairmal~ Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: November 28, 1995 7 COUNCIL OF THJ~ DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE ~etNo. BIi’230 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 10-10-95 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR IX ACTION &amp;amp; DATE APPROVEDI VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST RAY ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result C{mncilmember Aye Nay NW AB Cotmcilmernber Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X Indicates Vnte AB Absent Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington N~.’. Pres~mt not Voting [ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION~’D TEADOPTED FINAL READING, ii-7-95 I&amp;gt vo,cE VOTEA P P ROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ,BSENT SMITH ROLL CALL VOTE R~ul! C~,ut~d|memher Aye Na NV AB Councilmember A.~e Nay N¥ AB Coundimemher Aye Nay NV AB Chmn. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X-indicates no ~to the Co.oil Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Whittington AB-Absent NV-Present not voting ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE CERTIFICATION RECORD RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ t ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NW AB Chron. Clarke JarvLs Brazil Lightfoot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X. Indicates Vote AB- Absent Cotmdlmember Aye Nay N AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington N3,’ Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary. to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
