<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 11-84">
  <num type="law">11-84</num>
  <heading type="short">Uniform Foreign Money Judgments Recognition Act of 1995</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1996-02-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/11-84.pdf">D.C. Law 11-84</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 6787</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B11-0229">
      <narrative>Law 11-84, the “Uniform Foreign Money Judgments Recognition Act of 1995,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-229, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 10, 1995, and November 7, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 28, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-163 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-84 became effective on February 10, 1996.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 312 890 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA D.C. LAW 11-84 "Uniform Foreign Money Judgments Recognition Act of 1995 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 11-229 on first and second readings, October 10, 1995 and November 7, 1995 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 28, 1995, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 11-163 and published in the December 8, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 6787) and transmitted to Congress on December 12, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 11-84, effective February 10, 1996. Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Dec. 12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,27 Jan. 3,4,5,8,9,22,23,24,25,26,29,30,31 Feb. 1,2,5,6,7,8,9 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C, ACT ii-163 Codification District of Columbia Code 1996 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 28, 1995 To enact the Uniform Foreign Money Judgments Recognition Act in the District of Columbia. New Subchapter hi, Chapter 3, Title 15 BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Foreign Money Judgments Recognition Act of 1995 Sec. 2. Title 15 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents at the beginning of the title is amended by striking "15-357" and inserting "l 5-388" in its place b) The table of contents at the beginning of chapter 3 is amended by adding the following to the end Subchapter lII. Uniform Foreign Money Judgments Sec 15-381. Definitions 15-382. Recognition and enforcement 15-383. Grounds for nonrecognition 15-384. Personal jurisdiction 15-385. Stay in cases of appeal 15-386. Savings clause 15-387. Applicability 15-388. Uniformity of application and construction c) A new subchapter Ill of chapter 3 is added to read as follows Subchapter IlL Uniform Foreign Money Judgments § 15-381. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Foreign state" means any governmental unit other than the United States, or any state, the District of Columbia, or any territory or insular possession of the United States. New Section 15-381 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 Foreign money judgment" means any judgment of a foreign state granting or dewing recovery of a sum of money, other than a judgment for taxes, a fine or other penalty, or a judgment for support in matrimonial or family matters § 15-382. Recognition and enforcement Except as provided in section 15-383, a foreign money judgment meeting the requirements of section 15-387 is conclusive between the parties to the extent that it grants or denies recovery of a sum of money. The foreign money judgment is enforceable in the same manner as the judgment of a sister jurisdiction which is entitled to full faith and credit § 15-383. Grounds for nonrecognition a) A foreign money judgment is not conclusive if 1) The judgment was rendered under a system that does not provide impartial tribunals or procedures compatible with the requirements of due process of law 2) The foreign court did not have personal jurisdiction over the defendant; or 3) The foreign court did not have jurisdiction over the subject matter b) A foreign money judgment need not be recognized if 1) The defendant in the proceedings in the foreign court did not receive notice of the proceedings in sufficient time to enable the defendant to defend 2) The judgment was obtained by fraud 3) The cause of action on which the judgment is based is repugnant to the public policy of the District of Columbia 4) The judgment conflicts with another final and conclusive judgment 5) The proceeding in the foreign court was contrary to an agreement between the parties under which the dispute in question was to be settled otherwise than by proceedings in that court; or 6) In the case of jurisdiction based only on personal service, the foreign court was a seriously inconvenient forum for the trial of the action § 15-384. Personal jurisdiction a) A foreign money judgment shall not be refused recognition for lack of personal jurisdiction if 1) The defendant was served personally in the foreign state 2) The defendant voluntarily appeared in the proceedings, other than for the purpose of protecting property seized or threatened with seizure in the proceedings or of contesting the jurisdiction of the court over the defendant 3) The defendant, prior to the commencement of the proceedings, had agreed to submit to the jurisdiction of the foreign court with respect to the subject matter involved 4) The defendant was domiciled in the foreign state when the proceedings were instituted, or, being a body corporate, had its principal place of business, was incorporated, or had otherwise acquired corporate status in the foreign state 5) The defendant had a business office in the foreign state and the proceedings New Section 5-382 New Section 15-383 New Section 15-384 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL in the foreign court involved a cause of action arising out of business done by the defendant through that office in the foreign state; or 6) The defendant operated a motor vehicle or airplane in the foreign state and the proceedings involved a cause of action arising out of such operation b) The courts of the District of Columbia may recognize other bases of jurisdiction § 15-385. Stay in cases of appeal If the defendant satisfies the court that either an appeal is pending or the defendant is entitled and intends to appeal from the foreign money judgment, the court may stay the proceedings until the appeal has been determined or until the expiration of a period of time sufficient to enable the defendant to prosecute the appeal § 15-386. Savings clause This act does not prevent the recognition of a foreign money judgment in situations not covered by this act. New Section 15-385 New Section 15-386 "§ 15-387. Applicability This act applies to any foreign money judgment that is final and conclusive and enforceable where rendered even though an appeal therefrom is pending or it is subject to appeal § 15-388. Uniformity of application and construction This act shall be applied and construed to effectuate its general purpose to make uniform the law with respect to the subject of this act among states enacting it Sec. 3. Fiscal impact. This act will have no fiscal impact. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(c and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental New Section 15-387 New Section 15-388 3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of C mbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: November 28, 1995 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUM~BIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE BII-229 D~ket No ADOPTED FIRST READING, 10-10-95 [~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [ A~TION &amp;amp; DATE APPROVED [ VOICE VOTERECORDED VO2~E ON REQUEST RAY ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Cntmcilmember I Aye Nay NW kB Counci|member Chron. Clarke Jarvis Brazil Light foot Chavous Mason Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X l~dicates Vote Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington AB. Absent NV Present not Voting ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE CERTIFICA’flON RECORD Date ADOPTED FINAL READING, 11-7-95 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED SMITH [ I ROLL CALL VOTE- R~sult Co,ancilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp E~ans i~ X-indicates~o { ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [ I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NV AB Jarv~ Lightfoot Mason Patterson Ray AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Whittington NV-Present not voting l VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Na? NV AB Coundlmember Aye Nay NT AB Coun dlmember Aye Nay N AB X Indicates Vote Jarvis Light foot Mason Patterson Ray Smith, Jr. Thorn&amp;amp;s, Sr. Whittington AB- Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT Codification District of Columbia Code 1996 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To enact the Uniform Foreign Money Judgments Recognition Act in the District of Columbia. New Subchapter HI. Chapter 3, Title 15 BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Foreign Money Judgments Recognition Act of 1995" Sec. 2. Title 15 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents at the beginning of the title is amended by striking "15-357" and inserting "15-388" in its place b) The table of contems at the beginning of chapter 3 is amended by adding the following to the end Subchapter llI. Uniform Foreign Money Judgments Sec 15-381. Definitions 15-382. Recognition and enforcement 15-383. Grounds for nonrecognition 15-384. Personal jurisdiction 15-385. Stay in cases of appeal l 5-386. Savings clause 15-387. Applicability 15-388. Uniformity of application and construction c) A new subchapter III of chapter 3 is added to read as follows Subchapter 11I. Uniform Foreign Money Judgments § 15-381. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term: ’(1 Foreign state" means any governmental unit other than the United States, or any state, the District of Columbia, or any territory or insular possession of the United States. New Section 15-381 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 Foreign moneyjudgrnent" means any judgment of a foreign state granting or denying recovery of a sum of money, other than a judgment for taxes, a fine or other penalty, or a judgment for support in matrimonial or family matters § 15-382. Recognition and enforcement Except as provided in section 15-383, a foreign moneyjudgrnent meeting the requirements of section 15-387 is conclusive between the parties to the extent that it grants or denies recovery of a sum of money. The foreign money judgment is enforceable in the same manner as the judgment of a sister jurisdiction which is entitled to full faith and credit § 15-383. Grounds for nonrecognition a) A foreign money judgment is not conclusive if 1) The judgment was rendered under a system that does not provide impartial tribunals or procedures compatible with the requirements of due process of law 2) The foreign court did not have personal jurisdiction over the defendant; or 3) The foreign court did not have jurisdiction over the subject matter b) A foreign money judgment need not be recognized if 1) The defendant in the proceedings in the foreign court did not receive notice of the proceedings in sufficient time to enable the defendant to defend 2) The judgment was obtained by fraud 3) The cause of action on which the judgment is based is repugnant to the public policy of the District of Columbia 4) The judgment conflicts with another final and conclusive judgment 5) The proceeding in the foreign court was contratT to an agreement between the parties under which the dispute in question was to be settled otherwise than by proceedings in that court; or 6) In the case of jurisdiction based only on personal service, the foreign court was a seriously inconvenient forum for the trial of the action § 15-384. Personal jurisdiction a) A foreign money judgment shall not be refused recognition for lack of personal jurisdiction if 1) The defendant was served personally in the foreign state 2) The defendant voluntarily appeared in the proceedings, other than for the purpose of protecting property seized or threatened with seizure in the proceedings or of contesting the jurisdiction of the court over the defendant 3) The defendant, prior to the commencement of the proceedings, had agreed to submit to the jurisdiction of the foreign court with respect to the subject matter involved 4) The defendant was domiciled in the foreign state when the proceedings were instituted, or, being a body corporate, had its principal place of business, was incorporated, or had otherwise acquired corporate status in the foreign state 5) The defendant had a business office in the foreign state and the proceedings New Section 15-382 New Section 15-383 New Section 15-384 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL in the foreign court involved a cause of action arising out of business done by the defendant through that office in the foreign state; or 6) The defendant operated a motor vehicle or airplane in the foreign state and the proceedings involved a cause of action arising out of such operation b) The courts of the District of Columbia may recognize other bases of jurisdiction § 15-385. Stay in cases of appeal If the defendant satisfies the court that either an appeal is pending or the defendant is entitled and intends to appeal from the foreign money judgment, the court may stay the proceedings until the appeal has been determined or until the expiration of a period of time sufficient to enable the defendant to prosecute the appeal § 15-386. Savings clause This act does not prevent the recognition of a foreign money judgment in situations not covered by this act. New Section 15-385 New Section 15-386 "§ 15-387. Applicability This act applies to any foreign money judgment that is final and conclusive and enforceable where rendered even though an appeal therefrom is pending or it is subject to appeal § 15-388. Uniformity of application and construction This act shall be applied and construed to effectuate its general purpose to make uniform the law with respect to the subject of this act among states enacting it Sec. 3. Fiscal impact. This act will have no fiscal impact. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(c and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental New Section 15-387 New Section 15-388 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of C mbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ELEVEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE BII-229 Docket No ADOPTED FIRST READING, 10-10-95 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR APPROVEDVOICE VOT CO~ED VOTE ON ~QU~T RAY A~EN~ ROLL CALL VOTE Result ICotmdlmmtber Aye Nay N3 AB Cotmdlmember Aye Nay NT AB Cotmcibnember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Clarke Jarvis Smith, Jr. Brazil Lightfoot Thomas. Sr. Chavous Mason Whittington Cropp Patterson Evans Ray X- 1/~dic~tes Vote to the Council [X ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I~ ACTION &amp;amp; D~TE AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD N3,’ ¯ Presmt no~ Voting Date ADOPTED FINAL READING, 11-7-95 VOICE VOTE RECORDED OTE O’~ REQUEST ~BSENT APPROVED SMITH ROLL CALL VOTE. Remit C,,uncilmember A?e Na NV AB Councflmember A.~e Nay NT AB Cow.emir Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Clarke Jarv~ Smith, Jr. Brazil Light f~t Thomas, Sr. Chavous Mason Whittin~on Cropp Patterson Evans Ray t Co.all I ITeM O~ CONSENT CALEndAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE t ] VOlCEVOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ } ROLL CALL VOTE Resul! r Councilmember Chron. Clarke Brazil Chavous Cropp Evans Aye Na N AB Com~cilmemb~r Aye Nay NT AB Cotm~lmeml~r Aye Nay ST AB X ¯ Indicates Vote Jar vi.s Smith. Jr. Lightfoot Thomas, St. Mason Whittington Patterson Ray AB- Ah~nt i u| NV. Present not Voting CERTIF1CAT|ON RECORD St~’etar~ to the Council Dat~</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
