<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>20-712</num>
  <heading>Appraisal; supervised administration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In a supervised administration, the fair market value of each item listed in the inventory, as of the date of death of the decedent, shall be determined by an appraisal. Except as specifically provided by this subsection, the supervised personal representative may use either the standing appraisers or special appraisers, as the personal representative deems appropriate. The supervised personal representative may appraise the following items listed in section 20-711(a):</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>items listed in paragraphs (4), (5), and (6); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>items listed in paragraph (3) that are listed on any national or regional exchange or are sold in the over-the-counter market for which bid and asked prices are regularly published.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An appraisal shall be in columnar form, shall describe generally each item that has been appraised, shall assign a value to each item that has been appraised, and shall be verified by the appraiser. A verification under this section shall certify that the appraiser has impartially valued the property described in the appraisal to the best of the appraiser’s skill and judgment. Any appraisal not performed by the personal representative shall be delivered to the personal representative immediately upon completion and verification. The name and address of any appraiser shall be indicated on the inventory with the item or items appraised.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An appraisal fee shall be payable only to a person making an appraisal at the request of the personal representative.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the filing of the inventory was not required within 3 months after the appointment of the personal representative, either because the administration was at that time unsupervised or because it was waived pursuant to section 20-731, and if the inventory is subsequently required to be filed, the requirement for appraisals in that event shall be excused unless otherwise ordered by the Court for good cause shown.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-72" type="History">June 24, 1980, D.C. Law 3-72, § 101, 27 DCR 2155</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-241" type="History">Mar. 21, 1995, D.C. Law 10-241, § 3(ii), 42 DCR 63</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 20-712.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 10-241: See Application of Law 10-241 and Emergency act amendment notes to § <cite path="§20-701.01">20-701.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
