<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>20-744</num>
  <heading>Protection of person dealing with personal representative.</heading>
  <text>Except as otherwise provided in section 20-753  , a person who in good faith either assists or deals with a personal representative for value is protected as if the personal representative properly exercised his power. The fact that a person knowingly deals with a personal representative does not alone require the person to inquire into the existence of a power or the propriety of its exercise. Except for restrictions on powers of supervised personal representatives which are endorsed on letters as provided in section 20-504  , no provision in any will or order of court purporting to limit the power of a personal representative is effective except as to persons with actual knowledge thereof. A person is not bound to see to the proper application of estate assets paid or delivered to a personal representative. The protection here expressed extends to instances in which some procedural irregularity or jurisdictional defect occurred in proceedings leading to the issuance of letters, including a case in which the alleged decedent is found to be alive. The protection here expressed is not in substitution for that provided by comparable provisions of the laws relating to commercial transactions and laws simplifying transfers of securities by fiduciaries.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-72" type="History">June 24, 1980, D.C. Law 3-72, § 101, 27 DCR 2155</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-241" type="History">Mar. 21, 1995, D.C. Law 10-241, § 3(ccc), 42 DCR 63</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 10-241: See Application of Law 10-241 and Emergency act amendment notes to § <cite path="§20-701.01">20-701.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 20-744.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§20-743">20-743</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
