<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>20-732</num>
  <heading>Waiver of formal Court audit; supervised administration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A supervised personal representative shall be excused from a formal Court audit of the accounts required by sections 20-721, 20-722, and 20-723 if authorized by written waiver signed by each heir or legatee and filed with the Register. A waiver under this section shall state that the heirs or legatees are aware of their right to require a formal Court audit of accounts and of their right to revoke the waiver under subsection (c) of this section. Unless the will specifically provides otherwise, a trustee as legatee may authorize and sign a waiver under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon the filing of a waiver under this section, the Court shall conduct a cursory review to determine if the accounts appear regular on their face and are supported by reasonable documentation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any heir or legatee, including a trustee as legatee, who has signed a waiver under subsection (a) of this section, may require a formal Court audit of accounts by filing a written demand with the Register within 20 days of the approval of the final account under section 20-1301.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-72">June 24, 1980, D.C. Law 3-72, § 101, 27 DCR 2155</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-241">Mar. 21, 1995, D.C. Law 10-241, § 3(uu), 42 DCR 63</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 19(h), 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 13(d), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 20-732.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Application of Law 10-241: See Application of Law 10-241 and Emergency act amendment notes to § <cite path="§20-701.01">20-701.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
