<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-147" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-147</num>
  <num type="act">25-379</num>
  <num type="bill">25-540</num>
  <heading type="short">School Improvement Amendment Act of 2023</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the State Education Office Establishment Act of 2000 to establish a school support office within the Office of the State Superintendent of Education with authority to focus academic improvement in the lowest performing schools.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-10-16</introduced>
    <effective>2024-03-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/54056/Signed_Act/B25-0540-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=184215">D.C. Law 25-147</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 1443</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0540">
      <vote date="2023-12-19" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2024-01-09" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-02-01</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "School Improvement Amendment Act of 2023".</text>
  <section codify:path="§38-2602">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 3 of the State Education Office Establishment Act of 2000, effective October 21, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-176; D.C Official Code § 38-2602), is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert after="(c)" num-value="(d)"/>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>OSSE shall establish a School Support Office ("Office") to implement and administer a school support program ("Program") beginning in School Year 2025-2026. The Program shall provide support and resources for continuous academic improvement to DCPS schools and District public charter schools whose academic performance is, at minimum, in the lowest 5% of all public schools in the District.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>It shall be the goal of the Program to substantially improve academic outcomes within 5 years of a school entering the Program. Subject to appropriations, the Office shall provide local funding, in addition to any Formula or federal funding already available to low performing schools, to qualifying schools that participate in the Program.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>No later than September 30, 2024, OSSE shall submit a report to the Mayor and the Council, developed in consultation with the State Board of Education, DCPS, the District of Columbia Public Charter School Board ("PCSB"), and other stakeholders, which shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Compare and assess school improvement best practices from other jurisdictions;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Identify and explain the metrics that will be used to determine the schools whose academic performance is, at minimum, in the lowest 5% of all public schools in the District;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Propose evidence-based strategies for continuous school improvement models for the lowest performing 5% of District public schools, including:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>The processes and frameworks for implementing the models;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>How each strategy or model will address professional development for educators, direct coaching, and leadership focused on addressing instructional practice; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iii)</num>
              <text>How utilization of the models and Office funding will align with PCSB and DCPS accountability metrics and frameworks;</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Provide recommendations for how the Office will work collaboratively with qualifying schools and school stakeholders to select and implement evidence-based strategies to significantly increase proficiency and growth in reading and math through proven methods and improve other school designation metrics;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>Provide recommendations on how the Office may strengthen a designated school's finances, financial management, policies, and culture;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(F)</num>
            <text>Describe how a participating school's improvement will be evaluated, including the criteria for exiting the Program;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(G)</num>
            <text>Explain how the Program will adjust to address a school that has not demonstrated sufficient improvement to exit the program after 5 years;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(H)</num>
            <text>Explain the funding and resources needed to successfully establish and operate the Office and implement the Program for participating schools;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>Set forth what additional authority OSSE will need, if any, to implement the report's recommendations and establish the Office and Program; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(J)</num>
            <text>Discuss any additional items relevant to the needs of the Office or Program.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>No later than September 1, 2025, and subject to appropriation, OSSE shall apply the school improvement models developed by the school support office to participating schools.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Starting September 30, 2026, and every 2 years thereafter, OSSE shall submit a report to the Mayor and the Council on the improvement of schools in the Program. The report shall address the effectiveness of the continuous school improvement models and provide recommendations, if any, for Program improvement, including a description of evidence-based strategies developed or further refined in the years since the last report.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2602" applicability-path="§3" action="creation of subsection (d) paragraphs (1), (2), (4), and (5) of" display-template=""/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraphs (1), (2), (4), and (5) in new subsection (d) added to section 3 of the State Education Office Establishment Act of 2000, effective October 21, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-176; D.C Official Code § 38-2602), by section 2 shall apply upon the date of the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the provisions identified in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <!-- <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-147" path="§2" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/> -->
    <!-- <codify:repeal path="§38-2602|(d)|(1)" display-template="" history="false"/>
    <codify:find-replace path="§38-2602|(d)|(1)" count="1" display-template="" history="false">
      <find>Repealed.</find>
      <replace>Not funded.</replace>
    </codify:find-replace> -->
    <codify:repeal path="§38-2602|(d)|(2)" display-template="" history="false"/>
    <codify:find-replace path="§38-2602|(d)|(2)" count="1" display-template="" history="false">
      <find>Repealed.</find>
      <replace>Not funded.</replace>
    </codify:find-replace>
    <!-- <codify:repeal path="§38-2602|(d)|(4)" display-template="" history="false"/>
    <codify:find-replace path="§38-2602|(d)|(4)" count="1" display-template="" history="false">
      <find>Repealed.</find>
      <replace>Not funded.</replace>
    </codify:find-replace> -->
    <!-- <codify:repeal path="§38-2602|(d)|(5)" display-template="" history="false"/>
    <codify:find-replace path="§38-2602|(d)|(5)" count="1" display-template="" history="false">
      <find>Repealed.</find>
      <replace>Not funded.</replace>
    </codify:find-replace> -->
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval of the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of Congressional review provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C Official Code § 1-206.22(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
