<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-155" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-155</num>
  <num type="act">25-398</num>
  <num type="bill">25-653</num>
  <heading type="short">Protecting Adjacent and Adjoining Property Owners from Construction Damage Temporary Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986 to require a property owner, contractor, or person applying for certain permits for construction work to demonstrate that their insurance provides coverage for adjacent and adjoining property owners for loss or damage that arises out of the proposed construction work.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-01-04</introduced>
    <effective>2024-04-10</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/54575/Signed_Act/B25-0653-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=185346">D.C. Law 25-155</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 2091</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0653">
      <vote date="2024-01-09" reading="Oral"/>
      <vote date="2024-01-09" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2024-02-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-02-22</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Protecting Adjacent and Adjoining Property Owners from Construction Damage Temporary Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 6a(a)(2A)(B) of the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-261; D.C. Official Code § 6-1405.01(a)(2A)(B)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="2">
      <para>
      <!-- <codify:replace path="§6-1405.01|(a)|(2A)|(B)"/> -->
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The following permits shall require insurance pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; provided, that the requirements shall only apply to permits issued 30 days after the adoption of emergency or final rules issued by the Mayor pursuant to subparagraph (E) of this paragraph:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>An addition, alteration, and repair permit pursuant to which the applicant will be engaging in underpinning, construction at the property line or on the party wall of an adjacent or adjoining property, or any construction activity for which a permit listed under sub-subparagraph (iii), (iv), (v), (vi), (vii), or (viii) of this subparagraph would otherwise be required;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>An alteration and repair permit pursuant to which the applicant will be engaging in underpinning, construction at the property line or on the party wall of an adjacent or adjoining property, or any construction activity for which a permit listed under sub-subparagraph (iii), (iv), (v), (vi), (vii), or (viii) of this subparagraph would otherwise be required;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A foundation permit;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>A demolition permit;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>An excavation permit;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>A new building permit;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>A raze permit; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(viii)</num>
          <text>A sheeting and shoring permit.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1405.01"/>
    <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1405.01" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on November 21, 2024. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1405.01(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert> -->
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
