<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-16">
  <num type="law">25-16</num>
  <num type="act">25-87</num>
  <num type="bill">25-156</num>
  <heading type="short">Use of Force Review Board Temporary Act of 2023</heading>
  <heading type="long">To establish a Use of Force Review Board to review uses of force as set forth by the Metropolitan Police Department in its written directives, and to prescribe the Board's membership.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-03-01</introduced>
    <effective>2023-06-14</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/52398/Signed_Act/B25-0156-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=160410">D.C. Law 25-16</citation>
      <citation type="register">70 DCR 6333</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0156">
      <vote date="2023-03-07" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2023-04-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-04-26</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Use of Force Review Board Temporary Act of 2023".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Use of Force Review Board.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is established a Use of Force Review Board ("Board"), which shall review uses of force as set forth by the Metropolitan Police Department in its written directives.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Board shall consist of the following 13 voting members, and may include non-voting members at the Mayor's discretion:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Seven MPD members appointed by the Chief of Police who hold the rank of Inspector or above, or the civilian equivalent;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Three civilian members appointed by the Mayor, pursuant to section 2(e) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1- 523.01(e)), with the following qualifications and no current or prior affiliation with law enforcement, including being employed by a law enforcement agency or law enforcement union:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>One member who has personally experienced the use of force by a law enforcement officer;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>One member of the District of Columbia Bar in good standing; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>One District resident community member;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Two civilian members appointed by the Council with the following qualifications and no current or prior affiliation with law enforcement, including being employed by a law enforcement agency or law enforcement union:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>One member with subject matter expertise in criminal justice policy; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>One member with subject matter expertise in law enforcement oversight and the use of force; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>The Executive Director of the Office of Police Complaints, or their designee.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
   <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-353.01" action="creation of"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 2(e) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(e)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (38) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (39) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (40) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(40)</num>
          <text>Use of Force Review Board, established by section 2 of the Use of Force Review Board Emergency Act of 2023, effective March 4, 2023 (D.C. Act 25-65; 70 DCR 3842).</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-523.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
