<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-176" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-176</num>
  <num type="act">25-457</num>
  <num type="bill">25-298</num>
  <heading type="short">Black LGBTQIA+ History Preservation Establishment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To require the Office of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Questioning Affairs to research and produce a report documenting the Black LGBTQIA+ history of the District.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-05-26</introduced>
    <effective>2024-06-12</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53144/Signed_Act/B25-0298-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=189080">D.C. Law 25-176</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 5021</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0298">
      <vote date="2024-03-05" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2024-03-05" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2024-04-02" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-04-25</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 25-298 would establish a Black Queer History Commission to research and publish a report documenting the Black LGBTQIA+ history of the District of Columbia. </summary>
      <committee>Public Works and Operations</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Black LGBTQIA+ History Preservation Establishment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Black LGBTQIA+ history report.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Office of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Questioning Affairs ("Office") shall research and produce a report on Black LGBTQIA+ history in the District. The report shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The history of the Black Pride Movement in the District and the notable people, places, and events that contribute to the rich history of the national and global queer culture;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>An analysis of the unique history of Black Trans people in the District and the contributions they have made to culture, activism, education, and other important spheres of life;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The historical context of the AIDS Crisis, its effects on the Black LGBTQIA+ community in the District, and how policy choices impact the community to the present day;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Curriculum recommendations for teaching Black LGBTQIA+ history in public schools in line with the Social Studies Standards for District of Columbia students; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Recommendations on how to promote the report to the public.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In developing the report, the Office shall consult individuals with lived experience or expertise on the topics covered and may provide compensation to those individuals for their time and contributions.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Office shall gather input for the report before final publication as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Hold a minimum of 2 public meetings; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>At least 90 days prior to completing the report, shall publish a draft report and provide a 30-day public comment period.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Office shall submit the final report to the Mayor, the Council, the District of Columbia Archives, and the DC Public Library's People's Archives by May 1, 2025.</text>
    </para>
    <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1382" type="Editor's Notes" history="false">
      Sections 2, 3, and 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-176">D.C. Law 25-176</cite> required the Office of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Questioning Affairs ("Office") to research and produce a report on Black LGBTQIA+ history in the District; established an Advisory Committee to provide guidance and feedback on the development of the report; and provided that expenses incurred by the Advisory Committee as a whole, or by an individual member when the expenses are duly authorized by the Office, shall be reimbursed pursuant <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-611.08|(d)">D.C. Code § 1-611.08(d)</cite>.
    </codify:annotation>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Advisory committee.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is established an Advisory Committee to provide guidance and feedback on the development of the report required by section 2. The Advisory Committee shall consist of 6 members to be appointed as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>One member from a Historically Black College or University located in the District, with expertise in Black LGBTQIA+ history, recommended by the Office;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Two members, with expertise in Black LGBTQIA+ history, appointed by the Chairman of the Council;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Two members, with expertise in Black LGBTQIA+ history, appointed by the Mayor; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>One member who is the Executive Director of the Commission on the Arts and Humanities, or his or her designee, with expertise in Black LGBTQIA+ history.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Advisory Committee shall meet no more than once a month for up to 12 months to conduct its business and shall remain in effect until the completion of the report required by section 2.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Advisory Committee shall submit a final commentary summarizing its activities, recommendations, and any dissenting opinions to the Office, which shall be incorporated into the final report required by section 2.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Advisory committee compensation.</heading>
    <para codify:path="§1-611.08|(c-2)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 1108(c-2) of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code §1-611.08(c-2)), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="[(8)]">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (8) is amended by striking the period "." and inserting a semi-colon in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace position="last">
          <find>.</find>
          <replace>;</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (10) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert/>
            <num>(10)</num>
            <text>Each member of the Advisory Committee appointed pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-176" path="§3">section 3 of the Black LGBTQ History Preservation Establishment Act of 2024</cite>,<span codify:value=""> passed on 2nd reading on April 2, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-298),</span> may receive compensation in the form of a stipend of not more than $100 per meeting of the Advisory Committee, in accordance with standards the Mayor may establish by rulemaking.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 25-176" applicability-path="§5" display-template=""/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Expenses incurred by the Advisory Committee as a whole, or by an individual member when the expense was duly authorized by the Office, shall be reimbursed pursuant to section 1108(d) of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-611.08(d)).</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
       <!-- <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-176" path="§4|(a)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/> -->
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect after approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
