<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-243" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-243</num>
  <num type="act">25-598</num>
  <num type="bill">25-654</num>
  <heading type="short">Protecting Adjacent and Adjoining Property Owners from Construction Damage Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986 to require a property owner, contractor, or person applying for specific permits for construction work to demonstrate that his or her insurance will insure adjacent property owners for loss or damage that arises out of the proposed construction work.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-01-04</introduced>
    <effective>2024-12-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/54576/Signed_Act/B25-0654-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=200343">D.C. Law 25-243</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/54576/Signed_Act/B25-0654-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=200343">D.C. Act 25-598</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 12990</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0654">
      <vote date="2024-09-17" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2024-10-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-10-24</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 25-654 would add the following permits to permits required to have insurance:  1)alteration and repair permits where the applicant is engaging in underpinning or related construction activities; 2) foundation permits; and 3) new building permits.</summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Protecting Adjacent and Adjoining Property Owners from Construction Damage Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section codify:path="§6-1405.01|(a)|(2A)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Sec. 6a(a)(2A) of the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-261; D.C. Official Code § 6-1405.01(a)(2A)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="(B)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="2">
        <para>
        <codify:replace/>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>The following permits shall require insurance pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; provided, that the requirements shall only apply to permits issued 90 days after the adoption of emergency or final rules issued by the Mayor pursuant to subparagraph (E) of this paragraph:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>An addition, alteration, and repair permit pursuant to which the applicant will be engaging in construction at the property line or on the party wall of an adjacent or adjoining property, or any construction activity for which a permit listed under sub-subparagraph (iii), (iv), (v), (vi), (vii), or (viii) of this subparagraph would otherwise be required;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>An alteration and repair permit pursuant to which the applicant will be engaging in underpinning, construction at the property line or on the party wall of an adjacent or adjoining property, or any construction activity for which a permit listed under sub-subparagraph (iii), (iv), (v), (vi), (vii), or (viii) of this subparagraph would otherwise be required;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>A foundation permit;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>A demolition permit;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(v)</num>
            <text>An excavation permit;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(vi)</num>
            <text>A new building permit;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(vii)</num>
            <text>A raze permit; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(viii)</num>
            <text>A sheeting and shoring permit.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="(D)|(i)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subparagraph (D)(i) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="3">
        <para>
        <codify:replace/>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>"Adjacent property" means any privately held real property (all or a portion thereof) within 30 feet of a property line of the real property for which the permit is applied.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="(E)">
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Subparagraph (E) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="2">
        <para>
        <codify:replace/>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall issue rules to implement this paragraph, pursuant to the authority provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1409">section 10</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
