<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-232" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-232</num>
  <num type="act">25-589</num>
  <num type="bill">25-565</num>
  <heading type="short">Certified Nurse Aide Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 to establish and regulate the profession of certified nurse aides, to authorize the Mayor through rulemaking to grant expedited temporary licenses to nurse aides from Maryland and Virginia wishing to practice in the District; to amend the Department of Health Functions Clarification Act of 2001 to create an Advisory Committee on Nursing Assistive Personnel; and to amend the Direct Support Professional Payment Rate Act of 2020 to increase the minimum wage and tiered payment scale for direct support workers to on average 120% of the District minimum wage or living wage.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-11-06</introduced>
    <effective>2024-12-12</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/54229/Signed_Act/B25-0565-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=199935">D.C. Law 25-232</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/54229/Signed_Act/B25-0565-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=199935">D.C. Act 25-589</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 12970</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0565">
      <vote date="2024-09-17" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2024-10-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-10-24</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 25-565 would establish a new credential for direct care workers to replace the home health aide and certified nursing assistant certifications. It would also eliminate barriers to certified apprenticeship programs for direct care workers and lower the age requirement for direct care workers to 16 years of age.  It allows those certified in Maryland or Virginial to practice in the District and establishes a minimum wage for direct support services. </summary>
      <committee>Health</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Certified Nurse Aide Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§3-1202.04">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 204 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1202.04) is amended by adding a new subsection (h) to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(g)" num-value="(h)"/>
          <num>(h)</num>
          <text>Within 6 months of the effective date of this subsection, the Board shall provide recommendations to the Mayor for their consideration in developing and issuing rules governing nursing assistive personnel with the title of certified nurse aide, as described under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1209.07|(d)">section 907(d)</code-cite>, in accordance with guidelines approved by the Advisory Committee on Certified Nurse Aides and Nursing Assistive Personnel.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§3-1209.07">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 907 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1209.07) is amended by adding subsection (d) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(c)" num-value="(d)"/>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|I">Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>, issue rules setting forth the standards of education and experience required to qualify as a certified nurse aide, which shall include:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Combining the registration or certification process for nurse aides and home-health aides into one profession, which shall bear the title of certified nurse aide;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Establishing a transition process to ensure a person registered or certified in the District as a nurse aide or home-health aide before the effective date of this subsection shall be authorized to practice and represent themselves as a certified nurse aide; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Creating a temporary license that would authorize a person licensed or certified and in good standing as a nurse aide or equivalent in Maryland or Virginia to practice as a certified nurse aide in the District; provided, that within 5 business days of the Board of Nursing receiving a complete application for a temporary license, the Department of Health shall notify the applicant of:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>The temporary license being approved; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>The reasons why the application was denied and the necessary steps for approval.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section codify:path="7|7A|IV">
    <num>3</num>
    <text>The Department of Health Functions Clarification Act of 2001, effective October 1, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 7-743.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended by adding a new section 4949b to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <codify:insert after="§7-743.10" num-value="7-743.11" history-prefix="as added"/>
        <num>4949b</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Advisory Committee on Certified Nurse Aides and Nursing Assistive Personnel.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>There is established an Advisory Committee on Certified Nurse Aides and Nursing Assistive Personnel ("Committee"), which shall consist of the following 5 members:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>An individual who has experience working as a home-health aide or a certified nurse aide;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Two representatives of providers licensed in the District to provide certified nurse aide services, one of which shall represent home-health agencies and one of which shall represent certified nurse aide providers;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>One representative from entities approved to train certified nurse aides; and "(4) One representative from the Department of Health.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>The Committee shall develop and submit recommendations to the Board of Nursing for the certification of certified nurse aides. The guidelines shall set forth the education and competency-based standards for certification, consistent with the requirements established under 42 C.F.R. § 483.152 and 42 C.F.R. § 484.80.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>The Committee shall review barriers to the development and support of on-the-job training programs and registered apprenticeship programs of certified nurse aides, including certified nurse aides seeking advance credentials, and shall make recommendations on eliminating such barriers.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>The Committee shall sunset 2 years after its first meeting.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History" path="§4949b">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4949b</annotation>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text>The Direct Support Professional Payment Rate Act of 2020, effective April 16, 2020 (D.C. Law 25-161; D.C. Official Code § 4-2001 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§4-2002|(a)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 3(a) (D.C. Official Code § 4-2002(a)) is amended by striking the numeral "117.6%" both times it appears and inserting the numeral "120%" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="2">
        <find>117.6%</find>
        <replace>120%</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§4-2004">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 5 (D.C. Official Code § 4-4004) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(a)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a) is amended by striking the numeral "117.6%" wherever it appears and inserting the numeral "120%" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="4">
          <find>117.6%</find>
          <replace>120%</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(b)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (b) is amended by striking the numeral "117.6%" both times it appears and inserting the numeral "120%" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="2">
          <find>117.6%</find>
          <replace>120%</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
    </para>
    <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 25-232" path="§4" applicability-path="§5|(a)" action="amendments to" display-template=""/>
    <codify:marginalia display="Not Funded"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 4 shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-232" path="§4" date="pending" history="false" display-template=""/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the provision identified in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
