<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-237" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-237</num>
  <num type="act">25-593</num>
  <num type="bill">25-277</num>
  <heading type="short">Landscape Architect Services Sales Tax Clarification Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend Chapter 20 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to clarify that landscape architecture services performed by a landscape architect licensed in the District or provided by a professional design firm that employs a landscape architect licensed in the District are exempt from sales tax.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-04-27</introduced>
    <effective>2024-12-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/52958/Signed_Act/B25-0277-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=200337">D.C. Law 25-237</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/52958/Signed_Act/B25-0277-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=200337">D.C. Act 25-593</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 12980</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0277">
      <vote date="2024-09-17" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2024-10-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-10-30</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 25-277 would clarify that landscape architecture services performed by a landscape architect, licensed in the District or provided by a design firm that employs a landscape architect licensed in the District, shall be exempt from the requirement to charge sales tax on the sale of or charges for the service of real property maintenance and landscaping. </summary>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Landscape Architect Services Sales Tax Clarification Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Chapter 20 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§47-2001|(n)|(1)|(M)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 47-2001(n)(1)(M) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Strike the phrase "and landscaping." and insert the phrase "and landscaping; except, that the sale of or charge for landscape architecture services shall be exempt pursuant § 47-2005(41)." in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>and landscaping.</find>
          <replace>and landscaping; except, that the sale of or charge for landscape architecture services shall be exempt pursuant <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2005|(41)">§ 47-2005(41)</cite>.</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(ii)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Sub-subparagraph (ii) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term "landscaping" means any activity of arranging or modifying areas of land and natural scenery for an improved or aesthetic effect; the addition, removal, or arrangement of natural forms, features, and plantings; or the addition, removal, or modification or retaining walls, ponds, sprinklers systems, or other landscape construction services.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 25-237" applicability-path="§3|(a)" display-template=""/>
      <!-- duplicate annotations created -->
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§47-2005">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section § 47-2005 is amended by adding a new paragraph (41) to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(40)" num-value="(41)"/>
          <num>(41)</num>
          <text>The sale of or charge for landscape architecture services as described in § 47-2853.116 performed by a landscape architect licensed in the District or provided by a professional design firm that employs a landscape architect licensed in the District.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 25-237" applicability-path="§3|(a)" display-template=""/>
      <!-- duplicate annotations created -->
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-237" path="§2|(a)" date="not funded" history="false" display-template=""/>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-237" path="§2|(b)" date="not funded" history="false" display-template=""/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
