<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-278">
  <num type="law">25-278</num>
  <num type="act">25-649</num>
  <num type="bill">25-752</num>
  <heading type="short">Automatic Voter Registration Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955 to remove the requirement that the Department of Motor Vehicles determine whether an individual is already registered or preregistered to vote before transmitting voter registration information to the Board of Elections, clarify the responsibilities of the Department of Motor Vehicles and Board of Elections with respect to changing a voter's information when an individual submits a change of name or change of address to the Department of Motor Vehicles, and make other conforming changes..</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2024-03-21</introduced>
    <effective>2025-03-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/55018/Signed_Act/B25-0752-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=203060">D.C. Law 25-278</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/55018/Signed_Act/B25-0752-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=203060">D.C. Act 25-649</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 15790</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0752">
      <vote date="2024-10-29" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2024-11-12" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-12-12</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Executive Administration and Labor</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Automatic Voter Registration Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 699; D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 7(c)(1) (D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.07(c)(1)) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (B)(i) is amended by striking the phrase "card by a person who is not already registered to vote or preregistered to vote in the District" and inserting the word "card" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (F) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Sub-subparagraphs (i), (ii), and (iii) are amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="3">
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>If a person submits a change of name or address notice to the DMV, such application shall be considered notification to the Board of the change of name or address. If the person who submits the notice is already registered or preregistered to vote or on the preapproved for registration list, and the information provided in the notice differs from the person's name, residence address, or mailing address on the voter roll or preapproved for registration list, the Board shall use the information provided in the notice to update the person's record pursuant to sub-subparagraph (iv) of this subparagraph.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>If the Board determines that information transmitted by the DMV pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(D) of this section or  section 7b(a) or by the Department of Health Care Finance pursuant to section 7b(b), indicates that a person who is already registered or preregistered to vote or who is on the preapproved for registration list has supplied a name, residence address, or mailing address to the DMV or the Department of Health Care Finance that differs from the person's name, residence address, or mailing address on file with the Board, the Board shall use the information provided by the DMV or the Department of Health Care Finance to update the person's record pursuant to sub-subparagraph (iv) of this subparagraph.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iii)</num>
              <text>If the Board determines that information transmitted by a government agency designated pursuant to section 7b(c) or separately designated pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(A) of this section indicates that a person who is already registered or preregistered to vote or who is on the preapproved for registration list has supplied a name, residence address, or mailing address as part of a transaction with the agency that differs from the person's name, residence address, or mailing address on file with the Board, the Board shall use the information provided by the agency to update the person's record pursuant to sub-subparagraph (iv) of this subparagraph.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Sub-subparagraph (iv) is amended by striking the phrase "shall change the voter roll or preapproved for registration list to reflect the change of name or address" and inserting the phrase "shall update the voter roll or preapproved for registration list to reflect the change of name, residence address, or mailing address" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Sub-subparagraph (v) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="3">
            <para>
              <num>(v)</num>
              <text>If the person returns the form described in sub-subparagraph (iv) of this subparagraph and indicates that the change to the voter roll or preapproved for registration list was in error, the Board shall immediately correct the person's previously updated information in the voter roll or preapproved for registration list.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (J) is repealed.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (L) is amended by striking the phrase "in this subsection," and inserting the phrase "in this subsection and section 7b," in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 7b (D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.07b) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "to vote, is not already registered to vote in the District, and" and inserting the phrase "to vote, and" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (d)(1) is amended by striking the phrase "the District, upon" and inserting the phrase "the District or has already been added to the preapproved for registration list, upon" in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of July 1, 2025.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
