<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-254" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-254</num>
  <num type="act">25-613</num>
  <num type="bill">25-570</num>
  <heading type="short">Cardiac Planning and Response (“CPR”) Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Public Access to Automated External Defibrillator Act of 2000 to define the term cardiac emergency response plan and to require schools to establish cardiac emergency response plans.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-11-09</introduced>
    <effective>2024-12-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/54272/Signed_Act/B25-0570-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=200408">D.C. Law 25-254</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/54272/Signed_Act/B25-0570-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=200408">D.C. Act 25-613</citation>
      <citation type="register">71 DCR 13502</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0570">
      <vote date="2024-09-17" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2024-10-15" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2024-10-28</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 25-570 would define and establish the term cardiac emergency response plan.</summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Cardiac Planning and Response ("CPR") Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Public Access to Automated External Defibrillator Act of 2000, effective April 27, 2001 (D.C. Law 13-278; D.C. Official Code § 7-2371.01 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§7-2371.01">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2371.01) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (1A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(1)" num-value="(1A)"/>
            <num>(1A)</num>
            <text>"CERP" means a cardiac emergency response plan, which is a written document that establishes the specific steps to be taken to reduce death from cardiac arrest in any setting, be it a school, community organization, workplace, or sports facility.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (2B-i) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(2B)" num-value="(2B-i)"/>
            <num>(2B-i)</num>
            <text>"Department" means the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§7-2371.02c">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 3c (D.C. Official Code § 7-2371.02c) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(a)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>The lead-in language is amended by striking the phrase "Within 120 days after the effective date of the Public Safety Telecomunicator and District School CPR and AED Training Amendment Act of 2016, passed on 2nd reading on June 21, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-669), each school" and inserting the phrase "Each school" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>Within 120 days after October 8, 2016, each school</find>
            <replace>Each school</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(1)">
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the semicolon and inserting the phrase ", and by the beginning of School Year 2025-2026 adopt and implement a CERP compliant with subsection (a-1)(1) of this section;" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>;</find>
            <replace>, and by the beginning of School Year 2025-2026 adopt and implement a CERP compliant with subsection (a-1)(1) of this section;</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(2)">
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (2) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <codify:replace/>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Have at least one AED on-site at the school in a location that is identified in the school's CERP and complies with guidelines set by the American Heart Association, American Red Cross, or another nationally recognized, evidence-based standard;</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(3)">
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase "guidelines and includes" and inserting the phrase "guidelines, is described in the school's CERP, and includes" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>guidelines and includes</find>
            <replace>guidelines, is described in the school's CERP, and includes</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(7)">
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "and provide them with the school's CERP." in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>.</find>
            <replace>and provide them with the school's CERP.</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new subsection (a-1) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(a)" num-value="(a-1)"/>
            <num>(a-1)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The Department, in collaboration with the Office of the State Superintendent of Education and other stakeholders as needed, shall develop, maintain, and make accessible to schools a model CERP that addresses the appropriate use of school personnel and protocols for responding to incidents involving an individual experiencing cardiac arrest while on school grounds, specifically including during a school's athletic events and practices on school grounds.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The model CERP shall:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Integrate evidence-based core elements, such as those recommended by the American Heart Association, American Red Cross, or other nationally recognized evidence-based core elements; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Include guidance on the following components:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(i)</num>
                  <text>Establishing a cardiac emergency response team that includes the individuals referenced in subsection (a)(5) of this section and members' contact information;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(ii)</num>
                  <text>Activating the cardiac emergency response team in response to an incident of cardiac arrest;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(iii)</num>
                  <text>Appropriately locating AEDs and performing routine maintenance, as required by subsection (a)(2) and (3) of this section;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(iv)</num>
                  <text>Maintaining ongoing staff training in CPR and AED use in accordance with subsection (a)(5) of this section;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(v)</num>
                  <text>Practicing CERP protocols through the use of drills;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(vi)</num>
                  <text>Protocols for communicating with the Department and other emergency medical services in response to an incident of cardiac arrest; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(vii)</num>
                  <text>Regular annual review and evaluation of the CERP.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(b)">
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Subsection (b) is amended by adding a new paragraph (1A) to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(1)" num-value="(1A)"/>
            <num>(1A)</num>
            <text>The Mayor shall establish a procedure for monitoring school adherence to the requirements set forth in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the district of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
