<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-325" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-325</num>
  <num type="act">25-695</num>
  <num type="bill">25-435</num>
  <heading type="short">Fraudulent Vehicle Tag and Parking Enforcement Modernization Amendment Act of 2024</heading>
  <heading type="long">To establish the Parking Enforcement Management Authority under the Department of Public Works; to establish authority and procedures governing parking enforcement, immobilization, and impoundment of motor vehicles, to define unidentifiable vehicles as motor vehicles to require the Mayor to issue rules to standardize agency use of license plate reader systems, and to protect sensitive identifying information, to create and maintain a directory of all license plates and temporary tags issued by U.S. states and territories, to create a vehicle infraction point system for the purposes of determining a vehicle's eligibility for immobilization and impoundment based on moving and parking violations and safety-sensitive violations, to establish procedures for the reclamation and disposal of impounded vehicles, to establish procedures for the identification, enforcement, and disposal of abandoned and dangerous vehicles, and to allow for a one-time defense of 15 days if a vehicle owner files a report for damage to the vehicle, and to authorize the Mayor to make rules; to amend the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982 to specify that the production and distribution of counterfeit or fraudulent temporary vehicle identification tags constitutes an offense of forgery, and to direct the Mayor and Attorney General to pursue investigations, enforcement, and prosecution against any person or dealership knowingly selling counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent vehicle identification tags to District residents; to amend the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937 to clarify standards for clear display of a vehicle identification tag, to forbid the use of a plate cover regardless of the legibility of the information on the vehicle identification tag, to specify unlawful actions regarding counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent vehicle identification tags, and to establish procedures for forgiveness of infractions issued to individuals as a result of violations incurred due to a counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent vehicle identification tag; and to amend the District of Columbia Traffic Act of 1925 to create an opportunity for vehicle owners to cure violations related to an expired vehicle registration or identification tag and have any associated fines waived.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-07-14</introduced>
    <effective>2025-05-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53611/Signed_Act/B25-0435-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=206183">D.C. Law 25-325</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53611/Signed_Act/B25-0435-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=204907">D.C. Act 25-695</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 1284</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0435">
      <vote date="2024-12-03" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2024-12-17" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-01-24</enacted>
      <summary>FISCAL NOTE - This bill is Subject to Appropriations. Sections 113, 114, 121, 122(a)(2)(B), 202(b)(1)(B) and 302 are not funded. Please see the Fiscal Impact Statement for more information.</summary>
      <committee>Public Works and Operations</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Fraudulent Vehicle Tag and Parking Enforcement Modernization Amendment Act of 2024".</text>
  <!-- add <code-cite></code-cite> to sections 112(a)(2) and 125(b)(2) when funded -->
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="50" after="24" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
      <num>24A</num>
      <heading>Parking Enforcement Modernization.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>I</num>
    <heading>PARKING ENFORCEMENT MODERNIZATION</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>A</num>
      <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A" history="false">
        <container>
          <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
          <num>I</num>
          <heading>General Provisions.</heading>
        </container>
      </codify:insert>
      <section>
        <num>101</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Short title.</heading>
        <text>This title may be cited as the "Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024".</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="50|24A|I" num-value="50-2431"/>
        <num>102</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
        <text>For the purposes of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">this title</code-cite>, the term:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>"Abandoned vehicle" means any motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer that is left, parked, or stored on public space for more than 48 hours or on private property for more than 30 days, and to which at least one of the following applies:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The vehicle is apparently inoperable, including a vehicle missing its transmission, motor, or one or more tires, and is not undergoing emergency repair;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The vehicle serves as harborage for rats, vermin, and other pests; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>The vehicle does not display valid vehicle identification tags, a valid registration sticker, or is an unidentifiable vehicle; except, that a vehicle shall not be deemed an abandoned vehicle under this subparagraph solely because the vehicle displays expired tags or registration sticker, unless the tags or registration sticker expired at least one year before any enforcement action is taken under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">this title</code-cite>, which shall be measured concurrently with the period of time required to establish that the vehicle is abandoned, as described in the lead-in language of this paragraph.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>"Dangerous vehicle" means a motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer that, due to at least one of the following conditions existing for at least 24 hours, poses an imminent hazard to the public health, safety, or welfare:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The vehicle is extensively damaged, including damaged by fire or exposed broken glass or metal shards are present; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Another dangerous condition that poses an imminent hazard to the public health, safety, or welfare is present.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>"Department" means the Department of Public Works.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>"Director" means the Director of the Department of Public Works.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>"Immobilization device" means a device or mechanism that, when equipped to a motor vehicle, prevents the motor vehicle's operation but causes no damage to the motor vehicle unless the motor vehicle is moved while such device or mechanism is in place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>"Immobilization-eligible vehicle" means a vehicle that meets the requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2452">section 122</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>"Impounded" means a vehicle in the custody of the Department of Public Works or stored at a private storage facility at the direction of the Department as a result of the vehicle:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Having been removed from its location pursuant to District laws or regulations; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Having been transferred from the custody of the Metropolitan Police Department, or other agency, to the custody of the Department.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>"LPRS" means license plate recognition system, which is an electronic device that may be handheld, mounted on a vehicle, or positioned in a stationary location and is capable of recording data on, or taking a photograph of, a vehicle or its vehicle identification tag and comparing the collected data and photographs to existing databases for investigative and enforcement purposes.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>"Motor vehicle" shall have the same meaning as provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2301.02|(5A)">section 102(5A) of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2301.02(5A))</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>"Park" means to leave any motor vehicle standing on a public right-of-way, public space, or private space, either attended or unattended.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>"Parking violation" means a violation of:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Chapter 24 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.04a">Section 4a of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 680; D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.04a)</code-cite>;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2637">Section 6012 of the Unlawfully Parked Vehicles Act of 2015, effective October 22, 2015 (D.C. Law 21-36; D.C. Official Code § 50-2637)</code-cite>;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text><span codify:value="§§ ">Sections</span><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2454" codify:value="50-2454">124</code-cite> and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2462" codify:value="50-2462">132 of this act</code-cite>; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>Other parking, standing, and non-moving violations committed with a motor vehicle and adjudicated pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2303.01">section 301 of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2303.01)</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>"Physical characteristics of an abandoned vehicle" means any of the conditions set forth in paragraph (1) of this section.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>"Private property" means real property, including real property owned or under the jurisdiction of the District , other than public space.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>"Public right-of-way" means the surface, air space above the surface, and area below the surface of any public street, highway, bridge, tunnel, alley, or sidewalk.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>"Public space" means all the property owned or under the jurisdiction of the District, between lines on a street, as such property lines are shown on the records of the Surveyor of the District, and includes any public right-of-way, tree space, sidewalk, or parking between such property lines.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(16)</num>
          <text>"Safety-sensitive parking violation" means a stopping, standing, or parking violation that poses an immediate risk to the safety of users of public rights-of-way, including:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Obstruction of a crosswalk, sidewalk, alley, driveway, or intersection;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Stopping, standing, or parking in a fire lane, within 10 feet of a fire hydrant, or other violations that impact fire safety and emergency response;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Unauthorized stopping, standing, or parking in spaces reserved for individuals with disabilities;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Stopping, standing, or parking in a bus lane, bus parking zone, bicycle lane, or other shared use path; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>Other violations as determined by the Mayor.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(17)</num>
          <text>"Unidentifiable vehicle" means any vehicle found parked on any public right-of-way or public space in the District:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>That does not have a vehicle identification tag displayed or affixed to the vehicle;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>With an obscured or illegible vehicle identification number;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Displaying a counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent vehicle identification tag in the District;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Displaying a vehicle identification tag not identifiable in the directory required by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2444">section 114</code-cite>, or with a vehicle identification tag that can otherwise be clearly identified as counterfeit, altered, or otherwise fraudulent by visual inspection alone;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>Using any tinted, colored, painted, marked, clear, or illuminated object that:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Covers any of the characters of a vehicle's vehicle identification tag; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Distorts an image recorded by automated traffic enforcement or license plate recognition system of any of the characters of a vehicle's vehicle identification tag or other identifying features.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(F)</num>
            <text>Is obscured by a vehicle cover or tarp that obscures the vehicle identification tags; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(G)</num>
            <text>Has other characteristics that otherwise restrict the ability to issue the vehicle a notice of infraction for parking enforcement or automated traffic enforcement.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(18)</num>
          <text>"Vehicle" means motor vehicle.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(19)</num>
          <text>"Vehicle identification number" means a unique alphanumeric code or serial number used by the automotive industry to identify an individual motor vehicle when a vehicle is manufactured.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(20)</num>
          <text>"Vehicle identification tag" means:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>A permanent plate or tag issued by a jurisdiction containing letters, numerals, or a combination of both, attached to a motor vehicle, that serves as a unique identifier matching that motor vehicle; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>A temporary vehicle tag, dealer's tag, or manufacturer's tag issued in any jurisdiction for a vehicle awaiting issuance of permanent license plates.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </section>
    </container>
    <container>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A" after="I" history="false">
        <container>
          <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
          <num>II</num>
          <heading>Parking Enforcement Management Administration.</heading>
        </container>
      </codify:insert>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>B</num>
      <heading>PARKING ENFORCEMENT MANAGEMENT ADMINISTRATION</heading>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="II" num-value="50-2441"/>
        <num>111</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Parking Enforcement Management Administration.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>There is established a Parking Enforcement Management Administration ("PEMA") within the Department, the purpose of which is to provide:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>On-street parking enforcement services, including ticketing for parking violations, immobilization, and impoundment;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Removal of abandoned and dangerous vehicles; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Management of impounded vehicles.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>PEMA shall perform 3 primary organizational functions:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Removal of abandoned or dangerous vehicles from any public right-of-way, public space, or private property;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Enforcement of the District's parking regulations to promote vehicular safety and access to short-term parking at meters and long-term parking on residential streets; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Immobilizing and impounding immobilization-eligible vehicles on public space and relocating illegally parked vehicles impeding public rights-of-way.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="II" after="§50-2441" num-value="50-2442"/>
        <num>112</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Enforcement priority.</heading>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <text>The Director shall deploy Parking Enforcement Management Administration staff and resources to prioritize:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Unidentifiable vehicles, abandoned vehicles, and dangerous vehicles;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Vehicles eligible for immobilization and impoundment as a result of vehicle infraction points assessed pursuant to <span codify:value="§50-2451(b) [Not Funded]">section 121(b)</span>; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Safety-sensitive parking violations.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="II" after="§50-2442" num-value="50-2443"/>
        <num>113</num>
        <heading proof="needed">License plate recognition systems; usage and privacy.</heading>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <text>Within one year after the applicability date of this section, the Mayor shall issue rules to:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Ensure that all District agencies equipped with LPRS for enforcement of parking or moving violations utilize the same database of information;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Maximize the ability of District agencies equipped with LPRS to transmit information to the Department that may assist in identifying the location of immobilization-eligible vehicles;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Maintain reasonable security procedures and practices, including operational, administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect LPRS information from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>Implement a usage and privacy policy in order to ensure that the collection, use, maintenance, sharing, and dissemination of LPRS information is consistent with respect to individuals' privacy and civil liberties.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§113" applicability-path="§401" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="II" after="§50-2443" num-value="50-2444"/>
        <num>114</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Directory of vehicle identification tags.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>Within 90 days after the applicability date of this section, the Mayor shall establish, and thereafter maintain, a directory of all vehicle identification tags issued by U.S. states and territories.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall establish procedures for identifying tags as legitimate and ensure that all District employees tasked with enforcement of parking and moving violations are adequately trained in the proper verification of vehicle identification tags.</text>
        </para>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§114" applicability-path="§401" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
      </section>
    </container>
    <container>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A" after="II" history="false">
        <container>
          <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
          <num>III</num>
          <heading>Vehicle Immobilization and Impoundment.</heading>
        </container>
      </codify:insert>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>C</num>
      <heading>VEHICLE IMMOBILIZATION AND IMPOUNDMENT</heading>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="III" num-value="50-2451"/>
        <num>121</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Vehicle infraction points.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The Mayor shall establish a vehicle infraction point system for the purpose of determining a vehicle's eligibility for immobilization and impoundment.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>In addition to the infractions and offenses listed in subsection (b) and (c) of this section, the Mayor may enumerate new or additional categories of vehicle infractions and offenses and assign a corresponding point value based on the severity of the offense.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Vehicle infraction points imposed under this subsection shall be assessed in addition to any fines or points imposed against the driving record of an individual under 18 DCMR § 303.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Vehicle infraction points for convictions, sustained notices of infractions, including infractions detected by the automated traffic enforcement system described in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2209.01">section 901 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-198; D.C. Official Code § 50-2209.01)</code-cite>, or adjudications as a juvenile delinquent, within any consecutive 6-month period beginning after the applicability date of this section shall be assessed in accordance with the following table:</text>
          <text>
            <table>
              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>Infraction / Offense</td>
                  <td>Points</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Speeding 11-15 miles per hour over the speed limit</td>
                  <td>2</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Speeding 16-19 miles per hour over the speed limit</td>
                  <td>3</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Speeding 20 miles per hour or more over the speed limit</td>
                  <td>5</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Reckless Driving</td>
                  <td>5</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Aggravated Reckless Driving</td>
                  <td>10</td>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table>
          </text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>Vehicle infraction points for unpaid notices of infraction for parking violations and vehicle conveyance fees, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2301.02|(9)">section 102(9) of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2301.02(9))</code-cite>, that the owner was deemed to have admitted or that were sustained after a hearing, pursuant to <span codify:value="§§">sections</span> <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2301.05" codify:value="50-2301.05">305</code-cite> and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2301.06" codify:value="50-2301.06">306 of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code §§ 50-2301.05 and 50-2301.06)</code-cite>, shall be assessed in accordance with the following table:</text>
          <text>
            <table>
              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>Infraction / Offense</td>
                  <td>Points</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Safety-sensitive parking violation</td>
                  <td>3</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Expired motor vehicle tag or registration – under 60 days</td>
                  <td>1</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Expired motor vehicle tag or registration – 60 to 90 days</td>
                  <td>2</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Expired motor vehicle tag or registration – over 90 days</td>
                  <td>3</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>All other parking violations</td>
                  <td>1</td>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table>
          </text>
        </para>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§121" applicability-path="§401" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="III" after="§50-2451" num-value="50-2452"/>
        <num>122</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Vehicles eligible for immobilization or impoundment.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the following vehicles shall be deemed immobilization-eligible vehicles and subject to immobilization or impoundment as described in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2453">section 123</code-cite>:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Unidentifiable vehicles;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Vehicles parked on a public right-of-way or public space in the District against which:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>There have been issued 2 or more warrants;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>The Mayor has assessed 10 or more vehicle infraction points pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2451">section 121</code-cite>; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>There are 2 or more unpaid notices of infraction that the owner was deemed to have admitted or that were sustained after a hearing pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2209.02">section 902 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C, Law 11-198; D.C. Official Code 50-2209.02)</code-cite>; and</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num codify:value="[(3)]">(4)</num>
            <text>Abandoned or dangerous vehicles.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§122|(a)|(2)|(B)" applicability-path="§401" action="creation of subparagraph (a)(2)(B) in" display-template=""/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="III" after="§50-2452" num-value="50-2453"/>
        <num>123</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Immobilization and impoundment of immobilization-eligible vehicles.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The Department of Public Works, Metropolitan Police Department, United States Park Police, or the District of Columbia Department of Transportation is authorized to take the following actions against an immobilization-eligible vehicle:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Remove the vehicle from public space or private property pursuant to District law or regulation, through towing or other means, and transport the vehicle for impoundment; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Immobilize the vehicle using an immobilization device.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>A vehicle subject to impoundment pursuant to this section shall be taken to a District government impoundment facility or other facility as shall be determined by the Mayor.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="III" after="§50-2453" num-value="50-2454"/>
        <num>124</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Booting fee; penalty for damage or removal.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The owner of an immobilized vehicle shall be subject to a booting fee of no less than $100 for such immobilization.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Any person who damages, destroys, or removes a vehicle immobilization device without authorization of the Mayor shall be subject to a civil fine of no less than $900.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="III" after="§50-2454" num-value="50-2455"/>
        <num>125</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Immobilized and impounded vehicles; notice to owners and lienholders.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>In any case involving immobilization of a vehicle pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">this title</code-cite>, such law enforcement officer or employee shall cause to be placed on such vehicle, in a conspicuous manner, notice sufficient to warn any individual to the effect that such vehicle has been immobilized and that any attempt to move such vehicle might result in damage to such vehicle.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Before the removal of an immobilization device from a motor vehicle or the release of a motor vehicle from impoundment, the owner shall pay all outstanding fees, charges, civil fines, or penalties against the owner or any motor vehicle in which the owner has an ownership interest or had an ownership interest when a notice of infraction was issued</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>If the vehicle was immobilized or impounded with 10 or more vehicle infraction points assessed for violations pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2451" codify:value="§50-2451(b)">section 121(b)</code-cite>, or other moving violations as determined by the Mayor, the owner shall also provide evidence of completion of a safe-driving course created pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1405.02" codify:value="§50-1405.02(a)">section 9a(a) of the Motor Vehicle Services Fees and Driver Education Support Act of 1982, effective April 20, 2024 (D.C. Law 25-161; D.C. Official Code § 50-1405.02(a))</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>Except for vehicles disposed of pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2465">section 135</code-cite>, the Department shall send an impoundment notice, by first class mail, to the last known address of the owners of record of an impounded vehicle, and any lienholders of record, as that information is indicated in the records of the Department of Motor Vehicles or in the records of the appropriate agency of the jurisdiction where the vehicle is registered. If the vehicle was seized from private property other than real property owned or under the jurisdiction of the District, notice shall also be sent, by first class mail, to the owner of that property, as indicated in the records of the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>The impoundment notice required by subsection (c) of this section shall be mailed no later than 5 days after the vehicle is received at an impoundment or storage facility and shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Describe the year, make, model, and vehicle identification number of each vehicle;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Indicate the reason why the vehicle was impounded;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>If impounded for violating <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2462">section 132</code-cite>, indicate the nature of the violation;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>Advise the owner and lienholders of the procedures for reclaiming the vehicle and the applicable reclamation period for doing so; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>Warn the owner and lienholders that the vehicle will be sold, or otherwise disposed of, if those procedures are not completed by the expiration of the reclamation period.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>If the address of the owner or lienholders cannot be determined, the Department shall publish an impoundment notice in a newspaper of general circulation in the District within 10 days after a vehicle is received at an impoundment or storage facility. If the mailed notice is returned as undeliverable within 14 days after mailing, an impoundment notice shall also be published. The published notice may contain a listing of more than one vehicle and shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Describe the year, make, model, and vehicle identification number of each vehicle;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Provide a telephone number or website address that will inform the owner or lienholders of the vehicle reclamation procedures; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Indicate the date by which the vehicle must be reclaimed.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(f)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2302.05">section 205 of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2302.05) ("section 205")</code-cite>, the mailing of the impoundment notice shall constitute service of the notice of infraction for violations of this title. The notice of infraction shall be considered issued, within the meaning of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2302.05">section 205</code-cite>, on the 5th day after the impoundment notice is mailed.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(g)</num>
          <text>The Director shall determine whether each impounded vehicle has been reported to law enforcement agencies as stolen and shall record the vehicle identification number for each impounded vehicle in a database format that can be accessed by law enforcement personnel.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="III" after="§50-2455" num-value="50-2456"/>
        <num>126</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Vehicle reclamation periods.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>An impounded vehicle removed from public or private property pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">this title</code-cite>, or any other District law or regulation, must be reclaimed within 28 days after the impoundment notice sent pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2455|(c)">section 125(c)</code-cite>, or other time period established by the Mayor by rule.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>If the address of the owner and lienholders of an impounded vehicle is unknown, the vehicle must be reclaimed within 14 days after the publication date of reclamation notices published pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2455|(e)">section 125(e)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>The Director may provide for a one-time extension of the reclamation period for a vehicle if the owner of the vehicle shows proof of being enrolled in a safe-driving course created pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1405.02" codify:value="§50-1405.02(a)">section 9a(a) of the Motor Vehicle Services Fees and Driver Education Support Act of 1982, effective April 20, 2024 (D.C. Law 25-161; D.C. Official Code § 50-1405.02(a))</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="III" after="§50-2456" num-value="50-2457"/>
        <num>127</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Procedures for reclaiming impounded vehicles; lien; penalties.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>An owner or lienholder, or a person duly authorized by either, may reclaim an impounded vehicle stored at a District government impoundment facility at any time prior to the expiration of the applicable reclamation period described in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2456">section 126</code-cite>, by:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Satisfying the requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2455|(b)">section 125(b)</code-cite>;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Furnishing proof of entitlement to possession of the vehicle; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Paying to the District government, or the towing company, as directed by the Department, a towing fee of $100 and a storage fee of $20 per day; provided, that the towing fee shall be $275 and a storage fee of $20 per day shall be imposed if the size or the weight of the impounded vehicle requires the Department or an outside contractor to use special equipment to tow the vehicle; provided further, that the towing fee shall be $1,000 if the vehicle was impounded pursuant to a violation of 18 DCMR § 2405.3(e).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Fines and penalties due for parking tickets issued to a vehicle and the towing and storage fee charges due pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section shall constitute a continuing lien against the impounded motor vehicle. The lien thus created shall be an automatic lien, which is perfected as of the first date that the fines, penalties, or fees are due and shall be a prior and preferred claim over all other liens.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>Any person who has paid a fine for parking, storing, or leaving an abandoned or dangerous vehicle on public space, and who, after reclaiming the vehicle, thereafter again parks, stores, or leaves that vehicle on public space in violation of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2462|(a)|(1)">section 132(a)(1)</code-cite> of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">this title</code-cite>, shall be subject to a civil fine of not more than $500.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="III" after="§50-2457" num-value="50-2458"/>
        <num>128</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Disposal of unclaimed vehicles; penalties; auction admission fees.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The Department may, consistent with reasonable business practices, sell or otherwise dispose of an unclaimed vehicle, including all items of personal property left therein.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>If an unclaimed vehicle is sold at a public auction or through other means pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the purchaser shall take title to the vehicle free and clear of all liens and claims of ownership by others, receive a sales receipt, and be entitled, upon application and the payment of all applicable fees, to a certificate of title and registration; provided, that all other eligibility requirements are met.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>The Department shall retain the proceeds of the sale or disposition of any vehicle an amount that represents reimbursement for the costs of sale, the costs of towing and storing the vehicle, the costs of furnishing notice and other related enforcement activities, the payment of such liens as were declared null and void, and the remainder shall be deposited into the General Fund.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>Except for vehicles enclosed on private property or located on the property of a business engaged in the lawful repair, storage, salvage, or disposal of vehicles, any person who purchases a vehicle that has been sold for salvage only from the Department, and who, thereafter, leaves, stores, or parks the vehicle on public space or private property, shall be subject to a civil fine of not more than $2,500.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>The Director is authorized to establish a non-refundable cost-based auction admission fee. The proceeds from this fee shall be used to offset the costs of all vehicle auctions held on the day of the auctions. The proceeds from the fee shall be deposited into the General Fund.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="III" after="§50-2458" num-value="50-2459"/>
        <num>129</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Owners and lienholders remedy.</heading>
        <text>An owner or lienholder who fails to reclaim a vehicle within the time prescribed shall nevertheless be entitled to recover the fair market value of any vehicle disposed of pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A|III">this subtitle</code-cite> if:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The owner or lienholder requests a hearing with respect to the notices of infractions that provided the basis for the impoundment of the vehicle;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The hearing is requested within 60 days after the issuance of the notices of infraction;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>A hearing examiner dismisses the notices of infraction or finds no liability; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>The owner or lienholder establishes the vehicle's fair market value by a preponderance of the evidence; provided, that if the District has sold the vehicle, the price paid by a good faith purchaser, other than the owner, shall establish a rebuttable presumption of the fair market value of the vehicle.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
    </container>
    <container>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A" after="III" history="false">
        <container>
          <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
          <num>IV</num>
          <heading>Abandoned and Dangerous Vehicles.</heading>
        </container>
      </codify:insert>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>D</num>
      <heading>ABANDONED AND DANGEROUS VEHICLES</heading>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="IV" num-value="50-2461"/>
        <num>131</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Enforcement against abandoned and dangerous vehicles.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The Department shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Determine whether a vehicle is an abandoned or dangerous vehicle;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Determine whether the vehicle has been stolen, and if it has been stolen, relinquish custody of the vehicle to the Metropolitan Police Department;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Place or mail, as applicable, the appropriate warning notice described in <span codify:value="§§">sections </span> <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2463" codify:value="50-2463">133</code-cite> and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2464" codify:value="50-2464">134</code-cite>;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>Impound any abandoned or dangerous vehicle, if appropriate;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>Mail the impoundment notice required by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2455">section 125</code-cite> to the owner and lienholders of any impounded vehicle; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(6)</num>
            <text>Sell or dispose of unclaimed impounded vehicles, including all items of personal property left therein, pursuant to Subtitle C.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall use personnel who are charged with private or public space inspection, sanitation inspection, and traffic and parking enforcement responsibilities to investigate and place warning notices on abandoned and dangerous vehicles.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall encourage all District government agencies and residents to identify and report abandoned and dangerous vehicles to the Department.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="IV" after="§50-2461" num-value="50-2462"/>
        <num>132</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Unlawful acts.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>It shall be a violation of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|23">the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2301.01 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>, for any person to park or store:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>An abandoned or dangerous vehicle on public space;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Any motor vehicle on private property without the consent of the property owner; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>An abandoned or dangerous vehicle on private property, even with the consent of the property owner, unless the vehicle is:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Kept in a lawful enclosed structure or building completely shielded from the view of individuals on the adjoining properties; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Lawfully stored or kept on the property of a business engaged in the lawful repair, storage, salvage, or disposal of vehicles.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>It shall be a defense to a violation under subsection (a) of this section if the vehicle owner filed a report, including the time and date of the event, with the Metropolitan Police Department or the vehicle owner's insurer about the damage to the vehicle, prior to receiving the notice of infraction; provided, that such defense shall be valid for no more than 15 business days after the owner filed the damage report and may not be raised again after the expiration of the 15-day period for the same event or incident.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="IV" after="§50-2462" num-value="50-2463"/>
        <num>133</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Removal of abandoned and dangerous vehicles from public space; penalties.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The District government, or any towing company at the direction of the Department shall remove an abandoned or dangerous vehicle parked, left, or stored on public space in violation of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2462|(a)|(1)">section 132(a)(1)</code-cite> as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>An abandoned vehicle shall be removed 48 hours after a warning notice has been conspicuously placed on the vehicle. The warning notice shall be placed at the first sighting of a vehicle that meets the physical characteristics of an abandoned vehicle. The warning notice shall indicate the date and time it was placed and the date and time that the District is authorized to remove, impound, or dispose of the vehicle if the vehicle is not moved. The notice shall also include a statement indicating the vehicle will not be towed if the owner or other authorized person certifies to the Department that the vehicle is undergoing emergency repair. The notice shall provide a telephone number, and website if any, that will inform the owner how to accomplish the certification.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>A dangerous vehicle shall be immediately removed without the placement of a warning notice.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>If more than one basis exists for removing a vehicle, whether stated in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">this title</code-cite> or in any other law or regulation, the shortest removal period shall apply, including removal without a warning notice.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>No vehicle shall be removed from public space pursuant to this section until a notice of infraction is conspicuously placed on the vehicle.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>Except as provided in this section, it shall be unlawful for any person, except the owner, a person authorized by the owner in writing, an employee of the District government in connection with the performance of official duties, or a tow crane operator who has valid authorization from the District government, to do any of the following:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Tamper with, remove, or attempt to tamper with or remove any vehicle owned by another person;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Tamper with, remove, or attempt to tamper with or remove any vehicle that is on public space and to which a District government warning notice that relates to the removal of the vehicle has been affixed; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Remove, mutilate, or attempt to remove or mutilate the warning notice.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>Any person violating the provision of subsection (d) of this section shall be subject to a civil fine of not more than $500.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="IV" after="§50-2463" num-value="50-2464"/>
        <num>134</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Removal of abandoned, dangerous, and unlawfully parked vehicles from private property.</heading>
        <text>The District government or any towing company at the direction of the Department shall remove a motor vehicle parked, left, or stored, on private property in violation of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2462|(a)|(2)">section 132(a)(2)</code-cite> or <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2462|(a)|(3)" codify:value="(3)">(3)</code-cite>, as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>A vehicle parked, left, or stored without the consent of the property owner shall be removed immediately after a notice of infraction is issued and conspicuously placed on the vehicle.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A dangerous vehicle shall be removed, with or without the consent of the property owner, immediately after a notice of infraction is issued and conspicuously placed on the vehicle.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>An abandoned vehicle shall be removed, with or without the consent of the property owner, 45 days after a warning notice has been mailed by first class mail to the last known address of the property owner, as indicated on the records of the Office of Tax and Revenue. For the purposes of this subsection, notice may run concurrently with the period of time required to establish that the vehicle is abandoned.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The warning notice shall, at a minimum, indicate the make and model of the vehicle, the date that the vehicle was observed on the property, and the date that the District is authorized to remove, impound, or dispose of the vehicle if the vehicle remains unenclosed on the property.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>The warning notice shall be mailed after the first sighting of a vehicle that meets the physical characteristics of an abandoned vehicle. A notice of infraction shall be conspicuously placed on the vehicle prior to its removal. The notice shall also include a telephone number, and website if any, that will inform the owner how to contact the Department to certify that the vehicle is not abandoned.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="IV" after="§50-2464" num-value="50-2465"/>
        <num>135</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Post-removal disposition of certain vehicles without further notice.</heading>
        <text>Except for vehicles removed after traffic collisions, the Department may, without further notice, dispose of a dangerous vehicle or abandoned vehicle removed from the public space or private property pursuant to any District law or regulation if the vehicle does not display a valid vehicle identification number and recognizable registration.</text>
      </section>
    </container>
    <container>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A" after="IV" history="false">
        <container>
          <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
          <num>V</num>
          <heading>Rulemaking and Applicability.</heading>
        </container>
      </codify:insert>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>E</num>
      <heading>RULEMAKING AND APPLICABILTIY</heading>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="V" num-value="50-2471"/>
        <num>141</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Rulemaking.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|I">Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>, may issue rules to implement the provisions of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">this title</code-cite>, including:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Rules regarding towing, impoundment, and immobilization of vehicles in connection with enforcement of the District's parking restrictions;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Establishing the amount of, and implementing a system for collecting, a vehicle conveyance fee, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2301.02|(9)">section 102(9) of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2301.02(9))</code-cite>;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Establishing or modifying other cost-based fees that are within the scope of the Mayor's authority in order to implement the provisions of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">this title</code-cite>; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>Establishing additional categories of vehicle infraction points or modifying the schedules of vehicle infraction points enumerated in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2451">section 121</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>If the District enters into contracts with towing companies, or other contractors, that provide for such companies to receive full or salvage title to unclaimed vehicles, the Mayor may promulgate rules to implement the transfers consistent with the provisions of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">this title</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert path="V" after="§50-2471" num-value="50-2472"/>
        <num>142</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
        <text><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">This title</code-cite> shall apply to all vehicles immobilized or impounded after its applicability date.</text>
      </section>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading>FRAUDULENT OR OBSCURED VEHICLE TAGS</heading>
    <section>
      <num>201</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 679; D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.01 <em>et seq</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="§50-1501.01">
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Section 1 (D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.01) is amended by adding a new paragraph (13) to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(12)" num-value="(13)"/>
            <num>(13)</num>
            <text>The term "vehicle identification tag" shall have the same meaning as provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2431|(20)">section 102(20) of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Amendment Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§50-1501.02">
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.02) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(g)">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (g) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para codify:path="(2)">
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the term "who knowingly provides or obtains a counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent temporary identification tag; and" and inserting the phrase "who provides or obtains a counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent vehicle identification tag, regardless of the jurisdiction of issuance; and" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace count="1">
              <find>who knowingly provides or obtains a counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent temporary identification tag; and</find>
              <replace>who provides or obtains a counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent vehicle identification tag, regardless of the jurisdiction of issuance; and</replace>
            </codify:find-replace>
          </para>
          <para codify:path="(3)">
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (3) is amended as follows:</text>
            <para codify:path="(A)">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the phrase "DCMR; and" and inserting the phrase "DCMR;" in its place.</text>
              <codify:find-replace count="1">
                <find>DCMR; and</find>
                <replace>DCMR;</replace>
              </codify:find-replace>
            </para>
            <para codify:path="(C)">
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Subparagraph (C) is amended to read as follows:</text>
              <include lvl="2">
                <para>
                  <codify:replace/>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>To establish procedures, consistent with <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-325">the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</cite>, for the seizure and forfeiture of a motor vehicle used with a counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent vehicle identification tag; and</text>
                </para>
              </include>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iii)</num>
              <text>A new subparagraph (D) is added to read as follows:</text>
              <include lvl="2">
                <para>
                  <codify:insert after="(C)" num-value="(D)"/>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>To establish procedures for the forgiveness of infractions issued to individuals as a result of violations incurred because another individual falsified a vehicle identification tag associated with a vehicle registered in their name.</text>
                </para>
              </include>
              <aftertext>.</aftertext>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§50-1501.04">
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Section 4 (D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.04) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(a)|(4)">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a)(4) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <codify:replace/>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>For the owner of any motor vehicle to:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Use or permit the use of a motor vehicle with a counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent vehicle identification tag;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Use or permit the use of an unidentified vehicle, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2431|(16)">section 102(16) of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Amendment Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Use or permit the use of a vehicle in violation of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.04a">section 4a</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(a)">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A new paragraph (5) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(4)" num-value="(5)"/>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>For a person to make or copy a counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent vehicle identification tag.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§201|(c)|(2)" applicability-path="§401" action="amendment to" display-template=""/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>A new section 4a is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:insert path="50|15|I" after="§50-1501.04" num-value="50-1501.04a" history-prefix="as added"/>
            <num>4a</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Display of vehicle identification tags.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Vehicle identification tags shall at all times be securely fastened in a horizontal position to the vehicle or trailer for which they are issued and in a place and position to be clearly visible and legible.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>No insignia, emblems, brackets, holders, mounts, frames, trailer hitches, or couplings shall be mounted in such a way as to hide or obscure any portion of the vehicle identification tag or render any information on the vehicle identification tag illegible.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>No plate cover, glass, plastic, or any other type of material or substance shall be placed, mounted, or installed on or over any vehicle identification tag, regardless of the legibility of the information on the vehicle identification tag.</text>
            </para>
            <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 75-1-ch690" path="§4a">Aug. 17, 1937, 50 Stat. 679, ch. 690, title IV, § 4a</annotation>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section codify:path="§50-2303.05|(c-1)">
      <num>202</num>
      <text>Section 305(c-1) of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2303.05(c-1)), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>The existing text is designated as paragraph (1).</text>
        <codify:redesignate-para num-value="(1)"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (2) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(1)" num-value="(2)"/>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>A person admitting the commission of an infraction related to an expired motor vehicle registration or expired vehicle identification tag shall have the fine or penalty waived if the person includes in the answer definitive proof that the person cured the violation within 15 days after the issuance of the notice of infraction.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>III</num>
    <heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
    <section>
      <num>301</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Effect of the repeal of provisions.</heading>
      <text>Any repeal of a law or regulation by this act shall not invalidate any enforcement action, adjudication, or any other action made or taken pursuant to such law or regulation.</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>302</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Conforming amendments.</heading>
      <para codify:path="§22-2724">
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Section 6 of an Act For the suppression of prostitution in the District of Columbia, effective April 20, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-306; D.C. Official Code § 22-2724), is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(d)">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase "section 9(a)(6) of the Removal and Disposition of Abandoned and Other Unlawfully Parked Vehicles Reform Act of 2003, effective October 28, 2003 (D.C. Law 15-35; D.C. Official Code § 50-2421.09(a)(6)) ("Disposition Act")" and inserting the phrase section 127(a)(6) of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>
              <cite path="§50-2421.09|(a)|(6)">§ 50-2421.09(a)(6)</cite>
            </find>
            <replace>
              <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2457|(a)|(3)" codify:value="§50-2457(a)[(3)]">section 127(a)(6) of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>
            </replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(h)">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (h) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:replace/>
              <num>(h)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Vehicles that remain unclaimed may be disposed of pursuant to Subtitles C and D of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="I">Title I of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</cite>; provided, that if the owner wants to claim the vehicle before it is auctioned, the owner must pay the administrative civil penalty imposed by subsection (d) of this section in addition to the amounts required in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2457">section 127 of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§50-331">
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 2 of the Taxicab and Passenger Vehicle for Hire Impoundment Act of 1992, effective March 16, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-199; D.C. Official Code § 50-331), is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(d)|(4)">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (d)(4) is amended by striking the phrase "section 3 of the District of Columbia Abandoned and Junk Vehicle Removal Amendment Act of 1989, effective September 9, 1989 (D.C. Law 8-24; D.C. Code § 40-832)" and inserting the phrase "section 127 of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>
              <cite path="§50-2402">§ 50-2402</cite>
            </find>
            <replace>
              <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2457">section 127 of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>
            </replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(r)">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (r) is amended by striking the phrase "section 3 of the District of Columbia Abandoned and Junk Vehicle Removal Amendment Act of 1989, effective September 9, 1989 (D.C. Law 8-24; D.C. Code § 40-832)" and inserting the phrase "section 127 of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>
              <cite path="§50-2402">§ 50-2402</cite>
            </find>
            <replace>
              <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2457">section 127 of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>
            </replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Section 9a(a) of the Motor Vehicle Services Fees and Driver Education Support Act of 1982, effective April 20, 2024 (D.C. Law 25-161; § 50-1405.02), is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "safe driving practices and traffic regulations" and inserting the phrase "safe driving practices, parking, and traffic regulations" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace doc="D.C. Law 25-161" path="§2|includes|9a|(a)" count="1">
            <find>safe driving practices and traffic regulations</find>
            <replace>safe driving practices, parking, and traffic regulations</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (b)(1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <codify:replace doc="D.C. Law 25-161" path="§2|includes|9a|(b)|(1)"/>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The DMV may waive any outstanding fines for violations of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2201.04">section 9 of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (34 Stat. 1123; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.04)</code-cite>, or for violations of Chapter 24 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations based on an individual's participation in, and completion of, courses developed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>The District of Columbia Traffic Act of 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="§50-2201.03">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Section 6 (D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.03) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The section heading is amended by striking the phrase "; impoundment for outstanding violations".</text>
            <codify:find-replace path="heading" count="1">
              <find>; impoundment for outstanding violations</find>
              <replace/>
            </codify:find-replace>
          </para>
          <para codify:path="(k)">
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Subsection (k) is amended as follows:</text>
            <para codify:path="(1)">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Paragraph (1) is repealed.</text>
              <codify:repeal/>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Paragraphs (2) through (5) are repealed.</text>
              <codify:repeal path="(2)"/>
              <codify:repeal path="(4)"/>
              <codify:repeal path="(5)"/>
            </para>
          </para>
          <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§302|(d)|(1)|(B)|(i)" applicability-path="§401" action="amendment to subsection (k) paragraph (1) of" display-template=""/>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="§50-2201.04|(g)|(4)|(A)">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Section 9(g)(4)(A) (D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.04(g)(4)(A)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="2">
            <para>
              <codify:replace/>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Shall include a procedure to have the boot removed or the motor vehicle reclaimed from impoundment that is consistent with the requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">Title I of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>, and District government policy; and</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§50-2201.21">
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>Section 505 of the District of Columbia Traffic adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.21), is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="50|24|I">
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>The District of Columbia Abandoned and Junk Vehicle Removal Amendment Act of 1989, effective September 9, 1989 (D.C. Law 8-24, D.C. Official Code § 50-2401 <em>et seq.</em>), is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="50|24|II">
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>The Removal and Disposition of Abandoned and Other Unlawfully Parked Vehicles Reform Act of 2003, effective October 28, 2003 (D.C. Law 15-35; D.C. Official Code § 50-2421.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§50-2624">
        <num>(h)</num>
        <text>Section 2 of an Act To prohibit parking vehicles upon public or private property in the District of Columbia without the consent of the owner of such property, approved January 15, 1942 (56 Stat. 5; D.C. Official Code § 50-2624) is amended by striking the phrase "the Removal and Disposition of Abandoned Unlawfully Parked Vehicles Reform Act of 2003" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "Title I of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="3">
          <find><cite path="50|24|II">subchapter II of Chapter 24 of this title</cite> [<cite path="§50-2421.01">§ 50-2421.01</cite> et seq.].</find>
          <replace>
            <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">Title I of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>
          </replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The Scrap Vehicle Title Authorization Act of 2006, effective June 22, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-139, D.C. Official Code § 50-2701 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="§50-2701|(1)">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Section 2(1) (D.C. Official Code § 50-2701(1)) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <codify:replace/>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>"Abandoned vehicle" shall have the same meaning as provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2431|(1)">section 102(1) of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="§50-2702|(a)|(4)|(A)">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Section 3(a)(4)(A) (D.C. Official Code § 50-2702(a)(4)(A)) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="2">
            <para>
              <codify:replace/>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>The payment due for the towing charges and storage fees imposed pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2457">section 127 the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>;</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(j)</num>
        <text>Section 4 of the Strengthening Traffic Enforcement, Education, and Responsibility ("STEER") Amendment Act of 2024, effective April 20, 2024 (D.C. Law 25-161; 71 DCR 2248), is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a)(2) is repealed.</text>
          <codify:repeal doc="D.C. Law 25-161" path="§4|(a)|(2)"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Subsection (b) is repealed.</text>
          <codify:repeal doc="D.C. Law 25-161" path="§4|(b)"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <codify:marginalia display="DCMR"/>
        <num>(k)</num>
        <text>Section 2421 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection 2421.2 (18 DCMR § 2421.2) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <text>2421.2. The notice, reclamation, and disposition procedures set forth in Title I of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435) shall apply to any vehicle impounded under this section at a District government impoundment facility.</text>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection 2421.8 (18 DCMR § 2421.8) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <subsection>
              <num>2421.8</num>
              <text>The notice, reclamation, and disposition procedures set forth in Title I of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on first reading on December 3, 2024 (Engrossed version of Bill 25-435) shall apply to any vehicle impounded under this section at a privately operated storage facility.</text>
            </subsection>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>IV</num>
    <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
    <section>
      <num>401</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Sections 113, 114, 121, 122(a)(2)(B), 201(c)(2), and 302(d)(1)(B)(i) shall apply upon the date of inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§113" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§114" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§121" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§122|(a)|(2)|(B)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§201|(c)|(2)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
        <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 25-325" path="§302|(d)|(1)|(B)|(i)" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council for certification.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the provisions identified in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>402</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
      <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>403</num>
      <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
      <text>This act shall take effect after approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 60-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(2)).</text>
    </section>
  </container>
</document>
