<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-60">
  <num type="law">25-60</num>
  <num type="act">25-179</num>
  <num type="bill">25-327</num>
  <heading type="short">Green Housing Transition Temporary Amendment Act of 2023</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Green Building Act of 2006 to clarify the applicability of net zero energy requirements to housing projects already funded or in progress prior to the applicability of those requirements.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-06-14</introduced>
    <effective>2023-09-16</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53240/Signed_Act/B25-0327-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=168708">D.C. Law 25-60</citation>
      <citation type="register">70 DCR 11131</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0327">
      <vote date="2023-06-20" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2023-07-11" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-07-31</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Green Housing Transition Temporary Amendment Act of 2023".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 3(a)(3)(C) of the Green Building Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-234; D.C. Official Code § 6-1451.02(a)(3)(C)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="2">
      <para>
      <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1451.02|(a)|(3)|(C)"/>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Maintain net zero energy compliance; except, that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>This subparagraph shall not apply to residential projects selected by the District or a District Instrumentality for financing or land disposition for the purposes of providing rent or income-restricted affordable housing for tenants with designated household annual incomes if the District commits such assistance prior to December 31, 2023; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Nothing in this subparagraph shall be interpreted to allow housing projects to violate any other building energy mandate, including section 2(b) of the Clean Energy DC Building Code Amendment Act of 2022, effective September 21, 2022 (D.C. Law 24-177; D.C. Official Code § 6-1453.01(b)).</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1451.02|(a)|(3)|(C)"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1451.02" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on April 28, 2024. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1451.02(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
