<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-75" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-75</num>
  <num type="act">25-244</num>
  <num type="bill">25-372</num>
  <heading type="short">Family Re-Housing Stabilization Program Protection Temporary Amendment Act of 2023</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005 to establish grounds for an extension to the Family Re-Housing Stabilization Program, whereby the Department of Human Services or its designee will thoroughly consider the totality of the participant's circumstances, including their progress and eligibility for affordable housing.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-07-10</introduced>
    <effective>2023-11-28</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53499/Signed_Act/B25-0372-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=178046">D.C. Law 25-75</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53499/Signed_Act/B25-0372-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=178046">D.C. Act 25-244</citation>
      <citation type="register">70 DCR 13812</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0372">
      <vote date="2023-07-11" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2023-09-19" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-10-11</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Family Re-Housing Stabilization Program Protection Temporary Amendment Act of 2023".</text>
  <section codify:path="§4-753.01|(b)|(4)|(B)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 7(b)(4)(B) of the Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005, effective October 22, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-35; D.C. Official Code § 4-753.01(b)(4)(B)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The existing text is designated as sub-subparagraph (i).</text>
      <!-- <codify:redesignate-para num-value="(i)"/> -->
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>New sub-subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) are added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="3">
        <para>
        <!-- <codify:insert/> -->
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The Department, or the Department's designee, shall consider requests for Family Re-Housing Stabilization Program ("FRSP") assistance extending past 12 months if:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>There is funding available within FRSP;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>The participant has requested an extension in writing;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(III)</num>
            <text>The participant has made a good faith effort towards the achievement of goals set forth in an individualized plan with the aim of a targeted progression towards exit from the supports of FRSP, as observed by the service provider at consistent intervals, but cannot yet sustain housing stability independently of FRSP; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(IV)</num>
            <text>The participant has not yet been approved for permanently affordable housing.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
        <!-- <codify:insert/> -->
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>When making a determination of whether to grant a participant in FRSP an extension beyond 12 months, the Department or Department's designee shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>Consider the totality of the circumstances; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>Grant extensions of time in increments not greater than 6 months, with regular formal reviews every 3 months to ensure that participants are given the support necessary to exit FRSP with stable housing."</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
        <!-- <codify:insert/> -->
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>If a requested extension of FRSP assistance by a participant is denied, the participant shall be given 30 days written notice prior to the final subsidy payment explicitly setting forth the reason for the denial of additional assistance and inform the participant that the FRSP participant has a right to:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>Appeal the determination through a fair hearing and administrative review, including deadlines for requesting an appeal; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>The continuation of FRSP services pending the outcome of any fair hearing requested within 15 days of receipt of written notice of a termination.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.01"/>
      <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.01" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
          <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.01(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
        </codify:insert> -->
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of July 31, 2023.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
