<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-81" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-81</num>
  <num type="act">25-227</num>
  <num type="bill">25-386</num>
  <heading type="short">Vulnerable Youth Guardianship Protection Temporary Amendment Act of 2023</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, Chapter 3 of Title 13 of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide that publication may be substituted for personal service of process for appointments of a vulnerable youth guardian in certain circumstances; and to amend  Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code to authorize the Family Division of the Superior Court to appoint, modify, and terminate a new class of legal guardianship for vulnerable youth.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-07-10</introduced>
    <effective>2023-11-28</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53519/Signed_Act/B25-0386-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=178023">D.C. Law 25-81</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53519/Signed_Act/B25-0386-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=178023">D.C. Act 25-227</citation>
      <citation type="register">70 DCR 13754</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0386">
      <vote date="2023-07-11" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2023-09-19" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-10-11</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Vulnerable Youth Guardianship Protection Temporary Amendment Act of 2023".</text>
  <section codify:path="§13-336|(b)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 13-336(b) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="(7)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
      <!-- <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>; and</find>
        <replace>;</replace>
      </codify:find-replace> -->
    </para>
    <para codify:path="(8)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (8) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
      <!-- <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>.</find>
        <replace>; and</replace>
      </codify:find-replace> -->
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (9) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <!-- <codify:insert after="(8)" num-value="(9)"/> -->
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>actions for the appointment of a vulnerable youth guardian under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="16|23|VI">Subchapter VI of Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§13-336"/>
    <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§13-336" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§13-336(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert> -->
  </section>
  <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="16|23" after="V" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>VI</num>
      <heading>Vulnerable Youth Guardian.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert> -->
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The table of contents is amended by adding the following at the end:</text>
      <include>
        <container>
          <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
          <num>VI</num>
          <heading>Vulnerable Youth Guardian.</heading>
          <section>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.01</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
          </section>
          <section>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.02</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Guardianship petition.</heading>
          </section>
          <section>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.03</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Parties.</heading>
          </section>
          <section>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.04</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Timing and notice.</heading>
          </section>
          <section>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.05</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Conduct of hearings.</heading>
          </section>
          <section>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.06</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Adjudicatory hearings.</heading>
          </section>
          <section>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.07</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Order appointing a guardian of a vulnerable youth.</heading>
          </section>
          <section>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.08</num>
            <text>Effect of guardianship order</text>
          </section>
          <section>
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.09</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Additional available remedies.</heading>
          </section>
        </container>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new Subchapter VI is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <container>
          <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
          <num>VI</num>
          <heading>Vulnerable Youth Guardian.</heading>
          <section>
            <!-- <codify:insert path="16|23|VI"/> -->
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.01</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
            <para>
              <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
              <text>For purposes of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="16|23|VI">this subchapter</cite>, the term:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>"Guardian" means a person designated by the court pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="16|23|VI">this subchapter</cite> as the guardian of a vulnerable youth.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>"Guardianship order" means the court document that establishes legal guardianship and enumerates the guardian's rights and responsibilities concerning the care and custody of the vulnerable youth.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>"Noncitizen" means a person who is not a United States citizen.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>"Proposed guardian" means a person seeking to be appointed guardian of a vulnerable youth. The term "proposed guardian" includes a business or nonprofit entity, public corporation, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or other legal entity, whether or not a citizen or domiciliary of the District of Columbia and whether or not organized under the laws of the District of Columbia.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>"Similar basis" means conditions that have an effect on a vulnerable youth comparable to abuse, neglect, or abandonment, including the death of a parent.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>"Vulnerable youth" means an unmarried noncitizen who is at least 18 but younger than 21 years old.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <codify:temporary-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.01" interim-path="§16-2399" perm-eff="2024-07-19"/>
            <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.01" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
              <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024.*
      </text>
            </codify:insert> -->
          </section>
          <section>
            <!-- <codify:insert path="16|23|VI"/> -->
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.02</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Guardianship petition.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>A vulnerable youth or proposed guardian may file a petition with the Family Division of the Superior Court to appoint a guardian under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="16|23|VI">this subchapter</cite>. The petition shall name the proposed guardian and describe why:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The appointment is in the best interests of the vulnerable youth;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Reunification of the vulnerable youth with one or both parents is not viable due to abuse, neglect, abandonment, or a similar basis under District law; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>It is not in the best interests of the vulnerable youth to be returned to the vulnerable youth's or vulnerable youth's previous parents' country of nationality or country of last habitual residence.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The court shall determine whether it is in the vulnerable youth's best interests that a guardian be appointed by considering the following factors:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The vulnerable youth's need for continuity of care and caretakers, and for timely integration into a stable home, taking into account the differences in the development and the concept of time of youth of different ages and nationalities;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The physical, mental, and emotional health of all individuals involved to the degree that each affects the welfare of the vulnerable youth, the decisive consideration in regard to this factor being the physical, mental, and emotional needs of the vulnerable youth;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>Access to stability, safety, supports or services to remedy the impacts of prior abuse, abandonment, neglect, or a similar basis under District law;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The quality of the interaction and interrelationship of the vulnerable youth with his or her parents, siblings, relatives, and caretakers, including the proposed guardian; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>The vulnerable youth's opinion of their own best interest.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <codify:temporary-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.02" interim-path="§16-2399" perm-eff="2024-07-19"/>
            <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.02" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
              <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024.*
      </text>
            </codify:insert> -->
          </section>
          <section>
            <!-- <codify:insert path="16|23|VI"/> -->
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.03</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Parties.</heading>
            <text proof="needed">Parties to a guardianship proceeding shall be the vulnerable youth, the proposed guardian, and the vulnerable youth's parents. The court may, at its discretion, on its own motion, or in response to a motion for joinder or intervention, join additional parties to a guardianship proceeding.</text>
            <codify:temporary-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.03" interim-path="§16-2399" perm-eff="2024-07-19"/>
            <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.03" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
              <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024.*
      </text>
            </codify:insert> -->
          </section>
          <section>
            <!-- <codify:insert path="16|23|VI"/> -->
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.04</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Timing and notice.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>When a petition for guardianship is filed, the court shall promptly set a time for an adjudicatory hearing, as soon as administratively possible, shall cause notice thereof to be given to all parties and their attorneys.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>When it is appropriate to the proper disposition of the case, the court may direct the service of a summons upon other persons.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>If personal service under this section cannot be effected, then notice shall be made constructively pursuant to rules of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
            </para>
            <codify:temporary-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.04" interim-path="§16-2399" perm-eff="2024-07-19"/>
            <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.04" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
              <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024.*
      </text>
            </codify:insert> -->
          </section>
          <section>
            <!-- <codify:insert path="16|23|VI"/> -->
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.05</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Conduct of the hearings.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>All hearings and proceedings conducted pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="16|23|VI">this subchapter</cite> shall be held by a judge, without a jury.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>All hearings and proceedings conducted pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="16|23|VI">this subchapter</cite> shall be recorded by appropriate means.</text>
            </para>
            <codify:temporary-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.05" interim-path="§16-2399" perm-eff="2024-07-19"/>
            <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.05" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
              <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024.*
      </text>
            </codify:insert> -->
          </section>
          <section>
            <!-- <codify:insert path="16|23|VI"/> -->
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.06</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Adjudicatory hearings.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The court shall begin the adjudicatory hearing by determining whether all parties are present and whether proper notice of the hearing has been given.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>All parties have the right to present evidence and cross-examine witnesses.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The court shall hear evidence presented by the proposed guardian or vulnerable youth and the burden of proof shall rest upon the proposed guardian or vulnerable youth.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>Every party shall have the right to present evidence, to be heard on his or her own behalf, and to cross-examine witnesses called by another party.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>All evidence which is relevant, material, and competent to the issues before the court shall be admitted.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§14-306">14-306</cite> and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§14-307">14-307</cite>, neither the spouse or domestic partner privilege nor the physician/client or mental health professional/client privilege shall be a ground for excluding evidence in any proceeding brought under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="16|23|VI">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(g)</num>
              <text>The court may enter, modify, or terminate a guardianship order after considering all of the evidence presented, and after making a determination based upon a preponderance of the evidence that creation, modification, or termination of the guardianship order is in the vulnerable youth's best interests. If the court does not find that sufficient grounds exist to create, modify, or terminate a guardianship order, the petition may be dismissed.</text>
            </para>
            <codify:temporary-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.06" interim-path="§16-2399" perm-eff="2024-07-19"/>
            <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.06" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
              <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024.*
      </text>
            </codify:insert> -->
          </section>
          <section>
            <!-- <codify:insert path="16|23|VI"/> -->
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.07</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Order appointing a guardian of a vulnerable youth.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>After consideration of all the relevant, material, and competent evidence, the court shall issue an order establishing a guardianship if the court finds that the guardianship is in the vulnerable youth's best interests.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>After the guardianship is established, upon request by the proposed guardian or the vulnerable youth, the court shall, if the court finds that the allegations in the petition pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.02|(a)">§16-2399.02(a)</cite> are supported by a preponderance of the evidence, enter a guardianship order containing the following judicial determinations supported by relevant statutory citations and findings of fact:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Where the identity is known, the specific identity of the parent or parents;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>That the vulnerable youth is dependent on the court and has been placed under the care and custody of an individual or entity appointed by the court through the appointment of a guardian;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>That reunification of the vulnerable youth with one or both parents is not viable due to abuse, abandonment, neglect, or similar basis under District law; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>That it is not in the best interest of the vulnerable youth to be returned to the vulnerable youth or vulnerable youth's parents' country of nationality or last habitual residence.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The court may, upon motion of a party, modify or terminate a guardianship order when the modification or termination of the guardianship order is in the vulnerable youth's best interests.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The entry of a guardianship order under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="16|23|VI">this subchapter</cite> shall not impinge on the vulnerable youth's fundamental rights to make their own medical, educational, financial, or other such decisions.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>A guardianship order entered under this subchapter shall automatically terminate when the youth reaches age 21.</text>
            </para>
            <codify:temporary-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.07" interim-path="§16-2399" perm-eff="2024-07-19"/>
            <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.07" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
              <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024.*
      </text>
            </codify:insert> -->
          </section>
          <section>
            <!-- <codify:insert path="16|23|VI"/> -->
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2399.08</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Effect of guardianship order.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Unless the court specifies other rights and responsibilities, the guardian shall have the following rights and responsibilities concerning the vulnerable youth:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The guardian shall ensure that the legal rights of the vulnerable youth are not violated;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The guardian shall provide care and support to the vulnerable youth to promote the youth's stability and wellness; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The guardianship will promote the physical, mental, and emotional health of the vulnerable youth.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The guardian is not liable to third persons by reason of the relationship for acts of the vulnerable youth.</text>
            </para>
            <codify:temporary-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.08" interim-path="§16-2399" perm-eff="2024-07-19"/>
            <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.08" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
              <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024.*
      </text>
            </codify:insert> -->
          </section>
          <section>
            <!-- <codify:insert path="16|23|VI" num-value="[16-2399.09]"/> -->
            <prefix>§</prefix>
            <num>16-2409</num>
            <heading proof="needed">Additional available remedies.</heading>
            <para>
              <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
              <text>Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to prevent:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A proposed guardian or vulnerable youth from seeking any other remedy or protections available under District law; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The court from issuing judicial determinations similar to those in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-2399.07|(b)">§16-2399.07(b)</cite> in any other proceeding concerning a noncitizen under age 18.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <codify:temporary-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§[16-2399.09]" interim-path="§16-2399" perm-eff="2024-07-19"/>
            <!-- <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§[16-2399.09]" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
              <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on July 10, 2024.*
      </text>
            </codify:insert> -->
          </section>
        </container>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
