<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 25-91" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="law">25-91</num>
  <num type="act">25-287</num>
  <num type="bill">25-290</num>
  <heading type="short">Industrial Safety Act Clarification Amendment Act of 2023</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend An Act To protect the lives and health and morals of women and minor workers in the District of Columbia, and to establish a Minimum Wage Board, and define its powers and duties, and to provide for the fixing of minimum wages for such workers, and for other purposes to clarify the definition of "employer".</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2023-05-12</introduced>
    <effective>2023-12-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53011/Signed_Act/B25-0290-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=179114">D.C. Law 25-91</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/53011/Signed_Act/B25-0290-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=179114">D.C. Act 25-287</citation>
      <citation type="register">70 DCR 14506</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B25-0290">
      <vote date="2023-09-19" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2023-10-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-10-30</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 25-290 would establish a Minimum Wage Board, define its powers and duties, and provide for the fixing of minimum wages for workers particularly women and minor workers. It also clarifies the definition of employer. </summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Industrial Safety Act Clarification Amendment Act of 2023".</text>
  <section codify:path="ยง32-802|(1)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 2(a) of Title II of An Act To protect the lives and health and morals of women and minor workers in the District of Columbia, and to establish a Minimum Wage Board, and define its powers and duties, and to provide for the fixing of minimum wages for such workers, and for other purposes, approved October 14, 1941 (55 Stat. 738; D.C. Official Code ยง 32-802(1)), is amended by striking the phrase "District of Columbia or any instrumentality thereof" and inserting the phrase "District of Columbia, its agencies or instrumentalities, or any employee thereof acting within the scope of the employee's official duties" in its place.</text>
    <codify:find-replace count="1">
      <find>District of Columbia or any instrumentality thereof</find>
      <replace>District of Columbia, its agencies or instrumentalities, or any employee thereof acting within the scope of the employee's official duties</replace>
    </codify:find-replace>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of September 1, 2010.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
