<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-206</num>
  <heading>Board member qualifications; term of office; chairperson; conflict of interest.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each member of the Board shall be a resident of the District for at least 3 years immediately preceding his or her appointment and, during that period, have claimed a principal residence nowhere else.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No member of the Board shall hold any other full-time employment with the District government during his or her term of service on the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each member of the Board shall have a demonstrated record of substantial involvement in issues related to the community impact of licensed establishments before his or her appointment to the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All appointments shall be for a term of 4 years, except appointments made for the remainder of unexpired terms. Vacancies caused by death, resignation, or otherwise shall be filled by the Mayor, with the advice and consent of the Council, under <cite path="§25-201">§ 25-201</cite>. The Mayor may remove a board member for just and reasonable cause.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Board members may be reappointed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, with the advice and consent of the Council as provided by 25-201, shall appoint one member of the Board as chairperson.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The chairperson shall have a demonstrated knowledge of the laws and  regulations relating to the sale and delivery of alcoholic beverages in the  District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>No member or employee of the Board, directly or indirectly, individually, or as a member of a partnership, association, or limited liability company, or a shareholder in a corporation, shall have any interest in selling, transporting, or storing alcoholic beverages, or receive a commission or profit from any person licensed under this title to sell alcoholic beverages; provided, that a Board member or employee may purchase, transport, or keep in his or her possession an alcoholic beverage for his or her personal use or the use of the members of his or her family or guests.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Former board members may not represent a client before the Board for a period of one year following their service on the Board. Former board members may appear before the Board as an applicant for licensure, a protestant, or a witness during a protest hearing during this time period. This provision shall be applicable to future board members and for board members who are serving on the Board on May 3, 2001.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Jan. 24, 1934, 48 Stat. 321, ch. 4, §§ 4, 5</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Apr. 20, 1948, 62 Stat. 176, ch. 217, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Oct. 28, 1949, 63 Stat. 972, ch. 782, title XI, § 1106(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 3205(h), 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-157" type="History">Sept. 29, 1982, D.C. Law 4-157, § 15, 29 DCR 3617</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-51" type="History">Mar. 8, 1984, D.C. Law 5-51, § 2(b)(1), 30 DCR 5927</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-119" type="History">Sept. 26, 1984, D.C. Law 5-119, § 2, 31 DCR 4040</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-159" type="History">Mar. 14, 1985, D.C. Law 5-159, § 25(a), 32 DCR 30</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-122" type="History">May 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-122, § 2(b), 41 DCR 1658</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., §§ <cite path="§25-104">25-104</cite>, <cite path="§25-105" proof="true">25-105</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 25-206.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§25-201">§ 25-201</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
