<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-374</num>
  <heading>Transfer of location of establishments which permit nude dancing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A license under <cite path="§25-371|(b)">§ 25-371(b)</cite> may only be transferred to a location in the Central Business District or, if the licensee is currently located in a CM or M-zoned district, transferred within the same CM or M-zoned district, as identified in the zoning regulations of the District of Columbia and shown in the official atlases of the Zoning Commission of the District of Columbia; provided, that no license shall be transferred to any premises which is located:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Six hundred feet or less from another licensee operating under <cite path="§25-371|(b)">§ 25-371(b)</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Six hundred feet from a building with a certificate of occupancy for  residential use or a lot or building with a permit from the Department of  Consumer and Regulatory Affairs for residential construction at the premises.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>On or after January 1, 2013, a class CN license with a nude dancing endorsement under <cite path="§25-371|(b)">§ 25-371(b)</cite> shall not be transferred into Ward 5, as defined by [<cite path="§1-1041.03">§ 1-1041.03</cite>]; provided, that this section shall not prohibit the transfer of an existing CN license with a nude dancing endorsement within Ward 5.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding the restrictions of subsection (a) and (a)(1) of this section, but subject to the provisions in subsection (a)(2) of this section, if a licensee was located in a CM or M-zoned district, in or within 2000 feet of the footprint of the Ballpark, as of January 1, 2006, or was located within the Skyland Development Project site as described in <cite path="§2-1219.19|(c)|(1)" proof="true">§ 2-1219.19(c)(1)</cite> [repealed], as of January 1, 2007, then within one year of [October 18, 2007] a license may be transferred to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A location in any CM or M-zoned district, if the licensee was located in a CM or M-zoned district, respectively, as identified in the zoning regulations of the District of Columbia and shown in the official atlases of the Zoning Commission of the District of Columbia;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A location in any CM-zoned district, if the licensee was located within the Skyland Development Project site; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>In any C-3, C-4, or C-5 zone within 5000 feet from the Ballpark footprint.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term “Ballpark” shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§47-2002.05|(a)|(1)|(A)">§ 47-2002.05(a)(1)(A)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No more than 2 licensees may be transferred to any one ward pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Licensees transferring to a C-4 zone shall not count against the ward limitations set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision, licensees relocating pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall not locate within 1,200 feet from each other.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>No portion of any establishment granted a license pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be located within 600 feet of a church, school, library, playground, or the area under the jurisdiction of the Commission of Fine Arts pursuant to §§ <cite path="§6-611.01">6-611.01</cite> — <cite path="§6-611.02">6-611.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>All licensees shall consult the Advisory Neighborhood Commission in the area where the license is transferred pursuant to subsection (b) of this section regarding entering a settlement agreement with the community.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a license under subsection (b) of this section shall not be transferred prior to November 1, 2007, or to a location that has been rezoned by that date to a residential, C-1, or C-2 zoning district classification as identified in the Zoning Regulations of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-24" type="History">Oct. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-24, § 2, 54 DCR 8011</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(l), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(l) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of (a-1) and amendment of (f), see § 2(l) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-597, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1001).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Moratorium on Establishments Which Permit Nude Dancing Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-302, February 21, 2012,  59 DCR 1671).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-129">D.C. Law 19-129</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a-1) Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, no class CN license with nude dancing shall be issued in or transferred into Ward 5, as defined by <cite path="§1-1041.03">§ 1-1041.03</cite>; provided, that this section shall not prohibit the transfer of an existing CN license with nude dancing within Ward 5.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-129">D.C. Law 19-129</cite> added subsec. (a-1) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-310">D.C. Law 19-310</cite> added (a-1); and substituted “settlement agreement” for “voluntary agreement” in (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-24">D.C. Law 17-24</cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsecs. (b) to (g).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
