<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>39-115</num>
  <heading>Books from Birth program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Books from Birth program as a program of the District of Columbia Public Library (“DCPL”), to be administered by the Executive Director of DCPL.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Books from Birth program shall provide books to all children registered with the program, delivered to the residence of the child at the rate of one per month, from the month following the child’s birth or enrollment in the program to the child’s 5th birthday.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Executive Director shall make reasonable efforts to register every child under the age of 5 residing in the District who wishes to participate in the Books from Birth program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Executive Director may enter into such memoranda of agreement or understanding as necessary to ensure each family receives registration information upon the child’s birth.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the registration list shall be used solely for activities related to the Books from Birth program and shall not be sold or used for any other purpose.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Executive Director may use the registration list to conduct outreach and provide information about library programs and services, including those related to children, adult, or family literacy, or other educational or literacy material as DCPL considers useful to registered families.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Book titles for each age group shall be selected to reflect age-appropriate concepts and diversity of characters, culture, and authors.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Executive Director may enter into contractual and promotional agreements necessary to effectively implement the Books from Birth program.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 3, 1896, 29 Stat. 244, ch. 315, §  15</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">as added Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 4072, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 4072 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
