<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>39-202</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>As used in this chapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia established under § <cite path="§1-204.21">1-204.21</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term “Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia established under § <cite path="§1-204.01">1-204.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “Commission” means the Commission on the Arts and Humanities established by § <cite path="§39-203">39-203</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term “arts” includes, but is not limited to, music (instrumental and vocal), dance, drama, folk art, creative writing, architecture and allied fields, painting, sculpture, photography, graphic and craft arts, industrial design, costume and fashion design, motion pictures, television, radio, tape and sound recording, and the arts related to the presentation, performance, execution, exhibition of those major art forms, and the study and application of the arts to the human environment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The term “humanities” includes, but is not limited to, the study of the following: language, both modern and classical; linguistics; literature; history; jurisprudence; philosophy; archeology; comparative religion; ethics; the history, criticism, theory, and practice of the arts; those aspects of the social sciences which have humanistic content and employ humanistic methods; and the study and application of the humanities to the human environment with particular attention to the relevance of the humanities to the current conditions of national life.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The term “public art” means sculptures, murals, mosaics, bas-reliefs, frescoes, tapestries, monuments, fountains, environmental designs, and other visual art forms that are intended to enhance the aesthetic quality of a public building, park, street, or sidewalk or other public place with which they are physically or spatially connected. The term “public art” shall not include landscape design or the incidental ornamentation of functional structural elements or accessories unless designed by a visual artist as part of an artwork design authorized by the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The term “Fund” means the Arts and Humanities Enterprise Fund established by § <cite path="§39-205.01">39-205.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-22" type="History">Oct. 21, 1975, D.C. Law 1-22, § 3, 22 DCR 2083</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-125" type="History">June 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-125, § 2(a), 33 DCR 2945</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-42" type="History">Jan. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-42, § 2(a), 44 DCR 5577</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-2002.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 31-1902.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
