<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>39-203</num>
  <heading>Establishment; composition; terms; vacancies; compensation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In order to evaluate and initiate action on matters relating to the arts, to encourage programs and the development of programs which promote progress in the arts, there is established, in the Office of the Mayor, in the District of Columbia, a commission to be known as the Commission on the Arts and Humanities. The Commission shall consist of 18 members appointed by the Mayor, with the advice and consent of the Council, in accordance with § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>. Each member appointed to the Commission shall be a person who has displayed an interest or an ability in 1 of the various fields of the arts or humanities and/or has been active in the furtherance of the arts or humanities in the District of Columbia. Members shall be appointed to ensure that they are representative of all the various geographic areas and neighborhoods within the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Members of the Commission shall serve terms not to exceed 3 years, which shall regularly commence on July 1st in the year of appointment and expire on June 30th 3 years later. All terms shall be staggered so that 6 terms expire each year on June 30th beginning in 1982. Members may be reappointed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Should a vacancy occur, a successor shall be appointed by the Mayor within 30 days, with the advice and consent of the Council to serve until the end of the term of the member whom that successor succeeds. Failing to receive the nomination within the 30 days, the Council shall appoint a person to fill the vacancy. Members of the Commission on the Arts and Humanities established under Organization Order No. 74-4 of January 7, 1974, issued by the Commissioner of the District of Columbia, shall continue to serve until the members of the Commission established under this chapter are appointed and qualify. The Mayor shall nominate members to the new Commission within 30 days of October 21, 1975.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall nominate the Chairperson for the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Members of the Commission shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to receive, in accordance with applicable District of Columbia regulations, reimbursement for expenses incurred while actually performing duties vested in the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-22" type="History" path="§4">Oct. 21, 1975, D.C. Law 1-22, § 4, 22 DCR 2084</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-73" type="History">Mar. 10, 1982, D.C. Law 4-73, § 4(a), 28 DCR 5276</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 24, 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 1172, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Candidates for Commission on the Arts and Humanities, disclosure of interests, see § <cite path="§1-1106.02">1-1106.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mayoral nomination of Commission on the Arts and Humanities, review and approval of Council, see § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite> and § <cite path="§39-202">39-202</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-2003.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 31-1903.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “Council, in accordance with § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>.” for “Council.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</law-cite> deleted “but may not serve more than 2 consecutive terms” from the end of the last sentence in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  1172 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  1172 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  1172 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Former § 31-2003.1 1981 Ed., D.C. Law 4-73, § 4(b), provided as follows: “All official actions of the Commission on the Arts and Humanities taken by members appointed prior to March 10, 1982, are considered to be taken by a properly constituted Commission, regardless of the date of appointment and length of terms of its members.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
