<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>13-332</num>
  <heading>Service on infants; appointment and compensation of guardian and attorney.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When an infant is a party defendant in an action, the summons and complaint shall be served upon him personally and, when he is under 16 years of age, upon the person with whom he resides, if within the District. The infant shall be produced in court unless, for cause shown, the court dispenses with his appearance. The provisions of rules of court regarding guardians ad litem apply, and whenever in the judgment of the court the interests of an infant defendant require it, the court shall assign an attorney to represent the infant whose compensation shall be paid by the plaintiff, or out of the estate of the infant, at the discretion of the court.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An infant who secretes himself or evades service of process may be proceeded against as if he were a nonresident.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Whoever secretes an infant against whom process has issued, so as to prevent service of the process, or prevents his appearance in court, is liable to attachment and punishment as for contempt.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-241" type="History">Dec. 23, 1963, 77 Stat. 513, Pub. L. 88-241, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Condemnation of insanitary buildings, appointment of guardian ad litem in proceedings, see § <cite path="§6-909">6-909</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§13-340">13-340</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 13-332.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 13-332.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
