<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>23-554</num>
  <heading>Authorization for recovery of civil damages.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person whose wire or oral communication is intercepted, disclosed, or used in violation of this subchapter shall —</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>have a civil cause of action against any person who intercepts, discloses, or uses, or procures any other person to intercept, disclose, or use, such communications; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>be entitled to recover from any such person —</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>actual damages, but not less than liquidated damages computed at the rate of $100 a day for each day of violation, or $1,000 whichever is higher;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>punitive damages; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>a reasonable attorney’s fee and other litigation costs reasonably incurred.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Good faith reliance on a court order or legislative authorization shall constitute a complete defense to an action brought under this section or any other law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>As used in this section, the term “person” includes the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia shall not assert any governmental immunity to avoid liability under this section. Judgment against the District of Columbia shall not constitute a bar to action against any other person.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 626, Pub. L. 91-358, title II, § 210(a)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 23-554.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 23-554.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§23-556">§ 23-556</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Return of property by Property Clerk, see <cite path="§5-119.06">§ 5-119.06</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
