<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 13-159">
  <num type="law">13-159</num>
  <heading type="short">School Governance Charter Amendment Act of 2000</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2000-07-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/13-159.pdf">D.C. Law 13-159</citation>
      <citation type="register">47 DCR 2212</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B13-0469">
      <narrative>Law 13-159, the “School Governance Charter Amendment Act of 2000” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-469. The Bill was adopted on first, first amended and second readings on January 18, 2000, February 1, 2000 and February 17, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 1, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-295. The citizens of the District of Columbia voted on the legislation on June 27, 2000. The Board of Elections and Ethics certified (ratified) the results of the election on July 7, 2000. D.C. Law 13-159 became effective on July 7, 2000, pursuant to section 1 of the Public Law 106-226.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>RE-ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Charter of the District of Columbia to decrease the number of members of the District of Columbia Board of Education from 11 to 9, to create school districts consisting of compressed wards from which 5 members of the Board shall be elected, one of whom shall be elected President, with 4 members appointed by the Mayor, to delineate the authority of the Board of Education, to provide for a sunset of these provisions after 4 years with the composition and selection of the Board of Education to be made in accordance with local District law, and to authorize the Council to create a state education program. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "School Governance Charter Amendment Act of 2000 Sec. 2. Section 495 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 820; D.C. Code § 31-101(a is amended to read as follows Sec. 495. Board of Education a)(1) The Board of Education shall consist of 9 members. Four members shall be appointed by the Mayor and confirmed by the Council. Five members shall be elected. Four of the 5 elected members shall be elected from the 4 school districts created pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection. One member shall be elected at-large as the president of the Board 2) The 4 school districts for the election of Board members pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall be comprised of the 8 election wards created pursuant to section 2 of the Boundaries Act of 1975, effective December 16, 1975 (D.C. Law 1-38; D.C. Code § 1-1308 as follows A) Wards 1 and 2 shall comprise School District I B) Wards 3 and 4 shall comprise School District II C) Wards 5 and 6 shall comprise School District III; and D) Wards 7 and 8 shall comprise School District IV 3) The election of the members of the Board of Education shall be conducted on a nonpartisan basis and in accordance with the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 699; D.C. Code § 1-1301 et seq Codification District of Columbia Code RE-ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 4)(A) The Board of Education shall govern the public schools in the District of Columbia. The Board of Education shall establish policies, hire and evaluate a Superintendent who shall be responsible for the day-to-day operation of the public schools of the District of Columbia. The Board of Education shall have the authority to remove the Superintendent at any time for cause B) The Board of Education shall establish personnel policies and guidelines for the hiring of principals and other personnel by the Superintendent, but shall not have authority to make or approve personnel decisions or to negotiate with representatives of employee organizations C) The Board of Education shall approve an annual budget for submission to the Council that is consistent with the goals and objectives established by the Board of Education for the operation of the public schools of the District of Columbia b)(1) Subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section shall expire 4 years after the effective date of the School Governance Charter Amendment Act of 2000 2) As of the date specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, there shall be a Board of Education which shall be composed of and selected in such manner and for such terms as shall be provided by District law enacted pursuant to this title. There shall be a Superintendent of the public schools who shall be appointed by the Board of Education c) The Council may create a state education agency and may delegate to this agency the following responsibilities 1) Issuing rules to establish requirements to govern acceptable credit to be granted for studies completed at independent, private, public, and public charter schools and private instruction 2) Prescribing minimum amounts of instructional time for all schools in the District, including public, public charter, and private schools 3) Determining the content of basic standards used to assess all public school students where such assessments are required by law; and 4) Any other responsibilities not inconsistent with this Act Sec. 3. This act shall be subject to appropriation. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report prepared by the Committee on Education, Libraries and Recreation as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 5. This act shall take effect following ratification by a majority of the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia voting in a referendum held for such purpose and a 35-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 303 of the District of Columbia RE-ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3 Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-205 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
