<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 13-187">
  <num type="law">13-187</num>
  <heading type="short">Metrobus Ticket Transfer Amendment Act of 2000</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2000-10-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/13-187.pdf">D.C. Law 13-187</citation>
      <citation type="register">47 DCR 7073</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B13-0605">
      <narrative>Law 13-187, the “Metrobus Ticket Transfer Amendment Act of 2000,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-605, which was referred to the Committee on Local and Regional Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 26, 2000, and July 11, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 2, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-403 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-187 became effective on October 21, 2000.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the ticket transfer provision to make it applicable to the existing public transportation system, thereby permitting prosecution of persons who give a transfer ticket for Metrobus to someone else to use. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Metrobus Ticket Transfer Amendment Act of 2000 Sec. 2. An Act Authorizing certain extensions to be made of the lines of the Anacostia and Potomac River Railroad Company, the Washington Railway and Electric Company, the City and Suburban Railway of Washington, and the Capital Traction Company, in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes is amended as follows a) The first sentence of section 15 is amended to read as follows: “No transfer ticket or written or printed instrument giving or purporting to give the right of transfer to any person or persons from a rail transit car or from a public passenger vehicle with a capacity for seating 12 or more, owned or operated by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, which is transporting passengers in regular route service within the corporate limits of the city, shall be issued, sold, or given except to a passenger lawfully entitled thereto.” b) Section 17 is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase "Public Service Commission" and insert the phrase “Corporation Counsel” in its place 2) Strike the phrase “the Commission” and insert the phrase "the District of Columbia" in its place. Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813, D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Codification District of Columbia Code 2001 Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
