<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 13-227">
  <num type="law">13-227</num>
  <heading type="short">Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Special Education Student Funding Increase Non-service Nonprofit Provider Clarifying and Technical Temporary Amendment Act of 2000</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/13-227.pdf">D.C. Law 13-227</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 13-227, the “Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Special Education Student Funding Increase Non-service Nonprofit Provider Clarifying and Technical Temporary Amendment Act of 2000”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-858. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 3, 2000, and November 8, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 13, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-502 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-227 became effective on April 3, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend, on a temporary basis, the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula for Public Schools and Public Charter Schools and Tax Conformity Clarification Amendment Act of 1998 to increase funding for after hours needs of special education students attending District Public Schools or Public Charter Schools that provide students with room and board; and the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Act of 1999 to clarify that the Council must affirmatively approve the resolution submitted by the Mayor pursuant to section 2404, and to make a technical amendment. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Special Education Student Funding Increase Non-service Nonprofit Provider Clarifying and Technical Temporary Amendment Act of 2000 Sec. 2. The Uniform Per Student Funding Formula for Public Schools and Public Charter Schools and Tax Conformity Clarification Amendment Act of 1998 is amended as follows a) Section 106(c) is amended to read as follows c) These supplemental allocations shall be calculated by applying weightings to the foundation level as follows: Level/program Definition Weight- ing Supplemental per pupil FY 1999 Level 1 Special Education Residential Additional funding to support the after-hours level 1 special education needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or Public Charter School that provides students with room and board in a residential setting +0.374 $2,057 Codification District of Columbia Code 2001 Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 Level 2 Special Education Residential Additional funding to support the after-hours level 2 special education needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or Public Charter School that provides students with room and board in a residential setting +1.36 $7,480 Level 3 Special Education Residential Additional funding to support the after-hours level 3 special education needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or Public Charter School that provides students with room and board in a residential setting +2.941 $16,176 Level 4 Special Education Residential Additional funding to support the after-hours level 4 special education needs of students living in D.C. Public School or Public Charter School that provides students with room and board in a residential setting +2.924 $16,082 LEP/NEP Residential Additional funding to support the after-hours special instructional needs of limited and non-English proficient students living in a D.C. Public School or Public Charter School that provides students with room and board in a residential setting +0.68 $3,740 (b) Section 109 is amended by adding a new subsection (f) to read as follows f) For DCPS or Public Charter Schools that provide students with room and board in a residential setting, in addition to their instructional program, the facilities allowance determined pursuant to this section shall be multiplied by 2.7 for those students in residence at the school Sec. 3. Section 2404 of the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Act of 1999 is amended as follows a) The second sentence of the lead-in text is amended by striking the word "approval" and inserting the phrase "approval, and the Council has affirmatively approved in its place b) Paragraph (2)(H) is amended by striking the phrase "A non-server" and inserting the phrase "A non-service" in its place. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. There is no fiscal impact because the funds for the Per Pupil Funding Formula increase were included in the FY 2000 Budget Request Act. The amendments to section 2404 are clarifying and technical and have no fiscal impact. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3 Sec. 5. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
