<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 13-289" flag="true">
  <num type="law">13-289</num>
  <heading type="short">Motor Vehicle and Safe Driving Amendment Act of 2000</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2001-04-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/13-289.pdf">D.C. Law 13-289</citation>
      <citation type="register">48 DCR 2057</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B13-0828">
      <narrative>Law 13-289, the “Motor Vehicle and Safe Driving Amendment Act of 2000”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-828, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and the Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 8, 2000, and December 5, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 22, 2001, it was assigned Act No. 13-592 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-289 became effective on April 27, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 To amend the Compulsory/No-Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982, to authorize only the revise the schedule of fines for insurance violations; to amend An Act To Provide for the Mayor to charge the federal and District governments for inspections, to authorize the establish a penalty for late inspections; to amend the International Registration Plan amend An Act to Provide Additional Revenue for the District of Columbia to authorize drivers domiciled in the District of Columbia may be registered; to amend the District of Municipal Regulations to require suspension and revocation of driver licenses based upon continuously without fines or points, to eliminate points given by automated traffic issuance of an occupational license to drivers who have accumulated 16 points; to service of a notice of license suspension or revocation, to permit respondents to provide period within which traffic and parking notices of infraction must be answered before the where the notices of infraction have not been answered, to provide for default judgment hearing, to allow the hearing examiner to vacate a default judgment under specified the vacation of a parking ticket or moving violation default judgment; to amend the for simultaneous multiple violations of the act; to amend the Uniform Classification and Codification District of Code 2001 Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL Commercial Driver's License Act of 1990 to provide for penalties of violations of out-of- 1996 to condition the issuance of a District license or permit on the payment of Council review to grant authority to the Director to amend all regulations promulgated the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. act may be cited as the "Motor Vehicle and Safe Driving Amendment Act of 2000 Sec. 101. The Compulsory/No-Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982 is amended (a) Section 3 is amended as follows 2) Paragraph (4) is amended to read as follows: established pursuant to section 1822 of the Department of Motor Vehicles Establishment Act of (b) Section 4(d) is amended as follows A) Subparagraph (A) is amended to read as follows: registration certificate issued to the owner of a motor vehicle if the required insurance is not in regular mail of a notice of proposed suspension, unless the person provides proof that he or she also be advised that the fine established pursuant to section 15(b)(2) shall be imposed unless, the registration or reciprocity period. The suspension shall remain in effect until the person reinstatement fee and the applicable fine C) Sub-subparagraph (iv) is amended by striking the phrase "or (2) Paragraph (4)(A) is repealed. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3 (1) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows b) NOTICE OF CANCELLATION OF OR REFUSAL TO RENEW POLICY 1) No cancellation or refusal to renew by an insurer of a policy of motor vehicle insurance shall be effective unless the insurer has delivered or mailed to the named insured, at his or her last known address, a written notice of intent to cancel or refusal to renew. The required notice shall be provided to the named insured at least 30 days prior to the effective date of cancellation, or in the case of nonrenewal, 30 days prior to the end of the policy period. The notice shall contain a statement A) Of the specific reasons relied upon by the insurer as the basis of cancellation or refusal to renew B) Advising the named insured of his or her right to request, in writing, within 15 days of receipt of the notice, that the Commissioner review the action of the insurer in cancelling or refusing to renew the policy of the insured C) Advising the insured of the possible availability of other insurance which may be obtained through his or her agent, through another insurer, or through the District of Columbia Automobile Insurance Plan; and D) That the motor vehicle registration or reciprocity sticker of the vehicle shall be suspended or revoked for failure to maintain required insurance 2)(A) Or, in the case of a refusal or failure of the insured to pay a premium due under the terms of the policy, the notice shall be provided to the insured not less than 15 days prior to the effective date of the cancellation, or in the event of a cancellation or nonrenewal for refusal or failure or an insured to pay a premium due under the terms of the policy, within 15 days of receipt of the notice B) The provisions of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph may take effect when the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles certifies, as published in the District of Columbia Register, that the automated systems and procedures of the Department reasonably permits implementation of this change, but not later than October 1, 2002. Insurance companies shall file with the Commissioner by June 30, 2004, a report on the industry-wide economic impact, if any, of this section on the insurance premium downpayment for purchasing automobile coverage to residents of the District of Columbia with a goal of contributing to an overall reduction in the premium downpayment of 10% from the date of the implementation of subsection (b) of this section. The Commissioner shall issue a report to the Council on the overall industry reduction in the insurance premium payment on or before September 1, 2004. In the event the industry-wide insurance premium downpayment reduction is less than 10 the report shall state the reasons why the decrease is less than the goal 2) Subsection (i)(1) is amended to read as follows: “(1)(A) If the insured disputes the validity of a purported cancellation or nonrenewal, the insured may send, within 15 days of receipt of the notice of intent to cancel or not to renew, written notification to the Commissioner of the reasons the insured believes the 4 insurer a copy of the notification; or an insured to pay a premium due under the terms of the policy, within 15 days of receipt of the C) The provisions of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph may take District of Columbia Register, that the automated systems and procedures of the Department companies shall file with the Commissioner by June 30, 2004, a report on the industry-wide automobile coverage to residents of the District of Columbia with a goal of contributing to an subsection (b) of this section. The Commissioner shall issue a report to the Council on the the event the industry-wide insurance premium downpayment reduction is less than 10 the (d Section 15 is amended as follows: license”, and inserting the phrase “sticker or tags” in its place. “(A) In addition to the regulatory scheme established in section 4(d)(2) for a be assessed for each vehicle without the required insurance for a period of 1 to 30 days, and pursuant to section 5(d)(2)(A).”. Sec. 201. Section 2 of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937 is amended as (a) Subsection (c) is amended as follows: “(2) Has paid all applicable fines, fees, and taxes for the motor vehicle or trailer 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking “and”at the end. and” in its place 5) Is domiciled in the District of Columbia ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5 (b) Subsection (d)(2) is amended to read as follows: “(2) The Mayor shall issue, without charge, registration certificates and identification tags for all motor vehicles and trailers owned by the District of Columbia and the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority.”. Sec. 202. Section 4 of the International Registration Plan Agreement Act of 1997 is amended by adding new subsections (e) and (f) to read as follows e) At no point during operation, shall the gross weight of a vehicle registered pursuant to this act, or of the combination of vehicles of which the vehicle is a part, exceed the gross weight on the basis of which it is registered f) Any owner or apportioned operator who fails to comply with subsection (b c) or (e) of this section shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $500 or jailed not longer than 180 days, or both, for each violation. In addition, a police officer may impound the vehicle until a valid registration or a trip permit is obtained Sec. 203. An Act To Provide for the annual inspection of all motor vehicles in the District of Columbia is amended as follows a) Section 1(a) is amended by striking the second sentence and inserting the sentence “At the time of registration, or when otherwise established by the Director, an inspection fee shall be levied and collected for each motor vehicle or trailer.” in its place b) Section 4 is amended to read as follows All motor vehicles and trailers owned and officially used by the government of the United States, the government of the District of Columbia or the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority shall be subject to inspection c) Section 6 is amended as follows 1) The existing text is designated as subsection (a 2) A new subsection (b) is added to read as follows b) A late penalty of $15 shall be assessed if a vehicle has not been inspected by the date required by the Director pursuant to the provisions of this act. An additional late penalty of $15 shall be assessed for each month that the vehicle has not been inspected. All late penalties shall be deposited into the District of Columbia Motor Vehicle Biennial Inspection Fund established in section 2 TITLE III. ENFORCEMENT AND ADJUDICATION OF INFRACTIONS Sec. 301. Section 13(a) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925 is amended by adding after the phrase "permit is mandatory" the phrase "or where suspension or revocation is mandatory for accumulated point totals pursuant to Chapter 3 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations ENROLLED ORIGINAL 6 Sec. 302. The District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978 is amended as follows a) Section 102 (a) and (b) are amended to read as follows 1) The term "Department" means the Department of Motor Vehicles, established pursuant to section 1822 of the Department of Motor Vehicles Establishment Act of 1998 2) The term "Director" means the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles or his or her designee b) Section 103 is repealed c) Section 105 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a)(2)(A) is amended by striking the phrase “sections 205(d) or 305(d)” and inserting the phrase “sections 205(d)(1) and 305(d)(1)” in its place 2) A new subsection (c) is added to read as follows c) The Director may permit, in his or her sole discretion, persons owing substantial fines, fees or charges to the Department to pay the amounts owed in installments at intervals as the Director may decide d) Section 204 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase “fifteen (15) calendar days” and inserting the phrase “thirty (30) calendar days” in its place 2) Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase “on its face,” and inserting the phrase “on its face, for reasons other than compliance with subsection (c) of this section” in its place e) Section 205 is amended to read as follows Sec. 205. Answer a) In answer to a notice of infraction, a person to whom the notice was issued may 1) Admit, by payment of the civil fine, the commission of the infraction; or 2) Deny the commission of the infraction b) A person charged with a moving violation may contest the charge through an administrative hearing, except where adjudication by mail is authorized by the Director c)(1)(A) A person charged with a moving violation may admit, with an explanation, the infraction by mail or in person. A person admitting an infraction shall, at the same time they submit their answer, pay the civil fine and any additional penalties established pursuant to section 105 as may be due for failure to answer within the time required by subsection (d) of this section. Payment of the fine for the infraction shall be deemed a finding of liability. “(B) The provisions of this section which authorize admit with an explanation for parking violations shall take effect beginning October 1, 2002 2) A person admitting the infraction may include in their answer an explanation as to why points should not be assessed. A hearing examiner may, upon consideration of the explanation, order the waiver of applicable points, or authorize the deletion of the assessed ENROLLED ORIGINAL 7 points upon the satisfactory completion of driving school d)(1) A person to whom a notice of infraction has been issued must answer within 30 calendar days of date the notice was issued or within a greater period of time as prescribed by the Director by regulation 2) If a person fails to answer the notice within this 30 day period, the person's operator's permit, in the case of a resident of the District or a person with a District operator's permit, or the person's privilege to drive within the District, in the case of a nonresident or resident licensed in another jurisdiction, shall be suspended by operation of law pursuant to subsection (f) of this section e) If a person fails to answer the notice within 60 days after the date the notice was issued, or within a greater period of time as prescribed by the Director by regulation, the commission of the infraction shall be deemed admitted and all points, penalties, and fines shall be assessed. Not more than 50 days after the notice is issued, the Director shall send, by regular mail, notice of the outstanding notice of infraction and of the impending deemed admission. The notice may be combined with the notice of suspension described in subsection (f) of this section f) A notice of the suspension provided for in subsection (d) of this section shall be sent by regular mail to the respondent's address on the Department's records. Suspensions shall take effect 15 days after the date the notice was sent. The possession by the Department of a copy of a suspension notice addressed to a respondent, or a copy of the certificate or affidavit provided for in 18 DCMR § 307.6, establishes a rebuttable presumption that the notice, as written, was received by the respondent by the date the suspension became effective g) A suspension resulting from a failure to answer shall remain in effect until the person answers the notice, except that once the offense is deemed admitted the suspension may only be lifted by payment of the fine for the offense and any additional penalties established pursuant to section 105, as may be due for failure to answer within the time required by subsection (d)(1) of this section h)(1) The Director is authorized to implement amnesty programs as he or she considers necessary to encourage respondents to answer outstanding notices of infraction or pay outstanding fines. The Director shall send to the Council written notice of the intent to establish an amnesty program 45 days prior to its implementation 2) An initial 6 month amnesty period shall commence on the effective date of the Motor Vehicle and Safe Driving Amendment Act of 2000, and shall be applicable to any person issued a notice of infraction for a moving violation prior to April 9, 1997. During this amnesty period, any person who admits the commission of an infraction by payment of the fine shall have all applicable penalties and points waived. Any person eligible for the amnesty program, who fails to participate in the program, shall answer all outstanding notices of infraction 60 days after the conclusion of the amnesty period, after which they shall be deemed to have admitted the commission of the offenses and all point, penalties, and fines shall be assessed 3) Ninety days after the conclusion of the amnesty period described in ENROLLED ORIGINAL paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Director shall provide the Council with a report detailing the results of the amnesty program. The report shall indicate, by year, the number of outstanding for which payment was received and the total amount of the payment, the number of tickets answered during the final 60 day period, and the number of outstanding tickets remaining and the District may exercise options to send unpaid tickets to a collection agency.” f) Section 206 is amended as follows: the D.C. Rules and Regulations" and inserting the phrase "Chapter 10 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations" in its place b) If a person to whom a notice of infraction has been issued fails to appear at a hearing for which he or she received notice, the hearing examiner may enter a default judgment the person's license or privilege to drive in the District until the fines and penalties are paid, if the commission of the infraction is established by clear and convincing evidence. The judgment and notice shall further indicate that the default judgment may only be vacated if there is received, within 90 days of the effective date of the judgment, a written application to vacate the default 1) A sufficient defense to the charge; and 2) Excusable neglect as to the respondent's failure to attend the hearing i) Except where a stay is ordered, failure to pay any assessed civil fines and penalties due within 15 calendar days after final decision shall result in suspension of a respondent's operator's permit, or the person's privilege to drive within the District, in the case of a nonresident or resident licensed in another jurisdiction. The suspension shall take effect and pursuant to the provisions of this act shall be paid into the General Fund of the District g) Section 303(e) is amended by striking the phrase "on its face" and inserting the (h) Section 304a of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978 is amended as follows: Works" and inserting the phrase "Department of Motor Vehicles" in its place 2) Subsection (e) is amended to read as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 9 days of receipt, the monthly fleet infraction report, which sets forth the date and time of the infraction and other information contained in the original notice of infraction. Answers shall be consistent with section 305. The owner's failure to answer within 30 days shall result in the imposition of monetary penalties established by section 105, in addition to the potential civil fine for the infraction. If the owner fails to answer within 60 days, the owner shall be deemed liable for the violations. The Director may suspend program participation for multiple violations of this subsection i) Section 305 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a)(1) is amended to read as follows a) In answer to a notice of infraction, a person to whom the notice was issued may 1) Admit, by payment of the civil fine, the commission of the infraction; or 2) Deny the commission of the infraction 2) Subsection (d) is amended to read as follows d)(1) A person to whom a notice of infraction has been issued shall answer within 30 calendar days of the date the notice was issued, or within a greater period of time as prescribed by the Director by regulation. Failure to answer the notice within this period shall result in the imposition of monetary penalties established by section 105 of this act, in addition to the potential civil fine for the infraction 2) If a person fails to answer within 60 days, or within a greater period of time as prescribed by the Director by regulation, the commission of the infraction shall be deemed admitted and all penalties and fines shall be assessed. Not more than 50 days after the notice is issued, the Director shall send, by regular mail, notice of the outstanding notice of infraction and of the impending deemed admission. This subsection shall not apply to any participant in the fleet adjudication program j) Section 306 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "Chapter IX of Title 32 of the D.C. Rules and Regulations" and inserting the phrase "Chapter 10 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations" in its place 2) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase "or admitted with explanation 3) Subsection (d) is amended to read as follows d) If a person to whom a notice of infraction has been issued fails to appear at a hearing for which he or she received notice, the hearing examiner may enter a default judgment sustaining the charges, fix the appropriate fine, and assess appropriate penalties, if any, if commission of the infraction is established by a preponderance of the evidence 4) Subsection (e) is amended to read as follows e) A default judgment shall take effect and notice shall be given pursuant to section 205(f The notice shall further indicate that the default judgment may only be vacated if the Department, receives, within 30 day of the effective date of the judgment, a written application ENROLLED ORIGINAL 10 1) A sufficient defense to the charge; and 2) Excusable neglect as to the respondent's failure to attend the hearing read as follows d) The Department of Motor Vehicles shall assign points, pursuant to 18 DCMR § 1) Two points for a single violation; or 2) A total of 3 points for simultaneous multiple violations Sec. 401. The District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925 is amended as follows a) Section 2 is amended by adding a new subsection (d-1) to read as follows: wagon, pick-up, or jeep-type vehicle, having a wheel base over 114 inches b) Section 7a is amended by adding a new paragraph (5A) to read as follows; Service when they obtain or renew their driver's license. The provisions of this paragraph shall take effect October 1, 2002.”. follows a) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows: vehicle, other than a mini-van, may be operated or parked upon the public streets or spaces of the District of Columbia with: light transmittance; or B) A rear windshield or rear side windows that allow less than 50 2) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, no mini-van may be operated or parked upon the public streets or spaces of the District of Columbia with: light transmittance, or B) A rear windshield or rear side windows that allow less than 35 b) Subsection (h) is amended to read as follows h) This section shall not apply to: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 11 1) Limousines, ambulances, buses, and hearses meeting the requirements of 18 DCMR § 413.10 2) Church owned vehicles 3) All official government vehicles 4) Vehicles with tinted windows installed by the manufacturer prior to purchase; or 5) Vehicles exempted by the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles because the owner of the vehicle has a medical condition requiring windows which allows less light than permitted pursuant to subsection (a d) A new subsection (j) is added to read as follows j) The Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles is authorized to promulgate rules to implement the provisions this section and to amend existing provisions of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations to conform to its requirements. Rules promulgated or amended pursuant to this section shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days of Council recess TITLE V. OUT OF SERVICE ORDER PENALTIES Sec. 501. The Uniform Classification and Commercial Driver's License Act of 1990 is amended as follows a) Section 2 is amended by adding a new paragraph (5) to read as follows 5) Out-of-service order means a declaration by an authorized enforcement officer of a federal, state, Canadian, Mexican, or local jurisdiction that a driver, a commercial motor vehicle, or a motor carrier operation, is out-of-service pursuant to Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Regulations, 49 C.F.R. §§ 386.72, 392.5, 395.13, 396.9, or compatible laws, or the North American Uniform Out-of-Service Criteria.” b) Section 7 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a)(3) is amended by striking "or" at the end 2) Subsection (a)(4) is amended by striking the phrase "3-year period and inserting the phrase "3-year period; or" in its place 3) A new paragraph (5) is amended to read as follows 5) Operation of a motor vehicle where the driver, the motor vehicle or motor vehicle operation owning the vehicle has been issued an out-of-service order and that order has not been cancelled or withdrawn 4) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows b)(1) A person who is found to have committed any violation of paragraphs (1 4 of subsection (a) of this section may have his or her commercial driver's license suspended for one year for the first violation, from 10 years to life for the second violation, and for life for the third violation 2) A person who is found to have committed any violation set forth in ENROLLED ORIGINAL 12 subsection (a)(5) of this section may have his or her commercial driver's license suspended for 90 days to one year for the first violation, from one to 5 years for the second violation in any 10- year period, and from 3 to 5 years for the third violation in any 10-year period TITLE VI. REFUSAL OF GOVERNMENT LICENSING AND PERMITTING SERVICES Sec. 601. Section 47-2862(a) of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking "or b) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrase “due taxes and inserting the phrase "due taxes; or" in its place c) A new paragraph (5) is added to read as follows 5) Fines or penalties assessed pursuant to Chapter 6 of Title 40 TITLE VII. REGULATORY ENFORCEMENT AND ADJUDICATION OF INFRACTIONS Sec. 701. Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (Vehicles and Traffic is amended as follows a) Section 303 is amended as follows 1) Subsection 303.1 is amended to read as follows 303.1 Points shall be assessed against the driving record of an individual upon receipt of evidence of a traffic conviction, not including automated traffic enforcement systems as defined in section 303.15, or after an individual has either admitted committing, paid a fine for committing, or has been found by the Director or his designee, to have committed, a traffic offense made pointable by this or any other provision of this title, except that points may be assessed against a person under eighteen (18) years of age at the discretion of the Director 2) Subsection 303.3 is amended to read as follows 303.3 The Director or hearing examiner shall, in accordance with § 307.2, order the suspension of a person's license when the number of points accumulated reaches a total of ten (10) points 3) Subsection 303.4 is repealed 4) Subsection 303.5 is amended to read as follows 303.5 The Director or hearing examiner shall order the revocation of the person's license when the number of points accumulated reaches a total of twelve (12) points 5) Subsection 303.6 is repealed 6) Subsection 303.9 is amended to read as follows 303.9 The Director shall assign one (1) safe driving point each year, up to a maximum accumulation of five (5) points, to the driving record of a licensee who was not assessed points during the proceeding year 7) Subsection 303.10 is amended to read as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 13 "303.10 Accumulated safe driving points may be used to offset assessed points in the chronological order in which the points were assessed 8) A new section 303.15 is added to read as follows 303.15 For the purposes of this section the term "automated traffic enforcement system" means equipment that takes a film or digital camera-based photograph which is linked with a violation detection system that synchronizes the taking or a photograph with the occurrence of a traffic infraction b) Section 307 is amended as follows 1) Subsection 307.1 is amended by striking the phrase "proposes to revoke" and inserting the word "revokes" in its place 2) A new subsection 307.2 is added to read as follows 307.2 Whenever the Director or a hearing examiner, pursuant to §§ 303.3 and 303.5, orders the suspension or revocation of a license because of the accumulation of traffic points, the suspension or revocation order shall include a copy of the licensee's driver's record. The notice shall notify the person that the order will take effect within ten (10) days (fifteen (15) days if the person is a non-resident unless that person files a written objection with the Director or hearing examiner based solely upon the accuracy of the driving record. The filing of an objection operates as a stay of the order until the Director or hearing examiner renders a written decision on the objection 3) Subsections 307.2 through 307.6 are renumbered accordingly c) Section 310 is amended as follows 1) Subsections 310.1, 310.4, and 310.5, are amended to read as follows 310.1 Except as provided in § 310.7, a person whose driver's license is revoked or suspended may request, in writing, that the order be modified to allow the issuance or retention of a driver's license or privilege on a limited basis. An examiner shall not grant the application unless the applicant demonstrates that the suspension or revocation imposes an extreme hardship for which there is no practical remedy and, in the judgment of the examiner, the safety of the public will not be impaired. The determination shall be based solely upon the written application 310.4 The applicant may prove his or her general good character by submitting with the application letters of recommendation from responsible business people, the employer of the applicant, law enforcement officers, judicial officials, or other credible persons 310.5 If the applicant operates a commercial vehicle as a livelihood, the application shall be accompanied by a written request from the applicant's employer that the license be issued.” 2) Subsection 310.7 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (b) is amended by striking “or” b) Paragraph (c) is amended by striking the phrase “or revocation.” and inserting the phrase “or revocation;” in its place c) New paragraphs (d) and (e) are added to read as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 14 e) Applicants who received an occupational license within the preceding two (2) years 1004.2 The right to a hearing shall not extend to: “(a) Any act or decision that is based solely upon on the results of any test, examination “(b) The suspension or revocation of a driver's license based upon point totals; “(c) The suspension of a reciprocity sticker registration certificate; “(e) Any other instance where the decision to hold a hearing is left to the discretion of the Director or hearing examiner.”. “Director the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles or the Director of the Department of Public Works, as applicable 310.9 An occupational license shall be expressly conditioned on the licensee's compliance with all traffic laws and rules. Any violation, other than parking infractions, shall period of suspension of revocation TITLE VIII. AUTHORITY OF DEPARTMENT TO AMEND REGULATIONS promulgated pursuant to Regulation No. 72-13, effective June 30, 1972, that were published in Title 32 of the District of Columbia Rules and Regulations and are now contained in chapters 1 contained in the provisions of this act. Regulations promulgated or amended pursuant to this section shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of Council review, excluding resolution of disapproval has been introduced by 3 members of Council, the regulations shall not be deemed approved. Sec. 901. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule ENROLLED ORIGINAL 15 TITLE X. EFFECTIVE DATE Sec. 1001. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>801</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-911"/>
  </section>
</document>
