<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 13-218">
  <num type="law">13-218</num>
  <heading type="short">Moratorium on the Construction of Certain Telecommunications Towers Temporary Amendment Act of 2000</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/13-218.pdf">D.C. Law 13-218</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 13-218, the “Moratorium on the Construction of Certain Telecommunications Towers Temporary Amendment Act of 2000”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-822. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 11, 2000, and October 3, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 30, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-470 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-218 became effective on April 3, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To prohibit, on a temporary basis, the issuance of permits allowing the construction or expansion of any telecommunications tower which will reach a height above 200 feet until the Mayor formulates a policy on the location and other parameters for construction of telecommunications structures and the Council has approved the policy, and to declare the sense of the Council on the need to halt the construction of a tower at 4623 41st Street N.W. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Moratorium on the Construction of Certain Telecommunications Towers Temporary Amendment Act of 2000 Sec. 2. Moratorium on the issuance of permits a) No District of Columbia government agency shall issue any permit for the construction or expansion of any telecommunication structure which will reach a height above 200 feet, until the Mayor formulates a policy, in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, on the location and other parameters for construction of telecommunications structures b) The Mayor shall formulate the policy within 180 days of the effective date of this act, and shall transmit the policy to the Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding holidays, weekends and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the policy by resolution within this 30-day review period, the policy shall be deemed approved. The policy shall include a consideration of 1) The location of the telecommunications structure in relation to residential areas of varying density, to recreational areas, and to areas of fragile eco-systems 2) The size of the lot on which the telecommunications structure is to be located 3) The level of noise, electromagnetic radiation, and other types of emissions and environmental pollutants expected to be occasioned by the telecommunications structure in relation to the community 4) The impact of the telecommunications structure on the property values of the Codification District of Columbia Code 2001 Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 owners of properties adjacent to, and surrounding the telecommunications structure 5) The impact of the telecommunications structure on pedestrian and vehicle traffic 6) The impact of the telecommunications structure on the character of nearby historic properties, and national and local parklands; and (7) Any other criteria that shall serve to ensure the protection of residential neighborhoods and commercial centers, and the health and safety of the residents and workers in the District of Columbia. Sec. 3. Sense of the Council a) It is the sense of the Council that there exists an immediate need to halt the construction of the high definition digital television transmission antenna tower at 4623 41st Street, N.W because it is inconsistent with the intent of subsections 201.6, 701.8 and 2510.1 of Title 11 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations D.C. Zoning Regulations and subsections 411.1 and 1403.13(e) of the Comprehensive Plan 1) The tower is inconsistent with subsection 201.6 of the D.C. Zoning Regulations because the structure is an additional tower, and not an addition of an antenna to an existing tower. The tower under construction at 4623 41st Street, N.W is substantially taller than the existing tower. The appearance of this tower is substantially altered 2) The tower is inconsistent with subsection 701.8 of the D.C. Zoning Regulations because the tower under construction is not a roof-mounted antenna. The tower under construction is a ground-mounted antenna 3) The tower is inconsistent with subsection 2510.1 of the D.C. Zoning Regulations because the Mayor did not expressly exempt the tower under construction from the provisions of section 4(h) of An Act To regulate the height of buildings in the District of Columbia 4) The tower is inconsistent with subsections 411.1 and 1403.13(e) of the Comprehensive Plan of the National Capital, adopted in section 2 of the Comprehensive Plan Amendment Act of 1998, because to do nothing while waiting for conclusive evidence about human health effects is not a reasonable response to the potential risks associated with electromagnetic field generating facilities such as generators, power lines, and antennas b) The Council requests that the Mayor perform an Environmental Impact Statement EIS review on the tower under construction before further construction can take place. Since this tower is located in a heavily populated area, the EIS should include a measure of the levels of radio frequency radiation at varying distances from the tower, with the first measurement taken to be adjacent to the tower, and subsequent measurements to be taken every 35 feet c) The Council requests the Mayor to take all reasonable steps to protect the health, welfare and safety of the residents and workers in the District in general, and in particular, the ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3 residents and workers in the immediate area of the tower under construction. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. There is no fiscal impact. The fiscal impact statement is attached. Sec. 5. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
