<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 13-307">
  <num type="law">13-307</num>
  <heading type="short">Taxicab Drivers Protection Act of 2000</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2001-06-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/13-307.pdf">D.C. Law 13-307</citation>
      <citation type="register">48 DCR 600</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B13-0638">
      <narrative>Law 13-307, the “Taxicab Drivers Protection Act of 2000”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-638, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 8, 2000, and December 5, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-515 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-307 became effective on June 9, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To provide enhanced penalties for the commission of violent crimes against taxicab drivers. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Taxicab Drivers Protection Act of 2000 Sec. 2. Enhanced penalties. Any person who commits an offense listed in section 3 against a taxicab driver who, at the time of the offense, has a current license to operate a taxicab in the District of Columbia or any United States jurisdiction and is lawfully operating a taxicab in the District of Columbia may be punished by a fine of up to one and 1/2 times the maximum fine otherwise authorized for the offense and may be imprisoned for a term of up to one and 1/2 times the maximum term of imprisonment otherwise authorized for the offense, or both. Sec. 3. Enumerated offenses. The provisions of section 2 shall apply to the following offenses: taking property from another by force or by threat of force, murder, attempted murder, first degree sexual abuse, second degree sexual abuse, attempted rape, carjacking, kidnapping, robbery, attempted robbery, assault with a dangerous weapon, and aggravated assault. Sec. 4. Section (3) of the Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Act of 1985 is amended as follows a) Subsection (b)(2) is amended by striking the word "or b) Subsection (b)(3) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase or" in its place c) A new subsection (b)(4) is added to read as follows 4) Operators of taxicabs who possess valid taxicab licenses while picking up or transporting passengers for hire between the hours of 6:00 p.m. and 6:00 a.m d) A new subsection (c) is added to read as follows: Codification District of Columbia Code 2001 Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 c) Two years following the effective date of the Taxicab Drivers Protection Act of 2000, the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission shall submit to the Council a report on the impact on driver safety of subsection (b)(4) of this section Sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-3751"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-3751.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-3752"/>
  </section>
</document>
