<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 13-304">
  <num type="law">13-304</num>
  <heading type="short">Bail Reform Temporary Act of 2000</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/13-304.pdf">D.C. Law 13-304</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 13-304, the “Bail Reform Temporary Act of 2000”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-786. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 11, 2000, and October 3, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 17, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-443 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-304 became effective on June 8, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend, on a temporary basis, section 23-1329 of the District of Columbia Code to clarify the court's authority to initiate revocation of release and contempt proceedings for violating conditions of release, and to clarify the prosecutor 's authority to initiate contempt proceedings for violations of conditions of release. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Bail Reform Temporary Act of 2000 Sec. 2. Section 23-1329 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the period at the end of the first sentence and inserting the phrase "or the court's own motion in its place b) Subsection (c) is amended by adding a new sentence at the end to read as follows A judicial officer or a prosecutor may initiate a proceeding for contempt under this section Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. This amendment should have no negative impact on the budget of the District of Columbia. Sec. 4. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Codification District of Columbia Code 2001 Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
