<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 13-306">
  <num type="law">13-306</num>
  <heading type="short">Sales Tax Holiday Act of 2000</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2001-06-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/13-306.pdf">D.C. Law 13-306</citation>
      <citation type="register">48 DCR 569</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B13-0859">
      <narrative>Law 13-306, the “Sales Tax Holiday Act of 2000”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-859, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 8, 2000, and December 5, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 22, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-505 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-306 became effective on June 9, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code to provide for a sales tax holiday beginning at 12:01 a.m. on August 3, 2001 and ending at midnight on August 12, 2001, for clothing and school supplies costing less than $101; to require that not later than December 1, 2001, the Mayor shall report to the Council on the feasibility of enacting a permanent sales tax holiday in the District of Columbia; and to provide that these provisions will only go into effect upon a certification by the Chief Financial Officer that collected revenue exceeds the projected revenue for 2001. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Sales Tax Holiday Act of 2000 Sec. 2. Section 47-2005 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Paragraph (28) is amended by striking the word "and" at the end of the paragraph b) Paragraph (29) is amended by striking the period at the end of the paragraph and inserting the phrase and" in its place c) A new paragraph (30) is added to read as follows 30)(A) Subject to the other provisions of this paragraph, sales of any school supply or article of clothing for less than $101, when the purchase is made between 12:01 a.m. on Friday, August 3, 2001, and midnight on Sunday, August 12, 2001 B) The exemption shall apply to i) Each eligible item regardless of how many items are sold on the same invoice to a customer ii) Mail order sales, including online sales, if the seller accepts the order during the exemption period for immediate shipment. Shipping and handling charges shall be included as part of the sales price of the eligible item, whether or not separately stated. If multiple items are shipped on a single invoice, the shipping and handling charges shall be proportionately allocated to each item ordered and separately identified on the invoice iii) Layaway sales if the retailer and the customer enter into a layaway agreement during the exemption period or if the customer makes final payment on a Codification D i s t r i c t o f Columbia Code 2001 Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 layaway order during the exemption period iv) Sales using a rain check, regardless of when the rain check is issued, if the item is actually purchased during the exemption period; and v) Sales of eligible items purchased during the exemption period if the item is later exchanged for another exempt item after the exempt period C) The exemption shall not apply to i) Exempt items normally sold as a unit with nonexempt items if the items are separated in order to qualify for the exemption ii) Nonexempt items which are exchanged for the exempt items iii) Items advertised as "buy one, get one free or "buy one, get one for a reduced price if one or both items are averaged to qualify for the exemption iv) Items whose prices are reduced by a manufacturer's coupon to qualify for the exemption v) Repairs and alterations to exempt items vi) Items for rent; and vii) Items sold in public lodging establishments D) For the purposes of this paragraph, the term i Accepts the order" means an action to fill an order for immediate shipment, including placing a date stamp on a mail order or assigning a transaction number to a telephone order ii Clothing" means an article of wearing apparel for humans, including all footwear except skis, swim fins, roller blades, and skates iii Immediate shipment" means an order for which delayed shipment is not requested by the customer iv Public lodging establishment" means a hotel, motel, or any other transient lodging place. The term "public lodging establishment" shall not include a dormitory maintained by an educational institution for the use of students, a hospital, or a nursing home v School supply" means an item purchased for use in the classroom, at home, or for any school activity, including pens, pencils, stationery, book bags, lunchboxes, and calculators E) A customer who pays sales tax on an exempt item to a retailer during the exempt period shall be entitled to a refund of the tax from the retailer and not from the Mayor F) Not later than December 1, 2001, the Mayor shall report to the Council on the feasibility of enacting a permanent sales tax holiday in the District of Columbia Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3 Sec. 4. Applicability. Section 2 shall apply as of the date that the Chief Financial Officer certifies that the collected revenues for the Fiscal Year 2001 will exceed the projected revenues for Fiscal Year 2001 by an amount which is at least equal to the projected revenue loss from the operation of this section. This section shall not be effective unless the Chief Financial Officer makes such certification. Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
