<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 21-11">
  <num type="law">21-11</num>
  <num type="bill">21-106</num>
  <num type="act">21-49</num>
  <heading type="short">Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Amendment Act of 2014 to clarify that, for the purposes of the act, a private club is a place to which the public is invited, but does not include a private residence, and that the prohibition on consumption of marijuana in public is not limited by the Legalization of Possession of Minimal Amounts of Marijuana for Personal Use Initiative of 2014; and to amend Chapter 28 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to require the Mayor to revoke any license, certificate of occupancy, or permit held by an entity that knowingly permits a violation of section 301(a) of the Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Amendment Act of 2014 to occur at the specific address or unit identified in the license, certificate of occupancy, or permit.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-02-27</introduced>
    <effective>2015-06-04</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/33479/Signed_Act/B21-0106-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-11</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 4717</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0106">
      <vote date="2015-03-03" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2015-03-17" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-04-11</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 301 of the Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Amendment Act of 2014, effective July 17, 2014 (D.C. Law 20-126; D.C. Official Code § 48-911.01), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a)(3) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Any place to which the public is invited.  For the purposes of this subsection, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, a private club, which includes any building, facility, or premises used or operated by an organization or association for a common avocational purpose, such as a fraternal, social, educational, or recreational purpose, is a place to which the public is invited; provided, that a private club does not include a private residence.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new subsection (f) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(f)</num>
          <text>No provision of the Legalization of Possession of Minimal Amounts of Marijuana for Personal Use Initiative of 2014, effective February 26, 2015 (D.C. Law 20-153; 62 DCR 880), shall limit or be construed to limit the application of any provision of this section.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 47-2844(a-1)(1) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the phrase "Title 48; or" and inserting the phrase "Title 48;" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase "; or" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new subparagraph (D) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="2">
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>Conduct that violates section 301(a) of the Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Amendment Act of 2014, effective July 17, 2014 (D.C. Law 20-126; D.C. Official Code § 48-911.01(a)).  In addition, the Mayor shall revoke any certificate of occupancy or permit associated with the specific address or unit, whichever is more specific, of the holder of a certificate of occupancy or permit who knowingly permits a violation of section 301(a) of the Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Amendment Act of 2014, effective July 17, 2014 (D.C. Law 20-126; D.C. Official Code § 48-911.01(a)), to occur at the specific address or unit identified in the certificate of occupancy or permit.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(l) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(l)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
