<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 21-1">
  <num type="law">21-1</num>
  <num type="bill">21-51</num>
  <num type="act">21-37</num>
  <heading type="short">H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Retail Incentive Act of 2014 to modify the boundaries of the Bladensburg Road, N.E., Retail Priority Area; and to amend the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Incentive Act of 2010 to clarify that restaurants whose annual alcohol sales exceed 20% are not eligible for retail development project grants and to clarify the location of businesses that are eligible to receive retail development project grants.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-02-03</introduced>
    <effective>2015-06-04</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/33317/Signed_Act/B21-0051-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-1</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 4550</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0051">
      <vote date="2015-02-03" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2015-03-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-03-30</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 4(g) of the Retail Incentive Act of 2004, effective September 8, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-185; D.C. Official Code ยง 2-1217.73(g)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>There is established the Bladensburg Road, N.E., Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within the following area: Beginning at the intersection of Holbrook Street, N.E., and Mount Olivet Road, N.E.; thence east on Mount Olivet Road, N.E., to Bladensburg Road, N.E.; thence south on Bladensburg Road, N.E., to 17th Street, N.E.; thence south on 17th Street, N.E., to H Street, N.E.; thence east on H Street, N.E., to 19th Street, N.E.; thence south on 19th Street, N.E., to Benning Road, N.E.; thence east on Benning Road, N.E., to Oklahoma Avenue, N.E.; continuing southwest along Oklahoma Avenue, N.E., to the center line of E Street, N.E.; continuing west on E Street, N.E., to the center line of 21st Street, N.E.; continuing north on 21st Street, N.E., to the center line of Gales Street, N.E.; thence northwest on Gales Street, N.E., to 15th Street, N.E.; thence west on G Street, N.E., to 14th Street, N.E.; thence north on 14th Street, N.E., to Florida Avenue, N.E.; thence west on Florida Avenue, N.E., to Holbrook Street, N.E.; thence north on Holbrook Street, N.E., to the point of beginning.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Section 4 of the H Street, N.</heading>
    <text>E., Retail Priority Area Incentive Act of 2010, effective April 8, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-354; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-325.173), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b)(2) is amended by striking the word "restaurants" and inserting the phrase "restaurants whose annual alcohol sales exceed 20%" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (c)(2) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Frontage on a commercial corridor within the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area;</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>The H Street, N.</heading>
    <text>E., Real Priority Area Incentive Temporary Amendment Act of 2014, enacted on November 10, 2014 (D.C. Act 20-475; 61 DCR 12121), is repealed.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
