<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-156">
  <num type="law">21-156</num>
  <num type="bill">21-421</num>
  <num type="act">21-468</num>
  <heading type="short">Theodore 'Ted' Williams Alley Designation Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To designate the public alley in Square 2851 that runs north and south between Irving Street, N.W., and Columbia Road, N.W., in Ward 1, as Theodore "Ted" Williams Alley.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2016-10-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/34619/B21-0421-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-156</citation>
      <citation type="register">63 DCR 10162</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2016-06-28" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-07-12" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2016-07-21</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-156 designates the public alley on Square 2851, bounded by Irving Street NW, Columbia Road NW, 11th Street NW, located in Ward 1, as Theodore Ted Williams Alley.</summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Theodore 'Ted' Williams Alley Designation Act of 2016".</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Pursuant to section 401 of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-201; D.C. Official Code § 9-204.01) ("Act"), and notwithstanding the requirements of sections 403, 407, and 408 of the Act (D.C. Official Code §§ 9-204.03, 9-204.07, and 9-204.08), the Council designates the alley in Square 2851 that runs north and south between Irving Street, N.W., and Columbia Road, N.W., in Ward 1, as "Theodore 'Ted' Williams Alley".</text>
    <codify:street-designation-anno action="the Council designates the alley in Square 2851 that runs north and south between Irving Street, N.W., and Columbia Road, N.W., in Ward 1, as &quot;Theodore 'Ted' Williams Alley&quot;."/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Implementation of alley designation</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The name designated pursuant to section 2 shall be the official name of the alley.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of this act, the term "official name" means the legal designation of the alley for mailing address and other official purposes.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Update relevant records of the District of Columbia to reflect the official name of the alley, including:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department records;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency records;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia maps; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>Any other record of the District of Columbia used for way-finding or address purposes;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Notify the United States Postal Service, other relevant government agencies, and relevant private-sector entities of the official name of the alley; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Install signage indicating the official name of the alley using procedures established by the District Department of Transportation, and remove any signs with a previous name.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Transmittal.</heading>
    <text>The Council shall transmit a copy of this act, upon its effective date, to the Mayor, the District Department of Transportation, and the Office of the Surveyor.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code §1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
