<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-124">
  <num type="law">21-124</num>
  <num type="bill">21-313</num>
  <num type="act">21-378</num>
  <heading type="short">Transportation Reorganization Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002 to establish within the District Department of Transportation the Project Delivery Administration, the Operations Administration, the Administrative Administration, and the Performance Administration; to amend the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978 to require the Department of Motor Vehicles to provide the Department of Public Works and the District Department of Transportation with monthly reports about parking infraction adjudication and to require the Mayor to provide the Council with a report and recommendation about the location of parking infraction adjudication; to establish the Transit Rider Advisory Council and the Multimodal Accessibility Advisory Council; to amend the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985 to alter the structure of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission and rename it the Department of For-Hire Vehicles, and to establish the For-Hire Vehicle Advisory Council; and to amend the Confirmation Act of 1978, the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001, Chapter 28 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code, the Employee Transportation Amendment Act of 2012, the Taxicab and Passenger Vehicle for Hire Impoundment Act of 1992, the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996, and  the Non-Resident Taxi Drivers Registration Amendment Act of 2008 to make conforming amendments.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2016-06-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/34276/B21-0313-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-124</citation>
      <citation type="register">63 DCR 7076</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2016-03-01" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2016-03-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-04-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2016-05-04</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-124 establishes and provides for the administration of the Project Delivery Administration, the Operations Administration, the Administrative Administration, and the Performance Administration within the District Department of Transportation (DDOT); requires the Department of Motor Vehicles (DMV) to transmit monthly reports to the Department of Public Works and DDOT; establishes an 11 member Transit Rider Advisory Council (TRAC) and a 9 member Multimodal Accessibility Advisory Council composed of District employees and community representatives; changes the name of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission to the Department of For-Hire Vehicles (DFHV) and provides for its organization, including an Office of Client Services tasked with educating the public and the vehicle-for-hire industry about rules, standards, rates, charges, and orders issued by the DFHV; and requires the Mayor to transmit a study of parking infraction adjudication to the Chairperson of the Council committee with oversight of transportation.  </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Transportation and the Environment</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Transportation Reorganization Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>I</num>
    <heading>DISTRICT DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</heading>
    <section codify:doc="D.C. Law 14-137">
      <num>101</num>
      <text>The Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective May 21, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-137; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.01 et seq.), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Section 4 (D.C. Official Code § 50-921.03) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace path="§4"/>
            <num>4</num>
            <heading>Organization.</heading>
            <text>There is established within DDOT the following offices and divisions:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The Office of the Director, with subordinate staff responsible for:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Legal affairs;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Civil rights matters;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Compliance with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, approved July 26, 1990 (104 Stat. 327; 42 U.S.C. § 12101 et seq.);</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>Senior and elderly affairs; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Policy and legislative affairs;</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The Project Delivery Administration, with subordinate staff responsible for:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Design and engineering and related support;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Street and bridge construction project management and related support;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Material inspection and testing;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>Project materials specification review;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Construction project review and coordination;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(F)</num>
                <text>Construction contract execution;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(G)</num>
                <text>Intermodal planning;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(H)</num>
                <text>State Transportation Environmental Compliance;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(I)</num>
                <text>Project Identification and Development;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(J)</num>
                <text>DC Circulator bus service;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(K)</num>
                <text>DC Streetcar service;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(L)</num>
                <text>Freight and passenger rail, to the extent such authority has been delegated or required by federal law;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(M)</num>
                <text>Mass Transit Policy, with functions to include supporting the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority ("WMATA") Board members and acting as a liaison between WMATA and the District government on matters including:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(i)</num>
                  <text>Alternative transportation; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(ii)</num>
                  <text>School transit subsidy; and</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(N)</num>
                <text>Traffic safety planning, engineering, and construction;</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>The Operations Administration, with subordinate staff responsible for:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Tree planting and maintenance;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Tree inventory management;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Public space permits and records;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>Investigations and inspections relating to public space regulations;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Asset management;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(F)</num>
                <text>Bridge and street maintenance;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(G)</num>
                <text>Streetlight management;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(H)</num>
                <text>Traffic operations and safety;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(I)</num>
                <text>Transportation systems management;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(J)</num>
                <text>Traffic sign fabrication and installation;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(K)</num>
                <text>Concurrent with any other agency’s authority to do so, the enforcement of violations of motor vehicle parking offenses and violations of motor vehicle moving offenses, where necessary to manage the flow of traffic, respond to incidents, and manage special events;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(L)</num>
                <text>Parking, carsharing, tour bus, and motor carrier regulation, permitting, and operations; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(M)</num>
                <text>Advertisements on parking meters, including the back of receipts printed out by multi-space parking meters;</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>The Administrative Administration, with subordinate staff responsible for:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Human resources;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Workforce development;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Budget and financial services;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>Financial planning and management; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Contracting and procurement; and</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>The Performance Administration, with subordinate staff responsible for:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Coordinating and managing transportation system data;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Customer service;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Coordinating and managing the agency’s fleet, warehouses, and other facilities; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>Technology and information services.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 5(a) (D.C. Official Code § 50-921.04(a)) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:replace path="§5|(a)"/>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The offices of DDOT shall plan, program, operate, manage, control, and maintain systems, processes, and programs to meet transportation needs as follows:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The Project Delivery Administration shall:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Manage and implement transportation improvement plans and projects;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Develop and update the Intermodal State Transportation Plan, corridor management plans, and other traffic studies on a regular basis, focusing on the safe and efficient movement of people, goods, and information;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Conduct planning studies on the condition and quality of the District’s transportation system in order to locate areas where future investment is required;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>Manage and construct capital projects related to the design and installation of streets, alleys, curbs, gutters, bicycle lanes, sidewalks, streetscapes, and medians;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Review and approve the use of construction materials for capital projects;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(F)</num>
                <text>Administer the full range of processing required to execute construction contracts for transportation, from initial preparation of bid documents through final construction completion;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(G)</num>
                <text>Implement managed lane policies, including lane pricing, vehicle eligibility, and access control; provided, that at least one lane of traffic on a street with managed lanes shall be free of charge; provided further, that DDOT shall submit to the Council any policy created pursuant to this subparagraph for approval by act before implementation;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(H)</num>
                <text>With the consent of the Chief Property Management Officer, acquire real property by purchase, lease, grant, or gift for use by DDOT, and dispose of real property through sale, lease, or other authorized method, and exercise other acquisition and property disposition authority delegated to the Mayor;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(I)</num>
                <text>Conduct studies;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(J)</num>
                <text>Develop streetscape standards;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(K)</num>
                <text>Develop policies and programs to encourage and provide for the safe use of bicycles for recreation and work-related travel, including planning, developing, operating, and regulating a Bicycle Sharing program, and administering the Bicycle Sharing Fund established by <code-cite path="§9h">section 9h</code-cite> to fund a Bicycle Sharing program;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(L)</num>
                <text>Develop and update the District’s various transportation improvement plans, consistent with federal and local requirements;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(M)</num>
                <text>Plan, manage, and contract for all, or any part of, the design, engineering, construction, operation, and maintenance of any element of the Integrated Premium Transit System;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(N)</num>
                <text>Develop paratransit systems, water taxis, tour bus support systems, light rail streetcar transit systems, and other transportation services to provide for safe and efficient movement of persons throughout the city;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(O)</num>
                <text>Operate the District of Columbia School Transit Subsidy Program;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(P)</num>
                <text>Prepare studies on mass transit needs of District residents, including rail and bus services, review and revise bus routes, review and revise the location of bus shelter locations, support WMATA Board members, and act as a liaison between WMATA and the District government;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(Q)</num>
                <text>Operate, maintain, and regulate the DC Circulator pursuant to <code-cite path="III">Title III</code-cite>;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(R)</num>
                <text>Operate, maintain, and regulate the DC Streetcar pursuant to <code-cite path="V">Title V</code-cite>;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(S)</num>
                <text>Submit to the Transit Rider Advisory Council proposed fare or service adjustments, as that term is defined in <code-cite path="§11e|(a-1)|(3)">section 11e(a-1)(3)</code-cite>;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(T)</num>
                <text>Submit to the Transit Rider Advisory Council strategic or long-term plans to expand and improve local transit service;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(U)</num>
                <text>Develop and implement transportation safety programs; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(V)</num>
                <text>Incorporate transportation safety features in the development, design, and construction of pedestrian, bicycle, motor vehicle, and mass transportation facilities and programs.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The Project Delivery Administration may enter into agreements to allow the private sponsorship of bicycles, equipment, and facilities used in the Bicycle Sharing program, and the placement of a corporate logo, slogan, or other indicia of sponsorship on the bicycles or facilities, and on related websites and social media; provided, that an agreement that would modify the name or design of any part of the Capital Bikeshare system, including equipment or facilities, shall be submitted to the Council for a 30-day period of passive review before execution. The agreement submitted to the Council shall include detailed information about a proposed name or design. All proceeds collected from a private sponsorship agreement shall be deposited into the Bicycle Sharing Fund established by <code-cite path="§9h">section 9h</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>The Operations Administration shall:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Maintain a tree inventory system;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Perform routine tree maintenance;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Review transportation related construction plans to ensure the provision of adequate rights-of-way for tree planting;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>Plant, remove, and trim trees citywide;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Review, approve, and issue public space permit requests for occupancy, work within, or other use of the public space, including private use and utility work public space requests, and ensure that transportation services are maintained and that the infrastructure is restored after the occupancy, work within, or other use is complete;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(F)</num>
                <text>Maintain official public space records;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(G)</num>
                <text>Perform regular inspections of the transportation system infrastructure;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(H)</num>
                <text>Enter into agreements to allow the placement of advertisements on District property, under the control of DDOT, in public space and collect payments under the agreements, if:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(i)</num>
                  <text>The placement of the advertisement is not in violation of District or federal laws, regulations, or orders; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(ii)</num>
                  <text>All proceeds collected from the advertising agreement shall be paid into the DDOT Enterprise Fund for Transportation Initiatives, established under <code-cite path="§9e">section 9e</code-cite>; provided, that proceeds related to advertisements on bicycles, equipment, or facilities used for the purposes of the Bicycle Sharing program shall be deposited into the Bicycle Sharing Fund established by <code-cite path="§9h">section 9h</code-cite>;</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(I)</num>
                <text>Develop, implement, and enforce a comprehensive plan that covers the care, maintenance, and upkeep of public space and federal reservations under the control of DDOT;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(J)</num>
                <text>Ensure that the transportation system is maintained to the highest standards;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(K)</num>
                <text>Perform routine repair and maintenance activities to maintain a high quality of transportation infrastructure;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(L)</num>
                <text>Coordinate seasonal snow removal operation on streets throughout the District in conjunction with the Department of Public Works and other District agencies;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(M)</num>
                <text>Maintain the mechanical and electrical street light systems that support the transportation infrastructure;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(N)</num>
                <text>Provide a safe transportation system by maintaining a high-quality traffic control system, including traffic signals and street lights;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(O)</num>
                <text>Maintain the mechanical and electrical systems signal systems that support the transportation infrastructure;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(P)</num>
                <text>Where necessary to manage the flow of traffic, respond to incidents, or manage special events, concurrent with any other agency’s authority to do so, enforce all violations of statutes, regulations, executive orders, or rules relating to motor vehicle parking offenses and the operation of a motor vehicle, except those violations contained in <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 2-104" path="§202">section 202 of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2302.02)</code-cite>;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(Q)</num>
                <text>Allocate and regulate on-street parking;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(R)</num>
                <text>Develop a city-wide parking management program to balance the needs of parking in support of economic development;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(S)</num>
                <text>Establish citywide parking and curbside management regulations, taking into account input from other District agencies, as necessary;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(T)</num>
                <text>Install and maintain parking meters and other parking control devices and systems on public rights-of-way and other public spaces in the District; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(U)</num>
                <text>Establish policies encouraging energy conservation, the reduction of pollution, including through the use of alternative-fuel vehicles, the reduction of traffic congestion, and an increase in transportation services to persons with disabilities.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>The Administrative Administration shall develop alternative methods of financing transportation projects and services to achieve financial self-sufficiency.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>The Performance Administration shall:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Develop and maintain a performance monitoring system to measure the quality and effectiveness of transportation services; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Develop and maintain the transportation elements of the Geographic Information System.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Section 9h(a) (D.C. Official Code § 50-921.16(a)) is amended by striking the phrase "established pursuant to section 5(2)(K)" and inserting the phrase "established pursuant to section 5(a)(1)(K)" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§9h|(a)" count="1">
          <find>established pursuant to <cite path="§50-921.04|(2)|(K)">§ 50-921.04(2)(K)</cite></find>
          <replace>established pursuant to <cite path="§50-921.04|(a)|(1)|(K)">§ 50-921.04(a)(1)(K)</cite>
          </replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§11e">
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>Section 11e (D.C. Official Code § 50-921.35) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "The Mayor" and inserting the phrase "Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, the Mayor" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(a)" find="The Mayor" replace="Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, the Mayor" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A new subsection (a-1) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(a)"/>
              <num>(a-1)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Before making a fare or service adjustment for the DC Circulator, the Mayor shall hold at least one public hearing and publish notice of the fare or service adjustment in the District of Columbia Register. The notice shall:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Establish a public comment period of not fewer than 45 days from the date of publication;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Set a date for a public hearing on the fare or service adjustment, which shall be held not fewer than 20 days from the date of publication; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Include a hyperlink to a fare or service adjustment plan, which shall include:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>A summary of the proposed fare or service adjustment;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>A proposed timeline for the implementation of the fare or service adjustment;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iii)</num>
                    <text>An equity analysis illustrating any disparate impact of the proposed fare or service adjustment on populations protected under Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, approved July 2, 1964 (78 Stat. 252; 42 U.S.C. § 2000d et seq.); and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iv)</num>
                    <text>An explanation of the necessity of the fare or service adjustment and a description of alternative fare or service adjustments examined.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>In the event of an emergency declaration, the Mayor may make a fare or service adjustment for the DC Circulator for the duration of the emergency without complying with the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term "fare or service adjustment" shall mean a change in the fare, the creation of a new route, or a significant change to an existing route or schedule of the DC Circulator.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§11r">
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>Section 11r (D.C. Official Code § 50-921.76) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "The Mayor" and inserting the phrase "Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, the Mayor" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(a)" find="The Mayor" replace="Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, the Mayor" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A new subsection (a-1) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(a)"/>
              <num>(a-1)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Before making a fare or service adjustment for the DC Streetcar, the Mayor shall hold at least one public hearing and publish notice of the fare or service adjustment in the District of Columbia Register. The notice shall:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Establish a public comment period of not fewer than 45 days from the date of publication;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Set a date for a public hearing on the fare or service adjustment, which shall be held not fewer than 20 days from the date of publication; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Include a hyperlink to a fare or service adjustment plan, which shall include:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>A summary of the proposed fare or service adjustment;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>A proposed timeline for the implementation of the fare or service adjustment;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iii)</num>
                    <text>An equity analysis illustrating any disparate impact of the proposed fare or service adjustment on populations protected under Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, approved July 2, 1964 (78 Stat. 252; 42 U.S.C. § 2000d et seq.); and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iv)</num>
                    <text>An explanation of the necessity of the fare or service adjustment and a description of alternative fare or service adjustments examined.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>In the event of an emergency declaration, the Mayor may make a fare or service adjustment for the DC Streetcar for the duration of the emergency without complying with the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term "fare or service adjustment" shall mean a change in the fare, the creation of a new route, or a significant change to an existing route or schedule of the DC Streetcar.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading>DEPARTMENT OF MOTOR VEHICLES</heading>
    <section codify:doc="D.C. Law 2-104" codify:path="I">
      <num>201</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2301.01 et seq.), is amended by adding new sections 110 and 111 to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <codify:insert history-prefix="as added"/>
          <codify:organic num-value="50-2301.10"/>
          <num>110</num>
          <heading>Reports to Department of Public Works and the District Department of Transportation.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>Before the 10th day of each month, the Department shall transmit a report to the Department of Public Works ("DPW") and the District Department of Transportation ("DDOT") with the following information from the previous month:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The number of answers filed for parking infractions, including:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>The number of "admit" answers, including ticket payments, filed for parking infractions;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>The number of "admit with explanation" answers filed for parking infractions; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>The number of "deny" answers filed for parking infractions, including:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(i)</num>
                  <text>The number of determinations of liability of respondents who deny the commission of parking infractions; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(ii)</num>
                  <text>The number of dismissals of respondents who deny the commission of parking infractions;</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The most common reasons for the dismissal of respondents who deny the commission of parking infractions;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>The badge numbers of the officers whose notices of infraction most frequently resulted in the dismissal of respondents who deny the commission of parking infractions;</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>On a quarterly basis, the Department shall transmit a report to DPW and DDOT describing relevant trends in parking infraction adjudication and dismissals of respondents who deny the commission of parking infractions.</text>
          </para>
        </section>
        <section>
          <codify:insert history-prefix="as added"/>
          <codify:organic num-value="50-2301.11"/>
          <num>111</num>
          <heading>Study of parking infraction adjudication.</heading>
          <text>Before January 2, 2017, the Mayor shall transmit to the Chairperson of the Council committee with oversight of transportation a report and recommendation as to whether the adjudication of parking infractions should be transferred from the Department to a different entity, such as the Office of Administrative Hearings or the District Department of Transportation. The report shall review best practices in other jurisdictions and examine issues such as staffing levels, timeliness of decisions, caseloads, and qualifications of hearing examiners.</text>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </section>
  </container>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="|50" after="|50|23A" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
      <num>23B</num>
      <heading>Transportation Advisory Councils.</heading>
      <container>
        <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
        <num>I</num>
        <heading>Transit Rider Advisory Council.</heading>
      </container>
      <container>
        <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
        <num>II</num>
        <heading>Multimodal Accessibility Advisory Council.</heading>
      </container>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <container codify:doc="D.C. Code">
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="50|23B"/>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>III</num>
    <heading>ADVISORY COUNCILS</heading>
    <section>
      <codify:organic path="|50|23B|I" num-value="50-2361.01"/>
      <num>301</num>
      <heading> Definitions.</heading>
      <text>For the purposes of <code-cite path="III">this title</code-cite>, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>"DDOT" means the District Department of Transportation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>"Local transit" means intra-District streetcar and bus service.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>"MAAC" means the Multimodal Accessibility Advisory Council.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>"TRAC" means the Transit Rider Advisory Council.</text>
      </para>
      <codify:not-funded-anno applicability-path="§601" action="addition of"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <codify:organic path="|50|23B|I" num-value="50-2361.02"/>
      <num>302</num>
      <heading>Transit Rider Advisory Council.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>There is established a Transit Rider Advisory Council.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The TRAC shall be composed of 11 members appointed as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Director of DDOT, or the Director’s designee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The Director of the Office of Planning, or the Director’s designee; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Nine community representatives who are District residents who regularly use local transit and who do not receive a salary from, do business with, or lobby the District government, appointed as follows:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Each Ward Councilmember shall appoint one community representative; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>The Chairperson of the Council committee with oversight over DDOT shall appoint one community representative.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The community representatives shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, with initial staggered appointments of 3 community representatives appointed for one year, 3 community representatives appointed for 2 years, and 3 community representatives appointed for 3 years. The community representatives to serve the one-year term, the community representatives to serve the 2-year term, and the community representatives to serve the 3-year term shall be determined by lot at the first meeting of the TRAC.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment to the position that became vacant. Community representatives who are appointed to fill vacancies that occur before the expiration of a community representative’s full term shall serve only the unexpired portion of the community representative’s term.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>A chairperson shall be elected from among the community representatives at the first meeting of the TRAC, for a term of 2 years, and every 2 years thereafter.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>The TRAC shall meet on a quarterly basis, and more often as needed, at times to be determined by the chairperson of the TRAC at the first meeting of the TRAC.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>DDOT shall provide the TRAC with an annual operating budget, which shall include funds to maintain a website where the TRAC shall provide a public listing of members, meeting notices, and meeting minutes.</text>
      </para>
      <codify:not-funded-anno applicability-path="§601" action="addition of"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <codify:organic path="|50|23B|I" num-value="50-2361.03"/>
      <num>303</num>
      <heading>Functions and operations of the TRAC.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>The purpose of the TRAC shall be to serve as the advisory body to the Mayor, the Council, and DDOT on matters pertaining to operating, improving, and expanding local transit.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Before the notice of a proposed fare or service adjustment is published in the District of Columbia Register, pursuant to sections <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-137" path="§11e|(a-1)">11e(a-1)</code-cite> or <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-137" path="§11r|(a-1)">11r(a-1) of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act, effective May 21, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-137; D.C. Official Code §§ 50-921.35 and 50–921.76)</code-cite>, DDOT shall submit the proposed fare or service adjustment, to the TRAC.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The TRAC may hold public hearings on the proposed fare or service adjustment.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Before the expiration of the public comment period on the proposed fare or service adjustment, the TRAC shall submit comments to DDOT on the proposed fare or service adjustment, including proposed modifications to the proposal, if any.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>If DDOT does not incorporate the TRAC’s suggested modifications in its final fare or service adjustment, DDOT shall provide the TRAC with a detailed written explanation as to why the proposed modifications were not incorporated into the final fare or service adjustment.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term "fare or service adjustment" shall mean a change in the fare, the creation of a new route, or a significant change to an existing route or schedule of the DC Circulator or DC Streetcar.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Before finalizing a strategic or long-term plan to expand and improve local transit service, DDOT shall submit a draft of the proposed plan to the TRAC.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The TRAC may hold public hearings on the proposed planning plan.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Within 45 days, the TRAC shall submit comments to DDOT on the proposed plan, including proposed modifications to the plan, if any.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>If DDOT does not incorporate the TRAC’s suggested modifications into the final plan, the agency shall provide the TRAC with a detailed written explanation as to why the proposed modifications were not incorporated into the final plan.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <codify:not-funded-anno applicability-path="§601" action="addition of"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <codify:organic path="|50|23B|II" num-value="50-2361.31"/>
      <num>304</num>
      <heading>Multimodal Accessibility Advisory Council.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>There is established a Multimodal Accessibility Advisory Council.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The MAAC shall be composed of 9 members appointed as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Director of DDOT, or the Director’s designee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The Director of the Office of Disability Rights, or the Director’s designee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The Director of the Office of Human Rights, or the Director’s designee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Six community representatives, who are District residents and who represent the disability advocacy community, appointed by the Mayor.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The community representatives shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, with initial staggered appointments of 2 community representatives appointed for one year, 2 community representatives appointed for 2 years, and 2 community representatives appointed for 3 years. The community representatives to serve the one-year term, the community representatives to serve the 2-year term, and the community representatives to serve the 3-year term shall be determined by lot at the first meeting of the MAAC.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment to the position that became vacant. Community representatives who are appointed to fill vacancies that occur before the expiration of a community representative’s full term shall serve only the unexpired portion of the community representative’s term.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>A chairperson shall be elected from among the 6 community representatives at the first meeting of the MAAC, for a term of 2 years, and every 2 years thereafter.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>The MAAC shall meet on a quarterly basis, and more often as needed, at times to be determined by the chairperson of the MAAC at the first meeting of the MAAC.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>DDOT shall provide the MAAC with reasonable and accessible accommodations for holding meetings and an annual operating budget, which shall include funds to maintain a website where the MAAC shall provide a public listing of members, meeting notices, and meeting minutes.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>The purpose of the MAAC shall be to serve as the advisory body to the Mayor, the Council, and District agencies on making local transit and public space in the District more accessible to persons with disabilities.</text>
      </para>
      <codify:not-funded-anno applicability-path="§601" action="addition of"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <codify:organic path="|50|23B|II" num-value="50-2361.32"/>
      <num>305</num>
      <heading>Discussion of advisory council recommendations.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>At least once every 6 months, the Director of DDOT, or the Director’s designee, shall meet separately with the chairperson of the Bicycle Advisory Council, the Pedestrian Advisory Council, the TRAC, and the MAAC to discuss recommendations provided by the advisory councils to DDOT.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Following each meeting held pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, DDOT shall make publicly available all recommendations discussed between DDOT and the advisory councils, DDOT’s decision in response to the recommendations, and an explanation of the decision made by DDOT.</text>
      </para>
      <codify:not-funded-anno applicability-path="§601" action="addition of"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>IV</num>
    <heading>DEPARTMENT OF FOR-HIRE VEHICLES</heading>
    <section codify:doc="D.C. Law 6-97">
      <num>401</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official Code § 50-301.01 et seq.), is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <codify:ignore/>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>The undesignated section 1 (short title) is amended by striking the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 3 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.02) is amended by striking the word "Commission" wherever it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§3" find="Commission" replace="DFHV"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§4">
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Section 4 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.03) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (6) is repealed.</text>
          <codify:repeal path="(6)"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A new paragraph (8A-i) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(8A)"/>
              <num>(8A-i)</num>
              <text>"Director" means the Director of the Department of For-Hire-Vehicles.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>New paragraphs (9A) and (9B) are added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(9)"/>
              <num>(9A)</num>
              <text>"DFHV" means the Department of For-Hire Vehicles established by <code-cite path="§5">section 5</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(9A)"/>
              <num>(9B)</num>
              <text>"FHVAC" means the For-Hire Vehicle Advisory Council established by <code-cite path="§11a">section 11a</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (15) is repealed.</text>
          <codify:repeal path="(15)"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>New paragraphs (15A), (15B), (15C), and (15D) are added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(15)"/>
              <num>(15A)</num>
              <text>"ORPP" means the Office of Regulatory Policy and Planning established by <code-cite path="§7">section 7</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(15A)"/>
              <num>(15B)</num>
              <text>"OCS" means the Office of Client Services established by <code-cite path="§7">section 7</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(15B)"/>
              <num>(15C)</num>
              <text>"OCE" means the Office of Compliance and Enforcement established by <code-cite path="§7">section 7</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(15C)"/>
              <num>(15D)</num>
              <text>"OHCR" means the Office of Hearings and Conflict Resolution established by <code-cite path="§7">section 7</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(21)">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (21) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Strike the word "Commission" and insert the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Strike the phrase "Commission-approved meter" and insert the phrase "DFHV-approved meter" in its place.</text>
          </para>
          <codify:find-replace find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="2"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (29) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(29)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (30) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(30)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§5">
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>Section 5 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.04) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The section heading is amended by striking the phrase "Establishment of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles – Established" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="heading" find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission - Established" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles – Established" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and insert the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>Section 6 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.05) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace path="§6"/>
            <num>6</num>
            <heading>Department of For-Hire Vehicles – Director.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The DFHV shall be headed by a Director. The Director shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 2-142" path="§2|(a)">section 2(a) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(a))</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The Director shall have authority over the DFHV, its functions and personnel, including the power to re-delegate to employees authority as, in the judgment of the Director, is warranted in the interests of efficiency and sound administration.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The Director may organize the personnel and property transferred herein within any organizational unit of the DFHV as the Director deems appropriate.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The Director may promulgate rules, regulations, standards, and programs to preserve, protect, and enhance the environment that are at least as stringent as corresponding federal rules, regulations, and standards.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>Section 7 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.06) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace path="§7"/>
            <num>7</num>
            <heading>Department of For-Hire Vehicles – Organization.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>There is established within the DFHV the following offices and divisions:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The Office of the Director, which shall be responsible for the management of the DFHV, including the final approval of any rulemaking and ratemaking conducted by the ORPP. The Office of the Director shall include the Director, the General Counsel, and the Chief of Staff, with subordinate staff responsible for:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Administrative support;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Human resources;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Budget and financial services;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>Technology and information services;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(E)</num>
                  <text>Contracting and procurement;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(F)</num>
                  <text>Compliance with legislative directives, analysis, and opinions to ensure appropriate rulemaking and operational activities;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(G)</num>
                  <text>Receiving confidential complaints about hack inspectors;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(H)</num>
                  <text>Providing updated facts pertaining to operations and rulemaking through various communication platforms, including press releases, testimony, speech, and the DFHV website; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(I)</num>
                  <text>Serving as a liaison between the DFHV and the District Department of Transportation on policies related to transportation.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The Office of Regulatory Policy and Planning, which shall be responsible for regulatory policy, and industry-wide research, analysis, and planning related to the regulation of the vehicle-for-hire industry. The ORPP shall be responsible for proposing ratemaking, rulemaking, and fee adjustments related to public vehicles-for-hire and submitting such proposals to the Office of the Director for final approval.  The ORPP’s subordinate staff shall also be responsible for analyzing industry updates, market data, and trends for the purpose of planning, assessment, and rulemaking.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The Office of Client Services, which shall be responsible for communicating with and educating the public and the vehicle-for-hire industry regarding rules, standards, rates, charges, and orders issued by the DFHV.  The OCS’s subordinate staff shall also be responsible for:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Administering all license examinations applicable to the taxicab industry;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Providing all training and refresher courses required by <code-cite>this act</code-cite>;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Maintaining a system of electronic public records relating to licensed owners and operators of public vehicles-for-hire and public vehicle-for-hire companies, associations, and fleets, including:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>Developing, maintaining, and keeping current a body of information relating to public vehicle-for-hire industry operations within the District, regionally, and nationwide; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>Providing statistics, analyses, studies, and projections relating to matters such as revenue, operational costs, passenger carriage, profits, practices, and technologies pertaining to the public vehicle-for-hire industry;</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>Maintaining accurate records of in-service public vehicles-for-hire and retaining those records for a minimum of 3 years;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(E)</num>
                  <text>Communicating with the vehicle-for-hire industry and members of the public to inform them of agency procedures and regulations and solicit feedback to enhance public awareness; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(F)</num>
                  <text>Accepting applications for licenses applicable to public vehicle-for-hire operators and vehicles and issuing new licenses and renewals.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The Office of Compliance and Enforcement, which shall be responsible for:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Auditing public vehicle-for-hire companies and payment service providers to the extent authorized by <code-cite>this act</code-cite>, and regulations issued pursuant to <code-cite>this act</code-cite>, including review of vehicle records to ensure compliance with regulatory requirements, and private vehicle-for-hire companies to the extent authorized by <code-cite path="§20j-7|(b)">section 20j-7(b)</code-cite>;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Administering and enforcing all rules, rates, charges, and orders issued by the DFHV;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Collecting fees to recover the actual costs of producing and distributing official DFHV vehicle decals, stickers, and information placards;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(D)</num>
                  <text>Collecting any other fees obtained pursuant to <code-cite>this act</code-cite>;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(E)</num>
                  <text>Inspecting public vehicles-for-hire for compliance with safety regulations established by the DFHV and the Department of Motor Vehicles;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(F)</num>
                  <text>Performing hack inspections and issuing notices of infraction; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(G)</num>
                  <text>Providing street enforcement of the rules and regulations of the DFHV through the use of vehicle inspection officers.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>The Office of Hearings and Conflict Resolution, which shall be responsible for conducting all hearings, adjudications, appeals, and any form of conflict resolution, including mediation.  The OHCR’s subordinate staff shall also receive, document, and manage all complaints lodged against the owners and operators of public and private vehicles-for-hire, including taxicabs, taxicab companies, associations, fleets, and dispatch services, for the violation of any rule, regulation, order, rate, or law applicable to the vehicle-for-hire industry.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§8">
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>Section 8 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.07) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The section heading is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <section>
              <num>8</num>
              <heading>Department of For-Hire Vehicles – duties; jurisdiction; powers.</heading>
            </section>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          <codify:replace path="heading">
            <heading>Department of For-Hire Vehicles – duties; jurisdiction; powers.</heading>
          </codify:replace>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Commission" wherever it appears and insert the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="Commission" replace="DFHV"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:replace path="(a)"/>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>The DFHV is charged with the continuance, further development, and improvement of the vehicle-for-hire industry within the District, and for the overall regulation of limousines, sedans, taxicabs, taxicab companies, taxicab fleets, and taxicab associations.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Subsection (b) is repealed.</text>
          <codify:repeal path="(b)"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>New subsections (b-1), (b-2), and (b-3) are added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(b)"/>
              <num>(b-1)</num>
              <text>The DFHV shall employ no fewer than 20 vehicle inspection officers to enforce the laws, rules, and regulations pertaining to public and private vehicles-for-hire. A primary function of vehicle inspection officers shall be to ensure the proper provision of service and to support safety through street enforcement efforts, including traffic stops of public and private vehicles-for-hire, pursuant to protocol prescribed by the DFHV.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(b-1)"/>
              <num>(b-2)</num>
              <text>Nothing in <code-cite>this act</code-cite> shall abrogate the authority of officers of the Metropolitan Police Force to enforce and issue citations relating to taxicab requirements.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(b-2)"/>
              <num>(b-3)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>A proposed suspension or revocation of a license by the OCE issued pursuant to <code-cite>this act</code-cite> shall not take effect until a final decision is rendered by the OHCR upon a timely appeal taken by a licensee or, if no appeal is taken, upon the lapse of the period specified, by rule, for appeal.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The OCE may immediately suspend or revoke a license issued under the authority of <code-cite>this act</code-cite> where the OCE has determined that the operator of a vehicle poses an imminent danger to the public. Within 3 business days of the issuance by the OCE of an immediate suspension or revocation, an administrative hearing shall be held before the OHCR, or the matter may be referred to the Office of Administrative Hearings, pursuant to the <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-76">Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001, effective March 6, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-76; D.C. Official Code § 2-1831.01 et seq.)</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(c)">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Subsection (c) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (14) is amended by striking the phrase "Office of Taxicabs" and inserting the word "OHCR" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace path="(14)" find="Office of Taxicabs" replace="OHCR" count="1"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (16) is amended by striking the phrase "Office of Taxicabs" and inserting the word "OCE" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace path="(16)" find="Office of Taxicabs" replace="OCE" count="1"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (17) is amended by striking the phrase "Office of Taxicabs" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace path="(17)" find="Office of Taxicabs" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(d)">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Subsection (d) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "In exercising the rulemaking" and inserting the phrase "Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, in exercising the rulemaking" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace path="(1)" find="In exercising the rulemaking" replace="Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, in exercising the rulemaking" count="1"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (2) is amended to read as follows:</text>
            <include>
              <para>
                <codify:replace path="(2)"/>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Before adjusting rates, or changing any existing fee or charge relating to public vehicles-for-hire, the DFHV shall hold at least one public hearing and publish notice of the proposed change in the District of Columbia Register. The notice shall:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>Establish a public comment period of not fewer than 45 days from the date of publication; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>Set a date for a public hearing on the proposed change, which shall be held no fewer than 20 days from the date of publication.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>In the event of an emergency declaration, the DFHV may adjust rates for public vehicles-for-hire for the duration of the emergency without complying with the requirements of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (3) is repealed.</text>
            <codify:repeal path="(3)"/>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(h)</num>
        <text>Section 8a (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.07a) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal path="§8a"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Section 8b (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.07b) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal path="§8b"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§10b">
        <num>(j)</num>
        <text>Section 10b (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.09b) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(a)">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Strike the word "Chairperson" and insert the word "Director" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace find="Chairperson" replace="Director" count="1"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Strike the phrase "Office of Taxicabs" and insert the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace find="Office of Taxicabs" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (b)(4) is amended by striking the word "Commission" both times it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(b)|(4)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="2"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(k)</num>
        <text>Section 11 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.10) is amended by striking the word "Commission" both times it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§11" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="2"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(l)</num>
        <text>A new section 11a is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:insert after="11" history-prefix="as added"/>
            <codify:organic num-value="50-301.10a" after="§50-301.10"/>
            <num>11a</num>
            <heading> For-Hire Vehicle Advisory Council.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>There is established a For-Hire Vehicle Advisory Council.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The FHVAC shall be composed of 11 members appointed as follows:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>The Director of the DFHV, or the Director’s designee;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The Director of the District Department of Transportation, or the Director’s designee;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Nine community representatives, who do not work for the District government, appointed by the Mayor as follows:</text>
                  <para>
                    <num>(i)</num>
                    <text>Two District residents who operate public or private vehicles-for-hire in the District;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(ii)</num>
                    <text>Two representatives of companies providing vehicle for-hire industry services in the District;</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iii)</num>
                    <text>Two representatives of the hospitality or tourism industry in the District; and</text>
                  </para>
                  <para>
                    <num>(iv)</num>
                    <text>Three District residents, unaffiliated with the vehicle for-hire industry, who regularly use public or private vehicles-for-hire in the District.</text>
                  </para>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>The community representatives shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, with initial staggered appointments of 3 community representatives appointed for one year, 3 community representatives appointed for 2 years, and 3 community representatives appointed for 3 years. The community representatives to serve the one-year term, the community representatives to serve the 2-year term, and the community representatives to serve the 3-year term shall be determined by lot at the first meeting of the FHVAC.</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Each community representative shall serve until the appointment of a successor. No community representative shall serve more than 2 consecutive terms, which shall not include an appointment to fill a vacancy due to removal, resignation, or death of a member. The Mayor may remove a community representative for cause. An appointment to fill a vacancy occurring during a term due to removal, resignation, or death of a member shall be made in the same manner as other appointments and for the remainder of the unexpired term.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>A chairperson shall be elected from among the 9 community representatives at the first meeting of the FHVAC, for a term of 2 years, and every 2 years thereafter.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The FHVAC shall meet on a quarterly basis, and more often as needed, at times to be determined by the chairperson of the FHVAC at the first meeting of the FHVAC.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>The DFHV shall provide the FHVAC with an annual operating budget, which shall include funds to maintain a website where the FHVAC shall provide a public listing of members, meeting notices, and meeting minutes.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <text>The purpose of the FHVAC shall be to advise the DFHV on all matters related to the regulation of the vehicle for-hire industry.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(g)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>At least once every 6 months, the Director of the DFHV, or the Director’s designee, shall meet with the chairperson of the FHVAC to discuss recommendations provided by the FHVAC to the DFHV.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Following each meeting held pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, the DFHV shall make publicly available all recommendations discussed between the DFHV and the FHVAC, the DFHV’s decision in response to the recommendations, and an explanation of the decision made by the DFHV.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        <codify:not-funded-anno path="§11a" applicability-path="§601" action="addition of"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§12">
        <num>(m)</num>
        <text>Section 12 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.11) is amended as follows.</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The section heading is amended by striking the phrase "Full Commission meetings; annual report" and inserting the phrase "Annual report; budget and oversight." in its place.</text>
          <codify:replace path="heading">
            <heading>Annual report; budget and oversight.</heading>
          </codify:replace>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is repealed.</text>
          <codify:repeal path="(a)"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Subsection (b) is repealed.</text>
          <codify:repeal path="(b)"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Subsection (c) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:replace path="(c)"/>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>The DFHV shall provide an annual report to the Council during its annual performance and budget oversight hearings.  The report shall include information and statistics relating to licensing, enforcement, training courses relating to public vehicles-for-hire, the status of taxicab equipment, estimated industry revenues, and passenger carriage, and shall outline briefly the activities and goals of the agency.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Subsection (d) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:replace path="(d)"/>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The DFHV shall periodically evaluate program development and implementation of the hacker’s license training course and may issue policy directives pertaining to program content and program direction.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(n)</num>
        <text>Section 13 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.12) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal path="§13"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§14">
        <num>(o)</num>
        <text>Section 14 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.13) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(a)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(b)">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (b) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Strike the phrase "The Commission" and insert the phrase "The DFHV" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace find="The Commission" replace="The DFHV" count="1"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Strike the phrase "by the Commission" and insert the phrase "by the DFHV" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace find="by the Commission" replace="by the DFHV" count="1"/>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Subsection (c) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(c)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Subsection (d) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(d)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Subsection (e) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(e)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§15">
        <num>(p)</num>
        <text>Section 15 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.14) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (d) is amended by striking the word "Office" both times it appears and inserting the phrase "Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(d)" find="Office" replace="Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="2"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (h) is amended by striking the phrase "and Office" both times it appears and inserting the phrase "and the Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(h)" find="and Office" replace="and the Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="2"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(q)</num>
        <text>Section 17 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.16) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal path="§17"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(r)</num>
        <text>Section 18 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.17) is amended by striking the word "Commission" both times it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§18" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="2"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(s)</num>
        <text>Section 19 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.18) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <section>
            <codify:replace path="§19"/>
            <num>19</num>
            <heading>Existing taxi regulations.</heading>
            <text>Except as modified by <code-cite>this act</code-cite>, or until changed by the Office of the Director pursuant to <code-cite>this act</code-cite>, all regulations to taxicabs contained in the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations shall remain in effect.  Within 9 months of the appointment and confirmation of the Director, the DFHV shall cause a republication of all regulations relating to taxicabs, including applicable amendments to conform the regulations to <code-cite>this act</code-cite>, and revisions issued by the DFHV.</text>
          </section>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§20">
        <num>(t)</num>
        <text>Section 20 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.19) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(a)">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace path="(1)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase "Commission-approved" and inserting the phrase "DFHV-approved" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace path="(2)" find="Commission-approved" replace="DFHV-approved"/>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(b)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Subsection (d) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(d)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(u)</num>
        <text>Section 20a (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.20) is amended by striking the word "Commission" wherever it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§20a" find="Commission" replace="DFHV"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§20d">
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>Section 20d (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.23) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The section heading is amended by striking the phrase "Taxicab Commission Fingerprinting Fund" and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles Fingerprinting Fund" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="heading" find="Taxicab Commission Fingerprinting Fund" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles Fingerprinting Fund" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "Taxicab Commission" wherever it appears and insert the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "hacker and limousine" and inserting the phrase "public vehicle-for-hire" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(a)" find="hacker and limousine" replace="public vehicle-for-hire" count="1"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§20f">
        <num>(w)</num>
        <text>Section 20f (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.25) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para codify:path="(b)">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (b) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the word "Commission" both times it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace path="(1)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="2"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (2)(A)(vii) is amended by striking the phrase "The Commission." and inserting the phrase "The Department of For-Hire Vehicles." in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace path="(2)|(A)|(vii)" find="The Commission." replace="The Department of For-Hire Vehicles." count="1"/>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (c) is amended by striking the word "Commission" wherever it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(c)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Subsection (d) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(d)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Subsection (e) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(e)" find="Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Subsection (f) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(f)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Subsection (i) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(i)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(x)</num>
        <text>Section 20f-2 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.25b) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§20f-2" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(y)</num>
        <text>Section 20g (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.26) is amended by striking the word "Commission" wherever it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§20g" find="Commission" replace="DFHV"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(z)</num>
        <text>Section 20h (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.27) is amended by striking the word "Commission" both times it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§20h" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="2"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(aa)</num>
        <text>Section 20i (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.28) is amended by striking the word "Commission" both times it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§20i" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="2"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(bb)</num>
        <text>Section 20j (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.29) is amended by striking the word "Commission" wherever it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§20j" find="Commission" replace="DFHV"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(cc)</num>
        <text>Section 20j-1 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.29a) is amended by striking the word "Commission" wherever it appears and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§20j-1" find="Commission" replace="DFHV"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(dd)</num>
        <text>Section 20j-3(c) (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.29c(c)) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="20j-3|(c)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§20j-7">
        <num>(ee)</num>
        <text>Section 20j-7 (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.29g) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Commission" wherever it appears and insert the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Commission’s" and insert the word "DFHV’s" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <codify:find-replace find="Commission" replace="DFHV"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§20l">
        <num>(ff)</num>
        <text>Section 20l (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.31) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Commission" wherever it appears and insert the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Committee" and insert the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="Committee" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Commission’s" both times it appears and insert the word "DFHV’s" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <codify:find-replace find="Commission" replace="DFHV"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§20m">
        <num>(gg)</num>
        <text>Section 20m (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.32) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The lead-in language is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="text" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "Commission’s website" and inserting the phrase "DFHV’s website" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(1)" find="Commission’s website" replace="DFHV’s website" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>A new paragraph (2A) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(2)"/>
              <num>(2A)</num>
              <text>Allow the public to file confidential complaints through a hotline and electronically in a location of its website dedicated solely to the reporting of misconduct committed by hack inspectors;</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>New paragraphs (3A) and (3B) are added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(3)"/>
              <num>(3A)</num>
              <text>Respond, in writing, to the hack inspector against whom the complaint was filed, with a detailed description of the complaint against him or her, including the time, date, and location.  Provide an opportunity for the hack inspector to respond within 48 hours of receiving the notice of a complaint filed against him or her;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <codify:insert after="(3A)"/>
              <num>(3B)</num>
              <text>Maintain, update, and hold any records and documents relating to complaints filed with the DFHV. Any dispositions by the OHCR pertaining to complaints against hack inspectors shall be submitted to and reviewed by the Office of the Director, and held on file by the agency for at least 3 years from the date of disposition;</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "OHCR" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(6)" find="Commission" replace="OHCR" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(7)" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(hh)</num>
        <text>Section 20n (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.33) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace path="§20n" find="Commission" replace="DFHV" count="1"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="§20o">
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Section 20o(c) (D.C. Official Code § 50-301.34(c)) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Chairperson" both times it appears and insert the word "Director" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="Chairperson" replace="Director" count="2"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Commission" wherever it appears and insert the word "DFHV" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="Commission" replace="DFHV"/>
        </para>
      </para>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>V</num>
    <heading> CONFORMING AMENDMENTS</heading>
    <section>
      <num>501</num>
      <heading>Conforming amendments.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Section 2(e)(24) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(e)(24)), is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal doc="D.C. Law 2-142" path="§2|(e)|(24)"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:doc="D.C. Law 2-139" codify:path="§1108">
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 1108(c) of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-611.08(c)), is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (1)(E) is repealed.</text>
          <codify:repeal path="(c)|(4)" technical="true"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (2)(K) is repealed.</text>
          <codify:repeal path="(c-2)|(3)" technical="true"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Section 6(b)(3) of the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001, effective March 6, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-76; D.C. Official Code § 2-1831.03(b)(3)), is amended by striking the phrase "Taxicab Commission" and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace doc="D.C. Law 14-76" path="§6|(b)|(3)" find="Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§47-2829">
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>Section 47–2829 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Subsection (a)(1)(E) is amended by striking the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(a)|(1)|(E)" find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" both times it appears and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(d)" find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="2"/>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(e)">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Subsection (e) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para codify:path="(1)">
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (1) is amended as follows:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Strike the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and insert the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
              <codify:find-replace find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Strike the phrase "The Commission may" and insert the phrase "The Department of For-Hire Vehicles may" in its place.</text>
              <codify:find-replace find="The Commission may" replace="The Department of For-Hire Vehicles may" count="1"/>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para codify:path="(2)">
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (2) is amended as follows:</text>
            <para codify:path="(A)">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended as follows:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(I)</num>
                <text>Strike the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and insert the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
                <codify:find-replace find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(II)</num>
                <text>Strike the phrase "Office of Taxicabs" and insert the phrase "Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
                <codify:find-replace find="Office of Taxicabs" replace="Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the phrase "Office of Taxicabs, under the direction of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and inserting the phrase "Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
              <codify:find-replace path="(C)" find="Office of Taxicabs, under the direction of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(e-1)">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Subsection (e-1) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Strike the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and insert the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Strike the phrase "Office of Taxicabs" and insert the phrase "Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace find="Office of Taxicabs" replace="Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Strike the phrase "present to the Commission" and insert the phrase "present to the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace find="present to the Commission" replace="present to the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text technical="true">Subsection (e-2) is amended by striking the phrase "After March 25, 1987, the Office of Taxicabs under the discretion of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission, and prior to March 25, 1987, the Department of Public Works" and inserting the phrase "The Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(e-2)" find="After March 25, 1987, the Office of Taxicabs under the direction of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission, and prior to March 25, 1987, the Department of Public Works" replace="The Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Subsection (e-3) is amended by striking the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(e-3)" find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(e-4)">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Subsection (e-4) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text technical="true">Strike the phrase "After March 25, 1987, the Office of Taxicabs under the discretion of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission, and prior to March 25, 1987, the Department of Public Works" and insert the phrase "The Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace find="After March 25, 1987, the Office of Taxicabs under the direction of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission, and prior to March 25, 1987, the Department of Public Works" replace="The Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Strike the phrase "The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and insert the phrase "The Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
            <codify:find-replace find="The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="The Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Subsection (i) is amended by striking the phrase "the Office of Taxicabs" and inserting the phrase "the Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(i)" find="the Office of Taxicabs" replace="the Office of Client Services of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para codify:path="(j)">
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Subsection (j) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para codify:path="(1)">
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (1) is amended as follows:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Strike the phrase "The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and insert the phrase "The Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
              <codify:find-replace find="The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="The Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Strike the phrase "the Commission shall" and insert the phrase "the Department of For-Hire Vehicles shall" in its place.</text>
              <codify:find-replace find="the Commission shall" replace="the Department of For-Hire Vehicles shall" count="1"/>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (3) is repealed.</text>
            <codify:repeal path="(3)"/>
          </para>
          <para codify:path="(4)">
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (4) is amended as follows:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Strike the phrase "The Commission shall" and insert the phrase "The Department of For-Hire Vehicles shall" in its place.</text>
              <codify:find-replace find="The Commission shall" replace="The Department of For-Hire Vehicles shall" count="1"/>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Strike the phrase "granted by the Commission" and insert the phrase "granted by the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
              <codify:find-replace find="granted by the Commission" replace="granted by the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Paragraph (5) is amended to read as follows:</text>
            <include>
              <para>
                <codify:replace path="(5)"/>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>The Department of For-Hire Vehicles shall seek to actively license public vehicle-for hire drivers and vehicles.</text>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>Section 47-2853.04(c)(5) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2853.04|(c)|(5)" find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>Section 47–2862(a)(1)(E) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2862|(a)|(1)|(E)" find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>Section 102(b)(11) of the Employee Transportation Amendment Act of 2012, effective March 5, 2013 (D.C. Law 19-223; D.C. Official Code § 50-211.02(b)(11)), is amended by striking the phrase "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and inserting the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace doc="D.C. Law 19-223" path="§102|(b)|(11)" find="District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:doc="D.C. Law 9-199" codify:path="§2">
        <num>(h)</num>
        <text>Section 2 of the Taxicab and Passenger Vehicle for Hire Impoundment Act of 1992, effective March 16, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-199; D.C. Official Code § 50-331), is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Commission" both times it appears and insert the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Commission’s" wherever it appears and insert the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Strike the word "Chairperson" and insert the word "Director" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="Chairperson" replace="Director" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "Office of Taxicabs" and insert the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="Office of Taxicabs" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="2" technical="true"/>
        </para>
        <codify:find-replace find="Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles"/>
      </para>
      <para codify:doc="D.C. Law 11-198" codify:path="§505">
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Section 505 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-198; D.C. Official Code § 50-332), is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "Taxicab Commission" wherever it appears and insert the phrase "Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="Taxicab Commission" replace="Department of For-Hire Vehicles"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "Public Works and the Environment" both times it appears and insert the phrase "Transportation and the Environment" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="Public Works and the Environment" replace="Transportation and the Environment" count="2"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "Taxicab Hack Inspectors" and insert the phrase "vehicle inspection officers" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace find="Taxicab Hack Inspectors" replace="vehicle inspection officers" count="1"/>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para codify:doc="Stat. 75-1-ch690" codify:path="§3a|(b)">
        <num>(j)</num>
        <text>Section 3a(b) of the Non-Resident Taxi Drivers Registration Amendment Act of 2008, effective March 26, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-130; D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.03a(b)), is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "the Chairperson of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" and inserting the phrase "the Director of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace path="(1)" find="the Chairperson of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission" replace="the Director of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles" count="1"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase "used for the operational or capital needs of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission." and inserting the phrase "deposited in the Public Vehicles-for-Hire Consumer Service Fund, established by section 20a of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official Code § 50-301.)." in its place.</text>
          <codify:find-replace count="1">
            <find>used for the operational or capital needs of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission.</find>
            <replace>deposited in the Public Vehicles-for-Hire Consumer Service Fund, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 6-97" path="§20a" technical="should be '50-301.01'">section 20a of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official Code § 50-301.)</code-cite>.</replace>
          </codify:find-replace>
        </para>
      </para>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>VI</num>
    <heading>FISCAL IMPACT STATEMENT; EFFECTIVE DATE</heading>
    <section>
      <num>601</num>
      <heading>Applicability.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Sections 301, 302, 303, 304, 305, and 401(l) shall apply upon the date of inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <codify:applicability path="§301" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability path="§302" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability path="§303" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability path="§304" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability path="§305" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability path="§401|(l)" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>602</num>
      <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
      <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>603</num>
      <heading>Effective date.</heading>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </section>
  </container>
</document>
