<document 
  xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" 
  xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" 
  xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" 
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-175">
  <num type="law">21-175</num>
  <num type="bill">21-853</num>
  <num type="act">21-509</num>
  <heading type="short">Senior Law Enforcement Officer Temporary Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Retired Police Officer Redeployment Amendment Act of 1992 to authorize the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department to pay Metropolitan Police Department police officers who retired at a rank other than Officer and who are rehired a salary of not more than the salary paid for specified service steps.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2016-12-17</effective>
    <temporary>true</temporary>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/36361/B21-0853-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-175</citation>
      <citation type="register">63 DCR 13571</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2016-09-20" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-10-11" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2016-10-27</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Senior Law Enforcement Officer Temporary Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-761"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 2 of the Retired Police Officer Redeployment Amendment Act of 1992, effective September 29, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-163; D.C. Official Code § 5-761), is amended by adding a new subsection (h) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(h)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, a police officer who retired at a rank other than Officer who is rehired under subsection (a) of this section shall be eligible to be paid for the duration of rehire a salary of no more than the salary paid at the following service steps:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Class 1 (Officer) – Step 5;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Class 3 (Detective Grade 1) – Step 4; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Class 4 (Sergeant) – Step 3.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>