<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-184">
  <num type="law">21-184</num>
  <num type="bill">21-321</num>
  <num type="act">21-538</num>
  <heading type="short">Kennedy Street, N.W., Economic Development and Small Business Revitalization Advisory Committee Establishment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To establish the Kennedy Street, N.W., Economic Development and Small Business Revitalization Advisory Committee.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-07-14</introduced>
    <effective>2017-02-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/34286/Signed_Act/B21-0321-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-184</citation>
      <citation type="register">63 DCR 14353</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0321">
      <vote date="2016-10-18" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-11-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2016-11-18</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-184 establishes the Kennedy Street, N.W., Economic Development and Small Business Revitalization Advisory Committee. It specifies that the committee shall consist of 11 members, including a chairperson designated by the Councilmember for Ward 4. The Committee shall meet at least every quarter and provide recommendations to the Mayor and Council regarding the needs of the community, parking and transportation, and economic development opportunities. The Committee shall dissolve on December 31, 2020.</summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Kennedy Street, N.W., Economic Development and Small Business Revitalization Advisory Committee Establishment Act of 2016".</text>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="|2|12" after="V-C" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>V-D</num>
      <heading>Kennedy Street, N.W., Economic Development and Small Business Revitalization Advisory Committee.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="|2|12|V-D" num-value="2-1210.61"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Kennedy Street, N.W., Economic Development and Small Business Revitalization Advisory Committee.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is established the Kennedy Street, N.W., Economic Development and Small Business Revitalization Advisory Committee ("Committee").</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Committee shall consist of the following 11 members:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development or his or her designee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Office of Planning or his or her designee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The Councilmember from Ward 4 or his or her designee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Two business owners from the Kennedy Street, N.W., district, chosen by the Council Chairman from recommendations made by the Councilmember for Ward 4;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs or his or her designee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>Two members from the Kennedy Street, N.W., community, chosen by the Council Chairman from recommendations made by the Councilmember for Ward 4;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>One member chosen by Advisory Neighborhood Commission 4D;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(8)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Department of Small and Local Business Development or his or her designee; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(9)</num>
        <text>One member chosen by the Washington DC Economic Partnership.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Vacancies in the membership of the Committee shall be filled in same manner as individual appointments.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>All members of the Committee shall be District residents.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Chairperson of the Committee shall be designated by the Councilmember for Ward 4.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Members of the Committee shall serve without compensation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The Committee shall meet no less frequently than quarterly.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The purpose of the committee shall be to provide recommendations to the Mayor and Council regarding the portion of Kennedy Street, N.W., running from North Capitol Street to 14th Street, N.W., with respect to the following matters:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Implementation of recommendations of the Kennedy Street small area plan (the "Kennedy Street Revitalization Plan") adopted by the Council pursuant to the Kennedy Street Revitalization Plan Approval Resolution of 2008, effective July 15, 2008 (Res. 17-705; 55 DCR 8414);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The needs of the community, including providing retail uses that are accessible to the community and serve the needs of both the community and visitors to Kennedy Street, N.W.;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Parking and transportation issues; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Economic development opportunities that may be created for surrounding neighborhoods as a result of the Kennedy Street Revitalization Plan.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The Committee shall submit a report that includes its recommendations to the Mayor and Council after each meeting of the Committee.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The Committee shall dissolve as of December 31, 2020.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code§ 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(l)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
