<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 21-15">
  <num type="law">21-15</num>
  <num type="bill">21-76</num>
  <num type="act">21-68</num>
  <heading type="short">Events DC Technical Clarification Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994 to delete obsolete provisions, to clarify that the President of the Hotel Association of Washington, D.C. shall serve as an ex-officio voting member of the Board of Directors, and to repeal the establishment of the Washington Convention Center Advisory Committee.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-02-19</introduced>
    <effective>2015-07-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/33394/Signed_Act/B21-0076-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-15</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 6872</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0076">
      <vote date="2015-04-14" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-05-22</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-15 makes technical amendments, repealing language that is no longer applicable regarding the makeup of the Board of Directors (Board) of the Washington Convention and Sports Authority, also known as Events DC. This legislation specifies that the Board is comprised of 12 members, including 9 public members and 3 ex-officio members; and public Board members are required to serve 4 year terms. It clarifies that the President of the Hotel Association of Washington, D.C. serves as an ex-officio voting member of the Board. It also repeals the establishment of the Washington Convention Center Advisory Committee. </summary>
      <committee>Finance and Revenue</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Events DC Technical Clarification Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Title II of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective September 28, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-188; D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 205 (D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.05) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The Authority shall be governed by a Board of Directors ("Board"), which shall be comprised of 12 members, including the 9 members appointed pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection ("public Board members") and the following individuals, each of whom shall serve as an ex-officio voting member:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>The Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>The President of the Hotel Association of Washington, D.C.; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>An individual designated by the Mayor.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (5) is repealed.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (b)(1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>All public Board member terms shall be 4-year terms.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Subjection (g) is amended by striking the phrase "Each Board member" and inserting the phrase "Each public Board member" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Subsection (j) is amended by striking the word "Six" and inserting the word "Seven" in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 218 (D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.18) is repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § l-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(l) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approve December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(l)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
