<document 
  xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" 
  xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" 
  xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" 
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-178">
  <num type="law">21-178</num>
  <num type="bill">21-859</num>
  <num type="act">21-519</num>
  <heading type="short">Extension of Time to Dispose of 1300 H Street, N.E., and Approval of Amended Term Sheet Temporary Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes to extend the time in which the Mayor may dispose of certain District-owned real property commonly referred to as the R.L. Christian Community Library, located at 1300 H Street, N.E., known for tax and assessment purposes as Lots 97, 98, 99, 100, 101, 102, and 103 in Square 1026.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2016-12-28</effective>
    <temporary>true</temporary>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/36370/B21-0859-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-178</citation>
      <citation type="register">63 DCR 13593</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2016-09-20" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-10-11" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2016-10-31</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Extension of Time to Dispose of 1300 H Street, N.E., and Approval of Amended Term Sheet Temporary Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง10-801"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 1 of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code ยง 10-801), is amended by adding a new subsection (d-8) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(d-8)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, the time period within which the Mayor may dispose of District-owned real property located at 1300 H Street, N.E., known for tax and assessment purposes as  Lots 97, 98, 99, 100, 101, 102, and 103 in Square 1026, for the construction of a mixed-use residential and retail development pursuant to the 1300 H Street, N.E. Disposition Approval Resolution of 2014, effective September 23, 2014  (Res. 20-600; 61 DCR 10470), and section 3 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of 1300 H Street, N.E., and Approval of Amended Term Sheet Emergency Amendment Act of 2016, effective October 12, 2016 (D.C. Act 21-502; 63 DCR ___), is extended to March 23, 2017.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional reviewas provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>