<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document  xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" 
  xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" 
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-121">
  <codify:ignore/>
  <num type="law">21-121</num>
  <num type="bill">21-366</num>
  <num type="act">21-375</num>
  <heading type="short">Firehouse Parking Exception Regulation Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend section 2406 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations to require the Director of the District Department of Transportation ("DDOT") to coordinate with the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department ("FEMS") to ensure adequate parking for FEMS personnel near firehouses or fire stations and to authorize the Director of DDOT to reserve parking spaces near a firehouse or fire station to accommodate one on-duty platoon of FEMS personnel.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2016-06-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/34502/B21-0366-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-121</citation>
      <citation type="register">63 DCR 6862</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2016-03-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-04-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2016-04-26</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-121 authorizes the Director of the District Department of Transportation (DDOT) to coordinate with the Fire and Emergency Medical Services (FEMS) reserve parking spaces near firehouses or fire stations for FEMS Department Personnel. To do so, the director is authorized to place signs restricting parking to FEMS personnel. The spaces must be within sixty feet of the building and may be in front, alongside, or behind the building.</summary>
      <committee>Committee on Transportation and the Environment</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Firehouse Parking Exception Regulation Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 2406 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal</text>
    <text>Regulations (18 DCMR ยง 2406) is amended by adding new subsections 2406.19 and 2406.20 to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>2406.19</num>
        <text>The Director of the District Department of Transportation shall coordinate with the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department ("FEMS") to ensure adequate parking at District firehouses and fire stations.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>2406.20</num>
        <text>If a firehouse or fire station does not have adequate on-site parking to accommodate the personnel of one on-duty platoon, the Director of the District Department of Transportation may reserve parking within a distance not to exceed sixty feet (60 ft.) along the curb in front of, behind, or alongside of any building occupied by a firehouse or fire station for vehicles bearing special permits for FEMS personnel; provided, that the Director of the District Department of Transportation shall only reserve parking pursuant to this subsection to the extent necessary to accommodate parking at each firehouse or fire station for the personnel of one on-duty platoon.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(l) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(l)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
