<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 21-14">
  <num type="law">21-14</num>
  <num type="bill">21-25</num>
  <num type="act">21-67</num>
  <heading type="short">Prohibition of Pre-Employment Marijuana Testing Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To prohibit employers from testing potential employees for marijuana use during the hiring process, unless otherwise required by law.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-01-06</introduced>
    <effective>2015-07-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/33218/Signed_Act/B21-0025-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-14</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 6870</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0025">
      <vote date="2015-04-14" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-05-22</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-14 prohibits employers from testing job applicants for marijuana until a conditional offer has been accepted, unless prior testing is required by law. It also requires the Mayor to: (1) conduct a public information campaign that focuses on the impact of marijuana use and abuse; (2) report to the Council regarding substance abuse education in District schools, inclusive of marijuana use education; and (3) evaluate the effectiveness of the district's treatment programs in relation to the use and abuse of marijuana. </summary>
      <committee>Business, Consumer, and Regulatory Affairs</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Prohibition of Pre-Employment Marijuana Testing Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Restriction on pre-employment marijuana testing.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An employer may only test a prospective employee for marijuana use after a conditional offer of employment has been extended, unless otherwise required by law.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Nothing in this act shall be construed to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Affect employee compliance with employer workplace drug policies;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Require an employer to permit or accommodate the use, consumption, possession, transfer, display, transportation, sale, or growing of marijuana in the workplace or at any time during employment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Interfere with federal employment contracts; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Prevent the employer from denying a position based on a positive test for marijuana.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>"Employer" shall have the same meaning as provided in section 2(6) of the District of Columbia Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-186; D.C. Official Code ยง 32-1101(6)).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>"Prospective employee" means any individual applying for employment with an employer.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Reporting.</heading>
    <text>Within 6 months after the effective date of this act, the Mayor shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Establish a public information campaign aimed at educating the public on the impact of marijuana use and abuse;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Report to the Council the type, frequency, provider, and school grade level of health<strong>-</strong>education programs in public schools related to substance abuse, including programs designed to address alcohol, tobacco, and marijuana use; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Evaluate the effectiveness of the District government's treatment programs regarding the use and abuse of marijuana.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02 (c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
