<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 21-25">
  <num type="law">21-25</num>
  <num type="bill">21-209</num>
  <num type="act">21-97</num>
  <heading type="short">Heat Wave Safety Temporary Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Retail Electric Competition and Consumer Protection Act of 1999 to prohibit the electric company from disconnecting residential electric service when the heat index is forecasted to be 95 degrees Fahrenheit or above.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2015-09-23</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/33832/B21-0209-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-25</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 9454</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0209">
      <vote date="2015-06-02" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2015-06-16" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-07-02</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Heat Wave Safety Temporary Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Retail Electric Competition and Consumer Protection Act of 1999, effective May 9, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-107; D.C. Official Code ยง 34-1501 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended by adding a new section 106a to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <num>106a</num>
        <heading>Disconnection of service in extreme temperature prohibited.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "forecast of extreme temperature" means a National Weather Service forecast that the heat index for the District of Columbia will be 95 degrees Fahrenheit or above at any time during a day.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>The electric company shall not disconnect residential electric service during the day preceding, and the day of, a forecast of extreme temperature. If the forecast of extreme temperature precedes a holiday or weekend day, the electric company shall not disconnect residential electric service on any day during the holiday or weekend.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved  December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
