<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-234">
  <num type="law">21-234</num>
  <num type="bill">21-953</num>
  <num type="act">21-618</num>
  <heading type="short">Medical Marijuana Dispensary Temporary Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1999 to increase the number of medical marijuana dispensaries that may be registered to operate in the District from 5 to 6, and to require the Mayor to open an application period for the registration of a medical marijuana dispensary in Ward 7 or Ward 8.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-04-01</effective>
    <temporary>true</temporary>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/36798/B21-0943-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-234</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 883</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-01-24</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Medical Marijuana Dispensary Temporary Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 7(d)(2) of the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1999, effective July 27, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-210; D.C. Official Code ยง 7-1671.06(d)(2)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the number "5" and inserting the number "6" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new subparagraph (D) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall open an application period for the registration of a dispensary in Ward 7 or Ward 8 within 60 days after the effective date of the Medical Marijuana Dispensary Emergency Amendment Act of 2016, passed on emergency basis on December 6, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-952).</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง7-1671.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
