<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-207">
  <num type="law">21-207</num>
  <num type="bill">21-934</num>
  <num type="act">21-563</num>
  <heading type="short">Public School Nurse Assignment Temporary Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987 to require that any public school receiving school nurse services above 20 hours per week as of October 25, 2016 continue at that existing level of service, or the level recommended by the Department of Health's risk-based assessment, whichever is greater, for the remainder of school year 2016-2017.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2016-11-01</introduced>
    <effective>2017-02-18</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/36753/Signed_Act/B21-0934-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-207</citation>
      <citation type="register">63 DCR 15054</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0934">
      <vote date="2016-11-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-11-15" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2016-12-06</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public School Nurse Assignment Temporary Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  <section>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง38-621"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 2 of the District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987, effective December 10, 1987 (D.C. Law 7-45; D.C. Official Code ยง 38-621), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (c) is repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new subsection (c-1) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(c-1)</num>
          <text>Any school that, on October 25, 2016, received school nurse services pursuant to this section that exceeded the minimum hours per week prescribed by subsection (b) of this section shall continue the level of service existing on that date, or the level recommended by the Department of Health's risk-based assessment, whichever is greater, for the remainder of school year 2016-2017.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813, D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
