<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 21-27">
  <num type="law">21-27</num>
  <num type="bill">21-157</num>
  <num type="act">21-99</num>
  <heading type="short">Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Request Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To adopt the request of the District of Columbia government for appropriation and authorization for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-04-02</introduced>
    <effective>2015-09-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/33642/Signed_Act/B21-0157-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-27</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 9658</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0157">
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2015-05-27" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2015-06-10" reading="Final"/>
      <vote date="2015-06-10" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-07-09</enacted>
      <summary>An enrolled bill was first transmitted to the Mayor on June 22, 2015 and was returned on July 6, 2015.  A re-enrolled bill was transmitted on July 9, 2015 and was returned on July 10, 2015.</summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Request Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>The Council of the District of Columbia approves the following expenditure levels and appropriation language for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>DIVISION</prefix>
      <num>A</num>
      <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APPROPRIATION REQUEST</heading>
      <text>
        <strong>TITLE I -- FEDERAL FUNDS</strong>
      </text>
      <text>
        <strong>FEDERAL PAYMENT TO THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COURTS</strong>
      </text>
      <text>For salaries and expenses for the District of Columbia Courts, $274,401,000, to be allocated as follows: for the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, $14,192,000, of which not to exceed $2,500 is for official reception and representation expenses; for the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, $123,638,000, of which not to exceed $2,500 is for official reception and representation expenses; for the District of Columbia Court System, $73,981,000, of which not to exceed $2,500 is for official reception and representation expenses; and $62,590,000, to remain available until September 30, 2017, for capital improvements for District of Columbia courthouse facilities: Provided, That funds made available for capital improvements shall be expended consistent with the District of Columbia Courts master plan study and facilities condition assessment: Provided further, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, all amounts under this heading shall be apportioned quarterly by the Office of Management and Budget and obligated and expended in the same manner as funds appropriated for salaries and expenses of other Federal agencies: Provided further, That 30 days after providing written notice to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the District of Columbia Courts may reallocate not more than $6,000,000 of the funds provided under this heading among the items and entities funded under this heading: Provided further, That the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration in the District of Columbia may, by regulation, establish a program substantially similar to the program set forth in subchapter II of chapter 35 of title 5, United States Code, for employees of the District of Columbia Courts.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR DEFENDER SERVICES IN DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COURTS</heading>
      <text>For payments authorized under section 11-2604 and section 11-2605, D.C. Official Code (relating to representation provided under the District of Columbia Criminal Justice Act), payments for counsel appointed in proceedings in the Family Court of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia under chapter 23 of title 16, D.C. Official Code, or pursuant to contractual agreements to provide guardian ad litem representation, training, technical assistance, and such other services as are necessary to improve the quality of guardian ad litem representation, payments for counsel appointed in adoption proceedings under chapter 3 of title 16, D.C. Official Code, and payments authorized under section 21-2060, D.C. Official Code (relating to services provided under the District of Columbia Guardianship, Protective Proceedings, and Durable Power of Attorney Act of 1986), $49,890,000, to remain available until expended: Provided, That funds provided under this heading shall be administered by the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration in the District of Columbia: Provided further, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, this appropriation shall be apportioned quarterly by the Office of Management and Budget and obligated and expended in the same manner as funds appropriated for expenses of other Federal agencies.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR RESIDENT TUITION SUPPORT</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia, to be deposited into a dedicated account, for a nationwide program to be administered by the Mayor, for District of Columbia resident tuition support, $40,000,000, to remain available until expended: Provided, That such funds, including any interest accrued thereon, may be used on behalf of eligible District of Columbia residents to pay an amount based upon the difference between in-State and out-of-State tuition at public institutions of higher education, or to pay up to $2,500 each year at eligible private institutions of higher education: Provided further, That the awarding of such funds may be prioritized on the basis of a resident's academic merit, the income and need of eligible students, and such other factors as may be authorized: Provided further, That the District of Columbia government shall maintain a dedicated account for the Resident Tuition Support Program that shall consist of the Federal funds appropriated to the Program in this Act and any subsequent appropriations, any unobligated balances from prior fiscal years, and any interest earned in this or any fiscal year: Provided further, That the account shall be under the control of the District of Columbia Chief Financial Officer, who shall use those funds solely for the purposes of carrying out the Resident Tuition Support Program: Provided further, That the Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall provide a quarterly financial report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate for these funds showing, by object class, the expenditures made and the purpose therefor.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR SCHOOL IMPROVEMENT</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment for a school improvement program in the District of Columbia, $43,200,000, to remain available until expended, for payments authorized under the Scholarship for Opportunity and Results Act (division C of Public Law 112-10)<em>, </em>to be allocated as follows: for the District of Columbia Public Schools, $20,000,000 to improve public school education in the District of Columbia; for the State Education Office, $20,000,000 to expand quality public charter schools in the District of Columbia: Provided, That within funds provided for opportunity scholarships $3,200,000 shall be for the activities specified in sections 3007(b) through 3007(d) and 3009 of the Act.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT TO THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WATER AND SEWER AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, $24,300,000, to remain available until expended, to continue implementation of the Combined Sewer Overflow Long-Term Plan: Provided, That the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority provides a 100 percent match for this payment.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT TO THE CRIMINAL JUSTICE COORDINATING COUNCIL</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, $1,900,000, to remain available until expended, to support initiatives related to the coordination of Federal and local criminal justice resources in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR JUDICIAL COMMISSIONS</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment, to remain available until September 30, 2017, to the Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure, $295,000, and for the Judicial Nomination Commission, $270,000.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NATIONAL GUARD</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia National Guard, $435,000, to remain available until expended for the Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Program.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR CLIMATE RISK MANAGEMENT</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia for development of a climate change adaptation plan to identify climate risks to the District of Columbia, vulnerabilities, and mitigation options, $750,000.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR DC SOLAR POWER INITIATIVE</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia for the expansion of the D.C. Department of Environment's EnergySmart D.C. Solar Initiative, $1,000,000.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR ST. ELIZABETHS EAST CAMPUS DEVELOPMENT</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia for establishment of the St. Elizabeths Research and Development Innovation Center on the East Campus of the St. Elizabeths campus in Washington, D.C., $9,800,000.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia for construction of new transitional housing units for homeless families in the District of Columbia, $6,000,000.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR ARTS AND CULTURAL AFFAIRS GRANTS</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia Commission on Arts and Humanities for competitive grants for general operating support for District-based organizations whose primary function is the exhibition or presentation of, or training in, fine arts and humanities in the District of Columbia, $1,000,000.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR MASS TRANSIT INNOVATION PLAN</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority to fund a strategic plan for regional mass transit innovation, $1,000,000.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR TESTING AND TREATMENT OF HIV/AIDS</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment to the District of Columbia for the testing of individuals for, and the treatment of individuals with, human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immunodeficiency syndrome in the District of Columbia, $5,000,000.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FEDERAL PAYMENT FOR EMERGENCY PLANNING AND SECURITY COSTS IN THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</heading>
      <text>For a Federal payment of necessary expenses, as determined by the Mayor of the District of Columbia in written consultation with the elected county or city officials of surrounding jurisdictions, $14,900,000, to remain available until expended, for the costs of providing public safety at events related to the presence of the National Capital in the District of Columbia, including support requested by the Director of the United States Secret Service in carrying out protective duties under the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for the costs of providing support to respond to immediate and specific terrorist threats or attacks in the District of Columbia or surrounding jurisdictions.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
      <num>II</num>
      <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA FUNDS--SUMMARY OF EXPENSES</heading>
      <text>The following amounts are appropriated for the District of Columbia for the current fiscal year out of the General Fund of the District of Columbia ("General Fund"), except as otherwise specifically provided; provided, that notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in section 450A of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved November 2, 2000 (114 Stat. 2440; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.50a), and provisions of this Act, the total amount appropriated in this Act for operating expenses for the District of Columbia for fiscal year 2016 under this heading shall not exceed the lesser of the sum of the total revenues of the District of Columbia for such fiscal year or $13,021,761,000 (of which $7,355,059,000 shall be from local funds (including $320,375,000 from dedicated taxes), $983,019,000 shall be from Federal grant funds, $2,174,640,000 shall be from Medicaid payments, $587,347,000 shall be from other funds, $1,501,000 shall be from private funds, $116,350,000 shall be from funds previously appropriated in this Act as Federal payments, which does not include funds appropriated under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, approved February 17, 2009 (123 Stat. 115; 26 U.S.C. § 1, note), and $1,803,846,000 shall be from enterprise and other funds); provided further, that of the local funds, such amounts as may be necessary may be derived from the District's General Fund balance; provided further, that of these funds the District's intra-District authority shall be $807,710,000; in addition, for capital construction projects, an increase of $1,934,887,000, of which $1,508,479,000 shall be from local funds, $104,880,000 from the Local Transportation Fund, $106,000,000 from Federal Payment funds, $11,693,000 from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, and $203,835,000 from Federal grant funds, and a rescission of  $820,278,000, of which $732,349,000 is from local funds, $12,500,000 from private grant funds, $16,208,000 from the Local Transportation Fund, $16,545,000 from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, and $42,676,000 from Federal grant funds appropriated under this heading in prior fiscal years, for a net amount of $1,114,608,000, to remain available until expended; provided further, that the amounts provided under this heading are to be available, allocated, and expended as proposed under this title and Title III of this Act, at the rate set forth under "District of Columbia Funds Division of Expenses" as included in the Fiscal Year 2016 Proposed Budget and Financial Plan submitted to the Congress by the District of Columbia; provided further, that this amount may be increased by proceeds of one-time transactions, which are expended for emergency or unanticipated operating or capital needs; provided further, that such increases shall be approved by enactment of local District law and shall comply with all reserve requirements contained in the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 777; D.C. Official Code § 1- 201.01 et seq.), as amended by this Act; provided further, that the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia shall take such steps as are necessary to ensure that the District of Columbia meets these requirements, including the apportioning by the Chief Financial Officer of the appropriations and funds made available to the District during fiscal year 2016; except, that the Chief Financial Officer may not reprogram for operating expenses any funds derived from bonds, notes, or other obligations issued for capital projects.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
      <num>III</num>
      <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA FUNDS - - DIVISION OF EXPENSES OPERATING EXPENSES GOVERNMENTAL DIRECTION AND SUPPORT</heading>
      <text>Governmental direction and support, $ 786,472,000 (including $687,150,000 from local funds, $29,259,000 from Federal grant funds, $69,645,000 from other funds, and $408,000 from private funds); provided; that there are appropriated such additional amounts as may be necessary to account for vendor fees that are paid as a fixed percentage of revenue recovered from third parties on behalf of the District under contracts that provide for payments of fees based upon such revenue as may be collected by the vendor; provided further, that any program fees collected from the issuance of debt shall be available for the payment of expenses of the debt management program of the District, to be allocated as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Council of the District of Columbia. – $22,321,000 from local funds; provided, that not to exceed $25,000 shall be available for the Chairman from this appropriation for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10); provided, that all funds deposited into the Council Technology Projects Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Office of the District of Columbia Auditor. – $4,663,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Advisory Neighborhood Commissions. – $927,000 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited into the Agency Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Uniform Law Commission. – $50,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Office of the Mayor. – $11,111,000 (including $ 7,825,000 from local funds and $3,286,000 from Federal grant funds); provided, that not to exceed $25,000 shall be available for the Mayor for official reception and representation expenses; provided further, all interest earned on the funds that the District of Columbia received pursuant to the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2000, approved November 29, 1999 (113 Stat. 1501; Pub. L. No. 106-113), under the heading "Federal Payment for the Incentives for Adoption of Children" and for the establishment of a scholarship fund for District of Columbia children without parents due to the September 11, 2001 terrorist attack under this same heading, pursuant to the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2001, approved December 21, 2001 (115 Stat. 923; Pub. L. No. 107-96), shall be retained in the Fund without reversion to the General Fund and shall be available to the District of Columbia for the purposes of the Fund until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Mayor's Office of Legal Counsel. – $1,596,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Office of the Senior Advisor. – $1,894,000 from local funds ;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Office of the City Administrator. –$6,420,000 (including $6,129,000 from local funds and $291,000 from other funds); provided, that not to exceed $10,600 shall be available for the City Administrator for official reception and representation expenses;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Deputy Mayor for Greater Economic Opportunity. – $698,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>D.C. Office of Risk Management. – $2,923,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>D.C. Department of Human Resources. – $8,627,000 (including $8,175,000 from local funds and $452,000 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Office of Disability Rights. – $1,606,000 (including $1,070,000 from local funds and $536,000 from Federal grant funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Captive Insurance Agency. – $1,489,000 (including $1,422,000 from local funds and $67,000 from other funds); provided that all funds deposited into the Agency Fund (Free Standing Clinics/Insurance) Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Captive Insurance Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>Office of Finance and Resource Management. – $21,873,000 (including  $21,572,000 from local funds and $301,000 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>Office of Contracting and Procurement. – $21,343,000 (including $20,968,000 from local funds and $375,000 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(16)</num>
          <text>Office of the Chief Technology Officer. – $72,531,000 (including $58,268,000 from local funds, $114,000 from Federal grant funds, and $14,149,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the D.C. Net Service Support Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(17)</num>
          <text>Department of General Services. – $324,253,000 (including $317,877,000 from local funds and $6,376,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Eastern Market Enterprise Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Department of General Services Stormwater Retention Credit Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(18)</num>
          <text>Contract Appeals Board. – $1,449,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(19)</num>
          <text>Board of Elections. – $7,390,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(20)</num>
          <text>Office of Campaign Finance. – $2,704,000 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited into the Special Purpose Revenue fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(21)</num>
          <text>Public Employee Relations Board. – $1,274,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(22)</num>
          <text>Office of Employee Appeals. – $1,745,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(23)</num>
          <text>Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments. –$472,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(24)</num>
          <text>Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia. – $81,567,000 (including $57,133,000 from local funds, $22,177,000 from Federal grant funds, $1,849,000 from other funds, and $408,000 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Child SPT - TANF/AFDC Collections Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Child SPT -Reimbursements and Fees Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Child SPT - Interest Income Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Nuisance Abatement Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Litigation Support Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that not to exceed $10,600 shall be available for the Attorney General for official reception and representation expenses;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(25)</num>
          <text>D.C. Board of Ethics and Government Accountability. – $1,774,000 (including $1,684,000 from local funds and $90,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Lobbyist Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Board of Ethics and Accountability Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(26)</num>
          <text>Statehood Initiatives Agency. – $230,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(27)</num>
          <text>Office of the Inspector General. – $17,215,000 (including $14,595,000 from local funds and $2,620,000 from Federal grant funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(28)</num>
          <text>Office of the Chief Financial Officer. – $162,865,000 (including $118,144,000 from local funds, $525,000 from Federal grant funds, and $44,196,000 from other funds); provided, that not to exceed $10,600 shall be available for the Chief Financial Officer for official reception and representation expenses; provided further, that amounts appropriated by this Act may be increased by the amount required to pay banking fees for maintaining the funds of the District of Columbia; provided further, that all funds deposited into the OFT Central Collection Unit Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Recorder of Deeds Surcharge Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(29)</num>
          <text>Office of the Secretary. - $3,463,000 (including $1,963,000 from local funds and $1,500,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Emancipation Day Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</heading>
      <text>Economic development and regulation, $547,063,000 (including $254,832,000 from local funds (including $1,170,000 from dedicated taxes), $100,370,000 from Federal grant funds, $187,713,000 from other funds, $348,000 from private funds, $9,800,000 from funds previously appropriated from this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for St. Elizabeths East Campus Development"), and $1,000,000 from funds previously appropriated from this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for  Arts and Cultural Affairs Grants"), to be allocated as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development. – $48,772,000 (including $17,550,000 from local funds, $2,594,000 from Federal grant funds, $18,827,000 from other funds, and $9,800,000 from funds previously appropriated from this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for St. Elizabeths East Campus Development"); provided, that all funds deposited into the Industrial Revenue Bond program are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the H Street Retail Priority Area Grant Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Soccer Stadium Financing Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Office of Planning. – $10,312,000 (including $9,362,000 from local funds, $525,000 from Federal grant funds, $100,000 from other funds, and $325,000 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Historic Landmark and Historic District Filing Fees (Local) Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Historical Landmark and Historic District Filing Fees (O-Type) Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Department of Small and Local Business Development. – $10,338,000 (including $9,542,000 from local funds and $696,000 from Federal grant funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Small Business Capital Access Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Streetscape Loan Relief  Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Office of Film, Television and Entertainment. – $13,601,000 (including $3,405,000 from local funds and $10,196,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the DC Film Incentive Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Cable Franchise Fees Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Office of Zoning. – $2,606,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Department of Housing and Community Development. – $61,723,000 (including $12,619,000 from local funds, $47,057,000 from Federal grant funds, and $2,046,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the CU 1&amp;2 Affordable Housing Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the DHCD Unified Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Land Acquisition for Housing Development Opportunities (LAHDO) Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the RLF Escrow Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Rehab Repay Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Home Again Revolving Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the HPAP - Repay Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Department of Employment Services. – $142,203,000 (including $54,699,000 from local funds, $48,379,000 from Federal grant funds, $39,124,000 from other funds, and $1,000 from private funds); provided, that $1,385,343 shall be transferred to the Office of Administrative Hearings for hearing appeals related to unemployment insurance benefits; provided, that all funds deposited into the Workers' Compensation Administration Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the UI Administrative Assessment Tax Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the UI Interest/Penalties Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Workers' Compensation Special Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Reed Act Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Real Property Tax Appeals Commission. – $1,636,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. – $44,012,000 (including $15,052,000 from local funds and $28,959,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Basic Business License Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Green Building Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the R-E Guar. &amp; Educ. Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Nuisance Abatement Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the OPLA – Special Account are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Board of Engineers Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Corporate Recordation Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Office of the Tenant Advocate. – $2,788,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>D.C. Commission on the Arts and Humanities. – $16,880,000 (including  $14,696,000 from local funds, $684,000 from Federal grant funds, $500,000 from other funds, and $1,000,000 from funds previously appropriated from this Act, under the heading "Federal Payment for Arts and Cultural Affairs Grants", to fund competitively awarded grants for nonprofit fine and performing arts organizations based in and primarily serving the District); provided, that all funds deposited into the Special Purpose Revenue Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration. – $8,142,000 (including $1,170,000 from local funds (including $1,170,000 from dedicated taxes) and $6,972,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the ABC - Import And Class License Fees Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Public Service Commission. – $13,186,000 (including $435,000 from Federal grant funds, $12,729,000 from other funds, and $22,000 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Operating - Utility Assessment Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the PJM Settlement Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>Office of the People's Counsel. – $7,648,000 from other funds; provided, that all funds deposited into the Advocate for Consumers Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking. – $25,610,000 from other funds; provided, that all funds deposited into the Foreclosure Mediation Fund (Temporary) Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Insurance Assessment Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the HMO Assessment Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Foreclosure Mediation Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Capital Access Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(16)</num>
          <text>Housing Authority Subsidy. – $59,425,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(17)</num>
          <text>Housing Production Trust Fund Subsidy. – $50,179,000 from local funds; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(18)</num>
          <text>Business Improvement Districts Transfer. – $28,000,000 from other funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>PUBLIC SAFETY AND JUSTICE</heading>
      <text>Public safety and justice, $1,294,375,000 (including $1,087,295,000 from local funds, $147,445,000 from Federal grant funds, $60,000 from Medicaid payments, $56,676,000 from other funds, $435,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for the District of Columbia National Guard", $1,900,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council", and $565,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions"), to be allocated as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Metropolitan Police Department. – $510,973,000 (including $499,973,000 from local funds, $3,066,000 from Federal grant funds, and $7,934,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Asset Forfeiture Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department. – $231,798,000 (including $230,278,000 from local funds and $1,520,000 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Police Officers' and Firefighters' Retirement System. – $136,115,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Department of Corrections. – $150,733,000 (including $122,176,000 from local funds and $28,557,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Correction Trustee Reimbursement Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Welfare Account are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Correction Reimbursement-Juveniles Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia National Guard. –  $13,317,000 (including $5,026,000 from local funds, $7,855,000 from Federal grant funds, and $435,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for the District of Columbia National Guard"); provided, that the Mayor shall reimburse the District of Columbia National Guard for expenses incurred in connection with services that are performed in emergencies by the National Guard in a militia status and are requested by the Mayor, in amounts that shall be jointly determined and certified as due and payable for these services by the Mayor and the Commanding General of the District of Columbia National Guard; provided further, that such sums as may be necessary for reimbursement to the District of Columbia National Guard under the preceding proviso shall be available pursuant to this Act and the availability of the sums shall be deemed as constituting payment in advance for emergency services involved;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency. – $132,744,000 (including $4,552,000 from local funds and $128,192,000 from Federal grant funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure. – $295,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions";</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Judicial Nomination Commission. – $270,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions";</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Office of Police Complaints. – $2,292,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Sentencing and Criminal Code Revision Commission. – $1,610,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Office of the Chief Medical Examiner. – $10,501,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Office of Administrative Hearings. – $8,865,000 (including $8,805,000 from local funds and $60,000 from Medicaid payments);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Criminal Justice Coordinating Council. – $3,067,000 (including $1,167,000 from local funds and $1,900,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council");</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>Office of Unified Communications. – $45,168,000 (including $28,197,000 from local funds and $16,971,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the 911 &amp; 311 Assessments Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Prepaid Wireless 911 Charges Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>Department of Forensic Sciences. – $14,936,000 (including $14,476,000 from local funds and $460,000 from Federal grant funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(16)</num>
          <text>Corrections Information Council. – $482,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(17)</num>
          <text>Office of Victim Services and Justice Grants. – $30,363,000 (including $20,799,000 from local funds, $7,871,000 from Federal grant funds, and $1,693,000 from other funds) provided, that not less than $200,000 shall be available to fund the District of Columbia Poverty Lawyer Loan Assistance Program, established by the Access to Justice Initiative Amendment Act of 2011, effective September 14, 2011 (D.C. Law 19-21; D.C. Official Code § 4-1701.01 <em>et seq</em>.); provided further, that  $4,078,000 shall be made available to award a grant to the District of Columbia Bar Foundation for the purpose of providing support to nonprofit organizations that deliver civil legal services to low-income and under-served District residents; provided further, that $1,000,000 shall be transferred to the Community-based Violence Reduction Fund, established by section 3014 of the Fiscal Year 2009 Budget Support Act of 2008, effective August 16, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-219; D.C. Official Code § 1-325.121), for use by the Justice Grants Administration for the purpose of providing grants for the development of programs to intervene with children who are chronically truant; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Crime Victims Assistance Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Domestic Violence Shelter &amp; Transitional Housing Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Community-based Violence Reduction Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(18)</num>
          <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice. - $846,000 from local funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>PUBLIC EDUCATION SYSTEM</heading>
      <text>Public education system, including the development of national-defense education programs, $2,233,291,000 (including $1,891,784,000 from local funds (including $4,306,000 from Dedicated Taxes), $244,707,000 from Federal grant funds, $16,669,000 from other funds, $132,000 from private funds, $40,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Resident Tuition Support", and $40,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for School Improvement"), to be allocated as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Public Schools. – $785,860,000 (including $727,492,000 from local funds, $31,230,000 from Federal grant funds, $7,138,000 from other funds, and $20,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in the Act under the heading "Federal Payment for School Improvement"); provided, that this appropriation shall not be available to subsidize the education of any nonresident of the District at any District public elementary or secondary school during fiscal year 2016 unless the nonresident pays tuition to the District at a rate that covers 100 percent of the costs incurred by the District that are attributable to the education of the nonresident (as established by the Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools); provided further, that not to exceed $10,600 for the Chancellor shall be available for official reception and representation expenses; provided further, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the District of Columbia Public Schools on July 1, 2016, an amount equal to 10 percent of the total amount of the local funds appropriations request provided for the District of Columbia Public Schools in the proposed budget of the District of Columbia for fiscal year 2017 (as submitted to Congress), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for the District of Columbia Public Schools under the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2017; provided further, that all funds deposited into the E-Rate Education Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the ROTC Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the DHHS Afterschool Program-Copayment Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the At-Risk Supplemental Allocation Preservation Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the District of Columbia Public Schools Advertisements and Sponsorships Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Teachers' Retirement System. – $44,469,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Office of the State Superintendent of Education. – $415,918,000 (including $137,960,000 from local funds (including $4,306,000 from dedicated taxes), $212,558,000 from Federal grant funds, $991,000 from other funds, $104,000 from private funds, $40,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Resident Tuition Support", and $20,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in the Act under the heading "Federal Payment for School Improvement"); provided, that of the amounts provided to the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, $1,000,000 from local funds shall remain available until June 30, 2016 for an audit of the student enrollment of each District of Columbia public school and of each District of Columbia public charter school; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Blackman and Jones Consent Decree Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Charter School Credit Enhancement Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Student Residency Verification Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the State Athletic Acts Program &amp; Office Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Community Schools Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Public Charter Schools. – $677,744,000 from local funds; provided, that there shall be quarterly disbursement of funds to the District of Columbia public charter schools, with the first payment to occur within 15 days of the beginning of the fiscal year; provided further, that if the entirety of this allocation has not been provided as payments to any public charter schools currently in operation through the per pupil funding formula, the funds shall remain available until expended for public education in accordance with section 2403(b)(2) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code § 38-1804.03(b)(2)); provided further, that of the amounts made available to District of Columbia public charter schools, $230,000 shall be made available to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer as authorized by section 2403(b)(6) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code § 38-1804.03(b)(6)); provided further, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the District of Columbia public charter schools on July 1, 2016 an amount equal to 30 percent of the total amount of the local funds appropriations request provided for payments to public charter schools in the proposed budget of the District of Columbia for fiscal year 2017 (as submitted to Congress), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for such payments under the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2017; provided further, that the annual financial audit for the performance of an individual District of Columbia public charter school shall be funded by the charter school;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>University of the District of Columbia Subsidy Account. – $70,942,000 from local funds; provided, that this appropriation shall not be available to subsidize the education of nonresidents of the District at the University of the District of Columbia, unless the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia adopts, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, a tuition-rate schedule that will establish the tuition rate for nonresident students at a level no lower than the nonresident tuition rate charged at comparable public institutions of higher education in the metropolitan area; provided further, that this appropriation shall not be used for the purpose of relocating the community college from 801 North Capitol Street, N.E., to the University of the District of Columbia's campus located at 4200 Connecticut Avenue, N.W.; provided further, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the University of the District of Columbia on July 1, 2016, an amount equal to 10 percent of the total amount of the local funds appropriations request provided for the University of the District of Columbia in the proposed budget of the District of Columbia for fiscal year 2017 (as submitted to Congress), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for the University of the District of Columbia under the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2017; provided further, that not to exceed $10,600 for the President of the University of the District of Columbia shall be available for official reception and representation expenses;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Public Library. – $57,385,000 (including $55,927,000 from local funds, $919,000 from Federal grant funds, and $540,000 from other funds); provided, that not to exceed $8,500 for the Public Librarian shall be available for official reception and representation expenses; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Copies and Printing Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the SLD E-Rate Reimbursement Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Library Collections Account are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Books from Birth Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Public Charter School Board. – $8,000,000 from other funds; provided, that all funds deposited into the Public Charter School Board Administrative Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Non-Public Tuition. – $74,415,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Special Education Transportation. – $93,805,000 from local funds; provided, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the Special Education Transportation agency under the direction of the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, on July 1, 2016, an amount equal to 10 percent of the total amount of the local funds appropriations request provided for the Special Education Transportation agency in the proposed budget of the District of Columbia for fiscal year 2017 (as submitted to Congress), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for the Special Education Transportation agency under the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2017; provided further, that amounts appropriated under this heading may be used to offer financial incentives as necessary to reduce the number of routes serving 2 or fewer students;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>D.C. State Board of Education. – $1,182,000 (including $1,154,000 from local funds and $28,000 from private funds); and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Education. – $3,571,000 from local funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>HUMAN SUPPORT SERVICES</heading>
      <text>Human support services, $4,498,613,000 (including $1,875,649,000 from local funds (including $100,959,000 from dedicated taxes), $408,452,000 from Federal grant funds, $2,174,580,000 from Medicaid payments, $34,319,000 from other funds, $613,000 from private funds, $6,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Permanent Supportive Housing," and $5,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Testing and Treatment of HIV/AIDS"); to be allocated as follows;</text>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Department of Human Services. – $460,150,000 (including $270,601,000 from local funds, $170,551,000 from Federal grant funds, $15,798,000 from Medicaid payments, and $3,200,000 from other funds), and $6,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Permanent Supportive Housing,"; provided, that all funds deposited into the SSI Payback Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Child and Family Services Agency. – $233,814,000 (including $163,995,000 from local funds, $68,559,000 from Federal grant funds, $1,200,000 from other funds, and $59,000 from private funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Department of Behavioral Health. – $252,531,000 (including $226,856,000 from local funds, $17,411,000 from Federal grant funds, $3,471,000 from Medicaid payments, $4,251,000 from other funds, and $544,000 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the APRA - Choice in Drug Treatment (HCSN) Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; in addition to the funds otherwise appropriated under this Act, the Department of Behavioral Health may expend any funds that are or were paid by the United States Virgin Islands to the District in fiscal year 2015 or fiscal year 2016 to compensate the District for care previously provided by the District to patients at the St. Elizabeths hospital and are not otherwise appropriated under this Act; provided, that the availability of the funds is certified by the Chief Financial Officer before any expenditure; provided further, that the funds shall be expended in a manner determined by the Director of the Department of Behavioral Health;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Department of Health. – $211,644,000 (including $78,870,000 from local funds, $114,619,000 from Federal grant funds, $13,155,000 from other funds, and $5,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Testing and Treatment of HIV/AIDS"); provided, that all funds deposited into the Health Professional Recruitment Fund (Medical Loan Repayment) are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Board of Medicine Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Pharmacy Protection Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the SHPDA Fees Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Civic Monetary Penalties Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the SHPDA Admission Fee Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the ICF/MR Fees &amp; Fines are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Human Services Facility Fee Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Communicable and Chronic Disease Prevention and Treatment Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Department of Parks and Recreation. – $41,700,000 (including $39,159,000 from local funds and $2,541,000 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>D.C. Office on Aging. – $39,184,000 (including $31,369,000 from local funds and $7,815,000 from Federal grant funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Unemployment Compensation Fund. – $6,887,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Employees' Compensation Fund. – $20,221,000 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited into the Worker's Compensation Rev-Settlement Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Agency Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Office of Human Rights. – $4,005,000 (including $3,738,000 from local funds and $267,000 from Federal grant funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Office on Latino Affairs. – $2,782,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Children and Youth Investment Collaborative. – $4,260,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Office of Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs. – $835,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Office of Veterans' Affairs. – $419,000 (including $414,000 from local funds and $5,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Office of Veterans Affairs Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services. – $105,676,000 from local funds; provided, that amounts appropriated herein may be expended to implement the provisions of section 105(k) of the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services Establishment Act of 2004, effective April 12, 2005 (D.C. Law 15-335; D.C. Official Code § 2-1515.05(k)); provided further, that of the local funds appropriated for the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services, $12,000 shall be used to fund the requirements of the Interstate Compact for Juveniles;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>Department of Disability Services. – $162,374,000 (including $117,625,000 from local funds, $28,230,000 from Federal grant funds, $9,146,000 from Medicaid payments,  $7,363,000 from other funds, and $10,000 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Randolph Shepherd Unassigned Facilities Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Cost of Care-Non-Medicaid Clients Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(16)</num>
          <text>Department of Health Care Finance. – $2,291,126,000 (including $700,011,000 from local funds (including $71,345,000from dedicated taxes), $1,000,000 from Federal grant funds, $2,146,166,000 from Medicaid payments, and $2,605,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Healthy DC Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Nursing Homes Quality of Care Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Stevie Sellows Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Medicaid Collections-3rd Party Liability Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Bill Of Rights (Grievance and Appeals) Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Hospital Provider Fee Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Hospital Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(17)</num>
          <text>D.C. Health Benefit Exchange Subsidy. – $29,164,000 in local funds (including $29,164,000 in dedicated taxes); provided, that all funds deposited into the District of Columbia Health Benefit Exchange Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(18)</num>
          <text>Deputy Mayor for Health and Human Services. – $1,391,000 from local funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>PUBLIC WORKS</heading>
      <text>Public works, including rental of one passenger-carrying vehicle for use by the Mayor and 3 passenger-carrying vehicles for use by the Council of the District of Columbia and leasing of passenger-carrying vehicles, $ 772,365,000 (including $580,429,000 from local funds (including $66,664,000 from dedicated taxes), $34,524,000 from Federal grant funds, $154,662,000 from other funds, $750,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Climate Risk Management," $1,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for DC Solar Power Initiative," and $1,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Mass Transit Innovation Plan"), to be allocated as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Department of Public Works. – $132,553,000 (including $124,878,000 from local funds and $7,675,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Solid Waste Disposal Fee Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Super Can Program Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Department of Transportation. – $113,676,000 (including $85,025,000 from local funds, $7,945,000 from Federal grant funds, and $20,706,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Bicycle Sharing Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Performance Parking Program Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Tree Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the DDOT Enterprise Fund-Non Tax Revenues Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Sustainable Transportation Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that, in addition, there are appropriated any amounts received, or to be received, from the Potomac Electric Power Company, or any of its related companies, successors or assigns, for the purpose of paying or reimbursing the District Department of Transportation for the costs of designing, constructing, acquiring and installing facilities, infrastructure and equipment for use and ownership by the Potomac Electric Power Company, or any of its related companies, successors or assigns, related to or associated with the undergrounding of electric transmission lines in the District, and any interest earned on those funds, which amounts and interest shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the general Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, but shall be continually available until expended for the designated purposes; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Vision Zero Pedestrian and Bicycle Safety Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the BID Parking Abatement Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the DDOT Stormwater Retention Credit Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Department of Motor Vehicles. – $38,105,000 (including $28,091,000 from local funds and $10,014,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Motor Vehicle Inspection Station Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>District Department of the Environment. – $106,292,000 (including $17,156,000 from local funds, $26,579,000 from Federal grant funds, $60,807,000 from other funds, and $750,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Climate Risk Management," and $1,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for DC Solar Power Initiative"); provided, that all funds deposited into the Storm Water Permit Review Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, all funds deposited into the Sustainable Energy Trust Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Brownfield Revitalization Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Anacostia River Clean Up Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Wetlands Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Energy Assistance Trust Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the LUST Trust Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Soil Erosion/Sediment Control Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the DC Municipal Aggregation Program Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Fishing License Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Renewable Energy Development Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Special Energy Assessment Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Air Quality Construction Permits Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the WASA Utility Discount Program Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Pesticide Product Registration Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Storm Water Fees Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Stormwater In Lieu Fee Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Economy II Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Residential Aid Discount Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Residential Essential Services Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Benchmarking Enforcement Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>D.C. Taxicab Commission. – $8,399,000 (including $1,100,000 from local funds, and $7,299,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited into the Taxicab Assessment Act Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Public Vehicles for Hire Consumer Service Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission. – $127,000 from local funds; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. – $373,213,000 (including $324,053,000 from local funds (including $66,664,000 from dedicated taxes), $48,160,000 from other funds, and $1,000,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Mass Transit Innovation Plan"); provided, that all funds deposited into the Dedicated Taxes Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited into the Parking Meter WMATA Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FINANCING AND OTHER</heading>
      <text>Financing and Other, $1,085,819,000 (including $977,994,000 from local funds (including $147,275,000 from dedicated taxes), $18,262,000 from Federal grant funds, $74,663,000 from other funds, and $14,900,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia"), to be allocated as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Repayment of Loans and Interest. – $615,003,000 (including $591,627,000 from local funds, $18,262,000 from Federal grant funds, and $5,114,000 from other funds) for payment of principal, interest, and certain fees directly resulting from borrowing by the District of Columbia to fund District of Columbia capital projects as authorized by sections 462, 475, and 490 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 777; D.C. Official Code §§ 1- 204.62, 1-204.75, and 1-204.90);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Repayment of Interest on Short-Term Borrowings. – $3,750,000 from local funds for payment of interest on short-term borrowing;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Debt Service - Issuance Costs. – $6,000,000 from local funds for the payment of debt service issuance costs;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Schools Modernization Fund. – $14,276,000 from local funds for the Schools Modernization Fund, established by section 4042 of the Schools Modernization Amendment Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 1-325.41);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Repayment of Revenue Bonds. – $7,832,000 from local funds (including $7,832,000 from dedicated taxes) for the repayment of revenue bonds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Settlements and Judgments. – $21,292,000 from local funds for making refunds and for the payment of legal settlements or judgments that have been entered against the District of Columbia government; provided, that this appropriation shall not be construed as modifying or affecting the provisions of section 101 of this Act;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>John A. Wilson Building Fund. – $4,745,000 from local funds for expenses associated with the John A. Wilson building;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Workforce Investments. – $17,815,000 from local funds for workforce investments; provided, that all funds deposited into the CU 1&amp;2 Compensation and Class Reform Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Non-Departmental. – $21,286,000 (including $2,754,000 from local funds and $18,532,000 from other funds), to be transferred by the Mayor of the District of Columbia within the various appropriations headings in this Act, to account for anticipated costs that cannot be allocated to specific agencies during the development of the proposed budget;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Emergency Planning and Security Fund. – $14,900,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia"; provided, that, notwithstanding any other law, the District of Columbia may charge obligations and expenditures that are pending reimbursement under the heading "Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia" to this local appropriations heading;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Master Equipment Lease/Purchase Program. – $48,413,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Pay-As-You-Go Capital Fund. – $72,549,000 (including $21,532,000 from local funds and $51,017,000 from other funds) to be transferred to the Capital Fund, in lieu of capital financing;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>District Retiree Health Contribution. – $95,400,000 from local funds for a District Retiree Health Contribution;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>Highway Trust Fund Transfer. – $22,504,000 from local funds (including $22,504,000 from dedicated taxes); and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>Convention Center Transfer. – $120,054,000 from local funds (including $116,939,000 from dedicated taxes).</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>ENTERPRISE AND OTHER FUNDS</heading>
      <text>The amount of $1,803,846,000 from enterprise and other funds, shall be provided to enterprise funds as follows; provided, that, in the event that certain dedicated revenues exceed budgeted amounts, the District may increase its General Fund budget authority as needed to transfer all such revenues, pursuant to local law, to the Highway Trust Fund, the Washington Convention Center, and the Washington Metropolitan Transit Authority.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WATER AND SEWER AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Pursuant to section 445a of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved August 6, 1996 (110 Stat. 1698; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.45a), which provides that the Council may comment and make recommendations concerning such annual estimates but shall have no authority to revise the budget for the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, the Council forwards this non-appropriated budget request: For operation of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, $541,605,000  from enterprise and other funds, of which no outstanding debt exists for repayment of loans and interest incurred for capital improvement projects and payable to the District's debt service fund. For construction projects, $3,218,789,000, to be distributed as follows: $365,127,000, for the Sanitary Sewer System; $676,912,000 for the Water Treatment System; $545,245,000 for the Water Distribution System; $1,352,530,000 for the Combined Sewer Overflow Program; $99,116,000 for the Washington Aqueduct; $10,329,000 for the Stormwater Program; and $169,530,000 for the capital equipment program; in addition, $24,300,000 from funds previously appropriated in this Act under the heading "Federal Payment to the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority"; provided, that the requirements and restrictions that are applicable to General Fund capital improvement projects and set forth in this Act under the Capital Outlay appropriation account shall apply to projects approved under this appropriation account.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>WASHINGTON AQUEDUCT</heading>
      <text>For operation of the Washington Aqueduct, $62,728,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>D.C. LOTTERY AND CHARITABLE GAMES Control Board</heading>
      <text>For the Lottery and Charitable Games Enterprise Fund, established by the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1982, approved December 4, 1981 (Pub. L. No. 97-91; 95 Stat. 1174), for the purpose of implementing the Law to Legalize Lotteries, Daily Numbers Games, and Bingo and Raffles for Charitable Purposes in the District of Columbia, effective March 10, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-172; codified in scattered cites in the D.C. Official Code), $220,000,000 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that the District of Columbia shall identify the source of funding for this appropriation title from the District's own locally generated revenues; provided further, that no revenues from Federal sources shall be used to support the operations or activities of the Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board; provided further, that, after notification to the Mayor, amounts appropriated herein may be increased by an amount necessary for the Lottery and Charitable Games Enterprise Fund to make transfers to the General Fund of the District of Columbia and to cover prizes, agent commissions, and gaming related fees directly associated with unanticipated excess lottery revenues not included in this appropriation.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA RETIREMENT BOARD</heading>
      <text>For the District of Columbia Retirement Board, established pursuant to section 121 of the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act of 1979, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Stat. 866; D.C. Official Code § 1-711), $32,302,000 from the earnings of the applicable retirement funds to pay legal, management, investment, and other fees and administrative expenses of the District of Columbia Retirement Board; provided, that the District of Columbia Retirement Board shall provide to Congress and the Mayor and to the Council of the District of Columbia a quarterly report of the allocations of charges by fund and of expenditures of all funds; provided further, that the District of Columbia Retirement Board shall provide to the Mayor, for transmittal to the Council of the District of Columbia, an itemized accounting of the planned use of appropriated funds in time for each annual budget submission and the actual use of such funds in time for each annual audited financial report.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>WASHINGTON CONVENTION AND SPORTS AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>For the Washington Convention Center Enterprise Fund, including for functions previously performed by the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission, $129,670,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>HOUSING FINANCE AGENCY</heading>
      <text>For the Housing Finance Agency, $10,798,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>UNIVERSITY OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</heading>
      <text>For the University of the District of Columbia, $153,959,000 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that these funds shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available until expended, without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>D.C. PUBLIC LIBRARY AGENCY TRUST FUND</heading>
      <text>For the District of Columbia Public Library Trust Fund, $17,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE TRUST FUND</heading>
      <text>For the Unemployment Insurance Trust Fund, $235,000,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>HOUSING PRODUCTION TRUST FUND</heading>
      <text>For the Housing Production Trust Fund, $100,000,000 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that all funds deposited into the Housing Production Trust Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>TAX INCREMENT FINANCING (TIF) PROGRAM</heading>
      <text>For Tax Increment Financing, $70,006,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>BALLPARK REVENUE FUND</heading>
      <text>For the Ballpark Revenue Fund, $67,507,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>REPAYMENT OF PILOT FINANCING</heading>
      <text>For Repayment of Payment in Lieu of Taxes Financing, $18,741,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>NOT-FOR-PROFIT HOSPITAL CORPORATION</heading>
      <text>For the Not-For-Profit Hospital Corporation, $129,000,000 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>HEALTH BENEFIT EXCHANGE AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>For the District of Columbia Health Benefit Exchange Authority, $32,513,000 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that all funds deposited into the District of Columbia Health Benefit Exchange Fund are, without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>CASH FLOW RESERVE FUND</heading>
      <text>All funds deposited into the Cash Flow Reserve Fund, established pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-392.02, are without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>FISCAL STABILIZATION RESERVE ACCOUNT FUND</heading>
      <text>All funds deposited into the Fiscal Stabilization Reserve Account Fund, established pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-392.02, are without regard to fiscal year, authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>CAPITAL OUTLAY</heading>
      <text>For capital construction projects, an increase of $ 1,934,887,000, of which $1,508,479,000 shall be from local funds, $104,880,000 from the Local Transportation Fund, $106,000,000 from Federal Payment funds, $11,693,000 from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, and $203,835,000 from Federal grant funds, and a rescission of $ 820,278,000, of which $732,349,000 is from local funds, $12,500,000 is from private grant funds, $16,208,000 from the Local Transportation Fund, $16,545,000 from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, and $42,676,000 from Federal grant funds appropriated under this heading in prior fiscal years, for a net amount of $ 1,114,608,000; to remain available until expended; provided, that all funds provided by this appropriation title shall be available only for the specific projects and purposes intended; provided further, that amounts appropriated under this heading may be increased by the amount transferred from funds appropriated in this act as Pay-As-You-Go Capital funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container>
      <heading>TITLE IV--GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
      <text/>
    </container>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>101</num>
    <heading>There are appropriated from the applicable funds of the District of Columbia such sums as may be necessary for making refunds and for the payment of legal settlements or judgments that have been entered against the District of Columbia government.</heading>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>102</num>
    <heading>The District of Columbia government is authorized to approve reprogramming and transfer requests of local funds under this Act through November 7, 2016.</heading>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>103</num>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Amounts appropriated in this Act as operating funds may be transferred to the District of Columbia's enterprise and capital funds and such amounts, once transferred, shall retain appropriation authority consistent with the provisions of this Act.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia government is authorized to reprogram or transfer for operating expenses any local funds transferred or reprogrammed in this or the 4 prior fiscal years from operating funds to capital funds, and such amounts, once transferred or reprogrammed, shall retain appropriation authority consistent with the provisions of this Act.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia government may not transfer or reprogram for operating expenses any funds derived from bonds, notes, or other obligations issued for capital projects.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>104</num>
    <heading>Except as otherwise provided in this section, none of the funds made available by this Act or by any other act may be used to provide any officer or employee of the District of Columbia with an official vehicle unless the officer or employee uses the vehicle only in the performance of the officer's or employee's official duties.</heading>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term "official duties'' does not include travel between the officer's or employee's residence and workplace, except in the case of—</text>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>an officer or employee of the Metropolitan Police Department who resides in the District of Columbia or a District of Columbia government employee as may otherwise be designated by the Chief of Police;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>at the discretion of the Fire Chief, an officer or employee of the District of Columbia Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department who resides in the District of Columbia and is on call 24 hours a day or is otherwise designated by the Fire Chief;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>at the discretion of the Director of the Department of Corrections, an officer or employee of the District of Columbia Department of Corrections who resides in the District of Columbia and is on call 24 hours a day or is otherwise designated by the Director;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>the Mayor of the District of Columbia; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>105</num>
    <heading>Legislative Autonomy.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In General- Section 602 (sec. 1-206.02, D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking subsection (c).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Congressional Resolutions of Disapproval-</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>IN GENERAL- The District of Columbia Home Rule Act is amended by striking section 604 (sec. 1-206.04, D.C. Official Code).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>CLERICAL AMENDMENT- The table of contents is amended by striking the item relating to section 604.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>EXERCISE OF RULEMAKING POWER- This subsection and the amendments made by this subsection are enacted by Congress--</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the House of Representatives and the Senate, respectively, and as such they shall be considered as a part of the rules of each House, respectively, or of that House to which they specifically apply, and such rules shall supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent therewith; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change such rules (so far as relating to such House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of such House.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Conforming Amendments-</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA HOME RULE ACT-</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Section 303 (sec. 1-203.03, D.C. Official Code) is amended--</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>in subsection (a), by striking the second sentence; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>by striking subsection (b) and redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (b) and (c).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Section 404(e) (sec. 1-204.04(3), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking 'subject to the provisions of section 602(c)' each place it appears.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Section 462 (sec. 1-204.62, D.C. Official Code) is amended--</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>in subsection (a), by striking '(a) The Council' and inserting 'The Council'; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>by striking subsections (b) and (c).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>Section 472(d) (sec. 1-204.72(d), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>Payments Not Subject to Appropriation- The fourth sentence of section 446 shall not apply to any amount obligated or expended by the District for the payment of the principal of, interest on, or redemption premium for any revenue anticipation note issued under subsection (a).</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>Section 475(e) (sec. 1-204.75(e), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>Payments Not Subject to Appropriation- The fourth sentence of section 446 shall not apply to any amount obligated or expended by the District for the payment of the principal of, interest on, or redemption premium for any revenue anticipation note issued under this section.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>OTHER LAWS-</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Section 2(b)(1) of Amendment No. 1 (relating to initiative and referendum) to title IV (the District Charter) (sec. 1-204.102(b)(1), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking 'the appropriate custodian' and all that follows through 'portion of such act to'.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Section 5 of Amendment No. 1 (relating to initiative and referendum) to title IV (the District Charter) (sec. 1-204.105, D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking ', and such act' and all that follows and inserting a period.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Section 16 of the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955 (sec. 1-1001.16, D.C. Official Code)--</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>in subsection (j)(2)--</text>
            <para>
              <num>(I)</num>
              <text>by striking 'sections 404 and 602(c)' and inserting 'section 404', and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(II)</num>
              <text>by striking the second sentence; and</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>in subsection (m)--</text>
            <para>
              <num>(I)</num>
              <text>in the first sentence, by striking 'the appropriate custodian' and all that follows through 'parts of such act to',</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(II)</num>
              <text>by striking 'is held. If, however, after' and inserting 'is held unless, under', and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(III)</num>
              <text>by striking 'section, the act which' and all that follows and inserting 'section.'.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to each act of the District of Columbia--</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>passed by the Council of the District of Columbia and signed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>vetoed by the Mayor and repassed by the Council;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>passed by the Council and allowed to become effective by the Mayor without the Mayor’s signature; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>in the case of initiated acts and acts subject to referendum, ratified by a majority of the registered qualified electors voting on the initiative or referendum, on or after October 1, 2013.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>106</num>
    <text>Except as expressly provided otherwise, any reference to "this Act" contained in this division shall be tread as referring only to the provision of this division.</text>
    <text>This division may be cited as the ‘‘District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2016.”</text>
  </section>
  <container>
    <prefix>DIVISION</prefix>
    <num>B</num>
    <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA AUTHORIZATION REQUEST</heading>
    <text>
      <strong>OMNIBUS PROVISIONS</strong>
    </text>
    <section>
      <num>201</num>
      <text>Sections 47-391.07(b) and 47-392.09 of the District of Columbia Official Code are repealed.</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>202</num>
      <heading>Congressional review streamlining.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 23, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), is amended by striking the phrase "(excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays, and any day on which neither House is in session because of an adjournment sine die, a recess of more than 3 days, or an adjournment of more than three days)."</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to each act of the District of Columbia—</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>passed by the Council of the District of Columbia and signed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>vetoed by the Mayor and repassed by the Council; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>passed by the Council and allowed to become effective without the Mayor's signature, on or after the effective date of this section.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>203</num>
      <text>Section 11201 of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, approved August 5, 1997 (111 Stat. 734; D.C. Official Code § 24-101), is amended by adding a new subsection (a-1) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(a-1)</num>
          <text>Reimbursement to District of Columbia Department of Corrections.– The United States Government shall reimburse the District of Columbia Department of Corrections its costs of providing custody and care for:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Felons committed by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia from the date of sentencing until transfer to a penal or correctional facility operated or contracted for by the Bureau of Prisons;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Previously sentenced felons committed to the Department of Corrections as violators of parole, supervised release, or probation from the date of commitment until transfer to a penal or correctional facility operated or contracted for by the Bureau of Prisons; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Previously sentenced felons held by or committed to the Department of Corrections on writs from the date of commitment until transfer to a penal or correctional facility operated or contracted for by the Bureau of Prisons.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>204</num>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>IN GENERAL.--The District of Columbia is authorized to renew or enter into a new Interstate Compact for Juveniles for the purposes of placing youth in appropriate therapeutic settings and providing and receiving supervision for youth in other jurisdictions.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>DELEGATION.--Any compact for juveniles that the Council of the District of Columbia authorizes the Mayor to execute on behalf of the District may contain provisions that delegate the requisite power and authority to the Interstate Commission for Juveniles to achieve the purposes for which the interstate compact is established.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Section 406 of An Act to reorganize the courts of the District of Columbia, to revise the procedures for juveniles in the District of Columbia, to codify title 23 of the District of Columbia Code, and for other purposes, approved July 29, 1970 (84 Stat. 678; D.C. Official Code § 24-1106), is repealed.</text>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>205</num>
      <text>Section 103 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 777; D.C. Official Code § 1-201.03), is amended by adding a new paragraph (16) to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(16)</num>
          <text>The term "Attorney General" means the Attorney General for the District of Columbia provided for by part C-I of title IV.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>206</num>
      <text>Section 424b of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 774; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.26), is amended by striking the phrase "Procurement Practices Act of 1986" and inserting the phrase "Procurement Practices Reform Act of 2010" in its place.</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>207</num>
      <text>Sections 2, 3, and 4 of the Domestic Partnership Police and Fire Amendment Act of 2008, effective March 25, 2009 (D.C. Law 17-358; 56 DCR 1188), are enacted into law.</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>208</num>
      <text>Section 602(a)(5) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved on December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(a)(5)), is amended by striking the phrase "of the District" the first time it appears and inserting the phrase "of the District, unless his or her source of income derives from District local funds" in its place.</text>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>209</num>
      <text>Section 602(a)(5) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(a)(5)), is amended by striking the phrase "of any individual not a resident of the District" and inserting the phrase "of any individual not a resident of the District, except professional athletes," in its place.</text>
      <text>This division may be cited as the "District of Columbia Omnibus Authorization Act, 2016".</text>
    </section>
  </container>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect as provided in section 446 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 801; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.46).</text>
  </section>
</document>
