<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-21">
  <num type="law">21-21</num>
  <num type="bill">21-20</num>
  <num type="act">21-91</num>
  <heading type="short">Access to Contraceptives Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Women's Health and Cancer Rights Federal Law Conformity Act of 2000 to require that a health benefit plan authorize the dispensing of up to a 12-month supply of a woman's covered prescription contraceptive at one time.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2015-09-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/33213/B21-0020-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-21</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 8848</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2015-05-05" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2015-06-02" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-06-17</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-21 requires that an individual health plan or group health plan, a health insurer offering health insurance coverage that provides coverage for prescription drugs, and health insurance coverage through Medicaid shall provide benefits which allow for dispensing of up to 12 months of a woman's covered prescription for contraception at one time.  </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Health and Human Services</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Access to Contraceptives Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Women's Health and Cancer Rights Federal Law Conformity Act of 2000, effective April 3, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-254; D.C. Official Code § 31-3831 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended by adding a new section 5a to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="|31|38B" after="§31-3834" num-value="31-3834.01" history-prefix="as added"/>
        <num>5a</num>
        <heading>Full-year coverage for contraception.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>An individual health plan or group health plan, a health insurer offering health insurance coverage for prescription drugs, and health insurance coverage through Medicaid shall provide benefits that allow for the dispensing of up to a 12-month supply of a covered prescription contraceptive at one time.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>"Contraceptive" means a drug or drug regimen approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration to prevent pregnancy.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>"Medicaid" shall have the same meaning as provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-204.12|(2)">section 1502(2) of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Act of 2002, effective October 1, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-190; D.C. Official Code § 4-204.12(2))</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>This section shall not be construed to require additional coverage for contraceptives that are not covered under the health benefit plan.</text>
        </para>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-254" type="History" path="§5a">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-254, § 5a</annotation>
        <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-21">D.C. Law 21-21</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-21">D.C. Law 21-21</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2017.</annotation>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of January 1, 2017.</text>
    <codify:applicability path="§2" date="2017-01-01" history="false"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
