<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-267">
  <num type="law">21-267</num>
  <num type="bill">21-325</num>
  <num type="act">21-685</num>
  <heading type="short">Land Disposition Transparency and Clarification Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes to require the Mayor's analysis of whether real property is no longer required for public purposes to include a description of each public use considered and an accompanying narrative explaining why the real property will not satisfy each public use considered, to require the Mayor to hold a public hearing to obtain community input on potential public uses of real property before submitting a surplus resolution and at least 60 days before the Mayor issues a request for proposals or competitive sealed proposals, to require the Mayor to hold a public hearing or hearings in connection with a proposed disposition, including in the affected community of any off-site redevelopment related to the disposition, to require the Mayor to provide the Council with a description of the difference between the value of property to be disposed of and the purchase or lease price to be paid by a developer, a pre-disposition economic impact statement, and a valuation of the property to be disposed of, to be prepared by a licensed appraiser no earlier than 5 months before the submission of a disposition resolution, and to require that units dedicated as affordable housing remain so dedicated for the life of the ground lease, or, if not disposed of by ground lease, in perpetuity and secured by a covenant that runs with the land.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-04-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/34291/B21-0325-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-267</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 2152</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2016-11-15" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-12-06" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2016-12-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-02-17</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-267 requires the Mayor to transmit a semiannual report to the Council regarding the sale of District land. The report must describe among other things, the difference between the proposed sales price of the land and the market value of the land. The Mayor is also required to hold public hearings to obtain community input on potential public uses of the real property to determine whether the real property is no longer required for public purposes. It identifies how a resolution to dispose of real property that is determined to no longer be required for public purposes shall be submitted to the Council. It also establishes under what conditions the Mayor may waive certain affordable-housing requirements. </summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Land Disposition Transparency and Clarification Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 1 of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code § 10-801), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a) is amended by adding a new paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall submit to the Council a semiannual report explaining the status of each disposition approved by the Council during the previous 2 years, including a schedule for project completion of each disposition, an explanation of impediments, if any, to completion of the project, and a description of the steps that are being taken to resolve them.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a-1) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "and a detailed explanation as to why the real property is no longer required for public purposes".</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (2) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Whether the real property could have any use by the District, including a description of the District's current needs for real property, a description of potential public uses considered by the Mayor, and a narrative explaining why the real property is unsuited for each public use considered;</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the word "Why" and inserting the phrase "A detailed explanation as to why the real property is no longer required for public purposes, and why" in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (4) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>Before submitting a proposed resolution pursuant to this subsection, and at least 60 days before seeking proposals for the disposition of the real property or otherwise proceeding to negotiate the disposition of the real property, the Mayor shall hold at least one public hearing to obtain community input on potential public uses of the real property to inform the Mayor's determination whether the real property is no longer required for public purposes.  This surplus hearing shall be held at an accessible evening or weekend time and in an accessible location in the vicinity of the real property.  The Mayor shall provide at least 30 days written notice of the public hearing to the affected Advisory Neighborhood Commissions and shall publicize the hearing by posting a written notice at the site and placing a notice in the District of Columbia Register at least 15 days before the hearing.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (5) is repealed.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a-3) is repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The lead-in language is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>If the Mayorseeks to dispose of real property that is determined to no longer be required for public purposes pursuant to subsection (a-1) of this section, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a proposed resolution that contains the following:</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the phrase "(a-3)" both times it appears and inserting the phrase "(b-3)" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (8)(C) is amended by striking the number "20" and inserting the number "15" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (9) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <text>The Land Disposition Agreement for the disposition of the real property shall not be inconsistent with the substantive business terms of the transaction submitted by the Mayor with this resolution, unless revisions to those substantive business terms are approved by the Council.</text>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b-1) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (1) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>A new subparagraph (D) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include>
            <para>
              <num>(D)</num>
              <text>A pre-disposition economic impact statement in the form of a quantitative analysis that estimates the economic benefits, including revenues, tax receipts, and job creation, that will result from the disposition, including the anticipated benefits of any development project to be undertaken at the property and any offsite property, including direct, indirect, or induced outcomes.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (2)(A) is amended by striking the word "major" and inserting the word "substantive" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Paragraphs (3) and (4) are amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>An appraisal report of the value of the property prepared by an independent licensed appraiser performed no earlier than 5 months before the transmission of the proposed resolution to the Council.  The report shall analyze both the highest and best use value of the property and the value of the property under the development proposed pursuant to the disposition.  For the purposes of this subparagraph, the term "highest and best use" shall mean the reasonably probable and legal use that is physically possible, appropriately supported, and financially feasible, and that results in the highest value.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>An explanation of the difference, if any, between the appraised value (determined pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph) and the purchase or lease price to be paid pursuant to the disposition.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>An itemization, together with an explanation, of any government assistance to be received, or contemplated to be received, by the purchaser or lessee under the disposition, including any discount on the price or rent, grants, loans, tax credits, tax abatements, tax increment financing, affordable housing subsidies, land exchange, and negotiated contributions.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (5)(B) is amended by striking the phrase "at the time the resolution is transmitted." and inserting the phrase "at the time the resolution is transmitted; provided, that ifdocuments transmitted with the proposed resolution are revised during the pendency of Council consideration of the proposed resolution, the revised documents shall be clearly marked and transmitted promptly to the Council." in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (6) is repealed.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>New subsections (b-2), (b-3), and (b-4) are added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <text>(ii Within ¼ mile of a Priority Corridor Network Metrobus Route, as designated by the Washington Area Metropolitan Transit Authority, located entirely or partially within the District of Columbia;</text>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Subsection (d) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>Approval of the disposition of the real property by the Council shall expire 2 years after the effective date of the resolution of approval.  If the Mayor determines subsequent to Council approval that the property cannot be disposed of within the 2-year period, the Mayor may submit to the Council a resolution to extend the time for the disposition of the property, and shall include with the transmittal a detailed status report on efforts made toward disposition of the property as well as the reasons for the inability to dispose of the property within the 2-year period.  The resolution may extend the time for any specified period up to 2 years.  If the Council does not take action to approve or disapprove the resolution within 45 days of receipt of the resolution, not including Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, or days of Council recess, the resolution shall be deemed disapproved.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Subsections (h), (i), (j), (k), and (l) are repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
