<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-225">
  <num type="law">21-225</num>
  <num type="bill">21-615</num>
  <num type="act">21-597</num>
  <heading type="short">Notice in Case of Emergency Amendment Act of 2016</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Office of the Unified Communications Establishment Act of 2004 to require the implementation of an emergency medical information profile program that permits a resident to provide medical information to the Office of Unified Communications that may be necessary to assist the resident in an emergency and makes a vehicle or home decal available to residents to alert emergency responders that the resident has an emergency medical information profile, to limit the use of the information contained in a resident's emergency medical information profile, and to require the Mayor to establish rules regarding the implementation of the emergency medical information profile program; and to amend the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, to require the Mayor and the Office of Unified Communications to jointly develop a form or another method for an applicant who applies for the issuance, renewal, or correction of any type of driver's permit or identification card to authorize the Mayor to provide the Office of Unified Communications with the applicant's contact information for purposes of enrollment in the emergency medical information profile program.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2016-02-16</introduced>
    <effective>2017-04-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/35325/Signed_Act/B21-0615-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-225</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 154</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0615">
      <vote date="2016-11-15" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2016-12-06" reading="Final"/>
      <vote date="2016-12-06" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2016-12-06" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2016-12-06" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2016-12-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-01-06</enacted>
      <summary>Law 21-225 establishes a program in the Office of Unified Communications (OUC), the Emergency Medical Information Profile Program. It includes provisions that require OUC to establish and administer the emergency medical information profile program, provide decals for participants to affix to motor vehicles or homes, and collaborate with the Mayor to develop and disseminate an emergency medical information profile request form. </summary>
      <committee>Judiciary</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Notice in Case of Emergency Amendment Act of 2016".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="|1|3|XII|C">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Office of the Unified Communications Establishment Act of 2004, effective December 7, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-205; D. C. Official Code § 1-327.51 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A new section 3205b is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <codify:insert after="§1-327.54" num-value="1-327.54b" history-prefix="as added"/>
          <num>3205b</num>
          <heading>Emergency medical information profile program.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>Within 180 days after <span codify:value="April 1, 2017">the effective date of the Notice in Case of Emergency Amendment Act of 2016, passed on 2nd reading on December 6, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-615)</span>, the Office shall implement an emergency medical information profile program that:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Permits a resident to provide medical information to the Office that may be necessary to assist the resident in an emergency, including, at a minimum, any medical condition, medication, and allergies that the resident may have;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Provides the Office with access to a resident's emergency medical information profile through the resident's registered phone number;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Permits the Office to access a resident's emergency medical information profile through a Department of Motor Vehicles issued identification number, home address, social security number, or any other means developed through written standards by the Office;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>Allows a resident to enroll in the emergency medical information profile program or update information in their emergency medical information profile by completing a paper or an electronic form developed by the Office and emailed or mailed to the resident;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>Permits a resident to register or update the resident's emergency medical information profile by calling the call center;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(6)</num>
              <text>Makes a decal available to a registered motor vehicle owner to serve as notice to the agencies that the owner is a participant in the emergency medical information profile program; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(7)</num>
              <text>Makes a home decal available to a resident to serve as notice to the agencies that a resident of the home is a participant in the emergency medical information profile program.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>Agencies may use the information contained in a resident's emergency medical information profile for the following purposes:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>To identify a resident who has registered in the emergency medical information profileprogram under subsection (a)(4) of this section;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>To ascertain whether a resident participating in the emergency medical information profile program has a medical condition that may impede communications with the agencies;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>To communicate with the emergency contacts of a resident participating in the emergency medical information profile program about the location and general condition of the resident; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>To consider the current medications and pre-existing medical conditions of a resident participating in the emergency medical information profile program when administering emergency medical treatment to the resident.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>The Office may utilize a 3rd party vendor to establish and operate the emergency medical information profile program under subsection (a) of this section.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "resident" means a resident of the District of Columbia.</text>
          </para>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History" path="§3205b">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 3205b</annotation>
      <codify:not-funded-anno path="§1-327.54b" applicability-path="§4" action="creation of"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 3208 (D.C. Official Code § 1-327.57) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The existing text is designated as subsection (a).</text>
        <codify:redesignate-para doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-327.57" num-value="(a)"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new subsection (b) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert path="§1-327.57" after="(a)"/>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Within 180 days after <span codify:value="April 1, 2017">the effective date of the Notice in Case of Emergency Amendment Act of 2016&gt;, passed on 2nd reading on December 6, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-615)</span>, the Mayor, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="|2|5|I">Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq</em>.</code-cite>), shall issue rules to implement <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-327.54b">section 3205b</code-cite>, including rules regarding:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>The promotion and facilitation of registering aged residents in the emergency medical information profile program;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Updating aged residents' information in their emergency medical information profiles; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Outlining the role of public safety agencies and health and human services agencies in referring residents to enroll in the emergency medical information profile program or update information in their emergency medical information profile.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>"Public safety agencies" means any District agencies or entities within the purview of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>"Health and human services agencies" mean any District agencies or entities within the purview of the Deputy Mayor for Health and Human Services.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-327.57" applicability-path="§4"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 7 of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1121; D.C. Official Code § 50-1401.01), is amended by adding a new subsection (a-2) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1401.01" after="(a-1)"/>
        <num>(a-2)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Within 180 days after <span codify:value="April 1, 2017">the effective date of the Notice in Case of Emergency Amendment Act of 2016, passed on 2nd reading on December 6, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-615)</span>, the Mayor and the Office of Unified Communications shall jointly develop a form or another method for an applicant who applies for the issuance, renewal, or correction of any type of driver's permit or identification card to authorize the Mayor to provide the Office of Unified Communications with the applicant's contact information for purposes of enrollment in the emergency medical information profile program, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-327.54b">3205b of the Office of the Unified Communications Establishment Act of 2004, passed on 2nd reading on December 6, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-615)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall forward all authorizations received under paragraph (1) of this subsection to the Office of Unified Communications within 10 days after receipt.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1401.01" applicability-path="§4"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 21-225" path="§2|(a)" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 21-225" path="§2|(b)|(2)" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 21-225" path="§3" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
