<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 21-22">
  <num type="law">21-22</num>
  <num type="bill">21-184</num>
  <num type="act">21-92</num>
  <heading type="short">Medical Marijuana Cultivation Center Exception Temporary Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1998 to provide an exception to allow a cultivation center to operate in a Retail Priority Area if the applicant had an application pending or approved before the effective date of the law establishing or expanding a Retail Priority Area.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-05-04</introduced>
    <effective>2015-09-17</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/33747/Signed_Act/B21-0184-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-22</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 8850</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0184">
      <vote date="2015-05-05" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2015-06-02" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-06-17</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Medical Marijuana Cultivation Center Exception Temporary Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 7(g-1) of the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1999, effective July 27, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-210; D.C. Official Code ยง 7-1671.06(g-1)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "A cultivation center" and inserting the phrase "Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a cultivation center" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (3) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>An applicant that had an application for registration to operate a cultivation center pending or approved as of the effective date of a law establishing or expanding a Retail Priority Area that would include within its boundaries the proposed site of the cultivation center shall be permitted to locate the cultivation center at that site in the newly established or newly expanded Retail Priority Area.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1073 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
