<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 21-246">
  <num type="law">21-246</num>
  <num type="bill">21-999</num>
  <num type="act">21-662</num>
  <heading type="short">Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools Salary and Benefits Authorization Temporary Amendment Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to authorize the annual salary and the provision of certain employment benefits to the Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-04-07</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/37069/B21-0999-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 21-246</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 1620</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2016-12-20" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2017-01-10" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-02-09</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools Salary and Benefits Authorization Temporary Amendment Act of 2017".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-601.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 1052(b) (D.C. Official Code § 1-610.52(b)) is amended by adding a new paragraph (5) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection, Antwan Wilson shall be compensated $280,000 annually, effective February 1, 2017, while serving in the capacity of the Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Chancellor may be paid a performance bonus of up to 10% of his annual base salary for goal achievements in the 2017-2018 school year.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>In addition to such other benefits as the Chancellor may be entitled to receive under existing law or regulation, and notwithstanding subparagraph (A) of this paragraph and section 1058, the Mayor may make a separation payment to the Chancellor of up to 26 weeks of the Chancellor's base salary if the Chancellor's contract is terminated, unless the termination is for cause.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>For the purposes of this subparagraph, the term "cause" means:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(I)</num>
                <text>Being indicted for or convicted of any criminal offense;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(II)</num>
                <text>Committing on-duty conduct that is reasonably known to be a violation of a law or regulation;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(III)</num>
                <text>Using public office for private gain; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(IV)</num>
                <text>Committing any other act that would warrant removal pursuant to Chapter 16 of Title 6B of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (6B DCMR § 1600 <em>et seq.</em>).</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>The restrictions and reporting requirements specified in section 3602(b) of the Restrictions on the Use of Official Vehicles Act of 2000, effective October 19, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-172; D.C. Official Code § 50-204(b)), shall not apply to the Chancellor.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-610.52"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 1055(3) (D.C. Official Code § 1-610.55(3)) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; provided, that the Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools Antwan Wilson and his immediate family may be provided a reasonable temporary housing allowance for a period not to exceed 90 days." in its place.</text>
      <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-610.55"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
