<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>40-201</num>
  <heading>Hospital’s lien for services on recovery in accident cases.</heading>
  <text>Every association, corporation, or other institution, and any agency of the United States or the District of Columbia, maintaining a hospital in the District of Columbia, which shall furnish medical or other service to any patient injured by reason of an accident causing injuries not covered by the Employees’ Compensation Act or the Workmen’s Compensation Act, shall, if such injured party shall assert or maintain a claim against another for damages on account of such injuries, have a lien upon that part going or belonging to such patient, of any recovery or sum had or collected or to be collected by such patient, or by his heirs or personal representatives in the case of his death, whether by judgment or by settlement or compromise to the amount of the reasonable and necessary charges of such hospital for the treatment, care, and maintenance of such patient in such hospital up to the date of payment of such damages; provided, that the lien herein set forth shall not be applied or considered valid against anyone suffering injuries coming under the Employees’ Compensation Act or the Workmen’s Compensation Act in this District.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 76-1-ch255" path="§1">June 30, 1939, 53 Stat. 990, ch. 255, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 19, 1948, 62 Stat. 496, ch. 525, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 38-301.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 38-301.</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">The Employees’ Compensation Act, referred to in this section, refers to the Act of September 7, 1916 which is codified in  5 U.S.C. § 8101 et seq.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">The Workmen’s Compensation Act refers to former Chapter 5 of Title 36, which was repealed by the Act of July 1, 1980, <cite doc="D.C. Law 3-77">D.C. Law 3-77</cite>, § 46.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
