<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>40-303.01</num>
  <heading>Subcontractor’s lien — generally.</heading>
  <text>Any person directly employed by a contractor described by § <cite path="§40-301.01">40-301.01</cite> (any such contractor also referred to herein as original contractor), whether the person is a subcontractor, materialman, or laborer, to furnish work or materials for the completion of the project, shall be entitled to the same rights and subject to the same obligations as the original contractor under this chapter, subject to the conditions and limitations set forth in this chapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1384, ch. 854, § 1239</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1936, 49 Stat. 1921, ch. 804</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1948, 62 Stat. 991, ch. 646, § 32(b)</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 24, 1949, 63 Stat. 107, ch. 139, § 127</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-493" type="History">July 5, 1966, 80 Stat. 265, Pub. L. 89-493, § 15(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-84" type="History">Mar. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-84, § 2(b), 49 DRC 198</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-31" type="History">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-31, § 2(d), 52 DCR 7195</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Payment as defense to assertion of lien, see § <cite path="§47-2883.03">47-2883.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-2883.03">47-2883.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 38-103.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 38-103.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-84">D.C. Law 14-84</cite> rewrote the section, which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“Any person directly employed by the original contractor, whether as subcontractor, materialman, or laborer, to furnish work or materials for the completion of the work contracted for as aforesaid, shall be entitled to a similar lien to that of the original contractor upon his filing a similar notice with the Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia to that above mentioned, subject, however, to the conditions set forth in this subchapter.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-31">D.C. Law 16-31</cite> rewrote section, which had read as follows: “Any person directly employed by the original contractor, whether as subcontractor, materialman, or laborer, to furnish work or material for the completion of the work contracted for, shall be entitled to a similar lien to that of the original contractor, upon filing a notice which complies with the requirements set forth in § <cite path="§40-301.02">40-301.02</cite>, subject, however, to the conditions set forth in §§ <cite path="§40-303.02">40-303.02</cite> to 40-303.20.”</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
