<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-432</num>
  <heading>District restricted-use and non-essential pesticides.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department shall create and maintain lists of pesticides classified as District restricted-use or non-essential.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department shall, through regulations, designate as non-essential a pesticide that is non-critical to pest management in the District.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Critical pest management includes controlling:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Plants that are poisonous to touch or may cause damage to a structure infrastructure; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Insects that bite or sting, are venomous or disease-carrying, or that may cause damage to a structure or infrastructure.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department shall presume that a pesticide should not be classified as non-essential if it is intended primarily for use on or for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Agriculture;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Forestry;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Promotion of public health or safety; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Other prescribed uses set forth in regulation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department shall, through regulations, designate as District restricted-use any pesticide that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When used as directed or in accordance with commonly recognized practice requires additional restrictions for that use to prevent a hazard to human health, the environment, or property; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department determines presents a significant, scientifically sound basis justifying that reclassification.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Department shall offer an opportunity for public comment conforming to the conditions set forth in subsection (e) of this section before classifying as District restricted-use any pesticide that is not designated as restricted-use under 40 CFR § 152.175 or adding restrictions to a restricted-use pesticide designated under 40 CFR § 152.175.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The opportunity for public comment required by subsection (d) of this section shall include at least one published notice in the District of Columbia Register regarding the proposed reclassification of a particular pesticide and a comment period of at least 30 days; provided, that the agency is required to hold a public hearing only if significant public interest is expressed during the 30-day comment period.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-191" type="History" path="§3">Oct. 23, 2012, D.C. Law 19-191, § 3, 59 DCR 10166</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 14(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-191">D.C. Law 19-191</cite> provided that §§ 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, and 13 of the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§8-431">§ 8-431</cite> and <cite path="§8-440">§ 8-440</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
