<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-134">
  <num type="law">8-134</num>
  <heading type="short">Infant and Child Abandonment Prevention Amendment Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-06-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-134.pdf">D.C. Law 8-134</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 2613</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0404">
      <narrative>Law 8-134, the “Infant and Child Abandonment Prevention Amendment Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-404, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 13, 1990, and March 27, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 13, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-190 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 203 894 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRIC,T OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-134 "Infant and Child Abandonment Prevention Amendment Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-404 on first and second readings, March 13, 1990, and March 27, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 13, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-190, published in the April 27, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 2613) and transmitted to Congress on April 18, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-134, effective June, O. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: April 18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30 May 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24 June 5,6,7 Enroiled Original Codification, District of Columbia Code (19_91 Supplement) AN ACT D.C. ACT 8-190 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA !990 To amend the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977 to provide that a child left by a parent, guardian, or custodian in a hospital in the District of Columbia for at least 10 calendar days following the birth of a child, despite a medical determination that the child is ready for discharge, shall be deemed a neglected child; and to create a legal inference that a child left by a parent, guardian, or custodian in a hospital in the District of Columbia for at least i0 calendar days following the birth of the child, despite a medical determination that the child is ready for discharge, shall be deemed an abandoned child; and to require that any child that is deemed neglected or abandoned be taken into protective custody by the District of Columbia Department of Human Services. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Infant and Child Abandonment Prevention Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 16-2301 is amended as follows i) Subparagraph (9)(F) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase or" in its place 2) A new subparagraph (G) is added to read as follows G) who has resided in a hospital located in the District of Columbia for at least I0 calendar days following the birth of the child, despite a medical determination that the child is ready for discharge from the hospital, and the parent, guardian, or custodian of the child has not taken any action or made any effort to maintain a parental, guardianship, or custodial relationship or contact with the child b) Section 16-2309(a) is amended as follows: 1 Section 16-2301 Section 16"2309 Enrolled Original (i) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the period and inserting a semicolon in its place 2) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the period and inserting a semicolon in its place 3) Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase or" in its place 4) A new paragraph (6) is added to read as follows 6) by the Chief of the Child Protective Services Division of the Department of Human Services or his or her designee, upon written notification by the chief executive officer of a hospital located in the District of Columbia, that the child has resided in the hospital for at least i0 calendar days following the birth of the child, despite a medical determination that the child is ready for discharge from the hospital, and the parent, guardian or custodian of the child, as established by the hospital admission records, has not taken any action or made any effort to maintain a parental, guardianship, or custodial relationship or contact with the child c) Section 16-2316(d) is amended as follows i) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the period after the word "months" and inserting the phrase or" in its place 2) A new paragraph (4) is added to read as follows 4) the child has resided in a hospital located in the District of Columbia for at least i0 calendar days following the birth of the child, despite a medical determination that the child was ready for discharge from the hospital, and the parent, guardian, or custodian of the child did not undertake any action or make any effort to maintain a parental, guardianship, or custodial relationship or contact with the child d) Section 16-2353(b) is amended as follows i) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the word "and" after the phrase "foster parent 2) A new paragraph (3A) is added to read as follows 3A) the child was left by his or her parent, guardian, or custodian in a hospital located in the District of Columbia for at least i0 calendar days following the birth of the child, despite a medical determination that the child was ready for discharge from the hospital, and the parent, guardian, or custodian of the child has not taken any action or made any effort to maintain a parental, guardianship, or custodial relationship or contact with the child; and Section 16-2316 Section 16-2353 2 Er rdled OriEinai Sac. 3. Section 107 of the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977, effective September 23, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-22; D.C. Code, sec. 6-2105 is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) The Chief of the Division or his or her designee shall take custody of a child and remove the child from a hospital pending further custody proceedings if i) The Chief of the Division receives written notification from the chief executive officer of a hospital located in the District of Columbia that a child has resided in the hospital for at least i0 days following the birth of the child, despite a medical determination that the child is ready for discharge; and 2) The parent, guardian, or custodian of the child, as established by the hospital admission records, has taken no action or made any effort to maintain a parental, guardianship, or custodial relationship or contact with the child Section 6-2105 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(i and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. I Chglrman C~uncil of the District of Columbia ct o~ APPROVED: April 13, 1990 3 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bi 11 Adopted First Reading, 3-13-90 8-404 Approved Absent: Mason [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT X In&amp;amp;icates Vote A.B Abser~t N.V Pr’esent,no! voting RTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Cou~ COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ~NA.Y N.V.A.8. COUNCIL ME~BER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. CHMN CLARKE MASON THOMAS, SR. CRAWFORD NATHANSON WILSON JARViS RAY WIN’~ER KANE ROLA~K LIGHTFOOT I’ SMITH, JR.I, Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. Date Adopted Final Reading, 3-27-90 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: T.homa S ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCILMEMBER CI~MN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD N~THAN~’ON JARVIS ’ KANE R~LARK LI HltFOO’T AYE NAY N.V. AB. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER I sMITH, JR’. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to ~e C~ N.V Present, not voting AYE NAY N.V. Date Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LihHTFOOT AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote couNcIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON -’ RAY 0LA K SMIT, H, JR. A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. AB. N-.V PresenL not voting COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
