<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-145">
  <num type="law">8-145</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act of 1979 Amendment Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-06-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-145.pdf">D.C. Law 8-145</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 2977</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0487">
      <narrative>Law 8-145, the “District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act of 1979 Amendment Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-487, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 27, 1990, and April 10, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 26, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-201 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 203 370 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OFFICE OF THE GENERAL COUNSEL WASHINGTON, D C 20004 I TRANSMITTAL OF ENROLLED LEGISLATION Short Title: District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act of 1979 Amendment Act of 1990 Bill #8-487 Act Date Transmitted to LSD: Received by LSD: CC: CC: Councilmember Kane Codification Counsel (with attachment with attachment) Please notify me of any error/comment within 24 hours II. CLEARANCE OF ENROLLED LEGISLATION t e~X s T a ti V-e- Cd u n ey Codi fi catiLon Couns~l ’office of the secretary Dat~ Date Date III CLEARANCE OF CORRESPONDENCE BY LSU ’Le’tter(s) to th~ Mayor Date L~tter(s) to ’Congress Rev, 6/15/89 D~te COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-145 "District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act of 1979 Amendment Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-487 on first and second readings, March 27, 1990, and April I0, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 26, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-201, published in the May 11, 1990, edition of the D.C._Register Vol. 37 page 2977) and transmitted to Congress on May 2, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-145, effective June 22, 1990. Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: I,~ay 2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24 June 5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21 8-145 AN ACT ACT 8 201 Codification, District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APR 6 To amend the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act of 1979 to provide for an increase in the annuity payable from the Retirement Fund to minor children of members of the uniformed services of the District of Columbia who due to the death of the member are left without a surviving parent. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act of 1979 Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Section 3 of the Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act, approved August 21, 1957 (71 Stat. 396; D.C. Code, sec. 4-622 is amended as follows I) Subsection (c)(2) is amended to read as follows 2) In the case of a member or former member who is not survived by a wife or husband A) 75% of the member’s average pay at the time of death, divided by the number of elJ.gible children B) In the c~se of a member who was an officer or member of the United States Park Police Force, the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, or the United States Secret Service Division i) 75% of the basis upon which the former member’s annuity at the time of death was computed, divided by the number of eligible children ii 1,860; or iii 5,580 divided by the number of eligible children C) In the case of a member who was an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, 75% of the adjusted average pay of t~e former member, divided by the number of eligible children Section 4-622 (2) Subsection (e D.C. Code, sec. 4-622(e is amended as follows A) Paragraph 2 is amended to read as follows 2) The annuity of any child under this section shall begin on the Ist day of the month in which the member or former member dies, and the annuity shall terminate upon whichever of the following occurs Ist A) The child becomes 18 years of age or, if over 18 years of age and incapable of self-support, becomes capable of self-support B) The child marries; or C) The child dies B) Paragraph (3) is amended to read as follows 3)(A) The annuity of any student child under this section shall begin on the ist day of the month in which the member or former member dies, and the annuity shall terminate upon whichever of the following occurs Ist i) The student child marries ii) The student child ceases to be a student; years of age; or iii) The student child reaches 22 iv) The student child dies B) For the purposes of this paragraph, a student child whose 22nd birthday falls on or after July Ist shall not be considered to have reached 22 years of age until the June 30th following the student child’s actual 22nd birthday Sec. 3. To carry out the purposes of this act, the Mayor shall, pursuant to section 142(d)(I) of the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act of 1979, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Stat. 866; D.C. Code, sec. 1-722(d)(i D.C. Retirement Reform Act appoint an enrolled actuary to perform the required actuarial, study. The cost of the actuarial study shall be borne by the District of Columbia Police Officers and Fire Fighters’ Retirement Fund. The actuarial study shall be completed by June I0 990. Sec. 4. The increased benefits provided for in the District of Columbia Retirement Act of ~979 Amendment Act of ].990 shall begin to accrue on April I0, 1990, but shall not be paid until the change in benefits becomes effective pursuant to section 142(d)(I) of the D.C. Retirement Reform Act. Sec. 5. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Note, Section 4-622 1-722 Note, Section 1-722 4-622 2 Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: April 26, 1990 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ’ NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote Secretary to the Council ,r~ltem on Consent Calendar ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Q ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote Bill 5-487 Adopted First Readinq, 3-27-90 Approved all present COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY N.V. A.B ’ COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER N,V Present, not voting Date Adopted Final Reading, 4-10-90 Approved all present COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON W~NTER N.V Present, not voting J Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIIH, JR. A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD W J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
