<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-149">
  <num type="law">8-149</num>
  <heading type="short">DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA PUBLIC SCHOOL NURSE ASSIGNMENT ACT OF 1987 AMENDMENT ACT OF 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-07-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-149.pdf">D.C. Law 8-149</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 3717</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0511">
      <narrative>Law 8-149 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-511, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 1, 1990, and May 15, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 30, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-207 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag 103 202 657 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-149 "District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987 Amendment Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-511 on first and second readings, May i, 1990, and May 15, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on May 30, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-207, published in the June 8, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 3717) and transmitted to Congress on June 5, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-149, effective July 25, 1990 Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: June 5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,25,26,27,28,29 July 10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24 o c. LAW 8 Z 4 9 Enrolled Ori ,in l JUL Z 5 1990 AN ACT Codification, District of Columbia Code (1991 Su_mplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MAY 3 0 1990 To amend the District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987 to modify the level of medical coverage required at a District of Columbia interscholastic athletic event held in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987 Amendment Act of 1990" Sec. 2. Section 2 of the District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987, effective December I0, 1987 (D.C. Law 7-45; D.C. Code, sec. 31-2421 School Nurse Assignment Act is amended as follows a) By amending subsection (d) to read as follows d) Appropriate medical coverage, as defined in rules issued by the Board of Education in accordance with title 1 of the Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq and in consultation with the Commissioner of Public Health, shall be provided by the Board of Education at any interscholastic athletic event if the event is sponsored by a District public school, occurs in the District, and is identified as requiring medical coverage by rule. This medical coverage may include, but is not limited to I) A licensed medical doctor 2) A registered nurse 3) A certified athletic trainer 4) An emergency medical technician EMT or paramedic 5) A certified pre-hospital care provider (as determined by the Commissioner of Public Health or (6) An adult trained by the Red Cross with current certification in cardiopulmonary resuscitation CPR first aid, or life-saving Section 31-2421 1 (b) By amending subsection (e) to read as follows e)(1) Appropriate medical coverage shall be consistent with the risk of injury involved in the interscholastic athletic event. The medical personnel that shall be present at an interscholastic athletic event that occurs in the District and that is sponsored by a District secondary public school shall be detailed as follows A) Eor football, a licensed medical doctor B) For basketball, wrestling, soccer, indoor or outdoor track and field events, or cross-country, at least 1 licensed doctor, certified athletic trainer, registered nurse, EMT or paramedic, or any other certified pre-hospital care provider, as determined by the Commissioner of Public Health C) For volleyball, baseball, softball, or swimming, at least 1 licensed medical doctor, certified athletic trainer, registered nurse, EMT or paramedic, any other certified pre-hospital care provider, as determined by the Commissioner of Public Health, or adult trained by the American Red Cross with current certification in CPR, first aid, or life-saving D) For tennis or golf, medical personnel coverage shall be optional as financial resources allow E) For any other sport, the appropriate level of medical personnel coverage, commensurate with the risk of injury involved, shall be set by the Superintendent of Schools of the District of Columbia, in consultation with the Commissioner of Public Health, and approved by the Board of Education; and 2) The medical personnel coverage services shall be in addition to the minimum hours of registered nurse services required by subsection (a) or (b) of this section and (c) By adding the following new subsections to read as follows f) Sufficient funds to carry out the requirements of this section shall be appropriated out of the general revenues of the District g) Beginning with the Fiscal Year 1991, the responsibility for implementation of District of Columbia Public School Nurse Assignment Act of 1987 Amendment Act of 1990 shall be transferred from the Department of Human Services to the Board of Education Sec. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia 2 Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Co]hmbia Municipal Regulations Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District APPROVED: May 30, 1990 3 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: [] Item on Consent Calendar ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [~ VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Smith Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. Bill 8-511 Adopted First Reading, 5-1-90 AYE NAY N.V. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER X Indicates Vote A la, bsent N.V Present, not voting ~tary~ th~ Council 7 Date Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, 5-15-90 vo~c£ vo~£: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER! AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON THOMAS, SR. CRAWFORD NATHANSON WILSON JARVIS RAY WINTER KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A Absent N.V Present, not voting IFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Counci ’/ Date [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: F; ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT.H, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
