<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-157">
  <num type="law">8-157</num>
  <heading type="short">Preventive Health Services Amendment Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-09-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-157.pdf">D.C. Law 8-157</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 4165</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0385">
      <narrative>Law 8-157, the “Preventive Health Services Amendment Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-385, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 29, 1990, and June 12, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 18, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-219 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-157 "Preventive Health Services Amendment Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-385 on first and second readings, May 29, 1990, and June 12, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 18, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-219, published in the June 29, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 4165) and transmitted to Congress on June 21, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-157, effective September 11, 1990 C LARKE Chairman of the Council June July August Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: 21,22,25,26,27,28,29 10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30,31 1,2,3 September 5,6,7,10 AN ACT Enrolled Origi l Codification District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) D.C. aCT 8 9, 1 9 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUN 8 990 To permit the Commissioner of Public Health to exchange identifying cancer information to a registry maintained by a state in order to foster effective cancer research, prevention, and control efforts. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Preventive Health Services Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Section 2 of An Act to make cancer and all malignant neoplastic diseases reportable to the Director of Public Health of the District of Columbia, approved July 27, 1951 (65 Star. 124; D.C. Code, sec. 6-1202 is amended to read as follows a) By amending subsection (b)(1) by striking the 2nd "or b) By amending subsection (b)(2) by striking the period at the end and inserting or" in its place; and (c) By adding a new subsection (3) to read as follows 3) The identifying information is exchanged with a cancer registry that is maintained by a state and the Commissioner of Public Health receives a satisfactory assurance from the cancer registry that the confidentiality of the identifying information shall be preserved Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by th~ Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(i and Section 6-1202 Enrolled Original publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: June 18, 1990 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Item on Consent Calendar F# ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT Adopted First Reading, 5-29-90 Approved Crawford COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT 8-385 AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER MASON THOMAS, SR. NATHANSON WILSON RAY WINTER ROLARK SMITH, JR X Indicates Vote Absent NV Present, not voting Secretary to the Council(J Date Item on Consent Calendar Adopted Final Reading, 6-12-90 ’ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.8. CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVlS KANE LIGHTFOOT Approved all present COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR X Indicates Vote ,4, AB Absent N.V Present, not voting Secretae to the Co~ Item on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIT.H, JR. A.B Absent AYE NAY NV. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER A,Bo A.Bo Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
