<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-152">
  <num type="law">8-152</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 Physician Assistants Amendment Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-07-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-152.pdf">D.C. Law 8-152</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 3743</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0353">
      <narrative>Law 8-152, the “District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 Physician Assistants Amendment Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-353, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 1, 1990, and May 15, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 30, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-210 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag 103 204 413 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-152 "District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 Physician Assistants Amendment Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-353 on first and second readings, May I, 1990, and May 15, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on May 30, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-210, published in the June 8, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 3743) and transmitted to Congress on June 5, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-152, effective July 25, 1990. Chalrman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: June 5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,25,26,27,28,29 July 10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24 AN ACT Enrolled Codification, District of Columbia Code 1991 Supplement) 8 -21o IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MAY 1990 To amend the Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 to provide for the waiver of licensure requirements for any physician assistant who presently practices in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 Physician Assistants Amendment Act of 1990 Sec, 2. Section 203 the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Code, sec. 2-3302.3 is amended by adding a new subsection (a-l) to read as follows a-l)(1) The Board shall waive the educational and examination requirements for any applicant for licensure as a physician assistant who can demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Board, that he or she has performed the function of a physician assistant, as defined in this act and rules issued pursuant to this act, on a full-time or substantially full-time basis continuously for at least 36 months immediately preceding the effective date of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, and is qualified to do so on the basis of pertinent education, training, experience, and demonstrated current competence, provided that application for the license is made within 12 months of the effective date of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 Physician Assistants Amendment Act of 1990 2) An applicant licensed under paragraph (I) of this subsection shall be eligible for license renewal on the same terms as any other licensed physician assistant Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Section 2-3302.3 1 Enrolled Original Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations il of the District Coi m 2 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO Bill Adopted First Readinq, 5-1-90 Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: 8-353 Smith [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V X Indicates Vote 4~8 Absent TIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Counc~’~ Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final N.V Present, not voting Date ReadinG° 5-15-90 VOICE VOTF" Approved Recorded vote on ree uest Absent: a i 1 [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVlS KANE LIGHTFOOT present COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. AYE NAY N.V. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V X Indicates,Y, ot~ A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting ~I~TIFICATION RECORD ’ 7 o the Council Date [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIT.H, JR. A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J Jm COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER A.Bo A.B. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
