<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-165">
  <num type="law">8-165</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Statutory Savings Provision Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1990-09-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-165.pdf">D.C. Law 8-165</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 4827</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 8-165, the “District of Columbia Statutory Savings Provision Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-552, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 12, 1990, and June 26, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 12, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-230 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwilcrag’~ 103 201 792 COUNCI~ OF, THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-165 "District of Columbia Statutory Savings Provision Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-552 on first and second readings, June 12, 1990, and June 26, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 12, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-230, published in the July 27, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 4827) and transmitted to Congress on July 16, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-165, effective September 26, 1990. Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July 16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30,31 August 1,2,3 September 5,6,7,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25 AN ACT Enrolled Origi t Codification District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) O.CACP 8- o IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUL t 2 To provide a savings provision for repealed or expired acts of the Council of the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Statutory Savings Provision Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Savings provision a) The repeal of any act of the Council shall not release or extinguish any penalty, forfeiture, or liability incurred pursuant to the act, and the act shall be treated as remaining in force for the purpose of sustaining any proper action or prosecution for the enforcement of any penalty, forfeiture, or liability, unless the repealing act expressly provides for the release or extinguishment oZ any penalty, forfeiture, or liability b) The expiration of any act of the Council shall not release or extinguish any penalty, forfeiture, or liability incurred pursuant to the act, and the act shall be treated as remaining in force for the purpose of sustaining any proper action or prosecution for the enforcement of any penalty, forfeiture, or liability, unless the expiring act expressly provides for the release or extinguishment of any penalty, forfeiture, or liability. Sec. 3. Child Support Guidelines amendment. Section 16-916.1(q) of the Child Support Guidelines Amendment Act of 1990, signed by the Mayor on May 30, 1990 (D.C. Act 8-208; to be codified at D.C. Code, sec. 16-916.1 is amended by striking the phrase "ONE CHILDREN" and inserting the phrase "THREE CHILDREN" in its place. Sec. 4 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as Section 49-304 Section 16-916.1 Enrolled provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c i and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations a~ rman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: July 12, 1990 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO Item on Consent Calendar X~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT Adopted First Reading, 6-12-90 Bill 8-552 Approved AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYENAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Ray COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. A.8 AbsentX Indicates Vote Date N.V Present, not voting ~ncil ION RECORD }~ Item on Consent Calendar }~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, ]~ VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Wilson 6-26-90 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent C~ RECORD Secretary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar AYE NAY NV. A.B. N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. I WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIIH, JR. A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§45-404"/>
  </section>
</document>
