<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-193">
  <num type="law">8-193</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1991-03-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-193.pdf">D.C. Law 8-193</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 6728</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 8-193 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-384, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 25, 1990, and October 9, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 17, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-256 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag" 103 203 787 0 0 0 0 -0 0 0 0 0 CO 0 I 0 ¯ 0 0 0 AN ACT Enrolled Original Codification District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) D.C. ACl" 8 256 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to establish a procedure for employees of the District of Columbia government to elect to work flexible work hours in order to accommodate their free exercise of religion. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Religious Accommodation Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Section 701 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code, sec. 1-607.1 is amended by adding the following new subsect ions c) If an employee’s religious beliefs require the employee to take time off from work during certain periods of the workday or workweek, the employee may elect to make up the time off, rather than to charge the time off to leave, in accordance with the procedures established under subsections (d) and (e) of this section d) An employee who makes an election pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall, i£ the need to take off is foreseeable, request an adjustment of his or her work schedule and obtain supervisory approval of the ad3ustment at least i0 days before taking time off from work. A request to adjust a work schedule may be disapproved if it is demonstrated that the ad3ustment would clearly interfere with the efficient conduct of the activities of the entity of the District government for which the employee works e) Notice of an employee’s opportunity to obtain a religious accommodation shall be provided to the employee at the time the employee accepts appointment with the District government f) Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the use of other forms of leave authorized by the Section 1-607.1 1 Enrolled Original District government or to require a supervisor to allow an employee the opportunity to work more than 40 hours in a given week to make up for the time taken off for the rel ig ious accommodation ¯ Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c i and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia [] Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: September 25, 1990 VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request B8-384 Absent: Approved All Present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK UGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V X Indicates Vote ’ B Absent NV Present, not voting ERTIF,CAT,ON RECORD Secretary to the Cou~ Dee Item on Consent Calendar ~ACTION&amp;amp;DATE: Oc~obe~ 9 990 VOICE VOTE o~e~ Recorded vote on request Absent: A11 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. Present AYE NAY N.V. A.B: COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V X Indicates Vote A bsent N.V Present, not voting CEF~T,F~e~TION RECORD Secreta~ to the Council Date Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULI COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. I AB. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT.H, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.8. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
