<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-201">
  <num type="law">8-201</num>
  <heading type="short">TASK FORCE ON HUNGER ACT OF 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1991-03-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-201.pdf">D.C. Law 8-201</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 7476</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0510"/>
    <search-text>kwiktag 103 202 650 COUNCIL OFITHE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-201 "Task Force on Hunger Act of 1990 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-510 on first and second readings, October 23, 1990, and November 13, 1990, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 20, 1990, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-266, published in the November 30, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 7476) and transmitted to Congress on January II, 1991 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.Co Law 8-201, effective March 6, 1991 ’ WILSON Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January February March 11,14,15,16,17,18,22,23,24,25,28,29,30,31 1,4,5,6,7,19,20,21,22,25,26,27,28 1,4,5 AN ACT 8 66 Codification NewChapter 37 of Title 2 District of Columbia Code (11991 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOlO To establish a Task Force on Hunger to devise a comprehensive plan to end hunger in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Task Force on Hunger Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Task Force on Hunger established a) There is established a District of Columbia Task Force on Hunger Task Force that shall be comprised of 21 members. Each member of the Task Force shall be a resident of the District of Columbia District Members shall be appointed in the following manner I) Nine members shall be appointed by each Ward representative and the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia Council and (2) Twelve members shall be appointed by the Mayor. An appointee of the Mayor shall serve as Chairperson of the Task Force b)(1) The Council and the Mayor shall appoint as members clients who are served by public and private food assistance programs, experts in the areas of health and nutrition, members of the food industry, emergency food providers, and members of public and community interest organizations that are headquartered and provide service in the District 2) The Mayor shall make appointments that include representation from the Commission on Social Services, the Commission on Public Health, the Office on Aging, and any other agency that provides public assistance in the District c) The Task Force and the terms of its members shall expire 270 days from the ist meeting of the Task Force. Any vacancy that occurs on the Task Force shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. New, Section 2-3701 (d) Members of the Task Force shall be appointed within 45 days of the effective date of this act. The Chairperson of the Task Force shall convene an organizational meeting no later than 15 days after a majority of the members have been appointed. Sec. 3. Powers and duties of the Task Force a) The Task Force shall I) Identify and analyze the population that is subjected to hunger and investigate the reasons for its condition of hunger 2) Assess the needs of persons who are subjected to hunger and analyze the availability of counselling in the areas of health and nutrition, job training and placement, housing, and life skills development 3) Review District food assistance programs and identify areas of success and areas of inadequate service 4) Review private food assistance programs that operate in the District and review the extent of coordination of the private food assistance programs with District programs 5) Make recommendations that are designed to end hunger in the District and devise goals, objectives, and the steps necessary to implement the recommendations 6) Establish priorities and a timetable for achievement of the implementation of the goals, objectives, and steps recommended by the Task Force; and (7) Identify any individual, organization, or agency that can facilitate the implementation of the recommendations and ~oals of the Task Force b) The Task Force shall solicit public comment with respect to its recommendations c) Within 180 days after the Ist meeting of the Task Force, the Task Force shall submit to the Council and the Mayor a final comprehensive report that contains specific recommendations for appropriate legislative, administrative, and regulatory action on means to end hunger in the District. Sec. 4. Compensation and expenses of the Task Force Members. Each member of the Task Force shall serve without compensation. Sec. 5. Staffing and Budget. The Mayor shall provide office space, detail staff, and provide technical and administrative support to assist the Task Force in the fulfillment of its duties in accordance with section 3. New, Section 2-3702 New, Section 2-3703 New, Section 2-3704 2 Sec. 6. Rules a) The Mayor may, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq issue rules to implement the provisions of this act b) The Task Force may create and implement internal rules necessary to carry out the provisions of this act. Sec. 7. Applicability. The duties and rights established by this act shall apply after April 30, 1991. Sec. 8. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia New, Section 2-3705 New, Section 2-3706 New, Section 2-3707 APPROVED: November 20, 1990 3 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Item on Consent Calendar 1~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: C~ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT 8-510 Adopted First Reading, 10-23-90 Approved Wilson COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER i i AYE NAY N.Y. X Indicates Vote AB Absent N.V Present, not voting Secretary to the Co~ Date [~ltem on Consent Calendar ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [~XVOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Adopted Final Readinq, 11-13-90 Approved all~ present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent CEI~FICATIONRECORD } Secretary 1o the Counc Item on Consent Calendar AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Date i l AYE NAY N.V. ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVlS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIIH, JR. A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER 1 AYE NAY N.V. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2801"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2802"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2803"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2804"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2805"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2806"/>
  </section>
</document>
