<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-231">
  <num type="law">8-231</num>
  <heading type="short">General License Law Amendment Act of 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1991-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-231.pdf">D.C. Law 8-231</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 257</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0250">
      <narrative>Law 8-231, the “General License Law Amendment Act of 1990,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-250, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1990, and December 18, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-314 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 202 221 d ¯ AN ACT Emol i inal Codi fi cation District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) D,C, ACT 8-314 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC, 27, 1990 To amend An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes to provide for the revocation of a business license if the licensee has permitted illegal drug activity on the licensed premises. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "General License Law Amendment Act of 1990 Sec. 2. Paragraph 46 of section 7 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes, approved July I, 1902 (32 Stat. 628; D.C. Code, sec. 47-2844 is amended as follows a) By adding a new subsection (a-l) to read as follows a-l)(1) In accordance with section I0 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1208; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1509 the Mayor shall revoke the license of any licensee who knowingly has permitted on the licensed premises A) The illegal sale, negotiation for sale, or use of any controlled substance as that term is defined in the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, effective August 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-29; D.C. Code, sec. 33-501 et seq or the Controlled Substances Act of 1970, approved October 27, 1970 (84 Stat. 1243; 21U.S.C. 801 et seq or (B) The possession, sale, or negotiation for sale of drug paraphernalia in violation of the Drug Paraphernalia Act of 1982, effective September 17, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-149; D.C. Code, sec. 33-601 et seq Section 47-2844 Enrolled Original 2) The Mayor, by rule, shall establish costs and fines to cover revocation of any license revoked pursuant to paragraph (I) of this subsection Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(i and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regul at ions a i Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: December 27, 1990. Item on Consent Calendar ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE D~STRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Readinq, 12-04-90 Approved B8-250 Recorded vote on request all present Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent !AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, VOICE VOTE: Approved COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Date 12-18-90 AYE NAY N.V. Recorded vote on request Absent: Wi i S O n [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. ’ X Indicates Vote A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Item on Consent Calendar AYE NAY NV. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER N.V Present, not votin9 Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIIH, JR.’ A.B Absem AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER A.B, Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
