<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-237">
  <num type="law">8-237</num>
  <heading type="short">DEPARTMENT OF CONSUMER AND REGULATORY AFFAIRS CIVIL INFRACTIONS ACT OF 1985 TECHNICAL AND CLARIFYING AMENDMENTS ACT OF 1990</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1991-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-237.pdf">D.C. Law 8-237</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 314</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0203">
      <narrative>Law 8-237 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-203, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1990, and December 18, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-320 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 201 061 0 0 0 a~ " 0 Or) 0 0 AN ACT D,C, ACT 8-320 Codification District of Columbia Code (1991 Supplement) and District of Columbia Municipal Regulations IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC, 27, 1990 To amend the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infraction Act of 1985 to give the Mayor padlock authority, to make technical and clarifying amendments, and to extend the coverage of Titles I through III of the act to additional regulatory programs. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Technical and Clarifying Amendments Act of 1990 Sec. 2. The Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Code, sec. 6-2701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 102(2 D.C. Code, sec. 6-2702(2 is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the following phrase or for which another civil sanction may be imposed under any District laws or regulations b) Section 103 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-2703) is amended as follows I) By striking the phrase "Sec. 103. Hearing Examiners and inserting the phrase "Sec. 103. Administrative law judges and attorney examiners in its place 2) By striking, wherever it appears, the phrase "hearing examiners" and inserting the phrase "administrative law judges or attorney examiners" in its place 3) By amending paragraph (5) in subsection (b) to read as follows A) Paragraph (5) is amended to read as follows 5) Permitting the payment of monetary fines, penalties, and hearing and inspection costs in excess of $50 in monthly installments over a period not greater than 6 Section 6-2702 Section 6-2703 Enrolled Original months and allowing a fee of 1 percent per month of the outstanding amount owed by a respondent for the installment service; and 4) By adding in subsection (b) a new paragraph (7) to read as follows 7) Sealing the premises wher the conduct occurred which is the basis of the citation to enforce orders requiring the payment of monetary fines, penalties, or hearing and inspection costs 4) Subsection (c) is amended to read as follows 5) By inserting in subsection (c) immediately before the word "established" the phrase "or successor entity and (6) By adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) Administrative law judges and attorney examiners appointed pursuant to this section may hear cases pursuant to the District of Columbia Consumer Protection Procedures Act, effective July 22, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-76; D.C. Code, sec. 28-3901 et seq c) Section 104(b D.C. Code, sec. 6-2704(b is amended by striking the phrase "a hearing examiner" and inserting the phrase "an administrative law judge or attorney examiner" in its place d) A new section 106 is added to read as follows Sec. 106. Summary action a) If the Mayor determines, after investigation, that the conduct of a licensee presents an imminent danger to the health or safety of the residents of the District, the Mayor may order the sealing of the premises upon which the respondent is engaged in the unlawful conduct, provided that the premises are primarily used for the unlawful activity b) At the time of the sealing of the premises, the Mayor shall provide the licensee with written notice stating the action being taken, the basis for the action, and the right of the licensee to request a hearing c) A licensee shall have the right to request a hearing within 72 hours after service of notice of the sealing of the premises. The Mayor shall hold a hearing within 72 hours of receipt of a timely request, and shall issue a decision within 72 hours after the hearing d) Every decision and order adverse to a licensee shall be accompanied by findings of fact and conclusions of law. The findings shall be supported by, and in accordance with, reliable, probative, and substantial evidence. The Mayor shall provide a copy of the decision and order and accompanying findings of fact and conclusions of law to each party to a case or to each party’s attorney of record. Section 6-2704 Section 6-2706 e) Any person aggrieved by a final summary action may seek judicial review in accordance with title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 120&amp;amp D.Co Code, sec. 1-1501 e t (e) Section 201(a D.C. Code, sec. 6-2711(a is Section amended by striking the phrase "title I-III" and inserting 6-2711 the phrase "title I and II" in its place f) Section 201(c D.C. Code, sec. 6-2711(c is amended by striking the phrases "a hearing examiner" and inserting the phrase "administrative law judge or attorney examiner" in its place h) Section 202(g D.C. Code, sec. 6-2712(g is Section amended to read as follows: 6-2712 g) No notice of infraction issued pursuant to titles I and II shall abridge or abrogate any time periods established by the laws and regulations amended by title IV regarding cure of an infraction i) Section 203 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-2713) is amended as Secti0n follows: 6-2713 (I) By striking wherever they appear the phrases "hearing examiner" and "hearing examiner’s" and inserting the phrases "administrative law judge or attorney examiner" and "administrative law judge’s or attorney examiner’s" respectively in their places; and (2) By adding a new subsection (i) to read as follows i) The Mayor may place liens on property for non-payment of fines, penalties, and costs as follows I) Whenever the owner of real property in the District of Columbia fails to pay all fines, penalites, or costs associated with a final adjudication under this act, the District shall have a continuing lien upon the property and upon any improvements on the property in the amount of the outstanding charges 2) These liens shall have priority over all other liens except liens for District taxes and District water charges; and 3) If outstanding charges remain unpaid 90 days after the date to appeal a final adjudication, and no appeal has been taken, the property may be sold for costs at the next tax sale in the same manner and under the same conditions as property sold for delinquent general taxes, if the outstanding charges, together with penalties and costs, have not been paid in full prior to the sale j) Section 204 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-2714) is amended as 5ecti0n follows: 6-2714 (I) By striking the phrase "hearing examiner" and inserting the phrase "administrative law judge or attorney examiner" in its place; and Em’ol] d Originat (2) By designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) The Mayor may prepare a listing of delinquent respondents who have not paid or appealed within fifteen days of service, fines, penalties, or costs resulting from final decisions issued by attorney examiners and may periodically publish such a list in one or more general circulation newspapers published in the District of Columbia k) Section 301 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-2721) is amended as follows I) By striking the word "final" preceding the word "orders" and (2) By striking the phrase "March i, 1899 (30 Star. 923; D.C. Code, sec. 5-601 et seq and inserting the phrase "June I, 1910 (36 Stat. 452; D.C. Code, sec. 5-401 e_~t se in its place i) Section 302 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-2722) is amended as follows (I) By striking the word "final" preceding the word "order 2) By striking the phrase "titles I -III" and inserting the phrase "titles I and II" in its place; and (3) By striking the phrase "a hearing examiner" and inserting the phrase "an administrative law judge or attorney examiner" in its place m) Section 303 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-2723) is amended as follows I) By striking, wherever they appear, the phrase "hearing examiner" and "a hearing examiner" and inserting the phrase "administrative law judge or attorney examiner" and "an administrative law judoe or attorney examiner" respectively, in their places; and (2) By striking the phrase "title I -III" and inserting the phrase "titles I and II" in its place n) Section 414 is amended in the lead-in text by striking the year "1979" and inserting the year "1977" in its place o) Section 431 is amended in the lead-in text by striking the year "1942" and inserting the year "1962" in its place p) Section 442 is amended in the lead-in text by striking the phrase "64 Stat. 685" and inserting the phrase "64 Stat. 865" in its place q) Section 443 is amended as follows I) By amending the lead-in text to read as follows Section 615 of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1949, effective March I0, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-71; D.C. Code, Section 6-2721 Section 6-2722 Section 6-2723 Original sec. 47-2414 is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows and (2) By changing the designation of the new subsection from "c" to "d r) Section 447 is amended as follows I) Subsection (a) is amended in the lead-in text by striking the phrase "Section 3(b and inserting the phrase "Section 3 of chapter II" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended in the lead-in text by striking the phrase "Section 36(b and inserting the phrase "Section 36 of chapter II" in its place; and (3) Subsection (c) is amended in the lead-in text by inserting immediately following the phrase "Section 43" the phrase "of chapter II s) Section 448 is amended as follows I) Subsection (a) is amended in the lead-in text by striking the phrase "subsection (d and inserting the phrase "paragraph at the end" in its place; and (2) Subsection (b) is amended in the lead-in text as follows A) By striking the phrase "Section 37(b and inserting the phrase "Section 37" in its place; and (B) By inserting in the first sentence after the word "amended" the phrase "in the second paragraph t) Section 453 is amended by amending the lead-in text to read as follows Section 4 of title II of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, effective September 26, 1984 (D.C. Law 412; D.C. Code, sec. 47-2604 is amended by adding 2 sentences to the end to read as follows u) Section 462 (D.C. Code, sec. 35-1425) is amended in the lead-in text by striking the phrase "42 Stat. 412; D.C. Code, sec. 35-1425" and inserting the phrase "42 Stat. 414; D.C. Code, sec. 35-1428" in its place v) Section 485 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-905) is amended to read as follows Sec. 485. 20 DCMR is amended as follows a) Section 105 of chapter 1 is amended by inserting a new subsection 105.2 to read as follows 105.2. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this subtitle, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this subtitle shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 b) Section 3013 of chapter 30 is amended by adding a 20 new subsection 3013.4 to read as follows: Sections 47-2602, 47-2604 Sections 35-1425, 35-1428 20 DCMR 105.2 DCMR 3013.4 5 E iro led Original "3013.4. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of chapters 30 or 31, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of chapters 30 or 31 shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 3. Section 16 of the Veterinary Practice Act of 1982, effective March 9, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-171; D.C. Code, sec. 2-2735 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules and regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 4. D.C. Code, sec. 28-3902(e) is amended to read as follows e) The Mayor shall appoint 1 or more attorneys qualified to serve as administrative law judges or attorney examiners to conduct adjudicatory proceedings. Any administrative law judge or attorney examiner appointed pursuant to this subsection may hear cases pursuant to section 103 of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 5. Section 7 of An Act to regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms, and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real estate brokers in the District of Columbia, approved February 4, 1913 (37 Stat. 659; D.C. Code, sec. 26-707 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department Section 2-2735 Section 28-3902 Section 26-707 6 of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 6. Title III of the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, effective August 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-29; D.C. Code, sec. 33-531 et seq is amended by adding a new section 309 to read as follows Sec. 309. Civil infractions. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this title, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this title, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this title shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Section 33-539 Sec. 7. Section 200 of chapter 2 of the Business, 17 Industry, and Professions Regulations (17 DCMR sec. 200) is DCMR amended by adding a new subsection 200.9 to read as follows: 200.9 "200.9. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this chapter pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this chapter shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 8. Section III of chapter 1 of the Public Health and Medicine Regulations (22 DCMR sec. III) is amended by adding a new subsection 111.16 to read as follows 111.16. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this chapter pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this chapter shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 22 DCMR 111.16 Sec. 9. Section 8-2:808 of the District of Columbia Health Regulations, effective September 28, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-23; 21DCMR sec. 508 is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows d) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this chapter pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil 21 DCMR 508 Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this chapter shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. I0. Appendix I of the Regulation Establishing Administrative Rules for Occupational and Professional Licensing Boards, enacted January 28, 1972 (Reg. 72-3; 17 DCMR sec. i00 is amended by adding a new section 70.1 to read as follows Sec. 70.1 Alternative Adjudication as a Civil Infraction In the alternative, adjudication of any infraction of the regulations to which the Administrative Rules for Occupational and Professional Licensing Boards are applicable may be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of the regulations applicable to the Administrative Rules for Occupational and Professional Licensing Boards pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 17 DCMR i00 Sec. Ii. Section 8-6:120 of the District of Columbia Health Regulations, effective January 19, 1974 (Reg. 74-1, sec. 21; 23 DCMR, chapter 20 is amended as follows a) Subsection (b 23 DCMR sec. 2001.3) is amended by 23 striking the word "health" and inserting the phrase "health, DCMR the Director may take corrective action, including, but not 2001.3 limited to, the following" in its place b) Subsection (b)(1) is amended by striking the word "shall" and inserting the word "may" in its place c) Subsection (b)(2) is amended by striking the word "shall" and inserting the word "may" im its place; and (d) Subsection (e 23 DCMR sec. 2004.2) is amended by 23 designating the existing text as paragraph (I) and adding a DCMR new paragraph (2) to read as follows: 2004.2 2) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this part pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this part shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 12. Section 8-6:908 of the District of Columbia 23 Health Regulations, effective September 15, 1967 (C.O. DCMR 67-1301; 23 DCMR sec. 3200.4 is amended by designating the 3200.4 8 existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this part pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this part shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 13. Section 8-6:724 of the District of Columbia Health Regulations, effective September I, 1963 (C.O. 63-1891; 23 DCMR secs. 3125.5 and 3125.4 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this part pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this part shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 23 DCMR 3125.4 3125.5 Sec. 14. Section 2 of article 39 of the Police Regulations of the District of Columbia (24 DCMR sec. 2010) is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalites, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this article which involve any container that has been left unattended within a residential building or structure or which is not in plain view from public space pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this article which in not in plain view from public space shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 24 DCMR 2010 Sec. 15. Act of 1986, effective February 24, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-187; D.C. Code, sec. 45-2807 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of Section 8 of the Real Property Wet Settlement Section 45-2807 9 the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 16. Section 12 of the District of Columbia Interior Designer Licensure Act of 1986, effective February 2 1987 (D.C. Law 6-172; D.C. Code, sec. 2-3411 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 17. Section 5 of the Phosphate Soaps and Detergent Restriction Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-98; D.C. Code, sec. 6-974 is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 18. Section 12 of the Security Alarm Systems Regulations Act of 1980, effective September 26, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-107; D.C. Code, sec. 6-3111 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Section 2-3411 Section 6-974 Section 6-3111 I0 Enrolled Origina Sec. 19. Section 7 of the Hearing Aid Dealers and Consumers Act of 1977, effective October 26, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-33; D.C. Code, sec. 28-4006 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Section 28-4006 Sec. 20. Section 401 of the District of Columbia Section Prescription Drug Price Information Act, effective September 33-741 I0, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-81; D.C. Code, sec. 33-741 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and by adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows c) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-II1 of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 21. Part I, chapter of title 8 of the District of 22 Columbia Health Regulations, effective March 21, 1967 (C.O. DCMR 67-380; 22 DCMR, chapters 20-23 is amended by adding a new 20-23 section 8-7:137 to read as follows 8-7:137. ENFORCEMENT AS A CIVIL INFRACTION Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 22. Section 8-2:1009 of the District of Columbia 20 Health Regulations, effective July 9, 1970 (Reg. 70-33; 20 DCMR DCMR sec. 2010 is amended by designating the two existing 2010 paragraphs as subsections (a) and (b) respectively and adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows: II c) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 23. Section 901(f) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Code, sec. 45-2591(f is amended by striking the phrases "subsections (a) through (e and "this section" and inserting the phrases "subsections (b d and (e and these subsections" respectively in their places. Section 45-2591 Sec. 24. Section 4 of the District of Columbia Consumer Credit Protection Act of 1971, approved December 17, 1971 (85 Stat. 678; D.C. Code, sec. 28-3815 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Section 28-3815 Sec. 25. Section 124 of the District of Columbia Business Corporation Act, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Code, sec. 29-399.25 is amended by striking the phrase "of this act" the 3 places it appears and inserting the phrase "of this section" in its place. Section 29-399.25 Sec. 26. The District of Columbia Cooperative Association Act, approved June 19, 1940 (54 Stat. 480; D.C. Code, sec. 29-1101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 34 (D.C. Code, sec. 29-1134) is amended by striking the second internal subsection designation d and (b) Section 37 (D.C. Code, SeCo 29-I137(b is amended 5ecti0n by striking the internal subsection designation b 29-1137 Section’ 29-1101 Sec. 27. The llth paragraph of section 1 of An Act To authorize the Commissioners of the District of Columbia to make police regulations for the government of said District, Section 1-315 12 Emroit d Original approved January 26, 1887 (24 Stat. 369; D.C. Code, sec. 1-315(9 is amended by striking the phrase of the Sec. 28. Paragraph 48 of section 7 of An Act Making 5ecti.0n appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government 45-2846 of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thritieth, nineteen hundred and three, approved July I, 1902 (32 Stat. 628; D.C. Code, sec. 47-2846 is amended in the first and second sentences by striking the phrase "of this section" and inserting the phrase "of this paragraph" in its place. Sec. 29. 1978, effective March 13, 1985 (D.C. Law 5-139; D.C. Code, sec. 5-537(c)(I is amended to read as follows c)(1) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of this act, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Section 9a(c)(1) of the Smoke Detector Act of 5ecti0n’~ 5-537 Sec. 30. Section 7(c) of the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986, effective March 21, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-216; D.C. Code, sec. 5-1306(c is amended by deleting the phrase "not to exceed $300" Section 5-1306 Sec. 31. Section 8-3:612 of the District of Columbia Solid Waste Regulations, enacted June 29, 1971 (Reg. 71-21; 21 DCMR sec. 700 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of sections 704.3 through 704.5, and 711 pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of sections 704.3 through 704.5 and 711 shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 21 DCMR 700 Sec. 32. Section 6.103 of the District of Columbia 16 Consumer Retail Credit Regulation, enacted June II, 1971 DCMR (Reg. 71-18; 16 DCMR sec. 122.1 is amended by designating 122.1 the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of this 13 Enro le regulation pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this regulation shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 33. Section 15 the Regulations Governing the 16 Business of Furnishing Towing Service for Motor Vehicles, DCMR effective August 21, 1956 (C.O. No. 56-1678; 16 DCMR secs. 409.4~ 409.4 and 409.5) is amended by designating the existing text 409.5 as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of this regulation pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this regulation shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 34. Section 7.101 of the Regulation of the Business of Transporting Household Goods, enacted February 25, 1971 (Reg. 71-5; 16 DCMR sec. 700.5 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of this regulation pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this regulation shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 16 DCMR 700.5 Sec. 35. Section 26 of the Regulations Governing the Conduct of the Home Improvement Business in the District of Columbia, effective May II, 1961 (C.O. No. 61-563 DCMR sec. 800.6 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of this regulation pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this regulation shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 16 DC.NR 800,6 14 E rotled Origm t Sec. 36. Section 9 of Article 36 of the District of Columbia Police Regulations, effective November I, 1948 (C.O. 301/904/2; 19 DCMR sec. 1400.7 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this article pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this article shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985.’ 19 DCMR 140~.7 Sec. 37. Article 31 of the Police Regulations of the 24 District of Columbia (24 DCMR sec. 523) is amended by adding DCMR a new section 7 to read as follows: 523 "7. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this article pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affaris Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this article shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 38. The District of Columbia Applications Insurance Implementation Act, effective May 26, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-64; D.C. Code, sec. 5-301 et seq is amended by inserting a new section 6A to read as follows Sec. 6A Violations of any provision of this act, including the implementing regulations, are punishable by the following penalties I) Any person who violates any provision of this act shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and shall, upon conviction, be punishable by a fine of not more than $300 for each day of the violation, or imprisoned for not more than 30 days, or both 2) Any person who violates any provision of this act shall be liable to the District of Columbia for any and all consequential damages resulting from the violation, in addition to related costs and attorney fees 3) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department Section 5-306 15 of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Sec. 39. Section 8-4:911 of the District of Columbia Health Regulations, effective November 6, 1967 (C.O. 67-1196; 22 DCMR subsection 700.12 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions of this part pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infraction Act of 1985. Adudication of any infraction of this part shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 22 DCMR 700.12 Sec. 40. Section 28 of A Regulation Governing Vending Businesses in Public Space, enacted December 13, 1974 (Reg. 74-39; 24 DCMR subsection 501.9 is amended by designating the existing text as subsection (a) and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions of this act, or any rules and regulations issued unde the authority of this act, pusuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this act shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 24 DCMR 501.9! Sec. 41. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia 16 Enrolled Original Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. L_ Chairman ouncil of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: Decembe~ 27, 1990 17 @ Item on Consent Catendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE D~STRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: B8-203 Adopted First Reading, 12-04-90 Approved ¯ Recorded vote on request all present Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V, A.B, CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER NATHANSON SMITH, JR. A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. NV Present. not voting COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V ’* CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the ~ouncil Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, Date 12-18-90 Approved VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request WilsonAbsent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV, A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. A,B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting i CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the, L~ncil Item on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER J~’ i AYE NAY NV. Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVtS- KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH. JR AB Absent AYE NAY N.V. AB. NV Present, not votin9 CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
