<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-37" flag="true">
  <num type="law">8-37</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977 Amendment Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-10-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-37.pdf">D.C. Law 8-37</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 5748</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0216">
      <narrative>Law 8-37, the “District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977 Amendment Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-216, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 27, 1989 and July 11, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 27, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-66 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag 103 201 118 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE; D.C. LAW 8-37 "District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977 Amendment Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-216 on first and second readings, June 27, 1989, and july ii, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 27, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-66, published in the August ii, 1989, edition of the D.C. Re~ister Vol. 36 page 5748) and transmitted to Congress on August 4, 1989 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-37, effective October 18, 1989 v~,y Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30 d~ssional Review Period: August 4 September 6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,2~,25,26,27,28,29 October 2,3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,16,17 E~rolled Or~g~ua~ OCT I 8 1989 AN ACT Codification, District of Columbia Code (1990 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUL 1989 To amend the District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977 to strengthen the District of Columbia government’s hazardous waste program and make District law consistent with the most recent federal amendments that govern the regulation of hazardous waste. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977 Amendment Act of 1989 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977, effective March 16, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-64; D.C. Code, sec. 6-701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(a)(2 D.C. Code, sec. 6-701(a)(2 is amended to read as follows 2) To establish a program of regulation over the generation, storage, transportation, treatment, and disposal of hazardous waste and fuel containing hazardous waste and the production, marketing, distribution, and burning of fuel produced from or containing hazardous wasteibi Section 3 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-702) is amended by adding the following new paragraphs l-a) The term "guarantor" means any person, other than the owner or operator, who provides evidence of financial responsibility for an owner or operator 5-a) The term "person responsible" means a person who is or has been the generator of hazardous waste, the owner or operator of a site that contains or a vehicle that transports hazardous waste, or a person who by contract, agreement, or otherwise arranges or has arranged for disposal or treatment of hazardous waste c) Section 4 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-703) is amended to read as follows a) It is unlawful to own, construct, substantially alter, or operate any hazardous waste treatment, storage, or Sect ion 6-701 Section 6-702 Section 6-703 ¯ nrolled Original disposal facility or site or to generate, store, transport, treat, or dispose of any hazardous waste except in accordance with the terms of the permit issued by the Mayor for the facility, site, or activity b) The Mayor may issue, vary, or modify the terms of a permit or suspend, revoke, or deny a.permit to achieve the purposes of this act, except that the Mayor may not issue a permit for a period that exceeds 10 years. The terms of any permit for a treatment, storage, or disposal facility shall require that the permit holder take corrective action within or beyond the facility boundary if necessary to protect human health and the environment. The Mayor may establish the appropriate permit fee according to costs associated with its issuance d) Section 6 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-705) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a)(1)(H) is amended to read as follows H) Marketing, distribution, and burning of fuel produced from a hazardous waste or containing a hazardous waste 2) A new subsection (a)(1)(1) is added to read as follows 1) Requirements for on-site and off-site corrective action by owners or operators of a disposal, storage, and treatment facility and (3) A new subsection (b) is added to read as fol lows b) The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved e) Section 8 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-707) is amende~ to read as follows c) When there is a threat to human health or the environment, or a release of hazardous waste into the environment, and the responsible party or address is unknown, or cannot be located, written notice shall be served by conspicuously posting the notice on the property where the threat exists or the release occurred and sending a copy to the last known address via certified mail d) When dangerous chemicals and hazardous waste on property pose an imminent threat to human health or the environment, the Mayor may post the property and restrict access. The posting shall provide the public with notice that a dangerous condition exists and shall prohibit the owner from removing or handling the waste without prior approval by the Mayor Section 6-705 Section 6-707 0 0 I E:~olled Original would have been available to the owner or operator of the hazardous waste storage, treatment, or disposal facility if an action had been brought against the owner or operator by the claimant and that would have been available to the guarantor if an action had been brought against the guarantor by the owner or operator c) The total liability of any guarantor shall be limited to the aggregate amount that the guarantor has provided as evidence of financial responsibility to the owner or operator Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(i and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia MunicipalRegulations Chairman Council of the District of Columbia M APPROVED: July 27, 1989 4 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bi’ll 8-216 Adopted First Reading, 6-27-89 Approved present Recorded vote on request Absent: a i 1 [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS RAY KANE LIGHTFOOT COUNCILMEMBER MASON NATHANSON ROLARK SMITH, JR AYE NAY N.V. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER AYE THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER X Indicates Vote ~A.B Absent N.V not voting C~RTIFICATION RECORD Present’ Secretary to the Counci~ Date Iter Consent Calendar A~op~e~ £ ee~q 89 A~ove~ NAY ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY N.V. A.B.COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT all present COUNCIL MEMBER AYE MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY X Indicates Vote A Absent NV Present, not voting T, ICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: D ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT, COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. CHMN CLARKE CRAWFORD JA~’~/IS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIT, H, JR. A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V.A.B. N.V PresenL not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD [ 3 COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR WILSON WINTER AYE NAY Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
