<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-44">
  <num type="law">8-44</num>
  <heading type="short">ARMORY BOARD PROMOTIONAL EXPENSES AMENDMENT ACT OF 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1989-10-19</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-44.pdf">D.C. Law 8-44</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 5777</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0206"/>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 201 077 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-44 "Armory Board Promotional Expenses Amendment Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-206 on first and second readings, June 27, 1989, and july 11, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on August 1, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-77, published in the August 11, 1989, edition of the _D C. R.~ister Vol. 36 page 5777) and transmitted to Congress on August 8, 1989 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8rr/44, effective II/~VID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council DaN_tes Coun_~te~d D~urin~ the 30T~da__z_Co_~essional Review Period: September 6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22,25,26,27,28,29 October 2,3,4,5,6,10,11,12,13,16,17,18 Codification) District of Columbia Code (11990 Supplement) Oz’tgln AN ACT D.C. ACT 8 77 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act to establish a District of Columbia Armory Board to increase the amount available for promotional expenses. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Armory Board Promotional Expenses Amendment Act of 1989 Sec. 2. Section 8 of Chapter 418 of An Act to establish a District of Columbia Armory Board, and for other purposes, approved June 4, 1948 62 Stat. 341; D.C. Code, sec. 2-307 is amended by striking the number 20,000" and inserting the phrase 50,000, which may be adjusted annually by the Mayor, by rule, to reflect annual changes in the cost of living in its place. Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; DoC. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Section 2-307 Enrolled Orlglnal Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESI, COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.8, CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT Adopted First Reading, 6-27-89 Bill 8-206 Approved all present COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote A.B A~sent N.V E TION RECORD Present, not votin9 Secretary to the Council Date [~ltem on Consent Calendar [~ACTION&amp;amp;DATE: Adopted Final Reading, 7-11-89 [~VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request all present Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B, COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote A.B bsent NV Present, not voting Secretary to the Coun(~iLY "Date Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT.H, JR. X Indicates Vote AB Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
