<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-5">
  <num type="law">8-5</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Business Corporation Act Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-06-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-5.pdf">D.C. Law 8-5</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 2654</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0145">
      <narrative>Law 8-5, the “District of Columbia Business Corporation Act Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-145, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 14, 1989 and April 4, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 12, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-17 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag 103 201 542 0 ¯ i).c. 8 NUN o 1989 AN ACT D C. ACT 8 1 ’Z Enrolled Origin81 Codification, District of Columbia Code 1989 Supp IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APR l 1989 To amend the District of Columbia Business Corporation Act to provide a uniform annual report fee requirement for foreign and domestic corporations. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Business Corporation Act Amendment Act of 1989 Sec. 2. Section 121 of the District of Columbia Business Corporation Act, approved June 8, 1954 (68 Stat. 228; D.C. Code, sec. 29-399.22 is amended as follows a) By amending subsections (d) and (e) to read as follows d) Each foreign or domestic corporation authorized to do business in the District of Columbia or organized, incorporated, or reincorporated under the provisions of this act shall pay an annual report fee of $I00.00, which shall be paid at the time that the annual report, which is required of corporations under the provisions of this chapter, is filed. The provisions of this subsection shall apply to each annual report fee due and payable on April 15, 1989, and each following April 15th e) If the annual report fee of a domestic corporation is unpaid at the time that it is due, interest shall accrue on the annual report fee at the rate of 5% per month until the report fee is paid b) By striking subsections ifi and (g Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Section 29-399.22 Enrolled Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chai rman Council of the District of Columbia ~ayor District APPROVED: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: 8-145 Adopted First Readinq, 3-14.89 [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent El ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT CQUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE X CRAWFORD X JARVIS X KANE X LIGHTFOOT X X Indicates Vote Approved COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B MASON X NATHANSON X RAY X ROLARK X SMITH, JR A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR, WILSON WINTER "7 i/ 0 AYE NAY ’r~ICATIONRECORD Sec retary to thet ’-’~’~’~Cou nell ~’ ’~ [~ Item on Consent Calendar £ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Jarvis and Kane Date Adopted Final Reading, 4-4-89 Fn ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. AB. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B N.V Present, not voting CERTIFIC~TION RECORD Secr~tary to the"’~Co Item on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR WILSON WINTER ’ ’ AYE NAY N.V. Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALLVOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIIH, JR X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR WILSON WINTER AYE NAY NV. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
