<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-57">
  <num type="law">8-57</num>
  <heading type="short">Good Time Credits Amendment Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-01-30</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-57.pdf">D.C. Law 8-57</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 5761</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0303">
      <narrative>Law 8-57, the “Good Time Credits Amendment Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-303, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 27, 1989 and July 11, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 27, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-71 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag 103 202 604 0 Z 0 O~ oCO c- O JAN o 199o AN~ACT D.C. Enrolled Orlglnei], Codification, District of Columbia Code (1990 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA ju~ri To amend the District of Columbia Good Time Credits Act of 1986 to make clear that good time credits are not applicable to the minimum sentence of persons convicted of murder in the first degree. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Good Time Credits Amendment Act of 1989 Sec. 2. Section 8 of the District of Columbia Good Time Credits Act of 1986, effective April 11, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-218; D.C. Code, sec. 24-434 is amended to read as fol l ows Sec. 8. Exceptions Institutional and educational good time credits shall not be applied to the minimum terms of persons sentenced under the District of Columbia Mandatory-Minimum Sentences Initiative of 1981, effective March 9, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-166; D.C. Code, secs. 22-3202, 33-501 and 33-541 section 801 of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31Stat. 1321; D.C. Code, sec. 22-2404(b or section 4(b) of An Act to control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Stat. 650; D.C. Code, sec. 22-3204(b Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 60-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Section 24-434 ~nrolled Or$~na~ Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: July 27, 1989 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 6-27-89 [] VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. Bill 8-303 AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY I’HOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER N.Vl X Indicates Vote A 7 Absent N.V Present, not votin9 ClOT/CATION RECORD Secreta~ to the Council~ Date Item on Consent Calendar ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, 7-11-89 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Thomas [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOQT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER MASON THOMAS, SR. NATHANSON WILSON RAY WINTER ROLARK SMITH, JR. AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote A.B nt N.V Present, not voting L/ Secreta~ to the Council Date [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT, H, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER A.B. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
