<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-59" flag="true">
  <num type="law">8-59</num>
  <heading type="short">DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA TAXICAB COMMISSION AJUDICATORY AUTHORITY TEMPORARY AMENDMENT ACT OF 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1990-01-30</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-59.pdf">D.C. Law 8-59</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 7384</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0351">
      <narrative>Law 8-59 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-351. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 11, 1989 and September 26, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 13, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-89 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 204 399 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-59 "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Adjudicatory Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-351 on first and second readings, July 11, 1989, and September 26, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 13, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-89, published in the October 27, 1989, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 36 page 7384) and transmitted to Congress on October 18, 1989 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-59, effective January 30, 1990. L Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: October November January 18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30,31 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,13,14,15,16,17,20,21,22 23,24,25,26,29 l).C. LAW 8-59 ,JAN 0 AN ACT D.C. ACT &amp;amp 8 9 Codification, District of Columbia Code (1990 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA ,OCT1 1989 To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985 to authorize hearing examiners to adjudicate notices of civil infractions issued to taxicab operators and owners, and to clarify the procedures for administrative appeal. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Adjudicatory Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 1989" Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Code, sec. 40-1701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 8(b D.C. Code, sec. 40-1707(b is amended as follows I) Paragraph (2)(H) is repealed 2) A new paragraph (3) is added to read as follows 3) The Commission’s Panel on Adjudication shall have the jurisdiction, power, and discretion to consider appeals taken from any act, decision, or order of a 3-member component of the panel exercising adjudicatory functions, as determined by a majority of the panel b) Section 10(e D.C. Code, sec. 40-1709(e is amended by striking the phrase "8(b)(2)(H and inserting the phrase "8(b)(3 in its place c) A new section lOa is added to read as follows Sec. 10a (a) The Panel on Adjudication shall appoint at least 1 attorney to serve as a hearing examiner to adjudicate notices of civil infractions issued to taxicab operators and owners pursuant to section 825 of Title 15 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations DCMR b) A hearing examiner may: Note, 1-229 Note, 40-1707 Note, 40-1709 l~ote, new 40-1709.1 i) Preside over hearings in contested matters 2) CoMpel the attendance of witnesses by subpoena, administer oaths, take testimony of witnesses under oath, and dismiss, rehear, and continue cases 3) Conduct hearings in accordance with rules promulgated pursuant to section II; and 4) Issue proposed decisions including the imposition of fines for civil infractions set forth in section 825 of Title 15 of the DCMR c) Any party adversely affected by a proposed decision of a hearing examiner may appeal the decision to a 3-member component of the Panel on Adjudication in accordance with rules promulgated pursuant to section II d) Section 13(h)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "Bureau of Traffic Adjudication" and inserting the phrase "Panel on Adjudication" in its place. Sec. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Gover,~ental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Note, 40-1712 Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 13, 19 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Cotmcfl Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: [] Item on Consent Calendar 1~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Bill 8-351 Adopted First Reading, 7-11-89 Approved Crawford [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD’ NATHANSON JARVI~"’ RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting C~RECORD Secretary to the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, WILSON WINTER Date 9-26-89 ApprovedVOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER ] AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JAFIVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council I Item on Consent Calendar AYE I~AY N.V. A.B. r N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER I AYE THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER NAY N.V. Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON C’~AWFORD NATHANSOi~ JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY NV. A.B. N.’V Present, not voting’ CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER A.B, Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
