<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-84">
  <num type="law">8-84</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985 Amendment Temporary Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1990-03-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-84.pdf">D.C. Law 8-84</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 44</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 8-84, the “District of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985 Amendment Temporary Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-473. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 21, 1989, and December 5, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-134 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 203 291 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-84 "District of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985 Amendment Temporary Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-473 on first and second readings, November 21, 1989, and December 5, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 21, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-134, published in the January 5, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 44) and transmitted to Congress on January 23, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-84, effective March 15, 1990 x Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January February March 23,24,25,26,29,30,31 1,2,5,6,7,8,20,21,22,23,26,27,28 1,2,5,6,7,8,9,12,13,14 MAR, 15 1990 AN ACT Earolled Original Codification, District of Columbia Code (1990 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC_ 9 To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985 to allow a regional or nonregional bank holding company that seeks to acquire a District of Columbia bank or bank holding company to file a final application with the Federal Reserve Board at any time after filing a copy of the complete draft of the application with the Superintendent of Banking. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985 Amendment Temporary Act of 1989 Sec. 2. Section 5(c)(1)(A) of the District of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985, effective November 23, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-63; D.C. Code, sec. 26-804(c)(I)(A is amended as follows a) By adding the phrase or a nonregional bank holding company that seeks to acquire a District bank holding company or a District bank pursuant to section 7a of this act after the phrase "or a District bank b) By striking the phrase "no later than 130 days prior to filing an application with the Federal Reserve Board and (c) By striking the phrase "issuance of a final recommendation by the Superintendent" and inserting the phrase "filing the draft application with the Superintendent" in its place. Note, 1-229 Sec. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, Section 26-804&amp;lt i A) [] Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: B ± 11 Adopted First Reading, 11-21-89 8-473 Approved Thomas E3 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT j COUNCiL. MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER ~YE NA~’ N.V.A.B OUI~CIL’~EM~}ER CHMN CLARKE MASON THOMAS, SR CRAWFORD NATHANSON WILS~)’N JARVIS RAY WINTER KANE ROLARK L1GHTFOQT SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.8 bsent N.V Present, not votin9 ecr’etary to the Council Oate Item on Consent Calendar ACTION&amp;amp;DATE: Adopted Final Reading, 12-5-89 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request AYE NAY N.V. A.B, Absent Thomas ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NIV. A.B. OUNCIL MEMBER AYE "NA~’ I~i A.B. OUnCIL MEMBER CHMN’. CLARKE MAS6 THOMAS, SR. CRAWFORD N~kTHANSON WILSON JARVIS RAY WINTER KANE ROLARK ’ iGHTFOOT ’ SMITH, JR AYE NAY N.v X indicates vGe AB Absent N.V Present, not voting Secieta~ iO th~unc,l Date u Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: G VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. AB. CouNcIL MEMBER AYE"NA;f NV. A.B. CI’~MN’, CLARKE SON CRAWFOI~’ NATHANS’ON ’ j Rv,s R’:,Y KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIT.H, JR ’:,’ X In~;cati;s v;ie A.B- Al~ser N.V Present’, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER N.V, A.B. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
