<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-85">
  <num type="law">8-85</num>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-85.pdf">D.C. Law 8-85</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 8-85 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-469. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 14, 1989, and December 5, 1989, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 8-135 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 103 203 274 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 8-85 "Interference With Medical Health Care Facilities Temporary Act of 1989 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 8-469 on first and second readings, November 14, 1989, and December 5, 1989, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 21, 1989, this legislation was assigned Act No. 8-135, published in the January 5, 1990, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 37 page 46) and transmitted to Congress on January 23, 1990 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 8-85, effective March 15, 1990 ha i rma o t C Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January February March 23,24,25,26,29,30,31 1,2,5,6,7,8,20,21,22,23,26,27,28 1,2,5,6,7,8,9,12,13,14 AN ACT Enrolled Original Codification District of Columbia Code (1990 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DEC 1989 To prohibit, on ] temporary basis, any person from patrolling or picketing witllin I00 feet of a health care facility in the District of Columbia to intimidate, harass, or disrupt the staff or patients of the health care facility, or interfere with the free and safe ingress or egress of a health care facility. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Interference With Medical Health Care Facilities Temporary Act of 1989 Sec. 2 a) It shall be unlawful for any person to patrol or picket within I00 feet of a health care facility in the District. of Columbia to intimidate, harass, or disrupt the staff or patients of the hea.lth care facility b) It shall be unlawful for any person to interfere with the free and safe ingress or egress of a [health care fac~.lity in the District of Columbia c) Any person, who violates subsection (a) or subsection (b) of this sectioD upon conviction, shall be fined not more than $I.~000, imprisoned for not. more than 1 year, or both. Sec. 3 a) This act sha].l take effect after a 30--day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the ew{~nt of vetc by the Mayor, action by the Council of the Dist.rict of Columbia to .override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government a.nd Government.a] Reorganization Act, approved December 24 1973 (87 Star. 81.-3; D.C. Code, sec. ].-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the ’i.’ ti’ic’{; Of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or’ tlhe Dist ict of Columbia Municipal Regulations. 1-229 (b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect. Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 21, 1989 2 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill 8-469 Adopted First Reading, 11-14-89 Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Ray ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER X indicates Vote A.B Absent NV not voting Y Secretary to the Co C’~ Date Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Adopted F±nal Read±ng, 12-5-89 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Thomas ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A8. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote hB Absent N.V Present, not voting Secretary to the Council Date Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: @ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER MASON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMIIH, JR A.B Absent AYE NAY N,V. A.8. N,V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON i W~NTER AYE NAY N.V. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
