<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 8-91">
  <num type="law">8-91</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985 Amendment Act of 1989</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1990-03-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/8-91.pdf">D.C. Law 8-91</citation>
      <citation type="register">37 DCR 776</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B8-0456">
      <narrative>Law 8-91, the “District of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985 Amendment Act of 1989,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-456, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 19, 1989, and January 20, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 11, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-142 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENR9 LLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 204 304 5 0 0 0 O 0P 3 0 0 0 O.C. LAW 8 MAR 15 1990 AN ACT Enrolled Originat Codification District of Columbia Code (1990 Supplement) D.C. ACT 8 149 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA ,JAN 1 1 1990 To amend the District of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985 to allow a regional or nonregional bank holding company that seeks to acquire a District of Columbia bank or bank holding company to file a final application with the Federal Reserve Board at any time after filing a copy of the complete draft of the application with the Superin%endent of Banking. BE IT E}~ACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Di~strict of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985 Amendment Act of 1989 Sec. 2. Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985, effective November 23, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-63; D.C. Code, sec. 26-804(c)(i)(A is amended as follows a) By adding the phrase or a nonregional bank holding company that seeks to acquire a District bank holding company or a District bank pursuant to section 7a of this act after the phrase "or a District bank b) By striking the phrase "no later than 130 days prior to filing an application with the Federal Reserve Board and (c) By striking the phrase "issuance of a final recommendation by the Superintendent" and inserting the phrase "filing the draft application with the Superintendent" in its place. Section 5(c)(1)(A) of the District of Columbia 5ecti0n 26-804 Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(i) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1 Enrolled Original 1-233(c i and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Columbia APPROVED: January 11, 1990 [] Item on Consent Calendar r~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [~ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Eight RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 12-19-89 Bill 8-456 Approved Ray ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE LIGHTFOOT AYE NAY N.V.A.B. couNcIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. MAgON NATHANSON RAY ROLARK SMITH, JR X Indicates Vote A.B Absent NV Present, not voting ITIFICATION RECORD Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading J AYE NAY N.V.COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER Date 1-2-90 ApprovedVOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORD NATHANSON JARVIS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT’ SMITH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent [] Item on Consent Calendar AYE NAY N.V. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER AYE THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER N.V Present, not voting Date NAY N.V. [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICEVOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE MASON CRAWFORO NATHANSON JARVlS RAY KANE ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMIIH, JR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V PresenL not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER THOMAS, SR. WILSON WINTER AYE NAY N.V. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
