<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 4-138" flag="true">
  <num type="law">4-138</num>
  <heading type="short">Statehood Convention Procedural Amendments Act of 1982</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1982-08-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/4-138.pdf">D.C. Law 4-138</citation>
      <citation type="register">29 DCR 2761</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 4-138, the “Statehood Convention Procedural Amendments Act of 1982,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-450, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 25, 1982 and June 8, 1982, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 21, 1982, it was assigned Act No. 4-204 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>D.C. LAW 4 138 EFFECTIVE A U G 14 1982 AN ACT D.C. ACT 4 2 D 4 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUN 2 1 1982 To amend and clarify the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979, and for other purposes. Enrolled Original .las the BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Statehood Convention Procedural Amendments Act of 1982 Sec. 2. Section 4 of the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979, \ ffective March 10, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-171; D.C. Code, sec. 1-113) is amended as follows: Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows b) Upon the completion of the drafting of the constitution, the District of Coldmbia :Board of Elections and Ethics shall submit the proposed constitution to the registered qualified electors for their adoption or rejection at the general election to be held by the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics in November, 1982. If the constitution is adopted by a majority of the electors voting thereon, the constitution shall be submitted to the Con gress of the United States by the Mayor of the District of Columbia Subsection (c) is amended by striking the con the for new be gem Dis• the maj( thai CODIFICATICE D.C.Code, ele( sec. 1-113 (1981 ed Nov( aut] Sep the wit Con sha for of of Co( Rel 1 Co: pua imi Elo Co: Inl D elo Co. e1 St4 30 Fe Fe Enrolled Origin ten (10) days after his or her certification by the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics and shall expire on January 3, 1985. The terms of the first Senators elected pursuant to this act shall begin ten (10) days after their certification by the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics and shall expire on January 3, 1985, and January 3, 1989, respectively. At the initial election, the candidate for Senator receiving the highest number of votes will receive the longer term and the candidate receiving the second highest number of votes will receive the shorter term. A primary and a general election to replace a Representative or a Senator whose term is about to expire shall be held in September and in November respectively, of the year preceding the year during which the term of the Representative or the Senator expires. Each Representative shall be elected for a two (2)-year term and each Senator shall be elected for a six (6)-year term as of the United States 3) The District prescribed by the Constitution of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics shall (A) conduct elections to fill the positions of two (2) United States Senators and one (1) United States Representative, and (B) issue such rules and expressly delegate authority to officials and employees of the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics (such delegation of authority only to be effective upon publication in the District of 3 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 41. Chairman Council of District •f Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: June 2 1 1982 5</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-135"/>
  </section>
</document>
