<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 4-147">
  <num type="law">4-147</num>
  <heading type="short">Unemployment Trust Fund Revenue and Conformity Act of 1982</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1982-09-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/4-147.pdf">D.C. Law 4-147</citation>
      <citation type="register">29 DCR 3347</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 4-147, the “Unemployment Trust Fund Revenue and Conformity Act of 1982,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-431, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Economic Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 6, 1982, and July 20, 1982, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 21, 1982, it was assigned Act No. 4-218 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>overnment and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198, t 20 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 4-431 on first and second readings, July 6, 1982 and July n July 21, 1982, this legislation was assigned Act No. 4-218 1982, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 4-147 "Unemployment Trust Fund Revenue and Conformity Act of 1982 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- published in the August 6, 1982, edition of the D.C. ell21217 Vol. 29 page 3347) and transmitted to Congress on July 21, 1982 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(1) the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 4-147 effective September 17, 1982. ARRINGTOL DIXON Chairman of the Council Dates Counted Dun the 30-day Cong ressional Review r-io July 21,22,23,26,27 28,29,30 August j 2,3,4,5,6,9,10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20 September 3,9,10,13.14,15,16 of notice Enrolled Original AN ACT LAW 1 4. 7 SEP 17 1982 D.C. ACT -a 18 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUL 2 1 1282 amend the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act to increase revenue for the unemployment trust fund; to encourage prompt payment of contributions by employers; to charge the disqualification period for voluntarily quitting work without gocd cause connected with the work; to conform to the requirements of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1 98 1; and for other purposes. BE IT EXACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF CIDISIA, That this act may be cited as the 'Unemployment Trust Fund Revenue and Conformity Act of 3i2 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act, approved August 2 8, 193 5 (49 Stat. MO D.0 Code, sec. 4b-101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(c)(1 D.0 Code, sec. 46-103(c 1 is amended by striking the period at the rd of the first sentence and inserting the phrase PROVIDED, That contributions received after Jul y 1, 1981, by reason of the solvency tazz set forth in subparagraph (3 ii) of section 3 c 4) shall rot be credited to the separate account cf each emcloyer in lieu thereof. CCDIFMMTICN sec. 46-102 (1981 ed 2a:rolled Section 3(c)(2)(A D.C. Code, sec. 48-103(c)(2)(A is amended by striking the phrase "te a claimant at the time of such pa yment" in the last sentence thereof. By striking section 3(c)(8)(C D.C. Cede, sac. 46-103(c)(3)(C Section 3(e D.C. Cede, sec. 46-103(e is amended by strikinc the fourth sentence "After December 31, 1977, wages shall not include any amount in excess of $6,000 (cr in excess of the limi ta ion on the amount of taxable wages fixed by the Federal Unemployment Tax Act (26 U.S.C. secs. 3301 through 3311 whichever is greater) actually paid by an employer to any person during any calendar year and inserting the sentences 4 7 :cm January 1, 1978, through December 31, 1981, taxable wages shall not include any amount in excess cf 46,000. For the purpose of determining employer contributions after January 1, 1982, the term 'wages' shall not include any amount in excess of 57500 (or in excess of the limitation cn the amount of taxable wages fixed by the Federal Unemplcymert Tax Act, approved August 29, 1935 (49 Stat. 6397 26 U.S.C. sec. 3206 whichever is greater) actually paid by an employer to any person during any calendar year in lieu thereof. Section 4(c D.C. Cede, sec. 46-105 (c is amended as -2c11-ws 1) paragraph (1) is amended by striking the zh.rase "ene-half of and D.0 Code, sac. 46-103 (1981 ed 0.C.Cede, sec. 46-103 (1981 ed 0.C.C.cds, sec. 46-103 (1281 ed C moo, sec. 46-10 1381 ed 2 Enrolled Original (2) paragraph (2) is amended by striking the ase "not be less than $5 nor more than $25" and iserti ng the phrase "not be less than $100" in lieu 1:ereof f) Sectio n 7(b D.0 Code, sec. 46-108(b is ceded to read as follows b) An individual's 'weekly benefit amount' shall x an amount equal to one twenty-third (computed to the !ext higher multiple of $1) of his total wages for gured work paid during that quarter of his base eriod in which such total wages were highest: AVIDED, That effective January 1, 1982, the maximum weekly benefit shall be $206. The Mayor shall determine annually the average weekly wage paid to employees in insured work and before September 15th of each year shall recommend a maximum weekly benefit 'mount to the Council. The Mayor's recommendation of a IN maxi= weekly benefit amount shall become effective for the next January 1st unless the Council adopts a resolution disapproving the Mayor's recommendation within 45 calendar days from the date that the Mayor's recommendation is transmitted to the Chairman of the Council. In making his reccmmendaticn, the Mayor shall consider the amount which is 66-2/3 per cent of the average weekly wage; the total amount of benefits paid during the 12-month period ending June 30th of the preceding year; and the total amount of contributions l and interest paid into the fund during the same period D.C.Code, sec. 46-108 (1981 ed 3 r:T.:lied Or' The computation of the average weekly wage paid to empleyees in insured work shall be made by determining total wages reported as paid for insured work by employers in each 12-month period ending June 30th and dividing the total wages by a figure which results frcm 52 times the average of mid-month employmert retorted by employers for the same pericd. The Director, before January 1st of the calendar yea: in which it shall be effective, shall announce by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in the District of Columbia, the new maximum weekly benefit amount. The maximum weekly benefit amcunt determined and announced for a calendar year shall ap ply only to those claims filed in that year. All claims qualifying for payMent at the maximum weekly benefit a^ cur shall. be paid at the maximum weekly benefit in effect when the benefit year to which the claim relaees was first established, notw 4 thstarding a change in the maximum weekly amount for a subsequent calendar year. If the maximum weekly benefit amount is nOr. a multiple of then the maximum weekly benefit amount shall be ccmouted to the next higher multiple of ;1 g) Sec'nicr 7(g 0.0 Cede, sec. 46-10S is amended as fellows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended to read as fellows 1) As used in th..s sia'tsec lcr, unless the context clearly requires ceherwl'se C tia 53C. 46.4 (1381 aLl 4 Earolled Origimal A Extended benefit period' means a od which: Begins with the 3rd week r a week in which a State 'on' indicator occurs; Ends with either of the owing weeks, whichever occurs later: The 3rd week after the week for which there is a State 'off' indicator; or The 13th consecutive of such period: MM, That no extended benefit period ma y begin by on of a State 'on' indicator before the 14th week towing the end of a prior extended benefit period 'cllas in effect with respect to the District B) For weeks commencing after teeter 25, 1982, there is a State 'on' indicator for eDistrict for a week if the rate of insured employment under this Act for the period consisting such week and the 'immediately preceeding 12 weeks: Equaled or exceeded 120 per tun of the average of such rates for the expending 13-week period ending in each of the Keeding 2 calendar years; and Ecualed or exceeded 5 cent: PROVIDED, That with respect to benefits for eks of unemployment beginning on September 26, 1982, the daterminat on of whether there is a State 'or' or 5 yo ailed Or ya tat civi Chap este (inc epic Unit( provJ in hi indiv s b perio ixten p•rio 'who, eligi hi pens Ti off' indicator beginning or ending any extended benefit period shall be made under this subsection as This subparagraph did not contain sub-subparagraph (i) thereof, and The figure '5' contained in sub-subparagraph (ii) thereof was '6 TN,a notwithstanding any such provision of this subsection any week for which there would otherwise be a State 'on' indicator shall continue to be such a week and shall not be determined to be a week for which there is a State 'off' indicator C) There is a State 'off' indicator for the District for a week 12, for the period consisting of that w ek and the immediately preceding 1 1 weeks, either sub-subparagraph (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (3) of this paragraph satisfied D Rate of insured unemployment purposes of subparagraphs (3) and (C) of this paragraph, means the percentage derived by dividing (i) the averace weekl y number of individuals filing claims for regular benefits in the District f v6 weeks cf unempLoymerl wi respect to the most recent 13-consecutive week period as determined on the basis of reports to the Secretary of Labor, by (i L) the average mcnthly emoloyment covered under this Act the first 4 of the rest recent 6 completed calendar quarters ending before the end of such 1.3-week period. 6 Enrolled Original 'Regular benefits' means benefits le to an individual under this Act or under any to law (including benefits payable to Federal 1ian employees and to ex-servicemen pursuant to pter 85 of Title 5, United States Code) other than ended benefits Extended benefits' means benefits eluding benefits payable to Federal civilian loyees and to ex-servicemen pursuant to Chapter 85, iced States Code) payable to an individual under the isions of this subsection for weeks of unemployment his eligibility period Eligibility period' of an 'vidual means the period consisting of the weeks in s benefit year which begin in an extended benefit period and, if his benefit year ends within the extended period, any weeks thereafter which begin in a pl,:i0d Exhaustee' means an individual to, with respect to any week of unemployment in his eligibility period i) Has received, prior to such a week, all of the regular benefits that were available to him =ler this Act or any State law (including dependents' allowances and benefits payable to Federal civilian employees and ex-servicemen under Chacter 85 of Title 5, United States Code) in his current benefit year that includes such a week: PRCVILED, That for the 7 .11 n•n Ezro ro bed Or4 purposes of this subparagraph, art individual shall be deemed to have received all of the regular benefits sub that were available to him although as a result of a pending appeal with respect to wages that were not pros considered in the original monetary determination in be E his benefits year, he may subsequently be determined to elig be entitled to added regular benefits; cr tota Li) His benefit year having guar extired prior to such a week, has no, cr insufficient and wages on the basis of which he established a new benefit year that would include such a week; and follc iii)(I) Has no right to unemployment benefits or allowances, as the case may provi be, under the Railroad Unemployment I n suran ce Act, the Any i; Trade Ea-pans-ion Act of 1962, the Automotive Products rl Trade Ac- of 1965, and such other Federal laws as are specified in resulationd issued by the Secretary of (wail Labor; arc. 0 we II) gas not received and is nefj not seeking unemployment benefits under the pz unemployment c=moensation Law of Canada; but if he is divi seeking such benefits and the appropriate agency thin fna lT v determines that he is not entitld to 'terefits ndivi under such law he is considered an exhaustee. nefi 2 State law' means the unemoloyment insurance Law cf any State, approved by the Secretary nde of Labor under Sec. 22C4 of the :n areal Rever e Cede of 1954 81 Enrolled Original(2 Paragraph (3) is amended by adding new obparagraph (C) to read as follows C) Notwithstandin g any other =visions of this paragraph, an individual shall not :e eligible for extended benefits if his monetary eligibility for regular benefits was based upon the total base period wages that did not exceed his highest. prterly wages by at least one and one-half times aid (3) Paragraph (5) is amended by adding the following new subparagraph (C) to read as follows C) Notwithstanding any other covisions of this paragraph, if the benefit year of 17 individual ends within an extended benefit period the remaining balance of extended benefits that such an individual would, but for this section, be entitled to receive in that extended benefit period, with respect to weeks of unemployment beginning after the end of the benefit year, shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the product of the number of weeks for which the individual received trade readjustment allowances within that benefit year, multiplied by the individual's weekly benefit amount for extended benefits h) Sectic• 10(a D.C. Code, sec. 46-111(a is mended to read as follows a) For weeks commencing after Decembe r 13, 1981, any individual who left his most recent work D.C.Code, sec. 46-111 (1981 9 voluntarily without gccd cause connected with the work, as determined under duly prescribed regulations, shall not be eligible for benefits until he has been employed in each of four subsequent weeks (whether or net consecutive) and has earned remuneration equal to rot less than four times the weekly benefit amount to Which he would be entitled pursuant to section 7(b i) Section 10(i D .0 Code, sec. 4',5-111(i is amended to read as follows: 4 (i)(1) Not•vithstanding any other provision of this Act, no otherwise eligible individual sha ll be denied benefits or any week because A) he or she is in training enaroved under Section 226(a)(1) of the Trade Act of 1974 3) he or she is in such approved training by reason of leaving work to enter such training: PROVIDED, That the work left is rot suitable employment; or (C) because of the application to any such week in training of provisions in this law (or any ?ederal unemaloyment insurance law administered hereunder) relating to availability for work, active search tar work or refusal to acce pt work 2) For purposes of this subsection, the ter: amplaymenm. means, with respect an individual, work of a substantially equal or higher skill level than the individual's as adversely attected enaloyment (as defined for purpases of the Trade Acm of 1974 and wages as determined for purpcses of the Trade Aar. of 1974 10 Enrolled Original Section 13(c D.0 Code, sec. 46-114(c is nded by striking the words "Board" and "Congress" ^d inserting the words "Mayor" and "Council" in lieu ereof respectively. Section 18(b D.C. Code, sec. 46-119(b is ended as follows: By inserting the phrase "Except as reinafter provided" at the beginning thereof; By redesignating the current subsection paragraph 1 11 7 and (3) By adding new paragraphs (2) through (9 4 read as follows 2 An individual filing a new claim for cnemployment commensation shall disclose, at the time cf filing such a claim, whether the individual owes child support obligations as defined under paragraph 8) of this subsection. if any individual discloses that he or she owes child support obligations and is determined to be eligible for unemployment compensation, the Director shall notify the appropriate State or local child support enforcement agency that the individual has been determined to be eligible for dnemployment c=pensation 3) The Director shall deduct and withhold any unemployment compensation payable to an individual that owes child supcort obligations as defined under paragramh (8) cf this subsection the following: D.C.Code, sec. 46-114 (1981 ed D.C.Ccde, sec. 46-119 (1981 ed 1.1 Enrolled Or A) The amount specified by the individual to the Director to be deducted and withheld under this subsection if neither subparagraph (3) nor (C) of this paragraph is applicable 3) The amount (if any) determined pursuant to an agreement submitted to the Director under Section‘454(20)(3)(i) of the Social Security Act by the appropriate State or local child support errforcement agency, unless subparagraph (C) of this paragraph is a pplicable; or C) Any amount otherwise required to be so deducted and withheld from the unemployment compensation pursuant to legal process as that term is defined in Section 4-62(e) of the Social Security Act s"(4) Any amount deducted and withheld under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be paid by the Director to the appropriate State or'loc child support enforcement agency 5) Any amount deducted and withheld par h (2) of this subsection shall treated all purposes as if. it were paid to the individual as unemployment compensation and paid by such an individual to the State or local child enforcement agency in satisfaction of the individual's child support obligations 5) For purposes of paragraphs (2) through (5) of this subsection, the term 11.:nemployment compersaticn' means a•y c=rir.ersa'%Lor payable under the Pt Pz wi ef ent inc are nft 41infc defi only plan Act 1 and Socii nfor itY a ra th f sc. pe a: Enrolled Original hate law (including amounts payable by the District irsuant to an agreement under any Federal law ;roviding for compensation, assistance, or allowances ith respect to unemployment Deductions shall be made pursuant to ithis subsection only if appropriate arrangements have eeri made for reimbursement by the State or local child Mforcement agency for the administrative costs incurred by the Director under this subsection which ere attributable to child support obligations being enforced by the State or local child support enforcement agency. The term 'child support obligations' is defined for purposes of these provisions as includinc only obligations which are being enforced pursuant to a Aan described in Section 454 of the Social Security Act which has been approved by the Secretary of Eealth and Human Services under Part D of Title IV of the Social Security Act 9) The term 'State or local child enforcement agency' as used in these provisions means any agency cf a State or political subdivision thereof operating pursuant to a plan described in paragraph (8) of this subsection Sec. 3. The Unemployment Trust Fund Act of 1981, effective March 16, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-86; 29 DCR 429) is mealed. Sec. 4. Section 2(a b c d e f 13 Ncte, D .0 Code sus 10E 10 E 111 amp j 1 cr cel 7 Er'Irclled Orig4 (h and (j) shall take effect, for a period not to exceed 180 days, after a 30-day period of Congressional, review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, ap proved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 PROVIDED, That it shall not become effective until the expiration of the Unemployment Trust Fund Act of 1981, effective March 16, 1982 (0.C. Law 4-36; 29 OCR 429 Sec. 5. Section 2(g i and (k) shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) cf the District of Columbia Self-Government and Goverrmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813r D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 PROVIDED, That it shall not become effective unt il the expiration of the Unemployment Trust and Act of 1982, effective Ma:oh 15, 1982 (D.0 Law 4-86; 29 OCR 429 A-N.Ni''4 ` \ Cha-tzman \ Council of t 0-a District of C2:1=ciai ;Mayor District ct Columbia y2 ?LT 1J.1.7 21, 1982 :Sete, secs. 46-1 a -119 (1981 aL) la la le CZRITSI "ICN CF RECCRD Secretary a he Count COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Four Second Session rcciET B 4-431 Item cn Consent Calendar ACT/ON: p t e_Zzz6z:32 III WICE‘etrrE:Bv Mac7itv, Member Rol ark voted no Absent: all p resent MIL CALL 1/CM Mc1C7.1 WLNI'M C.ARKE SWORD JARVIS 8, AYEINAYIN.V. A.3.1CCUNCIL ME1`BERIAYEINAIN.V.IA.3.1CCLINCIL MEMBERIAYEINAYIN.V.iA.B. I I IKANE I I i I ISRACEZZION I I I i 1 I FASCN 1 I F !SPAULDING I r—r 7 MOORE, JR. IiIWILSON i RAY i 1 I I I I I IROLARK I I I I no.cates Vote A.S Atsent N.V Not Votr7 Item on Conw_nt Calendar Adorted Final Readin g 7-20-82 Unanimous Absent: all present x VOICE VOTE: I 1 ROLL cau, mis: axNal MEMBERIAYEINAYIN.V.IA.3.1COUNCIL XEMBERIAYEINAYIN.V. A.B.ICCUNCIL MEMBERIAYEINAYIN.V.IA.S. ISEMKLETCN 1 I I I I SPAULDLNG 1 7-7 I 1 wilzoN I I I I 1 i I I I I tjui „.ki ,r\ CV.A.U.s.11 Item on Cznsent Cmlndar ACTTON: I I VD= LCTE: Ar-salt: ICI ROLL CAL ACTT MN. OLMIN I I I I KANE I I manER i I I IMASON I I CARR I I i i &amp;amp;CORE JR. 1 I ClAYITCPD i i IRAY I I JARVIS /FCLARK 1 I I X Inicates Vote A.3 Atsent N.V Not Vctin Czex.T.:J.CATICN CF R..CRD 4 Se-et.ary to the Couly1J. CINCL XEXBERIAYEINAYIN.V.iA.3.iCCCNC:L XEMBff17:7127,7;2,,A.4.11,.3 KANE I I I SHAZILETCN I I IMASCN SPI1ULDING I iMOCRE, JR. WI-5CN RAY CLARK Inolcat_s A.3 Acsent CZRTIFICATION CF RECORD aecretary 0 zne -ate. MN. or= TervrEta c na OARCRD N V NCc il-P1314 Page 1 Page 2 Page 3 Page 4 Page 5 Page 6 Page 7 Page 8 Page 9 Page 10 Page 11 Page 12 Page 13 Page 14 Page 15 Page 16</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
