<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-117">
  <num type="bill">24-309</num>
  <num type="act">24-117</num>
  <heading type="short">Local Food Access Grants Emergency Amendment Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development Limited Grant-Making Authority Act of 2012 to authorize the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development to issue grants and loans to support the equitable distribution of food businesses across the District.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-06-24</introduced>
    <effective>2021-07-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/47421/Signed_Act/B24-0309-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-117</citation>
      <citation type="register">68 DCR 007321</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0309">
      <vote date="2021-06-29" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2021-07-21</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, that this act may be cited as the "Local Food Access Grants Emergency Amendment Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 2032 of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development Limited Grant-Making Authority Act of 2012, effective September 20, 2012 (D.C. Law 19-168; D.C. Official Code § 1-328.04), is amended by adding a new subsection (j) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-328.04"/>
        <num>(j)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Notwithstanding <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="1|3|XII-A|B">the Grant Administration Act of 2013, effective December 24, 2013 (D.C. Law 20-61; D.C. Official Code § 1-328.11 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite><span codify:value="[,]"/> the Deputy Mayor may make grants and loans for the purpose of supporting the equitable distribution of food businesses in Wards 7 and 8 and in eligible areas, including:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Grants and loans to assist in the startup, growth, and long-term sustainability of food businesses in Wards 7 and 8 and in eligible areas; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Grants for the provision of technical assistance to food businesses and individuals seeking to establish food businesses in the District.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The Deputy Mayor may issue one or more grants to a third-party grant-managing entity for the purpose of issuing or administering grants or loans authorized by this subsection on behalf of the Deputy Mayor.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term "eligible areas" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-3801|(1D)">D.C. Official Code § 47-3801(1D)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-328.04"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-328.04" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on October 19, 2021. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-328.04(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
