<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-1408</num>
  <heading>Use of conduits of Washington Railway and Electric Company by Potomac Electric Power Company.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized, in his discretion, to permit the Potomac Electric Power Company to make connections between its conduits and the conduits of the Washington Railway and Electric Company and all other companies controlled by the Washington Railway and Electric Company for the purpose of furnishing electric current through the said conduits for public and private uses, the use of said railway companies’ conduits to be upon such terms as may be agreed upon between the said companies.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Apr. 27, 1904, 33 Stat. 376, ch. 1628, § 1</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Public utility, service, valuation and accounts, multiple company use of equipment, see § <cite root="34-1102">34-1102</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 43-1208.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 43-1108.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
