<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1434</num>
  <heading>Reporting requirements and compliance fee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each electricity supplier shall submit an annual compliance report to the Commission, by a date and in a form prescribed by the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each report shall include clear and concise information that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Demonstrates that the electricity supplier has complied with the applicable standard under § <cite path="§34-1432">34-1432</cite> and includes the submission of the required amount of renewable energy credits; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Demonstrates the amount of electricity sales by which the electricity supplier fails to meet the applicable renewable energy portfolio standard.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each report shall also include any other information that the Commission by regulation or order may consider relevant.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If an electricity supplier fails to comply with the renewable energy portfolio standard for the applicable year, the electricity supplier shall pay into the Fund a compliance fee of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Five cents for each kilowatt-hour of shortfall from required tier one renewable sources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One cent for each kilowatt-hour of shortfall from required tier two renewable sources; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Fifty cents in 2011 through 2016; 35 cents in 2017; 30 cents in 2018; 20 cents in 2019 through 2020; 15 cents in 2021 through 2022; and 5 cents in 2023 and thereafter for each kilowatt-hour of shortfall from required solar energy sources.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Beginning on March 1, 2010, and annually thereafter, energy companies that sell electricity in the District of Columbia shall file an energy portfolio report for the preceding calendar year with DDOE, which shall include a breakdown of the average cost per kilowatt hour of electricity that the company sold in the District of Columbia by source of generation, to include coal, gas, oil, nuclear, solar, land-based wind, off-shore wind, and other renewable sources. The breakdown of cost should also include the average capital cost per kilowatt, as well as the average fixed and variable costs associated with operations and maintenance per megawatt.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The District Department of the Environment shall publish on its website at least annually a report that describes progress towards the solar generation goals provided in the renewable energy portfolio standard and a comparison with other sources of energy used in the District. Each report shall detail the equitable distribution of resources consistent with the policy findings in § <cite path="§34-1501.01">34-1501.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-340" type="History" path="§6">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-340, § 6, 52 DCR 2285</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-250" type="History">Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-250, § 301(c), 55 DCR 9225</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-36" type="History">Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-36, § 2(b), 58 DCR 6837</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-47" type="History">Dec. 13, 2013, D.C. Law 20-47, § 3, 60 DCR 15138</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§34-1435">34-1435</cite> and § <cite path="§34-1436">34-1436</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-250">D.C. Law 17-250</law-cite> rewrote subsecs. (c)(1) and (3); and added subsecs. (c)(4), (5).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-36">D.C. Law 19-36</law-cite> rewrote subsec. (c)(3); redesignated subsec. (c)(4) as subsec. (d); redesignated subsec. (c)(5) as subsec. (e); and repealed newly designated subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-47">D.C. Law 20-47</law-cite> added (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 301(c) of Clean and Affordable Energy Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-508, September 25, 2008,  55 DCR 10856).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Distributed Generation Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-126, August 1, 2011,  58 DCR 6766).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Distributed Generation Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-192, October 18, 2011,  58 DCR 9154).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-36">D.C. Law 19-36</law-cite>: Section 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-36">D.C. Law 19-36</law-cite>, as amended by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-245">D.C. Law 20-245</law-cite>, § 3, provided that the act (a) shall apply as of July 12, 2011; and (b) shall not apply to contracts entered into before August 1, 2011, provided that, for a contract entered into before August 1, 2011, the act shall apply to an extension or renewal of that contract executed on or after August 1, 2011.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
