<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-1313.14</num>
  <heading>Approval of schedule provisions applying the true-up mechanism to DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Charge.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Following the issuance of a series of Bonds, the electric company, or other person as may be designated by the Commission, shall file with the Commission, no later than April 1 of each year, or more frequently as necessary and as provided in the financing order, a request for approval of a schedule applying the true-up mechanism to the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Charges authorized under the financing order, based on factors set forth in the financing order.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A request for approval of a schedule filed pursuant to this section shall include, at a minimum, a narrative description of the proposed adjustments, a proposed form of public notice of the request suitable for publication by the Commission and the following exhibits, as applicable:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A showing that the allocation of DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Charges among the electric company’s distribution service customer classes conforms to the distribution service customer class cost allocations approved by the Commission in the electric company’s most recent base rate case; provided, that no such charges shall be assessed against customers served under the electric company’s residential aid discount or a succeeding discount program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Billing and collection data that show the proposed adjustment is expected to generate payments that correspond to the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Annual Revenue Requirement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A showing that the proposed adjustment is expected to result in neither a net over-collection nor under-collection of the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Annual Revenue Requirement; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Accounting work papers showing the electric company’s prior year’s receipts and disbursements of the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Charges.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commission’s review of a request for approval of a schedule filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be limited to a determination of whether there is any mathematical error in the application of the true-up mechanism to the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Charges.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any interested party may file comments with the Commission with respect to the mathematical accuracy of the electric company’s calculations in the application of the true-up mechanism within 10 days of the filing of the electric company’s request for approval of a schedule applying the true-up mechanism to the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Charges. The Commission shall act upon a request for approval of a schedule filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section within 20 days of the end of the comment period. If the Commission does not act within this 20-day period to correct any mathematical error, the request for approval of a schedule filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be deemed approved. The DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Charges set forth in the schedule shall take effect, subject to refund and adjustment, on the date the schedule is filed with the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>No schedule applying the true-up mechanism to the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Charges that is approved or deemed approved under this section shall in any way affect the irrevocability of the pertinent financing order approved pursuant to § <cite path="§34-1313.01">34-1313.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-102" type="History">May 3, 2014, D.C. Law 20-102, § 314, 61 DCR 1882</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§34-1313.01">34-1313.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
