<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1439</num>
  <heading>Rules, duties, and powers of the Commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission may impose an administrative fee on a renewable energy credit transaction, but the amount of the fee may not exceed the Commission’s actual direct cost of processing the transaction.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On or before May 1 of each year, the Commission shall provide a report to the Council on the status of implementation of this chapter, including the availability of tier one renewable sources, certification of the number of credits generated by the utilities meeting the requirements of § <cite path="§34-1432">34-1432</cite>, and any other such information as the Council shall consider necessary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall establish standards, by order or regulation, to account for customer generation from eligible renewable resources for compliance with § <cite path="§34-1432">34-1432</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-340" type="History" path="§11">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-340, § 11, 52 DCR 2285</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 2112, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</law-cite> substituted “May 1” for “April 1” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2112 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2112 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2112 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional ReviewEmergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
