<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1101</num>
  <heading>Utility service and charges to be just and reasonable; certification required.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Every public utility doing business within the District of Columbia is required to furnish service and facilities reasonably safe and adequate and in all respects just and reasonable.  The charge made by any public utility for a facility or service furnished, rendered, or to be furnished or rendered, shall be reasonable, just, and nondiscriminatory. Every unjust, unreasonable, or discriminatory charge for the facility or service is prohibited and unlawful.  Every public utility is required to obey the lawful orders of the Commission created by this subtitle.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No public utility shall furnish a service or facility, directly or indirectly, without first proceeding and proving to the satisfaction of the Public Service Commission (“Commission”) that the present and future public convenience and necessity requires that the service be provided or the facility be offered. Upon application of a public utility for a certificate of present and future public convenience and necessity pursuant to this subsection, the Commission, upon a hearing and notice to the public, shall issue an order granting or denying the application, in whole or in part, stating the reasons for the action. The Commission may prescribe terms and conditions upon a grant of an application for a certificate of present and future public convenience and necessity as the Commission, in its discretion, decides are necessary to further the present and future public convenience and necessity. The Commission is authorized to promulgate any rules necessary to implement this subsection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Every public utility that was regulated by the Commission and that furnished a service or facility within the District of Columbia as of June 27, 1989 is deemed to have been granted a certificate of public convenience and necessity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commission is authorized to promulgate any rules necessary to implement this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 62-3-ch150" path="§8|2">Mar. 4, 1913, 37 Stat. 977, ch. 150, § 8, par. 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-29" type="History">Sept. 20, 1989, D.C. Law 8-29, § 2, 36 DCR 4742</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-47" type="History">Oct. 19, 1989, D.C. Law 8-47, § 2, 36 DCR 5786</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Deregulation of streetlighting service: Section 130 of H.R. 3067, amended by H.R. 99-419, incorporated in Pub. L. 99-190 by § 101(c), the D.C. Appropriation Act, 1986, provided that the Public Service Commission is authorized to order and to approve the deregulation of streetlighting service to the District of Columbia as provided in its opinion and order in Formal Case No. 813, dated July 12, 1984 (Order No. 8056), § <cite path="§43-402">43-402</cite> § <cite path="§1-204.93">1-204.93</cite>, 2001 Ed., this section, and § <cite path="§43-1207">43-1207</cite> § <cite path="§34-1407">34-1407</cite>, 2001 Ed., and provided that the provisions of this opinion and order regarding deregulation of streetlighting service are hereby ratified and declared to be in effect as of July 12, 1984 and shall continue to be in effect until revoked or rescinded.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-301.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-501.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§34-1522">34-1522</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
