<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-1701</num>
  <heading>Ban on automated telephone dialing systems for commercial solicitation; definitions; prohibition; exceptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Automated dialing or push-button or tone-activated address signaling telephone system with a prerecorded message” is any equipment used for telephone solicitation purposes, which alone or in conjunction with other equipment, can convey a prerecorded or synthesized voice message to the number called.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Soliciting” means any attempt to sell or lease consumer goods, services, or real property to another person.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person may not use an automated dialing, push-button, or tone-activated address signaling telephone system with a prerecorded message for the sole purpose of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Soliciting a person over the telephone to purchase or lease goods, services, or real property; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Requesting survey information over the telephone where results are to be used directly for the purpose of soliciting a person to purchase or lease goods, services, or real property.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This section shall not apply if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The person soliciting is a federal, state, or local government agency that uses an automated dialing prerecorded message for emergency purposes; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A person has a preexisting business relationship with the party called and the call concerns goods, services, or real property that have been previously ordered or purchased.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any automated, push-button, or tone-activated address signaling telephone system used in the District must automatically create a disconnect signal or on hook condition which allows the called party’s line to be released within 10 seconds after the called party hangs up.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any person who violates this section shall be fined a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 for the 1st violation and not more than $5,000 for each subsequent violation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia, or his assistants, shall prosecute violations of this section in the name of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-14" type="History">July 13, 1991, D.C. Law 9-14, §§ 2, 3, 38 DCR 3384</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-1418.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
