<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-1435</num>
  <heading>Recovery of fees and costs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall allow the local distribution company to recover actual dollar-for-dollar prudently costs incurred, including a compliance fee under § <cite path="§34-1434">34-1434</cite>, in complying with a mandated renewable energy portfolio standard. The electricity distribution company may also pass through its prudently incurred additional costs, if any, associated with complying with the standard, through the end of the year of standard offer service in which the requirement took effect.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An electricity supplier may recover a compliance fee if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The payment of a compliance fee is the least-cost measure to ratepayers as compared to the purchase of tier one renewable sources, tier two renewable sources, or solar energy to comply with a renewable energy portfolio standard; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>There are insufficient tier one renewable sources, tier two renewable sources, or solar energy available for the electricity supplier to comply with a renewable energy portfolio standard.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any cost recovery under this section:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>May be in the form of a nonbypassable surcharge to current applicable customers; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shall be disclosed on applicable customer bills.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-340">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-340, § 7, 52 DCR 2285</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§34-1433">34-1433</cite> and § <cite path="§34-1436">34-1436</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
