<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-1264.02</num>
  <heading>Cable theft.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Cable service” means a cable system that has been granted a franchise to operate in the District, an Open Video System that is authorized to operate in the District, a Satellite Master Antenna Television System, Direct Broadcast Satellite, or any other video transmission system for which a person is expected to pay before receiving such transmission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Cable operator” means a person providing cable service as defined in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless authorized by a cable operator, it shall be unlawful for any person to do, or aid or assist another person in doing, any of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Attach or affix, or cause to be attached or affixed, any equipment or device, including, but not limited to, a decoder, descrambler, converter, or modem, which allows the access to, or the use of, a cable service without payment to the cable operator. A violation of this paragraph shall be a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of up to $2500 or imprisonment of up to 6 months, or both.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Receive a cable signal or obtain, intercept, or receive a service from a cable operator by any equipment or device, including, but not limited to a decoder, descrambler, converter, access code, or modem, with the intent to deprive the cable operator of compensation for the service. It shall be an affirmative defense to an offense under this paragraph that a cable operator has failed to disconnect a service at the request of a subscriber, or where the cable operator failed to disconnect service, upon a request, at the end of an occupancy and a new occupant moves in without knowledge of the existing service. A violation of this paragraph shall be a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of up to $5000 or imprisonment of up to 1 year, or both.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Make or maintain either a physical, electrical, acoustical, or other connection to a cable system, or tamper, interfere with, damage, or cut any cables, wires, components, moderns, lock boxes, pedestals, or other equipment of a cable operator, with the intent to deprive a cable operator of compensation for its service. A violation of this paragraph shall be a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of up to $5,000 or imprisonment of up to 1 year, or both.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Make or maintain any modification or alteration to any device, equipment, or apparatus or remove, disconnect or sell any device, equipment, or apparatus installed by a cable operator, without the authority of the cable operator, for the purpose of intercepting, descrambling, decoding, or receiving any program or other service offered by the cable operator. A violation of this paragraph shall be a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of up to $5,000 or imprisonment of up to 1 year, or both.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Make, manufacture, import into the District, assemble, transfer, distribute, promote, sell, lease, lend, offer, own, possess, or possess for sale, advertise or publish for sale or for lease any device, equipment, apparatus, or circuit board designed to intercept, decode, descramble, or otherwise make intelligible any encoded, encrypted, scrambled, or other nonstandard signal distributed by a cable operator. A violation of this paragraph shall be a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of up to $5,000 or imprisonment of up to 1 year or both.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person who commits a violation under subsection (b) of this section, for payment or offer of payment, or with the intent to profit from any consideration received or expected, shall be guilty of a felony and upon conviction shall be subject to a fine of up to $10,000 or imprisonment of up to 10 years, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person convicted for the violation of any of the offenses under subsection (b) of this section 3 times within a 10-year period shall be guilty of a felony.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A person may seek civil remedies, penalties, damages, or injunctions in addition to the criminal penalties provided under this section. In seeking civil penalties, damages, or injunctions, a person may use a guilty judgment or any other plea bargain agreement as evidence in support of such civil remedies, penalties, or damages.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-142">Aug. 21, 1982, D.C. Law 4-142, § 1402</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-193">as added Oct. 9, 2002, D.C. Law 14-193, § 2(b), 49 DCR 7334</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
