<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1515</num>
  <heading>Aggregation programs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may develop and administer a municipal aggregation program for the purchase of electricity supply and electricity supply services by District of Columbia ratepayers.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1A)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>There is established a fund designated as the Municipal Aggregation Fund, which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia and shall be used solely to pay the costs of the formation and administration of municipal aggregation contracts of the District. The funds collected under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, and all interest earned on those funds, shall be deposited into the Fund without regard to fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress. All funds deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this subparagraph, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Mayor may charge an administrative fee under any municipal aggregation contract entered into by the District.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, in conjunction with the Commission, shall issue regulations governing a municipal aggregation program implemented under this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office of the People’s Counsel shall assist any person seeking to implement a customer-based aggregation program. The assistance shall include help in understanding the technical and economic issues involved in purchasing electricity supply, electricity supply services, or any other service determined by the Commission to be a potentially competitive service.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Commission may adopt any reasonable regulations relating to customer-based aggregation programs that it determines to be in the public interest.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall prohibit the development and implementation of aggregation programs during the implementation of pilot programs.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-107" type="History">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, § 115, 47 DCR 1091</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-192" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-192, § 2082, 53 DCR 6899</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20" type="History">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 2022, 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</law-cite> added subsec. (a)(1A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</law-cite>, in subsec. (a)(1A)(B), deleted “, not to exceed $85,000,” following “fee”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2082 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-477, August 8, 2006,  53 DCR 7068).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2082 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-499, October 23, 2006,  53 DCR 8845).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2082 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-1, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1165).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2022 of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2081 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</law-cite> provided that subtitle G of title II of the act may be cited as the “Municipal Aggregation Fund Amendment Act of 2006”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2021 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</law-cite> provided that subtitle C of title II of the act may be cited as the “Municipal Aggregation Fund Amendment Act of 2007”.</text>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority-Retail Electric Competition and Consumer Protection Act of 1999, see Mayor’s Order 2007-56, February 9,</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
