<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1561</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Advanced Metering Infrastructure” or “AMI” means a system capable of providing 2-way communication with metering equipment to gather at least hourly energy consumption data on a daily basis for all customers.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“ARRA” means the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, approved February 17, 2009 (123 Stat. 115; 26 U.S.C. § 1, note).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Commission” means the Public Service Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Customer” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§34-1501">34-1501</cite>(12).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Electric company” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§34-207">34-207</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Meter Data Management System” means a system that provides a single data repository which can gather data from multiple metering systems and then supply that data to multiple applications such as billing, forecasting, customer service, system operation and maintenance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Regulatory asset” means specific costs that a public utility may defer to its balance sheet and accrue earnings thereon at its authorized rate of return.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Smart Grid” means the installation of advanced technology to enhance the operation of the electric distribution and transmission system.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2161, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Advanced Metering Infrastructure Implementation and Cost Recovery Authorization Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-107, June 18, 2009,  56 DCR 4929).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 2001, 2002 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-187, August 26, 2009,  56 DCR 7374).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2161 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2161 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2160 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle Q of title II of the act may be cited as the “Advanced Metering Infrastructure Implementation and Cost Recovery Authorization Act of 2009”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
