<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1731.01</num>
  <heading>Findings and purposes.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council finds that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Low-income residents and residents in economically disadvantaged areas of the District of Columbia are also likely to be digitally-disadvantaged in that they cannot afford access to the Internet or may lack the computer equipment and training necessary to benefit meaningfully from Internet access.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Certain assets of the District, including light poles and buildings, may provide value to telecommunications carriers for the attachment of wireless network antennae and the deployment of broadband internet services.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The District government does not have the funds to provide to digitally-disadvantaged residents the range of services necessary to afford Internet access and permit them to benefit meaningfully from that Internet access.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>By awarding one or more franchises that permit a telecommunications carrier to use District-owned assets such as buildings and poles on a nonexclusive basis in return for the provision of certain services to digitally-disadvantaged residents, the District government can meet the Internet access needs of these residents without additional cost or risk to the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The purposes of this chapter are to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Obtain value for the District through the awarding of rights to use poles, buildings, and other assets of the District for telecommunications purposes; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide for the furnishing of benefits to digitally-disadvantaged residents of the District in exchange for a franchise to use poles, buildings, and other assets of the District for Internet-related telecommunications purposes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-210" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-210, § 2, 53 DCR 9122</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Digital Inclusion Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-467, July 25, 2006,  53 DCR 6754).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
