<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1501.01</num>
  <heading>Policy findings.</heading>
  <text>The Council of the District of Columbia adopts the following policy findings in support of community renewable energy:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Local communities benefit from the deployment of tier one renewable energy in the District, and the Council hereby encourages the Department to establish programs that support development of such projects;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>It is in the public interest that the Department encourages broad participation in District-based tier one renewable electric generation by District residents, not-for-profit entities, and for-profit entities through outreach efforts and programs in all 8 wards;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>It is in the public interest that the Department enables the development and deployment of community renewable energy facilities for the following purposes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>To allow renters and low- to moderate-income retail electric customers to own interests in tier one renewable energy generating facilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>To allow interests in tier one renewable energy generation facilities to be portable and transferrable;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>To facilitate market entry for all potential subscribers, while prioritizing those persons most sensitive to market barriers; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>To encourage developers to promote participation by renters and low- to moderate-income retail electric customers; and</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>It is in the public interest for developers to encourage participation by renters and low- to moderate-income retail electric customers.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-107" type="History" path="§101a">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, § 101a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-47" type="History">as added Dec. 13, 2013, D.C. Law 20-47, § 2(b), 60 DCR 15138</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§34-1434">34-1434</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-47">D.C. Law 20-47</law-cite> added this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
