<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1254.06</num>
  <heading>Procedure for Council review and approval of initial franchise.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Office and the applicant agree on the terms of a proposed franchise agreement under § <cite path="§34-1254.05">34-1254.05</cite>, the Office shall submit to the Mayor and the Council a Recommendation for the Approval of a Franchise Application consisting of the franchise application, the proposed franchise agreement, and a summary of factors supporting the recommendation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If at the end of the initial or extended negotiation period under § <cite path="§34-1254.04">34-1254.04</cite>, the Office and the applicant are unable to agree on the terms of a proposed franchise agreement, the Office shall submit to the Mayor and the Council a Recommendation for the Denial of a Franchise Application consisting of the franchise application and a summary of the factors supporting the recommendation. The summary shall describe specific deficiencies of the application and a general description of why the application should not be granted.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Council may, by act, grant a franchise and approve the franchise agreement, with or without conditions or modifications which may override any provisions of the proposed franchise agreement, deny a franchise or reject the proposed franchise agreement and remand the proposed franchise agreement to the Office with recommendations to renegotiate any of the provisions of the agreement and submit a revised agreement to the Council, or deny a franchise or reject the proposed franchise agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Each applicant to whom the District grants a franchise shall pay to the District, within 30 days after the franchise is granted, a franchise award fee to be set in the act granting the franchise. The payment shall be nonrefundable. An applicant’s failure to pay the franchise award fee within the 30-day period shall make the franchise and franchise agreement void.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-142" type="History" path="§406">Aug. 21, 1982, D.C. Law 4-142, § 406</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-193" type="History">as added Oct. 9, 2002, D.C. Law 14-193, § 2(b), 49 DCR 7334</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
