<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1731.04</num>
  <heading>Insurance and bonds; liability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The franchisee shall assume all legal responsibility for, and shall hold the District harmless from, any costs or liability that arise because of injury to persons or property caused by, or in relation, to the provision of the package of services for digitally-disadvantaged residents or the franchisee’s use of District telecommunications assets pursuant to this chapter and the franchise agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall require the franchisee to obtain liability insurance sufficient to insure against all liability or costs that arise because of injury to persons or property caused by, or in relation to, the provision of the package of services for digitally-disadvantaged residents and the franchisee’s use of District telecommunications assets pursuant to this chapter and the franchise agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall require the franchisee to obtain a performance bond sufficient to guarantee the provision of the package of services for digitally-disadvantaged residents pursuant to this chapter and the franchise agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No person aggrieved or damaged in any way by any act or omission of the franchisee related to the offering or provision of the package of services for digitally-disadvantaged residents or the franchisee’s use of District telecommunications assets pursuant to this chapter and the franchise agreement shall have a cause of action against the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-210" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-210, § 5, 53 DCR 9122</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5 of Digital Inclusion Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-467, July 25, 2006,  53 DCR 6754).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
