<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-1436</num>
  <heading>Renewable Energy Development Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a fund designated as the Renewable Energy Development Fund, which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia and shall be used solely for the purposes set forth in this section. All fees, payment, investment earnings, or other funds received, and all interest on the funds, shall be deposited into the Fund without regard to fiscal year limitation and shall not any time be transferred to, or lapse into, or be commingled with the General Fund of the District of Columbia or any other fund or account of the District of Columbia, except as delineated in this section. The Fund shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund established by this section shall be administered by the Energy Office. The Energy Office may receive and review applications for loans, grants, rebates, and other financial incentives for eligible projects from the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used solely for the purpose of making loans, grants, rebates, and other financial incentives to support the creation of new solar energy sources in the District of Columbia and for otherwise administering the Fund. The Fund may be used to supplement programs supporting the creation of new solar energy sources in the District of Columbia through the Sustainable Energy Utility contract established by Chapter 17N of Title 8 [§ <cite path="§8-1773.01">8-1773.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Proceeds for the Fund shall be collected from the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Compliance fees paid under § <cite path="§34-1434">34-1434</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Payments received in repayment of a loan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Investment earnings of the Fund; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Energy Office shall establish the eligibility criteria for projects supported by the Fund. The Energy Office may allow the use of money of the Fund for administrative expenses related to the Fund and project review and oversight.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The DDOE shall provide to the Council a quarterly report detailing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Expenditures from the Renewable Energy Development Fund; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The performance of programs or projects funded by the Renewable Energy Development Fund.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Any compliance fees paid into the Fund by an electricity supplier that were charged to the District of Columbia government through a cost recovery surcharge authorized in § <cite path="§34-1435">34-1435</cite>(c) shall be transferred from the Fund to the General Fund of the District of Columbia and used to cover any surcharge owed by the District of Columbia government.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-340" type="History">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-340, § 8, 52 DCR 2285</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-250" type="History">Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-250, § 301(d), 55 DCR 9225</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 1112, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-36" type="History">Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-36, § 2(c), 58 DCR 6837</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 6063, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1508">47-1508</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-250">D.C. Law 17-250</cite> added subsec. (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in subsecs. (b) and (c), substituted “loans, grants, rebates, and other financial incentives” for “loans and grants”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-36">D.C. Law 19-36</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “account of the District of Columbia, except as delineated in this section” for “account of the District of Columbia”; and added subsec. (g).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> substituted “may receive” for “shall receive” in (b); and added the last sentence in (c).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 301(d) of Clean and Affordable Energy Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-508, September 25, 2008,  55 DCR 10856).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1112 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Distributed Generation Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-126, August 1, 2011,  58 DCR 6766).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Distributed Generation Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-192, October 18, 2011,  58 DCR 9154).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6073 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6063 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  2032 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1111 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle L of title I of the act may be cited as the “Renewable Energy Development Amendment Act of 2010”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">See note to §  32-1301.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-36">D.C. Law 19-36</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-36">D.C. Law 19-36</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-245">D.C. Law 20-245</cite>, § 3, provided that the act (a) shall apply as of July 12, 2011; and (b) shall not apply to contracts entered into before August 1, 2011, provided that, for a contract entered into before August 1, 2011, the act shall apply to an extension or renewal of that contract executed on or after August 1, 2011.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
