<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-209</num>
  <heading>“Gas company” defined.</heading>
  <text>The term “gas company” when used in this subtitle includes every corporation, company, association, joint-stock company or association, partnership, or person manufacturing, making, distributing, or selling gas for light, heat, or power, or for any public use whatsoever in the District of Columbia, their lessees, trustees, or receivers, appointed by any court whatsoever, and in said district selling, physically transmitting, or distributing natural gas in the District of Columbia to retail natural gas customers. The term excludes any building owner, lessee, or manager who, respectively, owns, leases, or manages, the internal distribution system serving the building and who supplies natural gas and other related natural gas services solely to occupants of the building for use by the occupants.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 62-3-ch150" path="§8|1">Mar. 4, 1913, 37 Stat. 975, ch. 150, § 8, par. 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-227" type="History">Mar. 16, 2005, D.C. Law 15-227, § 17(a)(3), 51 DCR 10549</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 58(a), 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-1773.01">8-1773.01</cite> and § <cite path="§34-1311.01">34-1311.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-213.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-113.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-227">D.C. Law 15-227</cite> rewrote the section which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“The term ‘gas corporation’ when used in this subtitle includes every corporation, company, association, joint-stock company or association, partnership, or person manufacturing, making, distributing, or selling gas for light, heat, or power, or for any public use whatsoever in the District of Columbia, their lessees, trustees, or receivers, appointed by any court whatsoever, and in said district owning, operating, controlling, or managing any gas plant, except where the gas is made or produced and distributed by the maker on or through private property solely for its own use or the use of its tenants and not for sale to or for the use of others.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite> made a change in the directory language of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-227">D.C. Law 15-227</cite> which resulted in no change in text.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Prevention of Unauthorized Switching of Customer Natural Gas Accounts Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-13">D.C. Law 14-13</cite>, July 10, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 6589).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
