<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-2110</num>
  <heading>Additional charge for overdue bills; enforcement of lien.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized, in order to encourage the prompt payment of the sanitary sewer service charge imposed by this subchapter, to impose an additional charge of 10% for any sanitary sewer service charge remaining unpaid for more than 30 days, impose a penalty at the rate of 1% per month compounded monthly for any sanitary sewer service charge that remains unpaid for more than 60 days, and the Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to shut off the water of premises for which such charge is not paid within 30 days, and to have and enforce a continuing lien for such charge upon the land and any improvements thereon furnished such sanitary sewer service, in the same manner and to the same extent as if §§ <cite path="§34-2407.01">34-2407.01</cite>, <cite path="§34-2407.02">34-2407.02</cite>, <cite path="§34-2407.03">34-2407.03</cite>, and <cite path="§34-2413.10">34-2413.10</cite> [repealed] were set forth in this subchapter, and such sections shall be deemed to be applicable in every particular to the sanitary sewer service charge imposed by this subchapter; provided, that whenever said lien is enforced by the sale of property against which it has been assessed, so much of the proceeds of such sale as represents said unpaid sanitary sewer service charges shall be credited to the General Fund of the District of Columbia as established by the Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may defer or forgive, in whole or in part, any sanitary sewer service charges due the District of Columbia with respect to any qualified real property approved pursuant to § <cite path="§6-1503">6-1503</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 83-2-ch218" path="§210">May 18, 1954, 68 Stat. 107, ch. 218, title II, § 210</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-42" type="History">Jan. 22, 1976, D.C. Law 1-42, § 3(f)(5), 22 DCR 6315</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-177" type="History">Oct. 20, 1988, D.C. Law 7-177, § 9(b), 35 DCR 6158</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-136" type="History">June 13, 1990, D.C. Law 8-136, § 2(f), 37 DCR 2620</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-65" type="History">Nov. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 10-65, § 501(b), 40 DCR 7351</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 13 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-177">D.C. Law 7-177</cite> provided that the Mayor shall issue rules to implement the provisions of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975, referred to in subsection (a) of this section, is the Act of January 22, 1976, <cite doc="D.C. Law 1-42">D.C. Law 1-42</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of D.C. Water and Sewer Operations Temporary Amendment Act of 1993(<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-3">D.C. Law 10-3</cite>, May 18, 1993, law notification  42 DCR 3404).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-1609.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-1610.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-1503">6-1503</cite>, § <cite path="§34-2202.19">34-2202.19</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1052">47-1052</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1303">47-1303</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1304">47-1304</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1306">47-1306</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1307">47-1307</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-1312">47-1312</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
