<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-2701</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The terms “demolition” or “demolish” mean any operation by which a structure or mass of material is wrecked, razed, moved, or removed by means of any tool, equipment, or explosive.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The terms “excavate” or “excavation” mean any operation in which earth, rock, or other material in or on the ground is moved, removed or otherwise displaced by means of any tool, equipment, or explosive, and include but are not limited to grading, trenching, digging, ditching, drilling, boring, augering, tunnelling, scraping, cable or pipe plowing and driving, wrecking, razing, moving, or removing any structure or mass of material.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “one-call center” means any organization among the purposes of which is to notify 2 or more public utility operators of planned excavation activities or demolition in a specified area.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term “person” means any individual, firm, joint venture, partnership, corporation, association, agency of the District of Columbia government, or other governmental body or authority, except the United States government, and shall include any trustee, receiver, assignee, or personal representative thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The term “public utility operator” means a person, agency or instrumentality of the District of Columbia government, who supplies or transports any of the following materials or services by means of a utility line or conduit:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Gas of any kind, including flammable, toxic, or corrosive gas;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Liquids, including coal slurry, petroleum, petroleum products, or other hazardous liquids;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Electric energy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Communication services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Sewage disposal and drainage;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Water; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>Steam.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The term “underground facility” means any item of personal property which is buried or placed below ground, or submerged for use in connection with the storage or conveyance of water, sewage, electronic, telephonic, or teletype communications, electric energy, oil, gas, or other substances, and shall include, but not be limited to, pipes, sewers, conduits, cables, valves, lines, wires, manholes, attachments, and those portions of poles located below the ground.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The term “utility line” means any cable, pipeline, or other conduit installed underground by which a public utility operator furnishes materials or services.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-129" type="History" path="§2">Mar. 4, 1981, D.C. Law 3-129, § 2, 28 DCR 264</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 48, 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-114" type="History">May 23, 2000, D.C. Law 13-114, § 2(a), 47 DCR 1993</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-1701.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-114">D.C. Law 13-114</cite> in subd. (5) rewrote the introductory text which previously read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“The term ‘public utility operator’ means a person, other than an agency of the District of Columbia, who supplies or transports any of the following materials or services by means of a utility line:”; and rewrote subpar. (B), which previously read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(B) Liquids other than water, including such liquids as coal slurry, petroleum, petroleum products, or other hazardous liquids;”; and following “(G) Steam”, deleted “Except, that the District of Columbia government shall not be included.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Utility Line Temporary Act of 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-301">D.C. Law 17-301</cite>, March 20, 2009, law notification  56 DCR 3012).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) provisions, see § 2 of Utility Line Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-568, November 3, 2008,  55 DCR 12110).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
