<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-2131</num>
  <heading>Commissioner authorized to develop plan for interceptor and sewer line.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia (or his designated agents), hereinafter called the Mayor, is hereby authorized to develop a plan for a sanitary interceptor and trunk sewer line to extend from Dulles International Airport to the District of Columbia system, hereinafter called the Potomac interceptor, which shall be of sufficient capacity to provide service for such airport and for the expected community growth and development in the adjacent areas in the States of Maryland and Virginia. Such plan shall be developed in consultation with the National Capital Planning Commission and the Washington Metropolitan Council of Governments.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 86-515" type="History" path="§1">June 12, 1960, 74 Stat. 210, Pub. L. 86-515, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§34-2132">34-2132</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-1621.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-1620.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
