<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-2103</num>
  <heading>Advances for sanitary sewage works; reimbursement for amounts advanced.</heading>
  <text>The Secretary of the Treasury, notwithstanding the provisions of the District of Columbia Appropriation Act, approved June 29, 1922 (42 Stat. 668), is authorized and directed to advance, on the requisition of the Mayor of the District of Columbia, made in the manner now prescribed by law, out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, such sums as may be necessary, from time to time, to meet the expenses of the District in connection with the construction, operation, maintenance, expansion, relocation, replacement, renovation, and repair of the sanitary sewage works of the District, as authorized by Congress, and such amounts so advanced shall be reimbursed by the said Mayor to the Treasury out of money in the General Fund of the District of Columbia (including any special account therein).</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 83-2-ch218" path="§204">May 18, 1954, 68 Stat. 105, ch. 218, title II, § 204</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-42" type="History">Jan. 22, 1976, D.C. Law 1-42, § 3(f)(3), 22 DCR 6314</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§34-2102">34-2102</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-1603.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-1604.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
