<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-2502</num>
  <heading>Penalty for refusal to remove conduits.</heading>
  <text>On violation of any of the provisions or restrictions of § <cite path="§34-2501">34-2501</cite> the said Mayor shall require the permittee, after 30 days notice, to abandon the use of said conduits or pipes and remove them from the alley or alleys in which they are located, and if said permittee shall neglect or refuse to remove said conduits or pipes and place the surface of the alley in good condition within 60 days after the date of said notice, the said permittee shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and shall be liable to a fine of $10 for each and every day that said conduits or pipes are allowed to remain in the alley, or the said alley shall remain out of repair, which fine shall be recovered in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, in the name of said District, as other fines and penalties are now recovered in said Court.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 56-1-ch587" path="§2">May 26, 1900, 31 Stat. 218, ch. 587, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-60" type="History">July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§34-2503">34-2503</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-1302.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-1302.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
