<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-2202.17</num>
  <heading>Transition provisions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Until the initial meeting of the Board, but for not longer than 180 days from April 18, 1996, the existing management structure of the Water and Sewer Utility Administration, Department of Public Works shall serve as the operator of the Authority, thereafter, the Water and Sewer Utility Administration of the Department of Public Works shall be abolished.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Until the Board establishes a personnel system and a procurement system, and until rules and regulations pertaining to the Board’s duties have been promulgated, <cite path="2|3A">Chapter 3A of Title 2</cite> [<cite path="§2-351.01">§ 2-351.01</cite> et seq.] and <cite path="§1-601.01">§ 1-601.01</cite> et seq., and implementing rules and regulations shall continue to apply to the Authority.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The administration of payroll services and personnel services, including benefits administration, shall be provided to the Authority by the Office of Pay and Retirement and the District of Columbia Office of Personnel at a negotiated fee. These services may be terminated by the Authority upon written notice to each provider.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All collective bargaining agreements shall remain in effect until they expire, or until they are renegotiated by the Authority, whichever comes first, unless otherwise agreed upon by the parties to the collective bargaining agreements.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Treasurer of the District of Columbia shall collect retail water and sewer payments on the Authority’s behalf until the Authority notifies the Treasurer that an independent collection system has been established and that retail water and sewer customers have been notified of any changes in payment procedures. Water and sewer payments collected by the Treasurer shall be expeditiously deposited into the Fund and shall not be commingled with the Cash Management Pool, the General Fund, or any other funds or accounts of the District of Columbia, except that payments made to District cashiers may be deposited directly into a District disbursement account until the Authority notifies the Treasurer that an independent disbursement system has been established. Dedicated revenues received by the District Treasurer shall be subject to any pledge of the Authority as if deposited into the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Treasurer of the District of Columbia is authorized to transfer funds from the Fund to a District disbursement account in order to pay the necessary and reasonable expenses of the Authority until the Authority notifies the Treasurer that an independent disbursement system has been established.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-111" type="History" path="§217">Apr. 18, 1996, D.C. Law 11-111, § 217, 43 DCR 548</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-184" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-184, § 202(l), 43 DCR 4265</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 216(b), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(l) of the Water and Sewer Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-397, October 9, 1996,  43 DCR 5686), § 2(l) of the Water and Sewer Authority Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-466, December 30, 1996,  44 DCR 165), and § 2(l) of the Water and Sewer Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-48, March 31, 1997,  44 DCR 2105).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(l) of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-293, July 9, 1996,  43 DCR 4160).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> substituted “<cite path="2|3A">Chapter 3A of Title 2</cite>” for “<cite path="§2-301.01">§ 2-301.01</cite> et seq.” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-1687.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§34-2202.07">§ 34-2202.07</cite>, <cite path="§34-2202.14">§ 34-2202.14</cite>, and <cite path="§34-2202.15">§ 34-2202.15</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
