<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-2401.26</num>
  <heading>Contract authority of Mayor regarding costs of Potomac River reservoir; contract payments; appropriations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to contract with the United States, any state in the Potomac River basin, any agency or political subdivision thereof, and any other competent state or local authority, with respect to the payment by the District to the United States, either directly or indirectly, of the District’s equitable share of any part or parts of the non-federal portion of the costs of any reservoirs authorized by the Congress for construction on the Potomac River or any of its tributaries.  Every such contract may contain such provisions as the Mayor may deem necessary or appropriate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless hereafter otherwise provided by legislation enacted by the Council, all payments made by the District and all moneys received by the District pursuant to any contract made under the authority of this Act shall be paid from, or be deposited in, a fund designated by the Mayor.  Charges for water delivered from the District water system for use outside the District may be adjusted to reflect the portions of any payments made by the District under contracts authorized by this Act which are equitably attributable to such use outside the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-263" type="History">Mar. 24, 1972, 86 Stat. 113, Pub. L. 92-263, § 1-3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-198" type="History">Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 808, Pub. L. 93-198, title IV, § 488</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-1553.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., §§ 43-1542, 43-1542a.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“This Act,” referred to in subsection (b) of this section, is the District of Columbia Home Rule Act.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">This section is also codified at § <cite path="§1-204.88">1-204.88</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Definitions applicable: The definitions in § <cite path="§1-201.03">1-201.03</cite> apply to this section.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
