<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-2403.03</num>
  <heading>Large-quantity consumers to maintain water meters.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The supply of water to all manufacturing establishments, hotels, livery stables, and other commercial buildings, shall be determined by meters erected and maintained at the expense of the consumer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The bill for water meter service, including a charge for any repair made by the District, shall be due and payable when rendered. The Mayor shall impose a one-time charge of 10% for any water meter service charge that remains unpaid for more than 30 days and a penalty of 1% per month compounded monthly for any water meter repair service that remains unpaid for more than 60 days from the date the bill is rendered.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In accordance with § <cite path="§34-2407.02">34-2407.02</cite>, the Mayor shall impose and enforce a continuing lien upon land and land improvements that are furnished water meter services if any charges remain unpaid for more than 60 days from the date the bill for services is rendered.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, with prior written notice to the owner of the date and time of entry, and consistent with constitutional guidelines, may enter any building, establishment, or other premises to inspect, install, replace, read, or repair any water meter required to be installed pursuant to the Public Works Act. If the Mayor is unable to gain entry to the real property after 2 attempts, the Mayor shall notify the owner or occupant to contact the Department within 3 business days after notice is mailed to the owner. If the owner or occupant fails to contact the Department, it shall be presumed that the owner refuses to permit entry to the property and the Mayor may impose a penalty of $100 and shut off the water supply to the real property. Upon the payment of the penalty or issuance of a final decision where the owner files a request for administrative review, the Mayor may restore the water supply.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">R.S., D.C., § 216</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-136" type="History">June 13, 1990, D.C. Law 8-136, § 4, 37 DCR 2620</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-1511.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-1509.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “Public Works Act,” referred to in the first sentence of (d), is 68 Stat. 104, ch. 218.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
