<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-731</num>
  <heading>Prosecution for violation of rules.</heading>
  <text>Prosecution for violation of any rule, order, or regulation issued, adopted, or approved by the Public Service Commission pursuant to this subtitle; § <cite path="§50-2201.03">50-2201.03</cite>(e), or Chapters 28 and 30 [repealed] of Title 47, shall be on information in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, in the name of the District of Columbia, by the Corporation Counsel or any of his or her assistants. Any person, corporation, or public utility violating any rule, order, or regulation shall, upon conviction, be fined not more than $10,000. With respect to orders, rules, or regulations made or adopted by the Public Service Commission under authority of this subtitle, this section shall be construed to apply only to the orders, rules, or regulations subject to the penalties specifically provided in § <cite path="§34-706">34-706</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 76-1-ch40" path="§1">Apr. 5, 1939, 53 Stat. 569, ch. 40, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Apr. 1, 1942, 56 Stat. 190, ch. 207,§ 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-60" type="History">July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-503" type="History">Aug. 30, 1964, 78 Stat. 634, Pub. L. 88-503, § 21</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-153" type="History">Mar. 14, 1985, D.C. Law 5-153, § 4(a), 31 DCR 6440</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-342" type="History">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-342, § 302, 52 DCR 2346</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Motor vehicles and traffic, rules and regulations, authority, see § <cite path="§50-2201.03">50-2201.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public Service Commission, creation, powers and duties, see § <cite path="§34-802">34-802</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§34-732">34-732</cite> and § <cite path="§34-1552">34-1552</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-307.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-907.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-342">D.C. Law 15-342</cite> substituted “$10,000” for “$300”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 302 of Omnibus Utility Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-12, January 28, 2005,  52 DCR 2945).</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Chapter 30 of Title 47, referred to in the first sentence, was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-136">D.C. Law 5-136</cite>, effective March 13, 1985.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
