<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-704</num>
  <heading>Rebates.</heading>
  <text>It shall be unlawful for any person to solicit, accept, or receive any rebate, concession, or discrimination in respect to any service in or affecting or relating to any public utility or the production, transmission, delivery, or furnishing of heat, light, water, or power, or any liquid, steam, or air, or the conveying of telegraph or telephone messages within the District of Columbia by a public utility, or for any service in connection therewith whereby any such service shall, by any device whatsoever or otherwise, be rendered free or at a less rate than that named in the schedules and tariffs in force as provided in this subtitle, or whereby any service or advantage is received other than is in this subtitle specified. Any person violating the provisions of this section shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of not less than $200 nor more than $1,000 for each offense.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 62-3-ch150" path="§8|83">Mar. 4, 1913, 37 Stat. 991, ch. 150, § 8, par. 83</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-107" type="History">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, § 201(d), 47 DCR 1091</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 43-304.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 43-904.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-107">D.C. Law 13-107</cite> deleted “firm, or corporation” following “person” in the first and second sentence, deleted in the first sentence “District of Columbia” preceding “, or for any service”, and inserted in its place “District of Columbia by a public utility”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
