<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1102</num>
  <heading>Compact administrator authorized.</heading>
  <text>Pursuant to this Compact, the Director of the Department of Mental Health shall be the Compact Administrator and, acting jointly with like officers of party states, shall have power to promulgate rules and regulations to carry out more effectively the terms of the Compact. The Compact Administrator is hereby authorized, empowered, and directed to cooperate with all departments, agencies, and officers of and in the government of the District of Columbia in facilitating the proper administration of the Compact or of any supplementary agreement or agreements entered into by the District thereunder.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Apr. 26, 1972, 86 Stat. 130, Pub. L. 92-280, § 3</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-56">Dec. 18, 2001, D.C. Law 14-56, § 116(e), 48 DCR 7674</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-1802.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 6-1602.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-56">D.C. Law 14-56</cite>, in subsec. (e), substituted “the Director of the Department of Mental Health shall be the Compact Administrator and,” for “the Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and empowered to designate an officer who shall be the Compact Administrator and who,”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 16(e) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-51">D.C. Law 14-51</cite>, October 30, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 10807).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 16(e) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-55, May 2, 2001,  48 DCR 4390).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 16(e) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-101, July 23, 2001,  48 DCR 7123).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 116(e) of Mental Health Service Delivery Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-144, October 23, 2001,  48 DCR 9947).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>The “Compact,” referred to throughout the section, is set forth in § <cite root="7-1101">7-1101</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Designation of Compact Administrator: The Director, Department of Human Resources, was designated Compact Administrator for the District of Columbia by Commissioner’s Order No. 72-241A, dated September 20, 1972. The Department of Human Resources was replaced by the Department of Human Services by Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, dated February 21, 1980.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
