<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1231.05</num>
  <heading>Service planning.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Consumers shall have the right to meaningful participation in the development of their service plans, as well as the opportunity to participate in planning for their transition from one provider to another. Such service planning shall include the right to be informed about one’s own condition and legal status, and of proposed or current services, treatment, therapies, or other available alternatives. In the course of service planning, no individual mental health service or mental health support shall be conditioned upon agreement to accept another service or support.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning at least one year before a consumer transitions into the system of care for adults, or sooner if required under applicable law such as IDEA, a youth’s Individual Plan of Care shall be revised to include a statement regarding the needed transition services for the youth, including, if appropriate, a statement of the interagency responsibilities or any needed linkages with other services and supports.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The opportunities for participation in service planning described in this section shall extend to the consumer’s family members or personal representative if the consumer so requests orally or in writing. Family members or personal representatives who are participating in the consumer’s service planning, and to whom the consumer has authorized the release of information in accordance with Chapter 12 of this title, shall be notified whenever there is a substantial change in the consumer’s services or placement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The consumer may revoke his or her consent to the participation or authorization for notification described in subsection (c) of this section at any time.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Department, or other providers as appropriate, shall be responsible for ensuring that a consumer’s service plan is implemented.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-56">Dec. 18, 2001, D.C. Law 14-56, § 205, 48 DCR 7674</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 205 of Mental Health Service Delivery Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-144, October 23, 2001,  48 DCR 9947).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
