<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1303.05</num>
  <heading>Application by parent or guardian for nonresidential habilitation.</heading>
  <text>Any parent or guardian may apply on behalf of an individual under 14 years of age who is or is believed to have an intellectual disability to any hospital, clinic, facility or community-based service owned or operated by, or under contract with, the District for nonresidential habilitation. Applications shall be made to the Director of the hospital, clinic, or service, or to the Department on Disability Services. If an application is filed with a Director and the Director determines that the particular hospital, clinic, facility or community-based service cannot provide the necessary habilitation, he or she shall refer the parent or guardian to the Department on Disability Services, and the Department on Disability Services shall assist the parent or guardian in locating a facility, hospital, clinic or service which can provide the required habilitation.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 305, 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-264">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 301(d), 54 DCR 818</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 26(g), 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(i), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-1925.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 6-1658.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-264">D.C. Law 16-264</cite> substituted “Department on Disability Services” for “Department of Human Services” throughout the section.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite> substituted “have mental retardation” for “be mentally retarded”.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “an intellectual disability” for “mental retardation” in the first sentence.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 301(d) of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1155).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
