<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1303.08</num>
  <heading>Discharge from commitment upon request by parent or guardian.</heading>
  <text>Individuals committed pursuant to § <cite root="7-1303.04">7-1303.04</cite>(b) or § <cite root="7-1303.06">7-1303.06</cite> shall be discharged if the parent or guardian who petitioned for the commitment requests the individual’s release in writing to the Court and the Court determines, based on consultation with the individual, his or her counsel and the individual’s advocate for a person with an intellectual disability, if one has been appointed, that the individual consents to such release. Such individuals also shall be discharged upon their own request when they have gained competence to make such a decision and have reached their 14th birthday. A hearing may be conducted pursuant to provisions of subchapter IV of this chapter to determine the question of competence.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 308, 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 506(g), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-199">Oct. 17, 2002, D.C. Law 14-199, § 2(d), 49 DCR 7647</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(k), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-1928.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 6-1661.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-199">D.C. Law 14-199</cite> substituted “§ <cite root="7-1303.04">7-1303.04</cite>(b)” for “§ <cite root="7-1303.04">7-1303.04</cite>”.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “individual” for “customer” or variants wherever it appears in the section; and substituted “advocate for a person with an intellectual disability” for “mental retardation advocate” in the first sentence.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 505(g) of Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Temporary Act of 1995 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-253">D.C. Law 10-253</cite>, March 23, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 1652).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 505(g) of the Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-389, December 29, 1994,  42 DCR 197).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(d) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-383, June 12, 2002,  49 DCR 5701).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(d) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-454, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8096).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
