<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1531.09</num>
  <heading>Manner of making, amending, or revoking anatomical gift of decedent’s body or part.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person authorized to make an anatomical gift under § <cite root="7-1531.08">7-1531.08</cite> may make an anatomical gift by a document of gift signed by the person making the gift or by that person’s oral communication that is electronically recorded or is contemporaneously reduced to a record and signed by the individual receiving the oral communication.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (c) of this section, an anatomical gift by a person authorized under § <cite root="7-1531.08">7-1531.08</cite> may be amended or revoked orally or in a record by any member of a prior class who is reasonably available. If more than one member of the prior class is reasonably available, the gift made by a person authorized under § <cite root="7-1531.08">7-1531.08</cite> may be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Amended only if a majority of the reasonably available members agree to the amending of the gift; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Revoked only if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A majority of the reasonably available members agree to the revoking of the gift; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The members of the class described in § <cite root="7-1531.08">7-1531.08</cite>(a)(4) are equally divided as to whether to revoke the gift.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A revocation under subsection (b) of this section is effective only if, before an incision has been made to remove a part from the donor’s body or before invasive procedures have begun to prepare the recipient, the procurement organization, transplant hospital, or physician or technician knows of the revocation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-145">Apr. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-145, § 10, 55 DCR 2532</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="7-1531.07">7-1531.07</cite> and § <cite root="7-1531.10">7-1531.10</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 10 of the Revised Uniform Anatomical Gift Act (2006).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
