<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1008</num>
  <heading>White Cane Safety Day.</heading>
  <text>Each year, the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall take suitable public notice of October 15th as White Cane Safety Day. He shall issue a proclamation commenting upon the significance of the white cane, and calling upon the citizens of the District of Columbia to observe the provisions of this chapter, to be aware of the presence of persons with disabilities in the community, to keep safe and functional for persons with disabilities the streets, highways, sidewalks, walkways, public buildings, public facilities, other public places, places of public accommodation, amusement, and resort, and other places to which the public is invited, and to offer assistance to persons with disabilities upon appropriate occasions.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-515" type="History">Oct. 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 972, Pub. L. 92-515, § 7</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 25(f), 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1708.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1507.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite> substituted “persons with disabilities” for “disabled persons” and “the disabled”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
