<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1131.17</num>
  <heading>Youth behavioral health program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>As of October 1, 2012, there is established within the Department, and shall be made available to all child development facilities, public schools, and public charter schools, a program that, at a minimum, provides participants with the tools needed to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Identify students who may have unmet behavioral health needs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Refer identified students to appropriate services for behavioral health screenings and behavioral health assessments.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Starting October 1, 2014, completion of the program shall be mandatory for all:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Teachers in public schools and public charter schools;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Principals in public schools and public charter schools; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Staff employed by child development facilities, who are subject to training or continuing education requirements pursuant to licensing regulations.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In addition to the individuals described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Mayor may determine through rulemaking other individuals who shall be required to complete the program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Department may make the program available to other interested individuals.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department shall keep a record of all participants who complete the program and shall provide the participants with written proof of completion.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If so approved by the Office of the State Superintendent for Education, the program may count towards professional development credits.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-56" type="History" path="§115b">Dec. 18, 2001, D.C. Law 14-56, § 115b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-141" type="History">as added June 7, 2012, D.C. Law 19-141, § 402(b), 59 DCR 3083</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, see § 7004 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, see § 7004 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, § 601, see § 4112 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, § 601, see § 4112 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 4111 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle K of Title IV of the act may be cited as the “South Capitol Street Memorial Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> originally provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite>, § 7004, provided that the applicability of only §§ 302(b)(1), 304, and 502(a) are contingent upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7016 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> provided that Sections 7001, 7004, 7007, 7009, 7011, and 7015 of the act shall apply as of June 19, 2012.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>, § 4112, provided that §§ 302(b)(1)(A) and (C) and 304(b)(1)(D) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> shall apply to public charter schools upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register. Section 302(b)(1)(A) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> added § <cite path="§38-203">38-203</cite>(i)(A-i); Section 302(b)(1)(C) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> added § <cite path="§38-203">38-203</cite>(i)(B-i); and Section 304(b)(1)(D) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> added 5 DCMR § A2103(c)(6).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
