<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-121</num>
  <heading>Mayor’s Council on Physical Fitness, Health, and Nutrition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Mayor’s Council on Physical Fitness, Health, and Nutrition (“Mayor’s Council”) with the mission to improve the health and wellness of all District residents through physical activity and healthy eating.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The following individuals, or their designees, shall be members of the Mayor’s Council:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The Chancellor of District of Columbia Public Schools;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The Chair of the Public Charter School Board;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Department of Aging; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Director of the Department of Health;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall designate one of the members listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection to serve as the chairperson. The chairperson shall serve at the pleasure of the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In addition to the members listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Mayor’s Council shall include:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Five members appointed by the Council of the District of Columbia; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Up to 14 members appointed by the Mayor.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>All members appointed pursuant to this paragraph shall:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Be residents of the District of Columbia;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Have experience related to physical fitness, health, or nutrition;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Serve 3-year terms; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Serve without compensation.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor’s Council shall meet no fewer than 2 times per year. The time and place of its meetings shall be provided by the executive committee, established by <cite path="§7-126">§ 7-126</cite>; provided, that the Department of Health shall convene at least 2 meetings per year.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-58" type="History" path="§2">Dec. 2, 2011, D.C. Law 19-58, § 2, 58 DCR 8969</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§7-126">§ 7-126</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
