<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1303.09</num>
  <heading>Transfer of individual from one facility to another.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department on Disability Services may recommend to the Court that an individual committed to the facility be transferred to another facility if the Department on Disability Services determines that it would be beneficial and consistent with the habilitation needs of the individual to do so. Notice of the recommendation shall be served on the individual, the individual’s counsel, the individual’s parent or guardian who petitioned for the commitment and the individual’s advocate for a person with an intellectual disability, if one has been appointed. If the proposed transfer is determined by the Court to be a transfer to a more restrictive facility, a mandatory hearing shall be conducted promptly in accordance with the procedures established in subchapter IV of this chapter. If the Court determines that the proposed transfer would be to a less restrictive facility, a Court hearing shall be held only if the individual, the individual’s parent or guardian, or, in the case of an individual committed under § <cite path="§7-1304.06a">7-1304.06a</cite>, the District requests a hearing by petitioning the Court in writing within 10 days of being notified by the Court of its determination. The hearing shall be held promptly following the request for the hearing. In deciding whether to authorize the transfer, the Court shall consider whether the proposed facility can provide the necessary habilitation and whether it would be the lease restrictive means of providing such habilitation. In the case of an individual committed under § <cite path="§7-1304.06a">7-1304.06a</cite>, the Court shall also consider whether the proposed placement can provide sufficient supervision or security to prevent the individual from causing injury to others as a result of the individual’s intellectual disability. Due consideration shall be given to the relationship of the individual to his or her family, guardian, or friends so as to maintain relationships and encourage visits beneficial to the relationship.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An individual admitted to a facility can be transferred to another facility if the individual consents to the transfer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit transfer of an individual to a health care facility without prior Court approval in an emergency situation when the life of the individual is in danger. In such circumstances, consent of the individual, or parent or guardian who sought the commitment shall be obtained prior to the transfer. In the event the individual cannot consent and there is no person who can be reasonably contacted, such transfer may be made upon the authorization of the  Department on Disability Services, with notice promptly given to the parent or guardian. Consent of the individual, parent, or  guardian is not required if the District sought commitment. The parent, guardian, counsel for the individual, and advocate for a person with an intellectual disability shall be notified promptly of the transfer.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 309, 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 506(h), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 14(a), 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-199" type="History">Oct. 17, 2002, D.C. Law 14-199, § 2(e), 49 DCR 7647</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-264" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 301(f), 54 DCR 818</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(l), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1929.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1662.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-199">D.C. Law 14-199</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-264">D.C. Law 16-264</cite>, in subsecs. (a) and (c), substituted “Department on Disability Services” for “Department of Human Services”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “advocate for a person with an intellectual disability” for “mental retardation advocate” in the second sentence of (a) and in the last sentence of (c); and substituted “intellectual disability” for “mental retardation” in the next to last sentence of (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 505(h), (i)) of Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Temporary Act of 1995 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-253">D.C. Law 10-253</cite>, March 23, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 1652).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 505(h) and (i) of the Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-389, December 29, 1994,  42 DCR 197).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-383, June 12, 2002,  49 DCR 5701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-454, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8096).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 301(f) of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1155).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
