<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1305.15</num>
  <heading>Coordination of services for dually diagnosed individuals.</heading>
  <text>If an individual is committed by the Court to DDS pursuant to this chapter or committed by the Court to the Department of Mental Health pursuant to subchapter IV of Chapter 5 of Title 21, or if an individual is temporarily placed with DDS pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1303.12a">7-1303.12a</cite> during the pendency of commitment proceedings, and DDS or the Department of Mental Health has reason to believe that the committed individual or the individual temporarily placed with DDS pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1303.12a">7-1303.12a</cite> is dually diagnosed as having both mental illness and an intellectual disability, DDS and the Department of Mental Health shall collaborate in assessing the individual and shall jointly provide appropriate supports and services for the individual.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137" type="History" path="§515">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 515</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-199" type="History">as added Oct. 17, 2002, D.C. Law 14-199, § 2(r), 49 DCR 7647</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-264" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 301(n), 54 DCR 818</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(tt), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-264">D.C. Law 16-264</cite> substituted “DDS” for “MRDDA”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “an intellectual disability” for “mental retardation.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§7-1305.15">7-1305.15</cite>, see § 2(p) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-383, June 12, 2002,  49 DCR 5701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§7-1305.15">7-1305.15</cite>, see § 2(r) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-454, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8096).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 301(n) of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1155).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
