<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1304.06</num>
  <heading>Hearings conducted in informal manner; procedural rights at hearing.</heading>
  <text>Except as provided in § <cite path="§7-1304.06a">7-1304.06a</cite>, hearings shall be conducted in as informal a manner as may be consistent with orderly procedure. Individuals whose admission has been questioned or respondents have the right to be present during hearings and to testify, but shall not be compelled to testify, and shall be so advised by the Court. They shall have the right to call witnesses and present evidence, and to cross-examine opposing witnesses. The presence of the respondent may be waived only if the Court finds that the respondent has knowingly and voluntarily waived his or her right to be present, or if the Court determines that the respondent is unable to be present by virtue of his or her physical disability.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 406, 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-199" type="History">Oct. 17, 2002, D.C. Law 14-199, § 2(k), 49 DCR 7647</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(v), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1946.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1673.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-199">D.C. Law 14-199</cite> substituted “Except as provided in § <cite path="§7-1304.06a">7-1304.06a</cite>, hearings” for “Hearings”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “physical disability” for “physically handicapping condition” at the end of the last sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(k) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-383, June 12, 2002,  49 DCR 5701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§7-1304.06a">7-1304.06a</cite>, see § 2(l) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-383, June 12, 2002,  49 DCR 5701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(k) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-454, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8096).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§7-1304.06a">7-1304.06a</cite>, see § 2(l) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-454, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8096).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
