<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1303.12a</num>
  <heading>Placement pending petition and commitment proceedings.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In the case of an individual found incompetent in a criminal case, the District shall have no more than 30 days from the date on which the finding is made that the individual is incompetent and not likely to gain competence in the foreseeable future in which to file a petition pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1303.04">7-1303.04</cite>(b-1). For extraordinary cause shown, the Court may extend the period of time within which the petition must be filed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In the case of an individual found incompetent in a criminal case prior to October 17, 2002, the District shall have 60 days following October 17, 2002, in which to file a petition pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1303.04">7-1303.04</cite>(b-1) for commitment of an individual who is committed pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1303.04">7-1303.04</cite>(a), or of an individual whom the Court, within 365 days prior to October 17, 2002, found incompetent and not likely to gain competency in the foreseeable future.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>While awaiting the District’s decision pursuant to subsection (a) of this section and during the pendency of any resultant commitment proceedings, the Court may order the individual placed with DDS for placement in a setting that DDS preliminarily determines can provide habilitation services consistent with the individual’s needs and supervision or security sufficient to prevent the individual from causing injury to others as a result of his or her intellectual disability.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the Court or DDS places the person in a setting that does not meet the definition of a facility contained in § <cite path="§7-1301.03">7-1301.03</cite>(13), the hearing pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1304.06a">7-1304.06a</cite> shall commence no later than 90 days from the date on which the finding is made that the individual is incompetent and not likely to gain competence in the foreseeable future. If the hearing does not commence before the expiration of the 90-day time period, the Court shall place the individual with the DDS for placement in a facility that does satisfy § <cite path="§7-1301.03">7-1301.03</cite>(13) and that DDS preliminarily determines can provide habilitation services consistent with the individual’s needs and supervision or security sufficient to prevent the individual from causing injury to others as a result of the individual’s intellectual disability.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 312a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-199" type="History">as added Oct. 17, 2002, D.C. Law 14-199, § 2(h), 49 DCR 7647</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-264" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 301(g), 54 DCR 818</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(p), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1303.12">7-1303.12</cite>, § <cite path="§7-1305.15">7-1305.15</cite>, and § <cite path="§24-531.07">24-531.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-264">D.C. Law 16-264</cite> substituted “DDS” for “MRDDA” throughout the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “intellectual disability” for “mental retardation” at the end of (c) and (d).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 301(g) of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1155).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
