<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1305.12</num>
  <heading>Maintenance of records; information considered privileged and confidential; access; contents.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Complete records for each individual shall be maintained and shall be readily available to professional persons and to the staff workers who are directly involved with the particular individual and to the Department on Disability Services without divulging the identity of the individual. All information contained in an individual’s records shall be considered privileged and confidential. The individual’s parent or guardian who petitioned for the commitment, the individual’s counsel, the individual’s advocate for a person with an intellectual disability and any person properly authorized in writing by the individual, if such individual is capable of giving such authorization, shall be permitted access to the individual’s records. These records shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Identification data, including the individual’s legal status;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The individual’s history, including but not limited to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Family data, educational background and employment record;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Prior medical history, both physical and mental, including prior institutionalization;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The individual’s grievances, if any;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An inventory of the individual’s life skills;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A record of each physical examination which describes the results of the examination;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A copy of the individual habilitation plan; and any modifications thereto and an appropriate summary which will guide and assist the professional and staff employees in implementing the individual’s program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The findings made in periodic reviews of the habilitation plan which findings shall include an analysis of the successes and failures of the habilitation program and shall direct whatever modifications are necessary;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>A medication history and status;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>A summary of each significant contact by a professional person with an individual;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>A summary of the individual’s response to his or her program, prepared and recorded at least monthly, by the professional person designated pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1305.04">7-1305.04</cite>(c) to supervise the individual’s habilitation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>A monthly summary of the extent and nature of the individual’s work activities and the effect of such activity upon the individual’s progress along the habilitation plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>A signed order by a professional person, as set forth in § <cite path="§7-1305.10">7-1305.10</cite>(b), for any physical restraints;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>A description of any extraordinary incident or accident in the facility involving the individual, to be entered by a staff member noting personal knowledge of the incident or accident or other source of information, including any reports of investigations of individual’s mistreatment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>A summary of family visits and contacts;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>A summary of attendance and leaves from the facility; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>A record of any seizures, illnesses, treatments thereof, and immunizations.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, information contained in an individual’s record may be used or disclosed for the purposes of and in accordance with Chapter 2A of this title [§ <cite path="§7-251">7-251</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 512, 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 506(w), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-264" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 301(m), 54 DCR 818</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-273" type="History">Dec. 4, 2010, D.C. Law 18-273, § 205, 57 DCR 7171</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(qq), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1371.06">4-1371.06</cite> and § <cite path="§16-1054">16-1054</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1972.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1692.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-264">D.C. Law 16-264</law-cite>, in the lead-in text, substituted “Department on Disability Services” for “Department of Human Services”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-273">D.C. Law 18-273</law-cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</law-cite> substituted “individual” for “customer” or variants throughout the section; and substituted “advocate for a person with an intellectual disability” for “mental retardation advocate” in the third sentence of the introductory language of (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 505(w) of Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Temporary Act of 1995 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-253">D.C. Law 10-253</law-cite>, March 23, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 1652).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disclosure of Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities Fatality Review Committee and Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities Incident Management and Investigations Unit Information and Records Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-143">D.C. Law 16-143</law-cite>, July 25, 2006, law notification  53 DCR 6686).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 402(j) of the Omnibus Budget Support Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-44, April 28, 1995,  42 DCR 2217) and § 506(w) of the Omnibus Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-124, July 27, 1995,  42 DCR 4160).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disclosure of the Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities Fatality Review Committee and Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities Incident Management and Investigations Unit Information and Records Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-363, April 26, 2006,  53 DCR 3628).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 301(m) of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1155).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 205 of Data-Sharing and Information Coordination Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-530, August 6, 2010,  57 DCR 8099).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 205 of Data-Sharing and Information Coordination Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-582, October 20, 2010,  57 DCR 10118).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</law-cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
