<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1303.11</num>
  <heading>Payment for habilitation and care.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person with an intellectual disability, or the father, mother, spouse, or adult child of a person with an intellectual disability, who receives habilitation, care, or both from the District pursuant to this chapter, shall pay to the District the costs of habilitation, care, or both received by the person with an intellectual disability if the person with an intellectual disability, or the father, mother, spouse, or adult child of the person with an intellectual disability, or the estate of the person with an intellectual disability is able to pay the costs of habilitation, care, or both received.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If any person made liable by subsection (a) of this section does not pay the costs of habilitation, care, or both received by the person with an intellectual disability, the court shall issue to the liable person a citation to show cause why that person should not be adjudged to pay a portion or all of the expenses of habilitation, care, or both of the person with an intellectual disability. The citation shall be served at least 10 days before the show cause hearing. If, upon the hearing, it appears to the court that the person made liable by subsection (a) of this section does not have sufficient resources to pay the full costs of habilitation, care, or both received by the person with an intellectual disability, the court may order the payment of a reasonable amount of the costs of habilitation, care, or both received based on the liable person’s resources. The court may order the liable person to make payments quarterly, monthly, or at any other interval deemed appropriate by the court. The order may be enforced against any property of the liable person as if the order were an order for temporary alimony in a divorce case.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may examine, under oath, the father, mother, spouse, adult child, and the executor of the estate of the person with an intellectual disability who receives habilitation, care, or both if the person lives in the District of Columbia, to ascertain the person’s ability, or the ability of the estate, to pay the full costs or contribute to the costs of habilitation, care, or both of the person with an intellectual disability.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, effective January 1, 2012, a person with an intellectual disability who is otherwise eligible to receive supports and services from the District pursuant to this chapter must either pay the full cost of such supports and services directly to the provider or become District Medicaid-eligible and maintain District Medicaid eligibility in order to receive supports and services under this chapter from a District Medicaid-eligible provider. This requirement shall not apply to a person:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Who is a former resident of Forest Haven;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Whose needs cannot reasonably be met by a District Medicaid provider;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Who is eligible for enrollment in the D.C. Healthcare Alliance; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Whose representative payee for the purposes of Social Security benefits is the Department of Disability Services or a provider agency who is contracted with the District to provide supports and services for that person, if the reason the person lost Medicaid eligibility is due to a failure by the representative payee.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department of Disability Services shall work with and support the person to become District Medicaid-eligible and to maintain District Medicaid eligibility, and the person and his or her representatives, estate, or both shall fully cooperate in such efforts.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 311, 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 506(i), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 5002(a), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(n), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-1931.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 6-1664.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> added subsec. (d).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “an intellectual disability” for “mental retardation” wherever it appears in the section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 505(j) of Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Temporary Act of 1995 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-253">D.C. Law 10-253</cite>, March 23, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 1652).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4(a) of Human Services Spending Reduction Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-29">D.C. Law 11-29</cite>, July 25, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 4002).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 505(j) of the Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-389, December 29, 1994,  42 DCR 197).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(a) of the Human Services Spending Reduction Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-35, April 11, 1995,  42 DCR 1834) and § 4(a) of the Human Services Spending Reduction Congressional Recess Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-104, July 21, 1995,  42 DCR 4014).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 506(i) of the Omnibus Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-124, July 27, 1995,  42 DCR 4160).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <annotation>Short title: Section 5001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle A of title V of the act may be cited as “Intellectual Disability Services Medicaid Maximization Reform Amendment Act of 2011”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
