<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1303.03</num>
  <heading>Application by individual for out-patient nonresidential habilitation.</heading>
  <text>Any individual 14 years of age or older who has an intellectual disability, may have an intellectual disability, or has been diagnosed with an intellectual disability may apply to any hospital, clinic or facility, or other community-based service owned or operated by, or under contract with, the District for out-patient nonresidential habilitation. Applications shall be made to the Director of the hospital, clinic, facility or service, or to the Department on Disability Services. If an application is filed with a Director and the Director determines that the particular hospital, clinic, facility or community-based service cannot provide the necessary habilitation, he or she shall refer the individual to the Department on Disability Services, and the Department on Disability Services shall assist the individual in locating a facility, hospital, clinic or service which can provide the necessary habilitation.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 303, 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-264" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 301(b), 54 DCR 818</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 26(e), 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(g), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1923.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1656.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-264">D.C. Law 16-264</cite> substituted “Department on Disability Services” for “Department of Human Services” throughout the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite> substituted “has mental retardation, may have mental retardation, or has been diagnosed with mental retardation” for “is, may be, or has been diagnosed mentally retarded”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “an intellectual disability” for “mental retardation” wherever it appears in the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 301(b) of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1155).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
