<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1304.01</num>
  <heading>Commencement of commitment proceedings; filing of written petition.</heading>
  <text>Proceedings for the commitment of an individual pursuant to subchapter III of this chapter shall be commenced by the filing of a written petition with the Court in the manner and form prescribed by the Court. The petition may be filed by a parent or guardian with respect to an individual who is or is believed to have an intellectual disability. If filed by the parent or guardian, a copy of the petition shall be served on the respondent and on his or her counsel, retained or appointed pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1304.02">7-1304.02</cite>. The petition may be filed by the District in the case of an individual with an intellectual disability found incompetent in a criminal case. If filed by the District, a copy of the petition shall be served on the individual, the individual’s counsel, the individual’s parent or guardian, and the individual’s advocate for a person with an intellectual disability.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 401, 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-199" type="History">Oct. 17, 2002, D.C. Law 14-199, § 2(i), 49 DCR 7647</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 26(j), 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(r), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1304.03">7-1304.03</cite> and § <cite path="§24-531.02">24-531.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1941.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1668.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-199">D.C. Law 14-199</cite> added the last sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite> substituted “have mental retardation” for “be mentally retarded”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “an intellectual disability” for “mental retardation” in the second and fourth sentences; and substituted “individual’s advocate for a person with an intellectual disability” for “individual’s mental retardation advocate” in the last sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(i) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-383, June 12, 2002,  49 DCR 5701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(i) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-454, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8096).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
