<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1305.01</num>
  <heading>Habilitation and care; habilitation program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To the extent that appropriated funds are available to carry out the purposes of this chapter, no District resident with an intellectual disability shall be denied habilitation, care, or both suited to the person’s needs regardless of the person’s age, degree of intellectual disability, or other disabling condition.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To the extent that appropriated funds are available to carry out the purposes of this chapter, each individual shall be provided a habilitation program that will maximize the individual’s human abilities, enhance the individual’s ability to cope with the individual’s environment, and create a reasonable opportunity for progress toward the goal of independent living.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, no individual subject to commitment pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1304.06a">7-1304.06a</cite> shall be denied habilitation, care, or both suited to the person’s needs, regardless of the person’s age, degree of intellectual disability, or other disabling condition.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, an individual subject to commitment pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1304.06a">7-1304.06a</cite> shall be provided a habilitation program that will maximize the person’s human abilities, enhance the person’s ability to cope with the person’s environment, and create a reasonable opportunity for progress toward the goal of independent living.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding the availability of an appropriation to carry out the purposes of this chapter in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, effective January 1, 2012, a District resident with an intellectual disability who is otherwise eligible to receive supports and services from the District pursuant to this chapter must either pay the full cost of such supports and services directly to the provider or become District Medicaid-eligible and maintain District Medicaid eligibility in order to receive supports and services under this chapter from a District Medicaid-eligible provider. This requirement shall not apply to a person:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Who is a former resident of Forest Haven;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Whose needs cannot reasonably be met by a District Medicaid provider;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Who is eligible for enrollment in the D.C. Healthcare Alliance; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Whose representative payee for the purposes of Social Security benefits is the Department of Disability Services or a provider agency who is contracted with the District to provide supports and services for that person, if the reason the person lost Medicaid eligibility is due to a failure by the representative payee.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department of Disability Services shall work with and support the person to become District Medicaid-eligible and to maintain District Medicaid eligibility, and the person and his or her representatives, estate, or both shall fully cooperate in such efforts.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 501, 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 9, 45 DCR 745</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-199">Oct. 17, 2002, D.C. Law 14-199, § 2(p), 49 DCR 7647</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 5002(b), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(dd), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 55, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-1961.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 6-1681.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-199">D.C. Law 14-199</cite> added subsecs. (c) and (d).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> added subsec. (e).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “an intellectual disability” for “mental retardation” in (a) and in the introductory language of (e)(1); substituted “degree of intellectual disability, or other disabling condition” for “degree of retardation, or handicapping condition” in (a) and (c); and substituted “individual” for “customer” or variants wherever it appears in (b).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 505(m) of Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Temporary Act of 1995 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-253">D.C. Law 10-253</cite>, March 23, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 1652).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4(e) of Human Services Spending Reduction Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-29">D.C. Law 11-29</cite>, July 25, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 4002).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 505(m) of the Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-389, December 29, 1994,  42 DCR 197).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(e) of the Human Services Spending Reduction Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-35, April 11, 1995,  42 DCR 1834) and § 4(e) of the Human Services Spending Reduction Congressional Recess Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-104, July 21, 1995,  42 DCR 4014).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 506(m) of the Omnibus Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-124, July 27, 1995,  42 DCR 4160).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 506(n) of the Omnibus Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-124, July 27, 1995,  42 DCR 4160).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(p) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-383, June 12, 2002,  49 DCR 5701).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(p) of Civil Commitment of Citizens with Mental Retardation Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-454, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8096).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 17(cc) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “Rights of Persons with Intellectual Disabilities” for “Rights of Mentally Retarded Persons” in the heading of subchapter 5.</text>
      <text>Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
