<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1303.14</num>
  <heading>Rules and regulations governing respite care.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department on Disability Services shall promulgate rules and regulations governing the provision of respite care for persons with intellectual disabilities. These shall provide that periods of respite care shall not exceed 42 days in a 12-month period without specific authorization by the Court after a hearing conducted in accordance with subchapter IV of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Should any person be detained for respite care for a period exceeding 42 days in a 12-month period without specific authorization by the Court after a hearing conducted in accordance with subchapter IV of this chapter, he or she shall be promptly discharged.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-137" type="History" path="§314">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-137, § 314, 25 DCR 5094</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-264" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 301(h), 54 DCR 818</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 26(i), 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 17(q), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mental health information, refusal or limitation on disclosures, see § <cite path="§7-1202.06">7-1202.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Rights of mentally retarded citizens, discharge following requests by parent, guardian or person committed, hearings, see § <cite path="§7-1303.08">7-1303.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Rights of mentally retarded citizens, effective date of chapter, see § <cite path="§7-1306.05">7-1306.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1934.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1667.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-264">D.C. Law 16-264</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “Department on Disability Services” for “Department of Human Services”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “persons with mental retardation” for “mentally retarded persons”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</law-cite> substituted “intellectual disabilities” for “mental retardation” in the first sentence of (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 301(h) of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1155).</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The Department of Human Resources was replaced by the Department of Human Services pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, dated February 21, 1980.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</law-cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
