<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1402</num>
  <heading>Transfers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The functions, real and personal property, personnel, unexpended balances of appropriations, and records of the Public Benefit Corporation shall be transferred to the Department of Health.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any monies remaining in the Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation Fund after July 12, 2001, shall revert to the General Fund to the credit of the Department of Health.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department of Health shall recognize collective bargaining representatives that have been duly certified by the District of Columbia Public Employees Relations Board and shall assume and be bound by all existing collective bargaining agreements entered into by the Public Benefit Corporation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Every employee of the Public Benefit Corporation shall be transferred to the Department of Health. All employees so transferred shall be under the direction and control of the Director of the Department of Health or that director’s designee or designees. Transferred employees shall retain the same rights and privileges that they had as employees of the Public Benefit Corporation before July 12, 2001, and shall not obtain any additional rights or privileges as a result of the transfer. They shall have all the duties and responsibilities that they had as employees of the Public Benefit Corporation in addition to whatever duties and responsibilities they acquire as employees of the Department of Health. Transferred employees shall constitute a separate competitive area within the Department of Health for purposes of reductions in force only pursuant to § <cite path="§1-624.08">1-624.08</cite>, and Chapter 24 of the District of Columbia Personnel Manual. Lesser competitive areas may be established by the personnel authority for these employees. The Mayor shall be the personnel authority for all employees of the Public Benefit Corporation who are transferred to the Department of Health, except that the personnel authority for accounting, budget, and financial management personnel who are transferred shall continue to be the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-18" type="History">July 12, 2001, D.C. Law 14-18, § 4, 48 DCR 4047</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
