<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1531.22</num>
  <heading>Facilitation of anatomical gift from decedent whose body is under jurisdiction of Chief Medical Examiner.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The relationship between the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner and a procurement organization shall be governed by a memorandum of understanding between the Chief Medical Examiner and the procurement organization, which shall contain protocols to resolve any conflicts between the Chief Medical Examiner and the procurement organization.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The time period within which a recovery must be performed to be compatible with the preservation of the part or parts for the purpose of transplantation, therapy, research, or education shall be medically determined, based on the best practices for the recovery of parts, pursuant to the pertinent protocols in the memorandum of understanding.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon request of a procurement organization pursuant to an anatomical gift, the Chief Medical Examiner shall release to the procurement organization the name, contact information, and available medical and social history of a decedent whose body is under the jurisdiction of the Chief Medical Examiner.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the decedent’s body or part is medically suitable for transplantation, therapy, research, or education, as determined by the appropriate procurement organization, the Chief Medical Examiner shall release post-mortem examination results to the procurement organization.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The procurement organization and any other recipient may make a subsequent disclosure of the post-mortem examination results or other information received from the Chief Medical Examiner only if relevant to transplantation, therapy, research, or education.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Chief Medical Examiner may conduct a medicolegal examination by reviewing all medical records, laboratory test results, x-rays, other diagnostic results, and other information that any person possesses about a donor or prospective donor whose body is under the jurisdiction of the Chief Medical Examiner which the Chief Medical Examiner determines may be relevant to the investigation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person that has any information requested by the Chief Medical Examiner pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall provide that information as expeditiously as possible to allow the Chief Medical Examiner to conduct the medicolegal investigation within a period compatible with the preservation of parts for the purpose of transplantation, therapy, research, or education.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If an anatomical gift has been or might be made of a part of a decedent whose body is under the jurisdiction of the Chief Medical Examiner and the Chief Medical Examiner determines that a post-mortem examination is not required, or the Chief Medical Examiner determines that a post-mortem examination is required but that the recovery of the part that is the subject of an anatomical gift will not interfere with the examination, the Chief Medical Examiner and procurement organization shall cooperate in the timely removal of the part from the decedent for the purpose of transplantation, therapy, research, or education.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If an anatomical gift of a part from the decedent under the jurisdiction of the Chief Medical Examiner has been or might be made, but the Chief Medical Examiner initially believes that the recovery of the part could interfere with the post-mortem investigation into the decedent’s cause or manner of death, the Chief Medical Examiner shall consult with the procurement organization, or a physician or technician designated by the procurement organization, and, at the discretion of the Chief Medical Examiner, with an attending physician, about the proposed recovery within a period compatible with the preservation of the part for the appropriate purpose.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>After consultation, the Chief Medical Examiner may allow or deny the recovery of the part.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Chief Medical Examiner shall allow recovery of a part if the Chief Medical Examiner determines that recovery would not interfere with the post-mortem investigation into the decedent’s cause or manner of death.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Following the consultation required under subsection (f) of this section, if the Chief Medical Examiner has not been able to expeditiously determine whether to allow recovery of the part, the Chief Medical Examiner, or designee, at the request of the procurement organization, may attend the removal procedure for the part before making a final determination not to allow the procurement organization to recover the part.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>During the removal procedure, the Chief Medical Examiner, or designee, may allow recovery of the part by the procurement organization to proceed, or, if the Chief Medical Examiner, or designee, reasonably believes that the part may be involved in determining the decedent’s cause or manner of death, deny recovery by the procurement organization.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If, during the removal procedure, the physician engaged by the procurement organization to recover the part discovers evidence that indicates that the cause of death may be suspicious, the physician shall immediately inform the Chief Medical Examiner of this information and shall not continue or undertake any procedures that would compromise this evidence without the approval of the Chief Medical Examiner.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in the memorandum of understanding described in subsection (a) of this section or a protocol pursuant thereto, if the Chief Medical Examiner, or designee, denies recovery under subsection (g) of this section, the Chief Medical Examiner, or designee, shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Explain in a record the specific reasons for not allowing recovery of the part;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Include the specific reasons in the records of the Chief Medical Examiner; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide a record with the specific reasons to the procurement organization.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>If the Chief Medical Examiner, or designee, allows recovery of a part, the procurement organization, upon request, shall cause the physician or technician who removes the part to provide the Chief Medical Examiner with a record describing the condition of the part, a biopsy, a photograph, and any other information and observations that would assist in the post-mortem examination.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-145" type="History">Apr. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-145, § 23, 55 DCR 2532</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1531.13">7-1531.13</cite> and § <cite path="§7-1531.21">7-1531.21</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 23 of the Revised Uniform Anatomical Gift Act (2006).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
