<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-151</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Department of Public Health.</heading>
  <text>There is established in the Executive Branch of the Government of the District of Columbia a Department of Public Health, which shall have as its responsibility the planning, development and implementation of the delivery of health care services to all District of Columbia residents.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-182" type="History">Mar. 13, 1992, D.C. Law 9-182, § 2, 39 DCR 8203</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-131.</annotation>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">Pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1996 each of the functions assigned, and authorities delegated to the Director of the Department of Human Services as set forth in Sections III. (K), (L), and (P), of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986, dated January 3, 1987.</text>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">The administrative and management support functions in the Department of Human Services as set forth in Sections III. (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), and (F), of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986, dated January 3, 1987, that relate to the functions set forth in section V. (A)(1) above were transferred to the Department of Health.</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment and Appointments — Mayor’s Bioterrorism Preparedness and Response Program Advisory Committee, see Mayor’s Order 2002-77, May 3, 2002 ( 49 DCR 4137).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment and Appointments — Mayor’s Hospital Bioterrorism Preparedness Planning Advisory Committee, see Mayor’s Order 2002-78, May 3, 2002 ( 49 DCR 4143).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Amendment of Mayor’s Order 2002-77, dated 4-5-02, Establishment and Appointments — Mayor’s Bioterrorism Preparedness and Response Program Advisory Committee, see Mayor’s Order 2002-145, August 30, 2002 ( 49 DCR 8411).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Amendment of Mayor’s Order 2002-78, dated 4-15-02, Establishment and Appointments — Mayor’s Hospital Bioterrorism Preparedness, see Mayor’s Order 2002-147, August 30, 2002 ( 49 DCR 8415).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
