<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-152</num>
  <heading>Organization of the Department of Public Health.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to <cite path="1|3|VI">subchapter VI of Chapter 3 of Title 1</cite>, the Mayor shall prepare and transmit to the Council a reorganization plan establishing a Department of Public Health no later than October 1, 1993.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The reorganization plan establishing the Department of Public Health shall have, at a minimum, all functions, powers and duties of the Commission on Public Health, including supportive services provided to the Commission on Public Health by the Department of Human Services’ Management and Support Services Division.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may prepare and transmit to the Council a reorganization plan for the remaining functions of the Department of Human Services at the same time as the reorganization plan establishing the Department of Public Health is transmitted to the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The reorganization plan establishing the Department of Public Health shall become effective no later than October 1, 1994.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-182" type="History" path="§3">Mar. 13, 1992, D.C. Law 9-182, § 3, 39 DCR 8203</annotation>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">Pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1996 each of the functions assigned, and authorities delegated to the Director of the Department of Human Services as set forth in Sections III. (K), (L), and (P), of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986, dated January 3, 1987.</text>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">The administrative and management support functions in the Department of Human Services as set forth in Sections III. (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), and (F), of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986, dated January 3, 1987, that relate to the functions set forth in section V. (A)(I) above were transferred to the Department of Health.</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-132.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
