<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1605</num>
  <heading>Confidentiality of medical records and information.</heading>
  <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this section, the Director shall use the records incident to a case of HIV infection or AIDS reported under this subchapter for statistical and public-health purposes only. Identifying information contained in these records shall be disclosed only when essential to safeguard the physical health of others. No person shall otherwise disclose identifying information derived from these records unless:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The person about whom the record pertains gives his or her prior written permission; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A court finds, upon clear and convincing evidence, after having granted the person reported an opportunity to contest the disclosure, that disclosure:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is essential to safeguard the physical health of others; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Would provide evidence probative of guilt or innocence in a criminal prosecution.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-121" type="History">June 10, 1986, D.C. Law 6-121, § 6, 33 DCR 2451</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-273" type="History">Dec. 4, 2010, D.C. Law 18-273, § 206, 57 DCR 7171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2805.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-273">D.C. Law 18-273</cite> rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “The provisions of the Preventive Health Services Amendments Act of 1985 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 6-83">D.C. Law 6-83</cite>), pertaining to the confidentiality of medical records and information on persons with AIDS, shall be applicable to this chapter.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 206 of Data-Sharing and Information Coordination Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-530, August 6, 2010,  57 DCR 8099).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 206 of Data-Sharing and Information Coordination Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-582, October 20, 2010,  57 DCR 10118).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to Law 6-121, see Mayor’s Order 86-171, September 30, 1986.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-121">D.C. Law 6-121</cite>, the “AIDS Health-Care Response Act of 1986”, see Mayor’s Order 2000-55, March 29, 2000 ( 47 DCR 4735).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
