<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1671.03</num>
  <heading>Restrictions on use of medical marijuana.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The maximum amount of medical marijuana that any qualifying patient or caregiver may possess at any moment is 2 ounces of dried medical marijuana; provided, that the Mayor, through rulemaking, may increase the quantity of dried medical marijuana that may be possessed up to 4 ounces; and shall promulgate through rulemaking limits on medical marijuana of a form, other than dried.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Medical marijuana shall not be administered by or to a qualifying patient anywhere other than the qualifying patient’s residence, if permitted, or at a medical treatment facility when receiving medical care for a qualifying medical condition, if permitted by the facility.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A qualifying patient or caregiver shall not administer medical marijuana at a dispensary or cultivation center.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a qualifying patient shall not use medical marijuana if exposure to the medical marijuana or the medical marijuana smoke would adversely affect the health, safety, or welfare of a minor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A qualifying patient or caregiver shall transport medical marijuana in a labeled container or sealed package in a manner and method established by rulemaking.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter permits a person to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Undertake any task under the influence of medical marijuana when doing so would constitute negligence or professional malpractice; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Operate, navigate, or be in actual physical control of any motor vehicle, aircraft, or motorboat while under the influence of medical marijuana.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The use of medical marijuana as authorized by this chapter and the rules issued pursuant to <cite path="§7-1671.13">§ 7-1671.13</cite> does not create a defense to any crime and does not negate the mens rea element for any crime except to the extent of the voluntary-intoxication defense recognized in District of Columbia law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other law, a person or entity may provide information about the existence or operations of a cultivation center or dispensary to another person pursuant to this law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A qualified patient, caregiver, or an employee of a cultivation center or a dispensary who is stopped by the police upon reasonable suspicion or probable cause that the stopped individual is in possession of marijuana may not be further detained or arrested on this basis alone if the police determine that he or she is in compliance with this chapter and the rules issued pursuant to <cite path="§7-1671.13">§ 7-1671.13</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-315" type="History" path="§4">Feb. 25, 2010, D.C. Law 13-315, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-210" type="History">as added July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-210, § 2, 57 DCR 4798</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
