<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1721.03</num>
  <heading>Purchase or possession of tobacco by minors under 18 years of age; use of false identification.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No person under 18 years of age shall purchase any cigarette or other tobacco product, possess any cigarette or other tobacco product, or attempt to purchase or possess any cigarette or other tobacco product.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to a person under 18 years of age who is handling or transporting cigarettes or other tobacco product under the terms of his or her employment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No person under 18 years of age shall falsely represent his or her age, or possess or present as proof of age an identification document which is in any way fraudulent, for the purpose of purchasing, possessing, or consuming cigarettes or other tobacco product in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any person who violates subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of $50.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any person who violates subsection (b) of this section shall be subject to a civil penalty for each offense of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>$100 the first time the offense or offenses occurred;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>$200 the second time the offense or offenses occurred; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>$300 the third and subsequent times the offense or offenses occurred.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A violation of subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall be a civil infraction for the purposes of Chapter 18 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-1801.01">2-1801.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], may issues rules to increase the amount of the fine for a violation of subsection (a) or (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 7, 1891, 26 Stat. 736, ch. 117, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-189" type="History">as added July 23, 2010, D.C. Law 18-189, § 3(d), 57 DCR 3019</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
