<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-177</num>
  <heading>Certain ordinances of Board of Health legalized — Alteration, amendment, or repeal.</heading>
  <text>The Council of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and empowered, in making regulations under the authority conferred by Congress, to alter, amend, or repeal any of the ordinances of the late Board of Health of said District which were legalized by §§ <cite path="§7-174">7-174</cite> and <cite path="§7-175">7-175</cite>, whenever in its judgment the public interest requires it.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Joint Res. No. 21" path="">Feb. 28, 1889, 30 Stat. 1390, Joint Res. No. 21</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(133) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-114.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-113.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
