<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1756</num>
  <heading>Penalties and remedies.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A manufacturer or wholesale dealer who knowingly fails to comply with any of the provisions of this subchapter, or regulations promulgated pursuant to this subchapter, shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $10,000 for each violation and not to exceed $100,000 for all such violations during any 30-day period.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A retail dealer who knowingly fails to comply with any of the provisions of this subchapter, or regulations promulgated pursuant to this subchapter, shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $5,000 for each violation and not to exceed $25,000 for all such violations during any 30-day period.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each day of violation shall constitute a separate violation and, unless provided otherwise by regulation, the prescribed penalty shall be applicable to each separate violation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to any penalty prescribed by subsection (a) of this section, any corporation, partnership, sole proprietor, limited partnership, or association engaged in the manufacture of cigarettes that knowingly makes a false certification pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1754">7-1754</cite> shall be subject to a civil penalty of at least $75,000 and not to exceed $250,000 for each such false certification.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to any other remedy provided by law, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia may file a civil action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for a violation of this subchapter, which may include a petition for injunctive relief and the recovery of costs or damages.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Law enforcement personnel or duly authorized representatives of the Mayor may seize and take possession of cigarettes that have not been marked in the manner required by § <cite path="§7-1754">7-1754</cite>(b). The seized cigarettes shall be turned over to the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, and shall be forfeited to the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Cigarettes seized pursuant to this subsection shall be destroyed; provided, that before the destruction of any cigarette seized, the true holder of the trademark rights in the cigarette brand shall be permitted to inspect the cigarette.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-157" type="History" path="§7">May 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-157, § 7, 55 DCR 3703</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1755">7-1755</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
