<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1703</num>
  <heading>Smoking restrictions.</heading>
  <text>Smoking shall be prohibited in the following:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Any elevator, except in a single-family dwelling;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Any public selling area of a retail store, except in a tobacco shop or store primarily concerned with selling tobacco and smoking equipment;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Any public assembly or hearing room which is owned or leased by any branch, agency, or instrumentality of the District of Columbia government; this subsection shall not apply to the District of Columbia National Guard Armory or to the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Any educational facility except as provided in § <cite path="§7-1702">7-1702</cite>(1);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>While transporting passengers within the corporate limits of the District of Columbia, any passenger vehicle owned or operated by the District of Columbia government, or any passenger vehicle for hire regulated under § <cite path="§47-2829">47-2829</cite>;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Any area of a health care facility frequented by the general public, including hallways, waiting rooms and lobbies. The operator of a health care facility may designate separate areas as smoking areas.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>When a health care facility permits patients to smoke in bed space areas, such facility shall make a reasonable effort to determine a patient’s individual nonsmoking or smoking preference and assign patients who are to be placed in bed space areas utilized by 2 or more patients to a bed space area with patients who have a similar smoking preference.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Hospital staff, visitors and the general public shall not smoke in bed space areas utilized by nonsmoking patients. “No Smoking” signs shall be conspicuously posted in such bed space areas.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Any restaurant except as permitted in § <cite path="§7-1703.01">7-1703.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Any public or private workplace, except as provided in § <cite path="§7-1703.02">7-1703.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>In a playground or public recreational facility or while sitting or standing within 25 feet of the property line of a playground or public recreational facility when another person is present; provided, that the following shall be exempt from this prohibition:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Smoking or using tobacco on residential property that is located within 25 feet of a playground or public recreational facility; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Smoking or using tobacco in places enumerated in section 2015.1 of Title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (20 DCMR § 2105.1) that are located within 25 feet of a playground or public recreational facility.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>In a bus stop or while sitting or standing within 25 feet of a posted bus stop sign located at any bus stop controlled or maintained by the District when another person is present; provided, that the following shall be exempt from this prohibition:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Smoking or using tobacco on residential property that is located within 25 feet of a bus stop sign posted at a bus stop controlled or maintained by the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Smoking or using tobacco in places enumerated in section 2015.1 of Title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (20 DCMR § 2105.1) that are located within 25 feet of a bus stop sign posted at a bus stop controlled or maintained by the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-22" type="History" path="§4">Sept. 28, 1979, D.C. Law 3-22, § 4, 26 DCR 390</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-100" type="History">Mar. 29, 1988, D.C. Law 7-100, § 2(c), 35 DCR 1182</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-262" type="History">May 2, 1991, D.C. Law 8-262, § 2(a), 37 DCR 8434</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-270" type="History">Apr. 23, 2013, D.C. Law 19-270, § 4, 60 DCR 1717</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-48" type="History">Dec. 13, 2013, D.C. Law 20-48, § 2(b), 60 DCR 15145</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">For additional restrictions on smoking in all places of employment and enclosed public areas, see § <cite path="§7-741">7-741</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-913.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-823.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite> deleted “except that smoking with the prior consent of all occupants of the vehicle shall be permitted when the vehicle is a limousine” following “under § <cite path="§47-2829">47-2829</cite>” in (5).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-48">D.C. Law 20-48</cite> added (9) and (10).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5, see § 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5, see 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-48">D.C. Law 20-48</cite>, § 4, see §  7007 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-48">D.C. Law 20-48</cite>, § 4, see §  7007 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-48">D.C. Law 20-48</cite>, § 4, see §  7007 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">For complete smoking ban in all places of employment and public places, see § <cite path="§7-742">7-742</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite> provided that the shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-48">D.C. Law 20-48</cite> would have added (9) and (10).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-48">D.C. Law 20-48</cite>: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-48">D.C. Law 20-48</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7017 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-48">D.C. Law 20-48</cite> was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7007.</text>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority under <cite doc="D.C. Law 3-22">D.C. Law 3-22</cite>, the District of Columbia Smoking Restriction Act of 1979, see Mayor’s Order 90-192, December 13, 1990.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
