<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1701</num>
  <heading>Findings and purpose.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council of the District of Columbia finds that the inhalation of concentrated smoke resulting from the smoking of tobacco in facilities in which the public congregates is a clear danger to health and a cause of inconvenience and discomfort to persons present in such facilities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The purpose of this subchapter is to protect the public health, comfort, and environment by prohibiting smoking in certain facilities, vehicles, and restaurants open to or used by the general public.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except to the extent that § 8 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 3-22">D.C. Law 3-22</cite> modifies the Fire Prevention Code approved pursuant to the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986, this subchapter is intended to complement the provisions of Part 2 of those regulations and the provisions of §§ <cite root="35-251">35-251</cite> to 35-253, which regulate public conduct on public passenger vehicles. It is not the intent of this subchapter to derogate in any manner from the provisions of the Fire Prevention Code approved pursuant to the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986 or from §    35-251(b)(1).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-22">Sept. 28, 1979, D.C. Law 3-22, § 2, 26 DCR 390</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-216">Mar. 21, 1987, D.C. Law 6-216, § 13(g), 34 DCR 1072</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-100">Mar. 29, 1988, D.C. Law 7-100, § 2(a), 35 DCR 1182</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-911.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 6-821.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>The “Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986,” referred to in two places in subsection (c), is <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-216">D.C. Law 6-216</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <annotation>Delegation of authority under <cite doc="D.C. Law 3-22">D.C. Law 3-22</cite>, the District of Columbia Smoking Restriction Act of 1979, see Mayor’s Order 90-192, December 13, 1990.</annotation>
      <annotation>Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 3-22">D.C. Law 3-22</cite>, the “District of Columbia Smoking Restrictions Act of 1979”, see Mayor’s Order 98-138, August 20, 1998 ( 45 DCR 6588).</annotation>
      <annotation>Amended Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 3-22">D.C. Law 3-22</cite>, the “District of Columbia Smoking Restrictions Act of 1979”, see Mayor’s Order 98-161, September 25, 1998 ( 45 DCR 7734).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 151 of Public Law 106-522 provided for a Federal contribution of $100,000 to the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia, effective upon the enactment by the District of Columbia of a law which banned the possession of tobacco products by minors; and provided that the Metropolitan Police Department shall use the contribution to enforce that law.</text>
      <text>Section 130 of Pub. L. 107-96 provided for a Federal contribution of $100,000 to the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia, effective upon the enactment by the District of Columbia of a law which banned the possession of tobacco products by minors; and provided that the Metropolitan Police Department shall use the contribution to enforce that law.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
