<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1803.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this part, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Brand Family” means all styles of cigarettes sold under the same trademark and differentiated from one another by additional modifiers or descriptors, including “menthol,” “lights,” “kings,” and “100s,” and includes any brand name (alone or in conjunction with any other word), trademark, logo, symbol, motto, selling message, recognizable pattern of colors, or any other indicia of product identification identical or similar to, or identifiable with, a previously known brand of cigarettes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Cigarette” has the same meaning as in § <cite path="§7-1801.01">7-1801.01</cite>(4).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Master Settlement Agreement” has the same meaning as in § <cite path="§7-1801.01">7-1801.01</cite>(5).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Non-participating Manufacturer” means any Tobacco Product Manufacturer that is not a Participating Manufacturer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Participating Manufacturer” has the meaning given that term in Section II(jj) of the Master Settlement Agreement and all amendments to it.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Qualified Escrow Fund” has the same meaning as that term is defined in § <cite path="§7-1801.01">7-1801.01</cite>(6).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Tobacco Product Manufacturer” has the same meaning as that term is defined in § <cite path="§7-1801.01">7-1801.01</cite>(9).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Units Sold” has the same meaning as that term is defined in § <cite path="§7-1801.01">7-1801.01</cite>(10).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Wholesaler” means a wholesaler licensed under § <cite path="§47-2404">47-2404</cite>(b)(1).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-150" type="History">Apr. 22, 2004, D.C. Law 15-150, § 3, 51 DCR 2809</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
