<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1811.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment of Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established a trust fund designated as the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund (“Fund”), to which shall be credited, without regard to fiscal year limitation:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>All revenue owed and accruing to the District from the payments under the tobacco litigation settlement agreement entered into on November 23, 1998 by the District of Columbia and leading United States tobacco product manufacturers (“Settlement Agreement”), except:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The first $16.05 million recognized as general fund revenue and already included in the base budget in Fiscal Year 2000;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>All payments under the Settlement Agreement sold to the District of Columbia Tobacco Settlement Financing Corporation under § <cite path="§7-1831.02">7-1831.02</cite>; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>All payments under the Residual Bond sold to the District of Columbia Tobacco Settlement Financing Corporation under § <cite path="§7-1831.02">7-1831.02</cite>;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If the Residual Bond has not been sold by the Fund, all payments received with respect to the Residual Interest, as the term is defined in § <cite path="§7-1831.01">7-1831.01</cite>(7);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B-i)</num>
        <text>If the Residual Bond has been sold by the Fund, all payments received under the Remainder Certificate, if any; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>All other funds which are directed to be deposited into the Fund by law, which shall include funds to be deposited into a Reservation 13 Benefit Area (“R13BA”) Health Care account (“R13BA fund”) pursuant to Chapter 15 of Title 10.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Fund shall be continuing. Revenues deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be managed by the Office of the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall have the power to indemnify or insure members of the board and officers of the Fund as it determines appropriate.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-38" type="History">Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-38, § 2302, 46 DCR 6373</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 3721(a), 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-300" type="History">Apr. 11, 2003, D.C. Law 14-300, § 7(b)(1), 50 DCR 406</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-69" type="History">Feb. 6, 2004, D.C. Law 15-69, § 3(a), 50 DCR 9824</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 89(b), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-142" type="History">July 25, 2006, D.C. Law 16-142, § 2(a), 53 DCR 4412</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 119, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-271" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-271, § 255(a), 62 DCR 1884</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1932">7-1932</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite> rewrote this section, which previously read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“Establishment of Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) There is established within the General Fund of the District of Columbia, a trust fund designated as the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund (’Fund’), to which shall be credited, without regard to fiscal year limitation, all revenue owed and accruing to the District from the proceeds of the tobacco litigation settlement, except for the first $16.05 million recognized as general fund revenue and already included in the base budget in FY 2000, and except for the second $16.05 million which is allocated first to the reserve to replace funds allocated from the reserve to the fund pursuant to title XX of this act. The Fund shall be continuing. Revenues deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b) Tobacco settlement monies received, or deposited into the Fund shall be used for the purposes set forth in legislation adopted by the Council.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-300">D.C. Law 14-300</cite>, in subsec. (a)(1)(C), substituted “by law, which shall include funds to be deposited into a Reservation 13 Benefit Area (‘R13BA’) Hospital account or R13BA Health Care account (collectively, ‘R13BA funds’) pursuant to Chapter 15 of Title 10” for “by law.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-69">D.C. Law 15-69</cite>, in subpar. (1)(C) of subsec. (a), substituted “Health Care account (‘R13BA fund’)” for “Hospital account or R13BA Health Care account (collectively, ‘R13BA funds)”, and made a technical correction that required no change in the text.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite>, in subsec. (a)(1)(C), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-142">D.C. Law 16-142</cite>, in subpar. (a)(1)(A)(i), substituted a semicolon for “; and”; in subpar. (a)(1)(A)(ii), substituted “§ <cite path="§7-1831.02">7-1831.02</cite>; and” for “§ <cite path="§7-1831.02">7-1831.02</cite>;”; added subpars. (a)(1)(A)(iii) and (a)(1)(B-i); added subsec. (c); and rewrote subpar. (a)(1)(B), which had read as follows: “(B) All payments received with respect to the Residual Interest, as the term is defined in § <cite path="§7-1831.01">7-1831.01</cite>(7); and”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in subsec. (a)(1)(B).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-271">D.C. Law 20-271</cite> substituted “Office of the Chief Financial Officer” for “Board of Trustees of the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund established under § <cite path="§7-1811.02">7-1811.02</cite>” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(d)(1) of Draft Master Plan for Public Reservation 13 Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-3">D.C. Law 15-3</cite>, May 3, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 3783).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of section, see § 2302 of the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-110, July 28, 1999,  46 DCR 6320).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3721(a) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) authorization for use of fund for certain bonus payments, see § 2 of the Funding for Compensation Units 1 and 2 Bonus Payment Authorization Emergency Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-211, December 14, 1999,  46 DCR 10476).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3721(a) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(d)(1) of Draft Master Plan for Public Reservation 13 Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-13, January 27, 2003,  50 DCR 1488).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of Draft Master Plan for Public Reservation 13 Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-273, December 18, 2003,  51 DCR 40).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 255(a) of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-481, Nov. 18, 2014, 61 DCR 12133, 20 STAT 4405).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 255(a) of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-7, Feb. 26, 2015,  62 DCR 2646, 21 STAT 807).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 2301 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-38">D.C. Law 13-38</cite> provided: “This title may be cited as the ‘Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund Establishment Act of 1999’.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
