<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1907</num>
  <heading>Ex parte temporary protection order.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a petition filed in accordance with § <cite path="§7-1906">7-1906</cite>(a) is supported by affidavit and alleges the existence of an immediate, substantial risk of life-threatening harm to an adult who the Department has determined is in need of protective services, the court may, upon a finding of probable cause and in accordance with § <cite path="§7-1906">7-1906</cite>(e), grant any relief listed in § <cite path="§7-1906">7-1906</cite>(d) immediately and without a hearing by issuing an ex parte temporary protection order. The Attorney General shall ensure that, within 48 hours after the issuance of such an order, notice of the hearing date and copies of the petition, supporting affidavit(s), and order are served on the same parties and in the same manner described in § <cite path="§7-1906">7-1906</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An ex parte temporary protection order shall remain effective for such period as the court may specify until a hearing is held and the petition for a provisional protection order granted or denied pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1906">7-1906</cite>. The court may modify or rescind an ex parte temporary protection order upon the motion of any person and for good cause shown.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-156">Mar. 14, 1985, D.C. Law 5-156, § 8, 32 DCR 13</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-67">Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-67, § 2(g), 53 DCR 40</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1905">7-1905</cite> and § <cite path="§7-1906">7-1906</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-2507.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-67">D.C. Law 16-67</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “Attorney General” for “Corporation Counsel”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Delayed application of Law 5-156: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§7-1901">7-1901</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
