<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1932</num>
  <heading>Authorization of grants.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to make grants from the Fund and to enter into agreements with the recipients of the grants containing any terms and conditions that the Mayor determines necessary or appropriate to effect a purpose of the Fund, as described in § <cite path="§7-1931">7-1931</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Of the funds available, the Mayor shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reserve up to $116 million for construction of health care facilities, subject to subsection (c) of this section. Any grant awarded pursuant to this paragraph shall be awarded through competitive bidding in accordance with Unit A of Chapter 3 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-301.01">2-301.01</cite> et seq.]. Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this paragraph, the Mayor may invest, subject to approval by the Council, up to $79 million to capitalize a public-private partnership by non-competitive negotiations with Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiary entities, to acquire, improve, and operate Greater Southeast Community Hospital; provided, that notwithstanding any agreement regarding the repayment of funds associated with this public-private partnership, beginning in calendar year 2009, repayment by Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiaries, of the $20 million working capital loan shall be deferred until December 31, 2015, at which time the originally agreed to repayment schedule shall resume.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Reserve up to $80 million for urgent and emergent care upgrades, subject to subsection (c) of this section. Any grant awarded pursuant to this paragraph shall be awarded through competitive bidding in accordance with Unit A of Chapter 3 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-301.01">2-301.01</cite> et seq.];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reserve $4.6 million to fund a comprehensive chronic disease management and prevention program related to the 10 leading causes of death in the District of Columbia to be administered by nonprofit organizations in partnership with the Department of Health. Any grant awarded pursuant to this paragraph shall be awarded through competitive bidding in accordance with Unit A of Chapter 3 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-301.01">2-301.01</cite> et seq.];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Grant $16.5 million to the D.C. Cancer Consortium to implement a comprehensive cancer prevention program, subject to subsection (d) of this section; provided, that $750,000 shall be utilized during fiscal year 2010 to support tobacco cessation programs including the DC Quitline and free nicotine replacement programs for District residents.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Grant $10 million to the American Lung Association of the District of Columbia to implement a tobacco cessation program in partnership with the American Cancer Society, subject to subsection (d) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Grant $6 million to the District of Columbia Primary Care Association (“DCPCA”), subject to subsection (d) of this section, for the purpose of establishing a regional health information exchange program, which shall be modeled on other regional health information organizations that have been established in other regions around the United States, among community health centers, hospitals, physician practices, and other health care providers to improve patient coordination of care and health outcomes and to build a secure database of patient health information that can be used for disease surveillance, quality-monitoring, policy-making, and clinical research; the DCPCA shall partner with the National Institute of Medical Informatics to develop a regional health information organization, with DCPCA initially acting as fiscal agent and subsequently sub-granting the funds to the regional health information organization once it is staffed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Grant up to $1.5 million to the Rand Corporation, subject to subsection (d) of this section, for the following purposes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Conducting a comprehensive assessment of the District’s health care delivery system for individuals with urgent or emergent medical needs and recommending improvements and expansions of that system;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Conducting a comprehensive assessment of the health care needs in Wards 7 and 8 and making recommendations to address the identified health care needs in those Wards; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Providing an analysis of the ongoing operating and capital costs associated with the development of ambulatory health care centers and of other health care facilities, including the Healthplex model;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Grant $1.5 million for the purpose of procuring emergency transport vehicles; subject to the completion of a deployment plan that indicates annual operating costs, staffing requirements, and maintenance costs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>For fiscal year 2010, grant $750,000 to support operational expenses associated with the Medical Homes DC Initiative, subject to subsection (d) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>For fiscal year 2011:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Allocate $4.4 million to support health services at the D.C. Jail; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Allocate $1 million to support the District’s AIDS Drug Assistance Program.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Use of the reserved funds as authorized by subsection (b)(1) and (2) of this section shall be contingent upon the findings of the comprehensive assessment described in subsection (b)(7) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor is authorized to issue a request for proposals based upon the findings of the comprehensive assessment described in subsection (b)(7) of this section to promote health care and for the delivery of health care related services in the District, including the construction of health care facilities and the operation of health care related programs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any reserved funds authorized by subsection (b)(1) and (2) of this section made available to Greater Southeast Community Hospital shall be contingent upon the condition that Greater Southeast Community Hospital changes ownership.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Mayor is authorized to enter into a public/private partnership with a new owner of Greater Southeast Community Hospital to assure the continued operation of the District’s existing programs (the psychiatric unit, clinics-primary care, specialty unit, and corrections unit) and the operation of planned programs (the comprehensive psychiatric emergency program, the expansion of the psychiatric unit, and a Detox unit) that are at, or planned for, the hospital, as well as other future programs, and the delivery of quality health care for the District’s residents living in the far northeast and southeast areas of the District; provided, that any public/private partnership requires that any new hospital constructed on the Greater Southeast Community Hospital campus integrate all of the mentioned existing and planned programs into the new facility; provided further, that the operating costs associated with the services described herein shall not come from the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund established by § <cite path="§7-1811.01">7-1811.01</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A grant awarded pursuant to subsection (b)(4),(5), (6), (7), or (9) of this section shall be awarded through noncompetitive negotiations; provided, that the grant be submitted to the Council for a 10-day period of review, excluding days of Council recess.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the Council does not approve or disapprove the grant by resolution within the 10-day review period, the grant shall be deemed approved.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-288" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-288, § 102, 54 DCR 976</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-167" type="History">June 5, 2008, D.C. Law 17-167, § 2, 55 DCR 5178</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 167(a), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, §§ 5101, 5161, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 5132, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 802(b), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 50, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1933">7-1933</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-167">D.C. Law 17-167</cite>, in subsec. (b)(1), substituted “Title 2. Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this paragraph, the Mayor may invest, subject to approval by the Council, up to $79 million to capitalize a public-private partnership by non-competitive negotiations with Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiary entities, to acquire, improve, and operate Greater Southeast Community Hospital;” for “Title 2;”; and, in subsec. (c)(3), deleted “and the findings of the comprehensive assessment described in subsection (b)(7) of this section” following “ownership”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in the punctuation in subsec. (c)(4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, in subsec. (b)(1), substituted “Community Hospital; provided, that notwithstanding any agreement regarding the repayment of funds associated with this public-private partnership, beginning in calendar year 2009, repayment by Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiaries, of the $20 million working capital loan shall be deferred until December 31, 2015; at which time the originally agreed to repayment schedule shall resume.” for “Community Hospital;”; and, in subsec. (b)(4), substituted “subject to subsection (d) of this section; provided, that $750,000 shall be utilized during fiscal year 2010 to support tobacco cessation programs including the DC Quitline and free nicotine replacement programs for District residents.” for “subject to subsection (d) of this section.”; added subsec. (b)(9); in subsec. (d)(1), substituted “subsection (b)(4),(5), (6), (7), or (9) of this section” for “subsection (b)(4),(5), (6) or (7) of this section”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “$4.6 million” for “10 million”; and, in subsec. (b), deleted “and” from the end of par. (8); substituted “; and” for a period at the end of par. (9), and added par. (10).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite>, in subsec. (b)(4), substituted “$16.5 million” for “$20 million”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> redesignated (b)(10) as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> as (b)(9); and substituted “(b)(4), (5), (6), (7), or (9)” for “(b)(4), (5), (6), (7), (9), or (10)” in (d)(1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-71">D.C. Law 17-71</cite>, January 23, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 1451).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Sections 3 and 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-154">D.C. Law 18-154</cite> substituted “Community Hospital; provided, that notwithstanding any agreement regarding the repayment of funds associated with this public-private partnership, beginning in calendar year 2009, repayment by Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiaries, of the $20 million working capital loan shall be deferred until December 31, 2015, at which time the originally agreed to repayment schedule shall resume; provided further, that the Mayor may withdraw the deferment and re-establish the loan repayment schedule.” for “Community Hospital;”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 8(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-154">D.C. Law 18-154</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of East of the River Hospital Revitalization Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-168, October 19, 2007,  54 DCR 10978).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of East of the River Hospital Revitalization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-249, January 23, 2008,  55 DCR 1255).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 5101, 5161 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 5101, 5161 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 3, 4 of Healthy DC Equal Access Fund and Hospital Stabilization Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-310, February 18, 2010,  57 DCR 1635).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5132 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 802(b) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 5100 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle K of title V of the act may be cited as the “Community Access to Health Care Amendment Act of 2009”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 5160 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle Q of title V of the act may be cited as the “Community Access to Health Care United Medical Center Amendment Act of 2009”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 5131 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle N of title V of the act may be cited as the “Community Access to Health Care Amendment Act of 2010”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 801 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> provided that title VIII of the act may be cited as “Fiscal Year 2011 Transfer of Special Purpose Funds Act of 2010”.</text>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-288">D.C. Law 16-288</cite>, the Community Access to Health Amendment Act of 2006, see Mayor’s Order 2008-74, May 2, 2008 ( 55 DCR 6930).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-288">D.C. Law 16-288</cite>, the Community Access to Health Amendment Act of 2006, see Mayor’s Order 2008-108, August 12, 2008 ( 55 DCR 9391).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Orders">Re-establishment—The Loan Repayment Schedule, see Mayor’s Order 2010-70, April 28, 2010 ( 57 DCR 4674).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
