<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2103</num>
  <heading>Rules.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall, no later than 12 months after August 13, 1986, and pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, issue all rules necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter. These rules may categorize and define the various types of facilities, may establish licensure fees, and shall at a minimum include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Procedures governing the issuance, renewal, conversion, suspension, and revocation of licenses, the orderly transfer and discharge of residents, the receipt and investigation of complaints or allegations of abuse, the issuance of variances, and appeals from licensure-related decisions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statement of residents’ rights and responsibilities for each type of facility;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Standards for continuing care, emergency care, therapeutic care, and aftercare; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Standards for each type of facility, including (when applicable), but not necessarily limited to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Programmatic standards with respect to educational, rehabilitative, and mental health services, recreational activities, parental and family involvement, the use of discipline and restraint, and the prevention of abuse;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Personnel and staffing standards with respect to the ratio of staff to residents, caregiver qualifications, and ongoing staff and volunteer training;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Personal care standards with respect to resident nutrition, hygiene, and emergency and routine health care;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Confidentiality and privacy standards with respect to a resident’s person, property, living quarters, case records, and subjection to searches for contraband;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Safety and sanitation standards with respect to all parts of the facility and grounds, fire protection and prevention, first aid, and the facility’s electrical, heating, cooling, ventilation, and water systems;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Environmental, structural, and architectural standards; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Administrative standards with respect to resident admissions and discharges, operating procedures, fiscal management, complaint investigation and review, quality assurance, recordkeeping, and reporting.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The standards adopted under subsection (a)(4)(A) of this section shall reflect a strong presumption that parental and family contact is in a resident’s best interest and that active parental and family involvement is essential to a resident’s care.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall ensure that, no later than 6 months after the issuance of rules under subsection (a) of this section, all facilities shall be licensed in accordance with those rules.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No later than 30 days after August 13, 1986, the Mayor shall appoint an advisory task force composed of social service, mental health, and education professionals, child welfare advocates, facility providers, community representatives, and representatives from relevant District government agencies. Within a time frame established by the Mayor, this task force shall formulate and present to the Mayor detailed, proposed standards for the rules required by subsection (a)(2) through (4) of this section. The Mayor shall give substantial weight to the task force’s recommendations and shall, on a regular basis before publication of proposed rules, maintain a formal, structured dialogue with task force representatives while reviewing and acting on those recommendations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may, upon a showing of extreme hardship and manifest public need and if not inconsistent with other provisions of this chapter or deleterious to resident health, safety, or welfare, grant variances to private facilities with respect to the standards established under subsection (a)(3) and (4) of this section. The Mayor shall maintain a public record listing all variances granted under this subsection and containing a complete written explanation of the basis for each variance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall not issue variances to facilities owned or operated by the District government.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-139" type="History">Aug. 13, 1986, D.C. Law 6-139, § 4, 33 DCR 3804</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-2102">7-2102</cite>, § <cite path="§7-2105">7-2105</cite>, § <cite path="§7-2107">7-2107</cite>, and § <cite path="§7-2108">7-2108</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-803.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
