<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-225</num>
  <heading>Penalties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A fine of not more than $200 or imprisonment of not more than 90 days, or both, shall be imposed on:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any person who willfully and knowingly violates any of the provisions of this chapter or refuses to perform any of the duties imposed upon him or her by this chapter or regulations issued under this chapter; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any person who willfully or negligently makes a false certification in any document required by this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this chapter, or the rules issued under authority of this chapter, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infractions shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-34" type="History">Oct. 8, 1981, D.C. Law 4-34, § 26, 28 DCR 3271</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-307" type="History">June 5, 2003, D.C. Law 14-307, § 502, 49 DCR 11664</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-205">7-205</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-225.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</cite> designated the existing text as subsection (a); and added subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 502 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 502 of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 502 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
