<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2231.01</num>
  <heading>Findings.</heading>
  <text>The Council finds that:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia has been designated a high-threat target city by the United States Department of Homeland Security, and needs commensurate capabilities for preventing, mitigating, and responding to terrorist attacks. These capabilities include risk-based strategic planning, threat and vulnerability analysis, and gap assessments.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>It is the policy of the District of Columbia to warn, inform, and protect its residents by providing timely and accurate information before, during, and after times of emergency. Such information can save lives, reduce property losses, and speed economic recovery by providing residents with the information they need to make informed decisions and to take appropriate protective actions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia seeks to promote transparency regarding homeland security efforts, in order that government officials and the public can assess the risks, adequacy of programs, the progress made, and gaps remaining.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Risks and vulnerabilities identified through an ongoing program of analysis should be addressed expeditiously and comprehensively.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The Final Report of the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States outlined appropriate roles for the federal government and its counterparts at the local government level, and concluded that homeland security priorities and assistance should be based strictly on an assessment of risks and vulnerabilities.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 11, 1950, 64 Stat. 440, ch. 686, ยง 201</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-262" type="History">as added Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-262, ยง 101(e), 54 DCR 794</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
