<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2301</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>As used in this chapter the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Communicable disease” means that term as it is defined in § <cite path="§7-132">7-132</cite>(2).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1A)</num>
    <text>“District of Columbia response plan” means the District of Columbia’s state plan for public emergency preparedness and prevention prepared pursuant to § 201 of the Disaster Relief Act of 1974 (42 U.S.C. § 5121) and § <cite path="§7-2302">7-2302</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1B)</num>
    <text>“Health care provider” means any person or entity who provides health care services, including hospitals, medical clinics and officers, special care facilities, medical laboratories, physicians, pharmacists, dentists, physician assistants, nurse practitioners, registered and other nurses, paramedics, emergency medical or laboratory technicians, and ambulance and emergency medical workers.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his or her designated agent.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Public emergency” means any disaster, catastrophe, or emergency situation where the health, safety, or welfare of persons in the District of Columbia is threatened by reason of the actual or imminent consequences within the District of Columbia of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Enemy attack, sabotage or other hostile action;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Severe and unanticipated resource shortage;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Fire;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Flood, earthquake, or other serious act of nature;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Serious civil disorder;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Any serious industrial, nuclear, or transportation accident;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>Explosion, conflagration, power failure;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(H)</num>
      <text>Injurious environmental contamination which threatens or causes damage to life, health, or property; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(I)</num>
      <text>Outbreak of a communicable disease that threatens or causes damage to life, health, or property.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Resource” means, but is not limited to, natural gas, heating fuel, automotive fuel, electricity, water, and food.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-149" type="History" path="§2">Mar. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 3-149, § 2, 27 DCR 4886</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-194" type="History">Oct. 17, 2002, D.C. Law 14-194, §§ 202(a), 903(a), 49 DCR 5306</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-534">2-534</cite>, § <cite path="§5-132.04">5-132.04</cite>, § <cite path="§7-2361.01">7-2361.01</cite>, and § <cite path="§8-634.01">8-634.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1501.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-194">D.C. Law 14-194</law-cite>, in par. (1), substituted “District of Columbia response plan” for “Emergency operations plan”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-194">D.C. Law 14-194</law-cite> redesignated par. (1) as par. (1A); added a new par. (1); in par. (1A), substituted “District of Columbia response plan” for “Emergency operations plan”; added par. (1B); made nonsubstantive changes in pars. (3)(G) and (3)(H); and added par. (3)(I).</annotation>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment of the Mayor’s Emergency Preparedness Council, see Mayor’s Order 2002-1, February 1, 2002 ( 49 DCR 896).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Amendment of Mayor’s Order 2002-1, dated January 2, 2002, Establishment of the Mayor’s Emergency Preparedness Council (EPC), see Mayor’s Order 2003-121, August 15, 2003 ( 50 DCR 7246).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Declaration of Public Emergency, see Mayor’s Order 2003-135, September 17, 2003 ( 50 DCR 8294).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Declaration of Termination of Public Emergency, see Mayor’s Order 2003-139, September 29, 2003 ( 50 DCR 9958).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
