<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2341.10</num>
  <heading>Provisional and restricted licenses and certifications.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue provisional licenses or certifications to new emergency medical services agencies or training facilities to afford the Mayor sufficient time and evidence to evaluate whether a new agency or facility is capable of complying with the provisions of this chapter, rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter, and other applicable provisions of law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>As an alternative to denial, nonrenewal, suspension, or revocation of a license or certification, when an agency, facility, or vehicle is not in substantial compliance with the provisions of this chapter, rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter, or other applicable provisions of law, and when the Mayor finds that the public interest would be served thereby, the Mayor may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Issue a provisional license or certification, if the owner or operator of the agency, facility, or vehicle is taking appropriate ameliorative action in accordance with an agreed-upon timetable; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Issue a restricted license or certification that prohibits the agency, facility, or vehicle from accepting new patients or students, or from delivering certain specified services that it would otherwise be authorized to deliver, until appropriate ameliorative action is taken.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue provisional certifications to emergency medical services personnel who do not fully meet the requirements specified in this chapter or in rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter if the Mayor finds that the public interest would be served thereby.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Provisional licenses or certifications issued pursuant to this section may be granted for a period of time up to and including 180 days, and may be renewed no more than once.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-357" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-357, ยง 11, 56 DCR 1167</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
