<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2404</num>
  <heading>Proposal for immediate negotiation.</heading>
  <text>Within 30 days of March 17, 1983, the Mayor shall propose to Congress, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, and the President the immediate negotiation with the Soviet Union of a permanent, mutual freeze on the testing, production, and further deployment of all nuclear weapons and their delivery systems.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-210" type="History" path="§5">Mar. 17, 1983, D.C. Law 4-210, § 5, 30 DCR 1088</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Prisons, privately operated facilities, authority to register firearms, see § <cite path="§24-261.02">24-261.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1514.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Initiative 37, <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-99">D.C. Law 10-99</law-cite>: <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-99">D.C. Law 10-99</law-cite> was enacted by the electors of the District of Columbia in Initiative Measure 37.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 1 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-99">D.C. Law 10-99</law-cite> requires the Mayor to notify the District’s Congressional Delegate, in writing, that a majority of District voters request that the Delegate propose a Constitutional amendment directing the U.S. government to: 1) abolish all nuclear warheads by the year 2000; 2) pursue a good faith effort to eliminate war, armed conflict, and military operations; 3) actively promote international peace and nuclear disarmament; and 4) convert weapons industries into constructive, ecologically beneficial peacetime industries and to redirect those resources to meet human needs, including housing, health care, agriculture, education, and environment.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-99">D.C. Law 10-99</law-cite> provided for severability of the act.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
