<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2509.11</num>
  <heading>Rules.</heading>
  <text>The Chief of the MPD, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], shall issue rules to implement the provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-279">D.C. Law 20-279</cite>, including rules:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>To establish criteria for determining when an applicant has, pursuant to section 6 of the Pistols and Other Dangerous Weapons Act [§ <cite path="§22-4506">22-4506</cite>]:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated a good reason to fear injury to his or her person, which shall at a minimum require a showing of a special need for self-protection distinguishable from the general community as supported by evidence of specific threats or previous attacks that demonstrate a special danger to the applicant’s life;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated any other proper reason for carrying a concealed pistol, which shall at a minimum include types of employment that require the handling of cash or other valuable objects that may be transported upon the applicant’s person; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated the applicant’s suitability to carry a concealed pistol, which shall at a minimum include evidence that the applicant meets the requirements of § <cite path="§7-2509.02">7-2509.02</cite>;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>To establish the type and amount of ammunition that may be carried concealed by a licensee;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>To establish the methods by which a pistol may be carried, including any standards for safe holstering;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>To establish all application forms, investigation procedures, background checks, and fees necessary to process an application for a license to carry a concealed pistol;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>To specify any procedures or requirements specific to non-residents who apply to carry a concealed pistol pursuant to § <cite path="§22-4506">22-4506</cite>, with regard to the registration requirements in this unit;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>To specify requirements for signage on any private premises where the owner or person in control of the premises prohibits the carrying of a concealed pistol pursuant to § <cite path="§7-2509.07">7-2509.07</cite>(b); and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>To establish procedures for the renewal of licenses.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, § 911</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-279">as added June 16, 2015, D.C. Law 20-279, § 2(f), 62 DCR 1944</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-279">D.C. Law 20-279</cite>, referred to in the introductory language of this section, enacted § <cite path="§7-2502.11a">7-2502.11a</cite> and this subchapter, amended §§ <cite path="§7-2502.01">7-2502.01</cite>(b)(4), <cite path="§7-2502.02">7-2502.02</cite>(a)(4), <cite path="§7-2502.03">7-2502.03</cite>(a)(4), <cite path="§22-4504">22-4504</cite>(a), and <cite path="§22-4506">22-4506</cite>, and repealed §  22-2511.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
