<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2504.10</num>
  <heading>District as federal firearms licensee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Whenever there is no active federal firearms licensee in the District of Columbia, the Mayor may seek from federal authorities a license for the District to act as a federal firearms licensee solely for the benefit of any District resident eligible and seeking to obtain a lawful handgun.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall delegate the authority under subsection (a) of this section to a subordinate agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The District shall act under the license obtained pursuant to subsection (a) of this section only until such time as there is an active federal firearms licensee in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The District may charge a fee to recover the cost of acting as a federal firearms licensee pursuant to subsection (a) of this section by charging $125 or its actual costs, whichever is less, for each handgun.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “active federal firearms licensee” means a person or business that has applied for and received a federal firearms license pursuant to 18 U.S.C. § 923 for the purpose of interstate transfer of handguns, and is operating commercially in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History" path="§410">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, § 410</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-170" type="History">as added Sept. 29, 2012, D.C. Law 19-170, § 2(l), 59 DCR 5691</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(l) of Firearms Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-352, May 11, 2012,  59 DCR 5116).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see § 2(l) of the Firearms Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-510, October 26, 2012,  59 DCR 12808).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
