<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2508.07</num>
  <heading>Penalties; mandatory release condition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any knowing violation by a gun offender of this subchapter or of rules or regulations established pursuant to this subchapter, including knowingly failing to register, verify, or update information in the manner and within the time periods provided for in this subchapter, shall be a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not more than $1,000, imprisonment of not more than 12 months, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Compliance with the requirements of this subchapter, including any rules or regulations adopted by the Chief pursuant to this subchapter, shall be a mandatory condition after the expiration of any time being served on probation, parole, supervised release, or conditional release for any gun offender convicted in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title VIII, § 807</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-88" type="History">as added Dec. 10, 2009, D.C. Law 18-88, § 205, 56 DCR 7413</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-2502.03">7-2502.03</cite>, § <cite path="§7-2507.06">7-2507.06</cite>, and § <cite path="§7-2508.02">7-2508.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) addition of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 1-85">D.C. Law 1-85</law-cite>, §§ 9<cite path="§01-910">01-910</cite>, concerning licenses to carry a pistol, see § 2(e) of the License to Carry a Pistol Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-169">D.C. Law 20-169</law-cite>, May 5, 2015, 61 DCR 11814).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 205 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-227, October 21, 2009,  56 DCR 8668).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 1-85">D.C. Law 1-85</law-cite>, §§ 901 to 910, concerning licenses to carry a pistol, see § 2(e) of the License to Carry a Pistol Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-447, Oct. 7, 2014, 61 DCR 10765, 20 STAT 4175).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of provisions concerning the applicability of new section 910 of the Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975, see § 4(b) and (c) of the License to Carry a Pistol Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-447, Oct. 7, 2014, 61 DCR 10765, 20 STAT 4175).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of emergency D.C. Act 20-447, § 4, the act’s applicability clause, see § 2 of the License to Carry a Pistol Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-448, Oct. 7, 2014,  61 DCR 10777, 20 STAT 4187).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 1-85">D.C. Law 1-85</law-cite>, §§ 901 to 910, concerning licenses to carry a pistol, see § 2(f) of the License to Carry a Pistol Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-564, Jan. 6, 2015, 62 DCR 866, 21 STAT 527).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of emergency D.C. Act 20-447, see § 4(b) of the License to Carry a Pistol Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-564, Jan. 6, 2015,  62 DCR 866, 21 STAT 527).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of temporary D.C. Act 20-169, see § 4(c) of the License to Carry a Pistol Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-564, Jan. 6, 2015,  62 DCR 866, 21 STAT 527).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) provision concerning the rules issued under the authority of D.C. Act 20-447, see § 5 of the License to Carry a Pistol Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-564, Jan. 6, 2015, 62 DCR 866, 21 STAT 527).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
