<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2504.02</num>
  <heading>Qualifications for dealer’s license; application; fee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person eligible to register a firearm under this unit and who, if a registrant, has not previously failed to perform any of the duties imposed by this unit; and, any person eligible under the acts of Congress to engage in such business, may obtain a dealer’s license, or a renewal thereof, which shall be valid for a period of not more than 1 year from the date of issuance. The license required by this unit, shall be in addition to any other license or licensing procedure required by law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each application for a dealer’s license and each application for renewal thereof shall be made on a form prescribed by the Chief, shall be sworn to or affirmed by the applicant, and shall contain:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The information required by § <cite path="§7-2502.03">7-2502.03</cite>(a);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The address where the applicant conducts or intends to conduct his business;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Whether the applicant, prior to September 24, 1976, held a license to deal in deadly weapons in the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Such other information as the Chief may require, including fingerprints and photographs of the applicant, to carry out the purposes of this unit.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each application for a dealer’s license, or renewal shall be accompanied by a fee established by the Mayor; provided, that such fee shall in the judgment of the Mayor, reimburse the District for the cost of services provided under this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as a Public Safety endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of Chapter 28 of Title 47.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title IV, § 402, 23 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(k)(2), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38" type="History">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 3(i)(2), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-2504.04">7-2504.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2342.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1842.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-38">D.C. Law 15-38</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “Public Safety endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” for “Class A Public Safety endorsement to a master business license under the master”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(i)(2) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003,  50 DCR 6896).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 1-85">D.C. Law 1-85</cite>, the Firearms Control Regulation Act of 1975</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
