<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2502.10</num>
  <heading>Procedure for denial and revocation of registration certificate.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If it appears to the Chief that an application for a registration certificate should be denied or that a registration certificate should be revoked, the Chief shall notify the applicant or registrant of the proposed denial or revocation, briefly stating the reason or reasons therefor. Service may be made by delivering a copy of the notice to the applicant or registrant personally, or by leaving a copy thereof at the place of residence identified on the application or registration with some person of suitable age and discretion then residing therein, or by mailing a copy of the notice first class mail, postage prepaid, to the residence address identified on the application or certificate. In the case of an organization, service may be made upon the president, chief executive, or other officer, managing agent or person authorized by appointment or law to receive such notice as described in the preceding sentence at the business address of the organization identified in the application or registration certificate. The person serving the notice shall make proof thereof by preparing an affidavit identifying the person served and stating the time, place, and manner of service. The applicant or registrant shall have 15 days from the date the notice is served in which to submit further evidence in support of the application or qualifications to continue to hold a registration certificate, as the case may be; provided, that if the applicant does not make such a submission within 15 days from the date of service, the applicant or registrant shall be deemed to have conceded the validity of the reason or reasons stated in the notice, and the denial or revocation shall become final.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 10 days of the date upon which the Chief receives such a submission, he shall serve upon the applicant or registrant in the manner specified in subsection (a) of this section notice of his final decision. The Chief’s decision shall become effective at the expiration of the time within which to file a notice of appeal pursuant to the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.) or, if such a notice of appeal is filed, at the time the final order or judgment of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals becomes effective.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Within 7 days of a decision unfavorable to the applicant or registrant becoming final, the applicant or registrant shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Peaceably surrender to the Chief the firearm for which the registration certificate was revoked in the manner provided in § <cite path="§7-2507.05">7-2507.05</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Lawfully remove such firearm from the District for so long as he has an interest in such firearm; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Otherwise lawfully dispose of his interest in such firearm.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a firearm is in the possession of the Chief, the Chief may maintain possession of the firearm for which the registrant is temporarily or permanently prohibited from having lawful possession until final disposition of the matter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title II, § 210, 23 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-62" type="History">Mar. 16, 1978, D.C. Law 2-62, § 2, 24 DCR 5780</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-372" type="History">Mar. 31, 2009, D.C. Law 17-372, § 3(i), 56 DCR 1365</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1831.03">2-1831.03</cite>, § <cite path="§7-2504.06">7-2504.06</cite>, § <cite path="§7-2505.01">7-2505.01</cite>, and § <cite path="§7-2507.05">7-2507.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2320.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1820.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-372">D.C. Law 17-372</cite> rewrote subsec. (a); and added subsec. (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(i) of Firearms Registration Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-651, January 6, 2009,  56 DCR 911).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
