<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2507.02</num>
  <heading>Responsibilities regarding storage of firearms.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It shall be the policy of the District of Columbia that each registrant should keep any firearm in his or her possession unloaded and either disassembled or secured by a trigger lock, gun safe, locked box, or other secure device.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No person shall store or keep any firearm on any premises under his control if he knows or reasonably should know that a minor is likely to gain access to the firearm without the permission of the parent or guardian of the minor unless such person:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Keeps the firearm in a securely locked box, secured container, or in a location which a reasonable person would believe to be secure; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Carries the firearm on his person or within such close proximity that he can readily retrieve and use it as if he carried it on his person.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person who violates subsection (b) of this section is guilty of criminally negligent storage of a firearm and, except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, shall be fined not more than $1,000, imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person who violates subsection (b) of this section and the minor causes injury or death to himself or another shall be fined not more than $5,000, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall not apply if the minor obtains the firearm as a result of an unlawful entry or burglary to any premises by any person.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <text>The provisions of § <cite path="§7-2507.06">7-2507.06</cite> shall not apply to this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “minor” shall mean a person under the age of 18 years.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History" path="§702">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title VII, § 702, 23 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-372" type="History">Mar. 31, 2009, D.C. Law 17-372, § 3(o), 56 DCR 1365</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-170" type="History">Sept. 29, 2012, D.C. Law 19-170, § 2(o), 59 DCR 5691</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-2502.03">7-2502.03</cite> and § <cite path="§7-2507.06">7-2507.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2372.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1872.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-372">D.C. Law 17-372</law-cite> rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “Except for law enforcement personnel described in § <cite path="§7-2502.01">7-2502.01</cite>(b)(1), each registrant shall keep any firearm in his possession unloaded and disassembled or bound by a trigger lock or similar device unless such firearm is kept at his place of business, or while being used for lawful recreational purposes within the District of Columbia.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-170">D.C. Law 19-170</law-cite> added “penalties” in the section heading; and added (c-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment, see § 2(c) of Firearms Control Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-422, July 16, 2008,  55 DCR 8237).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Second Firearms Control Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-502, September 16, 2008,  55 DCR 9904).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of D.C. Act 17-422, see § 5 of Second Firearms Control Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-502, September 16, 2008,  55 DCR 9904).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2(e) and 4 of Second Firearms Control Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-601, December 12, 2008,  56 DCR 9).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(o) of Firearms Registration Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-651, January 6, 2009,  56 DCR 911).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(o) of Firearms Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-352, May 11, 2012,  59 DCR 5116).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(o) of the Firearms Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-394, July 18, 2012,  59 DCR 8694).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of (c-1) and amendment of section heading, see § 2(o) of the Firearms Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-510, October 26, 2012,  59 DCR 12808).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
