<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2507.05</num>
  <heading>Voluntary surrender of firearms, destructive devices, or ammunition; immunity from prosecution; determination of evidentiary value of firearm.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a person or organization within the District voluntarily and peaceably delivers and abandons to the Chief any firearm, destructive device or ammunition at any time, such delivery shall preclude the arrest and prosecution of such person on a charge of violating any provision of this unit with respect to the firearm, destructive device, or ammunition voluntarily delivered. Delivery under this section may be made at any police district, station, or central headquarters, or by summoning a police officer to the person’s residence or place of business. Every firearm and destructive device to be delivered and abandoned to the Chief under this section shall be transported in accordance with § <cite path="§22-4504.02">22-4504.02</cite> and, in the case of delivery to a police facility, the package shall be carried in open view. No person who delivers and abandons a firearm, destructive device, or ammunition under this section, shall be required to furnish identification, photographs, or fingerprints. No amount of money shall be paid for any firearm, destructive device, or ammunition delivered and abandoned under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Whenever any firearm, destructive device, or any ammunition is surrendered under this section or pursuant to § <cite path="§7-2502.10">7-2502.10</cite>(c)(1), the Chief shall inquire of the United States Attorney and the Corporation Counsel for the District whether such firearm is needed as evidence; provided, that if the same is not needed as evidence, it shall be destroyed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History" path="§705">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title VII, § 705, 23 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-372" type="History">Mar. 31, 2009, D.C. Law 17-372, § 3(p), 56 DCR 1365</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Ammunition feeding devices transfers, prohibition, see § <cite path="§5-133.16">5-133.16</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§5-133.16">5-133.16</cite>, § <cite path="§7-2502.10">7-2502.10</cite>, § <cite path="§7-2504.06">7-2504.06</cite>, and § <cite path="§7-2505.01">7-2505.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2375.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1875.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-372">D.C. Law 17-372</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “shall be transported in accordance with § 4504.02,” for “shall be unloaded and securely wrapped in a package”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) provisions prohibiting the transfer by the Metropolitan Police Department of ammunition feeding devices, see § 2 of Prohibition on the Transfer of Firearms Temporary Act of 1995 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 11-35">D.C. Law 11-35</law-cite>, September 8, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 5304).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary prohibition on the transfer by the Metropolitan Police Department of any ammunition feeding device, see § 2 of the Prohibition on the Transfer of Firearms Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-58, May 18, 1995,  42 DCR 2574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(p) of Firearms Registration Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-651, January 6, 2009,  56 DCR 911).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Prohibition on transfer of ammunition feeding devices: For provisions prohibiting the transfer by the Metropolitan Police Department of ammunition feeding devices, see § <cite path="§4-191">4-191</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
