<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2509.05</num>
  <heading>Revocation and suspension of licenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Chief may limit or revoke a license upon a finding that the licensee no longer meets the requirements of § <cite path="§22-4506">22-4506</cite> and this subchapter, or as a penalty as specified in this unit.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The United States Attorney for the District of Columbia, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, or any person may apply to the MPD at any time for limitation or revocation of a license.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any person having knowledge that a licensee no longer meets the requirements of this unit or the requirements of § <cite path="§22-4506">22-4506</cite> may so notify the Chief or any other law enforcement officer who may take such action as may be appropriate.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Before a limitation or revocation taking effect, the Chief shall serve a notice of intent to limit or revoke the license. The limitation or revocation shall take effect unless the licensee requests an appeal to the Concealed Pistol Licensing Review Board established pursuant to §  7-2509.08 no later than 15 days after the date of the notice of intent.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Chief may summarily suspend or limit, without a hearing, a license, when the Chief has determined that the conduct of a licensee presents an imminent danger to the health and safety of a person or the public.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At the time of the summary suspension or limitation of a license, the Chief shall provide the licensee with written notice stating the action that is being taken, the basis for the action, and the right of the licensee to request a hearing.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A licensee shall have the right to request a hearing within 72 hours after service of notice of the summary suspension or limitation of the license. The Concealed Pistol Licensing Review Board shall hold a hearing within 72 hours after receipt of a timely request, and shall issue a written decision within 72 hours after the hearing.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, § 905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-279" type="History">as added June 16, 2015, D.C. Law 20-279, § 2(f), 62 DCR 1944</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
