<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2807</num>
  <heading>Duties of security alarm users.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An alarm system user shall not cause or permit any false alarm.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It shall be the responsibility of alarm users to instruct any employees or others who may have occasion to activate an alarm that alarm systems are to be activated only in emergency situations to summon an immediate police or fire department response. Alarm users shall also instruct appropriate employees as to the operation of the alarm system, to include setting, activation, and resetting of the alarm.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Alarm users shall be responsible for seeing that alarm systems are maintained in good working order and that defects which could cause false alarms are promptly repaired.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Users of alarm systems who have not contracted with an alarm dealer for an alarm agent to respond to the scene of alarm activations shall indicate the telephone numbers of at least 2 responsible persons who are capable of deactivating and resetting the alarm system and of assisting the police or fire department to secure the premises, if necessary, and who may be notified by the Metropolitan Police Department or District of Columbia Fire Department to respond to the scene by either: (1) posting the names of such persons on a sticker or other sign on the premises in a conspicuous place visible from outside the premises; or (2) filing the names with the Mayor as defined by regulation. Such person or persons shall respond to the scene within one-half hour after being requested to do so by the Metropolitan Police Department or District of Columbia Fire Department, unless good cause is shown.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-107" type="History">Sept. 26, 1980, D.C. Law 3-107, § 8, 27 DCR 3760</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-99" type="History">Mar. 29, 1988, D.C. Law 7-99, § 2(i), 35 DCR 1051</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-3107.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
