<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2805</num>
  <heading>Licensing of alarm agents.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No person shall act as an alarm agent within the boundaries of the District of Columbia without first obtaining a license to be known as an alarm agent’s license. A person to whom an alarm dealer’s license has been issued may obtain an alarm agent’s license without payment of any additional license fee. Any person who violates this section shall pay a fine of not more than $300. Alarm agents’ licenses shall be issued in the form of an identification card.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Application for an alarm agent’s license shall be made to the Mayor on a form prescribed by the Mayor. The information provided by the applicant shall be under oath and shall include, but shall not be limited to the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the applicant;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the alarm business by whom the applicant will be employed; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A signed statement by the owner or manager of the particular alarm business indicating that employment has been offered to the applicant.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each applicant for an alarm agent’s license shall furnish the Mayor with sets of his or her fingerprints, which shall be processed in the manner set forth in § <cite path="§7-2804">7-2804</cite>(c).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Each application required by this section shall be accompanied by a nonrefundable fee to be established by the Mayor; Provided, that such fee shall, in the judgment of the Mayor, reimburse the District for the cost of services provided under this section. The term of the license shall be determined by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Each alarm agent, and each alarm dealer whose duties include the installation, inspection, maintenance, servicing, or repair of alarm systems, shall carry on his or her person at all times while engaged in such duties a valid licensee identification card. Such identification card shall include the name of the alarm agent, a photograph of the alarm agent, and an identification number. Such card shall be displayed upon request. Identification cards are not transferable, and must be surrendered to the Mayor upon termination of employment as an alarm agent or suspension or revocation of an alarm agent’s license.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Alarm agents’ licenses shall be subject to denial, suspension, or revocation on the grounds set forth in § <cite path="§7-2804">7-2804</cite>(e). Procedures for the denial, suspension, or revocation of such a license shall be as set forth in § <cite path="§7-2804">7-2804</cite>(f), (g), (i), and (j).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of Chapter 28 of Title 47.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-107" type="History">Sept. 26, 1980, D.C. Law 3-107, § 6, 27 DCR 3760</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-99" type="History">Mar. 29, 1988, D.C. Law 7-99, § 2(g), 35 DCR 1051</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(l), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38" type="History">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 3(j), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Regulated non-health related occupations and professions, see § <cite path="§47-2853.04">47-2853.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-2853.04">47-2853.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-3105.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-38">D.C. Law 15-38</cite>, in subsec. (g), substituted “an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” for “a Class A Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to master business license under the master”.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(j) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003,  50 DCR 6896).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
