<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-3004</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Addiction Recovery Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established, as a nonlapsing, revolving fund, the Addiction Recovery Fund (“Fund”). Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, the Fund shall be comprised of general revenue funds appropriated by a line item in the budget submitted pursuant to § <cite path="§1-204.46">1-204.46</cite>, and authorized by Congress in an appropriations act for the purpose of the Drug Treatment Choice Program.  The Mayor shall, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act, deposit in the Fund any and all other funds received on behalf of the Fund for the purpose of the Drug Treatment Choice Program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All funds shall be deposited into the Fund without regard to fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress. All funds deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the purpose of the Drug Treatment Choice Program, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>There is established within the Fund a segregated account to be known as the ATR Account, into which shall be deposited the federal grant funds awarded to APRA for ATR, to be expended solely for the purposes of ATR, in accordance with federal requirements and regulations promulgated to implement this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, the Fund shall be used only for payments directly to treatment providers. The Fund shall be the sole source for payments to treatment providers under the Drug Treatment Choice Program. APRA shall administer the Drug Treatment Choice Program and the Fund from APRA’s appropriated operating budget.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Within 18 months of July 18, 2000, APRA shall develop a plan to incorporate all APRA funding for substance abuse treatment services into the Fund. APRA may propose to continue then existing contracts and grants upon a finding that the Program would not serve the specific needs of a particular clientele or group.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The plan developed by APRA pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall be submitted by the Mayor to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed plan, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed plan shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-146" type="History" path="§5">July 18, 2000, D.C. Law 13-146, § 5, 47 DCR 4350</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4202, 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 50, 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-219" type="History">Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 5002(b), 55 DCR 7598</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-3015">7-3015</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite>, in subsec. (a), designated par. (1), inserted “as a nonlapsing, revolving fund” before “established” in the first sentence of par. (1), and added par. (2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in subsec. (a)(1), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite>, in subsecs. (a) and (b), inserted “Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section,”; and added subsec. (a-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-142">D.C. Law 17-142</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, the Fund shall be comprised” for “The Fund shall be comprised”; in subsec. (b), substituted “Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, the Fund shall be used only for” for “The Fund shall be used only for”; and added subsec. (a-1) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a-1) There is established within the Fund a segregated account to be known as the ATR Account, into which shall be deposited the federal grant funds awarded to APRA for ATR, to be expended solely for the purposes of ATR, in accordance with federal requirements and regulations promulgated to implement this act.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-142">D.C. Law 17-142</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3802 of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Choice in Drug Treatment Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-280, January 29, 2008,  55 DCR 1534).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
