<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-3002</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration” (“APRA”) means the  agency or the successor agency within the Department of Health responsible for  administering substance abuse prevention and treatment services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Aftercare plan” means the services or other planned activities designed to sustain therapeutic gains and promote further recovery of the client with  regard to the issues relating to substance abuse.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Certification” means the process of ensuring that standards of care are met for the operation of a substance abuse treatment facility or program in  the District of Columbia as described by regulation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Client” means a person who has and is seeking to recover from substance abuse and has been selected for participation in the Drug Treatment Choice Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Drug” means any of the controlled substances enumerated in §§ <cite path="§48-902.04">48-902.04</cite>, <cite path="§48-902.06">48-902.06</cite>, <cite path="§48-902.08">48-902.08</cite>, <cite path="§48-902.10">48-902.10</cite>, or 48-902.12.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Dual diagnosis” means persons with the concurrent diagnoses of substance abuse and mental disease or disorder.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Intake screening and assessment” means the process performed by a  qualified substance abuse counselor for the collection of relevant information  about an applicant in order to determine eligibility for rehabilitation  program services and the development of an initial treatment plan and any  necessary referral.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Qualified substance abuse counselor” means a person who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Has received certification or credentials in substance abuse from the American Medical Association, the American Society for Addiction Medicine, the Nurses Professional Association, a state’s affiliate of the National Alcohol and Drug Counselors’ Association, or a state’s affiliate of the International Certification Reciprocity Consortium for Alcohol and Other Drugs of Abuse (“ICRC/AODA”);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Has registered with the District of Columbia Board of Professional Counseling as a Registered Addiction Professional; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Completes 40 hours of continuing education every two years.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Rehabilitation plan” means the course of action to be taken to address  the issues relating to substance abuse that were identified in the intake screening and assessment, including frequency of services, type of personnel providing services, monitoring of client progress, and plan revision.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Resident” means any person who lives in the District voluntarily, not  for a temporary purpose, and has no present intention of removing himself or  herself from the District. Temporary absence from the District, with  subsequent returns to the District, or intent to return when the purposes of the absence have been accomplished shall not interrupt continuity of residence. For the purpose of this chapter, whether a person is a “resident” shall not depend upon the reason that the individual entered the District  except that it may bear on whether the person is in the District for a temporary purpose.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Substance abuse” means a pattern of pathological use of a drug or alcohol that causes impairment in social or occupational functioning or produces physiological dependency evidenced by physical tolerance or physical  symptoms when the drug or alcohol is not used.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Treatment provider‘ means an entity, a facility, or a program that has been certified by APRA to be responsible for the delivery of substance abuse detoxification, rehabilitation, and aftercare services to an identified target population.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-146" type="History" path="§3">July 18, 2000, D.C. Law 13-146, § 3, 47 DCR 4350</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 18, 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-1345.01">4-1345.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “has and is” for “is afflicted with and” following “person who” in (4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
