<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-651.02</num>
  <heading>Execution and issuance of comfort care order.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The following persons may execute a comfort care order to communicate the decision that the person who is the subject of the order shall not be resuscitated if the person experiences cardiac arrest or respiratory arrest as a result of a specified medical or terminal condition:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any competent person, who is 18 years of age or older, on behalf of the competent person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An authorized decision-maker on behalf of an incapacitated person; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A surrogate on behalf of a minor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A comfort care order may be issued only by the attending physician of a person who is the subject of the Order. The attending physician shall explain to the person who does not wish to be resuscitated and the person’s authorized decision-maker or surrogate, as appropriate, the effect of the Order and the alternatives, including medical treatment and the issuance of another form of advanced directive. If the person, after reviewing the alternatives, wishes to execute an Order, the attending physician shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Issue the Order and a comfort care bracelet or necklace;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Place the bracelet or necklace on the person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Explain to the person, authorized decision-maker, or surrogate how the Order may be revoked; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Submit a copy of the comfort care order to the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall keep confidential any records containing patient social security numbers.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-224" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-224, § 3, 48 DCR 27</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-651.12">7-651.12</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
