<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-702.06</num>
  <heading>Confidentiality of records and identities of residents.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The program shall protect the confidentiality of the records (electronic or hard copy) of the residents and employees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No information or records (electronic or hard copy) maintained by the program shall be disclosed to the public.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the program shall not disclose the identity of any complainant, resident involved in a complaint, witness, or representative of a resident, unless the complainant, resident, or representative of a resident authorizes the disclosure.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A court may order the disclosure of information made confidential under this chapter if it determines that the disclosure is necessary to enforce this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A communication between a resident and a person who has access under § <cite path="§7-703.01">7-703.01</cite> shall be confidential, unless the resident authorizes the release of the communication or unless disclosure is authorized under § <cite path="§7-702.04">7-702.04</cite>(a)(1) or subsection (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-218" type="History" path="§206">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-218, § 206, 36 DCR 534</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-321" type="History">Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-321, § 2(c), 57 DCR 12438</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 54(b), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-3516.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-321">D.C. Law 18-321</cite>, in subsecs. (a) and (b), substituted “records (electronic or hard copy)” for “records”; in subsec. (c), substituted “Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the program” for “the program”; and added subsecs. (d) and (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
