<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-701.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Administrator” means the person who is responsible for the day-to-day operation and management of a long-term care facility, including, in the case of a community residence facility, the residence director.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Court” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs” means the District of Columbia Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs established pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1983.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3A)</num>
    <text>“Department of Health, Health Regulations and Licensing Administration” means the administrative office established in January 17, 2007 under the Department of Health.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Department of Human Services” means the District of Columbia Department of Human Services established pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979 and Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4A)</num>
    <text>“Department of Mental Health” means the Department of Mental Health established as a separate cabinet-level agency pursuant to § <cite path="§7-1131.03">7-1131.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Designee” means a person who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Has received a minimum of 15 hours of certified training in accordance with § <cite path="§7-702.04">7-702.04</cite>(a)(15);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is an employee or volunteer of the program established pursuant to § <cite path="§7-702.01">7-702.01</cite> or has written authorization to act on behalf of the ombudsman pursuant to § <cite path="§7-702.04">7-702.04</cite>(a)(3).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Director” means the Executive Director of the District of Columbia Office on Aging established by § <cite path="§7-503.02">7-503.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6A)</num>
    <text>“Home care agency” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§44-501">44-501</cite>(a)(7).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Long-term care facility” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A “community residence facility” as defined in § <cite path="§44-501">44-501</cite>(a)(4);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A “nursing home” as defined in § <cite path="§44-501">44-501</cite>(a)(3); or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>An “assisted living residence” as defined in § <cite path="§44-101.01">44-101.01</cite>(4).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7A)</num>
    <text>“Long-term care services” means services received at a long-term care facility and services provided to residents in the community who need a nursing home level of care and receive home health care through the Medicaid Elderly and Physically Disabled Waiver.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Ombudsman” means the District of Columbia Long-Term Care Ombudsman established by § <cite path="§7-702.02">7-702.02</cite>(a) and designated under § 307(a)(12) of the Older Americans Act of 1965; (42 U.S.C. § 3027(a)(12)), to perform the mandated functions of the Long-Term Care Ombudsman Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Office on Aging” means the District of Columbia Office on Aging established by § <cite path="§7-503.01">7-503.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Person” means an individual, an agent, a corporation, a partnership, or any other organizational entity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Program” means the District of Columbia Long-Term Care Ombudsman Program established by § <cite path="§7-702.01">7-702.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Record” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Medical, social, personal, or financial information maintained by a health-care facility covered by the Health-Care and Community Residence Facility, Hospice and Home Care Licensure Act of 1983, or by a District of Columbia (“District”) government agency that has responsibility for the care and maintenance of a resident in a long-term care facility; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>An administrative record, cost or incident report, or a report of a civil infraction, inspection, or deficiency maintained by a long-term care facility or a District government agency.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Resident” means a resident of a long-term care facility or an individual receiving long-term care services from a home care agency through the Medicaid Elderly and Physically Disabled Waiver.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>“Representative of a resident” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A person who is knowledgeable about the circumstances of a resident and has been designated by that resident to represent him or her; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A person, other than a facility, who has been appointed by a court to administer the financial or personal affairs of a resident or to protect and advocate for the rights of a resident; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The ombudsman or his or her designee, if no person has been designated or appointed in accordance with subparagraph (A) or (B) of this paragraph.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-218" type="History" path="§101">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-218, § 101, 36 DCR 534</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-321" type="History">Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-321, § 2(a), 57 DCR 12438</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-111" type="History">Mar. 14, 2012, D.C. Law 19-111, § 2(a), 59 DCR 455</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-3501.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-321">D.C. Law 18-321</law-cite> added pars. (3A) and (4A); in par. (5)(B), substituted “Is an employee or volunteer” for “Is an employee”; and, in par. (7), deleted “or” from the end of subpar. (A), substituted “; or” for a period at the end of subpar. (B), and added subpar. (C).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-111">D.C. Law 19-111</law-cite> added pars. (6A) and (7A); and rewrote par. (13), which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(13) ‘Resident’ means a resident of a long-term care facility.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “Health-Care and Community Residence Facility, Hospice, and Home Care Licensure Act of 1983”, referred to in paragraph (12), is <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 5-48">D.C. Law 5-48</law-cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-111">D.C. Law 19-111</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-111">D.C. Law 19-111</law-cite>, § 3, was repealed by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</law-cite>, § 7013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
