<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-734</num>
  <heading>Public Health Laboratory fees.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor is authorized to establish a schedule of fees for forms and for performing laboratory analysis of biological and environmental samples obtained from humans, animals, or various environmental media for the purpose of identifying environmental contaminants and performing epidemiological surveillance, including for cases of lead poisoning, tuberculosis, rabies, and sexually transmitted diseases. The schedule of fees may account for the provision of bulk services and may distinguish between services provided to individuals and organizations. The schedule of fees may be developed on a sliding scale based on a person’s or organization’s ability to pay for laboratory analysis, or may be waived in cases of extreme need.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History" path="§4905">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4905, 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-257" type="History">Mar. 27, 2003, D.C. Law 14-257, § 2, 50 DCR 244</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-257">D.C. Law 14-257</law-cite> rewrote the first sentence which had read: “The Mayor is authorized to establish a schedule of fees for performing laboratory analysis of biological and environmental samples obtained from humans, animals, or various environmental media for the purpose of identifying environmental contaminants and performing epidemiological surveillance for cases of lead poisoning, tuberculosis, rabies, and sexually transmitted diseases.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Public Health Laboratory Fee Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-208">D.C. Law 14-208</law-cite>, October 19, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 10464).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 5 of Department of Health Functions Clarification Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-60, June 6, 2001,  48 DCR 5701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 4405 of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Public Health Laboratory Fee Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-390, June 21, 2002,  49 DCR 6083).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Public Health Laboratory Fee Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-479, October 3, 2002,  49 DCR 9579).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
