<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-736.03</num>
  <heading>Communicable disease fees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Health may establish a schedule of fees for the prevention and treatment of communicable diseases, including HIV/AIDS, hepatitis, sexually transmitted diseases, and tuberculosis to be provided to any individual who presents for prevention or treatment services, regardless of health insurance coverage or ability to pay. The Director may periodically revise the schedule of fees and may establish a sliding fee scale, based on income, for uninsured individuals. The fees, including any sliding fee scale, shall be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director may seek reimbursement from any third-party payor for services provided relating to the prevention and treatment of communicable diseases.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, §  4907c</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">as added by Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  5012(b), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5012(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5012(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5012(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
