<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-741.03</num>
  <heading>Exemptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The following places shall be exempt from the provisions of this subchapter:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A retail store that is used primarily for the sale of tobacco products and accessories in which the total annual revenue generated by the sale of non-tobacco products or accessories is no greater than 25% of the total revenue of the establishment; provided, that it does not share space with any other establishment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A tobacco bar;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An outdoor area of a restaurant, tavern, club, brew pub, or nightclub;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A hotel room or motel room rented to one or more guests;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A medical treatment, research, or nonprofit institution where the activity of smoking is conducted for the purpose of medical research or is an integral part of a smoking cessation program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Theatrical productions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A hotel licensed under § <cite path="§25-113">25-113</cite> shall be exempt from the provisions of this part once a year for one day for the purposes of hosting a special event which permits cigar smoking; provided, that the hotel shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notify the Department of Health in writing in advance of the event;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pay a fee of $2,500 to be remitted to the Regulatory Enforcement Fund as established under § <cite path="§7-732">7-732</cite> [repealed]; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Permit employees to opt out of working the special event with no penalty.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History" path="§4917">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4917</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-90" type="History">as added Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-90, § 2(b), 53 DCR 1087</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 5102, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§7-743">7-743</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</law-cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-167">D.C. Law 18-167</law-cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) A hotel licensed under D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§25-113">25-113</cite>(e) shall be exempt from the provisions of this part once a year for one day for the purposes of hosting a special event which permits cigar smoking; provided, that the hotel:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Notifies the Department of Health in writing in advance of the special event;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Has a ballroom or special event catering space with an occupancy of 500 or more persons;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Permits employees to opt out of working the special event with no penalty; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) Pays a fee of $250 to be remitted to the Department of Health Regulatory Enforcement Fund established under section 4903.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-167">D.C. Law 18-167</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-53">D.C. Law 19-53</law-cite> rewrote subsec. (b) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) A hotel licensed under D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§25-113">25-113</cite> shall be exempt from the provisions of this part once a year for one day for the purposes of hosting a special event that permits cigar smoking; provided, that the hotel shall:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Notify the Department of Health in writing in advance of the event;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Have a ballroom or special-event-catering space with an occupancy of 500 or more persons;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Pay a fee of $250 to be remitted to the Regulatory Enforcement Fund as established under section 4903;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) Permit employees to opt out of working the special event with no penalty; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) Have been the recipient of a similar exemption between January 1, 2008, and October 1, 2011.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 15(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-53">D.C. Law 19-53</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Special Event Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-326, March 9, 2010,  57 DCR 2200).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5042 of Fiscal Year 2012 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-93, June 29, 2011,  58 DCR 5599).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Revised Fiscal Year 2012 Budget Support Technical Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-157, October 4, 2011,  58 DCR 8688).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 5101 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</law-cite> provided that subtitle K of title V of the act may be cited as “Special Events Exemption Amendment Act of 2011”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
