<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-743.03</num>
  <heading>Advisory Committee on Anesthesiologist Assistants.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Advisory Committee on Anesthesiologist Assistants to consist of 3 members as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Health, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An anesthesiologist licensed in the District with experience working with anesthesiologist assistants; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An anesthesiologist assistant licensed in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Of the appointees to the Advisory Committee on Anesthesiologist Assistants other than the Director, one shall serve an initial term of 2 years and one shall serve an initial term of 3 years. Subsequent appointments shall be for terms of 3 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Advisory Committee on Anesthesiologist Assistants shall develop and submit to the Board of Medicine guidelines for licensing and regulating anesthesiologist assistants in the District. The guidelines shall set forth the actions that anesthesiologist assistants may perform under the direct supervision of a licensed anesthesiologist, who shall be responsible for the overall medical direction of the care and treatment of patients.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Guidelines approved by the Board of Medicine under ยง <cite path="ยง3-1202.03">3-1202.03</cite> shall remain in effect until revised guidelines are submitted to and approved by the Board of Medicine.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Advisory Committee on Anesthesiologist Assistants shall submit revised guidelines to the Board of Medicine by June 22, 2015.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Advisory Committee on Anesthesiologist Assistants shall meet at least annually to review the guidelines and make necessary revisions for submission to the Board of Medicine.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, ยง 4943</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-271">as added May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-271, ยง  202(b), 62 DCR 1884</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
