<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-743.06</num>
  <heading>Advisory Committee on Polysomnography.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Advisory Committee on Polysomnography to consist of 3 members as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Health, or his or her designee; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two polysomnographic technologists licensed in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Of the appointees to the Advisory Committee on Polysomnography other than the Director, one shall serve an initial term of 2 years and one shall serve an initial term of 3 years. Subsequent appointments shall be for terms of 3 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Advisory Committee on Polysomnography shall develop and submit to the Board of Medicine guidelines for licensing, registration, and regulation of polysomnographic technologists, polysomnographic technicians, and polysomnographic trainees in the District. The guidelines shall set forth the education and experience requirements for registration and licensure and the actions that polysomnographic technologists, polysomnographic technicians, and polysomnographic trainees may perform.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Guidelines approved by the Board of Medicine under § <cite path="§3-1202.03">3-1202.03</cite> shall remain in effect until revised guidelines are submitted to and approved by the Board of Medicine.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Advisory Committee on Polysomnography shall submit revised guidelines to the Board of Medicine by June 22, 2015.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Advisory Committee on Polysomnography shall meet at least annually to review the guidelines and make necessary revisions for submission to the Board of Medicine.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History" path="§4946">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4946</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-271" type="History">as added May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-271, §  202(b), 62 DCR 1884</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
