<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-761.05a</num>
  <heading>Ticket to Work Employment Network Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Ticket to Work Employment Network Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by DDS in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall consist of revenue from payments from the Social Security Administration as an Employment Network for the Ticket to Work and Self-Sufficiency Program, establish pursuant to the Ticket to Work and Work Incentives Improvement Act of 1999, approved December 17, 1999 (113 Stat. 1863; 42 U.S.C. § 1320b-19).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used for the Ticket to Work and Self-Sufficiency Program; provided, that to the extent that payments received from the Social Security Administration represent administrative or other fee payments, those amounts shall be available to DDS to defray the costs and expenses associated with administering the program or for any other purpose as determined by the Director.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interest earned, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization by Congress, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-264" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 105a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">as added Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5032, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5032 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5032 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 5031 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle D of Title V of the act may be cited as the “Developmental Disabilities Service Management Reform Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
