<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-761.03</num>
  <heading>Establishment and purpose of the Department on Disability Services.</heading>
  <text>Pursuant to § <cite path="§1-204.04">1-204.04</cite>(b), the Department on Disability Services is established as a separate Cabinet-level agency, subordinate to the Mayor, within the executive branch of the District of Columbia, for the purpose of:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Leading the reform of the District’s intellectual and developmental disabilities system by coordinating the collaborative efforts of government agencies, contractor providers, Medicaid waiver providers, labor, and community leaders to improve the care and habilitation services provided to individuals;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Ensuring that District laws, regulations, programs, policies, and budgets are developed and implemented to promote inclusion and integration, independence, self-determination, choice, and participation in all aspects of community life for individuals with developmental disabilities and their families; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Promoting the well-being of individuals with developmental disabilities throughout their life spans, through the delivery of individualized, high-quality, safe services and supports.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-264" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-264, § 103, 54 DCR 818</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 15(b), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-761.02">7-761.02</cite> and § <cite path="§7-1301.03">7-1301.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite>, in (1), substituted “intellectual” for “mental retardation” and “individuals” for “consumers.”</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 103 of Developmental Disabilities Services Management Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-672, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1155).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
