<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-771.06</num>
  <heading>Department organization.</heading>
  <text>The Department shall:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Have a Chief Financial Officer separate from any financial cluster, who shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Be appointed by the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia after consultation with the Director;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Be qualified by experience and training to carry out accounting, budgeting, and financial management functions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Report directly to, be ultimately responsible to, and be under the supervisory direction of the District CFO, through the Director;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Engage in the accounting, budgeting, and financial management functions as authorized by the District CFO;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Serve as a member of the Department management team;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Advocate for and advance the policy objectives of the Director, to the extent consistent with the ultimate responsibility of the Department CFO to, and supervisory control by, the District CFO; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>Be subject to evaluation, discipline, and transfer by the District CFO, in consultation with the Director;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Have a general counsel or the equivalent, who shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Be appointed by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia as an employee of the Office of the Attorney General, after consultation with the Director;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Be an attorney admitted to the practice of law in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Be qualified by experience and training to advise the Department with respect to legal issues related to its powers and duties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Be in the Senior Executive Attorney Service as an at-will employee under the direction and control of the Attorney General;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Be subject to all applicable provisions of subchapter VIII-B of Chapter 6 of Title 1 [ยง <cite root="1-608.51">1-608.51</cite> et seq.];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Have an attorney-client relationship with the Department;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>Advocate vigorously for the positions of the Department on legal issues, and if that advocacy poses a conflict with a legal position of the Attorney General, seek exemption from the supervision of the Attorney General as to that position, in accordance with ยง <cite root="1-608.55">1-608.55</cite>(b); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(H)</num>
      <text>Be subject to evaluation, discipline, and transfer by the Attorney General, after consultation with the Director; and</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Have sufficient staff, supervisory personnel, and resources, and be organized to carry out the functions and duties set forth in this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-109">Feb. 27, 2008, D.C. Law 17-109, ยง 7, 55 DCR 216</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
