<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-901</num>
  <heading>Establishment of register; purpose.</heading>
  <text>That the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall establish and maintain a register of blind persons residing in the District of Columbia. Such register shall, under regulations prescribed by the Council of the District of Columbia, provide information of such nature as will or may be of assistance in the planning of improved facilities and services for blind persons and in the restoration and conservation of sight.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Aug. 3, 1968, 82 Stat. 633, Pub. L. 90-458, § 1</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="7-902">7-902</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-1601.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 6-1401.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Transfer of Functions</heading>
      <annotation>Organization Order No. 104 provided for the establishment, maintenance, and administration of a register of blind persons by the Department of Vocational Rehabilitation. All functions stated in such Order were transferred to the Director of the Department of Human Resources by Commissioner’s Order No. 69-96, dated March 7, 1969, as amended by Commissioner’s Order No. 70-83, dated March 6, 1970. The Department of Human Resources was replaced by the Department of Human Services, by Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, dated February 21, 1980.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
