<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-903</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purpose of this chapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term “blind person” means, and the term “blind” refers to, a person who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is totally blind;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Has impaired vision of not more than 20/200 visual acuity in the better eye and for whom vision cannot be improved to better than 20/200; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Who has loss of vision due wholly or in part to impairment of field vision or to other factors which affect the usefulness of vision to a like degree.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designated agent.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-458" type="History" path="§3">Aug. 3, 1968, 82 Stat. 633, Pub. L. 90-458, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1603.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1403.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
