<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>15-718</num>
  <heading>Juror fees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A juror serving in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall be paid an attendance fee of $30 for each day of actual attendance at the place of trial or hearing, except that jurors employed by a federal, state, or local government or by a private employer who pays regular compensation during the period of jury service shall not be paid an attendance fee. A person summoned for petit jury service in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia who does not serve on the petit jury shall not be paid an attendance fee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A travel allowance not to exceed $2 per day shall be paid to all jurors serving in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For jury service of 5 days or less, petit or grand jurors employed full-time in the District of Columbia shall be entitled to their usual compensation less the fee received for jury service. A person shall not be considered a full-time employed juror on any day of jury service in which that person:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Would not have accrued regular wages to be paid by the employer if the employee were not serving as a juror on that day; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Would not have worked more than 1/2 of a shift that extends into another day if the employee were not serving as a juror on that day. Employers with 10 or less employees shall not be required to pay a juror-employee his or her usual compensation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If an employer fails to pay an employee in violation of subsection (c) of this section, the employee may bring a civil action for recovery of wages or salary lost as a result of the violation. If an employee prevails in an action under this subsection, that employee shall be entitled to reasonable attorney fees fixed by the court.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Board of Judges of the Superior Court may increase the attendance fee and travel allowance provided by this section and, in such event, shall publish the new fee or allowance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-81" type="History">Mar. 9, 1988, D.C. Law 7-81, § 2(c), 34 DCR 8115</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-19" type="History">Aug. 17, 1991, D.C. Law 9-19, title I, § 104, 38 DCR 4066</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-43" type="History">Aug. 17, 1991, D.C. Law 9-43, § 2, 38 DCR 4985</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-156" type="History">Aug. 25, 1994, D.C. Law 10-156, § 2, 41 DCR 4876</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-272" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-272, § 2(a), 54 DCR 856</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of <cite path="§15-719">§ 15-719</cite> 1981 Ed., see § 2 of the Foster Children’s Guardianship Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-433, August 14, 2000,  47 DCR 7467).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-272">D.C. Law 16-272</cite> added subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 15-718.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
