<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 21-139">
  <num type="bill">21-311</num>
  <num type="act">21-139</num>
  <heading type="short">Margaret Peters and Roumania Peters Walker Tennis Courts Designation Emergency Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To designate the tennis courts at Rose Park, located at 2600 O Street, N.W., in Ward 2, as the Margaret Peters and Roumania Peters Walker Tennis Courts.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-07-14</introduced>
    <effective>2015-07-31</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/34273/Signed_Act/B21-0311-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 21-139</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 10880</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0311">
      <vote date="2015-07-14" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-07-31</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Margaret Peters and Roumania Peters Walker Tennis Courts Designation Emergency Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Pursuant to sections 401 of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-201; D.C. Official Code § 9-204.01) ("Act"), and notwithstanding the requirements of section 407 (D.C. Official Code 9-204.07) of the Act, the Council designates the tennis courts at Rose Park, located at 2600 O Street, N.W., in Ward 2, as the "Margaret Peters and Roumania Peters Walker Tennis Courts".</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Transmittal.</heading>
    <text>The Council shall transmit a copy of this act, upon its effective date, to the Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report for the Margaret Peters and Roumania Peters Walker Tennis Courts Act of 2015, passed on 2nd reading on July 14, 2015 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-174), as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code§ l-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
