<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 21-54">
  <num type="bill">21-161</num>
  <num type="act">21-54</num>
  <heading type="short">Jubilee Maycroft TOPA Notice Exemption Emergency Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To exempt, on an emergency basis, Jubilee Maycroft, LLC from the notice requirements of the Tenant Opportunity to Purchase Act of 1980 with respect to the real property located at 1474 Columbia Road, N.W., also known as The Maycroft.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-04-14</introduced>
    <effective>2015-05-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/33661/B21-0161-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 21-54</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 5952</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0161">
      <vote date="2015-04-14" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-05-07</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Jubilee Maycroft TOPA Notice Exemption Emergency Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The transfer of an interest, pursuant to section 402(c)(2)(H) of the Tenant Opportunity to Purchase Act of 1980, effective September 10, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-86; D.C. Official Code ยง 42-3404.02(c)(2)(H)) ("TOPA"), in Jubilee Maycroft, LLC, which owns Lots 2010 - 2072 in Square 2669, located at 1474 Columbia Road, N.W., also known as The Maycroft ("Property"), from Jubilee Housing, Inc. to one or more entities controlled directly or indirectly by Jubilee Housing, Inc. shall be exempt from the notice requirements of section 402(d) of TOPA with respect to the Property.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>No tenant or tenant organization shall have a right to challenge, under sections 503 or 503a of TOPA, the application of section 402(c)(2)(H) of TOPA to the transfer of interests in Jubilee Maycroft, LLC.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rue Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
