<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 5-86">
  <num type="law">5-86</num>
  <heading type="short">Health-Care Assistance Reimbursement Act of 1984</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1984-06-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/5-86.pdf">D.C. Law 5-86</citation>
      <citation type="register">31 DCR 2098</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 5-86, the “Health-Care Assistance Reimbursement Act of 1984,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 5-271, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 27, 1984, and April 10, 1984, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 26, 1984, it was assigned Act No. 5-124 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>40( DAVID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 5-86 "Health-Care Assistance Reimbursement Act of 1984 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 5-271 on first and second readings, March 27, 1984 and April 10, 1984, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 26, 1984, this legislation was assigned Act No. 5-124, published in the May 4, 1984 edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 31 page 2098) and transmitted to Congress April 30, 1984 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 5-86, effective June 14, 1984. Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: April 30 May 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24,30,31 June 1,4,5,6,7,8,11,12,13 New Chaptj 5 of titl 3 New D.C. Code, sec. 3-501 (1985 supp Enrolled Oigini AN ACT 1 D.C. LAW 5 8 6 DATE JUN 1 4 1984 D.C. ACT 5 1 2 4 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APR 2 6 1924 To authorize the District of Columbia to recoup all or part of the expense of providing health-care assistance when the beneficiary has, or would have had but for the government's assistance, a claim against a third party for the care and treatment the District has undertaken to provide or pay for. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Health-Care Assistance Reimbursement Act of 1984 Sec. 2. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term Beneficiary" means any individual who has received health-care assistance from the District and, if applicable, that individual's guardian, conservator, personal representative, estate, dependents, and survivors District" means the District of Columbia 3 Health-care assistance" means health or health-related care and treatment that the District has undertaken to provide or pay for free of charge or at a discounted rate, and includes future care and treatment that the Mayor, in his or her discretion, reasonably anticipates will be provided or paid for by the District. The term "hea l th-care assistance" includes, but shall not be limited to, medical, surgical, nursing, dental, hospital, nursing 1 Enrolled Original home, hospice, and home care, prostheses and medical appliances, physical and occupational therapy, counseling and psychotherapy, social work, related transportation costs, and funeral and burial expenses 4 Third party" means a third-party tortfeasor, beneficiary's insurer, or any other individual, organization, or entity that is or may be liable to a beneficiary, in tort or contract, for all or part of the care and treatment the District has undertaken to provide or pay for as health-care assistance. Sec. 3. Right to Reimbursement Established; Chapt Subrogation and Assignment. titl (a) Whenever the District provides health-care assistance to a beneficiary who has suffered an injury or illness under circumstances creating liability in a third party or under circumstances that would have created such a liability had the beneficiary instead of the District Code 3..50: incurred the expense of the health-care assistance, it shall 85 sup] have an independent, direct cause of action against that New D.C. Code, sec. 3-502 Note D.C. Code, sec. 32-11C (1985 supp. third party for the unreimbursed value or cost of the health-care assistance provided b) As soon as the District begins providing health-care assistance to a beneficiary, it shall become subrogated to any right or claim that the beneficiary has against a third party for the care and treatment it has undertaken to provide or pay for as health-care assistance, Alternatively, or in addition to the legal subrogation effected under this subsection, the Mayor may require a 2 Enrolled Origin beneficiary to execute a written assignment of that same right or claim. Sec. 4. Set-off. Except as provided in subsection (b whenever the District is a defendant in a proceeding brought by a beneficiary, it shall have a right to set off from a judgment against it any damages that represent compensation for the care and treatment it has undertaken to provide or pay for as health-care assistance. No set-off shall be allowed from a judgment entered against the District pursuant to any provision of the Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-137; D.C. Code, sec. 6-1901 et seq Sec. 5. Enforcement of Right; Waiver a) In enforcing its right to reimbursement, the District may: permit the beneficiary to proceed on behalf of the District in prosecuting, in conjunction with his or her own claims, the District's claim for the unreimbursed value or cost of the health-care assistance provided; intervene or join in any proceeding brought by the beneficiary; institute and prosecute a proceeding either alone (in its own or the beneficiary's name) or in conjunction with the beneficiary; or compromise or settle and execute a release of its claim against a third party. New D.C od sec. 3-5 Note D.C. Co secs, 61 1973 1974, 21-1110 (1985 s New D C, Cod. sec, 31-5 01985 so i 114:01111 d Origin (b) The Mayor may waive, in whole or in part, Mii.olled Original enforcement of the District's claim against a third party if enforcement in a particular case would not be cost effective New or would result in undue hardship to the beneficiary, D.C 1 sec. 3 including any dependents or survivors of the actual Note recipient of health-care assistance. If waiver is based on D.C. C secs. the avoidance of undue hardship, the Mayor may in addition 1973 1974, void the legal subrogation or assignment effected pursuant 21-1111 (1985 1 to section 3(b In determining whether and to what extent reimbursement should be sought or awarded under this act, the Mayor or a court, respectively, shall give due consideration to the extent of the beneficiary's injuries and his or her current and future needs, including the current and future needs of any dependents or survivors of few the actual recipient of health-care assistance ‘ C Code (c) No proceeding prosecuted or judgment received by ec, 3.75 985 Su; the District pursuant to this beneficiary's claim or cause act shall be a bar to a of action for elements of damage not covered by the District's cause of action, or shall operate to deny the beneficiary recovery of those elements of damage. Sec. 6. Settlement Probative of Liability. Any settlement or compromise of a claim or cause of action between a beneficiary and third party for more than what in the opinion of the court is a nominal amount in light of the claims asserted shall be admissible in evidence as probative of that third party's liability to the District. 4 New D.C. Code, sec. 3-505 (1985 supp Enrolled Origina Sec. 7. Notice. Any individual or institutional health-care provider that bills the District for health-care assistance furnished to a beneficiary shall provide the Mayor with written notice of any known or suspected third-party liability as soon as the health-care provider acquires knowledge of or suspects the existence of that liability. The written notice shall include the beneficiary's name and, if known, the name of the third party and a description of the circumstances allegedly creating a liability. If either the beneficiary or the Mayor separately institutes a proceeding against or settlement negotiations with a third party, the party instituting the proceeding or negotiations shall have 20 calendar days to give the other party written notice of the action by personal service or certified mail. If a court proceeding has been instituted, proof of timely notice shall be filed with the court. Whenever the Mayor separately institutes a proceeding under this act, written notice to the beneficiary shall advise him or her of the Mayor's right to reimbursement and, if the beneficiary has not proceeded to trial in another proceeding or executed a settlement agreement, his or her rights to intervene or join in the proceeding and to retain private counsel c) After deducting a beneficiary's litigation costs and reasonable attorney's fees, a third party who is aware that the District might have a claim against the remainder of a judgment or settlement awarded or executed in favor of New D. C. Code, sec. 3-506 Note D C. Cod:,1 sec 3-204 (1985 suppl 5 Enrolled Original 3 5 0 P: the beneficiary shall not satisfy the remainder of that judgment or settlement without first giving the Mayor both written notice of the judgment or settlement and 30 calendar days from the date notice is received to determine the appropriateness of a lien under section 8, and, if appropriate, to perfect and satisfy that lien d) If a beneficiary retains private counsel, counsel shall be responsible for giving all notices required by this section. Sec. 8. Lien a) Except as limited by subsections (b) and (c the District shall have a lien, perfected in accordance with subsection (d upon any judgment or settlement awarded or executed in favor of a beneficiary against a third party for that amount of the judgment or settlement that represents the care and treatment it has undertaken to provide or pay New D.C. Code. sec. 3-50 1985 supl for as health-care assistance. If the beneficiary prosecutes a claim on behalf of the District in a proceeding or settlement negotiations and 1001. incurs a personal liability for litigation costs and attorney's fees, the Mayor shall determine in good faith what, if any, contribution to those costs and fees would be appropriate, and that contribution shall be subtracted from the amount of the lien. The beneficiary shall have the right to retain at least 1/5 of the net amount of a judgment or settlement after deducting litigation costs and a reasonable attorney's fee. 6 Enrolled Crigi (d) To perfect a lien under this section, the Mayor, I before payment of any part of a judgment or settlement is made to the beneficiary, shall: file in the Office of the Recorder of Deeds, in a docket provided for this type of lien, a written notice containing the beneficiary's name and address, the approximate date and location of the incident that caused or allegedly caused the beneficiary's injury or illness, and the name of the third party; and provide by personal service or certified mail copies of the written notice of lien together with a statement of the date of filing to the beneficiary, the third party, and, if applicable and ascertained by the Mayor, the insurer of a third-party tortfeasor e) If after receiving a notice of lien under subsection (d)(2) a beneficiary, third party, or an insurer of a third-party tortfeasor disposes of funds covered by a lien perfected under this section without paying the District the amount of its lien that could have been satisfied from those funds after paying off any prior liens, that beneficiary, third party, or insurer shall, for a period of 1 year from the date the funds were improperly disposed of, be liable to the District for any amount that, because of the disposition, it is unable to recover. Sec. 9. Rules. The Mayor may, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq issue New D.C. Co: sec. 3 1985 s 7 Enrolled Original34 rules to effectuate the purposes of this act, including, but not limited to, rules for: determining the unreimbursed value of health or health-related care and treatment that the District undertakes to provide directly; determining the appropriateness and amount of a District contribution under section 8(b establishing procedures to implement the notice requirements in section 7; and facilitating the District's compliance with applicable federal regulations. New Sec. 10. Existing Rights to Reimbursement Preserved. D.C. Code, 3-509 This act shall not be construed to limit or repeal any .Note D.C. Code, other provision of law that invests the District with a secs. 1-624. 1-624.32, right to reimbursement for health-care assistance provided 4-501 (1985 supp to a beneficiary or specified class of beneficiary. Code, 3-508 supp Sec. 11. Partial Retroactive Application. Note D.C. Code, This act shall have full application and effect except sec. 3-501 t 3-509 for those pending cases in which a trial has commenced or a (1985 supp settlement agreement has been executed by the effective date specified in section 12. Sec. 12. Effective Date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of a veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 CC CF CF JA KA MI ayor District •f Columbia APPROVED: April 26, 1984 P2ro11ed or„T (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 Of 4111 ill Ai 4.nfi nMINLAMIgi Ch 'man C•uncil of the District of Columbia COl CH i CRd JAF KM MX CERTIFICATION RECORD 1„,ter:›e) Secretary to the Council Z Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Adopted Final Reading, 4-10-84 5 G,Zat! CERTIFICATION RECORD ate Secretary to e Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Or g COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Five — Second Session RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO. B 5-271 2 Item on Consent Calendar 2 ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Adopted First Reading, 3-27-84 VOICE VOTE Unanimous Recorded vote on request Absent Jarvis ROLL CALL VOTE: — RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE MOORE, JR. SPAULDING CRAWFORD RAY WILSON JARVIS ROLARK WINTER KANE SHACKLETON MASON SMITH, JR. X — Indicates V(c,te A.B. — Absent N.V — Present, not voting 2:1 VOICE VOTE Unanimous Recorded vote on request Absent Spaulding and Smith ROLL CALL VOTE: — RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE MOORE, JR. SPAULDING CRAWFORD RAY WILSON J JARVIS ROLARK WINTER KANE SHACKLETON ,MASON SMITH, JR. X — Indicates Vote A.B. — Absent N.V. — Present, not voting VOICE VOTE. Recorded vote on request Absent. ROLL CALL VOTE: — RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYEINAY N.V. I A.B. I COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. I COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY S N.V. I A.B. CHMN. CLARKE MOORE, JR. SPAULDING CRAWFORD RAY WILSON JARVIS ROLARK WINTER KANE SHACKLETON ,MASON SMITH, JR. X — Indicates Vote A.B. — Absent N.V. — Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date 83-9199-P wd33 Page 1 Page 2 Page 3 Page 4 Page 5 Page 6 Page 7 Page 8 Page 9 Page 10 Page 11</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-601"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-602"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-603"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-604"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-605"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-606"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-607"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-608"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-609"/>
  </section>
</document>
