<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>37-131.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Fund” means the Vending Regulation Fund established by § <cite path="§37-131.07">37-131.07</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Public market” means a vending operation that takes place in an area of public space set aside and permitted on a regular basis for the sale of goods, merchandise, or services provided onsite, which vending operation includes a farmers market, flea market, or antique market.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Vending locations” means the specific locations designated by the Mayor on sidewalks, roadways, and other public space at which a person may vend.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Vending site permit” means a permit or other authorization issued by the Mayor for a vending location.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-71" type="History">Oct. 22, 2009, D.C. Law 18-71, § 2, 56 DCR 6619</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1212.01">2-1212.01</cite>, § <cite path="§10-1141.02">10-1141.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§48-102">48-102</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-144">D.C. Law 19-144</cite> added pars. (1A) and (2A) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1A) ‘Healthy food vendor’ means a vendor that sells only unprocessed, unfrozen, whole, raw fruits and vegetables that have not been combined with other ingredients; provided, that the Mayor, by rule, may expand this definition to include other healthy food items.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2A) ‘Underserved area’ means a historically underutilized business zone, as defined by section 3(p)(1) of the Small Business Act, approved July 18, 1958 (72 Stat. 384;  15 U.S.C. § 632(p)(1)).”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-144">D.C. Law 19-144</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(a) of Vending Regulation Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-322, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3445).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(a) of Vending Regulation Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-9, January 29, 2009,  56 DCR 1638).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(a) of Vending Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-47, April 27, 2009,  56 DCR 3574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Fresh Healthy Mobile Cart Vending Pilot in Underserved Areas Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-325, March 18, 2012,  59 DCR 2261).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Transfer of Authority for Vending Regulation, see Mayor’s Order 2009-106, June 16, 2009, ( 56 DCR 6853).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
