<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>37-131.02</num>
  <heading>Vending from public space.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as set forth in subsection (b) of this section, a person shall not vend from a sidewalk, roadway, or other public space unless the person holds:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A basic business license properly endorsed as provided in subsection (c) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A vending site permit, or other authorization issued by the Mayor, setting forth the specific location on public space from which the person may vend; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Such other licenses, permits, and authorizations that the Mayor may require by rule.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may authorize the following persons to vend from public space without a basic business license or vending site permit:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An employee or youth assistant of a licensed vendor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person vending at a licensed special event;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A person vending at a public market that has been issued a valid permit by the Mayor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A person or entity authorized to vend from public space without a license pursuant to subsection (d) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An endorsement to vend food pursuant to this chapter shall be issued as a Food Establishments: Retail endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of Chapter 28 of Title 47 [§ <cite path="§47-2851.01">47-2851.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An endorsement to vend merchandise or engage in street photography pursuant to this chapter shall be issued as a General Sales endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of Chapter 28 of Title 47 [§ <cite path="§47-2851.01">47-2851.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish by regulation exemptions from the licensure requirement for a person, entity, or categories of persons or entities to vend from public space without a basic business license when the public interest would be served by establishing such an exemption.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-71" type="History">Oct. 22, 2009, D.C. Law 18-71, § 3, 56 DCR 6619</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-79" type="History">Mar. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-79, § 2(a), 63 DCR 762</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-79">D.C. Law 21-79</cite> added (b)(4) and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(a) of Vending Regulation Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-322, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3445).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(a) of Vending Regulation Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-9, January 29, 2009,  56 DCR 1638).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(a) of Vending Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-47, April 27, 2009,  56 DCR 3574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Vending Regulations Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-255, Jan. 6, 2016,  63 DCR 520).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority Pursuant to the Vending Regulation Act of 2009, see Mayor’s Order 2010-91, June 4, 2010 ( 57 DCR 4911).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
