<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>37-131.03</num>
  <heading>Vending locations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall designate the specific vending locations on sidewalks, roadways, and other public spaces where a person may vend.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person shall not vend from a location on a sidewalk, roadway, or other public space other than a vending location designated by the Mayor unless the person is vending at a special event or public market that has been issued a valid license or permit by the Mayor; provided, that notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, vending locations established pursuant to section 6(c-1)(3) of the Vending Regulation Temporary Act of 2008, effective June 5, 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-172">D.C. Law 17-172</cite>; 55 DCR 9144), and the District of Columbia Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Temporary Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-252">D.C. Law 16-252</cite>; 54 DCR 631), shall remain designated vending locations unless:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The space is to be used for a public purpose, including a roadway or public transportation needs, or to protect public safety; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The use of the real property in the immediate vicinity of the vending location changes and the Mayor determines, in his or her reasonable discretion, that the vending location is incompatible with such use.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No more than 350 vending locations shall be established in Ward 2 at any time; provided, that vending locations on the National Mall shall not be included in this limitation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An authorization from the Mayor shall not be required for vending activities subject to § <cite path="§5-331.05">5-331.05</cite>(h).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-71" type="History" path="§4">Oct. 22, 2009, D.C. Law 18-71, § 4, 56 DCR 6619</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-144">D.C. Law 19-144</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “provided, that vending locations on the National Mall and healthy food vendors located in underserved areas shall not be included in this limitation” for “provided, that vending locations on the National Mall shall not be included in this limitation”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-144">D.C. Law 19-144</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(a) of Vending Regulation Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-322, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3445).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(a) of Vending Regulation Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-9, January 29, 2009,  56 DCR 1638).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(a) of Vending Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-47, April 27, 2009,  56 DCR 3574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Fresh Healthy Mobile Cart Vending Pilot in Underserved Areas Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-325, March 18, 2012,  59 DCR 2261).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority Pursuant to the Vending Regulation Act of 2009, see Mayor’s Order 2010-91, June 4, 2010 ( 57 DCR 4911).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
