<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>37-201.28</num>
  <heading>Supervision of markets; investigations and reports.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered to make such regulations as may be necessary for the control, regulation, and supervision of all markets owned by the District of Columbia and the Director, under the direction of the Mayor, shall have supervision of all produce and other markets owned by the District of Columbia, shall enforce such regulations regarding the operation of the same as the Mayor may make, shall make such investigations regarding the sale, distribution, or prices of commodities in the District of Columbia as the Mayor may direct, and shall make reports and recommendations in connection therewith.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 66-3-ch118" path="§28">Mar. 3, 1921, 41 Stat. 1224, ch. 118, § 28</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Apr. 27, 1945, 59 Stat. 99, ch. 99, § 7</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Apr. 11, 1946, 60 Stat. 88, ch. 134, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-116" type="History">May 2, 2002, D.C. Law 14-116, § 4, 49 DCR 1945</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(199) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Home Rule Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Department of Weights, Measures and Markets abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§37-201.01">§ 37-201.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Food Regulation Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-147, October 23, 2001,  48 DCR 10183).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Food Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-128, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7939).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 10(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-55">D.C. Law 14-55</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-55">D.C. Law 14-55</cite> amended the section by substituting “Mayor” for “Council” wherever it appears.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-116">D.C. Law 14-116</cite> substituted “Mayor” for “Council”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 10-130.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 10-132.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Rules and regulations, see <cite path="§1-319" proof="true">§ 1-319</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
