<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-301</num>
  <heading>Immunity from liability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All other provisions of law notwithstanding, a good faith donor of food which is not known or believed to be unfit for human consumption, as defined in Chapter 1 of this title, or rules issued pursuant to that chapter at the time it is donated to a bona fide charitable or not-for-profit organization shall not be subject to criminal or civil liability arising from an injury or death due to the condition of such food unless such injury or death is a direct result of the gross negligence or intentional misconduct of such donor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All other provisions of law notwithstanding, a bona fide charitable or not-for-profit organization which in good faith receives and distributes food which is not known or believed to be unfit for human consumption, as defined in Chapter 1 of this title, or rules issued pursuant to that chapter at the time it is distributed, without charge or at a nominal charge, shall not be subject to criminal or civil liability arising from an injury or death due to the condition of such food unless such injury or death is a direct result of the gross negligence or intentional misconduct of such organization.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-39">Oct. 8, 1981, D.C. Law 4-39, § 2, 28 DCR 3391</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-245">Mar. 8, 1991, D.C. Law 8-245, § 2, 38 DCR 367</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-116">May 2, 2002, D.C. Law 14-116, § 3, 49 DCR 1945</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 33-801.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-116">D.C. Law 14-116</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “Chapter 1 of this title, or rules issued pursuant to that chapter” for “§ 8-6:102 of Title 8 of the District of Columbia Health Regulations (published as Title 8 of the District of Columbia Regulations; 1962 Revision, as amended) (’Health Regulations’)”; and, in subsec. (b), substituted “Chapter 1, of this title, or rules issued pursuant to that chapter” for “§ 8-6:102 of Title 8 of the Health Regulations”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Food Regulation Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-55">D.C. Law 14-55</cite>, December 6, 2001, law notification  49 DCR 356).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Food Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-128, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7939).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Food Regulation Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-147, October 23, 2001,  48 DCR 10183).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Section 8-6:102 of Title 8 of the District of Columbia Health Regulations, referred to in (a) has been superseded by the DCMR. See now  23 DCMR 9902.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
