<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-109</num>
  <heading>Prosecutions; violations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Whenever the Mayor has reason to believe that there has been a violation of this chapter or the rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter, the Mayor shall give written notice of the alleged violation to the licensee, person in charge, or employee. The notice shall state the nature of the violation and shall allow a reasonable time for the performance of the necessary corrective measures. Failure to comply shall result in penalties as set forth in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who violates any of the provisions of this chapter, or the rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter, shall be liable for a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed $10,000 for each violation. Each day of a violation shall constitute a separate offense and the penalties prescribed shall apply separately to each offense.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any person who knowingly violates any of the provisions of this chapter, or the rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter, shall be punished by a fine not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571">22-3571</cite>, or imprisonment not to exceed one year, or both. Each day of a violation shall constitute a separate offense and the penalties prescribed shall apply separately to each offense. Prosecutions for violations of this subsection shall be brought in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Corporation Counsel for the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this chapter, or any rules issued under the authority of this chapter, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Any person who contests a final order of the Mayor issued pursuant to this chapter, after exhaustion of all administrative remedies, is entitled to judicial review of the final order upon filing a written petition for review in the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 17, 1898, 30 Stat. 248, ch. 25, § 9</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Apr. 1, 1942, 56 Stat. 190, ch. 207, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-60" type="History">July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-42" type="History">Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-42, § 476, 32 DCR 4450</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-116" type="History">May 2, 2002, D.C. Law 14-116, § 2(h), 49 DCR 1945</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 251, 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-109.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 33-109.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-116">D.C. Law 14-116</cite> rewrote the section which had read as follows: “All prosecutions under this chapter shall be in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia on information brought in the name of the District of Columbia and on its behalf; and any person or persons violating any of the provisions of this chapter shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction, shall be punished by a fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this chapter, or any rules and regulations issued under the authority of this chapter, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infraction of this chapter shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not to exceed $10,000” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(h) of Food Regulation Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-55">D.C. Law 14-55</cite>, December 6, 2001, law notification  49 DCR 356).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(h) of Food Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-128, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7939).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(h) of Food Regulation Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-147, October 23, 2001,  48 DCR 10183).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 251 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
