<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-401</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Community garden” means an area managed and maintained by a group of individuals to grow and harvest food crops or non-food crops for personal or group consumption, donation, or fundraising that is incidental in nature, and that may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Include individuals working their own portions of a larger garden, or tending a communal garden together;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Be located in the ground, on a roof, or within a building; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Include common areas such as tool storage sheds.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Farm cooperative” means a type of urban farm or farms where production resources for farming such as land and machinery are pooled and jointly held by members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Food” means any substance produced for human consumption and nourishment using horticultural techniques, such as vegetables, fruits, grains, mushrooms, honey, herbs, nuts, seeds, and rootstock.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Horticultural techniques” means the scientific, artistic, and technological methods used to cultivate and manage an agricultural space, such as growing from the ground, hydroponics, container farming, vertical farming, or growing in greenhouses or raised beds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Urban agriculture” or “urban farming” means the practice of growing, cultivating, processing, and distributing vegetables, fruits, grains, mushrooms, honey, herbs, nuts, seeds, flowers, and rootstock within the District, including for profit, not for profit, and for educational purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Urban farm” means any property used for the growing, cultivating, processing, and distributing of vegetables, fruits, grains, mushrooms, honey, herbs, nuts, seeds, flowers, and rootstock within the District, including for profit, not for profit, and for educational purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Vacant lot” means any lot in the District on which there is no lawful structure.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-210" type="History" path="§2">Feb. 28, 1987, D.C. Law 6-210, § 2, 34 DCR 699</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-248" type="History">Apr. 30, 2015, D.C. Law 20-248, § 101(a), 62 DCR 1504</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 301 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-248">D.C. Law 20-248</cite> provided that nothing in the act shall be construed to create a governmental liability or cause of action against the District related to the safety of food purchased on District lands by non-governmental entities.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-248">D.C. Law 20-248</cite>: Section 6183 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> removed the funding requirement and other applicability restrictions in <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-248">D.C. Law 20-248</cite>, § 302, as enacted.</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-248">D.C. Law 20-248</cite>, § 302, see § 6183 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-248">D.C. Law 20-248</cite> rewrote this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-901.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§10-166.01">10-166.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
