<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-843.03</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Pharmaceutical Education Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an evidence-based Pharmaceutical Education Program (“Program”) within the Department of Health. The Program shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Educate prescribers who participate in the District of Columbia Medicaid program, and other publicly funded, contracted, or subsidized health-care programs, on the therapeutic and cost-effective utilization of pharmaceutical products;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Inform prescribers about pharmaceutical product marketing practices that are intended to circumvent competition from generic, other therapeutically-equivalent alternatives, or other evidence-based treatment options; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Utilize, or incorporate into the Program, other independent educational resources or models proven effective in promoting high-quality, evidenced-based, cost-effective information regarding the effectiveness and safety of pharmaceutical products.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Program shall be made available to prescribers who do not participate in the District of Columbia Medicaid program or other publicly funded, contracted, or subsidized health-care programs on a subscription basis.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If approved by the Board of Medicine, the PE program may be used to satisfy continuing education requirements for the practice of medicine.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-131">Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-131, § 403, 55 DCR 1659</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§48-844.03">48-844.03</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
