<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-801.02</num>
  <heading>Posters to be furnished pharmacies; contents.</heading>
  <text>Ten days prior to each issue date, the Office of Consumer Protection shall furnish to each pharmacy in the District a poster suitable for display of a type style and size so as to be easily readable at a reasonable distance, which:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Lists the 100 most commonly used prescription drugs in 2 commonly prescribed quantities, with space for the current selling price of each quantity;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Lists professional and convenience services, with space for each pharmacy to indicate:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Whether it offers each service; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The additional charge, if any, for that service;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Contains a heading stating “OUR CURRENT PRESCRIPTION PRICES” and containing spaces for the insertion of the name and address of each pharmacy;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Indicates in simple language that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The price of a prescription drug is often different at different pharmacies, and that the consumer may want to make a comparison on the cost of a prescription;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The pharmacy may be able to substitute a less expensive drug which is therapeutically equivalent to the one prescribed by the consumer’s doctor, unless the consumer does not approve; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The consumer has the right to know the exact price of a prescription before it is filled; and</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Provides space for each pharmacy to indicate the eligibility and terms of any discount it offers on legend drugs.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-81" type="History" path="§102">Sept. 10, 1976, D.C. Law 1-81, title I, § 102, 23 DCR 2460</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-114" type="History">Apr. 7, 1977, D.C. Law 1-114, § 3(c), 23 DCR 8743</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-712.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 33-812.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
