<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-902.12</num>
  <heading>Schedule V enumerated.</heading>
  <text>The controlled substances listed in this section are included in Schedule V unless and until removed therefrom pursuant to § <cite path="§48-902.01">48-902.01</cite>.</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Any compound, mixture, or preparation containing limited quantities of any of the following narcotic drugs, or salts thereof, which also contains 1 or more nonnarcotic active medicinal ingredients in sufficient proportion to confer upon the compound, mixture, or preparation valuable medicinal qualities other than those possessed by the narcotic drug alone:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Not more than 200 milligrams of codeine per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Not more than 100 milligrams of opium per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Not more than 100 milligrams of dihydrocodeine per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Not more than 100 milligrams of ethylmorphine per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Not more than 2.5 milligrams of diphenoxylate and not less than 25 micrograms of atropine sulfate per dosage unit; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Not more than 0.5 milligrams of difenopin and not less than 25 micrograms of atropine sulfate per dosage unit;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Repealed;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Deleted upon adoption of rule in 34 DCMR 4370 on July 10, 1987;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Unless specifically excepted or unless listed in another schedule, any material, compound, mixture, or preparation containing any of the following narcotic drugs and their salts, as set forth below:</text>
    <text>Buprenorphine;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Prophylhexedrine; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Pyrovalerone.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29" type="History">Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 212, 28 DCR 3081</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">amended by rule, 39 DCR 1882</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-300" type="History">June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-300, § 2(b), 47 DCR 7037</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-3002">7-3002</cite>, § <cite path="§44-1201">44-1201</cite>, § <cite path="§48-853.01">48-853.01</cite>, § <cite path="§48-902.01">48-902.01</cite>, § <cite path="§48-902.02">48-902.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§48-1004">48-1004</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-522.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-300">D.C. Law 13-300</cite> repealed par. (2) which had read: “(2) Cannabis;”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
