<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-902.08</num>
  <heading>Schedule III enumerated.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The controlled substances listed in this section are included in Schedule III, unless and until removed therefrom pursuant to § <cite path="§48-902.01">48-902.01</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Unless specifically excepted or unless listed in another schedule, any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following substances having a stimulant effect on the central nervous system, including its salts, isomers (whether optical, position, or geometric), and salts of such isomers whenever the existence of such salts, isomers, and salts of isomers is possible within the specific chemical designation:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Those compounds, mixtures, or preparations in dosage unit form containing any stimulant substances listed in Schedule II which compounds, mixtures, or preparations were listed on August 25, 1971, as excepted compounds under § 1308.32 of the Code of Federal Regulations, and any other drug of the quantitative composition shown in that list for those drugs or which is the same except that it contains a lesser quantity of controlled substances;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Benzphetamine;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Chlorphentermine;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Chlortermine;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Mazindol; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Phendimetrazine;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Unless listed in another schedule, any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following substances having a potential for abuse associated with a depressant effect on the central nervous system:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any compound, mixture, or preparation containing:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Amobarbital;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Secobarbital; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Pentobarbital; or any salt thereof and 1 or more other active medicinal ingredients which are not listed in any schedule;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any suppository dosage form containing:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Amobarbital;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Secobarbital;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Pentobarbital; or any salt of any of these drugs and approved by the Food and Drug Administration for marketing only as a suppository;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any substance which contains any quantity of a derivative of barbituric acid, or any salt of a derivative of barbituric acid:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Chlorhexadol;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Rescheduled to Schedule II;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Lysergic acid;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Lysergic acid amide;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Methyprylon;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>Sulfondiethylmethane;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>Sulfonethylmethane;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(viii)</num>
          <text>Sulfonmethane;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ix)</num>
          <text>Tiletamine &amp; Zolazepam Combination Product; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(x)</num>
          <text>Vinbarbital;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Nalorphine;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Unless specifically excepted or unless listed in another schedule, any material, compound, mixture, or preparation containing limited quantities of any of the following narcotic drugs, or any salts thereof:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Not more than 1.8 grams of codeine per 100 milliliters or not more than 90 milligrams per dosage unit, with an equal or greater quantity of an isoquinoline alkaloid of opium;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Not more than 1.8 grams of codeine per 100 milliliters or not more than 90 milligrams dosage unit, with 1 or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Not more than 300 milligrams of dihydrocodeinone per 100 milliliters or not more than 15 milligrams per dosage unit, with a 4-fold or greater quantity of an isoquinoline alkaloid of opium;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Not more than 300 milligrams of dihydrocodeinone per 100 milliliters or not more than 15 milligrams per dosage unit, with 1 or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Not more than 1.8 grams of dihydrocodeine per 100 milliliters or not more than 90 milligrams per dosage unit, with 1 or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Not more than 300 milligrams of ethylmorphine per 100 milliliters or not more than 15 milligrams per dosage unit, with 1 or more ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Not more than 500 milligrams of opium per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams or not more than 25 milligrams per dosage unit, with 1 or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Not more than 50 milligrams of morphine per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams with 1 or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Unless specifically excepted or unless listed in another schedule, any material, compound, mixture, or preparation containing any quantity of the following substances, drug, or hormonal substance, chemically and pharmacologically related to testosterone (other than estrogens, progesterons, and corticorsteroids) that promotes muscle growth and includes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Boldenone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Chlortestosterone (4-chlortestosterone);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Clostebol;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Dehydrochlormethyltestosterone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Dihydrotestosterone (4-dihydrotestosterone);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Drostanolone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Ethylestrenol;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Fluoxymestorone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Formebulone (formebolone);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Mesterolone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>Methandienone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(L)</num>
        <text>Methandranone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(M)</num>
        <text>Methandriol;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(N)</num>
        <text>Methandrostenolone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(O)</num>
        <text>Methenolone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(P)</num>
        <text>Methyltestosterone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(Q)</num>
        <text>Mibolerone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(R)</num>
        <text>Nandrolone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(S)</num>
        <text>Norethandrolone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(T)</num>
        <text>Oxandrolone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(U)</num>
        <text>Oxymesterone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(V)</num>
        <text>Oxymetholone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(W)</num>
        <text>Stanolone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(X)</num>
        <text>Stanozolol;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(Y)</num>
        <text>Testolactone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(Z)</num>
        <text>Testosterone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(AA)</num>
        <text>Trenbolone; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(BB)</num>
        <text>Any salt, ester or isomer of a drug or substance described or listed in this paragraph, if that salt, ester, or isomer promotes muscle growth. Except such term does not include an anabolic steroid which is expressly intended for administration through implants to cattle or other nonhuman species and which has been approved by Secretary of Health and Human Services for such administration. If any person prescribes, dispenses or distributes such steroid for human use such person shall be considered to have prescribed, dispensed or distributed an anabolic steroid within the meaning of this paragraph;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Cannabis; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Unless specifically exempted or unless listed in another schedule, any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of cannabimimetic agents, or which contains their salts, isomers, and salts of isomers whenever the existence of such salts, isomers, and salts of isomers is possible within the specific chemical designation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term “cannabimimetic agents” means any substance that is a cannabinoid receptor type 1 (CB1 receptor) agonist as demonstrated by binding studies and functional assays within any of the following structural classes:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>2-(3-hydroxycyclohexyl)phenol with substitution at the 5-position of the phenolic ring by alkyl or alkenyl, whether or not substituted on the cyclohexyl ring to any extent.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>3-(1-naphthoyl)indole or 3-(1- naphthylmethane)indole by substitution at the nitrogen atom of the indole ring, whether or not further substituted on the indole ring to any extent, whether or not substituted on the naphthoyl or naphthyl ring to any extent.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(III)</num>
            <text>3-(1-naphthoyl)pyrrole by substitution at the nitrogen atom of the pyrrole ring, whether or not further substituted in the pyrrole ring to any extent, whether or not substituted on the naphthoyl ring to any extent.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(IV)</num>
            <text>1-(1-naphthylmethylene)indene by substitution of the 3-position of the indene ring, whether or not further substituted in the indene ring to any extent, whether or not substituted on the naphthyl ring to any extent.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(V)</num>
            <text>3-phenylacetylindole or 3-benzoylindole by substitution at the nitrogen atom of the indole ring, whether or not further substituted in the indole ring to any extent, whether or not substituted on the phenyl ring to any extent.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The term “cannabimimetic agents” includes:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>(6aR,10aR)-9-(hydroxymethyl)-6,6-dimethyl-3- (2-methyloctan-2-yl)-6a,7,10, 10a-tetrahydrobenzo[c] chromen-1-ol)(HU-210);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>5-(1,1-dimethylheptyl)-2-[(1R,3S)-3- hydroxycyclohexyl]-phenol (CP 47,497);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(III)</num>
            <text>5-(1,1-dimethyloctyl)-2-[(1R,3S)-3- hydroxycyclohexyl]-phenol (cannabicyclohexanol or CP-47,497 C8-homolog);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(IV)</num>
            <text>1-pentyl-3-(1-naphthoyl)indole (JWH-018 and AM678);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(V)</num>
            <text>1-butyl-3-(1-naphthoyl)indole (JWH-073);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(VI)</num>
            <text>1-hexyl-3-(1-naphthoyl)indole (JWH- 019);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(VII)</num>
            <text>1-[2-(4-morpholinyl)ethyl]-3-(1- naphthoyl)indole (JWH-200);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(VIII)</num>
            <text>1-pentyl-3-(2-methoxyphenylacetyl)indole (JWH-250);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(IX)</num>
            <text>1-pentyl-3-[1-(4-methoxynaphthoyl)]indole (JWH-081);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(X)</num>
            <text>1-pentyl-3-(4-methyl-1-naphthoyl)indole (JWH- 122);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(XI)</num>
            <text>1-pentyl-3-(4-chloro-1-naphthoyl)indole (JWH- 398);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(XII)</num>
            <text>1-(5-fluoropentyl)-3-(1-naphthoyl)indole (AM2201);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(XIII)</num>
            <text>1-(5-fluoropentyl)-3-(2-iodobenzoyl)indole (AM694);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(XIV)</num>
            <text>1-pentyl-3-[(4-methoxy)-benzoyl]indole (SR- 19 and RCS-4);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(XV)</num>
            <text>1-cyclohexylethyl-3-(2- methoxyphenylacetyl)indole (SR-18 and RCS-8); and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(XVI)</num>
            <text>1-pentyl-3-(2-chlorophenylacetyl)indole (JWH-203).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may except by rule any compound, mixture, or preparation containing any stimulant or depressant substance listed in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) of this section from the application of all or any part of this chapter if the compound, mixture, or preparation contains 1 or more active medicinal ingredients not having a stimulant or depressant effect on the central nervous system, and if the admixtures are included therein in combinations, quantity, proportion, or concentration that vitiate the potential for abuse of the substances which have a stimulant or depressant effect on the central nervous system.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29" type="History" path="§208">Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 208, 28 DCR 3081</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">amended by rule, 39 DCR 1882</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">amended by rule Dec. 7, 1994, 41 DCR 7967</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-300" type="History">June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-300, § 2(a), 47 DCR 7037</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-320" type="History">June 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-320, § 301(d), 60 DCR 3390</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-3002">7-3002</cite>, § <cite path="§44-1201">44-1201</cite>, § <cite path="§48-853.01">48-853.01</cite>, § <cite path="§48-902.01">48-902.01</cite>, § <cite path="§48-902.02">48-902.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§48-1004">48-1004</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-518.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-300">D.C. Law 13-300</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), deleted “and” at the end of par. (4)(H), substituted “; and” for the period at the end of par. (5)(BB), and added par. (6).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-320">D.C. Law 19-320</law-cite> added (a)(7); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (a), see § 301(d) of the Omnibus Criminal Code Amendments Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-599, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1017).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 301(d) of the Omnibus Criminal Code Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-44, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5381, 20 DCSTAT 1281).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
