<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-903.08</num>
  <heading>Prescriptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except when dispensed directly by a practitioner, other than a pharmacy, to an ultimate user, no controlled substance in Schedule II may be dispensed without the written prescription of a practitioner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In emergency situations, as defined by rule of the Mayor, Schedule II drugs may be dispensed upon oral prescription of a practitioner, reduced promptly to writing and filed by the pharmacy. Prescriptions shall be retained in conformity with the requirements of § <cite path="§48-903.06">48-903.06</cite>. No prescription for a Schedule II controlled substance may be refilled.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except when dispensed directly by a practitioner, other than a pharmacy, to an ultimate user, a controlled substance included in Schedule III or IV which is a prescription drug as determined under § 353(b) of Title 21, United States Code, shall not be dispensed without a written or oral prescription of a practitioner. The prescription shall not be filled or refilled more than 6 months after the date thereof or be refilled more than 5 times, unless renewed by the practitioner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A controlled substance included in Schedule V shall not be distributed or dispensed other than for a medical purpose.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Whenever a practitioner dispenses any controlled substance on a written or oral prescription issued by a practitioner, the practitioner shall affix to the container in which such controlled substance is dispensed a label showing the name of the controlled substance or controlled substances contained therein unless otherwise so indicated by the prescribing practitioner; the serial number and date of initial filling; the directions for use; the practitioner’s name and registry number; the name of the ultimate user, or if the ultimate user is an animal, the name of the owner and the species of the animal; the name of the practitioner issuing the prescription; and caution statements, if any, as required by law.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29" type="History">Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, title III, § 308, 28 DCR 3081</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§48-904.02">48-904.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-538.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
