<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-911.01</num>
  <heading>Consumption of marijuana in public space prohibited; impairment prohibited.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other District law, it is unlawful for any person to smoke or otherwise consume marijuana in or upon a public space, or in or upon any of the following places:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A street, alley, park, sidewalk, or parking area;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A vehicle in or upon any street, alley, park, or parking area; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any place to which the public is invited.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No person, whether in or on public or someone else’s private property, shall be impaired due to smoking or otherwise consuming marijuana and endanger the safety of himself, herself, or any other person or property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any person violating the provisions of subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be punished by a fine of not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> or imprisoned for not more than 60 days.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia, or his or her assistants, shall prosecute violations of this section, in the name of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “smoke” means to inhale, ingest, or otherwise introduce marijuana into the human body, or to hold or carry a lighted roll of paper or other lighted smoking equipment filled with marijuana.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-126" type="History">July 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-126, § 301, 61 DCR 3482</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-11">D.C. Law 21-11</cite>, June 4, 2015,  62 DCR 4717).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment and addition of section, see § 2 of the Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2016 <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-98"> D.C. Law 21-98</cite>, April 6, 2016, 63 DCR 2211, 20 DCSTAT 3135).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-19, Mar. 26, 2015,  62 DCR 3857, 21 DCSTAT 852).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Marijuana Possession Decriminalization Clarification EmergencyAmendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-273, Jan. 14, 2016,  63 DCR 801).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 501 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-126">D.C. Law 20-126</cite> provided that the Mayor, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], may issue rules to implement the provisions of the act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
