<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-904.03</num>
  <heading>Prohibited acts C; penalties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It is unlawful for any person knowingly or intentionally:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To distribute as a registrant a controlled substance classified in Schedule I or II, except pursuant to an order form as required by § <cite path="§48-903.07">48-903.07</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To use in the course of the manufacture or distribution of a controlled substance a registration number which is fictitious, revoked, suspended, or issued to another person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To acquire or obtain possession of a controlled substance by misrepresentation, fraud, forgery, deception, or subterfuge;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>To furnish false or fraudulent material information in, or omit any material information from, any application, report, or other document required to be kept or filed under this chapter, or any record required to be kept by this chapter; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>To make, distribute, or possess any punch, die, plate, stone, or other thing designed to print, imprint, or reproduce the trademark, trade name, or other identifying mark, imprint, or device of another or any likeness of any of the foregoing upon any drug or container or labeling thereof so as to render the drug a counterfeit substance.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any person who violates this section is guilty of a crime and upon conviction may be imprisoned for not more than 4 years, fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29" type="History" path="§403">Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 403, 28 DCR 3081</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 252(c), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-543.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $50,000” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 252(c) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
