<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-903.05</num>
  <heading>Registration — Procedural rights involving suspension or revocation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If it appears to the Mayor that an application for registration should be denied or that an existing registration should be suspended or revoked, the Mayor shall notify the applicant or registrant of the proposed denial, suspension, or revocation, briefly stating the reasons therefor. In the case of a denial of renewal of registration, notice shall be served not later than 30 days before the expiration of the registration. Service may be made by delivering a copy of the notice to the applicant or registrant personally, or by leaving a copy thereof at the place of residence identified on the application or registration with some person of suitable age and discretion then residing therein, or by mailing a copy of the notice by certified mail to the residence address identified on the application or certificate, in which case service shall be complete as of the date the return receipt was signed. In the case of an organization, service may be made upon the president, chief executive, or other officer, managing agent, or person authorized by appointment or law to receive such notice as described in the preceding sentence at the business address of the organization identified in the application or registration certificate. The person serving the notice shall make proof thereof with the Mayor in a manner prescribed by the Mayor. In the case of service by certified mail, the signed return receipt shall be filed with the Mayor together with a signed statement showing the date such notice was mailed and if the return receipt does not purport to be signed by the person named in the notice, then specific facts from which the Mayor can determine that the person who signed the receipt meets the appropriate qualifications for receipt of such notice set out in this subsection. The applicant or registrant shall have 30 days from the date the notice was served in which to request a hearing before the Mayor to contest the proposed action to be taken by the Mayor; provided, that if the applicant or registrant does not request a hearing within 30 days after the serving of the notice of the proposed action, the applicant or registrant shall be deemed to have conceded the validity of the reason or reasons stated in the notice, and the denial, suspension, or revocation shall become final. Within 30 days of the date upon which any contest is noted, the Mayor shall convene a hearing. Within 10 days of the close of the hearing, the Mayor shall notify the applicant or registrant of the decision in the case. All proceedings, including the right to judicial review of the Mayor’s decision, shall be in accordance with the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act. Where the application for renewal of registration has been timely filed, proceedings to refuse renewal of registration shall not abate the existing registration, which shall remain in effect pending the outcome of the administrative hearing. With regard to summary suspension of any registrant or the denial of renewal to any registration pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, a hearing shall be convened within 5 days of the institution of proceedings in this section; except, that a registrant who has been summarily suspended or denied a renewal under this section shall be entitled upon request to a postponement of such hearing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may suspend, without prior notice and hearing, any registration simultaneously with the institution of proceedings under § <cite path="§48-903.04">48-903.04</cite>, or where renewal of registration is refused, if the Mayor finds that there is an imminent danger to the public health or safety which warrants this action, including, but not limited to, the danger that would be created by the outbreak of a serious fire on the business premises of a registrant on which controlled substances are stored, resulting in heat in excess of 110 degrees fahrenheit; grossly inadequate security measures; or while proceedings under § <cite path="§48-903.04">48-903.04</cite> are pending, continued and flagrant violations of the same sort which led to the institution of the pending proceedings.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The suspension shall continue in effect until the conclusion of the proceedings, including judicial review thereof, unless sooner withdrawn by the Mayor or dissolved by a court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29">Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 305, 28 DCR 3081</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 33-535.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>The “District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act,” referred to in the tenth sentence of subsection (a), is codified in Chapter 5 of Title 2.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
