<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-903.02</num>
  <heading>Registration — Required; renewal; exceptions; waiver; inspection.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Every person who manufactures, distributes, or dispenses any controlled substance within the District of Columbia, or who proposes to engage in the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of any controlled substance within the District of Columbia, must obtain annually a registration issued by the Mayor in accordance with the rules. Applications to renew a registration must be filed in a timely manner, not less than 60 days prior to the expiration of the registration, or the registration shall abate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Persons registered with the Mayor under this chapter to manufacture, distribute, dispense, or conduct research with controlled substances may possess, manufacture, distribute, dispense, or conduct research with those substances to the extent authorized by their registration and in conformity with the other provisions of this subchapter. Any person registered under this subchapter whose authority to possess, distribute, dispense, or conduct research with controlled substances is limited or otherwise restricted by any federal, state, or District of Columbia law, shall use such registration only to the extent authorized by said federal, state, or District of Columbia law unless otherwise specified.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The following persons need not register and may lawfully possess controlled substances under this chapter:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An agent or employee of any registered manufacturer, distributor, or dispenser of any controlled substance acting in the usual course of business or employment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A common or contract carrier or warehouseman, or an employee thereof, whose possession of any controlled substance is in the usual course of business or employment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An ultimate user or a person in possession of any controlled substance pursuant to a lawful order of a practitioner or in lawful possession of a Schedule V substance; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department, or a law-enforcement official or agent of the District of Columbia or the United States if he or she is on duty and is acting in the performance of officially authorized functions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may waive by rule the requirement for registration of certain manufacturers, distributors, or dispensers if the Mayor finds it consistent with the public health and safety.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A separate registration is required for each principal place of business or professional practice where the applicant manufactures, distributes, or dispenses controlled substances.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may inspect the establishment of a registrant or applicant for registration in accordance with subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29" type="History">Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, title III, § 302, 28 DCR 3081</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-136" type="History">July 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-136, § 2(b), 45 DCR 2942</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-284" type="History">June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-284, § 10(a), 46 DCR 1328</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§48-903.03">48-903.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-532.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 10(a) of Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-282">D.C. Law 12-282</cite>, May 28, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 5148).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 10(a) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization and Street Solicitation for Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-428, August 6, 1998,  45 DCR 45 5884), § 10(a) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-506, November 10, 1998,  45 DCR 45 8139), and § 10(a) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-13, February 8, 1999,  46 DCR 2333).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
