<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-904.10</num>
  <heading>Possession of drug paraphernalia.</heading>
  <text>Whoever, except for a physician, dentist, chiropodist, or veterinarian licensed in the District of Columbia or a state, registered nurse, registered embalmer, manufacturer or dealer in embalming supplies, wholesale druggist, industrial user, official of any government having possession of the proscribed articles by reason of his or her official duties, nurse or medical laboratory technician acting under the direction of a physician or dentist, employees of a hospital or medical facility acting under the direction of its superintendent or officer in immediate charge, person engaged in chemical, clinical, pharmaceutical or other scientific research, acting in the course of their professional duties, has in his or her possession a hypodermic needle, hypodermic syringe, or other instrument that has on or in it any quantity (including a trace) of a controlled substance with intent to use it for administration of a controlled substance by subcutaneous injection in a human being shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> or imprisoned for not more than 180 days, or both.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29" type="History">Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 410, 28 DCR 3081</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-151" type="History">Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151, § 112(b), 41 DCR 2608</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 252(e), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Needle exchange program, privileges and immunities, see § <cite path="§48-1103.01">48-1103.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-403">7-403</cite> and § <cite path="§48-1103.01">48-1103.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-550.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $1,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 252(e) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite>: Section 401 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
