<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-902.14</num>
  <heading>Treatment of controlled substance analogues.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A controlled substances analogue shall, to the extent intended for human consumption, be treated for the purposes of any District of Columbia law as a controlled substance in Schedule I.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the term “controlled analogue” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>a substance with a chemical structure that is substantially similar to the chemical structure of a controlled substance in Schedule I or II;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A substance that has a stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system that is substantially similar to or greater than the stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central system of a controlled substance in Schedule I or II; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A substance that, with respect to a particular person, is represented to have or is intended to have a stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system that is substantially similar to, or greater than the stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system of  a controlled substance in Schedule I or II.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Such term does not include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A controlled substance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any substance for which there is an approved new drug application;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>With respect to a particular person any substance, if an exemption is in effect for investigational use, for that person, under § 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, approved June 25, 1938 (52 Stat. 1052, 21 U.S.C. § 355) to the extent conduct with respect to such substance is pursuant to such exemption; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any substance to the extent not intended for human consumption before such an exemption takes effect with respect to that substance.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29" type="History" path="§214">August 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 214</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-99" type="History">as added May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-99, § 2(b), 47 DCR 791</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
