<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-905.05</num>
  <heading>Administrative inspections.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may make administrative inspections of controlled premises in accordance with the following provisions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For purposes of this section only, the term “controlled premises” means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Places where persons registered or exempted from registration requirements under this chapter are required to keep records; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Places including factories, warehouses, establishments, and conveyances in which persons registered or exempted from registration requirements under this chapter are permitted to hold, manufacture, compound, process, sell, deliver, or otherwise dispose of any controlled substance.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When authorized by an administrative inspection warrant issued pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, an officer, an employee designated by the Mayor, or a designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department, upon presenting the warrant and appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, may enter controlled premises for the purpose of conducting an administrative inspection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>When authorized by an administrative inspection warrant, an officer or employee designated by the Mayor may:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Inspect and copy records required by this chapter to be kept;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Inspect, within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner, controlled premises and all pertinent equipment, finished and unfinished material, containers and labeling found therein, and, except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, all other things therein, including records, files, papers, processes, controls, and facilities bearing on violation of this chapter; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Inventory any stock of any controlled substance therein and obtain samples thereof.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>This section does not prevent the inspection without a warrant of books and records pursuant to an administrative subpoena issued in accordance with § <cite path="§48-905.07">48-905.07</cite> nor does it prevent entries and administrative inspections, including seizures of property, without a warrant:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the controlled premises consents;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In situations presenting imminent danger to health or safety;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>In situations involving inspection of conveyances if there is reasonable cause to believe that the mobility of the conveyance makes it impracticable to obtain a warrant;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>In any other exceptional or emergency circumstance where time or opportunity to apply for a warrant is lacking; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>In all other situations in which a warrant is not constitutionally required.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>An inspection authorized by this section shall not extend to financial data, sales data, other than shipment data, or pricing data unless the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the controlled premises consents in writing.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Issuance and execution of administrative inspection warrants shall be as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, upon proper oath or affirmation showing probable cause, may issue warrants for the purpose of conducting administrative inspections authorized by this chapter or rules hereunder, and seizures of property appropriate to the inspections. For purposes of the issuance of administrative inspection warrants, probable cause exists upon showing a valid public interest in the effective enforcement of this chapter or rules hereunder, sufficient to justify administrative inspection of the area, premises, building, or conveyance in the circumstances specified in the application for the warrant.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A warrant shall issue only upon an affidavit of a designated officer or employee having knowledge of the facts alleged, sworn to before the judge and establishing the grounds for issuing the warrant. If the judge is satisfied that grounds for the issuance of the warrant exist or that there is probable cause to believe they exist, a warrant shall be issued identifying the area, premises, building, or conveyance to be inspected, the purpose of the inspection, and, if appropriate, the type of property to be inspected, if any. The warrant shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>State the grounds for its issuance and the name of each person whose affidavit has been taken in support thereof;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Be directed to a person authorized and designated by the Mayor to execute it;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Command the person to whom it is directed to inspect the area, premises, building, or conveyance identified for the purpose specified and, if appropriate, direct the seizure of the property specified;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Identify the item or types of property to be seized, if any; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Direct that it be served during normal business hours and designate the judge to whom it shall be returned.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A warrant issued pursuant to this section must be executed and returned within 10 days of its date unless, upon a showing of a need for additional time, the Court orders otherwise. If property is seized pursuant to a warrant, a copy shall be given to the person from whom or from whose premises the property is taken, together with a receipt for the property taken. The return of the warrant shall be made promptly, accompanied by a written inventory of any property taken. The inventory shall be made in the presence of the person executing the warrant and of the person from whose possession or premises the property was taken, if present, or in the presence of at least one person other than the person executing the warrant. A copy of the inventory shall be delivered to the person from whom or from whose premises the property was taken and to the applicant for the warrant.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29" type="History">Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 505, 28 DCR 3081</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-284" type="History">June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-284, § 10(d), 46 DCR 1328</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-555.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 10(d) of Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-282">D.C. Law 12-282</cite>, May 28, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 5148).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 10(d) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization and Street Solicitation for Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-428, August 6, 1998,  45 DCR 5884), § 10(d) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-506, November 10, 1998,  45 DCR 8139), and § 10(d) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-13, February 8, 1999,  46 DCR 2333).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
