<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-905.02</num>
  <heading>Forfeitures.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The following property is subject to forfeiture if determined to be used in furtherance of or as proceeds of the manufacture or distribution of a controlled substance as prohibited by §  48-904.01(a): containers, conveyances, equipment, raw materials, real property, money, currency, securities, negotiable instruments, instrumentalities, books, records, and research products, including formulas and data.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Contraband is not subject to forfeiture under this section, but may be seized and disposed of in accordance with applicable law; provided, that controlled substances shall be retained until the prosecutorial authority responsible for prosecuting a violation under this chapter certifies that such controlled substances are no longer needed as evidence.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No property shall be subject to forfeiture for conduct involving only a violation of § <cite path="§48-904.01">48-904.01</cite>(d).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All seizures and forfeitures under this section shall follow the standards and procedures set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-278">D.C. Law 20-278</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29" type="History">Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 502, 28 DCR 3081</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-96" type="History">Apr. 3, 1982, D.C. Law 4-96, § 2, 29 DCR 762</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-162" type="History">Sept. 29, 1988, D.C. Law 7-162, § 2, 35 DCR 5733</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 101-223" type="History">Dec. 12, 1989, 103 Stat. 1901, Pub. L. 101-223, § 6</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-138" type="History">June 13, 1990, D.C. Law 8-138, § 2(d), 37 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-155" type="History">Sept. 26, 1992, D.C. Law 9-155, § 2(a), 39 DCR 5679</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-253" type="History">Mar. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 9-253, § 3, 40 DCR 790</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-255" type="History">May 16, 1995, D.C. Law 10-255, § 25, 41 DCR 5193</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-284" type="History">June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-284, § 10(c), 46 DCR 1328</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-160" type="History">October 4, 2000, D.C. Law 13-160, § 403(b), 47 DCR 4619</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 9067(a), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 98(d), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-278" type="History">June 16, 2015, D.C. Law 20-278, § 201(b), 62 DCR 1920</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-2507.06a">7-2507.06a</cite>, § <cite path="§22-902">22-902</cite>, and § <cite path="§22-2723">22-2723</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 33-552.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-160">D.C. Law 13-160</cite> rewrote subsec. (b) which formerly provided: “(b) Property subject to forfeiture under this chapter may be seized by law enforcement officials, as designated by the Mayor, or designated civilian employees of the Metropolitan Police Department, upon process issued by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia having jurisdiction over the property, or without process if authorized by other law.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> rewrote subsec. (d)(3)(B), which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(B) Any person claiming the property may, at any time within 30 days from the date of receipt of notice of seizure, file with the Mayor a claim stating his or her interest in the property. Upon the filing of a claim, the claimant shall give a bond to the District government in the penal sum of $2,500 or 10% of the fair market value of the claimed property (as appraised by the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department), whichever is lower, but not less than $250, with sureties to be approved by the Mayor. In case of forfeiture of the claimed property, the costs and expenses of the forfeiture proceedings shall be deducted from the bonds. Any costs that exceed the amount of the bond shall be paid by the claimant. In determining the fair market value of the property seized, the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department shall consider any verifiable and reasonable evidence of value that the claimant may present. The balance of the proceeds shall be transferred to the Drug Interdiction and Demand Reduction Fund (’Fund’) created by subchapter VII of this chapter. The Fund shall remain available until expended regardless of the expiration of the fiscal year in which the proceeds were collected. The Fund shall be distributed in the following descending order of priority:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“ (i) To fund law enforcement activities of the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia, except that, beginning October 1, 1990, not more than 49% of the total amount deposited to the Fund in the immediately preceding quarter-year period shall be used for this purpose in the next succeeding quarter-year period; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(ii) To provide grants to fund community-based drug education, prevention, and demand reduction programs;”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-278">D.C. Law 20-278</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 10(c) of Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-282">D.C. Law 12-282</cite>, May 28, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 5148).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 10(c) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization and Street Solicitation for Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-428, August 6, 1998,  45 DCR 5884), § 10(c) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-506, November 10, 1998,  45 DCR 45 8139), and § 10(c) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-13, February 8, 1999,  46 DCR 2333).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 23-527, referred to in subsec. (a-1), did not exist in the 1981 Edition at the time of the recodification into the 2001 Edition.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor to implement public information program: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§48-901.02">48-901.02</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-278">D.C. Law 20-278</cite>, referred to in (d), enacted Chapter 3 of Title 41 (§ <cite path="§41-301">41-301</cite> et seq.), made amendments to the criminal offenses in §§ <cite path="§48-901.02">48-901.02</cite> and <cite path="§48-905.02">48-905.02</cite>, and made conforming amendments to §§ <cite path="§7-2507.06a">7-2507.06a</cite>, <cite path="§8-905">8-905</cite>, <cite path="§22-902">22-902</cite>, <cite path="§22-1705">22-1705</cite>, <cite path="§22-2723">22-2723</cite>, <cite path="§32-1343">32-1343</cite>, <cite path="§48-905.03">48-905.03</cite>, and <cite path="§50-1501.04">50-1501.04</cite>.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
