<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>35-233</num>
  <heading>Validity of reduced fares; requirements for eligibility.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>On regular school days, no student shall be charged a bus fare for regular route transportation within the District during peak and off-peak hours on the Metrobus Transit System and the DC Circulator.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The fare to be paid by a student on regular school days for regular route transportation during peak and off-peak hours on the Metrorail Transit System within the District shall be as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>$30 dollars for a monthly pass; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>$9.50 for a 10-trip rail pass.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The fares listed in paragraph(2) of this subsection shall be modified by the same percentage as future Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority fare increases or decreases, rounded to the nearest dime ($.10).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>This reduced student fare shall be valid only for transportation of students going to and from public, parochial, and private schools, and to and from related educational activities in the District of Columbia on school days.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Student travel on Metrobus and Metrorail during Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and vacations shall be charged at the regular rate charged to passengers other than students and senior citizens, except for travel to and from a recognized school-related educational activity in the District of Columbia. The Mayor shall issue rules and regulations to enforce this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Reduced fares for students under this section on the Metrobus and Metrorail Transit Systems and the DC Circulator shall be available only to persons who are under 22 years of age and are:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>District residents; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Currently enrolled in a regular course of instruction at an elementary or secondary public, parochial, or private school located in the District; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Youth in the District’s foster care system until they reach 21 years of age.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Reduced fares for students on the Metrorail Transit System shall be available only to persons who possess a valid student Metrorail discount card.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the fare to be paid by students on regular school days for regular route transportation during peak and off-peak hours on the Metrobus Transit System and on the Metrorail Transit System shall be $.15 from September 26, 1981, until December 31, 1981.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Youth in the District’s foster care system shall be eligible for a foster-youth transit-subsidy program (“Program”) as established by the Mayor until they reach 21 years of age.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Program shall allow qualified foster youth to travel on Metrobus, Metrorail, and public transportation services offered by the District at subsidized or reduced fares.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The subsidized or reduced foster-youth fare set forth in this subsection shall be valid only for the transportation of foster youth for educational or employment purposes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Participants in the Summer Youth Employment Program (“SYEP”) administered by the Department of Employment Services pursuant to <cite path="§32-241">§ 32-241</cite> shall be eligible for a summer youth transit subsidy program (“Program”) as established by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Program shall allow qualified SYEP participants to travel on Metrobus, Metrorail, and public transportation services offered by the District at subsidized or reduced fares.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The subsidized or reduced fares established pursuant to this subsection shall be valid only for the transportation of SYEP participants to and from their internships and related activities for the first 3 weeks of the summer 2015 SYEP.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Subject to available funds, the Mayor may establish a program for students to receive subsidies for the Metrorail Transit System that would supplement the reduced student fares established by this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To be eligible for the program, a student shall be:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Under 22 years of age; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Enrolled in a District of Columbia public school or public charter school at the 12th grade or lower or enrolled in an alternative, adult, or special education District of Columbia public school or public charter school.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall require each student, student’s parent or guardian, or student’s school counselor to file an application to participate in the program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The subsidy benefit shall be distributed by fare card or similar medium acceptable to the Washington Area Metropolitan Transit Authority.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The transit subsidy established by this subsection shall be capped at $100 per month per student.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The total appropriation available for the program shall not exceed $7 million.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-152" type="History" path="§2">Mar. 6, 1979, D.C. Law 2-152, § 2, 25 DCR 2534</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-33" type="History">Sept. 26, 1981, D.C. Law 4-33, § 2(a), (b), 28 DCR 3187</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 815, 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-156" type="History">Oct. 7, 1998, D.C. Law 12-156, § 2, 45 DCR 4617</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 6082, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, §§ 2112, 10003, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-117" type="History">June 26, 2014, D.C. Law 20-117, §§ 7, 8(c), 61 DCR 2032</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 2052, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, §  6192, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 2111 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle L of Title II of the act may be cited as the “Foster Youth Transit Subsidy Amendment Act of 2013”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 10001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Title X of the act may be cited as the “Revised Revenue Estimate Adjustment Allocation Act of 2013”.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-117">D.C. Law 20-117</cite>: Section 18 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-117">D.C. Law 20-117</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 6193 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> provided that § 6192 the act (which added (h)) shall expire on September 30, 2016.</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 9 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-292, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1211).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  2(b) and 5 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-164, Oct. 16, 2015,  62 DCR 13734).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 6192 and 6193 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2052 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2052 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2052 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2112 and 10003 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2112 and 10003 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the School Transit Subsidy Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-203, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15339).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 to 4 of the School Transit Subsidy Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-145, July 31, 2013,  60 DCR 11805, 20 DCSTAT 1996).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Foster Youth Transit Subsidy Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-65, May 11, 2013,  60 DCR 7228, 20 DCSTAT 1414).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 11 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-76">D.C. Law 21-76</cite>, Feb. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 264).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the School Transit Subsidy Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-43">D.C. Law 20-43</cite>, December 5, 2013,  60 DCR 14718).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Foster Youth Transit Subsidy Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-20">D.C. Law 20-20</cite>, October 3, 2013,  60 DCR 10876).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> added (h).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added (g).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-117">D.C. Law 20-117</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>, § 10003; rewrote (a) and (c); and added (g).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> rewrote (a) and (c); and added (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added (c)(4); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 44-214.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 44-217.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§35-234">§ 35-234</cite>, <cite path="§35-235">§ 35-235</cite>, and <cite path="§35-236">§ 35-236</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
