<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>35-215</num>
  <heading>Annual reports to Congress.</heading>
  <text>Every street-railroad corporation in the District of Columbia, and every such corporation which shall be organized after June 10, 1896, shall, on or before the 1st day of February in each year, make a report to each the Senate and the House of Representatives, which report shall be sworn to and signed by the president and treasurer of such corporation, and shall cover the period of 1 year ending the 31st day of December previous to the date of making the report. Such report shall state the amount of capital stock, with a list of the stockholders and the amount of stock held by each; the amount of capital stock paid in; the total amount now of funded debt; the amount of floating debt; the average rate per annum of interest on funded debt; amount of dividends declared; cost of roadbed and superstructure, including iron; cost of land, buildings, and fixtures, including land damages; cost of cars, horses, harness, and motors and other machinery; total cost of road and equipment; length of road in miles; length of double track, including sidings; weight of rail, by yard; the number of cars and of horses; the number of motors; the total number of passengers carried in cars; the average time consumed by passenger cars in passing over the road; repairs of roadbed and railway, including iron, and repairs of buildings and fixtures; total cost of maintaining road and real estate; cost of general superintendence; salaries of officers, clerks, agents, and office expenses; wages paid conductors, drivers, engineers, and motor men; water and other taxes; damages to persons and property, including medical attendance; rents, including use of other roads; total expense of operating road, and repairs; receipts from passengers; receipts from all other sources, specifying what, in detail; total receipts from all sources during the year; payments for maintenance and repairs; payments for interest; payments for dividends on stock, amount and rate per centum; total payments during the year; the number of persons injured in life and limb; the cause of the injury, and whether to passengers, employees, or other persons.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 10, 1896, 29 Stat. 320, ch. 395, § 10</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 44-222.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 44-215.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
