<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-155">
  <num type="law">15-155</num>
  <heading type="short">Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2004-05-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-155.pdf">D.C. Law 15-155</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 3389</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0606">
      <narrative>Law 15-155, the “Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-606, which was referred to Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 3, 2004, and March 2, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 18, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-390 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-155 became effective on May 18, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Choice in Drug Treatment Act of 2000 to rename and revise the membership of the Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission Amendment Act of 2004 Sec. 2. Section 15 of the Choice in Drug Treatment Act of 2000, effective July 18, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-146; D.C. Official Code § 7-3014 is amended to read as follows: “Sec. 15. Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission a)(1) There is established a Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission Commission with the purpose of advising on the implementation of the Program and recommending improvements to its infrastructure to the Council and the Mayor. “(2) The Commission shall consider approaches to reduce barriers to meaningful choice in drug treatment by working closely with APRA: “(A) To establish clear access to services; “(B) To provide for linkages among providers and other support services; “(C) To assure that services are culturally competent and sensitive; “(D) To assure that the delivery of services adjusts to changing needs and emerging issues; and “(E) To provide any other assistance that may be required. “(3) The Commission shall submit its recommendations to the Council and the Mayor in the form of a report, with specific steps for implementing its recommendations, within one year of the effective date of the Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission Amendment Act of 2004, passed on 2nd reading on March 2, 2004 (Enrolled version of Bill 15- 606 and every 6 months thereafter. “(b)(1) The Commission shall be composed of 13 members as follows: “(A) One representative from APRA, to be appointed by the Mayor for an initial term of 4 years; Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2004 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 7-3014 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. “(B) One representative from APRA who specializes in youth treatment and one representative from the Department of Mental Health, to be appointed by the Mayor for initial terms of 3 years; “(C) One representative from APRA and one representative from the Department of Human Services, Family Services Administration, to be appointed by the Mayor for initial terms of 2 years; “(D) One treatment provider who treats youths, one representative from the housing sector who assists homeless persons who have substance abuse problems to obtain housing, and one representative from the medical profession, to be appointed by the Council for initial terms of 4 years; “(E) Two treatment providers, one of whom must specialize in the treatment of Latinos with substance abuse issues, and one representative from the employment sector, to be appointed by the Council for initial terms of 3 years; and “(F) One treatment provider and one client representative, to be appointed by the Council for initial terms of 2 years. “(2) All appointments, following the initial appointments made pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall be for terms of 3 years. “(3) All initial appointments made pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be made within 180 days of the effective date of the Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission Amendment Act of 2004, passed on 2nd reading on March 2, 2004 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-606 “(4) A vacancy shall be filled in the same way the initial appointment was made. “(5) The initial Chairperson shall be appointed by the Council from among the members of the Commission. Subsequent chairpersons shall be appointed by the members of the Commission from among the members of the Commission. “(6) Each member shall serve without compensation. “(c) The Chairperson, or the Chairperson’s designee, shall convene all meetings of the Commission. Seven members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum. “(d) The Commission shall have the authority to create and operate under its own rules of procedure, consistent with this act and the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq “(e) All recommendations and reports prepared and submitted by the Commission shall be a matter of public record. “(f) The Commission shall have the authority to request directly from each department, agency, or instrumentality of the District government, and each department, agency, or instrumentality is hereby authorized to furnish directly to the Commission upon its request, any information deemed necessary by the Commission to carry out its functions under this act. “(g) The Commission is authorized to use space and supplies owned or rented by the District government. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. “(h) Funding for the Commission's operations shall be subject to annual appropriations, private sector assistance, or both.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia, dated January 14, 2004, as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
