<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-188">
  <num type="law">15-188</num>
  <heading type="short">Youth Pollworker Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2004-09-30</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-188.pdf">D.C. Law 15-188</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 6732</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0124">
      <narrative>Law 15-188, the “Youth Pollworker Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-124, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 4, 2004, and June 1, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 23, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-455 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-188 became effective on September 30, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955 to allow residents of the District of Columbia who are 16 or 17 years of age to serve as pollworkers. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Youth Pollworker Amendment Act of 2004”. Sec. 2. Section 5(e) of the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 700; D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.05(e is amended by adding a new paragraph (4) to read as follows: “(4) The Board shall select, appoint, and fix the compensation of temporary election workers to operate the polling places, including precinct captains who shall oversee the operations of polling places in accordance with rules and regulations prescribed by the Board, and polling place workers who shall assist the precinct captains. Precinct captains shall be qualified registered electors in the District of Columbia. Polling place workers shall be qualified registered electors in the District of Columbia, except that the Board may also appoint as polling place workers individuals who are 16 or 17 years of age on the day that they are working in this capacity, who reside in the District of Columbia, and who are enrolled in or have graduated from a public or private secondary school or an institution of higher education.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto and a 30-day period of Congressional review Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2004 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend §1-1001.05 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
