<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-131">
  <num type="law">15-131</num>
  <heading type="short">Neighborhood Investment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2004-03-30</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-131.pdf">D.C. Law 15-131</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 1797</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0128">
      <narrative>Law 15-131, the “Neighborhood Investment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-128, which was referred to the Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 2, 2003, and January 6, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 29, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-332 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-131 became effective on March 30, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To create a Neighborhood Investment Fund to finance economic development in certain District neighborhoods, develop a Neighborhood Investment Program for designated Target Areas and to designate 12 District neighborhoods as the initial Target Areas. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Neighborhood Investment Act of 2004 Sec. 2. Creation of Neighborhood Investment Fund a) There is established, as a nonlapsing, revolving fund outside the General Fund of the District of Columbia, a fund designated as the Neighborhood Investment Fund. Subject to appropriations, there shall be deposited annually into the Neighborhood Investment Fund 15% of the personal property tax imposed by section 47-1522(a) of the District of Columbia Official Code; provided, that the amount deposited into the Neighborhood Investment Fund from the personal property tax shall not exceed $10 million annually. Subject to the applicable laws relating to the appropriation of District funds, monies received and credited to the Neighborhood Investment fund shall be used to carry out the objectives of this act. All funds deposited into the fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the purposes of the act, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act b) The Mayor shall submit to the Council, as part of the annual budget, a request for an appropriation for expenditures from the Neighborhood Investment Fund c) Within 9 months of the effective date of this act, the Mayor shall develop an implementation plan for the first year of a 5-year program. In subsequent years, the yearly implementation plan shall be submitted to the Council prior to the start of the fiscal year. These implementation plans shall contain specific references to the amount to be spent each year by 1) Targeted area 2) Type of project; and (3) Specific project, where known d) The Mayor shall provide the Council with a report, within 90 days of the end of the fiscal year, detailing the expenditures from the Neighborhood Investment Fund by: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 (1) Targeted area 2) Type of project; and (3) Specific project e) The plans developed pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall be submitted by the Mayor to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed plan, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed plan shall be deemed disapproved f) The implementation plans for the 4th and subsequent years may include additional Neighborhood Investment Program Target Areas. Such neighborhoods shall be proposed by the Mayor and approved by the Council; provided, that 1) All new Target Areas must be areas that have A) A historic or ongoing lack of private investment; and (B) Areas of concentrated poverty where 30% or more of the population is below the federal poverty level 2) No more than 3 additional target neighborhoods are designated 3) The Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development shall announce and hold a public hearing after the selection of proposed new Target Areas and prior to Council approval, to gain input from District residents, businesses, Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, and community associations on the goals associated with the proposed Target Area. Sec. 3. Neighborhood Investment Program a) The Mayor shall develop a neighborhood investment plan designed to accomplish the goals of this act for each targeted area, which shall be 1) Developed with input from Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, community groups, neighborhood institutions, the faith community, representatives of the business community, and other neighborhood stakeholders 2) Submitted to the affected Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, community groups, neighborhood institutions, the faith community, representatives of the business community, and other neighborhood stakeholders for a comment period of one month; and (3) Submitted by the Mayor to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed plan, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed plan shall be deemed approved b) The neighborhood investment plans shall detail, where appropriate, the use of the following tools for neighborhood investment 1) The establishment of a pooled or subsidized revenue bond for the use of businesses and organizations within the Neighborhood Investment Program target areas 2) The use of tax increment financing districts for the Neighborhood Investment ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3 Program target areas 3) The specific dedication of District and other resources for the improvement of infrastructure and public spaces, such as roads, sidewalks, lighting, streetscape, parks, community centers, and libraries 4) An inventory of each property within the target area detailing the ownership, and, if the property is owned by the District government, a plan for the disposition or improved use of vacant, abandoned, underutilized, or negatively utilized lots, or if owned by the federal government, recommendations for the improved use of vacant, abandoned, underutilized, or negatively utilized lots 5) The use of payments in lieu of taxes or tax abatements to facilitate development; and (6) Increased dedication of the resources of the Metropolitan Police Department, for the purposes of neighborhood stabilization, where necessary c) The Department of Housing and Community Development may give priority scoring to the use of Housing Production Trust Funds or Community Development Block Grants in the targeted areas defined in section 4 or to the targeted areas proposed by the Mayor pursuant to section 3(f d) The plans shall outline the potential roles and responsibilities of the Housing Finance Agency, the National Capital Revitalization Corporation, the RLA Revitalization Corporation, the Office of Property Management, and the Board of Education where appropriate e) The plans shall be designed to ensure that expenditures from the Neighborhood Investment Fund are used to supplement, rather than supplant, operating and capital dollars already appropriated to District of Columbia agencies for similar purposes. The plans shall also seek to coordinate the expenditures of operating and capital dollars already appropriated to District of Columbia government agencies to support neighborhood goals f) The plans shall outline how funds will be used to develop, maintain, and improve physical facilities and infrastructure owned by the District of Columbia, particularly for projects or improvements in neighborhood plans that do not qualify for capital budget funding. Sec. 4. Neighborhood Investment Program Target Areas. There are established the following Neighborhood Investment Program Target Areas 1)(A) Target Area #1 Shaw. The Shaw target area is defined as starting at the corner of 9th Street and Florida Avenue, N.W east along Florida Avenue, N.W to North Capitol Street, south along North Capitol Street to Massachusetts Avenue, west along Massachusetts Avenue, N.W to 9th Street, N.W and north along 9th Street, N.W to Florida Avenue, N.W B) Among the goals of this target area are increasing foot and bicycle police patrols, the preservation of project based Section 8 multifamily affordable housing, increasing homeownership opportunities for neighborhood residents, and renovating and upgrading the Watha T. Daniel public library. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4 (2)(A) Target Area #2 – Logan Circle. The Logan Circle target area is defined as as starting at the corner of 9th Street, N.W and Florida Avenue, N.W south on 9th Street, N.W to Massachusetts Avenue, N.W west on Massachusetts Avenue, N.W to 16th Street, N.W north on 16th Street, N.W to U Street, N.W and east on U Street, N.W to Florida Avenue, N.W B) Among the goals of this target area are preserving affordable housing, including project based Section 8 housing, housing code enforcement and receivership of slum properties, acquisition, preservation, and redevelopment of 15 to 20 multifamily buildings for low-income residents, development of special-needs housing paired with social service delivery systems, and better library and recreation facilities, especially for neighborhood youth 3)(A) Target Area #3 – Deanwood Heights. The Deanwood Heights target area is defined as starting at the corner of Division Avenue, N.E east along Nannie Helen Burroughs Avenue, N.E southeast along Eastern Avenue, N.E southwest along Southern Avenue, S.E west along East Capitol Street, and north along Division Avenue, N.E B) Among the goals of this target area are the acquisition and demolition of abandoned properties, the acquisition and demolition of slum multifamily properties, the building of affordable housing, including housing for senior citizens and assisted living housing, the building of a full service recreation center, the revitalization of neighborhood commercial areas on Eastern and Division Avenues, infrastructure improvements to curbs, sidewalks, and roadways throughout the target area, and the development of a full service restaurant in the neighborhood 4)(A) Target Area #4 – Washington Highlands. The Washington Highlands target area is defined as starting at the corner of Southern Avenue and South Capitol Street, S.E north along South Capitol Street, north along Livingston Road, S.E northeast along Valley Avenue, S.E southeast along Wheeler Road, S.E and southwest along Southern Avenue, S.E B) Among the goals of this target area are the acquisition and demolition of abandoned properties, the building of affordable housing, including housing for senior citizens and assisted living housing, the building of recreational and entertainment facilities such as a bowling alley and ice skating rink on South Capitol Street, the building of a full-service supermarket, and the revival of neighborhood commercial strips to include book stores, florists, and other retail uses 5)(A) Target Area #5 – Columbia Heights. The Columbia Heights target area is defined as starting at the corner of Spring Road and Sherman Avenue, N.W northeast along Rock Creek Church Road, N.W to Warder Street, N.W south along Warder Street, N.W to 4th Street, N.W southwest along 4th Street, N.W to Gresham Place, N.W west along Gresham Place, N.W to Sherman Avenue, N.W south along Sherman Avenue to Florida Avenue, N.W west along Florida Avenue to W Street, N.W west along W Street, N.W to 16th Street, N.W west along Florida Avenue, N.W. to Champlain Street, N.W north along Champlain Street, N.W to Columbia Road, N.W northeast along Columbia Road, N.W to Mt. Pleasant Street, N.W northwest along Mt. Pleasant Street, N.W to Park Road, N.W west along Park Road, ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5 N.W to Mt. Pleasant Street, N.W north on Mt. Pleasant Street, N.W to Piney Branch Park, east through Piney Branch Park to Spring Road, N.W and east along Spring Road, N.W to Sherman Avenue, N.W B) Among the goals of this target area are housing code enforcement, and receivership of slum properties, the acquisition, preservation, and redevelopment of 15 to 20 multifamily properties in the area to preserve affordable housing, especially for immigrant families, rent stabilization measures, and the improvement of the Mt. Pleasant Street commercial corridor 6)(A) Target Area #6 – Brightwood and Upper Georgia Avenue. The Brightwood and Upper Georgia Avenue target area is defined as starting at the corner of Kennedy Street, N.W and 16th Street, N.W north along 16th Street, N.W to Alaska Avenue, N.W northeast along Alaska Avenue, N.W to Fern Street, N.W east along Fern Street, N.W to Fern Place, N.W east along Fern Place, N.W to Blair Road, N.W southeast along Blair Road, N.W to 5th Street, N.W south along 5th Street, N.W to Kennedy Street, N.W and west along Kennedy Street, N.W to 16th Street, N.W B) Among the goals of this target area are a comprehensive revitalization plan for Georgia Avenue, the development of a full service restaurants to serve the neighborhood, affordable housing for senior citizens and assisted living housing, the development of neighborhood oriented retail establishments such as coffee shops, ice cream parlors, books stores, and neighborhood recreation and entertainment centers such as a bowling alley and movie theater, and the enhancement of neighborhood parking 7)(A) Target Area #7 – Bloomingdale and Eckington. The Bloomingdale and Eckington target area is defined as starting at New York Avenue, N.W northwest along Florida Avenue, to 4th Street, N.W north along 4th Street, N.W to 5th Street, N.W east along Michigan Avenue, N.W to Franklin Street, N.E east along Franklin Street, N.E to 4th Street, N.E south on 4th Street, N.E to the CSX rail yard, south along the rail yard to New York Avenue, NE southwest along New York Avenue, N.E to Florida Avenue B) Among the goals of this target area are to clean and seal abandoned buildings, to create affordable housing, build a new recreation center and playground, increase foot and bicycle patrols by the Metropolitan Police Department and to eliminate drug trafficking and street prostitution, eradicate rodents through better vector control; revitalize Bloomingdale and Eckington neighborhood commercial areas, and build affordable housing at the Soldier’s Home and McMillan Reservoir sites 8)(A) Target Area #8 – Brookland and Edgewood. The Brookland and Edgewood target area is defined as starting at 4th Street, N.E and Rhode Island Avenue, N.E north along 4th Street, N.E to Michigan Avenue, N.E northeast along Michigan Avenue to South Dakota Avenue, N.E southeast along South Dakota Avenue, N.E to Rhode Island Avenue, N.E and southwest along Rhode Island Avenue, N.E to 4th Street, N.E B) Among the goals of this target area are to revitalize the neighborhood commercial areas in Brookland, along 12th Street, N.E and upper Rhode Island Avenue from ENROLLED ORIGINAL 6 13th Street to South Dakota Avenue, N.E eradicate prostitution in the Rhode Island Avenue corridor, build affordable housing in Ft. Lincoln, rebuild the Woodridge Library, and build a new youth recreation center 9)(A) Target Area #9 – Anacostia. The Anacostia target area is defined as starting at the Anascostia waterfront and Good Hope Road, S.E southeast along Good Hope Road, S.E to Naylor Road, S.E southeast on Naylor Road, S.E to Alabama Avenue, S.E southwest on Alabama Avenue, S.E to the Suitland Parkway, northwest along the Suitland Park to 18th Street, S.E north on 18th Street, S.E to Erie Street, S.E west on Erie Street, S.E to Morris Road, S.E and northwest on Morris Road, S.E to the Anacostia waterfront B) Among the goals of this target area are to clean and seal abandoned buildings, demolish blighted properties and replace them with affordable housing, build a recreation center for youth, revitalize the Good Hope Road neighborhood commercial district, build a new supermarket to serve the area, and renovate area schools and playgrounds 10) Target Area #10 – H Street, N.E. The H Street, N.E target area is defined as the area within 2 blocks north or south of H Street, N.E Benning Road, N.E and Maryland Avenue, N.E between North Capitol Street and 17th Street, N.E 11) Target Area #11 – Congress Heights. The Congress Heights target area is defined as the area bounded by a line starting at Mississippi Avenue, S.E and 13th Street, S.E and running north along 13th Street, S.E to Alabama Avenue, S.E then west along Alabama Avenue, S.E to the southwestern boundary of the St. Elizabeths campus, then northwest along the southwest boundary of the St. Elizabeths campus, then on a line parallel to Lebaum Street, S.E to Interstate 295, then southwest along Interstate 295 to a line parallel to 4th Street, S.E then along a line parallel to 4th Street, S.E. to 4th Street, S.E then along 4th Street, S.E to Mississippi Avenue, S.E then along Mississippi Avenue, S.E to the starting point 12) Target Area #12 – Bellevue. The Bellevue target area is defined as the area bounded by Galveston Street, S.W on the south, First Street, S.E on the east, Halley Street, S.E on the north, and Interstate 295 on the west. Sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December ENROLLED ORIGINAL 7 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1071"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1072"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1073"/>
  </section>
</document>
