<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-142">
  <num type="law">15-142</num>
  <heading type="short">Crispus Attucks Development Corporation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2004-04-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-142.pdf">D.C. Law 15-142</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 2589</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0068">
      <narrative>Law 15-142, the “Crispus Attucks Development Corporation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-68, which was referred to Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on January 6, 2004, and February 3, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 19, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-363 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-142 became effective on April 22, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to exempt from taxation certain property of the Crispus Attucks Development Corporation, a tax-exempt organization, and to provide equitable real property tax relief to the organization. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Crispus Attucks Development Corporation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 2004 Sec. 2. Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents for Chapter 10 is amended by adding a new section 47-1058 to read as follows: “47-1058 Crispus Attucks Development Corporation, lot 0046 in square 3117.” b) A new section 47-1058 is added to read as follows: “§ 47-1058 Crispus Attucks Development Corporation, lot 0046 in square 3117. “The real property located at 77 U Street, N.W Washington, D.C lot 0046 in square 3117, shall be exempt from all taxation so long as it is used to carry out the public purposes and activities of the Crispus Attucks Development Corporation and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ 47-1005, 47-1007, and 47-1009.”. Sec. 3. Real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against the real property located at 77 U Street, N.W Washington, D.C lot 0046 in square 3117, for the period of July 1, 1989, through January 31, 2003, shall be forgiven. Sec. 4. Applicability. Section 2 shall apply as of February 1, 2003. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2004 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher New § 47-1058 Note, § 47-1058 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Sec. 5. Inclusion in the budget and financial plan. This act shall take effect subject to the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement contained in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 7. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia Note, § 47-1058</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
