<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-240">
  <num type="law">15-240</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2005-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-240.pdf">D.C. Law 15-240</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 11225</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0670">
      <narrative>Law 15-240, the “District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-670, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 5, 2004, and November 9, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 30, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-597 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-240 became effective on March 16, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establish the Emancipation Day Parade to celebrate and commemorate District of Columbia Emancipation Day, and to establish the Emancipation Day Fund to accept and use gifts to fund the parade. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Act of 2004 Sec. 2. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Emancipation Day Parade" means the parade, and associated activities, held to celebrate and commemorate District of Columbia Emancipation Day 2 Fund" means the Emancipation Day Fund. Sec. 3. Establishment of Emancipation Day Parade. There is established the Emancipation Day Parade, to annually celebrate and commemorate District of Columbia Emancipation Day. Sec. 4. Emancipation Day Fund a) There is established the Emancipation Day Fund (“Fund”) to receive monies for the purposes of funding the Emancipation Day Parade and activities associated with the celebration and commemoration of District of Columbia Emancipation Day b) The monies in the Fund shall not be a part of, or lapse into, the General Fund of the District of Columbia or any other fund of the District c) By August 1st of each year, the Secretary of the District of Columbia shall submit a report to the Council that shall include a specific accounting of the expenditure of money in the Fund and any remaining balance. The report shall include 1) The name of any donors or list of anonymous contributions 2) The amount of each contribution 3) A description of any donated property; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 (4) A description of the use of monies for presenting the Emancipation Day Parade; and (5) Costs of parade-related programs, activities, and functions for which the money have been expended d) Monies shall only be expended from the Fund for the administration of the Emancipation Day Parade. Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 7. Effective date. This act shall take effect upon its approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-181"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-182"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-183"/>
  </section>
</document>
