<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-276">
  <num type="law">15-276</num>
  <heading type="short">National Guard Association of the United States Real Property Tax Exemption Reconfirmation and Modification Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2005-04-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-276.pdf">D.C. Law 15-276</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 831</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0311">
      <narrative>Law 15-276, the “National Guard Association of the United States Real Property Tax Exemption Reconfirmation and Modification Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-310, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 9, 2004, and December 7, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-667 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-276 became effective on April 5, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend section 47-1042 of the District of Columbia Official Code to reconfirm and modify the exemption from real estate taxation for the property known as lot 60, square 625 and owned by the National Guard Association of the United States. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "National Guard Association of the United States Real Property Tax Exemption Reconfirmation and Modification Act of 2004 Sec. 2. Section 47-1042 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended to read as follows The property situated in square 625 in the City of Washington, District of Columbia, described as lot 60, together with the improvements thereon, shall be exempt from all taxation so long as the property is owned by and titled in the name of the National Guard Association of the United States, a District of Columbia nonprofit corporation, is occupied by the Association, is used solely for purposes of the Association, and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ 47-1005, 47-1007, and 47-1009. The transfer of the property to the National Guard Association of the United States shall be exempt from all transfer and recordation taxes of the District of Columbia Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement contained in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813, D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect on its enactment (approval by the Mayor, or in the event of veto by the Mayor, override of the veto by the Council a 30-day period of Congressional Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Note, § 47-1042 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
