<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-275">
  <num type="law">15-275</num>
  <heading type="short">Public Charter School Real Property Tax Rebate Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2005-04-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-275.pdf">D.C. Law 15-275</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 829</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0304">
      <narrative>Law 15-275, the “Public Charter School Real Property Tax Rebate Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-304, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 9, 2004, and December 7, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-666 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-275 became effective on April 5, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 8 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to allow for a real property tax rebate to public charter schools which pay real property tax through a lease agreement. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as "Public Charter School Real Property Tax Rebate Act of 2004 Sec. 2. Chapter 8 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by adding a new section designation to read as follows “47-867. Public charter school property tax rebate.” b) A new section 47-867 is added to read as follows: “§ 47-867. Public charter school real property tax rebate. “(a) A public charter school that leases a school facility from an entity subject to tax under this chapter shall receive a rebate of that portion of the tax, if any, that represents the public charter school’s pro rata share of the lessor’s tax on the property if: “(1) It is liable under the lease for the pro rata share of the tax; “(2) It applies for the rebate of the tax on or before September 15 of the calendar year in which the school year ended; and “(3) The lessor paid the tax. “(b) The rebate shall be the amount of the portion of the tax paid by the public charter school. “(c) The application shall include: “(1) A copy of the lease; and “(2) Documentation the tax has been paid. “(d) If a proper application has been made, the Mayor shall rebate the tax on or before December 31 of the same calendar year.”. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher New § 47-867 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply as of October 1, 2005, subject to inclusion in the budget and financial plan. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
