<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-204">
  <num type="law">15-204</num>
  <heading type="short">Board of Education Continuity and Transition Temporary Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-204.pdf">D.C. Law 15-204</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 15-204, the “Board of Education Continuity and Transition Temporary Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-881, and was retained by Council. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 16, 2004, and June 29, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 21, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-478 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-204 became effective on December 7, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend, on a temporary basis, An Act To fix and regulate the salaries of teachers, school officers, and other employees of the board of education of the District of Columbia to sunset the hybrid Board of Education by January 2, 2009, to re-establish a Board structure in which 8 Board members are elected from each ward, one member is elected at-large, and the president is selected by and from among the 9 Board members, to provide that all Board member terms shall expire on January 2 of the appropriate year, to provide that the terms of the 2 Board members appointed for terms to begin January 2, 2007, shall expire at noon January 2, 2009, to provide that the terms of the 2 members of the Board of Education elected in 2006 from School Districts III and IV, and the President elected in 2006, shall expire on January 2, 2009; and to amend the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955 to make conforming amendments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Board of Education Continuity and Transition Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 Sec. 2. Section 2 of An Act To fix and regulate the salaries of teachers, school officers, and other employees of the board of education of the District of Columbia, approved June 20, 1906 (34 Stat. 316; D.C. Official Code § 38-101 et seq is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows a)(1) Beginning July 7, 2000, and ending at noon January 2, 2009, the Board of Education shall consist of 9 members. Four members shall be appointed by the Mayor and confirmed by the Council. Five members shall be elected. Four of the 5 elected members shall be elected from the 4 school districts created pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection. One member shall be elected at-large as the president of the Board 2) Beginning July 7, 2000, and ending at noon January 2, 2009, the 4 school districts for the election of Board members pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall be comprised of the 8 election wards created pursuant to section 2 of the Boundaries Act of 1975, Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2004 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Note, § 38-101 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. effective December 16, 1975 (D.C. Law 1-38; D.C. Official Code § 1-1011.01 as follows A) Wards 1 and 2 shall comprise School District I B) Wards 3 and 4 shall comprise School District II C) Wards 5 and 6 shall comprise School District III; and D) Wards 7 and 8 shall comprise School District IV 3) Beginning January 2, 2009, the Board of Education shall consist of 9 members. One member shall be elected from each of the 8 school election wards established pursuant to section 2 of the Boundaries Act of 1975, effective December 16, 1975 (D.C. Law 1- 38; D.C. Official Code § 1-1011.01 and one member shall be elected at-large. The Board shall select its President from among the 9 members of the Board b) Subsection (b) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended as follows A) Strike the phrase “paragraph (3)(C) and (3)(D)” and insert the phrase “paragraph (3)(C E and (F)” in its place B) Strike the phrase “including the President” and insert the phrase “including the at-large member” in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended as follows A) Subparagraph (A) is amended to read as follows: “(A)(i) The term of office of a member of the Board of Education elected in a general election shall commence on January 2 of the year following the election. The term of office of an incumbent member of the Board shall expire at noon January 2 of the year following the general election. “(ii) The term of a member elected from a school district or appointed pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section shall expire at noon January 2, 2009.” B) Subparagraph (D) is repealed C) New subparagraphs (E) and (F) are added to read as follows: “(E)(i) The 2 members of the Board of Education elected in 2006 from School Districts III and IV and the President elected in 2006 shall serve through January 2, 2009. “(ii) The 2 members of the Board of Education appointed by the Mayor and confirmed by the Council for terms to begin January 2, 2007, shall serve through January 2, 2009. “(F) The initial terms of the members of the Board of Education elected in the general election in November 2008 shall be as follows: “(i) The 4 members elected from wards 1, 3, 5, and 7 shall serve 2 year terms, ending at noon January 2, 2011; and “(ii) The 4 members elected from wards 2, 4, 6 and 8 and the member elected at-large shall serve 4 year terms, ending at noon January 2, 2013.” c) Subsection (c)(1) is amended by adding the phrase “or ward” after the phrase ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. “special school district” d) Subsection (f) is amended by striking the phrase “subsection (b)(3)(C)” and inserting the phrase “subsection (b)(3)(C) and (E)” in its place. Sec. 3. Section 8(n) of the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 699; D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.08(n is amended by adding the phrase “or ward” after the phrase “school district” wherever it appears. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia Note, § 1-1001.08</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
