<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-38">
  <num type="law">15-38</num>
  <heading type="short">Streamlining Regulation Act of 2003</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2003-10-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-38.pdf">D.C. Law 15-38</citation>
      <citation type="register">50 DCR 6913</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0019">
      <narrative>Law 15-38, the “Streamlining Regulation Act of 2003”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-19, which was referred to Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 3, 2003, and July 8, 2003, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 11, 2003, it was assigned Act No. 15-146 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-38 became effective on October 28, 2003.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 28 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to modify the master business license system by re-designating the master business license as a basic business license, by requiring registration only by persons who require a license which is issued in the form of an endorsement to engage in business, and by adding privacy provisions; to amend an Act To regulate the erection, hanging, placing, painting, display, and maintenance of outdoor signs and other forms of exterior advertising within the District of Columbia, the District of Columbia Funeral Services Regulatory Act of 1984, the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, the Law to Legalize Lotteries, the Daily Numbers Games, and Bingo and Raffles for Charitable Purposes in the District of Columbia, the Day Care Policy Act of 1979, An Act To regulate the placing of children in family homes, and for other purposes, the Department of Health Functions Clarification Act of 2001, the Youth Residential Facilities Licensure Act of 1986, the Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975, the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulations Act of 1980, the Asbestos Licensing and Control Act of 1990, the Solid Waste Facility Permit Act of 1995, the District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977, the District of Columbia Low-Level Radioactive Waste Generator Regulatory Policy Act of 1990, the Regulation of the Horse-Drawn Carriage Trade Act of 1990, An Act to control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, An Act To regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms, and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real-estate brokers in the District of Columbia, the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996, Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code, An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, An Act To amend the Code of the District of Columbia to provide for the organization and regulation of cooperative associations, and for other purposes, the Fire and Casualty Act, An Act To provide for regulation of certain insurance rates in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, the Drug Abuse, Alcohol Abuse, and Mental Illness Insurance Coverage Act of 1986, the Risk Retention Act of 1993, the Reinsurance Intermediary Act of 1993, the Employment Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2004 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Services Licensing and Regulation Act of 1984, the Education Licensure Commission Act of 1976, An Act To provide for the incorporation and regulation of medical and dental colleges in the District of Columbia, the Clinical Laboratory Act of 1988, the Health-Care and Community Residence Facility, Hospice and Home Care Licensure Act of 1983, the District of Columbia Substance Abuse Treatment and Prevention Act of 1989, the District of Columbia Charitable Solicitation Act, Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code, An Act To regulate within the District of Columbia the sale of milk, cream, and ice cream, and for other purposes, the District of Columbia Drug Manufacture and Distribution Licensure Act of 1990, the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, and the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985, to make conforming amendments, and to provide for a report by the Mayor to the Council on the effect of the basic business license system on the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Streamlining Regulation Act of 2003 Sec. 2. Chapter 28 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended as follows 1) Strike the section designation "47-2851.03. Classes of license and insert the section designation "47-2851.03. Endorsement categories; exemptions.” in its place 2) Strike the section designation "47-2851.16. Third party inspections for Class A license endorsements and insert the section designation "47-2851.16. Third party inspections for license endorsements.” in its place b) Section 47-2828 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase “and other transient Class A Housing businesses shall be issued under the master business license system as a Class A Housing: Transient endorsement on a master license” and inserting the phrase “bed and breakfasts, and other transient Housing businesses shall be issued under the basic business license system as a Housing: Transient endorsement on a basic business license” in its place 2) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase “cooperative associations, and other residential Class A Housing businesses shall be issued under the master business license system as a Class A Housing: Residential endorsement on a master license” and inserting the phrase “all community based residential facilities, and other residential Housing businesses shall be issued under the basic business license system as a Housing: Residential endorsement on a basic business license” in its place 3) Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase “Class B General Services and Repair endorsement to a master business license under the master business license system” Amend § 47-2828 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. and inserting the phrase “General Services and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system” in its place c) Section 47-2851.01 is amended as follows 1) A new paragraph (1) is added to read as follows: “(1 Basic business license" means the single document designed for public display issued by the business license center that certifies District agency license approval and that incorporates the endorsements for individual licenses included in the basic business license system that the District requires for any person subject to this subchapter. The term “basic business license” shall include a master business license issued prior to the effective date of the Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003, passed on an emergency basis on July 8, 2003 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-317 2) A new paragraph (1A) is added to read as follows: “(1A Basic business license application" means a document incorporating pertinent data from existing applications for licenses covered under this subchapter 3)(A) Existing paragraph (1) is re-designated as paragraph (1B B) Re-designated paragraph (1B)(A) is amended by striking the phrase “, and which pays, or is subject to the payment of, taxes on earnings, or fees in lieu of taxes, to the District of Columbia, or which qualifies for tax-exempt status under District law” and inserting the phrase “in the District of Columbia.” in its place 4) Paragraphs (6) and (7) are repealed 5) Paragraph (8) is amended by striking the phrase “to register with the District to do business in the District and” 6) Paragraph (12) is amended by striking the word “master” and inserting the word “basic” in its place d) Section 47-2851.02 is amended to read as follows: “(a) A person which is required under law to obtain a license issued in the form of an endorsement to engage in a business in the District of Columbia shall not engage in such business in the District of Columbia without having first obtained a basic business license and any necessary endorsements in accordance with this subchapter. “(b) A license shall be required for each business location. “(c) A person issued a license under this subchapter shall not willfully allow any other person required to obtain a separate license to operate under his or her license. “(d) Licenses granted under this subchapter may be assigned or transferred upon approval by the Department and payment of the applicable fee.” e) Section 47-2851.03 is amended to read as follows: “§ 47-2851.03. Endorsement categories; exemptions. “(a) Endorsements to a basic business license shall be issued in the following license endorsement categories: “(1) Alcoholic beverages, except that a basic business license bearing an Amend § 47-2851.01 Amend § 47-2851.02 Amend § 47-2851.03 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Alcoholic Beverages endorsement shall also indicate the class of endorsement applicable for the licensed business; “(2) Educational Services; “(3) Entertainment; “(4) Environmental Materials; “(5) Financial Services; “(6)(A) Housing: Transient; and “(B) Housing: Residential; “(7) Inspected Sales and Services; “(8) Manufacturing; “(9) Motor Vehicle Sales, Service, and Repair; “(10)(A) Public Health: Health Care Facility; “(B) Public Health: Human Services Facility; “(C) Public Health: Child Health and Welfare; “(D) Public Health: Public Accommodations; “(E) Public Health: Pharmacy and Pharmacology; “(F) Public Health: Funeral Establishment; “(G) Public Health: Radioactive Materials; “(H) Public Health: Biohazard; “(I) Public Health: Food Establishment Wholesale; and “(J) Public Health: Food Establishment Retail; “(11) Public Safety; “(12) Employment Services; “(13) General Sales; “(14) General Services and Repair; and “(15) General Business. “(b) All Class A or Class B license endorsements to master business licenses issued by the Department prior to the effective date of the Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003, passed on an emergency basis on July 8, 2003 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-317 are hereby redesignated as license endorsements, without designation of class, to a basic business license. Nothing in the foregoing shall be read as eliminating the criteria, established either by rule or statute, that govern the awarding of any license endorsement affected by this section. “(c) The Department shall maintain and periodically update a roster of all businesses which have been issued a basic business license, indicating the license endorsements appended to each basic business license. “(d) The following licenses shall not be a part of the basic business license system and shall be regulated by the Department of Health: “(1) Dog-Spayed; and “(2) Dog-Unspayed.”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 f) Section 47-2851.04(a) is amended by striking the word “master” and inserting the word “basic” in its place g) Section 47-2851.05 is amended by striking the word “master”wherever it appears and inserting the word “basic” in its place h) Section 47-2851.06 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a)(1) is amended by striking the word “master” and inserting the word “basic” in its place 2) New subsections (c) and (d) are added to read as follows: “(c) Notwithstanding any other provision of District law, information submitted to the Center under this subchapter shall not be made available to the public; provided, that a person may be furnished with such information for one registrant based upon the submission of either the name or address of the registrant; provided further, that the person shall be limited to one request per day.”. “(d) Federal Employer Identification numbers and social security numbers shall not be released to the public, except if: “(1) Requested by a law enforcement agency; or “(2) Directed by a court order.” i) Section 47-2851.07 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase “master application” both times it appears and inserting the word “basic business license application” in their place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word “master” and inserting the word “basic” in its place 3) Subsection (c)(2) is repealed 4) Subsection (e)(1) is amended by striking the word “master” and inserting the word “basic” in its place 5) Subsection (f) is amended by striking the phrase “master application” and inserting the word “basic business license application” in its place j) Section 47-2851.08 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended as follows A) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the word “master”wherever it appears and inserting the word “basic” in its place B) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the word “Master” and inserting the word “Basic” in its place 2) Subsection (b)(2) is amended by striking the word “Master” and inserting the word “Basic” in its place 3) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase “inspected or uninspected” 4) Subsection (d) is amended as follows A) Strike the phrase “general fund” and insert the phrase “General Fund of the District of Columbia” in its place. Amend § 47-2851.04 Amend § 47-2851.05 Amend § 47-2851.06 Amend § 47-2851.07 Amend § 47-2851.08 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 6Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 B) Strike the word “Government” and insert the word “government” in its place k) Section 47-2851.09 is amended by striking the word “master”wherever it appears and inserting the word “basic” in its place l) Section 47-2851.11 is amended by striking the word “master”wherever it appears and inserting the word “basic” in its place m) Section 47-2851.12 is amended by striking the word “master”wherever it appears and inserting the word “basic” in its place n) Section 47-2851.13 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended as follows A) Strike the word “Master” and insert the word “Basic” in its place B) Strike the word “propriety” and insert the word “proprietary” in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word “master”wherever it appears and inserting the word “basic” in its place 3) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the word “master” and inserting the word “basic” in its place o) Section 47-2851.15(a) is amended by striking the word “master” and inserting the word “basic” in its place p) Section 47-2851.16 is amended as follows 1) The section heading is amended by striking the phrase “Class A” 2) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the word “master”and inserting the word “basic” in its place 3) Subsection (d) is amended by striking the word “master” and inserting the word “basic” in its place q) Section 47-2851.17 is amended by striking the word “master” and inserting the word “basic” in its place r) Section 47-2851.19 is amended to read as follows: “Notwithstanding any provision of this subchapter, any business which was not required under law to obtain a license issued in the form of an endorsement to engage in a business in the District of Columbia and which did not obtain a basic business license prior to July 1, 2003, shall not be subject to any penalty or fine for failure to obtain a basic business license.” s) Section 47-2851.20 is amended by striking the word “master” and inserting the word “basic” in its place. Sec. 3. Conforming amendments a) Section 2(b) of An Act To regulate the erection, hanging, placing, painting, display, and maintenance of outdoor signs and other forms of exterior advertising within the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1931 (46 Stat. 1486; D.C. Official Code § 1-303.22 is amended Amend § 47-2851.09 Amend § 47-2851.11 Amend § 47-2851.12 Amend § 47-2851.13 Amend § 47-2851.15 Amend § 47-2851.16 Amend § 47-2851.17 Amend § 47-2851.19 Amend § 47-2851.20 Amend § 1-303.22 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 7Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. by striking the phrase “Class B General Services and Repair endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Services and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place b) Section 204(a) of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, effective March 29, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-96; D.C. Official Code § 2-534(a is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (9) is amended by striking the phrase “; and” and inserting a semi- colon in its place 2) Paragraph (10) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place 3) A new paragraph (11) is added to read as follows: “(11) Information exempt from disclosure by D.C. Official Code § 47-2851.06.” c) Section 6(e)(1A) of the District of Columbia Funeral Services Regulatory Act of 1984, effective May 22, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-84; D.C. Code § 3-405(e)(1A is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health Funeral Establishment endorsed to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health Funeral Establishment endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place d) Section 4(b) of the Law to Legalize Lotteries, Daily Numbers Games, and Bingo and Raffles for Charitable Purposes in the District of Columbia, effective March 10, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-172; D.C. Official Code § 3-1326(b is amended by striking the phrase “Class B General Sales endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Sales endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place e) Section 13(b) of the Day Care Policy Act of 1979, effective September 1979 (D.C. Law 3-16; D.C. Official Code § 4-412(b is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Child Health and Welfare endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Child Health and Welfare endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place f) Section 2(b) of An Act To regulate the placing of children in family homes, and for other purposes, approved April 22, 1944 (58 Stat. 193; D.C. Official Code § 4-1402(b is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Child Health and Welfare endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Child Health and Welfare endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place (g) Section 4903(b) of the Department of Health Functions Clarification Act of 2001, effective October 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 7-732(b is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase “Master License Fee” and insert the phrase “basic business license fees” in its place 2) Strike the phrase “Master Business License Fund” and insert the phrase “Basic Business License Fund” in its place h) Section 3(i) of the Youth Residential Facilities Licensure Act of 1986, effective Amend § 2-534 Amend § 3-405 Amend § 3-1326 Amend § 4-412 Amend § 4-1402 Amend § 7-732 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 8Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. August 13, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-139; D.C. Official Code § 7-2102(i is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Child Health and Welfare endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Child Health and Welfare endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place i) Title IV of the Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975, effective September 24, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-85; D.C. Official Code § 7-2501.01 et seq is amended as follows 1) Section 401(c D.C. Official Code § 7-2504.01(c is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Safety endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Safety endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place 2) Section 402(d D.C. Official Code § 7-2504.02(d is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Safety endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Safety endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place j) Section 5(g) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulations Act of 1980, effective September 26, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-107; D.C. Official Code § 7-2805(g is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place k) Section 4(d) of the Asbestos Licensing and Control Act of 1990, effective May 1, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-116; D.C. Official Code § 8-111.03(d is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Environmental Materials endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Environmental Materials endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place l) The Solid Waste Facility Permit Act of 1995, effective February 27, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-94; D.C. Official Code § 8-1051 et seq is amended as follows 1) Section 4(j D.C. Official Code § 8-1053(j is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Environmental Materials endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Environmental Materials endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place 2) Section 5(f D.C. Official Code § 8-1054 (f is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Environmental Materials endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Environmental Materials endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place m) Section 4(c) of the District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977, effective March 23, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-64; D.C. Official Code § 8-1303(c is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Environmental Materials endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Environmental Materials endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place. Amend § 7-2102 Amend § 7-2504.01 Amend § 7-2504.02 Amend § 7-2805 Amend § 8-111.03 Amend § 8-1053 Amend § 8-1054 Amend § 8-1303 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 9Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 n) Section 4(b) of the District of Columbia Low-Level Radioactive Waste Generator Regulatory Policy Act of 1990, effective March 7, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-226; D.C. Official Code § 8-1503(b is amended striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Radioactive Equipment endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Radioactive Equipment endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place o) Section 3(g) of the Regulation of the Horse-Drawn Carriage Trade Act of 1990, effective March 7, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-224; D.C. Official Code § 8-2002(g is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place p) Section 10(b) of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Stat. 652; D.C. Official Code § 22-4510(b is amended striking the phrase “Class A Public Safety endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Safety endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place q) Section 1(b) of An Act To regulate the business of loaning money on security of any kind by persons, firms, and corporations other than national banks, licensed bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, and real-estate brokers in the District of Columbia, approved February 4, 1913 (37 Stat. 657; D.C. Official Code § 26-901(b is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Financial Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Financial Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place r) Section 4(j) of the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996, effective September 9, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-155; D.C. Official Code § 26-1103(j is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Financial Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Financial Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place s) Section 28-4003(j) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place t) An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1189; scattered sections of the D.C. Official Code is amended as follows 1) Section 586b (D.C. Official Code § 29-615(b is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Educational Services endorsement to a master business license under the master" and inserting the phrase “Educational Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place. Amend § 8-1503 Amend § 8-2002 Amend § 22-4510 Amend § 26-901 Amend § 26-1103 Amend § 28-4003 Amend § 29-615 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 10Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 2) Section 648(b D.C. Official Code § 31-5201(b is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Financial Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Financial Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place u) Section 44(b) of An Act To amend the Code of the District of Columbia to provide for the organization and regulation of cooperative associations, and for other purposes, approved June 19, 1940 (54 Stat. 490; D.C. Official Code § 29-944(b is amended by striking the phrase “Class B General Business endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Business endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place v) Section 53(d) of the Fire and Casualty Act, approved April 18, 1966 (80 Stat. 126; D.C. Official Code § 31-1103 is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Financial Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Financial Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place w) Section 3(g) of the Reinsurance Intermediary Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-47; D.C. Official Code § 31-1802(g is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Financial Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Financial Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place x) Section 6(c)(5) of An Act To provide for regulation of certain insurance rates in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved May 20, 1948 (62 Stat. 245; D.C. Official Code § 31-2706(c)(5 is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Financial Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Financial Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place y) Section 7(e) of the Drug Abuse, Alcohol Abuse, and Mental Illness Insurance Coverage Act of 1986, effective February 28, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-195; D.C. Official Code § 31- 3106(e is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Human Services Facility endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Human Services Facility endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place z) Section 3(a)(3) of the Risk Retention Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-46; D.C. Official Code § 31-4102(a)(3 is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Financial Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Financial Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place aa) Section 3(e) of the Employment Services Licensing and Regulation Act of 1984, effective March 13, 1985 (D.C. Law 5-136; D.C. Official Code § 32-402(e is amended striking the phrase “a Class B Employment Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Employment Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place. Amend § 31-5201 Amend § 29-944 Amend § 31-1103 Amend § 31-1802 Amend § 31-2706 Amend § 31-3106 Amend § 31-4102 Amend § 32-402 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 11Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 bb) Section 6 of the Education Licensure Commission Act of 1976, effective April 6, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-104; D.C. Official Code § 38-1306 is amended as follows 1) The second subsection (e) is redesignated as subsection (f 2) The redesignated subsection (f) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Educational Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Educational Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place cc) Section 1(b) of An Act To provide for the incorporation and regulation of medical and dental colleges in the District of Columbia, approved May 4, 1896 (29 Stat.112; D.C. Official Code § 38-1401(b is amended striking the phrase “a Class A Educational Services endorsement to a master business license under the master" and inserting the phrase “an Educational Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place dd) The Clinical Laboratory Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-182; D.C. Official Code § 44-201 et seq is amended as follows 1) Section 3(j D.C. Official Code § 44-202(j is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Laboratory endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Laboratory endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place 2) Section 6(m D.C. Official Code § 44-205(m is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Laboratory endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Laboratory endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place ee) The Health-Care and Community Residence Facility, Hospice and Home Care Licensure Act of 1983, effective February 24, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-48; D.C. Official Code § 44- 501 et seq is amended as follows 1) Section 3(j D.C. Official Code § 44-502(j is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place 2) Section 5(k D.C. Official Code § 44-504(k is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place 3) Section 7(d D.C. Official Code § 44-506(d is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement or a provisional Public Health: Human Services facility endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement or a provisional Public Health: Human Services Facility endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place ff) Section 5(g) of the District of Columbia Substance Abuse Treatment and Prevention Amend § 38-1306 Amend § 31-1401 Amend § 44-202 Amend § 44-205 Amend § 44-502 Amend § 44-504 Amend § 44-506 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 12Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Act of 1989, effective March 15, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-80; D.C. Official Code § 44-1204(g is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place gg) Section 3(c) of the District of Columbia Charitable Solicitation Act, approved July 10, 1957 (71 Stat. 278; D.C. Official Code § 44-1702(c is amended by striking the phrase “Class B General Business endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Business endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place hh) Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows 1) Section 47-2404(i) is amended by striking the phrase “Class B General Sales endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase "General Sales endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place 2) Section 47-2603(b) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Financial Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Financial Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place 3) Section 47-2701(b) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place 4) Chapter 28 is amended as follows A) Section 47-2808(d) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place B) Section 47-2809(b) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Public Accommodations endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Public Accommodations endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place C) Section 47-2811(b) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Public Accommodations endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Public Accommodations endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place D) Section 47-2814(g) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Environmental Materials endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Environmental Materials endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place E) Section 47-2815(b) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Environmental Materials endorsement to a master business license under the master” and Amend § 44-1204 Amend § 44-1702 Amend § 47-2404 Amend § 47-2603 Amend § 47-2701 Amend § 47-2808 Amend § 47-2809 Amend § 47-2811 Amend § 47-2814 Amend § 47-2815 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 13Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. inserting the phrase “an Environmental Materials endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place F) Section 47-2817 is amended as follows i) Subsection (c)(2) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Environmental Materials endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Environmental Materials endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place ii) Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase “Class B General Services and Repair endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Services and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place G) Section 47-2818 is amended as follows i) Subsection (a)(2) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Manufacturing endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Manufacturing endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place ii) Subsection (b)(2) is amended by striking the phrase “Class B General Sales endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Sales endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place H) Section 47-2820(e) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Entertainment endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Entertainment endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place I) Section 47-2821(b) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Entertainment endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Entertainment endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place J) Section 47-2823(c) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Entertainment endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Entertainment endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place K) Section 47-2824(b) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Public Accommodations endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Public Accommodations endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place L) Section 47-2825(b) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Entertainment endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Entertainment endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place M) Section 47-2826(c) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Entertainment endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Entertainment endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place N) Section 47-2827 is amended as follows i) Subsection (i) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Food Amend § 47-2817 Amend § 47-2818 Amend § 47-2820 Amend § 47-2821 Amend § 47-2823 Amend § 47-2824 Amend § 47-2825 Amend § 47-2826 Amend § 47-2827 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 14Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Establishments: Wholesale endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Food Establishments: Wholesale endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place ii) Subsection (j) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Food Establishments: Retail endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Food Establishments: Retail endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place O) Section 47-2829(h) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place P) Section 47-2830(b) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Motor Vehicle Sales, Services and Repair endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Motor Vehicle Sales, Service, and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place Q) Section 47-2832(b) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Motor Vehicle Sales, Services and Repair endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Motor Vehicle Sales, Service, and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place R) Section 47-2832.01 is amended by striking the phrase “Class B General Services and Repair endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Services and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place S) Section 47-2834(d) is amended as follows i) Paragraph (d)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “as a Class A Food Establishment: Retail endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Food Establishments: Retail endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place ii) Paragraph (d)(2) is amended by striking the phrase “as a Class B General Sales endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Sales endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place T) Section 47-2835(b) is amended by striking the phrase “Class B General Services and Repair endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Services and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place U) Section 47-2836(b) is amended by striking the phrase “Class B General Services and Repair endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Services and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place. Amend § 47-2829 Amend § 47-2830 Amend § 47-2832 Amend § 47-2832.01 Amend § 47-2834 Amend § 47-2835 Amend § 47-2836 Amend § 47-2837 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 15Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 V) Section 47-2837(e) is amended as follows i) Strike the phrase “as a Class A Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “as an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place ii) Strike the phrase “Class B General Sales endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “General Sales endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place W) Section 47-2838(b) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Safety endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Safety endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place X) Section 47-2839(f) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Safety endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Safety endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place Y) Section 47-2884.03(e) is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place Z) Section 47-2885.08(g) is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Pharmacy and Pharmaceuticals endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Pharmacy and Pharmaceuticals endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place ii) Section 4(f) of the District of Columbia Drug Manufacture and Distribution Licensure Act of 1990, effective June 13, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-137; D.C. Official Code § 48-703(f is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Pharmacy and Pharmaceuticals endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Pharmacy and Pharmaceuticals endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place jj) Section 303(e) of the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, effective August 5, 1981 D.C. Law 4-29; D.C. Official Code § 48-903.03(e is amended by striking the phrase “Class A Public Health: Pharmacy and Pharmaceuticals endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Public Health: Pharmacy and Pharmaceuticals endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place kk) Section 20(c) of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official Code § 50-319(c is amended by striking the phrase “a Class A Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a master business license under the master” and inserting the phrase “Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” in its place. Amend § 47-2838 Amend § 47-2839 Amend § 47-2884.03 Amend § 47-2885.08 Amend § 48-703 Amend § 47-903.03 Amend § 50-319 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 16Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Sec. 4. Within 16 months of the effective date of this act, the Mayor shall provide the Council with a 12-month report on the effect of this act on the regulatory, economic development, and consumer protection operations of the District of Columbia, with recommendations for modification to the District of Columbia’s regulatory framework, as warranted. Sec. 5. The Council adopts the attached fiscal impact statement as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 6. This act shall take effect upon its approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto and a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
