<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-345">
  <num type="law">15-345</num>
  <heading type="short">Nonprofit Housing Organizations Tax Exemption Temporary Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-345.pdf">D.C. Law 15-345</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 15-345, the “Nonprofit Housing Organizations Tax Exemption Temporary Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-1180 and was retained by Council. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 21, 2004, and January 4, 2005, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 19, 2005, it was assigned Act No. 15-763 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-345 became effective on April 12, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend, on an temporary basis, section 47-3505 of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide certain nonprofit organizations with exemption from certain real property taxation. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Nonprofit Housing Organizations Tax Exemption Temporary Act of 2005 Sec. 2. Section 47-3505 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new subsection (f) to read as follows: “(f)(1) Beginning October 1, 2002, any nonprofit organization that has (i) acquired property to develop more than 10 units of housing for affordable or lower income home ownership in the District of Columbia ii) subdivided the acquired property into more than 10 units, and (iii) been denied exemption from District of Columbia real property taxes pursuant to § 47-1002 shall have 2 years from the date of the subdivision of the property to hold the property without liability for the recordation, transfer, or real property taxes associated with the acquisition and development of the property. “(2) Beginning October 1, 2002, no recordation, transfer, or real property taxes associated with the acquisition of properties pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be assessed against the nonprofit organization if it is not liable for taxes pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.”. Sec. 3. Inclusion in budget and financial plan. This act shall take effect subject to inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Note, § 47-3505 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The fiscal impact of this act is minimal in fiscal years 2003, 2004, and 2005. The Council adopts the attached fiscal impact statement as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
