<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-326">
  <num type="law">15-326</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Government Purchase Card Program Reporting Requirements Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2005-04-12</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-326.pdf">D.C. Law 15-326</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 1439</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0826">
      <narrative>Law 15-326, the “District of Columbia Government Purchase Card Program Reporting Requirements Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-826, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 9, 2004, and December 7, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-681 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-326 became effective on April 12, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 to establish new reporting requirements for the tracking of purchase card expenditures and interest penalty payments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “District of Columbia Government Purchase Card Program Reporting Requirements Amendment Act of 2004”. Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Official Code § 2-301.01 et seq is amended by adding a new section 322 to read as follows: “Sec. 322. Purchase card reporting requirement. “(a) For the purposes of this section, the term “purchase card” means a commercial credit or debit card issued to District government employees for the purpose of procuring goods and service. “(b) The Mayor shall submit to the Council a quarterly report by agency of all expenditures in the purchase card program for each quarter of the fiscal year. The quarterly report shall include the: “(1) Total purchase card budget for each agency; “(2) Fiscal year-to-date total purchase card expenditures by agency as a percentage of the total agency purchase card budget; “(3) Total unverified purchase card expenditures within each agency by object class and employee; “(4) Total purchase card expenditures approved by agency heads; and “(5) Total disapproved purchase card expenditures disapproved by agency, agency head, and employee. “(c) The provisions of this section shall apply to all agencies that participate in the purchase card program instituted by the Office of Contracting and Procurement.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
