<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-355">
  <num type="law">15-355</num>
  <heading type="short">Prevention of Premature Release of Mentally Incompetent Defendants Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2005-05-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-355.pdf">D.C. Law 15-355</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 10547</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0665">
      <narrative>Law 15-355, the “Prevention of Premature Release of Mentally Incompetent Defendants Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-665, which was referred to the Committee on Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 13, 2004, and October 5, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 1, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-566 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-355 became effective on May 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to require that an accused person who has been found mentally incompetent to stand trial or to participate in transfer proceedings and is to be released from detention in the criminal or transfer proceeding be remanded by the court to the hospital for detention pending a hearing on a civil commitment petition that was filed prior to the court’s determination that the person be released, to provide that a person who is so detained may request a probable cause hearing within 7 days of the remand order, to require that the requested probable cause hearing be held within 24 hours of receipt of the request, and to require that a court stay for a period not to exceed 48 hours execution of an order releasing an accused person who has been found mentally incompetent to stand trial or to participate in transfer proceedings, and for whom a civil commitment petition has not been filed, to afford the appropriate authority an opportunity to initiate proceedings for the person’s emergency hospitalization under Chapter 5 of Title 21 of the District of Columbia Official Code. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Prevention of Premature Release of Mentally Incompetent Defendants Amendment Act of 2004”. Sec. 2. Section 927 of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1340; D.C. Official Code § 24-501 is amended by adding a new subsection (a-1) to read as follows: “(a-1)(1) If the court determines after a hearing, or pursuant to a report of the superintendent of the hospital to which neither party objects, that the accused person is mentally incompetent to stand trial or to participate in transfer proceedings, and not likely to regain such competence in the reasonable future, and, if after a petition has been filed pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 21-541, the court further determines that the person shall be released from further detention in the criminal or transfer proceeding, the court shall remand the person to the hospital and the hospital may detain the person pending a hearing on the petition conducted pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 21-542. Within 7 days of the remand order, a person so Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 24-501 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. detained may request a probable cause hearing before the Family Court of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia under D.C. Official Code § 21-525 on the person's continued hospitalization, in which case a hearing shall be held within 24 hours after the receipt of the request. “(2) If the court determines that the accused person shall be released from further detention in the criminal or transfer proceeding, but a petition has not been filed pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 21-541, the court may stay the person’s release for a period not to exceed 48 hours and remand the person to the hospital for the period of the stay so that the superintendent of the hospital may have an opportunity to initiate proceedings for the person’s hospitalization under subchapter III of Chapter 5 of Title 21 of the District of Columbia Official Code.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
