<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-316">
  <num type="law">15-316</num>
  <heading type="short">Bonus Depreciation De-Coupling Temporary Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-316.pdf">D.C. Law 15-316</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 15-316, the “Bonus Depreciation De-Coupling Temporary Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-1111, and was retained by Council. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 9, 2004, and December 7, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 4, 2005, it was assigned Act No. 15-713 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-316 became effective on April 8, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend, on a temporary basis, section 47-1803.03 of the District of Columbia Official Code to de-couple District of Columbia law from the bonus depreciation provisions added to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 by the Job and Growth Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2003. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Bonus Depreciation De-Coupling Temporary Act of 2004”. Sec. 2. Section 47-1803.03 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) Subsection (a)(7) is amended by striking the phrase “September 11, 2004” and inserting the phrase “December 31, 2005” in its place b) Subsection(b)(6) is amended by striking the phrase “September 11, 2004” and inserting the phrase “December 31, 2005” in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the attached fiscal impact statement as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date a) This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Note, § 47-1803.03 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register b) This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
