<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-63">
  <num type="law">15-63</num>
  <heading type="short">Standard Valuation and Nonforfeiture Amendment Act of 2003</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2004-02-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-63.pdf">D.C. Law 15-63</citation>
      <citation type="register">50 DCR 9301</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0017">
      <narrative>Law 15-63, the “Standard Valuation and Nonforfeiture Amendment Act of 2003”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-17, which was referred to Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 8, 2003, and October 7, 2003, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 24, 2003, it was assigned Act No. 15-181 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-63 became effective on February 6, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend section 5c(c)(1)(A) of Chapter V of the Life Insurance Act to change the interest rate for calculating the minimum nonforfeiture amount for life insurance annuities from 3% to 1.5% because the 3% interest rate for cash surrender benefits is incompatible with the current low interest rate environment. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Standard Valuation and Nonforfeiture Amendment Act of 2003 Sec. 2. Section 5c(c)(1) of Chapter V of the Life Insurance Act, effective October 13, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-120; D.C. Official Code § 31-4705.03(c)(1 is amended as follows a) Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the phrase “3 per centum per annum” wherever it appears and inserting the phrase “1.5% per year” in its place b) A new subparagraph (A-1) is added to read as follows: “(A-1) Notwithstanding the interest rate of 1.5% per year used to calculate the minimum nonforfeiture amount under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the Mayor shall issue regulations which shall set forth the computation of the interest rate used to determine the minimum nonforfeiture amount. The regulations shall apply to any contract issued on or after the effective date of the regulations.”. Sec. 3. Rulemaking. The Commissioner shall issue rules and regulations to implement this act within 120 days of the effective date of this act. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2004 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 31-4705.03 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
