<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-108">
  <num type="law">18-108</num>
  <heading type="short">Income Tax Joint Filing Clarification Act of 2009</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2010-03-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-108.pdf">D.C. Law 18-108</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 22</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0312">
      <narrative>Law 18-108, the “Income Tax Joint Filing Clarification Act of 2009”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-312, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 3, 2009, and December 1, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 17, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-246 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-108 became effective on March 3, 2010.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 18 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to clarify the ability of married couples to file District income tax returns jointly or separately on a combined form and to amend references to husband and wife. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Income Tax Joint Filing Clarification Act of 2009”. Sec. 2. Chapter 18 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) Section 47-1801.04(26)(A) is amended by striking the phrase “husband and wife” and inserting the phrase “a married couple” in its place b) Section 47-1805.01 is amended by adding a new subsection (g) to read as follows: “(g) Joint filing of returns for married same-sex individuals. – Married same-sex individuals may file either a joint return or separate returns on a combined form prescribed by the Mayor as if the federal government recognized the right of married same-sex individuals to file jointly.” c) Section 47-1812.08(i)(3) is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase “a husband and wife” and insert the phrase “married individuals” in its place 2) Strike the phrase “the husband and wife” and insert the phrase “the married individuals” in its place. Sec. 3. Applicability. Section 2 shall apply for tax years beginning January 1, 2009. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2010 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 47-1801.04 Amend § 47-1805.01 Amend § 47-1812.08 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
