<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-164">
  <num type="law">18-164</num>
  <heading type="short">Campbell Heights Residents Real Property Tax Exemption Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2010-05-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-164.pdf">D.C. Law 18-164</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 3034</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0490">
      <narrative>Law 18-164, the “Campbell Heights Residents Real Property Tax Exemption Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-490, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 2, 2010, and March 16, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 2, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-356 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-164 became effective on May 27, 2010.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 46 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to exempt from real property taxation, and other impositions, real property located at 2001 15th Street, N.W located in Ward 1, and described as Lot 0207, Square 0204, which is to be maintained as affordable housing. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Campbell Heights Residents Real Property Tax Exemption Act of 2010”. Sec. 2. Chapter 46 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by adding a new section designation to read as follows: “47-4632. Campbell Heights project; Lot 0207, Square 0204.” b) A new section 47-4632 is added to read as follows: “§ 47-4632. Campbell Heights project; Lot 0207, Square 0204. “(a) For the purposes of this section, the term “covenants” means a restrictive covenant or regulatory agreements, or both, associated with the real property's receipt of federal low- income housing tax credits or other assistance pursuant to section 42 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved Oct. 22, 1986 (100 Stat. 2189; 26 U.S.C. § 42 or any other affordable housing program funded fully, or in part, by the District or its instrumentalities, including the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency, restricting the real property's use to multifamily rental housing for low-income housing. “(b) The real property, described as Lot 0207 (or any successor lot or lots Square 0204, shall be exempt from taxation under Chapter 8 of this title, and District of Columbia permitting fees relating to construction or renovation of improvements on the real property, for a period commencing on the day after the transfer of real property to the Campbell Height Residents Association, or its assignee, and the recordation against the real property of the covenants and terminating when the last of the covenants terminates, but for no less than 15 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2010 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher New § 47-4632 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. years in accordance with the applicable low-income housing requirements. “(c) To claim the exemptions provided under subsection (b) of this section, including a refund of any real property taxes already paid, Campbell Height Residents Association, or its assignee, shall file a copy of the recorded deed of the real property to Campbell Height Residents Association, or its assignee, and the recorded covenants, with the Office of Tax and Revenue.”. Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
