<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-182">
  <num type="law">18-182</num>
  <heading type="short">DC Circulator Bus Jurisdiction Expansion Amendment Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2010-05-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-182.pdf">D.C. Law 18-182</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 3404</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0489">
      <narrative>Law 18-182, the “DC Circulator Bus Jurisdiction Expansion Amendment Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-489, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and Transportation. The bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 2, 2010, and March 2, 2010, respectively. signed by the Mayor on April 7, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-381 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-182 became effective on May 27, 2010.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002 to approve the expansion of the DC Circulator to and from Rosslyn Metro station once it assumes the route of the Georgetown Metro Connection, to require an operations report for any DC Circulator route that operates to Rosslyn Metro station, and to limit replacement of Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Metrobus routes by the DC Circulator for a period of 8 months. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "DC Circulator Bus Jurisdiction Expansion Amendment Act of 2010 Sec. 2. The Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective May 21, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-137; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 11c(b D.C. Official Code § 50-921.33(b is amended by striking the phrase “procure those services.” and inserting the phrase, “procure those services; provided, that for a period of 8 months following the Council’s final approval of the DC Circulator Bus Jurisdiction Expansion Amendment Act of 2010, passed on 2nd reading on March 2, 2010 (Enrolled version of Bill18-489 no DC Circulator route shall replace more than 20% of the revenue miles or revenue hours of any WMATA route.” in its place b) A new section 11h is added to read as follows: “Sec. 11h. Jurisdiction expansion and evaluation. “(a) Pursuant to section 11g, the Council approves the expansion of the DC Circulator to and from Rossyln Metro station in Arlington, Virginia, once it assumes the route for the Georgetown Metro Connection. “(b) No later than 6 months after the initiation of service authorized in subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a report for this route. The report shall include: “(1) The overall ridership statistics; “(2) The passenger origin and destination statistics; “(3) The bus stop utilization rates; “(4) The operating and capital costs; Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2010 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 50-921.33 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(5) The impact of DC Circulator expansion on the finances and viability of WMATA Metrobus routes; “(6) The WMATA estimates for the cost of extending Metrobus route 38B to Dupont Circle; and “(7) The WMATA estimates for the cost of adding new Metrobus service between the Rosslyn Metro station and Dupont Circle, with buses operating at intervals similar to buses of the DC Circulator route authorized under this section.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
