<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-131">
  <num type="law">18-131</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Housing Authority Board of Commissioners Amendment Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2010-03-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-131.pdf">D.C. Law 18-131</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 1193</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0458">
      <narrative>Law 18-131, the “District of Columbia Housing Authority Board of Commissioners Amendment Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-458, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Workforce Development. The bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 15, 2009, and January 5, 2010, respectively. Approved without signature of the Mayor on January 25, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-293 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-131 became effective on March 23, 2010.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999 to expand the District of Columbia Housing Authority Board of Commissioners by adding an additional resident commissioner and a representative from the housing advocacy community. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “District of Columbia Housing Authority Board of Commissioners Amendment Act of 2010”. Sec. 2. Section 12 of the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999, effective May 9, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-105; D.C. Official Code § 6-211 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended as follows 1) The lead-in language is amended by striking the number “9" and inserting the number “11" in its place 2) A new paragraph (2A) is added to read as follows 2A) One resident Commissioner, nominated by the Mayor, with the advice and consent of the Council by resolution;” 3) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the word “and” at the end 4) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place 5) A new paragraph (5) is added to read as follows 5) One Commissioner who shall be a housing advocacy representative named by the D.C. Consortium of Legal Services Providers, except that the Commissioner shall not be an employee of the Authority b) Subsection (b) is amended by adding the phrase “pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section” after the phrase “nominated by the Mayor” c) Subsection (m) is amended by adding the phrase “nominated pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section” after the phrase “his or her 4 nominees” d) Subsection (o) is amended as follows: Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2010 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 6-211 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 1) Strike the word “Elected” the first time it appears and insert the word “Resident” in its place 2) Strike the phrase “an elected” wherever it appears and insert the phrase “a resident” in its place 3) Strike the phrase “the elected”and insert the phrase “the resident” in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02 (c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02 (c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
