<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-198">
  <num type="law">18-198</num>
  <heading type="short">Closing of Public Streets Adjacent to Square 1048-S (S.O. 09-11792) Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2010-07-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-198.pdf">D.C. Law 18-198</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 4528</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0694">
      <narrative>Law 18-198, the “Closing of Public Streets Adjacent to Square 1048-S (S.O. 09-11792) Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-694, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 20, 2010, and May 4, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 19, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-410 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-198 became effective on July 23, 2010.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 ZAN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To order the closing of a portion of Virginia Avenue, S.E between M Street, S.E and Water Street, S.E a portion of 14th Street, S.E between M Street, S.E and Water Street, S.E and a portion of M Street, S.E between former Reservations 129 and 299 adjacent to Square 1048-S; and to amend the District of Columbia Public Space Rental Act to waive vault rental payments for any vault occupying the Virginia Avenue right-of-way abutting Lot 1, Square 1048-S. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Closing of Public Streets Adjacent to Square 1048-S (S.O. 09-11792) Act of 2010 Sec. 2. Pursuant to section 201 of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-201; D.C. Official Code § 9- 202.01)(“Act” the Council finds that the portions of the streets adjacent to Square 1048-S, as shown on the Surveyor's plats filed under S.O. 09-11792, are unnecessary for street purposes and orders them closed, with title to the land to vest as shown on the Surveyor's plat. Sec. 3. The applicants under S.O. 09-11792 shall not be subject to the provisions of section 3 of the Comprehensive Plan Amendment Act of 1984, effective April 10, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-76; D.C. Official Code § 1-306.33 or the provisions of section 209(f) of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 9-202.09(f The applicants’ project, as generally described in S.O. 09- 1792, shall not be subject to section 4 of the First Source Employment Agreement Act of 1984, effective June 29, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-93; D.C. Official Code § 2-219.03 Sec. 4. Section 305 of the District of Columbia Public Space Rental Act, approved October 17, 1968 (82 Stat. 1159; D.C. Official Code § 10-1103.04 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase “Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section” and inserting the phrase "Except as provided in subsections (d) and (d-1) of this section" in its place b) A new subsection (d-1) is added to read as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 “(d-1) Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the owner of Lot 1 in Square 1048- S (“property”) shall not be required to pay the rent required by subsection (a) of this section for any vault occupying the Virginia Avenue right-of-way abutting the property and constructed after the effective date of the Closing of Public Streets Adjacent to Square 1048-S (S.O. 09- 11792) Act of 2010, passed on 2nd reading on May 4, 2010 (Enrolled version of Bill 18-694).”. Sec. 5. Transmittal. The Secretary to the Council shall transmit a copy of this act, upon its effective date, to the Office of the Surveyor and the Office of the Recorder of Deeds. Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 7. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1983 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
