<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-235">
  <num type="law">18-235</num>
  <heading type="short">Renovation Penalty Abatement Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2010-10-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-235.pdf">D.C. Law 18-235</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 7158</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0518">
      <narrative>Law 18-235, the “Renovation Penalty Abatement Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-518, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 15, 2010, and June 29, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 19, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-483 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-235 became effective on October 15, 2010.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend section 47-829 of the District of Columbia Official Code to exclude Class 1 Property from the special assessment procedures related to home improvement. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Renovation Penalty Abatement Act of 2010”. Sec. 2. Section 47-829(e-1) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended to read as follows: “(e-1) Class 1 Property, as defined under § 47-813(c-8)(2)(A shall not be subject to subsection (e) of this section.”. Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2010 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 47-813 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
