<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-287">
  <num type="law">18-287</num>
  <heading type="short">Blood Donation Expansion Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2011-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-287.pdf">D.C. Law 18-287</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 11495</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0127">
      <narrative>Law 18-287, the “Blood Donation Expansion Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-127, which was referred to the Committee on Health. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 19, 2010, and November 9, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 19, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-608 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-287 became effective on March 8, 2011.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To permit a minor 16 years of age who meets all the health requirements to donate blood with the written consent of a parent or legal guardian, and a minor 17 years of age or more who meets all the health requirements to donate blood without consent of a parent or legal guardian. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Blood Donation Expansion Act of 2010 Sec. 2. Minor blood donations. Provided that the minor meets all the health requirements for blood donation, a minor 16 years of age may donate blood with the written consent of a parent or legal guardian and a minor 17 years of age or more may donate blood without consent of a parent or legal guardian. Sec. 3. Rules. The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2011 Winter Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1551.31"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1551.32"/>
  </section>
</document>
