<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-240">
  <num type="law">18-240</num>
  <heading type="short">Residential Parking Protection Pilot Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2010-10-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-240.pdf">D.C. Law 18-240</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 7186</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0057">
      <narrative>Law 18-240, the “Residential Parking Protection Pilot Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-57, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and Transportation. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 29, 2010, and July 13, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 30, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-491 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-240 became effective on October 26, 2010.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establish a Ward 1 Enhanced Residential Parking Program, to require, upon Advisory Neighborhood Commission opt-in, that at least 50% of residential parking spaces that are within each Advisory Neighborhood Commission boundary be reserved for Zone 1 parking permit holders, that households within each Advisory Neighborhood Commission boundary be eligible to participate in the visitor parking pass program, and that residents on Residential Parking Permit eligible streets be allowed to receive Residential Parking Permit stickers, to require that blocks in streetscape construction project impact zones be excluded from the Ward 1 Enhanced Residential Parking Program, and to require that the Mayor issue rules to implement this act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Residential Parking Protection Pilot Act of 2010”. Sec. 2. Ward 1 Enhanced Residential Parking Program a) There is established a Ward 1 Enhanced Residential Parking Program (“Program” Any Ward 1 Advisory Neighborhood Commission (“ANC”) may, by resolution of that ANC, vote to include blocks within the ANC in the Program. The Program will consist of the following requirements 1) Any block that participates in the residential permit parking in Ward 1 shall have at least 50% of the legal residential parking spaces on that block designated as Zone 1 Permitted Parking Only 2) A visitor parking pass program shall be available to residents similar to the program in Mount Pleasant required by section 8 of the Performance Parking Pilot Zone Act of 2010, effective November 25, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-279; D.C. Official Code § 50-2537 and (3) Any resident owning a vehicle registered at an address on a Ward 1 residential block may be granted a Zone 1 residential parking sticker, in accordance with the process developed by the Mayor pursuant to section 3 b) Blocks within a streetscape construction project impact zone, as designated by the Mayor, shall be excluded from the Program until the Mayor declares that all major construction associated with the streetscape has been completed. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2010 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 3. Rules a) Within 90 days of the effective date of this act, the Mayor, pursuant to Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the rules, in whole or in part, by resolution, within this 30-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed disapproved b) The rules submitted to the Council shall address the following 1) The application of the requirements of section 2 to streets that are on the boundary of Ward 1 2) The application of the requirements of section 2 to streets that are on the boundary of an ANC 3) The definition of streetscape construction project impact zones as referenced in section 2(b 4) The process for receiving a visitor pass and the hours for the visitor pass programs; and (5) The eligibility requirements for who may receive the permit referenced in section 2(a)(3 Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2551"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2552"/>
  </section>
</document>
