<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-212">
  <num type="law">18-212</num>
  <heading type="short">Some, Inc., Technical Amendments Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2010-08-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-212.pdf">D.C. Law 18-212</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 4953</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0669">
      <narrative>Law 18-212, the “Some, Inc., Technical Amendments Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-669, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 4, 2010, and May 18, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 7, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-431 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-212 became effective on August 6, 2010.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to correct the corporate name of SOME, Inc and to clarify that the tax exemptions for these properties will continue so long as use restrictions are in effect during a federal low- income housing tax credit compliance period or a Department of Housing and Community Development compliance period. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “SOME, Inc Technical Amendments Act of 2010”. Sec. 2. Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by striking the phrase “47-1078. So Others Might Eat, Inc.” and inserting the phrase “47-1078. SOME, Inc.” in its place b) Section 47-1078 is amended as follows 1) The section heading is amended by striking the phrase “So Others Might Eat, Inc.” and inserting the phrase “SOME, Inc.” in its place 2) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows: “(a)(1) The real properties listed in paragraph (2) of this subsection and owned by SOME, Inc Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by SOME, Inc or Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc shall be exempt from real property taxation, effective as of the dates stated in paragraph (2) of this subsection, so long as: “(A) The real property continues to be used in accordance with the application for property tax exemption filed for that particular property; “(B) The owner continues to be SOME, Inc or Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by SOME, Inc or Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc or “(C)(i) The owner is any entity, for-profit or nonprofit; and “(ii) The real property continues to be under applicable use Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2010 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Note, § 47-1078 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. restrictions during a: “(I) Federal low-income housing tax credit compliance period; or “(II) Department of Housing and Community Development compliance period. “(2) The following real properties shall be exempt from real property taxation in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection: “(A) Lot 811, Square 3567, located at 1876 4th Street, N.E effective August 1, 2006; “(B) Lot 812, Square 3567, located at 1876 4th Street, N.E effective August 1, 2006; “(C) Lot 33, Square 5322, located at 360 50th Street, S.E effective June 1, 2007; “(D) Lot 34, Square 5322, located at 350 50th Street, S.E effective June 1, 2007; “(E) Parcel 2180096, Square 5616, located at 1701 19th Street, S.E effective April 1, 2006; “(F) Lot 815, Square 5637, located at 2810-2872 Texas Avenue, S.E effective June 1, 2007; “(G) Lot 47, Square 5760, located at 2125 18th Street, S.E effective July 1, 2005; “(H) Lot 894, Square 5765, located at 1667 Good Hope Road, S.E effective January 1, 2007; “(I) Lot 811, Square 6129, located at 3828--3830 South Capitol Street, S. E effective June 1, 2007; “(J) Lot 822, Square 6164, located at 740 Barnaby Street, S.E effective March 1, 2007; and “(K) Lots 2086--2127, Square 6164, located at 730--736 Chesapeake Street, S.E effective November 1, 2007.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
