<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-120">
  <num type="law">10-120</num>
  <heading type="short">Cogeneration Facilities Appropriateness Standards Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-05-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-120.pdf">D.C. Law 10-120</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 1648</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0447">
      <narrative>Law 10-120, the “Cogeneration Facilities Appropriateness Standards Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-447, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 1, 1994, and March 1, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 17, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-210 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-120 became effective on May 21, 1994.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENRO LMEN (S) kwiktag 062 313 604 AN ACT D,C, ACT I0-380 ENROLLED ORIGIHAL Co Ication District of Co!umbia Code { 1995 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 27, 1994 To amend title 16 of the District of Columbia Code to extend the remedies for intrafamily offenses to those in romantic relationships and to establish a misdemeanor penalty for violating a protection order. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Domestic Violence in Romantic Relationships Act of 1994 See. 2. Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 16-1001(5) is amended to read as follows 5) The term "intrafamily offense" means an act punishable as a criminal offense committed by an offender upon a person A) to whom the offender is related by blood, legal custody, marriage, having a child in common, or with whom the offender shares or has shared a mutual residence; or B) with whom the offender maintains or maintained a romantic relationship not necessarily including a sexual relationship. A person seeking a protection order under this subparagraph shall reside in the District of Columbia or the underlying intrafamily offense shall have occurred in the District of Columbia b) Section 16-1003 is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows d) An action for an intrafamily offense under section 16-1001(5)(B) shall not be brought more than 2 years from the date the right to maintain the action accrues b) Section 16-1005 is amended by adding a new subsection (g) to read as follows g) Any person who violates any protection order issued under this chapter shall be chargeable with a misdemeanor and upon conviction shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $1,000 or by imprisonment for not more than 180 days, or both Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override of the veto) as provided in section 602{c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-223(c)(1 Section 16-i001 Section 16-1003 Sect ~on 16-1005 ENROLLED ORIGINAL and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations hairma, Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: December 27, 1994 CO¢TI’W’CE[, OF THE: DISI~cr DE’ COI nJ~L-t C x::L1. 9ez::Lcx:l RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DCCKET NO Item on Consent CaJena ACTION&amp;amp; DATE cVOICE VOTE ecorclecl vote on re(:uesl Absent OLL CALL VOTE RESULT I COUNCIL MEMBER I AYE, N~,Y N.V I AIB. CEHH CLARKE! ’~ ’ BARRy i I B.RAZIL ’ 1CHAVOUS 1 1 CROPp I 1 } ~dopted First Reading, 11-1-94 B10- 477 Approved Barry 1 ’ i" RAY SMITH JR ]ARVI I I ’ ii IG~T~nnT i THOMAS~ SR MASON I ,i I }NATHANSON I I I XACTION &amp;amp; DATE vOiCE VOTE RecotCt~l vote on reClUest ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE CHMN. CLARK~ BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CRQPP X me, cams Vote A.B Al~sem ~1’~;’ 0 CER~FICATION RECORD i It Con~t ~ar ~ed Fi ~i proved not votlncJ Reading, 12-6-94 Jarvi s, U ghtfoot and Thorras (Ill jARVi~ i SMITH~ JR. I i ~l ’ I.IGHTFOOT [ L I THOMAS R I i i I i MA~QN I i [ i I I NATHANSO I l’ I ’ i i !I x vm~ A.B A~ N.V n~ vo~n I B~A~ON R~COB I ~m O ACI~ON &amp;amp; DATE; VOICE VOI~ RecorOe¢l vo~ on m¢lue~ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY N.V. kB COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY I N.V. RAY SMITH~ JR THOMAS, SR. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY I N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C~MN. CLARKE EVANSBARRY JARV I S BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CHAVOUS 1 MAS,,ON CROPP I NATHAN~QN X lnamale~ Vole CERTIRCA~ON RECORD</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-1301"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-1302"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-1303"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-1304"/>
  </section>
</document>
