<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-230">
  <num type="law">10-230</num>
  <heading type="short">Small Claims Service of Process Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1995-03-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-230.pdf">D.C. Law 10-230</citation>
      <citation type="register">42 DCR 11</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0089">
      <narrative>Law 10-230, the “Small Claims Service of Process Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-89, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 6, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-371 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-230 became effective on March 21, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwikta8 062 314 642 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10- 230 Small Claims Service of Process Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-89 on first and second readings, November 1, 1994 and December 6, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 27, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-371, and published in the January 6, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 11) and transmitted to Congress on Feburary 3, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-230, effective March 21, 1995. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 Mar. 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,17,20 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT District of Columbia Cod~ IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend section 16-3902 of the District of Columbia Code to allow the Clerk of the Small Claims and ConciIlatlon Branch of the Superior Court ot the District ot Columbia to authorize the use of a special process server in a small claims action, to extend the period of time allowed for service of process in actions commenced in the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch from J5 days to 30 days, and to extend the period of time fox" the District ot Columbia government to tile an answer in a small claims action against the District government. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Small Claims Service of Process Act of 1994 Sec. 2. Section 16-3902 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The last sentence in subsection (a) is amended to read as follows The mode of service shall be by the United States marshal, as provided by law, or by registered mail or by certified mall with return receipt, or by a person not a party to or otherwise interested in the action especially authorized by the Clerk of the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch or appointed by the judge for that purpose b) Subsection (g) is amended by striking the figure "15" and inserting the figure "30" in its place c) A new subsection (h) is added to read as follows h) Where the defendant is the District of Columbia or an officer or agency thereof, the Clerk shall schedule the hearing for a day that is not less than 30 days from the date of the filing of the action, service ota copy ot the action on the Corporation Counsel to be completed within 15 days of filing Sec. 3. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period ot Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event ot veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District ot Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and Section 16-3902 EHROLLEI) ORIGBIAI, publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations gt;f" i &amp;lt ha~man ’ Council of the District oE Columbia Mayor District oE Columbia 2 COET~C~ O Dr~t~CT O~’ RECORD OF Ol=lqClAI. COUNCIl= VOTE t~m on Condom C~ee¢~ Z ACI"1CN &amp;amp; 0A ’~C~C~ VQ ecor ote ;n e sent C~ CAL~ VCT ESULT AVE AY ,DOCKET NO B10,-89 Adopted First ~eadinq, 11ri-94 APproved X vOCE vo,rE I i X m:l l~ V~ ¯ vOwS VOTe, COUNCIL C~MN..CLARKE ~BARRY I’BRAZIL ’ L ~CHAVOU CROPP I Adopted Final Approved Barry Reading, 12-6-94 COUNOLFVAN~ MC~,IeER ,we, N Y }’,N,V I~E QARv s ’, i I I Ii ,MASON } { NA~AN~N I N.V P~ c m~omo i COUNCIl. EVANS ’ JARVIS LIGHTFOOT F MASQN NATHANSON A AI~ N.V m~e~ CF.RTIFICA‘rWDN R COFIO RAY ’ I SMITH JR I COUNCIL M~w~I~I RAY I ’i i SMITH JR i i’ (I THOMAS. SR ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C, ACT i0-371 District of Columbia Code IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 27, 1994 To amend section 16-3902 of the District of Columbia Code to allow the Clerk of the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to authorize the use of a special process server in a small claims action, to extend the period of time allowed for service of process in actions commenced in the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch from 15 days to 30 days, and to extend the period of time for the District of Columbia government to file an answer in a small claims action against the District government. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Small Claims Service of Process Act of 1994" See. 2. Section 16-3902 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The last sentence in subsection (a) is amended to read as follows The mode of service shall be by the United States marshal, as provided by law, or by registered mail or by certified mail with return receipt, or by a person not a party to or otherwise interested in the action especially authorized by the Clerk of the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch or appointed by the judge for that purpose b) Subsection (g) is amended by striking the figure "15" and inserting the figure "30" in its place c) A new subsection (h) is added to read as follows h) Where the defendant is the District of Columbia or an officer or agency thereof, the Clerk shah schedule the hearing for a day that is not less than 30 days from the date of the filing of the action, service of a copy of the action on the Corporation Counsel to be completed within 15 days of filing Sec. 3. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and Section 16-3902 ENROLLED ORIGINAL publication in either the District of Columbia l~egister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal l~egulations Y Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: De~ember 27, 1994 @ COUNCIL OF DI~r~CT OF COLUMBI~ Oxm~l n RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNC;L VOTE DOCKET NO: BI0-89 Adopted First Readinq~ 11-1-94 Approved Y "COUNCIL MEMB v I NA N.V. I A.&amp;amp; ] COUNC’,L MEMBEF W NAY ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE. vOICE VOTE Recor(:l vole on NATHANS( I A.@ AbSe~ N.V Preset mo~ voun Oate Adopted Final Approved Barry ROU.CAU.vo RESULT ’COU~CILMEMBER AYE{NAYIN.V A.B. COUNCILMEMBER AYE CHMN. CLARKE{~I EVANS BARRY ’{ ~ARViS B~AZI’L I LIGHTFOOT } CHAVOUS } HA:ON, CRQPP I J NATHANSON I Readin@, 12-6-94 NAY NV. X n~calU VO~e A.8 AOS N.V Preset f C~CA~ON R~ORO ¯ ’ } C it C AC’nON &amp;amp; DATE vO~E VOT ROLL CALL VOT RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYI~ NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZ,IL ~CHAVOUS :CROPP L x Ir~lmates voi~ l COUNCIL MEMBEm I AYe NAY 9.v. i ’ RAY_ [ I ’ ’ SM, ITH J R. i i i i !THOMAS R. I I ’ COUNClL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. EVANS RAY Jh JARVIS SMITH LIGHTFOOT" ’ THOMAS~ SR. I ’ M, ASON NATHANSON A.B AI~ N.V P~ n j CER~FICA~GN R~’CORO</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
