<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-244">
  <num type="law">10-244</num>
  <heading type="short">Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact Amendment Act of 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1995-03-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-244.pdf">D.C. Law 10-244</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 10-244, the “Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact Amendment Act of 1994,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-647, which was referred to the Committee on Regional Authorities and sequentially to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 21, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 30, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-390 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-244 became effective on March 21, 1995.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENRO kwiktag" 103 221 690 M NT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10- 244 "Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-647 on first and second readings, November 1, 1994 and December 21, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 30, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-390, and published in the January 13, 1995, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 42 page 234) and transmitted to Congress on Feburary 3, 1995 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-244, effective March 21, 1995. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-da.v Congressional Review PedQcl: Feb. 3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,21,22,23,24,27,28 Mar. 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,17,20 EliROLLEO ORIGINAL AN ACT Codification ’~ D,C. ACT i0-390 District of Columbia Cod 1995. Supplement| t IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 30, 1994 To amend the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact to expand the jurisdiction of the Metro Transit Police to include the entire Transit Zone and to allow Metro Transit Police to carry weapons at all times. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact Amendment Act of 1994" See. 2. Section 76(a) and (b) of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact, approved November 6, 1966 (80 Star. 1324; D.C. Code § 1-2431)(a) and (b is amended to read as follows a) The Authority is authorized to establish and maintain a regular police force, to be known as the Metro Transit Police, to provide protection for its patrons, personnel, and transit facilities. The Metro Transit Police shall have the powers and duties and shall be subject to the limitations set forth in this section. It shall be composed of both uniformed and plainclothes personnel and shall be charged with the duty of enforcing the laws of the signatories, the laws, ordinances, and regulations of the political subdivisions thereof in the Transit Zone, and the rules and regulations of the Authority. The jurisdiction of the Metro Transit Police shall be limited to the Transit Zone. The members of the Metro Transit Police shall have concurrent jurisdiction in the performance of their duties with the duly constituted law enforcement agencies of the signatories and the political subdivisions thereof in which any transit facility of the Authority is located or in which the Authority operates any transit service. Nothing contained in this section shall either relieve any signatory or political subdivision or agency thereof from its duty to provide police, fire, and other public safety service and protection, or limit, restrict, or interfere with the jurisdiction of or the performance of duties by the existing police, fire, and other public safety agencies b) A member of the Metro Transit Police shall have the powers, including the power of arrest, and shall be subject to the same limitations, including regulatory limitations, in the performance of his or her duties as a member of the duly constituted police force of the political subdivision in which the Metro Transit Police member is engaged in the performance of his or her duties. A member of the Metro Transit Police is authorized to carry and use only such weapons, including handguns, as are issued by the Authority, but is subject to such additional Note, Section 1-2431 F.IIP, OLLEO OI [GI tAL limitations in the use of weapons as are imposed on the duly constituted police force for the political subdivision in which he or she is engaged in the performance of his or her duties Sec. 3. The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall, for the District of Columbia, enter into agreements with the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Maryland to make technical amendments to title 3 of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact, so long as the amended version of the compact then substantially conforms to the amendments in section 2 of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact Amendment Act of 1994. The technical amendments shall become effective when the Mayor executes the agreements concerning the compact. See. 4. The provisions of sections 2 and 3 of this act shall apply upon the passage of similar acts by the State of Maryland and the Commonwealth of Virginia. See. 5. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia l~egister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Note, Section 1-2431 Note, Section 1-2431 District of Columbia APPROVED: December 30, 1994 COr~ICIL OF TKE DISTRICt OF COLUMBI~ O:mmc~_l Item on Consen! CalenQar ACTION &amp;amp; OATE ecor(:ecr vote on ~sent: RECORO OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE ,30C~T NO: B10-647 Adopted First Readin9, 11-1-94 Approved Barry, Chavous, Ray and Thomas CALL VOTE F~ESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE,NAY N.V !A.B COUNC:L.’.AEMBER ’ CHMN CLARKE. i i EV’ANS BARRY LBRAZIL I T r~}~T~nnT i CHAV01IS ’ MASON CROPP ] X rt(IIC;~teS VOte tt~ on Consent O LL ACTION &amp;amp; OATE vOiCE VOTE Recor{3~3 vot~ on ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT A.B Al=sent N. V q Preseot"rt~,vo~nq CERTIFICATION RECORD i A.E]. ] COUNC:L,~EMBER ’ ~YE NAY RAY SMITH, JR. THOMAS~ SR ate Adopted Final Reading, 12-21-94 Approved Barry and Evans ~gU~CILMEMBER!AYEINAYNVA’B’COUNCILMEMB~IAYEcHMN. CLARKE FVANq BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CR~PP X n~lca~ Vote A.B Ab~enl item 0¢t CO~ C~I~I ACTION VOICE VO~ Re~omed v~e ~n rea~e~ ROLL CALL V01 RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER ~MN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL :CHAVOUS CROPP AYE NAY N.V. A.B. X ln(~icate~ Vote NAY I N.V. COUN~.IL MEMBER RAY. IS,,M=TTH JR. ITHOMAS R !AYE NAY IV A COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. EVANS JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON ~ATHAN~QN A.B N.V Present n~l CERTIFICATION RECORO COUNCIL MEMBER AYE RAY SMITH JR. THOMAS~ SR. NAY I NV</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
