<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-34">
  <num type="law">10-34</num>
  <heading type="short">REGISTERED LIMITED LIABILITY PARTNERSHIP AMENDMENT ACT OF 1993</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1993-10-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-34.pdf">D.C. Law 10-34</citation>
      <citation type="register">40 DCR 5764</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0018"/>
    <search-text>kwiktag ® 062 313 840 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-34 "Reqistered Limited Liability Partnership Amendment Act of 1993 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Govlernmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-18 on first and second readings, June I, 1993, and July 13, 1993, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 29, 1993, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-66, published in the August 13, 1993, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 40 page 5764) and transmitted to Congress on August 3, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-34, effective October 15, 1993 A~~v Chairman of th Cou cil ~Dates Counted Duriqg. the 30-day Cg.n.gressional Review PeriQd: August September October 3,4,5,6 7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,17,20,21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30 1,4,5,6,7,12,13,14 AN ACT D.C. ACT 10-66 Enrolled Original District of Columbia Code Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 29, 1993 To amend the Uniform Partnership Act of 1962 to relieve a partner from individual and joint and several liability for partnership obligations created by another partner’s misconduct. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Registered Limited Liability Partnership Amendment Act of 1993 See. 2. The Uniform Partnership Act of 1962, approved September 27, 1962 (76 star. 636; D.C. Code § 41-I01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 41-101) is amended by adding 2 new definitions to read as follows Majority in interest" means those persons holding more than 50% of current interest in the profits of the partnership Registered limited liability partnership" means a partnership registered pursuant to section 44 and complying with sections 45 and 46 b) New sections 6a, 44, 45, 46, 47, 48, and 49 are added to read as follows Sec. 6a. Registration and fees a) The Mayor may require that partnerships register on forms provided by the Mayor, and that partnerships be assessed a fee for the registration b) The proposed fee schedule shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed fee schedule shall be deemed approved. Nothing in this section shall affect any requirements imposed upon the Mayor by title i of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1204; D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq Sec. 44. Registered limited liability partnerships a) To become a registered limited liability partnership, a partnership must file an application with the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Department that sets forth the following 1) The name of the registered limited liability partnership; Section 41-101 New Section 41-105.1 New Section 41-143 Entailed Odginal 2) The address of the principal office and the name and address of the registered agent for service of process on limited liability partnerships and general partnerships 3) The written permission of the registered agent to serve as registered agent d) The number of partners 5) A brief statement of the business in which the limited liability partnership engages 6) A statement that the limited liability partnership will maintain insurance coverage required pursuant to section 46 at all times during which it conducts business in the District; and 7) Any other information the Department considers appropriate b) The application must be executed by a majority in interest of the partners or by i or more partners authorized by a majority in interest of the partners c) The Department shall register or renew any partnership that submits a satisfactorily completed application d) Registration is effective for 1 year after the date the registration is filed, unless voluntarily withdrawn by filing with the Department a written withdrawal notice executed by a majority in interest of the partners or by 1 or more partners authorized by a majority in interest of the partners, and shall be renewed annually on the anniversary date of the original registration e) The Department shall provide forms for application or for renewal of registration f)(1) The Department shall assess charges and publish a schedule of fees for registration, renewal, and amendments 2) The proposed fee schedule shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed fee schedule shall be deemed approved. Nothing in this section shall affect any requirements imposed upon the Mayor by title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 star. 1204; D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq g) Unless otherwise specifically provided by other provisions of this act, the registered limited liability partnership shall be subject to all the provisions of this act Sec. 45. Name of registered limited liability partnerships The name of a registered limited liability partnership shall contain the words "Registered Limited Liability Partnership" or the abbreviation "L.L.P as the last words or letters of its name Sec. 46. Insurance requirement for registered limited liability partnerships a) A registered limited liability partnership shall carry liability insurance in the amount of coverage of either (i) at least $I00,000 of liability insurance of a type that is designed to cover the kind of errors, omissions, negligence, incompetence, or malfeasance for which liability is limited by section 47, or (ii) coverage in a minimum amount of not less than the amount carried by the individual partner carrying the greatest amount of individual liability insurance, whichever is greater. New Section 41-144 New Section 41-145 Enrolled Original b) If the registered limited liability partnership is in compliance with the requirements of subsection (a) of this section, the requirements of this section shall not be admissible or in any way made known to the jury in determining the issue of liability or extent of the debt or obligation or damages in question Sec. 47. Nature of partners’ liability in registered limited liability New Section partnership. 4 I- 146 a) A partner in a registered limited liability partnership is not individually liable for debts and obligations of the partnership arising from errors, omissions, negligence, incompetence, or malfeasance committed in the course of the partnership business by a second partner or a representative of the partnership not working under the supervision or direction of the first partner at the time the errors, omissions, negligence, incompetence, or malfeasance occurred, unless the first partner 1) Was directly involved in the specific activity in which the errors, omissions, negligence, incompetence, or malfeasance were committed by the other partner or representative; or 2) Had written notice or knowledge of the errors, omissions, negligence, incompetence, or malfeasance that were committed by the other partner or representative at the time of occurrence b) Subsection (a) of this section does not affect the joint liability of the partner for debts and obligations of the partnership arising from any cause other than those specified in subsection (a) of this section c) Subsection (a) of this section does not affect the liability of partnership assets for partnership debts and obligations See. 48. Foreign registered limited liability partnerships. New Section "Foreign limited liability partnerships may conduct business in the 41-147 District of Columbia upon filing a legally sufficient application pursuant to section 44 and other applicable laws and regulations of the District. The laws of the state or other jurisdiction under which a foreign registered limited liability partnership is organized shall govern its organization and internal affairs and the liability of its partners. A foreign registered limited liability partnership may not be prohibited from doing or transacting business in the District of Columbia by reason of any difference between the laws of the state or other jurisdiction under which it is organized and the laws of the District of Columbia Sec. 49. Applicability of chapter to foreign and interstate commerce a) A partnership or registered limited liability partnership organized and existing under this act may conduct its business, carry on its operations, and exercise the powers granted by this act in any state, territory, district, or possession of the United States or in any foreign country b) It is the intent of the Council that the legal existence of registered limited liability partnerships organized in the District of Columbia be recognized outside the boundaries of the District of Columbia and that, subject to any reasonable requirement of registration, a District of Columbia registered limited liability partnership transacting business outside the District of Columbia be granted full faith and credit c) The liability of partners in a registered limited liability partnership organized and existing under this act for the debts and obligations of the registered limited liability partnership, or for the acts New Section 41-148 Enrolled Odginal or omission of other partners, employees, or representatives of the registered limited liability partnership shall at all times be determined solely and exclusively by the provisions of this act and any regulations promulgated hereunder Sec. 3. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: July 29, 1993 COL~NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO I"1 Item on Consent Calendar I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: l~ VOICE VOTE Recorded vote on request Absent: BI0-18 Adopted First Reading, 6-1-93 Approved Chavous and Jarvis [3 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COL’INCIL MEMBER c A~ BARRY B-~AZIL ’ ’CHAV_OUS LCJROPPr X Indicates Vote I Secreti(9/t-° the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar AYE NAY NV A.B. COUNCILMEM~ER ’ EVAN.S’ ’, J~RVIS LIGH~FOOT ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request J J AYE NAY N.VI A.B COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B ’ SMITHr. JR- THOS~S, SR SON NATHAN=qO~ ’’" ’ A.8 A.bsent ¯ N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ’ 6 O=e Adopted Final Reading, 7-13-93 Approved Absent: Chavous [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT [ COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.I COUNCIL MEMBER "AYE NAY N.,V. A.B, COUNCIL MEMBER -AYE NAY N.V.A.B. CHMN. EAX EVANS M~TH, JR. BARRY JARVI S ’ BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CHAVOUS M~AS oN dROPP "’ NATHANSON ’ X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Sentry ~’o the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar ~HOM~S, SR. Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: BR~ZTT, c~pp [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT J W COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE i NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. I A.B. CHMN ’.’ .KAY EVANS SMIT.H, JR JARVI S THOMAS. SR. LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHAN SON X Indicates Vote ’ A.B Absent IN.VI Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
