<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-36">
  <num type="law">10-36</num>
  <heading type="short">Law on Credit for Reinsurance Act of 1993</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1993-10-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-36.pdf">D.C. Law 10-36</citation>
      <citation type="register">40 DCR 5812</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0128">
      <narrative>Law 10-36, the “Law on Credit for Reinsurance Act of 1993,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-128, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 29, 1993, and July 13, 1993, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 29, 1993, it was assigned Act No. 10-69 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-36 became effective on October 15, 1993.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D,C. LAW 10-36 "Law on Credit for Reinsurance Act of 1993 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-128 on first and second readings, June 29, 1993, and July 13, 1993, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 29, 1993, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-69, published in the August 13, 1993, edition of the D.C. Re~ister Vol. 40 page 5812) and transmitted to Congress on August 3, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-36, effective October 15 1993 BAVID CLARKE Chairman o£ ~he Council Oate~s counted D.u..r ng he 30-d.a#_CO.Dgressional Review Period: August 3,4,5,6 September 7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,17,20,21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30 October 1,4,5,6,7,12,13,14 Enrolled Original AN ACT DI M t of Co rnbl Code D, C. ACT 10-69 ,1994 Supplement) New Chapter 33, Title 35 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTt~ICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 29, 1993 To establish when credit shall be allowed when reinsurance is ceded to an assuming insurer which is licensed to transact insurance or reinsurance in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Law on Credit for l~einsuranee Act of 1993 See. 2. Credit allowed a domestic ceding insurer a) Credit for reinsurance shall be allowed a domestic ceding insurer as either an asset or a deduction from liability on account of reinsurance ceded only when the reinsurer meets the requirements of paragraph (2 3 4 or (5) of this subsection. If meeting the requirements of paragraph (3) or (4) of this subsection, the requirements of paragraph (6) of this subsection must also be met 1) Credit shall be allowed when the reinsurance is ceded to an assuming insurer which is licensed to transact insurance or reinsurance in the District of Columbia 2) Credit shall be allowed when the reinsurance is ceded to an assuming insurer which is accredited as a reinsurer in the District of Columbia. An accredited reinsurer is one which A) Files evidence of its submission to the District of Columbia jurisdiction with the Superintendent B) Submits to the District of Columbia authority to examine its books and records C) Is licensed to transact insurance or reinsurance in a least one state, or, in the case of a United States branch of an alien assuming insurer, is entered through and licensed to transact insurance or reinsurance in the District or at least one state; and (D) Files annually with the Superintendent a copy of its annual statement filed with the insurance department of its state of domicile and a copy of its most recent audited financial statement, and i) Maintains a surplus as regards policyholders in an amount which is not less than $20,000,000 and whose accreditation has not been denied by the Superintendent within 90 days of its submission; or (ii) Maintains a surplus as regards policyholders in an amount less than $20,000,000 and whose accreditation has been approved by the Superintendent. New Section 35-3301 Enrolled Original (3)(A) Credit shall be allowed when the reinsurance is ceded to an assuming insurer which is domiciled and licensed in, or, in the case of a United States branch of an alien assuming insurer, is entered through, a state which employs standards regarding credit for reinsurance substantially similar to those applicable under this statute, and the assuming insurer or United States branch of an alien assuming insurer i) Maintains a surplus as regards policyholders in an amount not less than $20,000,000 ii) Submits to the authority of the District of Columbia to examine its books and records; and (iii) Complies with the requirements of paragraph (6) of this subsection B) The requirement of paragraph (3)(A) of this subsection does not apply to reinsurance ceded and assumed pursuant to pooling arrangements among insurers in the same holding company system 4)(A) Credit shall be allowed when the reinsurance is ceded to an assuming insurer which maintains a trust fund in a qualified United States financial institution, as defined in section 4(b for the payment of the valid claims of its United States policyholders and ceding insurers, their assignees and successors in interest. The assuming insurer shall report annually to the Superintendent information substantially the same as that required to be reported on the NAIC Annual Statement form by licensed insurers to enable the Superintendent to determine the sufficiency of the trust fund. In the case of a single assuming insurer, the trust shall consist of a trusteed account representing the assuming insurerWs liabilities attributable to business written in the United States, and, in addition, the assuming insurer shall maintain a trusteed surplus of not less than $20,000,000. In the ease of a group of underwriters, which includes individuals, the trust shall consist of a trusteed account representing the groupWs liabilities attributable to business written in the United States and, in addition, the group shall maintain a trusteed surplus of which $100,000,000 shall be held jointly for the benefit of United States ceding insurers of any member of the group. The group shall make available to the Superintendent an annual certification of the solvency of each underwriter by the group’s domiciliary regulator and its independent public accountants B) In the case of a group of incorporated insurers under common administration which complies with the filing requirements contained in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, has continuously transacted an insurance business outside the United States for at least 3 years immediately prior to making application for accreditation, submits to the District of Columbia authority to examine its books and records and bears the expense of the examination, and has aggregate policyholdersv surplus of $10,000,000,000, the trust shall be in an amount equal to the groupVs several liabilities attributable to business ceded by United States ceding insurers to any member of the group pursuant to reinsurance contracts issued in the name of the group. The group shall maintain a joint trusteed surplus of which $100,000,000 shall be held jointly and exclusively for the benefit of United States ceding insurers of any member of the group as additional security for any liabilities, and each member of the group shall make available to the Superintendent an Enrolled Original annual certification of the member’s solvency by the member’s domiciliary regulator and its independent public accountant C) The trust shall be established in a form approved by the Superintendent of Insurance. The trust instrument shall provide that contested claims shall be valid and enforceable upon the final order of any court of competent jurisdiction in the United States. The trust shall vest legal title to its assets in the trustees of the trust for its United States policyholders and ceding insurers, their assignees, and successors in interest. The trust and the assuming insurer shall be subject to examination as determined by the Superintendent. This trust shall remain in effect for as long as the assuming insurer has outstanding obligations due under the reinsurance agreements subject to the trust D) No later than February 28th of each year the trustees of the trust shall report to the Superintendent in writing setting forth the balance of the trust and listing the trusCs investments at the preceding year end, and shall certify the date of termination of the trust, if so planned, or certify that the trust shall not expire prior to the next following December 31st t Credit shall not be allowed under this paragraph unless the assuming insurer complies with the requirements of paragraph (6) of this subsection 5) Credit shall be allowed when the reinsurance is ceded to an assuming insurer not meeting the requirements of subsection (i 2 3 or (4) but only with respect to the insurance of risks located in jurisdictions where the reinsurance is required by applicable law or regulation in that jurisdiction 6) If the assuming insurer is not licensed or accredited to transact insurance or reinsurance of the District of Columbia, the credit permitted by paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection shall not be allowed unless the assuming insurer agrees in the reinsurance agreements A) That in the event of the failure of the assuming insurer to perform its obligations under the terms of the reinsurance agreement, the assuming insurer, at the request of the ceding insurer, shall submit to the jurisdiction of any court of competent jurisdiction in any state of the United States, shall comply with all requirements necessary to give the court jurisdiction, and shall abide by the final decision of such court or of any appellate court in the event of an appeal; and (B) To designate the Superintendent or a designated attorney as its true and lawful attorney upon whom may be served any lawful process in any action, suit, or proceeding instituted by or on behalf of the ceding company b) No credit shall be allowed to a domestic ceding insurer if the assuming insurer’s accreditation has been revoked by the Superintendent after notice and hearing c) This provision is not intended to conflict with or override the obligation of the parties to a reinsurance agreement to arbitrate their disputes, if such an obligation is created in the agreement. Sec. 3. l~eduction from liability for reinsurance ceded by a domestic insurer to an assuming insurer. New Section 35-3302 Enrolled Original A reduction from liability for the reinsurance ceded by a domestic insurer to an assuming insurer not meeting the requirements of section 2 shall be allowed in an amount not exceeding the liabilities carried by the ceding insurer, and such a reduction shall be in the amount of funds held by or on behalf of the ceding insurer, including funds held in trust for the ceding insurer, under a reinsurance contract with the assuming insurer as security for the payment of obligations thereunder, if the security is held in the United States subject to withdrawal solely by, and under the exclusive control of, the ceding insurer, or, in the case of a trust, held in a qualified United States financial institution. This security may be in the form of 1) Cash 2) Securities listed by the Securities Valuation Office of the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and qualifying as admitted assets 3) Irrevocable, unconditional letters of credit issued or confirmed by a qualified United States institution no later than December 31st in respect of the year for which filing is being made, and in the possession of the ceding company on or before the filing date of its annual statement. Letters of credit meeting applicable standards of insurer acceptability as of the dates of their issuance or confirmation shall, notwithstanding the issuing or confirming institution’s subsequent failure to meet applicable standards of issuers acceptability, continue to be acceptable as security until their expiration, extension, renewal, modification, or amendment, whichever occurs first; or (4) Any other investment which the Superintendent concludes is sufficiently secure and liquid to provide adequate security. Sec. 4. Qualified United States financial institutions a) For purposes of this act, the term "qualified United States financial institution" means an institution that 1) Is organized or, in the case of a United States office of a foreign banking organization, licensed under the laws of the United States or any state 2) Is regulated, supervised and examined by United States federal or state authorities having regulatory authority over banks and trust companies; and (3) Has been determined by either the Superintendent or the Securities Valuation Office of the National Association of Insurance Commissioners to meet the standards of financial condition and standing considered necessary and appropriate to regulate the quality of financial institutions issuing letters b) For the purposes of this act, the term a "qualified United States financial institution" means, for purposes of those provisions of this act specifying those institutions that are eligible to act as a fiduciary of a trust, an institution that 1) Is organized, or, in the case of a United States branch or agency office of a foreign banking organization, licensed, under the laws of the United States or any state and has been granted authority to operate with fiduciary powers; and (2) Is regulated, supervised and examined by federal or state authorities having regulatory authority over banks and trust companies. New Section 35-3303 Enrolled Original Sec. 5. l~ules. The Mayor shall, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative l~rocedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1204; D.C. Code §§ 1-1501 through 1-1510 issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. Sec. 6. l~epealer. Section 37 of chapter III of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1934 (48 Star. 1154; D.C. Code § 35-635 is repealed. Sec. 7. Applicability. Sections 2 through 5 shall apply to all cession after the effective date of this act under reinsurance agreements which have had an inception, anniversary, or renewal date not less than 6 months after the effective date of this act. See. 8. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia l~egister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal l~egulations. At1 C~ the District of Columbia APPROVED: July 29, 1993 Note, New Section 35-3301 Section 35-635 Note, New Section 35-3301 I~ Item on Consent Calendar I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: 5~ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COU2~CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: BI0-128 Adopted First Reading, 6-29-93 Approved Barry and Chavous ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCILMEMBER C~N. RA~ BARRY ’~RAzIL HAqOUS BOPP NAY N.V. A8. COUNCILMEMB£~ EVANS &amp;lt;ARVIS LIGH~FOOT’ ’ {ASON NAT~ANRON Indicates VoW A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V, A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE I NAY N,V. A.B. SMITH JR TH O~L S, SR. N.V Present, not voting Se~etary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: CERTIFICATION RECORD Adopted Final Reading, 7-13-93 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Barry and Chavous COUNCIL MEMBER ’ CHMN. HAY BARRY BRAZIL CHAV0~S ’ CRoPP [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY N.v. A,B. COUNCILMEMBER EVANS JARVI"’S LIGHTFOOT ~ON NATHhNSON’ X--’lndicatesvote ’ Absent u AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER !AYE NAY N.V.A.B. N.V Present, not voting &amp;lt CERTIFICATION RECORD Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER ’AYE NAY N.V. A:B. CHMN RAY BARRY BRAZIL .C~AVOTLq } COUNCIL’MEMBER AYE’ NAY’ N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. EVANS SMITH, JR. JARV’i S THO.Y.~S~ SR. L._IGHTFOOT MASON ATHA SO X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N’IV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-501"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-502"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-503"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-2602.06"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-4438"/>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
