<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-40">
  <num type="law">10-40</num>
  <heading type="short">Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act of 1993</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1993-10-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-40.pdf">D.C. Law 10-40</citation>
      <citation type="register">40 DCR 6009</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0093">
      <narrative>Law 10-40, the “Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act of 1993,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-93, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 29, 1993, and July 13, 1993, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 4, 1993, it was assigned Act No. 10-75 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-40 became effective on October 21, 1993.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>kwiktag ’~ 062 314 ~55 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10-40 "Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act of 1993" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-93 on first and second readings, June 29, 1993, and July 13, 1993, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on August 4, 1993, this legislation was a~signed Act No. 10-75, published in the August 20, 1993, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 40 page 6009) and transmitted to Congress on September 1, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C Law 10-40, effective October 21, 1993 Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: September 7,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,17,20,21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30 October 1,4,5,6,7,12,13,14,15,18,19,20 =nrolled Original AN ACT Codification District of Cokanbia Code D.C, ACT i0-75 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA AUGUST 4, 1993 To create in the District of Columbia Treasury a trust fund designated as the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund; to provide funding for the Insurance Administration to discharge its duties as provided in the insurance statutes, regulations, and rules of the District of Columbia; and to amend the Compulsory/No-Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982 Amendments Act of 1985. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act of 1993 See. 2. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Assessable year" means the calendar year in which the direct gross receipts are received or derived from insurance business in the District of Columbia 2 Direct gross receipts" means all policy and membership fees and net premium receipts or consideration received in a calendar year on all insurance risks and annuity contracts originating in or from the District of Columbia 3 Insurance Administration" means the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Insurance Administration, which is responsible for administering the insurance laws of the District of Columbia 4 Insurer" means any person, firm, association, or corporation duly licensed in the District of Columbia pursuant to the applicable provisions of District insurance law as an insurer. In addition, Group Hospitalization and Medical. Service, Incorporated, shall be defined as an insurer 5 Net premium receipts or consideration received" means gross premiums or consideration, received less the sum of premiums received for reinsurance assumed and premiums or consideration returned on policies or contracts cancelled or not taken 6 Superintendent" means the Superintendent of Insurance or Insurance Administration for the District of Columbia. New Section 35-2701 Sec. 3. Establishment of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund a) There is established within the general fund of the District of Columbia a trust fund designated as the Insurance Regulatory Trust New Section 35-2702 Enrolled Original Fund, to which shall be credited all funds obtained pursuant to this act without regard to fiscal year limitation. All interest earned on monies deposited in the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund shall be credited to the Fund and used solely for the purposes of this act b) Subject to the applicable laws relating to the appropriation of District funds, monies received and deposited in the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund shall be used to defray the expenses of the Insurance Administration in the discharge of its administrative and regulatory duties as prescribed by law. These monies shall be deemed to include all administrative costs for insurers doing business in the District of Columbia, and no other additional assessments shall be charged for such purpose after the effective date of this act. The Mayor shall be responsible for the deposit and expenditure of these monies as provided by law e)(1) The Mayor shall submit to the Council, as a part of the annual budget, a requested appropriation for expenditures from the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund. Any monies received but not expended in a given fiscal year shall be retained by the Fund and applied against the budget for the ensuing year, and the assessments for that year reduced accordingly 2) The Mayorts request shall be based on an estimated projection of the expenditures necessary to perform the administrative and regulatory functions of the Insurance Administration. This estimate shall include, but not be limited to, expenditures for salaries, fringe benefits, overhead charges, travel, training, supplies, technical, professional, and any and all other services necessary to discharge the duties and responsibilities of administering the insurance laws of the District of Columbia d) The Council of the District of Columbia shall approve and establish the budget of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund in the same manner and at the same level of detail as approved and established for departments and agencies under the administrative control of the Mayor as provided in section 404(f) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act of 1973, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 787; D.C. Code § 1-227(f This review shall be conducted as part of the review of the budget of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. Sec. 4. Assessments a) The Mayor shall assess each insurer doing business in the District annually an amount based on a percentage of its direct gross receipts for the preceding year, provided that each insurer shall be subject to a minimum annual assessment of $1,000. The Mayor shall establish in each assessable year the assessment rate, not to exceed 3/10 of 1% of the direct gross receipts. In no event shall the amount assessed exceed the amount budgeted by the Council b) The Mayor shall compute the assessment for each insurer and send the insurer this information in a "Notice of Assessment Each insurer shall pay to the Mayor the amount stated in the Notice of Assessment within 30 days of the mailing date of the Notice of Assessment c) The annual billing cycle for the assessment established by this section shall be the fiscal year of the District of Columbia. New Section 35-2703 Enrolled Original Sec. 5. Failure to pay share of assessment a) Any insurer that fails to pay an assessment on or before the date set forth in section 4 shall be subject to a penalty imposed by the Mayor, which shall be 10% of the assessment plus interest at one-half of 196 per month for the period between the due date and the date of full payment. If a payment is made in an amount later found to be in error, the Mayor shall do one of the following 1) If an additional amount is due, notify the insurer of the additional amount which shall be due within 15 days of the date of mailing of the notice; or (2) if over payment is made, order a refund b) If an insurer fails to pay the amount of the assessment in a timely manner, the Mayor shall send the insurer a notice of deficiency and 10 days after serving the deficiency notice may take whatever action, in the Mayor’s discretion, the Mayor deems appropriate, including suspending or revoking the insurer’s certificate of authority or license to transact business, or any other appropriate action or sanction authorized under the insurance laws for failure to comply with District laws, including referring the matter to the Corporation Counsel for legal action to collect the assessment c) In the event that any insurer fails, by reason of insolvency, impairment of capital and surplus, or other reason approved by the Mayor, to pay its assessment in full, the unpaid amounts shall be assessed against the remaining insurers on a proportionate basis in comparison to their direct gross receipts. Any insurer paying this additional assessment shall have a claim against the defaulting insurer for the amount paid. See. 6. Appeal from assessment. Any insurer aggrieved by an assessment may appeal under procedures established in section 101 of Title 26 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (26 DCMR 101 or as otherwise may be provided by the Mayor. If an appellant fails to pay the assessment when due, the appellant shall be liable for any amounts correctly assessed and any penalties and interest due thereon. The appellant shall pay any amounts owed within 10 days of a final decision and the Mayor may take whatever action is appropriate under this act, including action under section 5, or any other laws regulating the insurance industry to effect collection. In addition, the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Bureau may appeal to the Mayor the entire annual assessment or a specific expenditure or category of expenditure, in accordance with the procedures established in 26 DCMR 101, if it believes the assessment is not in accordance with this act or applicable laws. See. 7. Insurers continuing obligations. Any insurer whose license has been revoked, cancelled, terminated, or surrendered shall continue to be bound by the obligations of this act, including payment of all assessments, regardless of whether the insurer continues to do business in the District of Columbia. Sec. 8. Records. The Mayor shall, at all reasonable times, make books, records, and files available to insurance company representatives for the purpose of New Section 35-2704 New Section 35-2705 New Section 35-2706 New Section 35-2707 Enrolled Original examining any matter coming within the scope of the act and the insurance laws of the District of Columbia. Sec. 9. Establishment of Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Bureau. All insurers subject to assessments in accordance with this act shall be members of an Insurance Regulatory Trust Bureau, organized and maintained by such insurers at their own expense, for the purpose of advising the Superintendent of Insurance annually as to the need for the proposed assessments, the fairness of the proposed assessments, and any other matters with respect to the administration of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund. The Superintendent shall submit to the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Bureau annually, in advance of the Mayor’s budget submission to the Council, a detailed budget showing how the proposed assessments are to be expended. Sec. 10. Annual audit of Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund. Upon a vote of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Bureau taken in accordance with its bylaws, the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Bureau, at its own expense, may annually arrange for an independent audit of the expenditures made in any fiscal year by the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund. The Superintendent, the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, and all other elements of the Government of the District of Columbia shall cooperate with such an audit and shall make available all documents and records reasonably necessary to the conduct of the audit. Sec. 11. Applicability a) All life, health, property, marine, title, casualty, fidelity, surety, insurance companies and fraternal benefit associations now or hereafter incorporated or formed in the District of Columbia or authorized to do business in the District of Columbia, shall be subject to this act. This act shall also apply to Group Hospitalization and Medical Service, Incorporated, and any other company or organization whether for profit or nonprofit subject to regulation by the Insurance Administration b) The provisions of this act shall not apply until October 1, 1993. Sec. 12. Rules. The Mayor may, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1204; D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. Sec. 13. Repealers a) Section 9 of the Compulsory/No-Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982, effective September 18, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-155; D.C. Code § 35-2108 is hereby repealed b) An Act To Provide for regulation of certain insurance rates in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved June 1, 1944 (58 Star. 267; D.C. Code §§ 35-1601 through 35-1609 providing for the regulation of fire insurance rates is repealed. New Section 35-2708 New Section 35-2709 New Section 35-2710 Note, New Section 35-2701 Section 35-2108 Sections 35u1601 through 35-1609 Enrolled Original See. 14. Conforming amendment. Section 2 of An Act To provide for regulation of certain insurance rates in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved May 20, 1948 (62 Stat. 242; D.C. Code § 35-1702 is amended by adding the phrase "fire after the phrase all forms of" and striking the phrase except those forms of insurance not enumerated herein which are within the scope of Chapter 16 of this title Sec. 15. Effective ~date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c~1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Regis_fle the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of~[umbia Municipal Actinx’ i~’n~an Cou ’~he District of Columbia Section 35-1702 District of Columbia August 4, 1993 5 COI~NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL~btBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO Bill .I0-93 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Adopted First Reading, 6-29-93 Approved Barry and Chavous ROLL CALL VOTE RESU COL,tNCILMEMBER ~E NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCILMEMBER ,AYE NAY ~MN. RAx EVANS ’ ~ARRY JARVIS RAZIL LiGHTFO0T’ I M~SON ’r CHAqOUS kCROPP X Indicates V~e F-I item~on Co:s~:i~tahre Council ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Record~ vote on r~uest Absent N.V LB. COUNC|LMEMBER AYE INA¥ N.V LB. SMITH, JR. ’ THO m_S, SR. I~ATNANRON A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Adopted Final Reading, 7-13-93 Approved Barry and Chavous [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. BARRY BRAZIL ~HAVOUS CROPP ’ ’ ’ ,I X Inclicates Vote S~p-Jretary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar ’-COUNCILMEMBER’ AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCILMEMBER AYE NAY N.Q.’ A.B. EVANS JARVIS LIGH~FoOT msoN NATHANSON N.V Present, not votir!g CERTIFICATION RECORD SMIdT JR. THOM~AS. SR I O~e A.B Absent ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE Recorded vote on request Absent 1~ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN..KAY ’BARRY BRAZIL I .C~AVOI]R X I .ndicates Vote c~p. EVANS COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY r N.V A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V LB SMITH JR. JARVI S THONGS. SR. LiGHTF00T MASON N~ATHANSONI A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-1201"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-1202"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-1203"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-1204"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-1205"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-1206"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-1207"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-1208"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-1209"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-1210"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>13</num>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-2408"/>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
