<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-57">
  <num type="law">10-57</num>
  <heading type="short">CHILDREN'S ISLAND DEVELOPMENT PLAN ACT OF 1993</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1993-11-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-57.pdf">D.C. Law 10-57</citation>
      <citation type="register">40 DCR 7227</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0331"/>
    <search-text>ENRO LMENT(S) kwiktag 103 222 295 Enrolled Original AN ACT Codification District of Cotumbia Code 1994 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establish, on an emergency basis, a fund to compensate persons who sustained real or personal property damage as a direct result of the breaks in the water main in the 1600 block through the 2500 block of Minnesota Avenue, S.E Washington, D.C on March 7, 1991, January 14, 1993, and January 25, 1993. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Water Main Break Fund Establishment Emergency Act of 1993 See. 2. Minnesota Avenue, S.E Water Main Break Fund established. There is established, within the Water and Sewer Enterprise Fund established by the Mayor pursuant to section 7(h) of the District of Columbia Fund Accounting Act of 1980, effective June 14, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-70; D.C. Code §47-375(g the Minnesota Avenue, S.E Water Main Break Fund Fund to compensate persons who sustained real or personal property damage as a direct result of the breaks in the water main located in the 1600 block through the 2500 block of Minnesota Avenue, S.E Washington, D.C on March 7, 1991, January 14, 1993, and January 25, 1993 water main breaks See. 3. Eligibility. To be eligible for compensation for damages from the fund, each person shall 1) Demonstrate, in accordance with criteria established by the Mayor, that the damage to the real or personal property for which the person requests compensation was the direct result of the water main breaks 2) Certify that the claim for compensation made pursuant to this act is the only claim pursued by the person against the District of Columbia District government for damages sustained as a result of the water main breaks 3) Certify that the claim for compensation made pursuant to this act is the only claim that the person will pursue against the District government for damages sustained as the result of the water main breaks; and (4) File a claim for damages pursuant to this act within 6 months of the effective date of this act. No te, Section 47-375 Enrolled Original See. 4. Compensation. Compensation for damages provided from this fund shall be not more than $10,000 for each household. I~or the purposes of this section, the term "household" means all persons who resided at a single address within a 6 block radius of the 1600 block through the 2500 block of Minnesota Avenue, S.E Washington, D.C. on March 7, 1991, January 14, 1993, and January 25, 1993. See. 5. Reports a) The Department of Public Works shall provide an annual report to the Council on the anniversary of the effective date of this act and on January 1st each subsequent year thereafter, which describes the condition of the entire water main system of the District. The report shall include the following information for each water main 1) The number of the water main as indicated on the water main map established pursuant to subsection (b) of this section 2) The age of the water main 3) The material of which the water main is constructed 4) The expected remaining life of the water main; and (5) If the water main has sustained any amount of damage within the last 20 years, then state A) The date or dates of the damage B) The type of damage sustained C) Whether the damage was repaired; and (D) If the water main was repaired, state the date the repair was made, the type of repair that was made, and the person or entity making the repair. If the water main was not repaired, state the reason or reasons the repair was not made and indicate a scheduled date for repair b) The Department of Public Works shall provide the Council with a water main map that illustrates the entire water main system of the District. Each water main shall be labeled, on the map, with consecutive numbers so that each water main can be identified when the map is used in conjunction with the report required pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. The water main map shall be submitted by the Department of Public Works, to the Council on the anniversary of this act, and on January 1st of each year when the map is updated. The water main map shall be updated each time a water main is added or is taken out of service. See. 6. Repairs. In the event that water main breaks occur in a concentrated area suggesting that there is weakness throughout that section of the infrastructure, the Department of Public Works shall repair the affected infrastructure in a timely fashion. Sec. 7. Effective date. This act shall take effect upon its enactment (approval by the Mayor, or in the event of veto by the Mayor, override of the veto by the Council) and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and 2 Enrolled Original Governmental tteorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 788; D.C. Code § 1-229(a cA~ D~str~et of Columbia VETOED Mayor District of Columbia AUGUST 4 [993 3 COENCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLLqMBIA ~COUNCIL PERIOD TEN RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: B 10- 347 [] Item on Consent Calendar F2 ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: r~ VOICE VOTE: Adopted Final Reading, 7-13-93 Approved Recordedvoteonr~uest Absent: Barry, Chavous and Thomas CHMIN. RAY ’ [BRAZIL ’.~HAVDUS, CROPP [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT ICOL%NCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B, COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N,V. A.B. EVANS, I J.ARVIS LIGHTFOOT £ASON NATHANSON X Indicates Vote A.B Absent NIV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD [3 Item ]- gecre {0 ~h~ Council on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER SMITHr, JR. THOS~S, SR. AYE NAY NV. [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V, A.B. CHMN. ’FAY BARRY BRAZIL :CHAVOUS CROPP ’ X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMB~R AYE NAY N.V.A.B. EVANS JARVIS LIGHT~6OT msoN NATHANSON A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER £HOMAS, SR. AYE A.B. A.B. Secretary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [3 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V, A.B. CHMN RAY BRAZIL CHAVOI]S c~OP.P x Indicates’ vote COUNCIL MEMBER EVANS LIGHTFOO~ MASON A.B Absent AYE ’NAY N.v. lAB. N.V Present. not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J J COUNCIL MEMBER i AYE NAY SMITH JR. THOZJ%S~ SR A.B. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1431"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1432"/>
  </section>
</document>
