<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-75" flag="true">
  <num type="law">10-75</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-75.pdf">D.C. Law 10-75</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 249 890 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 NOV ,0 3 1993 The Honorable Sharon Pratt Kelly Mayor of the District of Columbia 441 4th Street, N.W llth Floor Washington, D.C. 20001 Re: Transmittal of Bill 10-417 South Africa Sanctions Temporary Repeal Act of 1993 Date of Council Action: 11-2-93 Dear Mayor Kelly: The above named temporary enacted bill is hereby transmitted in accordance with Section 404(e) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 in.cerel~$iI C2~airman of the Council Enclosure Enrolled ungmm AN ACT Codification of Columbia Code Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To repeal, on a temporary basis, the sanctions imposed on the Republic of South Africa by the Prohibition of the Investment of Public Funds in Financial Institutions and Companies Making Loans to or Doing Business with the Republic of South Africa or Namibia Act of 1983 and the South Africa and Namibia Contracting Sanction Amendment Act of 1986. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "South Africa Sanctions Temporary Repeal Act of 1993 See. 2. Section 3(c) of the District of Columbia Depository Act of 1977, effective October 26, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-32; D.C. Code § 47-342(c is repealed. Section: 47-342 Sec. 3. Section 141(a)(5) of the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Star. 866; D.C. Code § 1-721(a)(5 is repealed. See, 4. The District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Act, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-135; D.C. Code § 45-2101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 406 (D.C. Code § 45-2136) is amended by striking the phrase "and in accordance with section 412 b) Section 412 (D.C. Code § 45-2142) is repealed. Sec. 5. Sections 5, 6, 7, and 8 of the Prohibition of the Investment of Public Funds in Financial Institutions and Companies Making Loans to or Doing Business with the Republic of South Africa or Namibia Act of 1983, effective March 8, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-50; D.C. Code §§ 47-139 through 47-142 are repealed. Section 45-2136 Section 45-2142 Sections 47-139 thru 47-142 Sec. 6. The District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Code § 1-1181.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 107(2 D.C. Code § 1-1181.7(2 is amended by striking after the word "means" the phrase for purposes other than those set forth in title Xa b) Title Xa (D.C. Code § 1-1192.1 et seq is repealed. Section 1-1181.7 Sections i-i192.1 thru 1-1192.6 Enrolled Original Sec. 7. Section 3(e) of the Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Act of 1993, signed by the Mayor on October 1, 1993 (D.C. Act 10-109; 40 DCR is repealed. Sec. 8. Effective date a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect or upon the effective date of the South Africa Sanctions Repeal Act of 1993, whichever occurs first Chairm~ff Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Bill 10-417 Adopted First Reading, 10-5-93 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE t NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE CHMN. CLARKE I EVANS BARRY 1 JA~VIS .BRAZIL I. IGHTFnnT CHAVOUS MASON CROPP NATHANSON X Indicates Vote A.B Absent SecretaL,r,q/to tt’l~ Council ]~ Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request CERTIFICATION RECORD NAY NV. AB. COUNCIL MEMBER RAY ,’I SMITH~ JR. THOMAS: SR. N.V Present, not votin9 Date Adopted Final Approved Reading, 11-2-93 IAYE NAY Absent: Barry and Mason ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. CLARKE EVAN£ ¯ BARRY JARV BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CHAVOUS MASON CROPP NATHANSON COUNCIL MEMBER RA~ SMITH~ JR. THOMAS AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secr~ary to the Counci [] Item on Consent Calendar Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: C VOICE VOTE Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLLCALLVOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B ’CHMN. CLARKE "’BiRRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP X Indicates Vote COUNCILMEMBER EVANS JARVIS LI.GHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A.8 Absent AYE [ NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ’ COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. RAY .SMITH‘ JR. THOMAS, SR. Secreta~ to the Council Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW I0-75 "South Africa Sanctions Temporary Repeal Act of 1993 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. I0-417 on first and second readings, October 5, 1993, and November 2, 1993, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 4, 1993, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. I0-142, published in the November 19, 1993, edition of the D.C Re.~i.ster Vol. 40 page 8072) and transmitted to Congress on November 15, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D,C, Law 10-75, effective March 8~ 1994 Chai~an of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: November January February March 15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,26 25,26 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,22,23,24,25,28 1,2,3,4,7, Enrolled Original AN ACT D,C, ACT i0-142 Codification D,istrl= of ColUmbia Code 99,,3 SupPlement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 4, 1993 To repeal, on a temporary basis, the sanctions imposed on the l%epublic of South Africa by the Prohibition of the Investment of Public Funds in Financial Institutions and Companies Making Loans to or Doing Business with the Republic of South Africa or Namibia Act of 1983 and the South Africa and Namibia Contracting Sanction Amendment Act of 1986. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "South Africa Sanctions Temporary Repeal Act of 1993 Sec. 2. Section 3(c) of the District of Columbia Depository Act of 1977, effective October 26, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-32; D.C. Code § 47-342(c is repealed. Section 47-342 See. 3. Section 141(a)(5) of the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Star. 866; D.C. Code § 1-721(a)(5 is repealed. 1-721 Sec. 4. The District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Act, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-135; D.C. Code § 45-2101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 406 (D.C. Code § 45-2136) is amended by striking the phrase "and in accordance with section 412 b) Section 412 (D.C. Code § 45-2142) is repealed. Sec. 5. Sections 5, 6, 7, and 8 of the Prohibition of the Investment of Public Funds in Financial Institutions and Companies Making Loans to or Doing Business with the Republic of South Africa or Namibia Act of 1983, effective March 8, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-50; D.C. Code §§ 47-139 through 47-142 are repealed. Section 45-2136 Section 45-2142 Sections 47-139 thru 47-142 Sec. 6. The District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Code § 1-1181.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 107(2 D.C. Code § 1-1181.7(2 is amended by striking after the word "means" the phrase for purposes other than those set forth in title Xa b) Title Xa (D.C. Code § 1-1192.1 et seq is repealed. Section 1-1181.7 Sections i-i192.1 thru 1-1192.6 Enrolled Original Sec. 7. Section 3(e) of the Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children’s Trust Fund Act of 1993, signed by the Mayor on October 1, 1993 (D.C. Act 10-109; 40 DCR is repealed. Sec. 8. Effective date a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect or upon the effective date of the South Africa Sanctions Repeal Act of 1993, whichever occurs first Chairm~ Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED November 4, 1993 2 COETNCIL OF DIS~I~IC~ OF Council Period RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted First Reading, 10-5-93 Bill 10-417 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER A.B. CHMN CLARKE ~LBARRY~RAZlI, CHAVOUS CROPP F COUNCIL MEMBER} AYE NAY N.V. A.B. } COUNCIL MEMBER EVANS ’ RAY ,]ARVIS ’SMITH JR. ITGNTFOOT THOMAS SR. IMASON IN~THANSON I, A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting AYE I NAY ~4 Indicates Vote CERTIFICATION RECORO 1 Secret to Counc, tAYE i Item on ConsentCalendar ~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICEVOTE: Recordedvoteonrequest [’ D~te Adopted Final Reading, 11-2-93 Approved NAY N.V. Absent: Barry and Mason ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. CLARKE EVANS BARRY 4ARViS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT C.HAVOUS MASON CROPP NATHANSON AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE RAY_ SM_ITH~ Jl~’. THOMAS. SR. NAY N,V. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORO Orb i I Secr~,ary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLLCALLVOTE RESULT COUNCILMEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A,B. COUNCILMEMBER -CHMN. CLARKE ’ EvAN~ BARRY JARVIS BRAZIL LI.GHTFOOT, CHAVOUS ~ASON CROPP NATHANSON X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.Y. RA"Y SMITH, JR. THOMAS~ SR. A.B. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
