<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-70" flag="true">
  <num type="law">10-70</num>
  <heading type="short">METROPOLITAN POLICE HOUSING ASSISTANCE PROGRAM AND COMMUNITY SAFETY ACT OF 1993</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-02-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-70.pdf">D.C. Law 10-70</citation>
      <citation type="register">40 DCR 7575</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0325"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 222 185 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 10- 70 "Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program and Community Safety Act of 1993 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-325 on first and second readings, September 21, 1993, and October 5, 1993, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 25, 1993, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-124, published in the November 5, 1993, edition of the D.C. Re qister Vol. 40 page 7575) and transmitted to Congress on October 29, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-70, effective February 23 1994 7 DAVID A. CLARKE Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Con gressional Review Period: October 29 November 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,26 January 25,26 February 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,22 AN ACT D.C, ACT i0-124 ro!!sd Original Godif[ca6orl 13istrict of Columbkz Oode 1994 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 25, 1993 New Chapter 22B, Title 45 To establish a Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program; to amend the District of Columbia Government Employer-Assisted Housing Program Act of 1992 to provide home buying and rental assistance to Metropolitan police officers as incentives for residing in the District of Columbia; and to allow Metropolitan police officers, who live in the District, to keep patrol vehicles in their possession during off-duty hours. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL O1~ THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program and Community Safety Act of 1993" See. 2. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term: New, Section (1 Department" means the Distriot of Columbia Department 45-2231 of Public and Assisted ttousing Development 2 First-time homebuyer" means a purchaser who has no ownership interest in a principal residence at any time during the 3 year period ending on the date of the application for assistance, but includes an applicant who has divorced or separated during the 3 year period where a formal settlement did not convey an ownership interest in a principal residence which had been jointly owned 3 Housing unit" means any room or group of rooms forming a single-family residential unit, including a semi-detached condominium, cooperative, or semi-detached or detached home that is intended to be used or used for living, sleeping, and the preparation and eating of meals by human occupants 4 Police officer" means officers of all ranks employed by the District of Columbia Metropolitan Police Department. See. 3. l~ental assistance. New, Section (a) The Department shall offer public housing units at a discounted 45-2232 rental rate to Metropolitan police officers. In assigning public housing units, the Department shall establish a priority for Metropolitan police officers who already reside in the District b) Notwithstanding any other provision of District of Columbia law or regulation, Metropolitan police officers who reside in the District of Columbia may receive discounted rent from private or public housing providers. Enrolled Original (c) All Metropolitan police officers who receive a discounted rent from a private or public housing provider shall notify the Chief of Police of the terms of the discount, and provide a copy of any lease or written agreement detailing the terms of the housing arrangement d) Any discounted rent received by a Metropolitan police officer shall not be considered income for purposes of District of Columbia income tax. See. 4. Community police presence. New, Section All Metropolitan police officers who reside in the District of Columbia 45-2233 shall be eligible to keep in their possession at all times, overnight and off-duty, the official vehicles assigned for patrol purposes. In assigning police vehicles to be taken by police officers while off-duty, the Chief of Police shall establish priorities based on District residency, dispersion by geographic locations, and other factors the Chief of Police may deem appropriate. Note See. 5. t~ules. New, Section (a) The Mayor shall, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia 45-2231 Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1204; D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq issue rules within 90 days after the effective date of this act to implement the provisions of this act b) The rules shall include, but not be limited to the following 1) An application procedure for the Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program; and (2) A standard of eligibility and selection of Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program applicants. The Mayor may establish priorities for eligibility based on length of residency in the District, geographic location, or other means as deemed appropriate. See. 6. Report on cost of tax exemption for police substations. Six months from the effective date of this act, the Department of Finance and Revenue shall submit a report to the Council on the fiscal impact of providing a real property tax exemption to that portion of the real property belonging to any individual, partnership, or corporation that is provided rent free to the District for use solely by the Metropolitan Police Department as a police substation. The exemption shall be applicable only while the property is used as an active police substation. Note New, Section 45-2231 See. 7. Report on fiscal impact. At the end of 1 year from the issuance of regulations to implement this act, similar incentives for teachers and firefighters shall be considered, and the Department of Finance and Revenue shall submit a report to the Council on the fiscal impact of these incentives. Note, New Section 45-2231 See. 8. Home purchase assistance. The District of Columbia Government Employer-Assisted Housing Act of 1992, effective June 11, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-118; D.C. Code § 45-2221 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 45-2222) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the word "and Section 45-2222 Enrolled Original (2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase and" in its place 3) A new paragraph (4) is added to read as follows 4) Property tax and income tax credits for Metropolitan police officers b) A new section 6a is added to read as follows Sec. 6a. Assistance available for Metropolitan police officers. New, Section a) In addition to the assistance provided in section 6 of this act 45-2226 and section 304(a-1) of the Housing Finance Agency Ac of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-135; D.C. Code § 45-2124(a-1 Metropolitan police officers who are first-time homebuyers in the District of Columbia shall be eligible for the following assistance 1) A sliding-scale property tax credit as follows A) An 80% property tax credit for the first year B) A 60% property tax credit for the second year C) A 40% property tax credit for the third year D) A 20% property tax credit for the fourth year; and E) A 20% property tax credit for the fifth year 2) A $2,000 income tax credit in the tax year the officer purchases his home and each of the 4 immediately succeeding tax years, provided the officer remains eligible for the tax credit. The credit shall not be prorated and any portion of the credit that is not utilized in a tax year shall not be carried forward, carried back, or refunded to the officer b) Any real property owner eligible to receive a real property tax credit under this section shall receive the tax credit as of the next half of the real property tax year following the date the real property owner applied for the credit. The real property owner shall continue to receive the real property tax credit for each succeeding 9 halves of the real property tax year, provided the real property owner remains eligible to receive the tax credit c) A new section 6b is added to read as follows Sec. 6b. Rules a) The Mayor shall, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Note SectionAdministrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; 45-2221D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq issue rules within 90 days after the effective date of the Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program and Community Safety Act of 1993 to implement the home purchase assistance and tax credit provisions of the act b) The rules shall include, but not be limited to the following 1) An application procedure for the Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance Program; and 2) A standard of eligibility and selection of Metropolitan Police Housing Assistance ]Program applicants. The Mayor may establish priorities for eligibility based on length of residency in the District, geographic location, or other means as deemed appropriate See. 9. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved 3 Enrolled Original December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia ~lunicipal l~.egulation. Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED October 25, 1993 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Ten RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Approved Bill 10-325 First Reading, 9-21-93 VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Barry and Evans [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNC}L MEMBER CHM_N RA_Y BARRY RAZIL ~HA~OUS ROPP AYE NAY N.V. AB. X Indicates Vote COUNCILMEMBER EVANS JARVIS ’LiGHTFO0 MASON NATHANSON A.B Absent AYE NAY N.Y. A:B COUNCIL MEMBER secretly to the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: NV Present. not voting. Date AYE NAY N.V. VOICE VOTE: CERTIFICATION RECORD Recorded vote on request Absent: Adopted Final Reading, 10-5-93 Approved all present i ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL CHAVOUS CROPP 1 J A.8. I COUNCIL MEMBER EVANS RVIS LIGH!FQOT MASON i N&amp;amp;THA~SON X Indicates Vote A.B Absent A¥’E NAY N.V.A.B, N.V Present, not voting J J I COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. RAY IITH, JR. CERTIFICATION RECORD Sec%t~ry t~ the Council Item on Consent Calendar THOMAS SR: Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: E] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A,B. CHMN. CLARKE BARRY BRAZIL LCHAVOUS CROPP X Indicates Vote L cOUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAYCOUNCIL MEMBER EVANS J.ARV!S L GHTFOOT M_ASON NATHANSON A.B Absent AYE NAY N.Y. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD R~Y SMITH, JR. TH.OMAS SR. Secretary to the Council Date OF THE WHOLE I~IEPOgL PUBLICATION DOCUMENT N ’ INTRODUCED BY: REFERRAL COMMENTS FROM: DATE No. of Days ABBREVIATED 7 NOTICE REQUIREMENT HAS BEEN MET PUBLIC H.EARINGS &amp;amp; PUBLIC ROUNDTABLES ITEMS MISSING FROM THE RECORD: I. 2. 4. 5 ECORD COMPLETE COMMITTEE MEETING RECORD ~EGULAR COIV~ITTEE MTG 7"APPITIONAL CO~ITTEE MTG SPEC~kL COMMITTEE MTG, ITEMS :MISSING EROS{ THE RECORD: I. 2. 3. 4. 5 RECORD COMPLETE LEG ISLATIVE RECORD ITEMS MISSING FROM THE RECORD (Including Ex~_e.u.tiv~ Comme,n,t I. 2. 3. 4 RECORD COMPLETE COMMENTS /r--TWITH CONDITIONS ~’~WITHOUT CONDITIONS AGENDIZED DaCe. of Le.g,Z~la,tive. Me.P ing Date of LPpgi~lat, Lve, Me.e.,cing</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2901"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2902"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2903"/>
  </section>
</document>
