<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 10-98">
  <num type="law">10-98</num>
  <heading type="short">BOARD OF REAL PROPERTY ASSESSMENTS AND APPEALS AMENDMENT ACT OF 1994</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1994-03-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/10-98.pdf">D.C. Law 10-98</citation>
      <citation type="register">41 DCR 531</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B10-0475"/>
    <search-text>E L MENT(S) kwikta~ ¯ 062 313 596 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.Co LAW 10-98 "Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals Amendment Act of 1994 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 10-475 on first and second readings, December 7, 1993, and January 4, 1994, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on January 25, 1994, this legislation was assigned Act No. 10-182, published in the February 4, 1994, edition of the D.C. Re. gister Vol. 41 page 531) and transmitted to Congress on January 31, 1994 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 10-98, effective March 23, 1994. Dates Counted During the 30-day. Congressional Review_period: February 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,22,23,24,25,28 March 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22 AN ACT D.C. ACT 10-182 Enrolled Original Codification. District of Columbia Code 1994 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JANUARY 25, 1994 To amend the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974 to require that 6 members of the Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals be active members of the District of Columbia Bar with real estate experience and that 6 members be District of Columbia real estate appraisers. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Board of l~eal Property Assessments and Appeals Amendment Act of 1994 See. 2. Section 426a(a) of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, effective March 17, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-241; D.C. Code § 47-825.1(a is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended as follows 1) Subparagraph (A) is amended to read as follows A) The Board shall comprise 18 members, all of whom shall be residents of the District of Columbia District Subject to the requirements of subparagraph (E) of this paragraph, 6 Board members shall be active members of the District of Columbia Bar with real estate experience, 4 Board members shall be District certified general real estate appraisers, and 2 Board members shall be District licensed residential real estate appraisers. The remaining 6 Board members shall be certified public accountants, mortgage bankers, licensed District real estate brokers, or persons possessing significant real property experience 2) Subparagraph (B) is amended to read as follows B) The Mayor shall appoint the members of the Board with the advice and consent of the Council. From time to time, the Mayor shall appoint, with the advice and consent of the Council, the chairperson of the Board from among the members meeting the qualifications of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph. The member shall serve as chairperson for a term of 2 years or until the end of the member’s term, whichever occurs first 3) New subparagraph (E) is added to read as follows E) Beginning on the effective date of the Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals Amendment Act of 1993 and until the Board’s composition meets the requirements of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the Mayor shall nominate only individuals who meet all the qualifications of subparagraphs (A) through (D) of this paragraph and Section 47-825.1 Enrolled Original who are either active members of the District of Columbia Bar with real estate experience or District certified general or licensed residential real estate appraisers. The Mayor shall nominate alternatively from the two classes of Board members stated in this subparagraph until the Board’s composition meets the requirements of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph b) Paragraph (2) is amended by designating the first two sentences as subparagraph (A designating the last sentence as subparagraph (C) and inserting a new subparagraph (B) to read as follows B) A Board member shall be prohibited from reviewing an appeal involving real property with which the Board member has had any financial dealings in the 2-year period prior to the date of the appeal. For the purposes of this subsection financial dealings" shall include, but not be limited to, the assessment, appraisal, purchase, sale, or rental of the real property in question Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c}(1} and publication in the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia M~y’or" v District of Columbia APPROVED January 25, 1994 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period I0 RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill 10-475 Adopted First Reading, 12 93 Approved Recorded vote on. request Absent: Chavous, Smith and Nathanson [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEM~ COUNCIL MEMBER X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, nol votin..q CERTIFICATION RECORD Adopted Final ~Council [] Item on C~onsent Calendar Approved ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE Reading, i-4-9 Recorded vote on request Absent: Evans [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N,V. A.B. ’CHMN. CLARKE EYAN BARRY ’. JARViS BRAZIL K.IGHTFOOT CHAVOUS MASON CROPP NATHANSON X Indic~es Vg A.8 Absent COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N:V. CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretat~#’~he Co until [] Item on Consent Calendar A.8. ’1 COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.v. ’ A.B. ’~ RAY-’ SMIT_H, JR. THOMAS. SR J r N,V Present, not voting [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN..CLAR.KE BA.RRY .BRAZIL L,,CHAVOUS CROPP AYE NAY N.V. A.B. X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER EVANS JARVI~ LIGHTFOOT MASQ~ NATHANSON A.B A~ent AYE NAY N.V, A.B, N.V Present. not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J A__J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. RAY ¯ MITH’ JR. THOMA.S, SR. A.B. Secreta~/to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
