<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-135">
  <num type="law">17-135</num>
  <heading type="short">Operation Enduring Freedom and Operation Iraqi Freedom Active Duty Pay Differential Amendment Act of 2008</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2008-03-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-135.pdf">D.C. Law 17-135</citation>
      <citation type="register">55 DCR 1683</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0121">
      <narrative>Law 17-135, the “Operation Enduring Freedom and Operation Iraqi Freedom Active Duty Pay Differential Amendment Act of 2008”, which was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-121 which was referred to the Committee on Workforce Development and Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 11, 2007, and January 8, 2008. Signed by the Mayor on February 5, 2008, it was assigned Act No. 17-286 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-135 became effective on March 26, 2008.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to allow District of Columbia government employees who serve in the reserve units of the United States Armed Forces and who have been called to active duty as a result of Operation Enduring Freedom, or in preparation for or as a result of Operation Iraqi Freedom, to receive a pay differential. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Operation Enduring Freedom and Operation Iraqi Freedom Active Duty Pay Differential Amendment Act of 2008”. Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-601.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 1103(a D.C. Official Code § 1-611.03(a is amended by adding a new paragraph (7) to read as follows: “(7)(A) Any full-time permanent, indefinite, or term District government employee who serves in a reserve component of the United States Armed Forces and who has been or will be called to active duty as a result of Operation Enduring Freedom, or in preparation for or as a result of Operation Iraqi Freedom, shall receive, upon application and approval, an amount that equals the difference in compensation between the employee’s District government basic pay reduced by the employee’s basic military pay. This amount shall not be considered as basic pay for any purpose and shall be paid for any period following the formal inception of Operation Enduring Freedom in 2001, any period following the beginning of the preparation for Operation Iraqi Freedom in 2002 and 2003, or for any period following the formal inception of Operation Iraqi Freedom in 2003, during which the employee is carried in a non-pay status from the time the employee is called into active duty, until the employee is released from active duty occasioned by any of these military conflicts. “(B) The Mayor shall issue rules within 30 days of the effective date of the Operation Enduring Freedom and Operation Iraqi Freedom Active Duty Pay Differential Amendment Act of 2008, passed on 2nd reading on January 8, 2008 (Enrolled version of Bill 17- Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2008 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 1-611.03 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 121 to implement the provisions of this paragraph.” b) Section 1111(d D.C. Official Code § 1-611.11(d is amended by striking the phrase “and (6)” and inserting the phrase “and (7)” in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia Amend § 1-611.11</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
