<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-306">
  <num type="law">17-306</num>
  <heading type="short">Pharmacy Practice Amendment Act of 2008</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2009-03-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-306.pdf">D.C. Law 17-306</citation>
      <citation type="register">56 DCR 23</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0787">
      <narrative>Law 17-306, the “Pharmacy Practice Amendment Act of 2008”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-787 which was referred to the Committee of Health. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 18, 2008, and December 2, 2008, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 16, 2008, it was assigned Act No. 17-606 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-306 became effective on March 20, 2009.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 to permit pharmacists licensed in the District of Columbia to administer immunizations and vaccinations when certified by the Board of Pharmacy to do so, to amend the definition of the practice of pharmacy, to amend the definition of prescription to include approved electronic forms, and to allow pharmacists certified to administer vaccinations and immunizations to administer emergency anaphylactic treatment pursuant to an approved protocol. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Pharmacy Practice Amendment Act of 2008”. Sec. 2. The Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 102(11 D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.02(11) is amended as follows 1) Subparagraph (A) is amended to read as follows: “(A) “Practice of pharmacy” means the interpretation and evaluation of prescription orders; the compounding, dispensing, and labeling of drugs and devices; drug and device selection; responsibility for advising and providing information, where regulated or otherwise necessary, concerning drugs and devices and their therapeutic values, content, hazards, and uses in the treatment and prevention of disease; responsibility for conducting drug- regimen reviews; responsibility for the proper and safe storage and distribution of drugs and devices; the administration of immunizations and vaccinations upon receipt of a written physician protocol and a valid prescription or standing order of a physician when certified by the Board of Pharmacy to do so; conducting health screenings, including obtaining finger-stick blood samples; the offering or performance of those acts, services, operations, and transactions necessary in the conduct, operation, management, and control of a pharmacy; and the maintenance of proper records therefor.” 2) Subparagraph (B)(ii) is amended by striking the phrase “in writing, dated” and inserting the phrase “in writing, or on an approved electronic form, dated” in its place. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2009 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 3-1201.02 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 b) Section 208 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1202.08) is amended by adding new subsections (f) and (g) to read as follows: “(f) An individual licensed to practice pharmacy pursuant to this act may administer immunizations and vaccinations only if certified to do so by the Board and only pursuant to a written protocol and valid prescription or standing order of a physician. “(g) The Board and the Board of Medicine shall jointly develop and promulgate regulations to implement and regulate the administration of vaccinations and immunizations by pharmacists and to authorize pharmacists certified to administer vaccinations and immunizations to administer emergency anaphylactic reaction treatment pursuant to an approved physician-pharmacist protocol.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D. C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia Amend § 3-1202.08</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
