<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-324">
  <num type="law">17-324</num>
  <heading type="short">Targeted Ward 4 Single Sales Moratorium and Neighborhood Grocery Retailer Act of 2008</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2009-03-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-324.pdf">D.C. Law 17-324</citation>
      <citation type="register">56 DCR 239</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0941">
      <narrative>Law 17-324, the “Targeted Ward 4 Single Sales Moratorium and Neighborhood Grocery Retailer Act of 2008”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-941 which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and the Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 18, 2008, and December 2, 2008, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 22, 2008, it was assigned Act No. 17-629 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-324 became effective on March 21, 2009.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 3 of Title 25 of the District of Columbia Official Code to prohibit the sales of single containers of beer, malt liquor, or ale by off-premises retailers located in a targeted area of Ward 4, to exempt a new, full service grocery store or substantially renovated full service grocery store in ANC 4C07 from the current moratorium on applying for a Class B alcoholic beverage retailer’s license, and to exempt an existing full service grocery store in ANC 3/4G from the current restriction on applying for a Class B alcoholic beverage retailer’s license. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Targeted Ward 4 Single Sales Moratorium and Neighborhood Grocery Retailer Act of 2008”. Sec. 2. Chapter 3 of Title 25 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by adding 2 new section designations to read as follows: “25-340.01. Special restrictions for Ward 4. “25-341.01. Targeted Ward 4 Moratorium Zone.” b) Section 25-336 is amended by adding a new paragraph (e) to read as follows: “(e)(1) For the purposes of this subsection, the term “ANC 3/4G” means the single member district area partly in Ward 3 and partly in Ward 4, established under § 1-309.03. “(2) Notwithstanding the restriction in subsection (a) of this section, a full service grocery store in a residential-use district in ANC 3/4G with a certificate of occupancy issued prior to the effective date of the Targeted Ward 4 Single Sales Moratorium and Neighborhood Grocery Retailer Act of 2008, passed on 2nd reading on December 2, 2008 (Enrolled version of Bill 17-941 may apply for a retailer Class B license. “(3) The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq may issue rules to implement the provisions of this subsection. The proposed rules shall be Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2009 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 25-336 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. submitted to the Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution, within this 30-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved.” c) New sections 25-340.01 and 25-341.01 are added to read as follows: “§ 25-340.01. Special restrictions for Ward 4. “(a) For the purposes of this section, the term: “(1) “ANC 4C07” means the single member district area in Ward 4, established under § 1-309.03. “(2) “Ward 4” means the area defined as Ward 4 in § 1-1041.03 on September 30, 2004. “(b) Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, no class A or B license shall be issued in or transferred into Ward 4; provided, that this section shall not prohibit the transfer of a class A or B license within Ward 4. “(c) This section shall not apply to any application for a new or transferred license pending on September 30, 2004. “(d) An exception to the moratorium imposed by subsection (b) of this section on the application of a Class B license shall be granted for a full service grocery store or substantially renovated full service grocery store located within the boundaries of ANC 4C07, with a certificate of occupancy issued after the effective date of the Targeted Ward 4 Single Sales Moratorium and Neighborhood Grocery Retailer Act of 2008, passed on 2nd reading on December 2, 2008 (Enrolled version of Bill 17-941 provided, that no licensee shall devote more than 3,000 square feet to the sale of alcoholic beverages. “(e) The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq may issue rules to implement the provisions of this section. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution, within this 30-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved. “§ 25-341.01. Targeted Ward 4 Moratorium Zone. “(a) For the purposes of this section, the term “Targeted Ward 4 Moratorium Zone” means the area bounded by the line starting at 13th Street, N.W and Eastern Avenue, N.W thence in a southerly direction along 13th Street, N.W to Fern Street, N.W thence in an easterly direction along Fern Street, N.W to Georgia Avenue, N.W thence in a southerly direction along Georgia Avenue, N.W to Aspen Street, N.W thence in a westerly direction along Aspen Street, N.W to 13th Street, N.W thence in a southerly direction along 13th Street, N.W to Piney Branch Road, N.W thence in a southerly direction along Piney Branch Road, N.W to 13th Street, N.W thence in a southerly direction along 13th Street, N.W to Colorado Avenue, N.W thence in a southwesterly direction along Colorado Avenue, N.W to Madison New § 25-340.01 New § 25-341.01 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Street, N.W thence in a westerly direction along Madison Street, N.W to 16th Street, N.W thence in a southerly direction along 16th Street, N.W to Spring Road, N.W thence in an easterly direction along Spring Road, N.W. to 13th Street, N.W thence in a northerly direction along 13th Street, N.W to Randolph Street, N.W thence in an easterly direction along Randolph Street, N.W. to 10th Street, N.W thence in a southerly direction along 10th Street, N.W to Spring Road, N.W thence in an easterly direction along Spring Road, N.W to Rock Creek Church Road, N.W thence in an easterly direction along Rock Creek Church Road, N.W to 7th Street, N.W thence in a northerly direction along 7th Street, N.W to Randolph Street, N.W thence in an easterly direction along Randolph Street, N.W to Rock Creek Church Road, N.W thence in a northeasterly direction along Rock Creek Church Road, N.W to Varnum Street, N.W thence in a westerly direction along Varnum Street, N.W to Grant Circle, N.W thence in a westerly direction along the southern circumference of Grant Circle, N.W to Varnum Street, N.W thence in a westerly direction along Varnum Street, N.W to 8th Street, N.W thence in a northerly direction along 8th Street, N.W to Ingraham Street, N.W thence in an easterly direction along Ingraham Street, N.W to 2nd Street, N.W thence in a southerly direction along 2nd Street, N.W to Farragut Street, N.W thence in a southeasterly direction along Farragut Street, N.W to 1st Street, N.W thence in a northeasterly direction along 1st Street, N.W to Gallatin Street, N.W thence in an easterly direction along Gallatin Street, N.W to North Capitol Street; thence in a northerly direction along North Capitol Street to Riggs Road, N.E thence in an easterly direction along Riggs Road, N.E to South Dakota Avenue, N.E thence in a southeasterly direction along South Dakota Avenue, N.E to Kennedy Street, N.E thence in a northeasterly direction along Kennedy Street, N.E to Madison Street, N.E thence in a northwesterly direction along Madison Street, N.E to 6th Street, N.E thence in a northeasterly direction along 6th Street, N.E to Nicholson Street, N.E thence in a northwesterly direction along Nicholson Street, N.E to 6th Street, N.E thence in a northerly direction along 6th Street, N.E to Eastern Avenue, N.E thence in a northwesterly direction along Eastern Avenue, N.E to New Hampshire Avenue, N.E thence in a southwesterly direction along New Hampshire Avenue, N.E. to Blair Road, N.E thence in a northwesterly direction along Blair Road, N.E to North Capitol Street; thence in a northwesterly direction along Blair Road, N.W to Aspen Street, N.W thence in an easterly direction along Aspen Street, N.W to Willow Street, N.W thence in a northeasterly direction along Willow Street, N.W to Eastern Avenue, N.W thence in a northwesterly direction along Eastern Avenue, N.W to the point of beginning at the intersection of 13th Street, N.W and Eastern Avenue, N.W provided, that the Targeted Ward 4 Moratorium Zone shall not include the area bounded by the line starting at the intersection of 8th Street, N.W and Dahlia Street, N.W thence in a southerly direction along 8th Street, N.W to Aspen Street, N.W thence easterly along Aspen Street, N.W to Piney Branch Road, N.W thence southwesterly along Piney Branch Road, N.W to 8th Street, N.W thence in a southerly direction along 8th Street, N.W to Madison Street, N.W thence in an easterly direction along Madison Street, N.W to 3rd Street, N.W thence in a northerly direction along 3rd Street, N.W to Whittier Street, N.W ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. thence in a westerly direction along Whittier Street, N.W to 5th Street, N.W thence in a northerly direction along 5th Street, N.W to Dahlia Street, N.W thence in a westerly direction along Dahlia Street, N.W to the point of beginning at the intersection of 13th Street, N.W and Dahlia Street, N.W. “(b) Within the Targeted Ward 4 Moratorium Zone, a licensee under an off-premises retailer’s license, class A or B, shall not: “(1) Divide a manufacturer’s package of more than one container of beer, malt liquor, or ale, to sell an individual container of the package if the capacity of the individual container is 70 ounces or less; or “(2) Sell, give, offer, expose for sale, or deliver an individual container of beer, malt liquor, or ale with a capacity of 70 ounces or less. “(c) The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq may issue rules to implement the provisions of this section. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution, within this 30-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the December 2, 2008 fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1- 206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
