<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-312">
  <num type="law">17-312</num>
  <heading type="short">Veterans Appreciation Scholarship Fund Establishment Act of 2008</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2009-03-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-312.pdf">D.C. Law 17-312</citation>
      <citation type="register">56 DCR 35</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0027">
      <narrative>Law 17-312, the “Veterans Appreciation Scholarship Fund Establishment Act of 2008”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-27 which was referred to the Committee on Workforce Development and Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 18, 2008, and December 2, 2008, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 19, 2008, it was assigned Act No. 17-612 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-312 became effective on March 20, 2009.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To provide tuition assistance to United States military personnel returning to the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Veterans Appreciation Scholarship Fund Establishment Act of 2008”. Sec. 2. Veterans Appreciation Scholarship Fund a) There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Veterans Appreciation Scholarship Fund “Fund”, which shall be used solely for the purposes set forth in subsection (c) of this section. The Fund shall be funded by appropriations b) All funds deposited into the Veterans Appreciation Scholarship Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (a) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress c) Subject to the availability of funds in the Fund, United States military personnel whose service began on or after September 11, 2001, and who are residents of the District of Columbia shall be granted reimbursement of tuition, fees, books, and other materials from the Fund for undergraduate and graduate courses at the University of the District of Columbia for a period of 4 years after their return from active duty. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer, dated October 21, 2008, as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1- 206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2009 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-325.141"/>
  </section>
</document>
