<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-40">
  <num type="law">17-40</num>
  <heading type="short">Historic Preservation Tax Credit Partnership and Limited Liability Company Clarification Amendment Act of 2007</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2007-10-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-40.pdf">D.C. Law 17-40</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 8050</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0182">
      <narrative>Law 17-40, the “Historic Preservation Tax Credit Partnership and Limited Liability Company Clarification Amendment Act of 2007”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-182 which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 21, 2007, and July 10, 2007, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 27, 2007, it was assigned Act No. 17-102 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-40 became effective on October 18, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 to exempt a transfer of interests for the purposes of utilizing historic preservation tax credits to improve or renovate real property that is located at 733 15th Street, N.W and is not occupied by residential tenants. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Historic Preservation Tax Credit Partnership and Limited Liability Company Clarification Amendment Act of 2007 Sec. 2. Section 402(c)(2) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980, effective September 10, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-86; D.C. Official Code § 42-3404.02(c)(2 is amended by adding a new subparagraph (H-i) to read as follows H-i)(i) A conveyance or re-conveyance for a project that improves or renovates the real property located at 733 15th Street, N.W Lot 22, Square 222 commonly known as "The Woodward Building if I)(aa) It was operated as an office building until being vacated by commercial tenants to accommodate rehabilitation of the building; “(bb) It was or is being redesigned for residential tenants, having previously not been designed for such use; and “(cc) It was not occupied by residential tenants at the commencement of the project or as of the effective date of this subparagraph; “(II) Its zoning is appropriate for its proposed residential use III) There is a conveyance by 15th and H Street Associates, LLP to the Master Tenant by entering into a master lease with the Master Tenant for the purpose of utilization of historic tax credits for the improvement or the renovation; “(IV) 15th and H Street Associates, LLP: “(aa) Submits a complete application for historic tax credits to the U.S. Department of Interior, National Park Service; Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2007 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 42-3404.02 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(bb) Receives approval of part 1 and part 2 of the application; and “(cc) Pursues approval of part 3 of the application in good faith V) There is a re-conveyance of the ownership interests within 120 months of the commencement of the project to 15th and H Street Associates, LLP, which re-conveyance restores the ownership interests in 15th and H Street Associates, LLP as existing at the commencement of the project (subject to any other transfers otherwise exempt under this section) and terminates the interest of the Master Tenant in the real property; “(VI) 15th and H Street Associates, LLP does not sell the real property to the Investor Member except as permitted by this subparagraph; “(VII) A Notice of Transfer is issued in accordance with subsection (d)(1)(A) of this section; and “(VIII) Prior to the execution of a residential lease for the building, which execution occurs prior to the re-conveyance provided for in sub-sub- subparagraph (IV) of this sub-subparagraph, the proposed tenant receives a written notice, on a single page, in a minimum 14-point bold Times Roman font, that: “(aa) 15th and H Street Associates, LLP has entered into a master lease with the Master Tenant for the purpose of utilizing historic tax credits; “(bb) Within 120 months of the execution of the master lease, there may be a re-conveyance of the interest held by the Master Tenant to 15th and H Street Associates, LLP, which re-conveyance restores the ownership interests in 15th and H Street Associates, LLP as existing at the commencement of the project (subject to any other transfers otherwise exempt under this section) and terminates the interest of the Master Tenant in the real property; and “(cc) The conveyances and re-conveyances, with respect to the real property only, are exempt from the provisions of this act if the requirements of this subparagraph are met, including the requirement that 15th and H Street Associates, LLP: “(1) Submits a complete application for historic tax credits to the U.S. Department of Interior, National Park Service; “(2) Receives approval of part 1 and part 2 of the application; and “(3) Pursues approval of part 3 of the application in good faith. “(ii) For the purposes of this subparagraph, the term: “(I) “Conveyance” or “re-conveyance” means a transfer of interests in real property or an entity, including by sale, exchange, or execution or termination of a master lease, or a combination thereof. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(II) “Historic tax credits” means tax credits under section 47 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 16, 1962 (76 Stat. 966; 26 U.S.C. § 47 “(III) “Investor Member” means an investor in the Master Tenant. “(IV) “Master Tenant” means a limited partnership or limited liability company that will: “(aa) Be primarily owned by Investor Members who will have a noncontrolling interest; and “(bb) Own a noncontrolling interest in 15th and H Street Associates, LLP. “(V) “Noncontrolling interest" means an equity interest under which the Investor Member shall not, notwithstanding the Investor Member’s customary consent rights, and absent a default or breach by the managing partner: “(aa) Exercise management or control over any aspect of the project, including acting as directors, officers, managers, or decision-makers in the project; or “(bb) Play a role in selecting, recommending, or choosing directors, officers, managers, or decision-makers in the project. “(iii) For the purposes of this subparagraph, failure to comply with the requirements of sub-subparagraph (I) through (VIII) of this subparagraph shall require 15th and H Street Associates, LLP to comply anew with the requirements of this act as though this subparagraph had not been enacted Sec. 3. Sunset. This act shall expire 120 months after its effective date. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
