<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-57">
  <num type="law">17-57</num>
  <heading type="short">Homestead Housing Preservation Amendment Act of 2007</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2007-12-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-57.pdf">D.C. Law 17-57</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 10712</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0040">
      <narrative>Law 17-57, the “Homestead Housing Preservation Amendment Act of 2007”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-40 which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Urban Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 10, 2007, and October 2, 2007, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 17, 2007, it was assigned Act No. 17-131 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-57 became effective on December 11, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Homestead Housing Preservation Act of 1986 to allow proposals to develop homestead properties submitted by for-profit developers to be considered by the Administrator; provided, that 100% of the units are affordable to low- and moderate- income persons with at least 50% affordable to low-income persons. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Homestead Housing Preservation Amendment Act of 2007 Sec. 2. Section 7(a)(3) of the Homestead Housing Preservation Act of 1986, effective August 9, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-135; D.C. Official Code § 42-2106(a)(3 is amended by striking the phrase “non-profit developers” and inserting the phrase “nonprofit developers, and for- profit developers who agree to make 100% of the units affordable to low- and moderate-income persons with no less than 50% of the units affordable to low-income persons,” in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2008 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 42-2106 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
