<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-80">
  <num type="law">17-80</num>
  <heading type="short">Retail Service Station Amendment Act of 2007</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2008-01-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-80.pdf">D.C. Law 17-80</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 11883</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0142">
      <narrative>Law 17-80, the “Retail Service Station Amendment Act of 2007”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-142 which was referred to the Committee of Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 2, 2007, and November 6, 2007, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 26, 2007, it was assigned Act No. 17-191 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-80 became effective on January 29, 2008.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Retail Service Station Act of 1976 to remove the divorcement provision with respect to jobbers, to prohibit gasoline distributors from attempting to threaten or coerce a retail dealer into converting his station to a non-full service facility, and to require the Gasoline Station Advisory Board to report to the Council on the effect of this act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Retail Service Station Amendment Act of 2007”. Sec. 2. The Retail Service Station Act of 1976, effective April 19, 1977 (D.C. Law 1- 123; D.C. Official Code § 36-301.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3-102 (D.C. Official Code § 36-302.02) is amended as follows 1) Subsections (a) and (b) are amended by striking the phrase “jobber,” wherever it appears 2) Subsection (c) is repealed b) Section 5-301 (D.C. Official Code § 36-304.01) is amended as follows 1) A new subsection (d-1) is added to read as follows: “(d-1) A distributor shall not attempt to threaten or coerce an operator of a full service retail service station into: “(1) Converting the station from a full service retail service station to a non-full service retail service station; or “(2) Submitting a petition for exemption from the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of this section to the Board.” 2) A new subsection (f-1) is added to read as follows: “(f-1) On January 1, 2009, the Gas Station Advisory Board shall provide to the Council a report on the impact of the Retail Service Station Amendment Act of 2007, passed on 2nd reading on November 6, 2007 (Enrolled version of Bill 17-142 The report shall include statistical data as to the impact on independent dealers as a result of jobbers operating the retail service stations they own on: “(1) Independent dealers; “(2) Gasoline prices; “(3) Opening of new retail service stations; and “(4) Closing of existing retail service stations.”. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2008 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 36-302.02 Amend § 36-304.01 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
