<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-1">
  <num type="law">1-1</num>
  <heading type="short">Zoning Commission and Zoning Board of Adjustment Compensation Act of 1975</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1975-05-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-1.pdf">D.C. Law 1-1</citation>
      <citation type="register">21 DCR 3938</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-1, the “Zoning Commission and Zoning Board of Adjustment Compensation Act of 1975,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-5, which was referred to the Committee of the whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 18, 1975, and March 4, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 10, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-2 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>j 1 I 1 r COUNCIL or THI: DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198)(the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-5 on first and second readings February 18, 1975 and March 4, 1975, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on March 10, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-2 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D.C. Law No. 1-1, effective date May 13, 1975. Chairman of the Council l l f I D.C. Law 1-1 In the Council of the District of Columbia May 13, 1975 To amend Section 14 of the Act entitled "An Act providing for the zoning of the District of Columbia and the regulation of the location, height, bulk, and uses of buildings and other structures and of the uses of land in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes" approved June 20, 1938 {52 Stat. 802 as amended (D.C. Code, Sec. 5-426 BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That the second and third sentences of section 14 of the Act entitled "An Act providing for the zoning of the District of Columbia and the regulation of the location, height, bulk and uses of buildings and other structures and cf the uses of land in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes approved June 20, 1938 D.C. Code, sec. 5-426) are amended to read as follows Each member cf the Zoning Commission and of the Board of Zoning Adjustment shall be entitled to receive compensation, according to regulations cf the Mayor of the District of Columbia, of $100 for each day actually spent performing the duties cf such a member. No compensation, however, shall be paid to any such member r ww o• §ii#¥il4 II 111!1"5 !iCSWW Ji\ JW II P 14 l r J\ct ao. M gt;.y 13, 2 1-2 1975 who is also an officer or employee of the United States or of the District of Columbia government Sec.2. The Act shall take effect upon becoming law by operation of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Government Reorganization Act and upon becoming law, Sec. 1 of this Act shall be applied retroactively to February 5, 1975. Sec. 3. This act may be cited as the "Zoning Commission and Board of Zoning Adjustment Compensation Act 11 \ </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
