<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-107">
  <num type="law">1-107</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Marriage and Divorce Act</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1977-04-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-107.pdf">D.C. Law 1-107</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 8737</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-107, the “District of Columbia Marriage and Divorce Act,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-89, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary and Criminal Law. The Bill was adopted on amended first readings on July 27, 1976 and September 15, 1976, and second readings on November 22, 1976 and December 7, 1976. Signed by the Mayor on January 4, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 1-193 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> t t COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT O F C O L U MBIA NOTICE April 13 I 1977 "District of Columbia Marriage and Divorce Act" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Recqan1.%ation Act, CPL 93-198) t he Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-89 on first amended first and second readings July 27 1976, September 15, 1976 November 2.2, 1976 and December 7, 1976, respectively. Fo llowinq the signature of the Mayor on January 4, 1977, this legislation was assiqned Act No. 1-193, published in the February 11, 1977, edition of the D.C. \ Register and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review in accordance with Section 602 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has ~pired and therefore, ci tes the followinq legislation as D .C. Law -107, effective April 7, 1977. I J amp;T NG TU~ttR .J-f Chairman of Council (Ref. 23, D. C. Req 5869, February ll, 1977 O.C. LAW 1-107 IN THE COONCIL OF THE DISTlUC! OF COLOMBIA Acril 7, 1977 A bill to amend the laws of the District of Columbia relating to marriage, divorce, and child custody abolition of certain conmion law causes of action; and for other purposes BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the •01strict of Columbia Marriage and Divorce act l'I'l'LE I Sec. 101. Section 16- 902 ot the o.c. Code (1973 Edition is amended to read as follows No action for divorce or legal separation shall be maintainable unless one of the parties to the marriaqe has been a bona fide re~ident of the Distri ct of Columbia for at least six months next preceding the commencement of the action. No action for .annulment of &amp;amp; m.arriaqe performed outside the District .of Columbia or tor affi.rmance of any marriage shall be maintainable unless one of the parties is a bona fide resident of the District of Columbia at the time of 2- the o 1111e11cerent of tbe action be residence of the parties to an action for ai:mu.lment of a tmrriage per!ormed in the District of Collmi:&amp;gt;i.a. shall cot be considered in determ:i.d.ng whether such act ion shall be mintainahle. I! a ue:zber of the aI ed forces of the United States resides ill the District of Coluxi:&amp;gt;ia. for a contimlous period ot six m gt;nths during his or her period of mill tary service. he or sbe shall be deEmed to reside in the District ot Coluai)ia for purposes o this section only Sec. 102. Section 16-904 of tbe D.C. Code (1973 Edition is ampnded to read as follows a} A divorce fran the bonds of rmrriage.imy be granted i:t l} both parties to the marrUie ba.ve mutually aDd voluntarily lived separate and apart witbout cobabitatioo for a. period of six m::intbs next preceding the a:mneIJCE!IEnt of the action 2) both parties to the marriage ba.ve lived separate and apart witb gt;ut cohabitation for -a period of one year next preceding tbe ccmrencement o! the action b) A legal separation !rem bed and board may be graiited it 3 1 both parties to the marriage have IIUtually and "90lunta.rily lived separate aJ:ld apart witbout cohabitation 2) lxlth parties to the marriage have ll ved separate and apart witbout cohabitation for a period ot one year next preced:iilg the o 11 "eicarent of the action 3) either party bas camrf tted a.d:ul tery; or 4) ei tb.er party has eDgaged in coD&amp;lt;h1ct wbicll COIIStitmes cruelty toward the other. lar pwp:xses ot subsections (l and (2) of paragraphs (a) am (b) of this section, parties wbo ba.ve pursued separate lives, sba.r1ng neither bed nor l:xlard, shal1 be deemed to have lived separate and apart tl'OD one another even tbcugh l) they reside UDder the same root; or 2) the separation is pursuailt to an order of court d) Marriage contracts may be anm1J J ed in the followiDg ca es: either o:t the parties thereto had a !onner wi.f e been lawfully diS'SClved I I J 2 where such marriage was con't:ra.Cted duri.Dg the insanity o! eitber parey unless there bas been volunt:az;9 cohabitation a!ter the d.iscovery of the insanity 3) where such marriage was procured by biwd or coercion 4) wbere eitller party was ma.trim:m1a]Jy iooapacitated at the time ot marriage wit.bout tbe kDcwledge of tbe other and bas continued to be so 1ncapa.c1tated 5) where either of the parties had wt attained tbe age of legal conse:rt to tbe contract of marriage unless there has been voluntary cohabitation aft.er a.tta1n1ng the age of legal consent but in such cases only at the suit of the party wbo had mt attained such age Sec. 103. {a) Section lfr905 of the D.C. C.ode (1973 Edition) is mended 'by add1ng a to the beginn:1.cg thereof, and by adding t o tbe eDd thereof the following b Ibe court may enlarge its decree ~t legal separation to an absolute divorce upon application ot the party to wbc:m the decree of legal separatiog. was grant:ed, a copy of which application shall be duly served upon tbe -s adverse party, if the court finds on the basis of affidavits that no reconciliation has ta.ken place or is probable and that a separation has continued voluntarily and without interruption for a six-month period or without interruption for a period of one year b) The heading of section 16-905 a.nc the reference thereto in the table of sections of Chapter 9 of Title 16 of such Code are amended to read as follows 16-905. Revocation and enlargement of decree of leqal separation Sec. 104 a) Section 16-907 of the o.c. Code (1973 Edition) is amended to read as follows a) The term 'legitimate' or 'leqitimated' means that the parent-child relationship exists for all riqhts, privileqes, duties, and obligations. under the laws of the District of Columbia b) The term 'born out of wedlock' solely describes the circUl!lStances that a child has been born to parents who, at the time of its birth, were not marr~ed to each other. The teni 'born in wedlock' solely describes the circumstances that a child has been born to parents who, at the .ti.me of its birth.were married to each other b) The heading of section 16-907 and the reference thereto in the table of sections of Chapter· 9 of Title 16 of such Code are amended to read as follows 16-907. Parent and child relationship defined Section 105 a) Section 16-908 of the o.c. Code {1973 Edition) is amended to read as follows: I I 6 A child born in wedlock or born out of wedlock is the legitimate child of its father and mot her and is t he le&amp;lt itimate relative of ·its father's and mother' s relati ves by blood or adoption.n (b The heading of section 16-908 and the reference thereto in the table of sections of Chapter 9 of Ti tle 16 of such Code are amended to read as follows 16-908. Relationship not dependent on marriaae Sec. 106 a section 16-909 of the D.c. Code (1973 Edition is amended to read as follows Ca) A child's relationship to its mother· is established by its birth to her. A chil~'s relationship to its father is established by provin9' by a sireponderance of evidence that be is the father, and there shall be a presur.i~tion that he is the father l) if he and the child's mother are or have been married and the child is born during the marri age or within 300 days after the termination of marital cohabitation by reason of death annull!l.ent, divorce, or separation ordered by a court: or (2) if, prior to the child's birth, he and the child's mother .have attempted to marry, anc some form of marriage has been perfoilned in apparent compliance with law, though such attempted marriage is or might be declared void for any reason, and the child is born during such attempted marriage, or within 300 days after the termination of such 7- atte:npted marital cohabitation by reason ot death, anm1lment, divorce, or separation ordered by a coort; or (3) i:t, a!ter the c.bild's birth, b.e and the c.bild' s ax:rther marry or a.tt.empt to mrry with the attezpt invol villg sane :fOI"m of marriage cerewny tba.t bas been perfcnmed ill apparent ccmpl 1ance with law tlDlgh such aUmipted marriage is or might be declarecl void for any reason, and he bas acknnwledged tbe child to be his b) l:t questioned, a presumption created by subsection (a 1 3) am.y be tried and detexmined by the Superior Court e) Upon the entry o:t a tinal j11dgxrent dete:rm:i.Il1Dg the pa.ren'tage ot a ch11d by SUperior CQurt cne pn:ivisions a! section 1~2341 or by any other court ot ccmpetent jur1sdict1on, the parent-child relationship is conclu.siVely establ 1 Shed d Ille parert~d relationship bet:ween an adoptive parent and a child ma.y be establisbed conclusively by proo:t ot adoption b nle beading of section 16-909 a.JJd the reference thereto 1J1 the table of sections at Cllapter 9 ot. Title 16 of such Code are I I 8- amended to read as follows 1~909 Proof of cb.ild s relationshio to mt.her and father Sec. 107. Section 1~910 of tile D.C. Code (1973 Edition) is amended to read as follows Upon tbe entry of a final decree 0 1' anm2lrnerrt or divorce in the absence of a valid a.ate-nuptial or post-nupti.a.l ag:Ieement or a. decree of legal separation disp:&amp;gt;s:i.Dg the property o1' the spouses, the court sba.11 a) assign to each p;irty b.i.s or her sole and separate propez ty a.cquired prior to the acd bis or ber sole and sepa ate property acquired duritlg the marriage by gift, bequest, devise, or descent, and any increase thereof or property acquired in excbange therefor; and (b) distribute all other property acom1lated ch&amp;gt;.ring the amTi.age, regardless of whether title is beld individually-or by the parties in a fOJ:?l of joint tenancy or teoaDcy by tbe entireties, in a manner that is equitable, just and reas:&amp;gt;nable, after considering all relewnt factors including, but oot limited to the duration o the marriage, any prior n:arriage of either party, the ie, heal th, occupation, am runt and sources of in&amp;lt;xJre, vocat1onal ski JJ s, ei;&amp;gt;loyabili ty, assets deb'ts and needs 01' each of the parties, provisions for the custody 01' minpr children, wbetller the distribution is in lieu 9- ot or in add1 tion to ?IBiirtena.r.ce, aDd the opp:lrtUn1 ty ot eadl tor tuture acquisition o! assets and incane Ibe court sha 11 al.so consider ea.ch party's contribution to the acquisition, preservation, appreciation, dissipation ar depreciation in value o! the assets subject to d:1st:rilxltion under ttds Sllbsection, am eacll party's ccmt:r1brtion as a bare•taker or to tile family unit. Sec. 108 a) Section 1~9ll ot the D.C. Code (1973 F.dition as amended, is turther al'el1ded by add1 ng a to the beginning tbere:&amp;gt;t b) Pa.rqrapb (1) ot section 16-911 ot sutjl Code, as amended, 1.Dsert:illg in lieu thereot ga;rn1.s1mmt am/ or :1mprisormlent !or (c) Paragr.iph (3) of section 16-9ll o~ such Code_ 1.s arrended by strik::1J:lg the word 113lldu at tile end thereot am by adding a new paragraph 4) to read as follows 4) U a party under court order to make ,paj!Dellts under this section is in arrears, order the party to make an assi gme&amp;gt;t o! part o:t his or her saJ.a.ry, wages, earnings or other inCf'17J'!l to the person entitled to receive the pa.yments; and d 4) of section 16-911 ot such C.ode, as ammded 10- is remJit&amp;gt;ered. as paragraph 5 and further an:ended by addi ng to the end thereof the following In determining· the eare and custody or 1nfant children, the best interest of the child sba.11 be the primary coosideration. To detennine the best interest ot the child, the court shall consider all relevant factors including, but oot limited to 1) the wishes ot the child as to his or her custodian, where practicable 2) tbe wishes of the child's parent or parents as to the cb.lld's custody 3) the interaction ai:id interrelationship of. the child with his or ber parent or parents, bis or ber sibl.iilgs and any other person wbo my EnDtioca.lly or psycb:Jlogically a!tect tbe child's best interest 4) the child' s adjust:zxent to bis or her heme, scbool, a.IJd crnmmi ty 5) tbe mental and physical heal th o! all 1:ad1 vi ctna ls involved e) Section 16-9ll of such O:&amp;gt;de, as ameDded, is further amended by addi ng to the eDd thereof the !ollowi.og b lhe attadment, garni.saDent or assigIJDeOt -ll- under paragrapbs (1) and (4) o! subsection (a) is binding on the employer, trustee, or other payor ot salary, wages, esrni.l:lp, or otber 1.nccme. No e:IJployer sbaJ.J disc.barge or otherRise disc;pllne an eI;&amp;gt;loyee because of such attadvent, g:a.rnisl:ment, or a.ssigrnrent {c) Opon ita own motion or upon motion of either party the court may order at any time, that mailltenac.ce or supp:&amp;gt;rt pa~ be made to the clerk ot the court tor renittance to the person entitled to receive the payments Sec. 109. Section l.S-914 o! the D.C. Code (1973 Edition as ampnded, is further ameaded py U:lserti.Dg a at the beginning thereat a.pd by adding to the end thereo:t the !ollow:illg In dstetm1ning the care and custody o 1.ntant children, the best interest of the child shall be the primary consideration. To determine tl:le best interest of_ the child, the court sba.11 consider all relevant factors including; but nbt l:1mited to 1) where practicable 2) the wishes o:t the child's parent or pa.rents as to tbe child ts custody 3) the interaction a.cd interrela.tioaship o! the child with his or her pa.re?lt or parents, his or ber s1b11ngs, and any other person wbo ma.y E!IX&amp;gt;tiocally or psycbolqp ca lly affect the cl:l1ld' s best in'terest 12 4 the child' s adv"'usilnen't to b.:i.s or ber lx:me school and crnmmity 5) the mesttal and physical heal th o! all indi vidnal s involved b Notice of a OlStody proceeding sball be given to the ch 1 ld s parents, guardian, or other custodian Ibe c:curt Upon a s1xJwiJJg of good cause, may permit intervention by any interested party. ft Sec. 110 (a) Section 16-918 of the D.C. Code (1973 Edition) is amended to read as fol.l..o'Rs a) In all cases UDder this chapter, where the ccw-t deans it necessary or pxq:er, a disinterested attorney may be appointed by the court to enter his appearance for the de!eodant am actively de!em the cause b) In any proceedi:ag wherein the custod,y of a child is in question, the court may api;oint a disinterested attorney to appear on beha.lt of the child and represent his best interests c) An attorney appointed Under this section my receive such COJJpenSation for bis services a.s the court detemines to be proper, wbic.b the court may order to be pa.id by eitiler or both of tbe parties 13 d Notwi.t.bstalldiJ:lg any otber provision ot law or any l'ul.e o! court, the appearance o:t an attorney in any action under this chapter ~ore a court ot original jul1.sdict.ion shall be deemed to have ter.ninated for the purpose ot service o! any m:rtion, precess, or any other pleiiding, upon ccmpletion o1 the case endi ng in a jndgm=mt adjudication, decree, or fillal order frcm which co appeal bas been taken when the time allowed tor a.u appeal expires am, it notice ot appeal bas been entered. upon the date o! tbe :tinal disposition o! tbe appeal Ibere shall be no subsection, but the court bavillg jul1.sdiction over the matter may suspeIJd t1Je termfna:tion o:f the appearance on 1 ts own action, or ai tbe aot1ou ot UJ.Y party to the case prior to the ecpira.tiou ot the t:ime for a.ppe.al b lbe beading o1 section 16-918 and the reference thereto in the table of sections of Chapter 9 o1 Title 16 o! the D C~ c.ode are m-nded to read as folloa 16-918. Aooointment of counsel camensa.tion; temina:tion at appointment Sec. lll a) Ola.pt~ 9 ct Title 16 o! the D.C. Code (1973 Edition) is amended by adding to the end thereot the followlD.g l.S-923. A!:lolltion ot action tor brea:cll ot prani.se, aller:ia.tion of a!fections, 3lld c:r1m1nal. conversation 14- QlnsP..s of action tor breach ot premise, al1eca.tioc of a!fections, and crlminal conversation are hereby abol..i.sbed b) Tbe table of sections ot Q)apter 9 of Title 16 of 'the D.C. Code is arrended. by adding to the end thereof the following 16-923. Abolition ot action for brea.cb of premise, alienation of a.tfectiocs and cr:iminal conversation Sec. 112 (a) Section 16-2345 of tbe D.C. Code (19T.3 F.dition) is amended by strild.Ilg therefran ore the O:mni ssioner of tbe District o! ColurziJia or bis desigllated agent or bas been ackcowledged in ao affidavit swore to by the husband before a. judge or the clerk of a court ot ~rd, or before an officer of tbe armed. forces of the United States authorized to administer oaths, and the affidavit is delivered to the Cmmissiooer or his desigca.ted agent" and inserting in lieu thereof or wben the parentlxxxi ot a. child born out of wedlock bas been established by judicial. proces or by ~owled.genent by the person wbose parentbood is thus detennioed b) Section 16-2345 of such Code is arrended b? inserting before the last sentence thereof the followizlg lbe new birtb certificate sba.11 nowhere on its ace shew that the parentage has beeo established by judicial process or by admowledgement c } The heading of section 16-2345 and the reference thereto in the table of sections o Subchapter II of Cllapter 23 of Title 16 of such Code are ~nded to read as follows 16-2345. New birth record upon 15- mrriage or detem1nation of natural pa.rents Sec. 113 a) Section 1291 o:f the Act o March 3, 1901 (D.C. Oxie, sec 30-110) is ameaded by str1kiIJg "names, ages, and color" and insert.iDg 1n lieu tbereo:f names and ages b) Section 1296 ot the Act of March 3, 1901 (D. C. Code, sec. 30-l.l.8) is repealed. Sec. 114. Section 20 o the Act of July 10, 1957 (D.C. Code sec. 30-320 as anended J.s :turther amended by striking under oath Sec. W be Act at. Septe:Wer 14, 1.965 (D.C. Code, sec 21-104 (1973 Edition as amended, 1s further amended by inserting tbe words "or ma:rries" 1mnpd1ately atter the mrds bectllles 1B years of age Tl'Ill: ll Sec. 201 a) Section 13-340 (a ot the D.C. Code (1973 F.dition) 1 1s ametlded by adding to the esld thereof tile following la actions for divorce in wh1ch service by publicatiOn: is under this chapter, and satisfactory ev1deDce is presented to the court that tbe pla..iJlti!f is unable to the cost of publishing a.n advertiseDent pursuant to D.C. Code sec. 13-340, witbout substantial ba.rd.ship to b.Unselt or bersel or to bis or ber family the court my direct that such publication my be made by posting the order of publication d.e:filled in D.C. Oxie sec. 13-339, for a period ot twenty~e calendar da.ys, in the Clerk's O!fi.ce o the Family Division o the Superior Court of the District of Coluzmia 16 b) Section 13-34.Q (b) o! tb.e D.C. Code (197'3 Edition is ~nded by inserting a.fter tlle "iVOI'd "a.dvert.1.SaDeat" the oll.owi.Dg "or the order of the publication posted pursuant to subsection a ot this SECtion Sec. 202 a Section 1!&amp;gt;-712 of the D. C. Code (1973 Edition) is amended to read as follows a) Any District of Columbia. court may authorize the coxmenca:oent, prosecution or de:i'ense of any oon-crim1na1 suit actioa or proceeding, or a'ppeal therein, without prepayment of fees and costs or security therefor, including tlle fees for transcripts on appeal, by a person who is unable to pay such costs or give security t.bere.tar witbol.lt mibstalltial. bardsbip to bjmself or herself or b.is or her tamily, as established by a.ftidavit or other proof sa.tista.ctory to the court b) Any person wbo makes an affidavit a.s provided 1.n subsection a and states therein that he or she receives public assistance under the Di.strict of Colunbia Aid to Fam! J 1 es with Dependent Chi.ldren or General Public Assistance .Programs, or receives assistance under Title- XVI of the Social Security Act (Supplement~ Security Inccne 76 stat. 197) shall be prestmied eligible to proceed wi:tbout prepayment of fees a.cd costs or security therefor I I 17 b Ille heeding ot section n.2 alld the re:tereoce thereto, in the table of s~iv r hapter 7 ot Title 15 o! the D.C. Code are ane&amp;gt;ded to read as tol.l.ows 15-712. J \ nss in Form. Pauper1s II TlTIE III Sec. 301 Ibis act shall take e tect pursuant to the provisions of sectioo 602(c) ot the District ot Colmbia Self-Govermnent and Ocm!rmental Reorganization Act Ooc:ket for the Bill Consi~red in Council November ZZ, 197 6 Amended First Reading Am~nded First Veta November 22, 1976 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE C:OUNC:U. IOl&amp;amp;MeCR A'l'C v C:OUNCU MCIOl•CR AYC 14A 'I' H.v eou c:u A YC TUCKER x I 'OI:roN x SP UI.DING x ~POR D. x HARDY x WII.SON x BAR.RY x HOBSON x WmttR. x CUB.I&amp;lt;£ x MJORE~ J, x I COA.ttS x S'P.ACKI N x Final Vote in Counc:il Dece mber 7, 1976 (Secretary of the Council) R EC 0 R 0 0 F C ·O U N C I L V 0 TE C:OUHc:I CMeCR C:OUHC:I~ M lllol ecit UCKZR I x DDDN X&amp;gt;Ott o. x BAlmY BARRY x BOBSON CLAR { I M:&amp;gt;Q..R.,L_ J. COATES x SRAcxu:TON ~EC 1 7 '976 Presented to die Mayor Mayor 's Action: A 'l't x v x NA'I' H.v C:OUHC:J~ MCMeC { SPAUIJYING x WII$0N tmn"ER x I x Q).J)Llf.{ ef (Secretary of the Council Secretary of the Council I I Approved I 4 JAN 1!17 Disapproved Mayor's Signature J Enacted without Mayor's Signature Secretary of the Council) H A T I I A I l I I H A Y I x I I 4 JA~I Reccnsiclered by Council Bill Ood&amp;lt;et i-_a_9 P1g9Two Vote RECORC OF COUNCii. VOTE CDUNcn. lllCM8P •l't N.AY MoV 1 C:OUNCJ&amp;amp MSM•CJll A'rS HAT I N.v C:O\IKCU I H•Y I H .V. I TUCKER I HOBSON HARDY MOO.RE, D. BARRY I MOORE r I CLA.AKE I .ROLARK DIXON ~KLE'ION amp i:adla&amp;amp Vo&amp;amp;9 A. B P"wted to Vie President Sustain Mayor's Vf/tZJ Not Sustain MaYar's Veta JAff 2 5 f!l7 Submined to the Ccngnm Senata Action Resclution Number Secretary of the Senate~ Enac ad wfthout Congns:sicnal action Seenlt31V of the Council) I I U..eu I S P AtJLDL.'lG I W!LSON I WINTER I I N V-'fot Vo.d:tq (Secretary of the Council Scntary of the Council Pnisident of the U. S.l (SecmatY of ttl• Counci I) House ktlon Aescluucm-Number CJerl&amp;lt; of ttle House) I I I l I I</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
