<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-114" flag="true">
  <num type="law">1-114</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-04-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-114.pdf">D.C. Law 1-114</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 8743</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-114 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-324, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 22, 1976 and December 7, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 11, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 1-204 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE April 31, 1977 D.C LAW 1-114 "Prescription Drug Price Information Amendme:ltu. Pursuant t o Section 412 of the Distr ict of Columbia Self-Goverru:1ent and Goverru:1ental Reor;aniza tion Act (PL 9 3-198 Act, the Council of the District o f Colum!&amp;gt;ia aco?ted Bill first and second r eadings November 22, 1976, and 7, 1976, respectively. Following the signature o! t~e January 11 1977, this legislation was assigned Act in the January 28, 1977, edition of the .C. Register, anc transmittec t gt; both Houses of Congress for review, in accordance with Section 602(c} (l of ~he Ac The council of the Distr ic t of Columbia here~y notice that the 30- day Congressional Review Period has ired and, therefore, cites the !ollowing legislation as C. Law 1-114, effective April 7, 1977 \ /I .L I t s RLil'G TtiCllR Chairman of the Counc il 23, o.c eg S042, January 28 77 I D. C. LAW 1-114 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTR1CT OF.COLUMBIA April 7, 1977 To amend the District of Columbia Prescription Drug Price Information Act (O.c. Law 1-81 BE IT ENACTED BY THE COL"NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Prescription Drug Price Information Amendments Sec. 2 a) Subsections 2 (d f g and (j) of the District of Columbia Prescription Drug Price Information Act (O.c. Law 1-~1, 22 D. C. Reg 99, effective September 10 1976; hereafter in t.~is act cited as the "Information Act are repealed bl Subsection 2(b) of the Information Act is amended to read as follows bl 'Most conunonly used prescription drugs' mear.s the prescription drug products which were most frequently paid for by the Medicaid program operated by the District of Columbia Gover::unent under a State plan filed in accordance with section 1902 of the Social 2- Security Act (112 o.s.c. l396a in the tbl:ee consecutive months ending sixty days before an j;ssue date Sec. 3 a) Sections lOl, 103, a~d 105 of the Infoniation Act are each amended by inserting he word •presc iption" a fte:r tile 'WO:rds 100 most commonly used" and before -i e wcrd "drugs {b) Sections 103 and 1011 of the In.formation ~ct are amended l::y s-i:riking the word "legend" and inserting the "p:escription cl Subsection l02(a) of the I.nfo mation Act is amended as follows: tt(a) lists the 100 most commonly used prescription drugs in two commonly prescribed quan~ties, with space for the current sel..1ing price of each guar.tity d) Section 1011 of the .I.nforlllation Act is amended by "in writing, by telephone, or in any .otlle manner insert.ing in lieu thereof "in writing or by telephone Sec. 4 a) sections 301, 302, and 303 of t.,e for~aticn ~ct are amended to read as follows Sec. 301. The Depa=t:nent of Human Resources shall publish. a fo:inulary of drug products, with che chemical or generic name of each, that are determi~ed to be the:apeutically equivalent to specified brand name drug produc~s. The Cepa:t::tent shall deterz;rine the ccntents 3- of the forim:lary cnly after recommendatior.s a:e made by a committee of nine members appointed by the Director of that· Department. The committee shall consist of one licensed physician and one licensed pbarmacise employed by the Depart ent, two licensed physicians ar.d three licensed i;:ha::macists in private practice in the District, and tlolO pha~acologists on the faculty of a university in the District. The recO mendations of the committee shall require concurrence· of a majority of t.;e members c! the committee. The committee's recomrnendatior.s shall ~e published in the District; of Columbia Reaister as proposed reg_ulations of the Department. The Depa l!lent•s determinat:.ons shall be· made in accoroance with sections tll:ough 7 of t!le District of Col=bia Administrative Procedure rl {O.C. Code, sec"tions 1-1503 to l-1506) and published'i the District of Columbia Recister as final regulations. The committee shall review the published for~ulary annually, or whenever an amendment to it appears necessa:y. T~e co111111ittee shall publish its first recommendations no later than eight months after the effective date of s act Sec. 302. caJ When a pha.:macist receives a prescription for a brand name drug for which one or ~ore 4 equivalent d:uqs are listed in the f or111ulary prepared by the Depart:nent of Human Resources the pha lllcist may dispense any or.e of t he listed equivalent pr oduc4 s and if a listed equiva l e'-t pr oduct is dispensed, the pharJMcis t must dispense the product in stock having the lowest current selling price Tbe pharmacist shall do so i! th~ purchase: so requests, except as provided in se1:tion 303 bl When a phar111aci~ receives a presCJ:iption fo: a d:uq l:y generic came, t he pharmacist shall dispe.nse the listed product in stoc:Jc havi::g the l.owe~ current selling pric e c) Until the first promulgation of the forJnulary by the Oepartment of Su:nan Resources pharmacists licer.sed i.'\ tbe Oist:ict shall have the saJ!le power wb.icb they had p: ior to September 10, 1976 t o exercise their proiessional judqi nt in selec-;i g the cL-ug product to be dispensed Sec 303. The pha=33c1st shall not dis:iense an equivalent druq product under sect.ion 302 if a) The person purc~asinq the drug product or the patient for whom it is intended indicates a p:efe:e.~ce for the d::uq product actually prescribed s b) The prescriber, in the case of a written pre6cri~ion order signed by the prescriber, writes in the ~rescriber s own handwriting "dispense as written" or O. A.W or a simi1ar notation A ?rocedu.re for checking or initialing a box, pre~rinted or starnped on a pr escription forin will not constitute an acceptable notation c) The prescriber, in the case of a pr escription coaununica:.ed 1:;y t elephone, e&amp;gt;q:resaly indicates the prescription is to be disFensed as corr.municated, a~d this indication is noted in the phar111.acist •s o..i:i handwritiog in the manner provided in subsection (bl b) section 305 (bl of tbe formation Ac~ is a111ended striking defined in" and inserting in l~eu thereof •4ete.r::dned under s ection 30S(c) of the Infcrination Act is 1:;y striking "a c~ain drug produ and il!serting the: eof "t.ha l:rand sec. s: section 11011 of the Inforl!latio:i Ac is ame:ided r ead as follows sec GO This act shall become effective u?on t~e date of the act ent itl ed 1 ?rescription Drug Price Amend:nen s Sec. 6 his act shall be effec ive i111111edia.tely fOllC"J! ng the period providee for c ressional view in 6- section 602 (c l) of the District of Columbia Self GOvernment and Gcvernmental Reorc;anizatio::i JI.ct </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
