<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-124">
  <num type="law">1-124</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-04-19</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-124.pdf">D.C. Law 1-124</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 8749</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-124 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-375, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 3, 1976 and December 17, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 25, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 1-226 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>Law 1·124 LAWS OP'l'HE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA 19"17 Law 1-124 Law 1-124 fte,•enue Act for Fiscal Year 1978 1n the Council of the District of Columbia, A11ril 19, 1~77: To provide additional revenue for the Dlstr!cl of Columbia, and for other purposes. ilE IT ENACTED llY THE COUNCIL OF TH£ OISTillCT OP COLUJ\UUA THAT Sec. JOO.] This act may be cited 11.s the "Revenue Act for Fiscal Year 1978 TITLE 1. FEES FOR REGISTRATION OF CLASS A AND CLASS B MOTOR VEHICLES AND OTHER PROVlSIONS RELATING TO MOTOR VEHICLES c. 101. Section 3 of Title IV of lhe District of Columbia Revenue Acl of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stal. 681; D.C. Code, see. 4(H03) is amended as follows a) The paragr.iph designated "Class A" of subsection (b relating to registration fees for passenger vehicles) is am1&amp;lt;nded by I) Deleting 50 57 83" and 96" uod inserting in lieu thereof 35 42 68" and 16 respectively, and (2) Striking the figures "2800" and "2801" and inserting in lieu thereof the figures "2'799 and "2800 respectively b) The par graph designated "Class B" of subseetion (bl (relating to registratiClll fees for lrucks, t:rae!Ors and certain commercial moror vehicles) is amended by strikini; the figure "SSOO and inse.rting in lieu lhercof the figure 340 c) The paragraph designated Class G" in subsection (b) is repealed. Su. 1112. The first sentence ofsection 6 of Title 111 of tbc District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1949, approved May 27, 194!1 (63 StaL 972; D.C. Code, sec. 4~03(j is amended by stn'lung the figures "2800 ind "2801" and insert ing in lieu thereof the figures "2799" nnd "2800 respectively. Sec. 103. The first paragraph in ~ection 2 of Appendix A to Title 32 of tbe D.C. Rules and Regulations is amended by deleting the words "and $0.50 for reflectoriied covering of metal 1.:11.rs" and by placing a period after the figure 3.00 Sec. 104. The paragraphs entitled "Class G" and "Vehicles equipped with solid tires" in section U of Appendix A to Title 32 of the D.C. Rules and Rtgu!Ations are herl!by repeaied. TITLE II. RENTAL OF PUBLIC SURFACE AND SUBSURFACE SPACE. Sec. 201. Section 1 of D.C. Council Resolution No. 69·75, adopted September 179 Law l-124 Dll&amp;gt;"TklCf OP COl.UM:BIA SIATCTES AT LA Km: Law 1-124 16, 1960 (ttlaun11 IA&amp;gt; lhe renllll of p11blic sw1iu:c Ce) is hereby am~nded by \11S()rtin1t "lmiea sixty-five jk'teenl" alter I.he nnl at &amp;amp;n annual r.lle of 5 perunt amp;nJ by inwtt.mg "tunes sixty-five p;!n:enl" after t.hu onki "at an ;lnnual nl.e ur pcrttnt c. 20 ctloo 1 of D C C.Ouncil Resolution No. 69-'l 1, adopl&amp;lt d Sept.ember 16, 1!169 (mint.mg 10 lhc ttn!Jll or 1.111.bl~ subsur(act pao 15 hereby amended by Jcleung on tlie br.,si~ of I.he nssesS&amp;lt d value" and onst·rtini: an lieu 1hereof on lhe litu&amp;lt;i~ or AiXty•rl\'e pPrcent of the llSl&amp;gt;CSSl!d vulue" TITLE Ill i IME FOR PAYMENT OF REAi, ANO PF. llSONAL TAXES. Sec. 301 ti) Thu nl'\IL parugraph of sec1ion 5 or the act cntilled "An Ael 10 amend sections !i und nor the Act of Congress making l\ppro11riut.ions to provide for the 01Btrict of Columliia for the fisul year endonl( June 30, 1003 lpproved July I, lUO\ and for 01her purposes a pproved July 3, 1926 (44 Still. sa:I, D.C. Cock sec lt;17- l:?Oll a1 amended. is further am&amp;lt;:nded to read M follows Real c~tat.o 1.:1xes nre due snd payable m (ull 1&amp;gt;n or bdore !\evt.:mber 15 annu.ally cx~pl lhaL whtte the real CO&amp;gt;UIU' \.U leu l.han 011e hundred lhow;and doll&amp;amp;n, auch tax shall be due :ind payable um1:annually m two eqwol 1nstallmcn1S, the hn.l inst.&amp;amp;!lmenL to be paid on or before Sep~mlier IS, and the St.-cond 1n•1 gt;llm.;nL to be p:iid on or before March 31 Persons al.es o! all kinda 1&amp;lt;re due anrl IHIYllble in full u the ume prescnht.od for lhe fihng oI tho: tax l'\;\urn If any ~uch uu or any installmenL lhereof, is nul paid within thu l.ime vrescr1bcd, there hhall be added 10 1ud1 l.U~ or inalAllmem a penalty u( um l"'r«nl of t.hc unpuid amount plllS inlere on 1uch 11111lnid amount 111 Lh~ r:otc or one pcn:o1nt tier month or porlinn uf a monLll uuul the i.ax or i11stal1111cnt I~ p11ill, 1'hc 11mounL of unpalll tax, 111· h1»tl1llmc11l lhi:reof, 1ilus 1he iitmalty or mlcre~I due, 5hull con~titute a delinquent. Lax LO be coill"CtcJ in the mariner prcRcrlbt:cl l1y lnw bl The Mayor or lht- Oistriet of Columbia is dlrc1•t.ed to r~1&amp;gt;0rl to lhe Council his t~~ommcndtillUll.li with respect to '1 program O( r•ul pruperty UiX p.&amp;amp;yment incentivH and/or di~ount.'I whicli would 1illow for 01ition:&amp;amp;l 1'11rticlpal~1n, and be opcnuomd tor the pay men\ for r(-al and pm;on&amp;amp;I vl gt;pert L&amp;amp;XE'S bl-coming due :md IJ.•yable afU'r June ao, 1978. A report on tl\1:1 pro~ram 1hall lie sulimitied to the Counal on or bt!fo~ two hundred \e\dll) d:ly a(k-r the effc.;tive d31e of t.h1s 11cl, snd 11r1or LO 1mplcmenU1tion or such pru1tr.1m TITLE IV. AMENDMENTS TO THE OIBTRICT Of' COLU)tnlA INCOlJE A~O RANCffiSI TAX ACT OF 1!147 Sec lt;IOI. The OuslriCL or Columbia lncom4! and F'runch111t Tax Act of 1947, approved July IG, 1947 (61 SU!t i:n; D.C. Cud uc. 47·t lir1l) iR umend d as follows l1} Subs~ctl.in (c) or ecctinn 2 of 'l' itle Lii (rolt1ting t.o ndjustAld rcrosH income U.C. Code, sec 7-Hi57a(c I amended to rend aa follows cl AdJuRWd rcross incomt&amp;gt The wordis 'adjW1ted l(l'OSll mcome' as used in lhls arllcle m1•an gross income less the deduction iLlluwcd undur section 3(a) or Tiu~ 111 or this r.rti.:le, pr(Wid 1 that the ik.-ducuons l't\l dltt'Ctly iucurn&amp;gt;d m c rymi II u ltndu or business, aud k alimony 1.ayments; and 11rorided lbO l-'lw 1·124 further, th;it 10 ~tcrnm allov.nf for charitabk 001 •lllndsrd deduction, loss&amp;lt; or for an allo10·:111ce for &amp;amp; 11&amp;lt;·n1on or persons haul, i&amp;gt;almCOIJI mad by Ohl to a dea of 11" on or J\lunnny vaymenl.l! alluwe&amp;lt; on the rcross income of ti Disl'rict b) Section 3(a) of thr Title Codu ec 17·1M7h) j~ 11111e11 I) Subse.:tion (2) 1r.,1;111 H IM7b(n)(2 is am1:nd&amp;lt;'d "{2J Interest a) Then or attru4'd within t11 ra bl Iii If personal µn. a ton~c. A. Wlu~h prund. 15 to be made 111 ID&amp;gt; R. In wbidi c..m rharge cannot be :0 Ulxa.ble yeu under lhl~ section as 1f 1 h· 3•'Prl&amp;lt;l unp ii,l li;olu fi'or the purposes bahinc~ is the ~um 01 o( each month beJ,oin For the purpose Urv niean."4 nnl from an eJuc-dUOn~I facull and t'W'n Ulu. of 81 udents in au.-nd. an c:itried on ;Ind 1 insutution ii) In the case of an\ amount truted as m ngirrogate c:&amp;amp;rt)'tnK chi. h1.IC3ble y&amp;lt;'ar c) For the purposes of 1 n redeemable ground rem ahnll he treated a;i intereR1 (d iJ ho thu case of a ~nlncorporated business. th m aubparagr.iph (vi&amp;gt;D) olh• subf)arnl(raph (2) shall be Ii A Ten thous.anJ J.il. l&amp;gt;eJ)Utat.e return by a ma.rrr 4 )y 5 an JeT led eof 3. l to ide &amp;gt;ved D.C r 15 .dred ,qual and .es of ng of vi thin ?nalty nt i\t ax or U$ the in the uncil ymcnt and be g due mirted e dat.e iOME 1947, ded llS L.iw 1-124 L"WS OF TH DISTRICT OF t:OLll/lllllA 1971 Law 1·12·1 further, th11t in dcternilni11g adjusted i;ros:&amp;lt; inl'ome, no d..ductions &amp;amp;hall l&amp;gt;P allowed for charitable ct.111trihutlon med and dtmtJil ~1.enses. nn optional standard cfl!duclion, lo~e" of 1&amp;gt;ro1~rty nut comicct.cd with u trado l)r liusmes or for an allowance for ~ularics or ro111pcn~11tio11 for J.Jcrsuual servict-s of th person or persons liable for the tax. Alimony J.l&amp;lt;~}'meDL'i mean periodir payment mado by one spouse to his ur her spoui;e ur former spoWie J.lUrsu:mc lo a d.-crte of divon-e ur :1 lei.rally binning lt J&amp;gt;aratc maint~na11ce 3.Wt'emen1 Alimony PU)'m&amp;lt;·rtUI alluwc1I ai&amp;lt; an ndjusl.111enl to lfro&amp;gt;s i11romt gt;h:1ll IJ&amp;lt 1oduJ&amp;lt;'d an I.he grosb 1nrum of th1- l'\-etpienl, 1( the t\1'ipi"'1l is a resident of th" District b) Section :l(a) of Lhe Tille 111 (relalini; to dedu~tiCln~ from~ income l).C. Cede, gee, 47· 15ro7b) is amended a&amp;gt;1 followi I) Subsection (2 n:lating to U1e deduclioo for lnkrc~t D.C. Code. l!&amp;lt;!C. 47·1557b(a)(2l) L~ tllDendcd to read l&amp;lt;ll follows 2) Interest u) There llhall be allowed '1$ a dl lt;luctioo all mtere&amp;gt;t paid or accrued within the t:1xable year on ind;,btt:dness b i) If pe~onol pl"OJ*rl) or educational scr~ices arc purchased under n contraci A. Which pro,·ide~ th!1l paymenl or p.art or all of the purchase pric~ is to be made i11 lnst&amp;lt;illmeot aod B. In which carrying ch11ri:es 11re Reparatdy stated but tht\ mter st charge c11n11ot b~ a~certained, then, Lhe pnyments rnnde during the t.axahlu y~ur under the contract shall treall:d for the )lurpos~s of this sccuun M 1f they included inwrc~t cqu:ol tu six percent nr the average unp1•itl liulunce under the coc1 tmct .Jurin chc rn.i.able y~ar For th~ purJlOijeR nr the rrcceding si:ntence, thu :1\·ernlf" un11nid lmlanc~ 1~ the surn oft.h e un11aid b~lunce out.standing on the l'i1 l clay or each rnonlll bcgi1111i11g during tlw tnx~•hlc year dh'ideu by twt•lvc. For the purpOSl of this subsection (b the term ·educntionnl services' rroeans nny ~ervicc (ineludi11g lodgin1 ll) which ls pun:ha&amp;lt;ed from nn education11I anstitution hicll normally maintain~ a rcgulur faculty and curriculum and normally hns a rcguln.r!y organit~'\l body of students i11 i1t.Lennnnce at the µInce where itb educa1ional activitit.:s are curri&amp;lt;:ci and (2) which is pro~itll'd for lt;tutlent of ~uch inKtitulion ii) In the cu11e of uuy conlracl to wtiicb par:igrnph (i) applies, lhc amount trented as mt-Ortst for any taxable ye&amp;amp;r shall not eJCcecd the aggrcgal.e carryin1: chargit which is properly attributable to that taxable yea r (c) For the purposu of thi~ lllle, nny a.n.nual or period~ rental under a n.-decm11ble ground rent (excluding alll-Ount.s in redemption lhert lt;&amp;gt;0 ahall be lrcatl'd 11!1 interest on nn indelitedness secured by a mortg11gc d i) lu the case of a taxpayer other than a rorporation or ttn unincorpon\lt:d business, the &amp;gt;lDIOURt or im'CStmeOI. 1ntel'CSl (as Jefinl'&amp;lt;I m Aubpar:ign1ph (vi)O) othtrwise allo\\·able as :t deduction un\ler thi~ sub1iaragraph (2) shall be llmite\l, in the followinl( order, to: A. Ten thousand dollnrs (five thou6and dollars, in tht: c e of a separate return by a rn~rrit:tl individual 11111 Uj) Law I 12'1 DISTIUCT Of' COU 1&amp;lt;111A STAnrf~ AT I.AKO£ Law 1·124 8 The amount or the net inve:.uncnl 1~nll as defined in subpar..grspb (v1 \} plus the an10W1t Ci! any) by •1uda tile~ allow~blc 11nder this sub=.ecuon (nl(21 (dettrmin d without regard ID tlus subsection (d)(i and subst c:tion Kl&amp;gt; {as it rebtes to the lkoduction tor ordinary and lll!«'SS41 trade or busintsll expenses tn)(31 (ai, it n:lald to the de.luction for Uixes on M1.I nnd personal propcrtyl and (ltl(l2 rclulltlg to the deducllofl for non-trade or non-business e&amp;gt;.penscs) of s«tiun 3 uf Title 111 of I.Ilia aet annlmtable t.O property of the tax:pa) er subJttt IO a net l..a e~cttds the rental income produced by U•c pruJl&amp;lt;!rly for the wuhle year. Jn the case or a tnJJ.t, the t.en thuuisand dollllr$ amount sr&amp;gt;ecui J 111 su~h A, ahall be zero ii) The ~nt or di!!allowed mvesttMnt 1nl.&amp;lt;!rtst for any taxable year shall be treat lt aa 1nve&amp;lt;&amp;gt;uneflt mU!rt•st paid or accrued in the succeedinii tanblc y&amp;lt;!nr, but in no nt ~hnll ctU'T}'O\'tt a pply to a carryover detennm~ in a t.u&amp;amp;blc )ie.sr bc!(iMln&amp;amp; befon&amp;lt; January I, um iillA For the purposes of du sab5«uon Id property subject 1.o 11 lea..e sh.all ht&amp;gt; treiltrd 115 proverty held for lnv.-stment :md not as Pl'Olll'rly UM.&amp;lt;Cl iJ2 a tr.Ide 4C bUSJ for a l.&amp;amp;DLlc fe!U if: i Fur such ts.uble )CU the sum or thr deducunns or the ~r with n:spe&amp;lt;:t to such property hith lllJ"I allowat.li! IOlely by~­ or su~ecll&amp;lt;ln (11 of section 3 of Title 111 of thu. act (other liuln rents and relmbun lt;I amounm v. ith rellp Cl to such prope is letiS lh11n fifteen tllll'l:i!nt or the rcnuil iru;omc prudu~ by s uch vropcrty, or ii. the lc~i.or is either guar.&amp;amp;nl.4.'l!d a s eclfied return or is guaraou.-eti Ill whole or in !J8.rt ll~ninKl lo~S or income. B. 1P the ca.'\4: o! a other tlwi an wllnrorporated bu.s1ne5!l as defined in ecl:Jllo l of Tille V l 11 or uus Act) each P3rlJler shaJJ is.Ae inlO attaunt separately his d..t.nliuuve £ilatt of the ~hip's invHUllCDt 111tereat and t.bc olher items of ioeome and •xpcnse t:ihn inlD accoUPl under th11 su di. C. Por the pu es of lhil sabs«Uon Cd) rn!A!rest paid or 11cuueJ on 1ndd&amp;gt;1.ednes' incum:d or continu~ 111 the constructlClo of property lO be used in .s trUde or business shall not be treated u investment 1nt.erest 1v) Thill 1ubs bon (d) ahall not apply w1th re.pea ID lnvesbnenl in1.eres1, inv~tment income, and inveaunent expen•c Mtnlluted to a apecifrc iwn or property, if th inde.blA.'dneas w ith rcspeet to such property: A. ls for a •pecified U!nn, and 8. Was ineu~ before Oetober 28. 19'!6 or Ii incurred aft.er Oc1obo:r Zl. 1976 pursuant toi a wntwn contract or commitment which, on ouch d.it.c and at all tunes thereafttr pnor tot.he incurring of suth 1ndd1t.ednts:s, is binding on the Ulxpayer. I 1-'ort.ua.bk &amp;gt; sh:ill Ii llPVla d IY) f'or o~ I- A lfupar l) r n.ol't' i.,4 tax114yer, ht. as subJKt 10 8. Al Lhr 3PPI) with in uw for 111o 8 of suhp.i Jl u the Mayur In the co.se busiilC!SS, or ubs Ct1on Ill~ L Fui n ii The ant ID\'Clllnl&amp;lt;'nt I tJ.e at'Quw1 businc:-M r In UK' cu 1hou 1mJ ri ll dvll;t 'rh1. paraJlrui uxpa r. hrs murc uf lhl! cot frfty Ptln nl u1 budine1&amp;lt;&amp;gt;1 nr l4r I• 1) For tl.e JlUt A l"b lt' t n: tn\·~stmen1 tnl."u B n t.erua L Th i'n u. 1llo o( prul'Crl\· h· iii } tu. f rorn dislJOoin l~launlf lu J{ll th lnt.en l I l'X h.rn It lt;&amp;gt jll described m s. lrtlalrng 10 fin• COR\'l!l'SIO!b b ore not dt'ri\ t The term 111 un&amp;lt;lcr ~ub cti.1 Cl:flt a S)t "t a b Law 1·124 Lii W~ O~"l'li i Ul$1'1t1C'I' lW (j()JA:M Il l/\ 1 ~77 Law 1-124 For 1.ux:1bh: yuurs b~gmnmg after Uecember 31, 1976, tllis paragraph s l1111l b~ tov11licd on un :1llowt.ion b11sl.ll rutJ1cr than a specific item basis vi Fur the purposes Df ~ubparagraph (1ii)A Df this subsection (d A. If II vi•~I or t.:81 property of the t:J.xpayer is leased under two or mon: lc11S1.'1 1;urngrnph (iii)A. i. shall, al the election of lhc lllXfllly~r. b" 11wlwJ w ll'Ca\Jng all lc:isl't.I JJOrciuns of s uch properly as &amp;gt;ubJl'Cl lo a 'ins;ll' ll'llllt 1u11I 8. At tht elec1.4&amp;lt;1n or lhe wcpayer. pardgraph (iii)A..L shall not apply w1Lh ni.pttt to real property or the taxpayo;r which has been in llltU for nlOn' Ulan fiv years An &amp;lt;!l&amp;lt;?ctioo under subsection A. or B or ~UblMfUl.'l'lllJh fiil) »fwlf !i maJe at !IUch time :UJd in SUeh manner th Miiyor p-crib hy rl!jl\llations. In the c:ll!U uf nny Mty IJCrtenl own&amp;lt corporation, unineorponued busm&amp;lt amp;ll, nr Jlllrlrter!ll1111. the ten thous:md dollar figure specified in ~ubs&amp;lt;.oeuon (J)(1) sh111J be 1ncrcastod by the les~r of: i. F'1rte n thownnd tlolbr:s, or ii. The tnl(&amp;gt;rest piud or accrued dtuinic t he taxable Y on invei&amp;lt;tllll'11t 111tleht!'tln~1&amp;lt i11cu rred 11r continued in connection v.•ith thu 11et1ui~1ti1Jn 11r the int~ri:btb in bUCh cvrpurution, unincol'J)tlrated buRi11e~s. or rm rt n11r~hi11. I n the c:llle or n ~epl\rnte retiirn by a married individual, seven tho11~an1I rive humh•otl dullt1rij ~hull be &amp;gt;Ju b~titutcd for the fifteen thuu$und &amp;lt;lLJ llur figu rll in claU$e i·of tbis s ubsection B. Thi~ 1mr11i.:mph ~ha ll UIJfJly with r:o~poct tu indcl.au"lne~&amp;gt; only if t.lae U11C)l1.1ycr, hi~ R])OUKIJ, 11t1d hi~ or her children own fifty percent or more of Ll111 t.01111 vnluc o 11 11 clu~~c~ or 1:1wck of the corporation or fifty percent or more of nil capita l inl(&amp;gt;roests in the unincorporated lrnsinu~s or tJurtnu1·shi1i. as the case may be vi or tho purposeu of this ~ubparagraph (2 A. The l~ru1 'uet lnvcRlment l11conte' means the excess o f iJivc~tmcnl h1como over hwe~lllMll expenses. Il The term 'invClllmcnl incom m1:&amp;lt;1ns I, The r:ro income Crom inl.:1'11$\, dividends, rents and royalties. It Tl1P lll'Li&amp;lt;linrt· lt'rm 1-:1 11i1Ju 1.rni11 allribut:i.ble to the disposition of r&amp;gt;ruf"'rl held tor Ul\'l'iLinent and iil. All u111&amp;gt;unt l.n!llt.t.'6 1111dcr i.ections 12-1 gt ri'lating to gain (rum dispos1Lt0ru; of certain depreciable property) and 1250 (n:l11tmi; to i:•nn from d1Spositio11s uf certain depreciable realty) nf llic lntcrnul Ru,·cnuc ~c uf !\ISi gnin Crom w sale or exchu111(t of 11roperty "hicl1 1 1w1lher a capita.I asset nor property descnl&amp;gt;ed In sectu•m 12::11 of the inl(&amp;gt;n&amp;gt;al ltev-t!nue Code of 1!15-1 (l'l: l~tinl( lu pro11(:rty llR-d in the tr.tole or bu.~in s and involuntary convert.inn but only tn thf. e\tenl such income, g-.iln, and amounts art- 11111 tl•·nwd from th i:vntlu•t or a l r.ul or business. C. The te rm 11IVl'lltmcnt cl\l'l!n mcaru. the dctlu~tions allowable under suL.wctlOllll h1)(1 relating to ordinary 3.Dd nect!"SSllr bm;inesi&amp;lt; ex11cMl'lll 111 11)(1 t1.1 it rd1t ll lo n il anti fH:r.;Onal property l83 Law J-124 DISTRIC'l'm' COL.Ul.IBIA STATLTES AT LAR(;E Law 1·124 taxe a)(S relating to lrnd deut a)(7 relnti ng to depreciation or (aK12 \!fating to nontntuc r nonhu~iness eKpcn.•es) CJf section 8 of Till llJ of this Act directly connected wittt the production of investment in~ome. For Lhe purpnses or this suhparai;raph (2 the deduction allowable with respect to gt property under sul.osection (a)(7) of section I ofTitic 111 of this Act may be treated as tho amount which would have been alfowalJle bad the l3Xpayer U~preci:'\ted the p roperty under th~ straight line 1nothod for each taxable y~ar of Its useful life for which the u1xpayer bas held the property. 0 The wrm 'investment iut.erest rnenns interest paid or accrued on indebtedness incurred or continued to purchnse or carry property held for invt'SUnent E. The term 'd isallowed investment interest' means, with respect co any la..xable year. the: amoum not allowable as a deductiou solely by reu~on of thu limil:ition iu 8ubparagmph (d)(i} of th~q s uhparagraph t2J 2) Subsection (3 rela tinit to the deduction for taxes D.C. Code, sec. 47-1557b(a)(3 i~ amended to read a~ follows 3) Taxes a) Exc.ept as olherwise provided in this $ection. the Followini taxes ~hat! Ix! allowed as u deduction for the t;1xablc year within which paid or accrued i) State and local taxes paid on real propcr cy, person11 I property or intang ibles, provided that the property or inurngihle is non·incomc producin1 ii) Stat.t: and local tuxes on income producini: real property, person:ll property or int.nngiules, but only to the extent that and in the ratio that. the income from the properly or int.Angibl~ is subject to luxation under this arlicle iii) State and local sales taxes iv) State and l~ ta.Y.e.q on the ~le of gasoline und other motor fuels v) The District tax imposed pursuant to su bscction (a) of section 303 of lhe Acl of Murch 2, 1962 (relating to the ta.x on deeds 76 St:tL 12: D.C. Code, sec, 45-723(11 vi) Effective (or uixable years beginning before January I. 1978. the Di~trict fee impo~ed p\l rsuani to suction !l of Title TV o( the District of Columbia Rt,•enuo Ac1 of 1937 (relating to the motor vehicle registr11tion feel (60 Stat. GS O.C. Code. see. 40·103 vii) State aud loeal caxe~ not described in th preced ing ~uhsection~ which arc paid or accrued within the ta.xaule year in carrying on a trade or business or lln activitv described in subparagraph (ll of subsection (a relating to the ded~ction for nontrade or nGnbusiness expenso provided that. no deduction s hall be atlowed on account of (i) the i.llx imposed under Title VTI (relating to the tax on corporations) or 'l'itle VUJ {relating to the tax on unincorpor.iled huRinesses) of thl&amp;amp; Act or (ii) s tate, local or foreign income taxes b) No deduction shsil be allowed for tho following iaxQs: 184 Law 1-124 (iJ Taxi~ the value u the deduct rnaiatena 111 (ii) T:ixe such. taxes (iii) Taxe, Act iv axes Code of 195. M Fcd~ra A. Thee of 1954 (rel Contrilluri, tJ l1u; L Re•cntHJ c. a11d railrou&amp;lt; C. The tu lnLernal Rth revenu Ju vi) Federal (\·ii) €sc.w viii) lnco1ni authorlty of an the taxpayer cl; of the loternnl h (c i} For the JlL property is sold dt A. Somuch part of su1•h Y• shall be ~at;&amp;gt B. So mu~h, part of su1·h ye: as a ti1.x impus ii) A In the 1 A Ulxp:i deduct any at 2) l'hc o tfi property tax) I I.ax year, lhr subparagraph the date oi ch. subsection C(i) taxpayt'r. Por I J)arty is liablo f the tim~ tho Uix Hahl for the re. 24 10 ion of tho lion .unt the fits spect ;olely this owini; h paid rt or income rsonal tlo t hat under r motor tion 303 Stnt. t'l: 197 the Dis trict. vehicle bscctions n a trade ubsection expense i he tax s) or Title L~ Act or Law 1·124 I WS OF Tm: UISTRICT OF OLUMBIA lll'11 LaYt 1·124 (i) Taxes n~sessed agains t local benefits of a kind lending U&amp;gt; increase the value of the property ai1sessed; but this panl{:taph shall not pre,•1.&amp;gt;nl the deduction or so much of s uch laxes as is properly allocable to maintenance or interest charges Ii) Taxes on real proper ty, to the cxt.ent that subsection (c) requires such taxes to be treatc-d as impost J on another taxpayer iii) Taxes taken as a credit unde r paragraph 5(a) of Title VI of this Act iv) Taxes im1&amp;gt;osed purs uant t-0 section 1451 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 (rulaling to tax·free covenanl bQnds and (v) Pederal in~ome taxc ir1cludini A. The tax (mpoi&amp;gt;cd by section 3101 of Lh~ In ternal Revenue Codt! of 1954 (relac.ing to the tax on employuu~ under the Federal lnti urancc Contributions Act B. The taxes imposed by St!Ctions 3201 and S2ll of the Internal Revenue Code of 195.1 (relating to the Laxes on railroail e11111loyees nnd railroad employee repre8cntatlves and C. The tax withheld al ~ource on wages w1dcr section 3402 of the lnwrnal Revenue Code or 1954 and corresponding provisions of prior revenue lawi vi) Federal war profits and excess profits taxes vii) Estate, Inheritance, legacy, s uccession and gift taxes viii) lncome, war profits and exc&amp;lt 8 profits Luxt!S impo~ed by the authority of any foreign country or possession or the United States, i! the taxpayer chooses to U•k" to any l'Xlcnt th~ benefits or ~ection 901 of tha Internal Revenue Code of 1954 (relating to the foreign tnx credit c i) For the purposes of s uu~ection (a) of this subparagraph if real properly is sold during any real prorerty tax year, then: A. So much of I.he re!ll property t.sx a.sis prnperly allocable to tb:it part of such year which onds on th~ day before the date of the sale shall be treated as a tax Imposed 011 lhe seller, and B. So much of the real pro11erty tnx as is properly allocable lo that part of such year which begins on u1e date of the sale shall be t reated as a tax impoAed on lhe plll'Chascr ii) A. Jn the case of any sale of real property, if 1) A l&amp;gt;l&amp;gt;epaycr may not, by re,1soo of his method of accounting, deduct any amount for wxes unleSli paid and (2) The other part to t:ie sale is (under lhe l~w impo~i11g the re.-tl prOJlerty tax) liable for thu real property tax for the real p roperty tax year, then for the purposes of subsection (a) of this subparagraph (3) the taxpayer shall be t.rcated as having paid, on tbc date of the sale, so much of the ma! property tax as, under ~ubsection C(i) of this s ubsection is treated us imposed o n the taxpayer. Fa r the purposes of the preceding sentence, if neither party r liable for the taX, then Lh party holding the proper ty a t I.he time the wx becomes a lieu on the pr-0perty shall be cun:&amp;lt;idered liable for the real woperty tax for the real properly taX yt:ar. 185 L:;w l· ll!4 tH~TltlC'T OF COLUMBIA !JTATUTr.S AT LAll(;E L:;w 1·124 S. SubAeclion (b)(il of lh1~ 11ubr111m rin1ph 1) shall noL apply to taxable ycnra end1nl aJ t1ir De1•emb&amp;lt;!r :11, 1976 but only in lhe case or aales 11Cter December 3t, 1976. c. In the CU&amp;lt ur s:ilc or real properly r the taxpayer's iaxable U1com11 ror the laicablc ycnr &amp;lt;lunng which thti sale O«Urs is computed under an uccrulll metlHJJ or accountitlg, anJ if no elt:et.ion uf\der section 46Ucl or the lni.m.il Re•enuc Code or l!fiH as or January I, 19'11 {rdallnit to thi! 1.Ct'ru&amp;amp;I or rtal property Ullll applies, then CK lhc purpose. o( SUbst.-ction (a) or this suhp:lr:lv:raPh (3 lhal portion or such tax v. h1ch 1 I• lift unclEr sut.ecuon (cl(i) or tbis subparagraph (3) ru. 1mpostd on the taxp;1ycr, a.nd nnt l\f lhl' l:\ lt;plt&amp;gt;'er's m€lhod or ;u~countmg l~u t lt;J b} tt t r ftH amp;U) caubJ IE tLJ k" C"C tc-J aa havmi: t.ctrued on ll1&amp;lt dut.c or th" s11le. Id) Wh~r u cor1&amp;gt;0rat1uo pay• a Wx 1m~ on 3 sha:rt-hulder on his th~~\ 1.~r' t.vidct a.hc.l v. l1trt U ti.a.r~l1•1ldcr does not rcimLursc the corp0r;allon, I.hen Ill The deduct.on allowed by aubs,-coon (a) of lh11 snbp:irsg:raph UI) shall be 11llowed 10 lho COl'llOl'lltlun; and (ii) No dt-Ouctlon shMll be ullowed t.O the ~hareholder for such w.x e) For the purµoijes or 1his subparab'Tl!(lh (3 ii Tho term personnl 11ro1ierly tax' mcuns an ad valorem u x which tR mpobed un nu 11nnual nsiM in reilpecl of personal property 1l)A The I.Nm '11cncrol ~alcij wx' means 11 mx impo,ed at one nue 1n rcKpucL ur tlic 8t1le 11t rct.all of n llroad nmg~ of classes of iLem B. In the cnse o( items of food, clothlni medieal supplies and moLOr vehiclcti I. The ~11\'l thnl the tm, do~s not npply in r«vcct of some or all of su\'11 it.oms Mho.11 nut I&amp;gt;&amp;lt taken inw account in t.letcrminln[( wl1elher the tftx applies In respect or a broi1d rani:e or classes of items, nnd II. Th~ ract thnt the rnw of tax applicable in respect of some or All uf such items luwt:r thun the i;:eneral rnte of U&amp;lt;X $hall not be taken Into .ircou11l in tletcrminmll' whe1her thl' tax ii imposed st one n.U C x«pt m the cue ot a lower rate or applicable in respect of a.n item ducnbed in •Ubpangraph (ii)ll of this sub.~eetion (c no clecluctt0n 1h~ll be allowed under thu. dubpan~ph (3 or 1an) general nlca Utx 1mpo.et.l m peel o( an iL&amp;lt;!rn at a rate other than the jftnCral ralr or tAA 0 A COmJK:nsating u..e tax 1n r~-spect or :in item shall be 1.re:ncd u a ge1 ral le~ UUt For the purpo11es of the p~ seni.ence the term 'compen..atmg use tax' means, in respecl of any item, a~ which. I. Is impoaed on the UM II.Ora or consumption of the item, and 1116 L111 II (1; l'l JcJuc11o111 bulJ at rt't il~n1 r \ l• po IU» UI th" fun-i:1111 F ,\ furt'1i a fo t~O C\iU C If the 141 or r~lm u fXttnt that th t han 111 cunn1 klll'r, 111 im. the co1uium r i!l) Sub liun t'll tr \11 n•I tU &amp;lt l ti I u r t'llKOll i.,11wt (111 he lutll l&amp;gt;t• com111.·n~Jt&amp;lt;:d for h1 h) Tl1l mouui I lll\M!Jit' Y r hvJu1 for mcd1cul c11r1• ur dcf1111•d In ~ubs 11erc~111 nr ll1i• 1111, 11 Iii) An amoum cu onc·li:t1r oJ' chc Jl cun.:srn uc s 1111·1ffc:t1 dr1~·11J11nts h) Amuunt.1 fMi l 111 lbu t for tl11 ulr.i~cciui J11tlucuo11 undl'r i1ub:s lhMl tilt' Bl:ll"'ltlll\' of l:rO~lli lltt'UOI\" lt)(1I for lht· 1111.,iu of Lii\• IJUJl:&amp;lt r "h1 •h J &amp;lt lll'flt Wl{lllllllll ti It I l~ated u p:11tl II\ 111, 1 htJ lr f•l1 It Olht'r Di.tm t or &amp;lt ul 14'Q!,1&amp;lt l"IWI&amp;lt of th1 I" 1llu11 tJ1t' ltm d lh«r t f1I~ A A "Wh·n•"nl lkJuu1011 011 Ull\ UI B A r of tl1 1 d,.Juci.on ,111 •11 1-124 ply to .e case :axable mput.ed under January then 3 that .ph (S) as countinll e treated der on his reimburse ragraph (3) such tax. tax which rty. 1 al 0 11e r.&amp;lt;te of items. supplies and f some or all determining of classes of ct of some or shall not be is imposed M a.b\e ln resvect bsection (e no h {S) for any rat.e other than shall be treauid eding aent.ence, uuy item, a ta t ion of the item, Law 1·124 LAWS OF THE Db"TRlf:T Ot" COIJ!M81A 1977 Law l-124 ii. Is complcnientJtry to 11 general saltos lax, but nuly if :1 deduction is alluwablv undor sulJ lt;·lion (a)(iii) in res1i&amp;lt;.oet of itemi olcl at r\'tail in thCJ wxilig jurisdiction which are ~i111ilar lo such itern. E. A stale or local lax includes onl.v a tax im1}0sed by a ij(ate, a poos ssion of th Unit.cd States, a µol itiml sutidi"isioo of ithe1· uf the foregoing, or by th~ JJislrict. F. A foreign tttx includt'l; only a tax impo8Cd by the 'tu\hority of a foreign couotry. G. lf the amount of any general Rules m x or of any tax on the salu of g~oline or other motor fuel j sepa rately staled, then, Ul thu extent. that the amount so stntod i~ paid by t.he consumer (othorwisv than in conrtectfon with thu consumer's trade or bu-ioe&amp;gt;kl) to his scllP.r, the amount shall be treated o.s u w imposed on and paid by the c.onsun1cr.11 (3) Sub$ectfon (9 relating to the deduction for mc-dical, dental and other xpeMesJ (lJ. C. Code, sec. 47-1.S57b(a l is ameml~d to read u• follows: u(!l fodieal. dental ;111d oth1·r ex1w·11scs a) There s hall lie a llowed 11s a dcductiuu the following amounl.S, nol compensated for loy insura.ncli or olherw iRe i) The amount by whkh the mnoun t of the expenses pail during th~ tax:1\ole year (rcdu.:ed by ~ny amounl dedudilolc under suhp;1r11graph (ii) for medrcal care of the tax(ltlycr, his or lier ~fJ'IUSc, and depen1J nts (rui dufined in ~uhsecLion (u) M secUon 4 of 1'iLlc I of thi~ Act) exc~~ds thrt&amp;gt;c 1x:rtenl of the udju,a~"I gro illcumto, and (ii) An amount (llot io excoss of ou~ hundred rifLy dollar equal to onc·ha.lf uf the cx1&amp;gt;enscs 1•a1d during the t.axalole :l"'ar for inRurancc which cnn,;tit.ut.eo m~llical c·a.re for the taxpuyer, his or her RPQUl&amp;lt;A aurl depondents hi Amounts p·.tid during tht taxable year for meJjcine ami drug which (but For thiR s ul&amp;gt;sect.ion tbll would be taken into nccount. in comJ&amp;gt;U tini: the d&amp;lt tluction under hUb~Lion (ll):ihall Ix' lakc11 into ar.count only t.o th&amp;lt P.xu•nl that t.11e ui:i.:regalA of t.hoge &amp;lt;imount.:i exccc&amp;lt;Jg one percent of tht.&amp;gt; aclj~tcJ ~o&amp;gt;s int'f•me c)(i) For the purpo•es of subi;c;:llon (n ex1&amp;gt;P.11ses Cor the mt lt;lical care of lhe taxpayer which a re paid out of his &amp;lt;&amp;gt;r lter o~tak •luring the 1)11C lt;'1lr period l&amp;gt;egmning wiU1 the day after the dulc of bh; or her dcatl1 s hall I treated a~ µaid hy the taxpayer at Lite time incurreu lii) P:1ragra11h (i) shrLll not apply if the amount p~l1I is cl:1irncJ on any other Di~trict 11f Colunihi:t l&amp;lt;tx rclurn u~ a dcductiun in 1·11mpuling t.he taxul&amp;gt;le Cijtute of th1&amp;gt; decedent, but Uois parugrarh shall not t1pply if (within the time and in the mann•:r an1l form prescrihed l&amp;gt;y th&amp;lt ll'layM) thcrv is filed: A. A statcmem lliat ~uch amounL ha~ not l&amp;gt;L&amp;gt;en a llowvd llS a ded uct ion 011 nny QLher Oi:it.ricl of C11l11moi11 tax ri;turu nnd B. A waiver of the rit:ltt to lta \'e such amount a llowP.d at UL1y time as a deduclinu on flny other Di~trict of Coluonl&amp;gt;ia ttL'{ return K7 Law 1-124 OISTltlCT m· COLUMlllA S'l'ATlll't.'S AT l.\RGt: Law J.124 (d) F or the purposes of lhis subsectiun (9 i) The term 'medical care' means amounts paid: A. For the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment or prevention uf disease, or for U1e purpose of nf(ecti1\1' any s tructurt• or function of tho budy, B. Por transporllltion primarily for anrl e~11ential to medic(ll car~ reforred to in subparngi-aµh (n or C. For insurance (including amounts paid M premium~ under part B of title X VH I of the Social s urity Act relating to supplementary medical insurancl! for the aged) con:ring medical cur~ referred to in subpuragra11hs A and B ii) In the casi; of an insurance contract under which amount.&amp;lt; are payable for other than medical care referred to in subpar~graphA A and B of subparagraph (i) of thiA sub$ection (d A. No nmount sh111l be treated as paid for insurance to which parai(raph (i)C. applies unless the charge for the intiurancc is ciU1er separately stated in the contracl, or furnished to the policyholder by the insurance company in a scparatu statement, K"The ~mount wkcn into account as the amount paid for the insurance shall not cxceeJ the tharge rnJ C. No amount shall be treawd as paid for the insurance if the amou nt specified in the eontract (or furnished to LhP pulicyhulder l&amp;gt;y the insurunce company i11 a ~eparate s1ateml·nt) as the charge for the insurance i~ unrca~onalJly large in relation to the rot11I charge.&amp;gt; undtr W\e e-0ntrnct. {u0 Subject to the limitations of subparagraph (ii premiums paid during the l:1xablc year IJ.Y a bixpay~r before he or shP atlllins lhe ag~ of sixty-five for ins urance covering medical care (within lh" meaning of subparagraphs A. and B. of subparai:truµ h (i for the taxpayer, hia or h~r spouse, or a rlepcnclenl nfter the taxpayer BtlainR the age of sixty-five shall be treated a~ expenses paid during tlie w xable year ror insurance which coM titu k medicil.l car~ if 1iremiums for the insurnnee are payable (on a level paym~nL basis) under the contract fo1· a period of ten years or mon: o r until the yea r in which th~ 1axva.ver attains the aRe of sixty· five ihut in 110 ca~e for u period or less lhlin fi ve ycursl iv) The determination of whether an individual i~ married :it any time during the t.uxablc year sha ll IJe mac.le as follows: A. The st-.itus as husband and wife of two individuals IU1\•ing taxable years beginning on tbc ~amc dny shr1ll be determined: i. If both hnve the same taxable year, as of the close of such year; and ii. If one dies before the close of tile taxable year of the otl1er, as of the time of su~h dealh. B. An indi1·idual who legally separated froro hi or her i,pouse under a decree o f divorce or of separate mai11tcnat1tc shall not be consid.ered as marrfod e) Any cxpen~e for household and dependent cai·c 5hall not be treated as an expense paid for medical care 188 Law 1-124 LAI Subsection (JO mnmtenance paymei (5) Effective for before January l 197 an,d dependent care&amp;gt 18) Household 31 such amount was ded of 1954 on .Tlinuarv household and de~n• provided, that the r eq1 shall not be applicnblE (c) Section 2 Qf Titlt\ amended to read as foll f) l .Every unincorpo o~ bu.smeos within the District within the meai $l2,000, regardless of 1 by tho taxpayer or uixi (d) Title VI (relating tu 47·1567) Is amended as fo l) Sectlon 5 (relatini; is am~nded by adding .1 c i) In the t·a includes as a member a llowed as a credit aga an amount equul ro ~i by an individua I durini allowed excl1ed the nm&amp;lt; subsectio11. Iii) The aruaunc uf ny taxable year wl1t (1) shall nor exceed; A. Two thousano respect to the taxp: B. F'our thou Run individuals with re iii) Except !Is oth the employmeitt·relate. may be taken Into nee• A. In the case of~ taxable year, the ind B. fn the ca~e of ixable Year, the less. lllCOme of his or hur (iv) In tho ca~c of a s for the Purposes of sul.ip 1-1 :24 on or :if the l cnro 1;ar t 'nmry l to in ,ts a r" A and which eilher der by or the amount by the for the sunder ms pa id the agll anini: of is or her Lxty·fh•e surance payable n year.&amp;lt; of ~uxt any t ime g taxable 11ch year; other. as e r ~pnu~e ll nol be be Lroated Law 1·124 I.A ws OF TB£ DISTRICT or COLUMBIA 1!1'77 Law 1·124 (4) Subsection (10 relating to the deduction for alimony and separate maintenance payments) is he reby repealed 5) Effeclive for taxable years beginning after December 31, 197 4 but before January 1, 1977 subsect ion (18 relating lo the deduction for household and dependent care services amended oo read as follows 18) Household and Dependent Care Services. To lhe same extelll that such amount was deductible unuer section 214 of the Internal Revenue Code of HIS4 on Januu ry l, 197.S, nny amount expended by an indh•idual for household and dependent car &amp;lt Aervices ncct-.ssary for l\'ain ful employment; proviucu, that the requirement tha t married couples file a s ingle return jointly shall not be applicable c) Section 2 of Title V {relating to r elUrnR 0 .C. Code, sec. 47· 1564a(f ill amended t.0 read as follows O Every unincorporated business engagmi: in or carrying on any trade or business within the District o r teceivins: income from ~ources within the Dis trict withiu the meaning of Title X and having a gross income of more tha!l $12,000, regardles~ of whethe r it has a net income. The return shall be made by the trucpayer or taxpayers liable for lhe payment of the tax d) Tille Vl {relating lo the tax on residents and aonres;denls D.C. Code, sec. 47-1567) i~ amended as follows 1) Section 5 (relating to cr·edits again~t the tax D.C. Code, sec. 47 ·1567d} i~ amended by adding a new s uusection (c) tll read as Collnws c i) Tn the case of an individual who mainiains n household which includes as a member one or more qualifying individuals, the re shnll be a llowed as a credit aga\m; t th e tax irnposerl by thi~ tit le for the taxaille yea r an amount equal to s ix percent of the employment-related e){pensos pa.id by an individual du ring the \&amp;lt;txable year, but in no event s hall the credit a llowed exceed the amount or tax oth~rwiRe due without prderence to th L~ subS gt;&amp;lt;:lion ii) The amvum of the cm(lloymen t related expense~ incurred during uny taxable year which may be taken into account under subpara.c;raph (i) shall not exceed: A. Two thousand dollars if th~re is one qual!fvini indi,.idual with respect LO the taxpayer for s uch uixohle year, or B. Four thousand dollar;s if t here are two or more qu11lirylng ladi\·iduala wit h respect to the taxp:i.ycr for such taxable year ill) Except us otherwis~ provided in thi~ subsection (c the am(lunt of the employmcnl·related expenses incurr1 lt;l during any uuable yllllr which may be taken into acrounl under sabpurngraph Ii) shnll not exceed: A. In the cuse of im individual who ii; not married at the close of the taxable yeur, the individuul'i; earned inwrf1e for the year, or B. In the case of an individual wt10 is married 11t the dose of the t:a.'Ulbie year, the lesser o{ I.he individual's earneu income or the earned income of hL~ or her spouAe for lhc tAK3ble yea r i\ In the Cllbe o r a spoIDic who is :1 udent or qua lified indi1:idual, for the purposes of subparagraph (iii) the spou~e shall bu deemed for each 189 Law 1·124 DLSTl!IC1' Of COLUMHIA STATt;T£S AT LARGo: Law 1-124 month during which h&amp;lt or she 1s a (ull·timu sludem al un educational inatilution or is u quv.lifymi indivlduul lO lie gamfully employo:d a11d to hav\! earned income of nol loss lhan: A. One hundred ~ixty·$IX dC1llar.1 if s ubsc.'Clion (ii) A. applies for !Jle taxable y1:ar. or B. Three hundred thirty·three dollal'!i if ~uhsection (ii) B. apµlies for the tanble y~r. In iliu cn'IC of any husb:iud ml wife, this paragraph shall apply with respect t.o only the 6pouse for any one month v) For the purpoiro:i, of this subsccllon (c An individual shill! be lreated W&amp;gt; malnt.Bining a hous~hold for any period only If over hall the cust uC utaintaining I.he how;ehold for the period is furnished by the mdividual (or, if tht&amp;lt; in•foidual is married during such periuJ, is funlii!hed by his or her spousl B. If the taxpayer is lllllnied at th" close of the taxable year. th&amp;lt ci:e&amp;lt;tit shall be allowed under subpar.igraph (l) only if I.ho: taxpayer and his or her spouse Cil~ a JOmt return or i;c1&amp;gt te rutun1~ on a combined fonn for lhe taxable year. C. An individual lega.lly separated from his or ht'r spouse under a tli!cree or divorce ur of $ep11r11tc malnwnanL~ shall nul be considered l•ti married vi) If: A. An i11tllvidual whn Is murri1:d and whu riles a separate return i) Maintnius n~ hii; or her home n househ&amp;lt;ild wltlcl\ constitutes !or more thun nnc~hulf o( the 1.11xablc year Lhu principal place or abode of 3 qu11hf ying i11dividur.I, aud (ii) F'urnishoti over h11lf of the cost of maintaining the ho1&amp;lt;sehold during the taxnlJle year, und B. During lhe last i;ix monthi; of the taxaiJle year the individual's spoust! is not n member nt lhu hou~el\ofd, lhe indiviouul shull not be considererl as m1.1rricd vii) rt: A. A child (i.11 i son, stopison, d:oiughter or stc1"1aughtcr) who b; un~er the n~e of fifteen 11r who i~ physic11lly l)r mentally incapable or cllnng for htm~l:lf or beri;clf receive$ o~·er hulf of his or her support during the calend!ll' yel\r from his or her parents who are divorced under a decree of divorce or leitally separated under a written separation 11greumclll, and 8. Such child is ht the cuslOdy of one or both of his or her parenl&amp;lt;i for more than one-hall of lh~ caknd.1r year, in lhe case of any taxable year be&amp;amp;mninrr m the Cllleodar yc11r the child &amp;gt;&amp;lt;hall tic treated ti being 3 qualifying individual with ri:~pecl w that parent who bas custody for a longer VCriod dunng lhe C3Jendtar year than the Otht:r pan!nl ind shall not~ treated us lieinK a 11ualifylng individual wi1h respoc~ ta the other parent viii) A. Except u providt.od in subst tion B. nq credit shall he alluwed under i;ubll~tion C ii for any .irnouut paiJ by th&amp;lt taxpayer ta an individual beuring 11 relationt1hi11 lo the wx1&amp;gt;ayer dcsen"bed in p:iragr.Aphs 190 Law l· l 24 (I) lhrnui:h (rel:umg to pj:lragruµh B. Subk Lu on md1 taxpayer his or her 1 tt1on (relating t• St:n·ic emplormcr, Re1·enul' C Ix) For th&amp;lt; A. Tl1 to Ii) A 1k with rwp. seeuo11 Ir 11 d incapable (iii l'he mcnU11ly IJ i for the rullo· enuble Lho r.a there are J o1 (AJ EJ B) Ex (ii) Empt 1) which ar, ghall be t.ak, indh-1dual d. C. Th l&amp;lt;'rn cnltJntlnr 11111n1 cducutionul or, D. The ter1 1nsutulio11 whi1 and normully h at 1111! plA1 J Section IS ll'l'l.11 47-1567g) hi amc11d.,1J A. Effective for •ubsec:tion (al(~J uf read 33 lollowa 12) 1'he perccn• this •u~tion fo following tabl pr hundred dollar 1-124 -tional gt;nd to :or the lies for a graph for itnY for the married ·ear, lhe ayer and .ombim:d under a. Jnsidered return utes for o 1budc household dividual'1; all not b er) who is cupable o f er ~upport re divorced n \VriUen he r parents any taxable d as being custody for parent, and spcct to the U be allowed payer to an paragr:iµh:s Law 1-124 LA w~ OF Tt!h! DISTRIC'r OF COIJlllffilA 1977 Law 1·124 (1) through (8) of cction 152(a) of the Internal Revenue Corle of 1954 (rclnting to the definition of dependent) Or to u dependent described in parngraph (9) of such section l!\2(a B. Subsection A. shall 11ot apply to ttny amount .Paid by the taxpayer to an indh'idual wilh respect to whom, for the taxable year of Lhe t11xpnyer in whkh the service is performed. neither the ta.xpnyer nor his or her spouse is entitled to a deduction under the provisions of subsection (e) of section 151 of the Internal Revenue ode of 1954 (rel;;ting to the personal exemption for dependents but only if the servic~ with respect to which the amount is paid constitutes umployment within the meaning of seclion 3l21(b} of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 Ix) For the purposes of this subparaA'raph (cl: A- The term 'qunlifyini: individual' means i) A dependent of the taxpayer wli&amp;lt;&amp;gt; is under the nge o{ fifteen and wit.h respect to whruu the l.:lxpnyl·r is etitiUed to :1 dedut·tio11 unde r section 15l(c) of the lntenml Re\'~nuo: C-Odc of 1954 ii) A dependent pf the taxpayer who is physically or mentally mcapable of caring for him,;clf or herself, or (iii) The spouse of lhe tllXE&amp;gt;ayer, if he ur she io physically or mentally incapable of caring for himself or herself. B i) 1'hc tum 'employmcnt.-relal.:d eiqmnses' m ans amounts 113id for the followinJ expen~e but only if the expenses are Incurred lo onuble the t.axpaycr to be g;uofully ~mployc&amp;lt;l for any period for which th&amp;lt;:rt! are J or rnore qualifying illdiviJuaJs will1 resp«t t-0 the taxpayer A) ExpcMes for houtichold services ind 3) £xve11ses fo1· the care of a q ualifying individual ii) Employment-rul(1ted expenses ns described in subparagraph ll i) which ara incurred for services outside the taxpayer's household HhaU bl! taken intu accounlonly if inc11rreil for the care of a qualifying Lndividual dcSfrihed in s ub1mragr.iph (\•iii) A. C. The term 'student' means an individual who during cnch of five calendar months during the taxable year i~ a full-time studenr. at 110 cd1.1cationnl organi,.ation. D. The term 'educational organiiation' meanA an educational illlltitutlon which normally maintain~ a rel!Ul:ir faculty anol curriculum und normully h11~ a regularly ori.:anized l.&amp;gt;ody of students in attendunc at \.he plucc where it• educational &amp;lt;IClivitics are canied on 2) S.:ction 8 (relatini to lhe credit for property taxes D.C. Code, 11ec. 47-1567g) is amended ns follows: A. Effective for taxable years b€giJming aft.er December lH, 1977, subsection (a)(2) of section 8 (D.C. Code, sec_ 47·1667g(n)(2 is amended to read U$ follows 2) The pnn.-entagc requirt lt;l by panl rapb (1) to be detcrmlaed under this subsection for r.a:qmye rs shall be lh~ percentage specified in the following table, provided howeve r. that the credit shall not exceed fou r hundn.-d dollars. 191 Law 1·124 DISTRICT OF COLUMJJlA STATUTES AT LAR()E L:i.w 1·1&amp;lt;!4 Ir household 1,ri·oss i11t-om1i is: The percentage of the real property tax paid or rent corisLituting the real property ta.x, which shall constitute the credit is: Under $3.000 95 per cent um of tax in excess of 2 per centurn of income 3,000 to $4,999 90 per centum of tux in excess ofil per et&amp;gt;nLUm of income 5,000 to $6,999 85 per cent um Qf tax in excess of 4 per ccntum of income 7,000 to $10,000 80 per centum of tax in excess of 4 per cent.um Qf income B. Subsection lbl(5l!Al !U.C. Code. sec. 47-1567tb){511A.l1 is amended to read as follows S)(A) The term 'r ent paid' is that amount paid by or on behalf of a cJaimant to a landlord solely for the rig ht of occupancy of a home in the District, including the right to use lhe personi\I property located the rein. Utility charge$ may be included in the amount of rent paid if they ani included in the amount pa id to a landlord in connectiun with the right to occupa.;cy Rem pa id' does not include: advance renuil Pf•yments for another period; rental deposits, whether or not expressly set out in the rental agreement; a ny charge~ for m~dical St!rvices or food prt&amp;gt;\'ided by the landlord; or paynu:ntti marte Lo a lsmllord for the right of oc.:upancy of property whicl; is exempt from DisLrict n•a l property taxes B) The t&amp;lt;:rm rent constituting propc l'ty tmces accrued' means 15 per centum of the rent paid in any calendo.r year by a claimant solely for the right of occupancy of his home in the ca lendar year. and which constitutes the basis of a claim in the succeecling ca lendar y~ar for n credit for pro]Jerty taxes paid C. Subsection (e D.C. Code. sec. 47-1567g(e Is amended to read as follows e)(l} Beg inning with ca lendar year 1977 and for each succeeding calendar year, if a daimllnt owns and occupies his home in chc Dis trict on December lH of a11y such yea r µ roperty taxes accr ued meima real property taxes (exc lusive of special a~s~sment.s, interest on a delinquency in pa}•ment of tax, and any penalties and scn•ice charges) as reOecled on the Di&amp;gt;1trict real estate tax bill ordinarily sent out in $opt.ember of such year If a home is an integral part of a lar"er unit such as a multipurpose building or a mulii-&amp;lt;lwelling buildinit, properly taxe$ accrued shall be that percenmge of the total prQperty taxes accrued as the value of the home bears to the tot.al valu1: of the property 2) When s clnimtint owns or rents t wo or more dirfcrent homes in the District m the same calendar yClll property taxes accrued or rent constit uting property tnxcs accrued' shall be based on che claimMt's status as an o'vner or renter on December 31 of ~uch calendar year 3) When a claimauc rents two or more d ifferent homes in the Dis trict in the same calendar year, rent paid by the cluimanc during that year 192 Law 1-124 LA sh.a ll be deter agr~ment in during that mulliplyiug ti 0 Subsection (I la.o;t two sentence Any claim f uxpiration of t limitations shall year for wh ich 1 £. S ubsection (j phrase "except tJ househc)Jd income by inser ting n p, precedes the word F. Subsection ii G. Subsection (l follows m) A claim:\ substantiate th H, Subsection (1 (e) Section 6 of Ti rcde~ignating subsecti b) to read as follows b) Failure to fi l~ under this tm .icli' to rnade under authori1 any information for ]Jay or collect ~uch w s uch information, sl guilty of a misdeme dollars or imprisooed under this ~ection ~r Columbia on au info Columbia or oue of I f) Section 1 of Titl~ amended by deleting 12,000 Sec. 50 l. Section S appro,•ed Jun1i 29, 191 follows e i) Tl1e Mayor for ~olid wa.,ste cnll11e be lice!llied sep:iratd. 4 ed f he in. are to for the by cy per for hich or a g trict real es ed ru; es in 'rent ant's year. istricl year Law 1·124 LA ws or TllE Ull&amp;gt;ll!ICT OF COLtnIBIA 1977 Lnw 1·124 shall be dcwrmined by dh-iding the rent paid pur.1uant l.o Lhu last rental agreement in force during that ca.lcndar year by the number of months during th:it calendar year for which thi rent was paid und by mulLi1&amp;gt;lyinl{ the result by twelve D. Subs~ction (h D.C. Code uc. 47·Hi67g(h i~ amended by ~lrikinJ the last two SP.nlenccs and inserting In lieu thi&amp;lt;rcof the following Any clnlm for credit ~hall bu tiled with the District on or b&amp;lt;'forc the expirntlon of lhe three year SUllulQ of limitations. The statute of limitntions shall commence to run on April 15 of the year following the year for which the claim is made E. Subsection (j D.C. Code, sec. 47-lfm7g(j is amended by striking the phrase "except l.here shall be excluded from the computation of gross household income the first one thousand dollar earned by a dependent" and by inserting a period aft.er tho word "household" which imm~diatcly precedes thu word "except F. Subsection 1 l O.C. Code. sec. 47·1{16'1,:i( l) is reocaled. C. Sub~ection (m D.C. Code ec. 47· l 567g(m is amended to read as follow m) A claimant whose cl~im is bu~ed on the amounl of rent.1miu $hall substanlialc the re,nt paid upon n request by the Mayor H. Subsection (p D.C. Code, sec 47·1567g(p is repealed e amp;etion 6 of Tit.le XTil (D.C. Code, sec 47·1089c) it&amp;lt; amended by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (e) 1tnd by adding a new subsection (b) to read WI follows b) Failure to file return or pay t.ux due thereunder. Any person required under this article to pay or collect ani• Ulx, or n'quired by law or regulations made under authority thereof to muke a return, keep any rcCOt'd ur ijupply any information for the purposes of this llrticle who shall fail or neglect lo pay or collect such t.~x. lo make such return nr keep such recoruij or lo gupply such infonnalion, shall, in addition to ulher penalties pro~icled hy law, be bruilty of a mis&amp;lt;lcmcanor and shall be fined nol more lhan lhr(!c thousand dollars or imprisoned for not more than six month or both. A 11 rrosccuticms under lhi~ st&amp;gt;ct.ion shall be brought in the Superior Court of the nistrict of Colu111bh1 on un !nformatioH by the CurtJOraLion Counsel for the Uistrfct of Columbia or out: of hfa or her assisl.aolS in Lite name of the District f) Section I of Till~ XIV (relating to litcnscs D.C. Code, sec. 47·1591) is amended by dele~ini 5,000" whe reve1· il npµca rs aml inserting in lieu t hereof 12,000 TITLE V. USF.:R CHARGES. Sec. 501. Section 8·3:G06 of Regulation 71 ·21 (Solid Waste Rci:ulations appro,·ed June 29, 1971, is atneoded by mcndinl subsection lo) to read as follows c i) The Mayor shall fix the license fees for solid waste collecwrs and for solid waste collecli&amp;lt;m vehicles. t:ach collector and collectio11 vehicle ~hall bu licensed se1)flrnt.ely. 19ll Law 1-124 DISTRICT OF COLU~IBI S'l'ATUTES AT l.i\RGE L.-iw t-124 (ii) The prescribed license fees for solid wMte collectors and their collection vehicles shall be submitted with the Uceru;c applications to lhc Mayor. Licenses iihall date from the first day of November o{ 1ch year and expiru on the 31st day of the following October, bul Uie fees th~refor may b{) prorated in Mcordancc with paragraph 5 of seclion 7 of th~ Act of July 1, 1!102 (0.C. Code, Sl'C. 47·2Jl05 iii) Each licensed collector, olher than al{ents or cmrloyees of lhe Di:;tricL Government, who disposes or solid wa~te al a disposal area owned or operated by or under conlrnct with the Oistricl sha ll pay a diapOtial fee of eight dollars for each wn or solid wa~le disposed, except that 11 minimum fee of two dollars shall be imposed on loads of Jive hundred pounds of wlid waste or les If a solid wa~te collector do~ nol pay lhu :solid waste disposal fee within one month of the bllling date, the collector s hall pny lO the Mayor, in addition to the fee, a late payment charge of one percent for each full month of the delinquency iv) No le!ls frequently than once every two ycar.1, the Mayor shall re(ommend to the Council of the Dislrict of Columliia a disposal foe and lulc paymenl chargu to be set by the Council or the tli~lrict of Colombia Sec. 1\02. The Mayor of t.he Dist.rid of Columbia is aulhori1.ed, aft.er a public hearing, lO cstabli~h from time 1.0 time a (e~ to be churi:ed for l rtan:&amp;lt;porlation sun-ices provided by Lhe Emerp;uncy Ambuh111ceServici: of the Fire Department in such amount as may be reasonable in consi1leration of the inrnrests of lhe public and the per~ons required to pay the fee, and in consideration of the approximate cos t of furnishing such i;en•lcei provided, that no one s hall be denied the services becuuse ~f hiti or her inability to pay and furtlier pro\·iJed that no ono shall be que~tionecl n1&amp;gt;out his or-her abil ity lo pay at the time the services arc requested. TITLE VI. AM.ENDMl::NT TO THE SALF.S AKD US T.-\X ACT Sec. 601. Section 148(a) of the 'District 11f Columliia Sales Tax Ac t, awrovcd May 27, 1949 Stal. 12;1; D.C. Code, sec. 47-2625(a is amended by deleting 00 and inserting in lieu Lli•!reo one thou~and dollu r!&amp;lt; or im1&amp;gt;ri..oned for nol more than six months, or lloth TITLE Vil AJ.lENnMJ!:NT TO ACT RF:LATlNG TO TRF. LEVYlNG ANTI COLLECTING or TAXES AN l) ASSESSMENTS. S~c. 701. Section G of the Act entitled "An Act Relating to the levyini mid collecting Of laxes and aSsessmenl and for uther purpnRPS approved June 25, tu38 52 Stat. 1200; D.C. Code ec. 47·110f1l is ~ndcd by striking the fir.&amp;lt;\ sentence the reof and inserting in lieu thercvf Lhe following new ~i;ntentc All asRessmen\ij authorized to be lovied by the Oi&amp;amp;tiicl or Columbia to reimbu n1e it for money expended in Lhe removal of nuis:l.l'lces ~hall bear interest al the rate of one and 011e-hal( perttnl per month or part lherevf from the dlltu i1uch asses~ment was levied 194 Luw 1-12-1 TITLE Vil AM E Stt. 801. T he regul promulgated under ut approved May 27, 19- amended as follows 11) Sec. S(c St'c. 6.8' ls amended by strikiu~ lieu thereof t11e wo rd b) Sec. f\(a)(2 Sl!c Re1,rulations) is amend lhereof lhe Cigure l (c} Sec, ll(b)(5J (S Rcgul:ilions) is amend· theteof t.he figure S:l Cd) Sec. 8(c){4)(b) 1S Rct,'Ulationll) i~ anwud. thereof the figure 6. TTTl.E Sl'C. 90 I U before Urut.cd Status ha"c fall, payment by the Cedern I ser\'ice, and sanitnrv Committee on i nanc-e or its succ~ssor comn resolution, by t.he Cou n Sec. 902 he Mayor s imultaneously with an~ atatement with supporti measu re or l;ill upon th• by the measure or aet. Sec 03. Ile.fore Mn1 Finance and RtJvcnuc at ~nnitary sewer ~rvict- r. mailed to con.ium.in Tl ns of the firs t day of tho 1 (l) for each billing ca1 Southwest, Norr.heast, culltom.,r.i, lou1l numl&amp;gt;&amp;lt;·1 wate r con;umed tif 111~1 thirty days) and 2) un certification shaU also l ti.,n;cc anti ewer $en•k1 total federnl co113ump110 and January I, 1977, inc Law 1-124 tors :md their !ications to the f each year and •B therefor may the Act of July •Sor tht! Dis trict area owned or dispoo;al fee of :hat a minimum po11nds of solid d waste disposal ay 10 the Mayor nt for each ft:\\ :he Mayor 3hall 10&amp;gt;\al foe an lute ,f Columbia d. after a public &amp;gt;r transporlutinn Fire Department i11t.1Jrests of the ~ideration of the no one 8hall be f urlher pro•·i1led y nt the time the TAX ACT ax Acl, apprO\'ed ended by delct:ng or imprisoned for ro THE :o the levying nnd a111irovcd June 25, striking the fi rs t new i;entencc: ct nf Colu mbin to i~ancc~ shall bear part the reof from Law 1-124 [,/\ WS OF rm: IHSTRICT 01" COLill!DIA 1971 Law 1-12-1 TITLE VIII. AMENDMENT TO CIGARF:J'TE TAX REGULATIONS. Sec. 801. The regulations perW.1ining to Dis trict o'f Columbin cigarette truces, promulgated under au thority of Lhe District of Columbia Cigare tte Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 6;J Sta\. 139; U.C_ Code, sec. 4'7·2808) urc here by amended as follows a) Sec. 5(c Sec. 6.3(d Chapter l Title 16 of the TI .C. Rules nn&amp;lt;l Regulntions) is umended \iy striking the word Jmie" wherever il a ppears nnd inserting in lieu thereof thu word "September b) Sec. i!(u)(2 Sec. 9.2(b Chapter I, Title lG o f the D.C Rule nnd Regulations) i~ amended uy striking the fig ure 1.00 and inserting in lieu the reof !he flg11r0 3.00 c) Sec. 8(b)(5 9.il{e Chuptcr I Title JG nf the U Rules and ltegulatioM) i~ amended by striking the fi1 1.lrC 1 .00" and inserting in lieu thereof the fi irurt 3.00 d) Sec. 8(c)(1)(b Sec l.4{d)(2 Chapter 1, Title 16 &amp;lt;tf the D.C. Ruic~ und Regulations) is amended by striking the fig11re 2.00" and inserting in lieu thcrt'&amp;lt;lf the figure 6.00 TITLE IX. MlSCELl..A lt;EOUS PROVISIONS. Sec. 901. If before Septembe r 2, 1977 tho Congress and the Prc~ident o( the United Stales hu\·e failed to enact legislal.ion which will provido for the advance payment. by t he fcdcnil government lo the Oi~trict of Columuia for wa ler, waler service, and sani~ry sewer service, then the MAyor sha ll &amp;gt;1ubmit lO the Committee on Finance and Rc."enue of tho Co uncil of the District of Colu mbia or iL; succes~or commi ttee a revised finnncial plan for the approvul, by resolution, by the Council of the llistric~ o( Columbia. Sec. 902. T hl! Mayor 11hall submit lo the Co uncil of the District of Columbia, slmultaneously with any proposed l'Cvenuc measure or proposed act, a dot&amp;lt;1iled statement wllh supporting dat.1 cor1cerning the direct and indirect impact of the measure or I.Jill upon those ta..xpayt&amp;lt;rs who will be dirc.clly or indirutly aff..cted by the mea"ure or act. Sec. 903. Before Muy 15, 197'7, lhe Mayor &amp;gt;&amp;lt;hall submit to the Comminee on F inance and Revenue a certifica tion lh:it all billings for water, water servic~ and sanit&amp;lt;1ry ~ewer •Cr viee for wa ter consumed pr1or LO November 1, l!l76 have lx:en mailed to con• umers. The certifict1lion shall include the followin g informa tion as of the first !lay of the month frum Septeml;cr 1. 1976 to May 1, \ 077, indusive 1) Cor e:icll billini: category (i_e priv11t.e and chnritabl&amp;lt Southeast and Southwes t Northeast, fl:o rlhwest City and Nor lhwe"t County n umber of cus tOrners, tolul number of bills mailed, toml number of bills nudited, hillalJle water consumed (if meters were read for the category duriug t he preceding thirty days) and 2) an e:&amp;lt;bmatc of the total nonbillnble alt·r consumed. The certification s hall also include the to tal revenue collected for wa ter, wmer service and sewer servictJ between Scplemlier 1, 197!1 and May 1. 1977, inclu~ive: totnl federdl COl\~umption and total District consumption uetwcc11 J uly l 1976 and J:tnuur y 1, 19"77, inclusi~e. Law 1·124 Dl!&amp;gt;"IRICT OF COLU~lBIA ~1'ATU1'E!S A1' l,All&amp;lt E Law 1 124 S~&amp;lt 904 a) The provis ions of this uct arc severable, an&amp;lt;l if any provision, sente nce, clause, section or part is held ill~gal, i11vulid. u~onstitu(ional or Inapplicable t.o any porson or circumstances, such illegality, invalidity, unconstitutionality or inapplicaliility ~hall not nffcet or imp:iir any of the rem;1ining provis ions, sentences, clauses, sections or parl.q of the act or their application to other pel"Suns or circutnst:mce It iii hereby declared to be U1e legi11lative intent that this act would have been adopted if such illegal, invalid, inapplicable or unconstitutionnl pro ~ision, scntenl do.use, section or part had not h&amp;lt en includl'&amp;lt;i herein and if I.he person or circu mst.·rnces to which the act or any µart is inaµplicable hlid beon speciffoa lly exempted b l'he repeal or amendment by thill act of any provision of law 8hall not affect any act done or any right accru ed or accruini under such provision or law before tho effccti\•IJ date of this &amp;lt;tel, or any suit or µrocecdinK had or comn mced, but till Mghts and liabilitic~ unde r such law shall continue and may be enforced in the b3ffiC manner :md to the same extent us if lhe repeal or amend ment had M t bee!\ made. Any act, suitute: or law inconsistent with the provisions of thi act are hereby repealed to the extent of such inconsistency. Sec. 905. The Muyor is hereby delegated the authority to an&amp;lt;l directed to promulgate r egulations implementing this act, but not inconsistent with thi~ act. Such regulations shall be issul&amp;gt;d in accordance with the Dis trict of Columbia Administrat.ive Procedure Act (D.C. Code, sec. 1·150l TITLE X. AMEN DMENT RELATING '1'0 TAXES O~ INSUHA.'JCE C01\lPA1\lES. Sec. 1000. Section 6 of Title lI of the Aet of August 17 1937 iO Stat. 676 (D.C. Code sec. 47· 180li relating to taxes on insurance companies) is amended to read as follows Sec. 6 a) All 8 UCh Companie including companies which issue annuity contracts, shall also puy to the District 0£ Columbia, for each calendar year, a sum of money iis taxes equal to two per centum o f thetr µolicy and membership fees and net premium receipts or consideration received in such ca lendar year on a ll in~urance and annuity conlractl! on ri~ks in the Dil:itricl of Columbia. S uch tax s hall bi! in lit!u of all other taxes except {1) taxes upon real estate and (2) foes and charges provided for by the insurance laws of the Dis trict including amendments made to such laws by tlli~ title Net premium recei1&amp;gt;ts or consideraLion received means gross prtmtiums or consideration rec11ived less the sum of the following: 1. Premiums received for reinsurance assumed and premiums or con~ideration rolurnc•l on policio:s or ronLracts canceled or not tnken. 2. Dividends paid in eash or used by the pulicyholdor~ in payment or enewal premiums. Nothing contained in this ~eetion or in sections 1Ol'7 of thi~ t.itle shall 11(lply with res1lect to m11rine !nsuran e written within the said Dis trict :md reported, 13Xed and licensed under the provisions of the Acl entilled An J\ct Lo regulate m.-rine insurnnce in t he Distr ict or Columbin. and for otl1er J&amp;gt;!lr(lOSCS appro,•ed March 4. 1922, as amfl!lded. 196 Law 1·124 (bKl) Th" ti. calendar year Mnreh of the 1 (2) Excep1 imposed for $hall be µaic tl1e month$ 1 income lo be to at least calendar yell company sh" pay the rem: the close uf t-0 the comp: tit the elecli&amp;lt 3) The in a1&amp;gt;ply in the ca lenJ.ar yea b~ paid 0 11 \&amp;gt; ralend:.r y.i c) TJ;e certi: to pay Ille U1~ Sec. 1101. This of $ection 602(c) o Reorganiza tion Ac1 a. Sections 10: a ppfy a fter Septt b. Section 30 I personal taxes becomhlg due a11 e. Title I\ ex. ca re) und WJ I apply with res1w. d. Seetiou 40 l apply with resp Sau.tee UM.lll to R~ur 1tnizi.lio11 Act. tPL \ S76 on riri1 and aiecorul t.ht! 11gn11.ture 1lf tlK' M publis hOO io th£&amp;gt; ftbrut• of Cungreu for llurt) Tht! Council\ 1h1t t1 re':icw ~rriod h iui £&amp;gt plr April 19. 1!171 1- t:IA &amp;gt;vision, Jnal or ·a\idity, of lhe J r the ir be ihc invalid gt;art had 1e act or .hall not 1ision of had or and may ·epea I or with the sistoncy. rect.ed lo i this act. Columbia Stat. 676 amended e annuity ndar year, olicy and ed in such District axes upon aws of the roiums o r miums or taken. aymenl or shall apply d reported, t.o regulate purposes Law l-12·1 LAWS 01 I'H E Dll&amp;gt;'TRICT OF COLUMIJIA 1971 Law 1-124 {b)(l) The Ul.X imposed by sul.isection (a) of this !le(;Oon shall, for each calendar year prior to calendar year 1977, be paid bl'fore the fin&amp;gt;t day or Marth of the next succeeding ~alend:ir year 2) Except as provided in oubsection (b I) o f t hib seetion, the ta x imposed for calendar year 1977 and for each calenu:ir year thereafte r slrnll be paid ln three installment~ on or before the first dny of eaeh of lhe months of May, July a.nd Septemher of the culendur year in which the income to be taxed is received. li:nch in~tallmcnl shall be M amount equal tu nt leas t 253 of the total t11.x liability determined (or lhe preceding calendar year. In ucc:ordance wilh rules prescriLed by the Mayor, each company shall determine its total tax liability for each calendar year and pay the remainder, if a ny, on or before the firnt da of March following the close of each c11lcndur year. O•·e rpaymcnts of tax mny be. 1·o f11nded to the company or c redi lt;:d to the company's nex t installmt!.nt payment, at lhe election of the company 3) The insw llment pnym~nt prnvision of ~ubsection (h)(2) shall not apply in the case of any company having a t.a.x liability for the pr~ceding calendar year Jess than t wo thousanu dollar Jn ueh c11ses lhe tax sha ll be paid on or be fore the firs t day of Mnrch following the close of the calender year c) The cert ifica te of authority of any t&amp;gt;mpany muy be revoked for failure to pay the tax required by this title J'TTLE Xl. EFFECTJVF. DATES. Sec. 1101. This aci shall become effective in uccordance with the pro,·is ions of section 602(c) of the District of C-0lumbia Self·Government nnd Go\'er11m~ntnl Reorganization Act, provi&amp;lt;led tha t: a. Sections lO l (a)(l relaling t.o t he motor vehicle rcgls trntion fee) shall apply after September 30, 1977. b Section 301 (relat ing to the l ima for pnymcnl of real prop&amp;lt;,rt rond pe rsona l i.axes) s hall apply with res~i to taxe:;i, or insrnll111enlS thereof, becoming due and payable after June 30, 1978. c. Title IV (except ~ections 40I(bX5 relating to lhe d~uctioo fl)r child care) and 40l(d)(2)A relating to e ligibility for the µropcrty tax cr~dlt) shall npply with respect to taxable yc:ir• beginning after Deceml&amp;gt;er ai. 1!176. d Section .101 (d)(2)A (rclnLing to e ligibility for the property tax credit) shall apply with respect to u.xablc year~ bel(i11ning afwr Dect!mb~r 31, 1977. Sou.rc4 Pursuu.nt to li~ction 2 o( the Di~crlcto( Colontbia s~tC·C&amp;lt;&amp;gt;\'Ct 1Unt&amp;gt;nt t1n1I Govtirnml•nui.I Rf'Or~tation Art PL !}.'\.l9dl, Lbt: Atl, Lhe CoUUC'il 11f tlle Oistrlt·l 1&amp;gt;f Col11Jr.l1iu ntlnptcd flill No. 1~16 on f'irst xnd scconrl rcadin Ot'Ct!n1ber:t. l916 i.11d m\&amp;gt;f r l 1976. l""Spttli\·cly. 1-'oUowu'\g. tllH wignnture of lht! Mnyor &amp;lt;Ill Jununr 25, 1971, thlK IC'j:tl,,li.tion was 1111111ii:i;1H1tl Art S°o. 1-Z:!ti, pubbsht.&amp;gt;d in the Pebruur JR. IU17. t 1.Ution uf the 0 C. R(~ltu+"r. nr.tt lnu111111Utt 1I to l)nlh Hou•t IJ( C.:ongr11 for. lbfrt 1J:ay (\'IVICW, fn i:u.oeordllute lh SE UOn r.rec.:xn '1( \lw AM Tiu Councjl 6f the OiSlri1:t &amp;lt;1C Cotun;bi:t bt.•relJ Riv gt; no~lcu chl\l tht hirty-1 lu) Coni:trt:-i ron:~I rei.·it-wvc.nod h:ut upiml u1.d, \hert'fu ciu.•it Ot ft&amp;gt;l \uwlng )C·l{i utiUJI a.s U.1 L 1-1 amp vffec;t i\'t' April 19, W71. 197</search-text>
  </meta>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>IX</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>902</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.61"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <section>
    <num>502</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-416"/>
  </section>
</document>
