<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-12">
  <num type="law">1-12</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1975-09-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-12.pdf">D.C. Law 1-12</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 1806</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-12 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-75, which was referred to the Committee on Higher Education/University of the District of Columbia. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 13, 1975 and May 27, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 13, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-18 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198)(the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-75 on first and second readings May 13, 1975, and May 27, 1975, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 13, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-18 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c}(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law No. 1-12, effective September 9 19 75 j J STERLING T-zKER Chairman olt~e Council 1 i I I i r g r f W r f~~t~11 E ff~Iffff iiii F f D. c. Law ~o. 1-12 In the Council of the District of Columbia September 9, 1975 To extend the effective dates of the District O'f Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act, and for other purposes. Be it enacted by the Council of the District of Colucbia, That this act may be cited as the "University of the District of Columbia Effective Date Act Sec. 2. It is the intent of the Council of the District of Columbia to approve the Congressional intent (expressed in section 102 of the District of Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act) to authorize a public land grant university through the reorganization of the existing institutions of public postsecondary education in the District of Columbia. It is the clear and specific intent of the Council that the University provide a range of programs and studies designed to reach the widest possible number of citizens and residents of the District of Columbia including career and technological education, liberal arts, sciences, teacher education, and graduate and postgraduate studies. Sec. 3. The District of Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act is amended as follows: {a) Section 20l(b) of that Act is amended by {l) I striking out "August 2, 1975" and inserting in lieu thereof 2 August 2, 1976, and (2) striking out "June 30, 1976" and inserting in lieu thereof "June 30, 1977 b) Section 20l(c) of that Act is amended by striking out "September 2, 1975" and inserting in lieu thereof "September 2, 1976 c) Section 207 of that Act is amended by striking out "June 30, 1977 d) Section 407 of that Act is amended by striking out "July l, 1975" each place it occurs in that section and inserting in lieu thereof in each such place "July 1 9 1976 Sec. 4. This act, including the amendments made by this act, shall be effective at the end of the 30 day period provided for Congressional review of acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 602 (c) of the D.istrict of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. t Docket for the Dill 1-75 Considered in Council 5/13/75 First vote 5/13/7 s RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE c;oum:tL t-U'.MUrll Yl:f; UO T'.n.,l'.0. IU\. 1 COIJl~Cll. MC"1Drl! YCS NO r.11. A.O A. i COUNC:IL r Tt 1 r r 1~ 1 u.u 1 1 i i 1 1 SP 1.tf--G 1 IX i~ X-lndicn1cr. Vote I R.-Prcscnt A. B.-Ab:.cn1 n. A.-ncndopted i~lui ct l&amp;lt;)tl \0 (Secretary of the Council) Final vote in Council 5/27/75 BARRY Y 1 'HOBSON Y I lw l x I _G.IAB.KE. x I Mf"'ll"'llH' T y i i I I I l""f"'l rc- X I ~H.arYTi="TON x I I !i I I I X-Inciica!er. Vote P. R.-Prcscn1 1 B Al-.se s R. A RC!'r.dc t~d Presented to the ayor 6/_2 7_5 Me yor•s ·action 1 J \975 approve: disapproves lSecretary of the Council) \. D tct-Q.L Secretary of the Council Signature) 1 S JUN 1975 Enacted without )1ayor•s signature Secretary of the Council) I Bill Docket 1-75 Pare Two Reconsidered by Council Vote RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE r i COUUC:IL MCM(lt:R YCS 'NO R -l~ j t COUNCIL MCMtlCR YCS NO r.1&amp;lt;.1A.D.11t.A. j COUNCIL Ml llEft I Yt:S NO 11'.lt.!A.n. 11.1 t 11 I I 1-I i 1_ I I i gt tndic111c~ Vose P. n.-Frcscn2 11 13.-h.bacnl R RcadopScd Submitted to the Congress -6-17-75 lt;llVLtlA Secretary of the Council) Senate action House acti.on resolution number resolution number Secretary of the Senate Clerk of the House Enacted with out Con~ressional action Secretary of the Council)</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
