<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-17">
  <num type="law">1-17</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1975-09-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-17.pdf">D.C. Law 1-17</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 1990</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-17 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-58, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 29, 1975 and May 13, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 19, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-23 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, PL 93-198 The Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-58 on first and second.readings April 29, 1975, and May 13, 1975, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 19, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-23, published in the July 28, 1975, edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 3 0-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law No. 1-17, effective September 23, 1975. D. C. Law No. 1-1 7 1. September 23, 1975 In the Council of the District of Columbia To define certain terms for all acts and resolutions of the Council of the District of Columbia, to provi&amp;lt;le for an enacting clause for those acts and resolutions, and for other pu.rposes. Be it enacted by t.'1e Council of the District of Columbia, That this act may be cited as t.'1e "General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975 Sec. 2. For the purposes of any act or resolution of the Council of the District of Colu..rnbia, unless specifically provided otherwise 1) words L~porting the singular include and apply to se\,'e_ral persons, parties, or things 2) words importing t.'1e plural include the singular; {3) words importing one gender include and ·apply to the other genci.er as well 4) worns used in the present tense include t.'Lie future as well as the ?resent 5) t.'1e words "person 11 and "Hhoever" include corporations, companies, association ir~s, partn~rships, http:genci.er -2 societies, and joint stock conpanies, as well as individuals 6 officer" includes any person authorized by law to perform the duties of the office 7 signature" or "subscription" includes a mark when the person making it intended that mark as such 8 oath" includes affirmation, and "sworn" includes affirmed; and (9 writing" inclunes printing and typewriting and reproductions of ~risual symbols by photographing, multigraphing, mimeographing, manifolding, or otherwise. Sec. 3 a)"Each act of the Council of the District of Columbia shall have an enacting clause only in the first section of each act and such enacting clause shall be in the following form Be it enacted by the Council of the Dis~rict of Columbia b) Each resolution of the Council of the District of Col u.rr.bia shall have a resolving clause in t.lie following form Resolved, by the Council of t 1e District of Col urnb ia c) Each section of each act or resolution shall be numbered consecutively 3 Sec. 4. For the purposes of any act or reso1ution of the Council of the District of Columbia, unless specifically pro•1ided otherwise a) The terr'.\ "Council" Means the Council of the District of Colw"Tl.bia established un~er section 411 of District of Colunbia Self-Govern~~nt and Governmental Reorganization Act b) The term ayor" neans the Mayor of the District of Columbia established under section 421 of the District of Colur.hia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act c) The term "Act" means an Act. of th.e Congress d) The term "act" means an act of the Council. Sec. 5. This act shall be effecti,re i.mnediately at t.'1-ie end of the thirty day period (e~ccluc'l.ing Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days on which either House of Congress is not in session) beginning on the date this act is submitted to the Congress, as provi~e~ in section hn2(c) of the District of Coln.T'Tlbia Self-Governrrient and- Governl'1ental Reorganization Act.</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.45"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.46"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.47"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.47a"/>
  </section>
</document>
