<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-23">
  <num type="law">1-23</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1975-10-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-23.pdf">D.C. Law 1-23</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 2091</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-23 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-47, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first, and second readings, and reconsideration of second reading, on April 15, 1975, June 1, 1975, June 24, 1975 and July 11, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 23, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-34 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF TEE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE ?ursuant to Section 412 of the Dis ict of Columbia Sel:f- Govermnent and Governmental Reorqani.Zation Act PL 93-198)(the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-47 on first and amended first readings April 15, 1975, and june l, 1975; on second read.L"lq June 24, 1975, and reconsideration of second :eadinc; on July ll, l97S. Followinq the signature of the Mayor on July 23, 197 this leqiSlation was assigned Act No. 1-34, pu.Ol shed in the Auqust 6, 19 75, edition of the 0. C. Register and transmitted to bot."l Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional r-ev1.ew period has expired and therefore, cites the following leqislation as D. C. Law No. 1-23, effective Oc:tctier Z l 19 75 D. c. Law No. 1-23 In the counciJ. of the Ois rict of Colwnbia October 21, 1975 To provide additiona.l revenue for the Oisttict of Columbia, and for other purposes. Be. it enacted by the council of the Ois t-itt of Columbia, T!lat t.'ti.s a~ may be cited as the "Revenue Act of 1975 TITLE I REGI.srnATION FEES AN'D EXCISE TAX'!S FOR MOTOR VDD:CI.ES Sec. 101. Section 3 of Title rl of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (D.c. Code, sec. 40-103 is amended as follows 1) The paragraph designated "Class A" of subsect:ion (b re.lating to registration fees for passenger motor vehicles) is amended by striking out 11 S30" and "SSO and inserting in lieu thereof "SUO" and "S67 respectively 2) The paragraph designated "Class B" of subsection {b relating to registration fees for trucks, tractors and certain commercial motor vehicles) is amended by striking out "S53 S59 69 80 S91 S99 112 S128 163 S191 229 and "S269 and ins~ing i n lieu the eof 71 11 $79 S92 S107 S122 S132 150 11 $171 S218 S225 S306 and "S359 respectively I 2 3) The paragraph designated "Class C" of subs~ion {b relating tc regis ration fees f o:r t:aile:rs is amended by s'1:.riking out 11 S16 S27 S~3 61 80 99 123 163 S203 and 11 s2q3 and insertinq in lieu thereof "S15 22 36 11 58 S82 S107 132 S164 218 271 and 323 respectively 1 The paragraph designated "Class 0" of subsection (b relating to registration fees fo:r motorcycles, motor bicycles, motor .tricycles and motor wheels) is amended by st:ikinq out "S12 and inserting in lieu thereof "S 1 6 5) The paragraph designated "Class Z" of subsection (} re.la ting to registration fees for antique motor vehicles) is amended by striking out "SS" and inserting in lieu thereof 7 6) The paragraph designated "Class F" of subsec ion {b relatinq to registration fees for deale s identification tags) is amended by striking ou 30 and "S 10 and insertj.ng in lieu thereof Zl0 and "S11p respectively i) SUbsection (d) of such section 3 is amended to read as follows d) Twenty-five per centum of the qross proceeds f:rom fees payable unde:r th.is title shall be paid into the Metrobus Fund established under section 10 3 of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1975. The remainder of the proc~ds f=om fees payable under t is ~it.le shall -3- be divided between tbe General Fund and t e Eighway Fund. The Council of tile District oi Columbia shall determine the percentage of such remainder which shall be deposited to the credit of the General Fund of the District of Columbia, except that t e percentage of such remainder deposited to the credit of the General Und shall be not less than forty-two per centwn or more than forty-seven per centum of such remainder. The amounts of such remainder not deposited to the credit of "t e General. Fund, along with specified moneys collected from tt:e motor-vehicle-fuel tax, and S"pecifi ed amounts of fees charged for the titling of motor vehicles and trailers, including specified amounts of fees charged for the issuance of permits to operate motor vehicles. shall. be appropriated and used solely and exclusively for 1) construction, reconstro.ction, improvement, and maintenance of public highways, including t.&amp;gt;:ie necessary administrative expenses in connection therewith 2} the expenses of the office of the director of vehicles and traffic incident to the regulation and control of t=affic and the administ--a.tion of he same; and 3) t!le expenses necessarily involved in he police cont--ol, regulation, and administration of traffic upon the highways, except t!la-e t 1e ~otal amount to be expended under this item sh.all not exceed 15 ?e centum of the t.otal payment appropria~ed for pay and aJ.lowances of of:icers and members of t le Met=o"POli tan Police force sec. 102 (a) Section 6 (j) of the Oist:i.ct of Col.um.bia Traffic Act, approved Marcil 3, 1925 (D.c. Code, sec o- 603 (j is amended by st::iking out "5 per ce.?ltum" and inserting in lieu thereof "6 per centum b) Notwi t.hstandinq any other provision of law, not less than one-si.~th of the proceeds collected under section 6 (j) of the District of Columbia Tra:fic A.ct, 19 25 {D. c. Code~ sec 0-603(j shal.l be deposited into the Metrobus Fund established by sec i.on 1 03 of this title, toget.-ier with sudl additional proceeds collected under section 6 (j} as the Mayor of the District of Columbia inay, in his discretion, deem to be appr0t:itiate and necessary. Sec. 103 (a) There is hereby established a spetial fund to be known as the "Metrobus FUnd hereinafter in tr.is section ref erred to as the "Fund The Fund shall consist of amounts paid into it. from time to timer from the revenue collected as follows 1) Twenty-five per cent of the amounts coll eeted under Title rl of the District of COluml:lia Revenue Act of 1937 (D.c. Code. sec 0-101 et seq 5 At least one-si.X h of t.~e amounts collected under sec on 6 (j) of t.~e Oisi:=i~ of Columbia af::ic Act 1 925 {D. c. Code sec. i+0-603 (j 3) The amounts collected unde= section 125 (1 of the District of Columbia Sales Tax A D.C. Code~ sec 7-2602 imposing a tax on the gross receipts om parking} At least one-fi£th of the amounts collec ed under the first se~icn of t!le Ac of Apri.l 23, 19 2U (imposing a tax on motor-vehicle-fuel such amounts to be deposited into the Fund no sooner t an July 1, 1976 b) The amounts in the Fund shall be available, when appropriated, to pay the District of Colwnbia's share of the cost of the construction and operation of t.~e Metrobus system. Sec. 104(a} The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall submit to the Council of the District of Columbia no later than January 1 1976, proposed legislation detailing a three-tier registration fee for automobiles in class A of section 3(b) of Title rv of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937 (D.C. Code sec. 40-103) to replace the existing two-tier strncture with dispropo'rtionately lower fee increases for lighter weight. compact and subcompac~ automobi.les b) The Mayor of the District of Colwn.bia shall sumbit to the council of e District of Colwnbia. no later than -6- January 1, 1976, proposed legislation detailing a rest uC"tu:rec three-tier motor ver.icle excise tax rate which provides for a substantially lower tax rate for lighter weight, compact and subcompact automobiles. Tn"I.E I1 MOTOR VEH!CU: FUEL TAX; On:D RECORDA'l'ION TAX sec. 201 (a) The first sentence of the first section of the Act entitled "An Act to provide for a tax on motor- vehicle fuels sold within the Dist=ict of Columbia, and for other purposes approved April 23, 192 O.C. Code, sec. 14i-1901) is amended by serikinq out "8" and inse:tinq in lieu 'thereof "10 b) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, on and after the effective date of this section, not less than one- fifth of the procoaeds collected under the Act enti t.led "An Act to provide for a tax on mator-vehicie fuels sold within the Oistrie1 of _Columbia, and for other purposes O.c. Code, sec. 47-1901) to wh.ich reference is made in subsection (a) of this section, shal1 be deposited into the Metrobus Fund established by S ion 103 of tiile I of this act, toqether with such adcli tionaJ. proceeds collected under the Act entitled "An Act to provide for a tax on motor-vehicle fuels sold in the Oistriet of Colwnbia and for other purposes0 gt c. Code, sec 7-1901) as the Mayor of the Oist=i~ of Columbia may, in his discretion, deem to be appropriate and necessary 7- Sec. 202. The Mayor of the Distrie"t of Columbia shall submit to tile Council of he Dist=ict of Columbia y January 1, 1976, a thorough, doc.imented study outlining the advisabi.l.ity of di!ferential tax rates on leaded and unleaded gasoline, and weighing positive and negative l:lea.lth~ envirorunenta.l and income-class impacts of such a dif£erentia.l tax pol.icy. Sec. 203. Section 303(a) of the District of Columbia Real Es ate Oeed Recorda~ion Tax Act~ approved March 2, 1962 (D.C. Code, sec. 45-723(a is amended by striking out "one-half of 1 per centum" and inserting in lieu t.'1ereof "1 per centum Tr:t'LZ Ill AM!:NOMENI'S TO TE OLSTRJ:C OF COLOM.BIA SAL.ES AND OS'E TAX ACTS Sec. 301. The District of Columbia Sales Tax Act is amended as f cl.lows 1) Paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of section 1 1 of such Act (D.C. Code sec. U7-2601 14 (a l)} is amended to read as follows 1) Food or drink served, prepared for immediate consumption or sold, in or by, restaurants, lllnch counters ca£eterias, hotels, snack bars, caterers, boarding houses, ca=rtout shops and ot er like places of ~usiness, and food or drink sold =eacy for immediate consumption f=om carts, and motor vehicles or any ot er -a- f ol:'ln of vehicle. aot or cold sandwiches are considered prepared foods 2) Subsection (a) of section 114 of sue Act (D.C. coder sec i-2601 14{a is amended by adding at the end thereof the following new paragraph 12) The sale Of or charges made for the service of parking, storing or keeping motor vehicles or trailers. For the purposes of this paragraph 'motor vehicles' mean any vehicle propelled by an internal- combustion engine or by electricity or steam. except road rollers, fa::m tractors. and vehicles propelled only upon stationary rails or tracks; and 'trailer• means a vehicle without motor power intended or used for car.:ying propei-:y or persons and drawn or intended to be drawn by a motor ve i cl e, whether such vehicle wi thou~ motor power carries the weight of the property or persons wholly on its own structure or whether a part of such weight rests upon or is carried by a motor vehicle 3) Para~aphs (4) and (i) of S'tlbseetion (a) of section 11 ii of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. 4 7-2601, 14 (a Li) and (7}) are repealed U) Paragraph (11) of subsection (a) of section 11~ of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. U7-2601 (1U a 11 is amended to read as follows 9 11) The rental of tex-tiles to commercial users, the essential par of such rental includes t e recuL.~ng service of lamldering or cleani."l.g thereof 5) Section 114 (b 1 A) of such Act (D .C. Code, sec 7-2601) is amended by s't:riking out "other than sales of local telephone service and paragraph (1 B) of subsection (b) of section 114 is repealed 6) Subsection (b) of section 11~ of such Ac D.C. code, sec 7-2 6 O 1 1 b is amended by adding at t.te .end thereof the following new paragraph 5) Food or drink sold in the same form, condition. quantities and packaging as is commonly sold in grocery type food stores, except when sold by 'businesses as described in paragraph (1) of subsec ion (a) of this section 7) Se~-ion 125 of such Act (D.C. Code, sec 7-2602) is amended to read as fol.lows Sec. 125. A tax is imposed upon a.ll vendors for the priv.ilege of selJ.ing at retail certain tangible p~onal property and for the privilege of selling certain selected services (defined as retail sale and sale at retail in this title The rate of such tax shall be 5 per centum of the gToss receipts from sales of or charges for such tangible personal property and services, except tha 10 1) the rate of tax shall be 8 pe= centum of the gross receipts from e sales of or charges for the service of parking or storing motor vehicles or trailers 2) the rate of tax sha.ll be 6 per centum of the gross receipts from sales of or charges for (A} any room or rooms, lodqi.nqs, or accommodations, furnished to transients by any hotel, inn r tourist camp, tou_rj.st cabin, or any other place in which rooms, lodgings, or accommodations are reguJ.arly furnished to transients; and (B) food or dl:i.nk served. prepared for immediate conswnption, or sold as described in sec-:ion 11 a l) and 3) the rate of tax shal.l be 6 per centum of the qross receipts from sales of spi.ritous or malt liquors, beer and wines; and 4) the rate of tax shall be 2 per cent.um of the gross receipts from the sales of food and drink as des~ed in section 114(a} (1) of this title when sold from vending machines 8) Section 127 of such Act (D.C. Code, sec i-260~} is a.mended to read as follows Sec. 127. For the purpose of collecting his reimbursement as provided in section 126 of this title insofar as it can be done and yet eliminate the fractions of a cent, the vendor s.ha.ll add to the sales -11- price and collect f=om the purchaser such amoun~s as may be presc::i~ed by tbe Counc~l of he Oist=ict 0£ c~lumbia to carry out the purposes of this section 9} SUbsection l} of section 128 of sue~ Act {D c. Code, sec. 47-2605(1 is amended to read as follows 1) Sales of naturaJ. or arti£icial gas and el ectrici t:f 10) Section 128 (o) of such Act (n.c. Code, sec. 47- 2605 (o is amended by inse ing 1he~er or no-tn a:f-:e dxugs Sec. 302. The District of Columbia Ose Tax Act (n c. coder sec. 47-2701) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (5) of sec ion 201 (a) of such Act c. Code, sec 47-2701 (a 5 is amended by inserting as described in section 114 {a 1) of title I of this act immediately after "consideration 2) Section 212 of such Act (0.C. Code, sec. 47-2702) is amended to read as follows Sec. 212. There is hereby imposed and there shall be paid by every vendor engaged in business in t le District and by every purchaser a tax on the user storage, or consumption of any tangible personal property and services sold or purchased at retail sale. The rates of tax imposed by this section shall be S centum of the sales price of such tangible pe=sonal property o: services, except that l2 a) the rate of tax shall be 6 per centum of t.11e gross receipts f=om the sales of or c!larges for 1) any room or rooms, lodgings, or accommodations, furnished to transients by any l:lote.l, i:m, tourist camp, tourist cal::Ji.n, or any other place in which rooms, lodgings, or accommodations are regularly fnr.lished to transients, and (2) food or drink served, prepared for immediate consumption, or sold as described in section 11U(a 1 and (3) spiritous or malt liquors, beer and wines: and b) the rate of tax shall be 8 per centum of the gross r~eipts from the sales of or charges for the service of parking or storing motor vehicles or tl:ai.lers and c) the rate of tax shall be 2 per centum of the gross receipts from the sale of food and d:'ink as described in Sec. 114 (a 1) of tit.le I of t.11is act when sold from vending machines 3) Paraqraph (2) of subsection (a} of section 201 of sud: Act (D.C. Code, sec. 4 7-2701 (a 2 is repealed 4) Paragraph (9) of subsection (a) of section 201 of such Ac:t (D.C. Code, sec 7-2701 (a 9 is amended to read as follows 9) The rental of textiles to conunereial users, the essential part of which rental includes recurring service of laundering or cleaning thereof 13 5) Paragraph (1) of subsection (b) of sec'tion 20 1 of such A D. c. Code sec. 4 7-27 01 1 (b 1 i s amendec by striking out "other than sales of l oca l tel e phone services T l'I.E IV Sec. 401 a} section 603 of the District of Columbia Cigarette Tax Act (D. c. Code, sec. 47-2802) is amended by striking out 6 cents" and inserting in lieu thereof 1 0 cents b 1) In the case of cigarette tax stamps which have been purchased prior to the effective date of the amend.men~ and wruch on such date are held (affixed to a cigarette package or otherwise) by a wholesaler, retailer, or vending machine operator, licensed under the Oistri~ of Co lumbia Cigarette Tax Act, such licensee sball pay to the Mayor (in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection) an amount equal to the di££erence be~n the amount of tax represented by such tax stamps on the date of their purchase and the amount of tax which an equal nlJmber of cigarette tax stamps would represent if purchased on the effective date of the amendment 2) Within twenty days after the effective date of suc!'l amendment, each such licensee {A) shall file with the Mayor an affirmed state01ent (on a form to be prescribed by t..11e Ma yor) sh owing the number of such cigare~te t ax s~amps he ld 'by him as of the beginning of the 1ay after the eff ecti ve -1 date of th.is amendment, or if suc!'l. day is a Sunday. as of the beginning of the following day and (E} shall pay ~o t e Mayor the amount specified in paragraph 1) of this subsection 3) Each such licensee shall keep and preserve for t.~e twe.lve-mcntb period immediately following the effective date of such amendment the inventories and other records znade whidl form the basis fer tbe infer.nation furnished to t e Mayor on t.be statement required to be filed under ~his sul::sect.ion 4 or p~ses of this subsection. a tax st~ shall be considered as held by a wholesaler, retailer, or vending machine opentor if title thereto has passed to such wholesaler, retailer, or operator (whether or not delivery to him has been made) and if title to such stamp has not a~ any time been transferred to any person other than such wholesaler, retailer. or operator 5) A violation of the provisions of paragraph (1 2 or (3) of this subsection shall be punishable as provided in section 6 11 of the District. of Columbia Cigarette Tax Act (D.C. Code. sec. 47-2810 TI'I'LZ V AMENDMENTS TO PRO~SZONS IMPOSING A TAX ON nNANCJ:AL INST:!TUT:tONS, GUARANTY COMPANJ AN!l PUBLIC OTll.IT'IES Sec. 501. {a) Section 6 of the Act entitled "An Act making appropriations to provide for expenses of the -15- government of the Ois"t:'ict of Columbia for ~he fiscal yea= ending June t.'ii tietb nineteen hundred and t.i-ir-ee, and for oi:.her purposes approved Ju.ly 1, 1902 (D.C. Code, sec 7 1701 et seq is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (5) of such section 6 (D.C. Code, sec 7-1701) is amended by striking out "5 percentum" and inserting in lieu thereof "6 per centum 2) Paragraph 6 of such section 6 (D.C. Code. sec 7- 1702) is amended by st=iki.ng out "one and one-hal er centum" and inserti."lg in lieu thereof "t.i.iree per centum 3) The lasi sentence of parag:rap 7) of such section 6 (D. c. Code, sec 7-1703) is amended by striking out our per centum per anm:unn and inserti."lg in lieu 1=.hereof "six per centum pe annum Pa::aqraph 9 of such section 6 (D.C. Code, sec 7- 17 04) is amended by s""t:riking out "two per centum per annum" and inserting in lieu thereof "three per centum per annum TITLE VI AMENDMENTS TO DISTlUCT OF COLUMBIA. INCOME AND F'RANClllSl: TAX ACT OF 19~7 sec. 601. The District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 (D.c. Code, sec. 47-1501 et seq is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (u) of section q of Title I of such AC D .C. Code, sec. q7-1551c(u is amended to read as follows 6 u) The term 'depe."ldent' means a dependent as defined in section 152 of t."le Internal rtevenue Code of 1954 2) The last sentence of paragraph (v) of section u of Title I of such Act (O.C. code, sec. 47-1551c(v is amended to read as fo.l1ows he term 'head of a family' means an individual who is single, or if married, separated from husband or wife 3) The commencing phrase in section 1 of Title I! of such Act {D.C. Code, sec 7-155U) is amended to read as follows The following organizations shall be exempt from taxation under this ar icle, except to t!'le extent -c lat such organizations have unrelated business taxable income subject to tax under sections 511 of the Internal Revenue Code of 195U, in which even~ such orqanizations sbal.l be subject to tax under this article on said unrelated business taxable income U) Subsection {b) of section 2 of Title II:I of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. u7-1S57a) is amended by addi.ng at the end thereof the following new paraqraph {18) On employment Compensation Payments received by an individual from the Oist:ict of Columbia Onemployment compensation Board or a similar State agency for those periods du:ing wr..ich he is unemployed 17 5) Paragraph (16 entitled "Real state Ir.vestments TruS"CS of sec~ion 6(a) of Title III of such A D.C. Coder sec. 47-1557b(a 16} is renumbered as paragraph 17 6) Subsec"ti.on (a} of section 3 of Title III of such Act co.c. code sec 7-1557b(a is amended by adding at the end thereof· a new paraqraph as follows 18) Household and Dependent Care Se~vices To the same extent t.hat such amount is de u~ible under section 214 of the Internal Revenue Code of 195U, any amount expended by an individual for household and dependent care services necessary for gainful employment; Provided however r that the requirement of sect.ion 214 of tbe Inte al Revenue Code of 195U t.hat married couples must file a single return jointly, shall not be applicable 7) Pa:aqraphs (a) and (b) of section 2 of Ti~le V of sue Act (D.C. code, secs. 47-156Ua(a) and 47-1564a(b) } are amended to read as follows a) Residents and Nonresidents Zvery nonresident of the District receiving income subject to tax under this article and every resident of the Oistrictr except fiduciaries r then his g=oss income for tbe taxable year single, or if married and not li V:.ng with husband or wife, exceeds the personal exemptions authorized for the -1 8- taxpayer as of July 1, 1975, by subsec~ion {b) of section 151 of the Inte:nal Revenue Code of 195 or 2) his gross income for the taxable year. mar.ried and living with husband or wife. exceeds ~he combined amount of the personal exemptions aut."lorized for the taxpayer and the spouse of the taxpayer as of Ju..ly 1 1975, by subsection (b) of section 1S1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954; or 3) his gross sales or gross receipts from any trade or business other than an unincorporated business subject to tax under title VIII of this article, exceeds SS,000, regard1ess of the amount of his gross income; or 4) the combined gross income for the taxable year of a husband and wife living together exceeds t."le combined amount of the personal exemptions authorized as of July 1, 1975, for the taxpayer and the spouse of the taxpayer by subsection (b) of section 151 of the Internal Revenue Code of 19 54, or the combined gross sales or gross receipts from any trade or business, other than an cni.nc:orporated business subject to tax under title of th.is article, exceeds SS,000, regard1ess of the amount of their qross income b) Fiduciaries Every !iduciary {except a receiver appointed by aut ority of law in possession of on.ly pa=t of the property of an individual) for 19 1) every individual if single, or i! ma=ied and not living with husband or wife, for whom he a~s having a gross income for t e taxable year i 1 excess of t..1.e amount of his personal exemption as authorized for tie taxpayer as of July 1, 1975, by subs~ion {b) of sect.ion 151 of the Internal Revenue code of 1954 2) every individual, if married and ll vinq with husband or wife, for whom he acts having a g:oss income for t.11.e taxable year in excess of t."leir personal exemptions as aut orized for the taxpayer as of July 1, 1975 r:Jtf subsection (b) of section 151 of t.~e Internal Revenue Code of 1954 3} eve y estate for which he acts, tile c;=oss income of which for t.~e taxable year is in excess of its personal exemption, which is equivalen~ to the personal exemption authorized for an indi vi.dual as of July 1, 1975, by subsec ion (b) of section 151 of the In~er:ial Revenue Code of 1954; or 4} every t=ust for which he acts, the gross .in.come of .which for the taxable year is .S100 or over 8) Section 2 of Title VI of such Act (D.C. Code, sec 7-1567a) is amended to read as follows Sec. 2. Personal exemptions a 1) There shal.l be allor..red to residents the same deductions for personal exemptions as are allowed as of July 1, 1975, under section 151 of the .L~ternal Revenue Code of 195 20 2) A taxpayer who qualifies as head of a family shall be allowed a personal exemption in an amount which is twice the amount al.lowed the taxpayers as of .July 1, 1975, by subsection (b) of section 151 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 b tn the case of a retUl:n made for a frac ional pa.rt of a taxable year, the personal exemptions shall be reduced to amounts which bear the same ratio to the fu.ll exa-mptions provided as the number of months in the period for which the return is made bears to twelve mont s 9) Subsection 4(b) of Title VI of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. 47-1567 (b 1 is amended to read as fol.lows 1) Zn applyinq such table the taxpayer• s marital status on the last day of the taxable year shall control 10) Section 6 of Tit.le VI of such Act (O.C. code~ sec. 47-1567e) is repealed Sec. 602. The Mayor of the Distric:t of Colwnbia shall, within six months after the effective date of this section, su.l:mit to the Finance and Revenue Committee of the Council of the Ois~ct of Columbia and to the Oist ic:t of Coll.llllbia Auditor, a report which shall analyze t e total i.m~ct of all District of Columbia taxes and user charges. This report shall set forth al.l information which the Mayor deems useful to a fu.l.l understanding of t.i.ie impact of the tax structure. It shall specifically set forth the impaee and -21- revenue of all taxes. as a sum, on individual residents grouped by income class and fami.ly s-:a tus incl uciinq unma:l:ied, married, single parent, retired, and ch other classifications as are appropriate The same analysis shall be qi ven for each separate tax on in di vi duals. Such analysis shall include consideration of business taxes and charqes likely to be passed on to consumers. The report shall also set forth the impact and revenue of each tax on commercial and professional activity, and on businesses grouped by type and size of business activity. In addition to the impact and revenue analysis, the report sha.ll set forth tbe dist i.bution of returns for each tax grouped by quartile of revenue starting from the quartile containing be fewest returns An estimate of t le revenue effect and collection expense should be given for changes in major exemptions and deductions. Sec. 603. Section 2 of Title VII of the Oistric of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 19U7 (O.C. Code, sec. 47-1571a) is hereby amended to read as follows Sec. 2. For the privilege of carrying on or engaging in any trade or business within the District and of receiving income from sou=ces within the District, there is hereby levied for one taxable year beginning on and after January 1r 1975, a tax at ~he rate of 12 per centum upon the taxable income of every corporation, whet er domestic or foreign (except t~ose 22- expressly exempt under section 47-1554 The minimum tax payable shall be S25. 00. For the ~xable years beginning on and after January, 1976, there is hereby levied a tax at t.'le rate of 9 per centum upon t le taxable income of every cor"f)Oration, whether domestic or foreign {except those expressly exempt under section ~7- 1554 The mininnlJn tax payable shall be S25.00 sec. 604. Section 3 of Title VIII of the Dist=ict of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 194 D.C. Code, sec. 47-1574b) is hereby amended as follows Sec. 3. For tlle privilege of carrying on or enqaq:i.nq in any t:rade or business within the District and of recei vinq income from sources within the District, there is hereby levied for one taxable year beginning on and after January 1 1975, a tax at the rate of 12 per centum upon the taxable income of every unincorporated business. whether domestic or foreign (except t:.hose expressly exempt under section ~7-1554 The minimum tax payable shall be S25.00. For the taxable years beqinninq on and after· January i, 1976, there is hereby levied a tax at the rate of 9 per centum upon the taxable income of every unincorporated business, whether domestic or fore.ign (except t ose expressly exempt under section ~7-155U The minimum tax payable shall be S25.00 23- Sec. 605. Section 1 of Title V:!II of the Dist--ict of Columbia Income and ranchise Tax Ac~ of 19q7 (D.C. Code, sec 7-15i4) is hereby amended by striking tbe followi~g sentence The words 'un:i.ncorporated business• do no~ include any trade or business which by law, customs or et tics cannot be incorporated, any trade, business, or profession which can be incorporated only under the Dist=ict of Columbia Professional Corporation Act, or any trade or business in which more than 80 per centum of the gross income is derived f:'om t!le personal services actually rendered by the individual or members of the pare ersru.p or other en ti ey in the conducting or carrying on of any trade or business and in wh.ic~ capital is not a material income-producing factor Sec. 606. sections 2 and S of Title :aJ::r: of t.~e District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Ac: of 1947 (D.C. Code, sec. 47-1589a, c and d) are amended by striking the words "one-half of 1 per centum0 wherever they appear and inserting in lieu thereof t.~e words "thr~fou tb.s of 1 per centum Sec. 607. Subsections b c and "{d of section 1 of Title D:!I of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 (D.C. code, sec. 47-1589 (b c and (d are amended ty redesigna~ng said subse~ions as c d and e}" respectively, and as redesignated by -24- striking from subsection d t..lle figure "6" and inse~ing in lieu thereof the figure "9 and by inserting he following new subsection b) FA.II.ORE TO PAY. In the case of any failure to pay the amount of tax required by titles V:t:I and ~II of this article within the time prescribed by law or prescribed by the Mayor or council in pUJ:"suance of law, 5 per centum of the tax shall be added to the tax for eac!l month or frac-:ion t!le~eof that such failure continues, not to exceed 25 per centum in the aggregate except that when the tax is paid after such time and it is shown that the failure to pay was due to reasonable cause and not due to wilful neqlect, no such addition shall be made to t e tax Sec. 608. Section 14 of Title XI! of t.~e District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 (t).C. Code sec. in-15861-1) is amended by striking the figure "6" wherever it appears therein and inserting in lieu thereof the fiqure "9 Sec. 609. sec ion 4(h 2) of Tit.le I of the District of col~ia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 19U7 {o.c. Code, sec 7-1551c(h 21) is hereby repealed in i~s entirety. TrrL.Z VJ WATn ANtl S~ER SZRVICE RAT~S Sec. 701 {a) Water and Wat.er Service Rates and C."larges. Notwit.hs"Canding any other provision of law or requlation 25- the following rates and charges shall be applicab l e fo r water and water services provided on or after Jul y 1 1975 1) Rates and Charges for Metered se.:vi ces The minimwn rate for w-ater furnished any premises tbrouqh a metered service shaJ..l be $8. 75 semiannu.a.lly for the use of tlp to 3.,600 c:ubic feet of water, payable in advance and for water furnished during such perio:J in excess of that qua.nti ty the rate shal.l be thirty cents per one hundred c-~bic feet of water b) 5ani tary Sewer Service Rates and Charges. The charge for sanitary sewer service furnished any premises in the District of Col1JI11.bia shall be 90 per centum of t h e charge for water or water service fu:nished any such premises from t.~e Oistrict of Columbia Water Supply System and shaJ.l be collected in the same manner and at t."le same time as water charges are collected. When water is suppli ed any such premises from a source or sources other t."lan he District of Columbia Water Supply Sys-cem, the charge for sanitary sewer service shall be the same in amount as would be charged if the same quantity of water were furn.ished such premises from the District of Columbia water supply System through metered service. The sanitary sewer charge shall be added as a separate item on the billr if any, for water and water service fu=nished such premises. {c Paymen~ of Rates and Cha=ges. All rates for water and water se vice and t.-ie c!Jarges for sanitary sewer s e vi ce -26- hereby established shall be payable at least once semiannually. When the com~tation of the amount of any bill for any of such services results in a fraction of one- balf cent or more, the ner highest amount not com aining a fraction sha.ll be charged. sec. 702. Penalties. T!le penalties to be imposed for failure to pay bills for water and sewer service after t.~e expiration of thirty days from the date of rendition there&amp;lt gt;£. and the payment of any costs incurred by the District of Columbia in connection with discontinuing and restoring the .wa~er supply to any premises, shall be as provided by sections 102 and 210 of the Oistric of Columbia Publ.ic works Act of 195U (0.C. code, secs 3-1521a 3- 1609 Sec. 7 03. Change of Ownership or occupancy. A.ny person who desires a statement of the account of any water or sewer service cha.rqe to the date of the acquisition of any premises shall make a written request to the Water Registrar on or before the date of such acquisition, except that the authority to enforce payment of water and sewer service charges by shutting off the water supply or by refusing to restore the water supply may be exercised without regard to any change of ownership or occupancy of any such premises. The Water Registrar shall have access to all premises fu nished water or sewer service, and if any such premises is vacant, any request for a statement of account shall -27- contain a fixed time at whicil a representative of tbe Wate~ Regist=ar may obtai:l access. sec. 704. ay November 15, 1975, tbe Mayor of t e Dis-t:i~ of Columbia shall submit to the Council of the Di.strict of Co.lumbia a water rate structure which shall a) continue the increasing price rate structure contained in this tit.le whereby per unit water rates increase with increased consum~tion b) a plan to provide for a minimum bill for water usage not to exceed S2.89 for the first 1,200 cubic feet of water used during each six month period c) provide a scheme whereby residents of muJ.ti- family units will benefit on an equal basis with residents of single-family units in the lo..w-minimum water usage rates; and (d) provide detailed substantiation for the rate st iJCture. The structure, plan and scheme submi&amp;lt ted bv the Mayor under this section shall be designed to make no change in the amount of revenue derived from the water rates and sewer service cha.rqes, and shall not take effect unless implemented by further action ot the CotJncil. Sec. 705. The water rates and sewer service charge contained in this title, to be effective ~uly 1, 1975, shall terminate on January 1, 1976. unless 28 1) the Mayor of t.~e District of Columbia submi~s to the Council of the District of Columbia, by November 15, 1975, a complete report substantiating t.~e increased water rates and sewer service charges as necessitated by increased government cost; and {2) the council adopts a resolution {before January 1, 1976) stating that the council concurs in the Mayor's report. In the event such report is not submitted to the council by November 1 5, 1 975, or the Council does not adopt such resolution by January 1, 1976, then the water rates and sewer service charges in effect on June 30, 1975 shall again be effective beqinninq January r 976. Sec. 706. Seed.on 1520c of Ti~le 43 of the District of Colwnbia Code (D.c. Code, sec 3-1520c) is hereby amended by striking the second sentence therein and inserting in lieu thereof the following In eomputi.ng the charge for the consumption of water, if such charge is for a period beginning prior to a change in water rates and ending thereafter, such charge shall be prorated in such a manner as to charge for water consumed prior to the effective date of such new water rates at the rate which is in effect during that period of consumption, and to charge for water consumed after be effective date at the new rates 29- sec. 801 (a) The amendments made by sections 101. 102, 201. and 203 shall take effect on t.,e fi=st day o= t.~e fi=st montb. after i:.he day this act becomes law according to the provisions of section 602(c) of t.~e Dist ict of Columbia Se lf-Gove.rnment and Governmental Reorganization Act b) The amendment ma.de by section "O 1 shall apply with respect to cigarette tax stamps sold on and after the first day of the first month which begins more than thirty days after the day this act becomes law according to the provisions of section 602 (c) of the District of Columbia Se.lf-Gove:rrunent and Governmental Reorqanization Ac-c c) The amendments made by section 501 shall apply with respect to gross receipts or gross ea nings for the year ending June 30, 1976, and for eac!l succeeding year ending on the thirtieth day of June. The amenements made by section 50 1 (b) sha.l.J. take e£feet on the first day 0£ the first month after the day this ac:t becomes law according to the provisions of section 602(c of the Dist--ict of Columbia Self-Government and Govern.mental Reorganization Act d) The amendments made by section 60 1 shall apply with respect to taxable years beginning on and after January 1 1975 e) Tit.le VII of this Act shall take ef£ect on July 1 1975 f) sections 103, 104, 202, and 602 shall take effect on the date this act becomes law according to the provisions 30- of section 602(c) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Gove=nmental Reorganization AC g) Sections 603, 60U, 605, and 609 shall take effeC't with taxable years beginning on and after January 1, 1975 h) Sections 606, 607, and 608 shall take ef!ec on January i, 1976 i) Section 301, with the exception of subsections (3 5) and (9) of that section, shall take effect on the fi=st day of the first month. which begins more than 30 days afte the effective date of this Act j) Subsections (3 5) and (9) of section 301 shall take effect on J'une 1, 1976 k) Section 302, with tbe exce-ption of su.bsections (3 and (5) of that section, sha.l.l take effect on the first day of the first month which begins more than 30 days after the effective date of t!lis Act l} Subsections (3) and (5} of section 302 shall take effect on June 1, 1976. Sec. 802(a) If any provision of this act, including any amendment made by this act, or the application thereof to any person or c:ircumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of the act, including t."le remaining amendments, and the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby. {b) The repeal or amendment by this Act of any provision of law shall not a£feet any act done or any right -31- accrued or accruing under such provision of law before the effective date of tis AC't or any sui~ or proceeding had or commenced before the effec ive da~e of this Act ut al.l such rights and liabi.li ties in t e same manner and to t..11e same extent. as if such repeal or amendment had not been made c} Al.l offenses cownittedr and all penalties incurred prior to t!le effective date of t!ti.s Act under any provision of law hers.by repealed or amended, may be prosec~ted and punished in the same manner and with the same eifect as if this Act had not been enacted Docket for ·the 13 ill 1-4 7 Considered in Council 4-LS-7~ First vote 4-15-75 RECORD OF COUNC I L VOT X-lndic:ues Vote l n.-i'resC'nt 1 1 1 Iii L 1 c 1 u \ l lt tt S~cretary of =he Council l Final vote in Cou cil 6-24-75*"11 R E c 0 R D 0 F c 0 u N c l L v 0 T E l"t:S 71 n H A i COUNCii 4C&amp;gt;Ar flt s i ~of .ti A.D A CCll&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Cll 1CMOCn COUN 11 C CN Yt.:S o 1 r 1 a n TUCKER ~IXON I MOORE D. I x i I I I ii E~BJJV II\ v I x I I I I Ii µOBSON I T a~Ja: i 2s: I I I I II MQQE~ T I rl""lll'T'~c.o I x I I I I 1! S~ ACKlE~ON X-lnciicaics Vote l R escnt Presented to the i!:ayor 1 1_1 1_s_ M.e.yor•s action approve: l /2 J Jt:L 19i5 i I '1 x I 1 ~s A..ll l.DI~G I x I I I I I x i ji i~IT S Qi\I X I I x i I I I ll~I1t r~t? i x I I x i I I I I! I I I I x i I I I i1 I I I I A Al·sc:~t n. A.-il I f I I 1secretary of :he Council L 1 Tc 1 1 C Seer tary of the Council L ts 1i4 t disapprov.e-1 Mayor's S ignci t~re 2 lt:L SiS Enac~ed without Mayor's signature Secre?t~ry of the Council Counci.l Members u..nanimous ly recon~idered second-reading cf !Hll 1-4 7 with tec n1ca 1 amendments On Jul'Y. U, 1975 vote~ 11":0 2 absent Coun il adopte:c ·unanL':lously ~n a:mend.ea. first re3ding June 1 l 97S Vote ll;-0 ab s l r Bill Docket l -47 Pa{."e Two Rccon~idcred by Cotmcil Vote RECCRD OF COUNC IL VOTE X-lndical~ Vore J\. u.-A.lla~nl (Sec etar i of t!1~ Co·.mcil Pre ted to the P e:r, ident Sec=c:t:.ary o f th Council Susta i lt;ayvr' s v:to Mot Su::t i n yor• c vc ~o Presioent of the U.S Subrnit~ed t.o the Cong~e~s Secretary of the Co·~nc.il Senate action House ac'tion re~olution numbe resolu~ion nu~bcr Secretary of the Senate Clerk of the Bouse Enacted withou't Con~ressional action Secrct~ry of t~e Councill •</search-text>
  </meta>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>VII</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>701</num>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-2105"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-2401.05"/>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-2413.09"/>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>703</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-2401.06"/>
    </section>
  </container>
</document>
