<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-3">
  <num type="law">1-3</num>
  <heading type="short">Horizontal Property Act Amendment Act of 1975</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1975-05-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-3.pdf">D.C. Law 1-3</citation>
      <citation type="register">21 DCR 3944</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-3, the “Horizontal Property Act Amendment Act of 1975,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-12, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Urban Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 25, 1975, and March 11, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 27, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-5 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOlICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of· Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198)(the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. l-12 on first and second readings February 25, 1975 and March 11, 1975, respectively. Following the .signature of the Mayor on March 27, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act ~o. 1-5 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D .C. Law No. 1-3, effective May 22, 1975 cL STERLING TU"hR Chairman of the Council E l i D.C. Law 1-3 In the Council of the District of Columbia May 22, 1975 To amend the Horizontal Property Act of the District of Columbia Be it ·enacted by the Council of the District of of Columbia, That this act may be cited as· the "Horizontal Property Act Amendment Act of 1975 Sec. 2. The Horizontal Property Act of the District of Colu.'11.bia (O.C. Code, secs. 5-901--5-933) is amended as follows 1) Section 2 of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. 5-902) is amended {A) by striking out i• structure" in sub- section (b) and inserting in lieu thereof "project and {B) by amending subsection {c) to read as follows {c Condominium project' or 'project' means a real estate condominium project; a plan or project condominium project; a plan or project whereby five or more apartments, rooms, office spaces, buildings, or other units which may be. either conti~uous or detached i in existing or propo~cd buildings or structures are offered or proposed to be offered for sale 2) Sections 4, 6{c ll(c ll~a 13(a}, 14 (a 3) and 5 14 (b 15, 16 (b 21 (a and 22 of such Act (D.C. Code, secs. 5-904, 5-906(c 5-9ll(a 5-913 (a 5-914 (a 3) and (5 5-914 (b 5-915, 5-916 {b S-92l(a and 5-922, respectively) are each amended by striking out "building" each place it occurs and insert- ing in lieu thereof in each such place i•project {3) Section 2l(b) of such Act (D Code, sec. S-92l(b) is amended by striking out."buildings" and in- serting ,in lieu thereof "project Sec. 3. The amendments made by this act shall take effect as provided in section 602(c) of the District. of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act i f I I</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
