<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-30">
  <num type="law">1-30</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1971</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1975-11-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-30.pdf">D.C. Law 1-30</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 2545</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-30, the “District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1971,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-156, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 15, 1975 and July 29, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 13, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-42 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>RGE Law 1-29 ·espectively. Following the Act No. 1-40, published in &amp;gt;th Houses of Congress for thirty-day Congressional Law No. 1-29, effective Law 1-30 LAWS OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA 1975 Law 1-30 Law 1-30 Revenue Act of 1975-Amendment In the Council of the District of Columbia, November 1, 1975: To amend the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1975 (Bill No. 1-47 BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA THAT: [Sec. 1.] This act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1975 Sec. 2. Section 501 of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1975 is amended by adding the following paragraph to be designated as paragraph (b b) Every bank, trust company, and building association, all gas, electric lighting and telephone companies, and all bonding, title, guaranty and fidelity companies, subject to the provisions of section 50l(a) of the Revenue Act of 1975, shall make and file a declaration of estimated tax at such time or times and under such conditions, and shall make payments of such tax in such amounts and at such times and under such conditions as the Mayor shaH, by rule, prescribe. Such payments shall not be in excess of the amount by which said tax was increased by provisions of this act Sec. 3. This act shall take effect upon becoming law by operation of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. Source. Pursuant to section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, PL 93-198 &amp;lt;the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-156 on first and second readings July 15, 1975, and July 29, 1975, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on August 13, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-42, published in the August 25, 1975, edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a thirty-day review. in accordance with ~ection 602(C)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the thirty-day Congm;;sional review period has expired and, therefore, cites this legislation as D. C. Law No. 1-30, effective November 1, 1975. 73</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
