<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-44">
  <num type="law">1-44</num>
  <heading type="short">Amended Unincorporated Business Franchise Tax Revision Act of 1975</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1976-02-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-44.pdf">D.C. Law 1-44</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 4055</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-44, the “Amended Unincorporated Business Franchise Tax Revision Act of 1975,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-188, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Urban Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 7, 1975 and October 21, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 5, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-62 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the Distr ict of Columbia Self- Government and Governmenta l Reorganization Act, PL 93 198 the Act) the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No 1-188 on first and second readings October 7, 1975, and October 21, 1975, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 5, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act No 1- 62, published in the November 13, 1975, edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 3 0- da y rev iew, in accorda nee with Section 602(c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30- day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the fo llowing legislation as D. C. Law No. 1- 44, effective February 3, 1976 r D C Law 1 14 In the Council of the District of Colum~ia February 1, 1Q7n The second amendment of lq7~ to the District of Columbia Income ann Franchise Tax Act of 1947 as it affects unincorporated businesses. BE IT ENACTED BY THE C&amp;lt;1UNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OP COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Amended Unincorporated Business Franchise Tax Revision Act of 1Q75 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Unincorporated Business Franchise Tax Re~Tision act of 11:171 C.a. 1-.11) is hereby repealed. Sec. 3. Section 1(a 15) of the Title II I of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of l q4 7 (D. c. Code, sec. 47-1557b(a 15 is amended to read as follows: n 15) Reasonable Allowances for Salaries A reasonable allowance for salaries or other compensation for personal services actually rendered, except that A) in the case of an unincorporated business i) which by law, custom, or ethics cannot be incorporated ii) which can be incorporated only under the District of Columbia Prof essional Corporation Act (D. C. Code, sec. 29-1101 et seq.)7or -2 iii} in which more· than 80 pcr c n t 0 income is derived from the persona l services actually rendered by the indiviQual owners or t he membe rs of the partnership or ot!1er entity and in which capital is not a material income-producing factor, the aggregate deduction for service s r end2red by t he individual owners or Lle~bers actively engage~ in the conduct of sue~ an unincorporated business shall in no event exceed 70 percent of the net i~ccne of such uni.'1:corporatecl business cor:-iputed &amp;gt;li t:~c:.ut be nefit of th.1-.s deduction; and B) in the case o f all otLer U!"lin c gt po::ated businesses t o which paragraph (A) docs not apply, the aggregate deu~ction for services rendered by the individual o~mers or rnenhers act ively engaged in t he conduct of the unincorporated business shall in no event ceed 3 O percent of the net income of such I I unincorporated business computed without benefi t of this deduction Nothing contained in paragraphs (A) or (B) shall be construed to exempt any salary or other compe~sution for per sonnl services from taxat ion as a part of the taxable income of the person rece iving such salary or other compensation .n f:urallod Original 3 Sec. 4. Section 4 of Title VIII of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 (D.C. Code, sec. 47-1574c) is amended to read as follows Sec. 4 xemption. taxable income of- Before computing the tax on the a) an unincorporated business l) which by law, custom or ethic cannot be incorporated 2) which can be incorporated only under the District of Columbia Professional Corporation Act (D.C. Code, sec. 29-1101 et seq or 3) in which more than 80 percent of the gross income is derived from the personal services actually rendered by the individual owners or members of the partnership or other entity and in which capital is not a material income-producing factor, there shall be deducted therefrom an exa~ption of $2500, except that where the period covered by any return is for less than a .Year, or where a return shows that an unincorporated business has been engaged in for less than twelve ·months, such exemption shall be prorated on a daily basis; and b) all other unincorporated businesses to which paragraph (a) does not apply, there shall be deducted therefrom an exemption of $5000, except where the period covered by any return is for less than a year, or where d 0-i i:nal r:rrollC D -4- the return shows that the· unincorporated business has been engaged in for less than twel~e months, such exemption ~hall be prorated on a daily basis. Any amount exempte&amp;lt;.1 under the provisions of this section from the tax imposed by section 3 of this Title shall be reported and included in the gross income of that person or those persons entitled to a share therei~ in proportion to the share to which each person is entitled, and shall be reported in the return of each such person for his taxable year in which is ended the taxable year of the unincorporated business Sec. 5. The amendments made by this act shall apply with respect to taxable year~ beginning on or after January l, 1975. I j I· Docket for the Dill 1-188 Considered in Council 10-7-75 Fir.s t vote 10-7-75 Secretary of the Coun.cil) Final vote in Council l 0-21-75 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE -CO_U_l_'C-l l M_C:_M E n h_c_s_i·-NO r n A-.O CCLJl:C11 l.MOCn n.i tt .A i' cou 11 C•U:·C~ TUCK_ER I x I II DD&amp;lt;O. N I x I I I 1-;ls..PAUJ DT1 MOORE D. I I _JJLJ ii HABDV x I ii M l\i JI v BA&amp;gt;RBV I x I I I HOSS ON i x I l=:Jr r r x_l 1 i l c T .ARKE. I I I II M gt T. I x I I J 1--ll t T.ES x I 'lS.HA.C1Ll..ETON x I I l ·1 4 X-Inclica!cs Vole P R rcsc111 A. B.-A.l' SC::11 n. A RNc lt;'d Yr P f A. ts \rt LK._l Presented td the ~ayer ccr 2 4 ig1s MC?.yor' s action ap ov V ilii uV i3/S P- e c Signat_ure.U 5 NOV 1975 disappr-ov_e·i I I Enacted without Mayor's signature Secretary of the Council I v n Dill Dor.kct 1-188 Pare Two Reconsidered by Council Vote RECCRD OF COUNC I L VOTE Presented to the Prccidcnt Sus t n lt yor' s v to Not Su~ tt: in r yo s veto Submitted t.o the Cong=e~s Senate action i resolution number Secrct~ry of the Senate) Enacted without Congressional action (Sccrct~ry of the Council Secreta ry of t 11c Co·.mc i l Secre t ary o f th2 Co uncil Pres i dent o f the U.S Secretary of the Co~ncil House action resolution nm:i H:!r Clerk o f t he House n a 0 Q</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
