<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-45">
  <num type="law">1-45</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1976-02-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-45.pdf">D.C. Law 1-45</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 4678</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-45 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-184, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 7, 1975 and October 21, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 7, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-65 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, PL 93-198 (the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No, 1-184 on October 7, 1975 and qctober 21, 1975, respectively. Following the Mayor's signature on November 7, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act no. 1-65, published in the November 2 8, 1975, editron of the C Register, and trans.mitted to both Houses of Con~ess for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c){l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D.C. Law No. l-45, effective February 17, 1976. Chairman o the Council 1-45 In the Council of the District ot Columbia February 17, 1976 A hill to amenn publication of sample ballots requirements; and for other purposes. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCII. OF THE D!STP.!CT OF co:r_,mtBIA I That this act may he cited as the "Publication of Sample Ballots act of 1975 Sec. 2. Paragraph 3 of subsection (a) of Section 5 of the District of r.olu:rnhia Elections Act D.C. Code, sec. 1- llOS(a 3}}, is arnenden hy deleting the perioc at the end of the subsection anrt by inserting the folloving at the end of the sub section: II PRO~!InEn, however, not ling contained herein shall require the publication of a saMple copy of the official ballots to he usen in the Advisory Neighborhood Commissions' elections Sec. 3. This act shall becoMe effective as providen by section ~02{c) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and r:ievernrnental Reorganization Act Doclcc:t fot• the Dill 1-184 Conoidcrad in Council October 7, 1975 r"irot vote October 7 I 197 5 Rl COJ~D. OF COUNCIL VOTC Final vote in Council Octooer 21, 1975 RECORD OF COUNCI L VOTE lf 1 y t [ ittii F· 1 µ·y T. 11 iili amp tTf r t ll f&amp;lt 1~ossoN 1 x i-·J }w.m.IER Lx..L 1 i c= MOOBJ D Ix D.V xi =liY&amp;lt;IIS!lt' ix I 1 I j _c.u.JlKE j- 1..M..QQR.E..J._j..X L 1_J I 1 I I I -COh.1:£,C: I X I ![S.HA.CK.L.UQN X l i :J 1 ir I I i X-lnclkatcs Vojc r&amp;gt H c:scr:t A Al c~I fl l\ 7RN:ic&amp;gt;p!rd ecretary of the Council} Presented to the Uayor 4~:IT Cr Vd.~eC w Secre ary of the Council Wvt;;z!/Lt Mayor's action approve i t 7 NO'J 1975 di~approvp l NO'i Enacted without Mayor's signature \ I l Sc c r ct il r y of the Council Bill Docket 1-184 Pare Two Reconsidered by Council Vote Secretary of the Co•Jncil) Prer::i nted to the Pre~ ident Secretary of th~ Council) Sust 5.n ii:ayor's veto Not Suctc.in t.:G.yor•s veto Presi,'ient of th~ U.S Submi ttcd t.o the Congret3s NOV 1 7 1Si5 Secretary of the Co~ncil Senate action House action reS l_ution number resolution nm:'lber Secretary of the Senate Clerk of the House nacted without Congressional action ecretary of the Council)</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
