<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-50">
  <num type="law">1-50</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Boxing and Wrestling Commission Act—Amendment of 1976</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1976-02-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-50.pdf">D.C. Law 1-50</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 5127</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-50, the “District of Columbia Boxing and Wrestling Commission Act—Amendment of 1976,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-168, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 21, 1975 and November 4, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 20, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-70 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, PL 93-198 (the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-168 on October 21, 1975 and November 4, 1975, respectively. Following the Mayor's signature on November 20, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-70, published in the December 3, 197 5, edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Con;ress for a 30-day review in accordance with Section 60 2 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D.C. Law 1-50, effective February 26, 1976 J STERLING TU,ZER Chairman to ft: Council D. c. LAW l-sn In the Coun c:il of the District of Columbia February 26, 19 7 6 To amend the law of the District of Columbia relating to the licensing of funeral directors, exhibitions of martlal arts, and for other purposes. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Boxing and Wrestling Commission act Amendment act Sec. 2. Paragraph 44A(d 3) of section 7 of the Act entitled "An Act making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes approved July 1, 1902 (D.C. Code, sec 47- 2344a(d)(3 is amended by 1) striking out paragraph (B) thereof; and (2) striking out A immediately after 3 Sec. 3. The District of Columbia Boxing and Wrestling Commission act (Council act no. 1-31) is amended by (A) striking the words wrestling, and martial arts events" and inserting in lieu thereof "and wrestling" within Sec. 2. of said act B) striking Sec. 3 g C) striki the words wrestling, and martial arts 0 and inserting in lieu thereo.f "and wrestling" wherever they appear in Se.cs. 6.(a 7.(b)(l 7.(j 7.(1 and 2 D) striking the words wrestling, or martial arts" and inserting in lieu thereof "or wrestling" wherever they appear in Secs. 6.(a 7.(b)(l 7.(k 8.(c and 9.(a Sec. 4. This act shall take effect as provide~ for acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in Section 6n2(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Go~ernMent and Governmental Reorganization Act. Docket for the Dill 1-168 Concidcred in Council l~b 2~1-_7~5 Firat vote 10-21-75 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTG: Final. vote in Council 11-4-75 11-6-75 Presented to the Uayor t.iayor 's action: approve: disapprove t a J 1llL~~w 1 Secretary of the Council i~K!AfAd Mayor's Signature 20NOV.127:0 Enacted without Mayor's sifnature secretary of the Council) http:O-Lett.IL</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
