<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-51">
  <num type="law">1-51</num>
  <heading type="short">Interstate Parole and Probation Compact Act</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1976-03-12</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-51.pdf">D.C. Law 1-51</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 5296</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-51, the “Interstate Parole and Probation Compact Act,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-91, which was referred to the Committee on Public Safety. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 4, 1975 and November 18, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 4, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-71 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE .DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorgatlization Act, PL 93-198 (the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. l-9i ,on November 4, 1975 and November 18, 1975, respectively. Following the Mayor's signature on December 4, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-71, published in the December 12, 1975, edition of the D.C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section .602 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of theDistrict of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law 1-51, effective March 12 1976 STERLING TtrC Chairman tq the Council \ \ D. C. LAW 1-51 In the Cotmcil of the District of Colurn.~ia March 12, 19 7F. To authorize the District of ColUMbia to enter into the Interstat~ p~~ole and Probation Compact BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUMCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLOMBIA, That this act may be'cited as the "Interstate Parole and Probation compact Act Sec. 2. The· Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized to execute a compact on behalf of the District of Columbia with any of the States legally joining therein in the form substan:t;ially as follows A COMPACT Entered into by and among the contracting states, signatories hereto, with t~e consent of the Congress of the United States of Am!!rica, granted by the Act of May 24, 1949 (4 u.s.c. 1112) given to states (including the CO!!tmonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands Guam, and the District of Columbia) to enter into compacts for cooperative effort and mutual assistance in the prevention of crime and in the enforcement of their respective criminal laws and policies THE CONTRACTDTG STATES SOLEM?JLY AGREE That { http:St.at.es 2 1 1) It shall be competent for the duly constituted judicial and administrative authorities of a state party to this compact (herein called •sending state to permit any person convicted of an offense within such state and placed on probation or released on parole to reside in any other state party to this compact (herein called 'receiving state whire On probation or parole if a) Such person is in fact a residen~.of or has his family residing within the receiving state and can obtain employment there1 "{b Though not. a resident of the receiving state and· not having his family residing there,·the receiving state consents to such person's being sent there Before granting such per:rD.ission, opportunity shall be granted to the receiving state to investigate the home and prospective employment of such person. A resident of the receiyilig .state, wi~in the meaning o~ this section, is one who has been an actual inhabitant of such state continuously for more than one year·prior to his coming to the sending state and has not resided within the sending state more th~n. six continuous months immediately preceding the commission of the offense for which he has been convicted 2) Each receiving state will assume the duties of visitation of and supervision.over probationers or parolees of any sending state and in the exercise of those duties will nrollc~ Original 3 \ I gt 1 be governed by the same standards that prevaii for its own probationers and parolees 3) Duly accredited officers of a sending state may at all times enter a receiving state and there apprehend and retake any person on probation or parole. For tha€ purpose no formalities_ will be required C?ther than establishing·the authority of the' officer a,nd the identity of the person to be retaken. All legal requirements to obtain extradition of fugitives from justice are hereby expressly waived on the part of the states party hereto, as to such persons. The decision of the sending state to re~ake a person on probation or parole shall be 'conclusive upon and not reviewable within the receiving ·state PROVIDED, however, That if at the time when a state seeks. to retake a probationer or ·parolee there sqoul:d be pending against him within the receiving state any criminal charge, or he should be suspected of having committed within such a state a criminal offense, he shall not be retaken without the consent of the r~ceiving state until discharged from prosecution or from imprisonment~;or such offense 4) The duly accreclited officers of the sending s"tate will be permitted to "transport prisoners being re.taken through any and all states parties to this compact, without interference 5 The Governor of each state may designate an officer who, acting jointly with like officers of other contracting states, if and when appointed, shall promulgate a 4- I r r i lt such rules and regulations as may be deemed necessary to more effectively carry out the terms of this compact 6 l'his compact shall become operative immed~ately upon its execution by any state as· between it and any other state or states so executing. When executed it shall have the full force"and effect of law within such state, the form of execution to be in accordance with the laws of the executing state 8 (7 This com~act shall continu~ in force and remain binding upon· each executing state until renounced. by it. The .duties and obligations hereunder of a renouncing state shall continue as to~parolees or probationers residing therein at the·tir.ie of withdrawal until retaken or finally discharged by the sending state Renunciation. of this compact shall be by ·the same authority which executed it, by sending six months' notice'in writing of its intention to withdraw from the compact to the other states party hereto Sec. 3. As used in this act, the term •state" m~ans any of the several states of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto. Rico, the Virgili Is.lands, Gualil, and the District of Columbia~ and_ the ~erm G0vernor" means the chief executive officer of any such jurisdiction. Sec. 4. If any secti~n or provision of this act is held to be unconstitutional or invalid, such unconstitutionality or invalidity shall not affC!ct the remaining- sections or prov~sions of this act I b:irolled. Original -s Sec. s. This act shall take effect at the end of the period proviued for Congres~ional Review o~ acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in subsection (c) of Section 602 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act Docket for the Dill 1-91 Concidcrcd in Council 11~4-75 i I i Firnt vote 1'~4~75 f RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE Jndic::atei VoJe Final vote in Council 11-18-75 0 R EC 0 RD OF C 0UNC1 L V 0 t'E I I I couuc f.~Ct.11 ER YES I NO .n i..a. It.A. I COUNCIL Mi:t&amp;gt;10CR YCS HD 1r.n.1A.D.jn.A. I: C:DUNC:IL C U\CM r.R.jA,D.1H x I x Q.i..Ud.j amp i I ctw 1'secretary of the Council w Presented to the Mayor l~l-_1~9 7_5 amp;.DtC 1975 Ma yor's action approve: [ d~approve QM Secretary Council I 4. DEC 1975 Enacted without ~1ayor•·s signature sccrct~ry of the Council ll Bill Docket 1-_9_1 Page Two Reconsidered by Council Vote RECCRD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCIL MEMUCR Yl 5 HO r.n. A.ll COUNCIL Mc ucn 1'CS NO r.n. A.U. JI.A C:.OUHCll M£Mo"'Cftl;.c:.sl NO l".a n.11 F I I { I I X-lndicutc= Vote P. 11.-Present A. 13.-Ab.sent n A.-Rcadopl«:d {Secretary of the Co•.lncil} Presented. to the President {Secretary of the Council Sustain Mayor•s veto ot Sustain Mayor's veto (President of the U.S.} Submitted to the Congress {Secretary of the Council) Senate action House action resolution nu.~ber resolution number {Secretary of the Senate) {Clerk of the House Enacted without Con~ressional action {Secretary of the Council)</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-451"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-452"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-453"/>
  </section>
</document>
