<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-67" flag="true">
  <num type="law">1-67</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1976-06-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-67.pdf">D.C. Law 1-67</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 501</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-67 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-125, which was referred to the Committee on Transportation and Environmental Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 24, 1976 and March 9, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 1, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-104 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>{ \ COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198) the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No.1-125 on first and second readings February 24, 1976 and March 9, 1976, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 1, 1976, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-104, published in the April 15, 1976, edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both House of Congress for a 30 \ day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore \ ·\ \ I \ I STERLING TUCKER Chairman of th$ Council \ \ D.C. LAW 1-67 I n the Council of the Di strict of Col umbia June 11, 1976 To gran t the consent of the District of Columbia to amend the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact to authorize the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authori t y to establish and maintain a Metro Transit Police force; to authorize the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Author i ty to enter into mutual aid agreements with the various j urisdictions within the Transit Zone, and for other purposes BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Metro Transit Pol ice Force Act of 1975 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia hereby consents to, adopts and enacts amendments to articles I and XVI of title III of the Was hington Metropoli tan Area Transit Reg ulation Compact (D.C. Code, sec. 1-1431 note) as follows a) Section l(g) of article I is amended by striking out "and" at the end thereof. Enralled Origi=al 2 b) Section l(h) of article I is amended to read as follows h Transit Zone' or 'Zone' means the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Zone created by and described in section 3, as well as any additional areas that may be added pursuant to section 83(a and c) Section 1 of article I is amended by adding at the end thereof the following i WMATC' means Washington Metropolitan Area Transit CoITu~ission d) Section 76 of article XVI is amended to read as follows 76 a) The Authority is authorized to establish and maintain a regular police force, to be known as the Metro Transit Police, to provide protection for its patrons, personnel, and transit facilities. The Metro Transit Police shall have the powers and duties and shall be subject to the Enrolled Original 3- limitations set forth in this section. It shall be composed of both uniformed and plainclothes personnel and shall be charged with the duty of enforcing the laws of the signatories, the laws, ordinances, and regulations of the political subdivisions thereof in the Transit Zone, and the rules and regulations of the Authority. The jurisdiction of the Metro Transit Police shall be limited to all the transit facilities owned, controlled, or operated by the Authorityf but this shall not limit the power of the Metro Transit Police to make arrests in the Transit Zone for violations committed upon, to, or against such transit facilities while in hot or close pursuit, or to execute traffic citations and criminal process in accordance with subsection {c The members of the Metro Transit Police shall have concurrent jurisdiction in the performance of their duties with the duly constituted law enforcement agencies of the signatories and of the political subdivisions thereof I 4- in which any transit facility owned, controlled, or operated by the Authority is located or in which the Authority operates any transit service. Nothing contained in this section shall either relieve any signatory or poli°tical subdivision thereof or agency thereof from its duty to provide police, fire, and other public safety service and protection, or limit, restrict, or interefere with the jurisdiction of or the performance of duties by the existing police, fire, and other public safety agencies b) Except as otherwise provided in this section, a member of the Metro Transit Police shall have the same powers, including the power of arrest, and shall be subject to the same limitations including regulatory limitations, in the performance of his duties as a member of the duly constituted police force of the political subdivision in which the Metro Transit Police member is engaged in the performance of his duties. However, a member of the Enrolled Ori_gi:Jal I \ \ c -s- Metro Transit Police is authorized to carry and use only such weapons, including handguns, as are issued by the Authority, and only in the performance of his duties or while on the· transit facilities owned, controlled, or operated by the Authority in direct transit to or from a duty assignment. A member of the Metro Transit Police is authorized to carry such weapons only in the performance of his duties or while in direct transit to or from a duty assignment and is subject to such additional limitations in the use of weapons as are imposed on the duly constituted police force for the political subdivision in which he is engaged in the performance of his duties c) Members of the Metro Transit Police shall have power to execute on the transit facilities owned, controlled, or operated by the Authority any traffic citation or any criminal process issued by any court of any signatory, or of any political subdivision of a signatory, for any felony \ \ 6- misdemeanor, or other offense against the laws, ordinances, rules, or regulations specified in subsection (a However, with respect to offenses committed upon, to, or against the transit facilities owned, controlled, or operated by the Authority, the Metro Transit Police shall have power except in the State of Maryland, to execute criminal process within the Transit Zone d) Upon the apprehension or arrest of any person by a member of the Metro Transit Police pursuant to the provisions of subsection (b such member, as required by the law of the place of apprehension or arrest, shall either issue a summons or a citation against the person, book the person, or deliver the person to the duly constituted police or judicial officer of the signatory or political subdivision where the apprehension or arrest is made, for disposition as required by law. Enroll ed Ori ginal. I I \ 7 e) The Authority shall have the power to adopt rules and regulations for the safe, convenient, and orderly use of the transit facilities owned, controlled, or operated by the Authority, including the payment and the manner of the payment of fares or charges therefor, the protection of such transit facilites, the control of traffic and parking upon such transit facilities, and the safety and protection of the riding public. In the event that any such rules and regulations contravene t he laws, ordinances, rules, or regulations of a signatory or any political subdivision thereof which are existing or subsequently enacted, these laws, ordinances, rules, or regulations of the signatory or the political subdivision shall apply and the conflicting rule or regulation, or portion thereof, of the Authority shall be void within the jurisdiction of that signatory or political subdivision. In a l l other respects the rules and regulations of the a- Authority shall be uniform throughout the Transit Zone. The rules and regulations established under this subsection shall be adopted and published in accordance with all standards of due process, including, but not limited to, the publishing or otherwise circulating of a notice of the intended action of the Authority, the affording to interested persons the opportunity to submit data or views orally or in writing; and the holding of a public hearing. Any person violating any rule or regulation of the Authority shall, upon conviction by a court of competent jurisdiction, pay a fine of not more than $250.00 and costs f) With respect to members of the Metro Transit Police, the Authority shall Cl) establish classifications based on the nature and scope of duties, and fix and provide for their qualification, appointment, I \ c -9- removal, tenure, term, compensation, pension, and retirement benefits 2) provide for their training and for this purpose, the Authority may enter into contracts or agreements with any public or private organization engaged in police trainirig, and this training and the qualifications of the uniformed and plainclothes personnel shall at least equal the requirements of each signatory and of the political subdivisions therein in the Transit Zone for their personnel performing comparable duties; and 3) prescribe distinctive uniforms to be worn g) The Authority shall have the power to enter into agreements with the signatories, the political subdivisions thereof in the Transit Zone, and public safety agencies located therein, including those of the Federal Government, for the delineation \ 10- of the functions and responsibilities of the Metro Transit Pol ice and the duly constituted police, fire, and other public safety agencies, and for mutual assistance h) Before entering upon ·the duties of office, each member of the I-letro Transit Police shall take or subscribe to an oath or affirmation, before a person authorized to administer oaths, faithfully to perform the duties of that J:J OJ J ice Sec. 3. The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and directed t o enter into and execute on behalf of the District of Columbia amendments, substantially as set forth in section 2 of this act, to title III of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulati on Compact with the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Maryland, which amendments shall become effective immediately upon execution of same Docket for the Bill amp;l IZ S Considered in Council 2 2 4 7-.6 \ First Vote 1 3 0 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.8 COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE NAY N.V A.B. COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE TUCKER x DIXON x SPAULDING x MOORE, D. x HARDY x WILSON x BARRY x HOBSON x WINTER x CLARKE x MOO RE, J. x COATES x SHACKLETON x X-Indka.ies Vote A. B.-Absent N,A V.-Not Voting er Secretary of the Council) Final Vote in Council 3 9_-7_6 13-0 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCii. MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.S. COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.a COUNCii. MEMBER AYE TUCKER x DIXON x SPAULDING x MJORE, D. x HARDY x WILSON x BARRY x HOBSON Ix WINTER x CLARKE x MOORE J. x COATES Ix I SHACKLETON x I X-Indii:a1e$ Vote A. B.-Absent N. V.-Not Voting MAR 1 8 1976 Presented to the Mayor Mayor's Action 1 APR 1976 Approved i Disapproved Enacted without Mayor's Signature Secretary of the Council I (Secretary of the Counci l Mayor's Signature Secretary of the Council) NAY NAY N.V. A.B. N .V. A.a l APR 1976 r \ Bill Docket l l_Zs Page Two Reconsidered by Council RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY TUCKER DIXON MOORE, D. HARDY BARRY HOBSON CL.~RKE IDORE, J. COATES SHACKLETON X-Ind.ic:ates Vote A. B.-Absent Presented to the President Sustain Mayor's Veto Not Sustain Mayor's Veto Submitted to the Congress Senate Action Resolution Number Secretary of the Senate) Enacted without Congressional action N.V. A.a. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. SPAULDING WILSON WINTER N. V.-Not Voting (Secretary of the Counci l Secretary of the Council) {President of the U. S Secretary of the Counci ll House Action Resolution Number Clerk of the House) A.B.</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1107.03"/>
  </section>
</document>
