<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-69">
  <num type="law">1-69</num>
  <heading type="short">Criminal Justice Supervisory Board Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1976-06-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-69.pdf">D.C. Law 1-69</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 531</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-69, the “Criminal Justice Supervisory Board Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-211 which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Criminal Law. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 24, 1976 and March 9, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 29, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-102 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self Government and Governmental Reorganization Act PL 93 198 the Act, t he Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No 1-211 on first and second readings February 24, 1976, and March 9, 1976, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on March 29, 1976, thi s legislation was assigned Act No 1- 102, published in the April 12, 1976, edition if the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30 day review, i.n accordance wit h Section 602 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia her eby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D.C. Law No. 1-69, effective June 15, 1976 lt v lt STERLING TUCXER Chairman of t~e Council D.C. LAW 1-69 In the Council of the District of Columbia June 15, 1976 To extend the authorization of appropriation for the provision of legal defense to indigent persons in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Criminal Justice Act Authorization Extension act Sec. 2. Section 11-2608 of the Act of September 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1089 (D.C. Code, sec. 11-2608) is amended by striking therefrom the words "for fiscal years 1975 and 1976 Sec. 3. This act shall take effect at the end of the thirty day period provided f or Congressional review o f acts of the Council in section 602(c) of the District of Col umbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act 8 ill Docket lt;B il l 1 2 l=l Page Two Reconsidered by Counci l RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE NAY N.V A .S COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE NAY TUCKER DIXON MOORE, D. HARDY BARRY HOBSON CL.&amp;lt;\RKE }DORE, J. COATES SHACKLETON X-Indieaies Vote A. B Absent Presented to the President Sustain Mayor's Veto Not Sustain Mayor's Veto APR 1 9 1976 Submitted to the Congress Senate Action Resolution Number Secretary of the Senate) Enacted without Congressional action Secretary of the Counci I) N.V A.S COUNCI L. MEM B ER AYE NAY N.V. SPAULDING I WILSON WINTER N. V.-Not Voting (Secretary of the Counci l Secretary of the Counci l President of the U. S Secretary of the Council) House Action Resolution Number Clerk of the House) A.S. j I i 81·11 1- 211 Docket fo r the Bill Considered in Counci l 2 2 4 7_6 First Vote 1~3 o RECORD O F CO U NC I L VOTE COU N CI L. MEMB E R AYE N AY N 11 A.B C O UNCI L. MEMBER AYE N A Y N .V. A.B COUN CIL. M E M B ER AYE TUCKER x DI XON x SPAULDING x MOORE, D. IX HARDY x WILSON x BARRY x HOBSON x WI NTER x CLARKE IY MOO RE J. x COATES IY SHACKLETON x X- lndica.tes Vote A. B.-Absent N V.-Not Voting a LU ;J!ut Secretary of the Council) Final Vote in Council 3 9- 76 13 0 RECORD O F CO U NCI L V O T E NAY I N 11 COUNCIL. MEMBER. I AYE N.11 1 A.B. CO UNCI L. MEMBER AY E A .B NAY COUNCIL. MEM B ER AY E TUCKER x I DIXON x MJORE D. IY HARDY x BARRY x HOBSON x CIARKE MOORE, J x COATES iX' SHACKLETON x X-Indica.tes Vote A. B A.bsen t Presented to the Mayor MAR. 1 5 1976 Mayor's Action Approved v/2 9 MAR 1976 Disapproved Enacted without Mayor's Signatu re I I SPAULDING T 1X I WILSON y _J WINIER x I I N. V Not Voting (Secretary of the Council Secretary of the Counci l Mayor 's Signature Secretary of the Council) NAY NAY N.11. A.B. I N.V. A.a 2 9 MAR 1976</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
