<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-76">
  <num type="law">1-76</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Consumer Protection Procedures Act</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1976-07-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-76.pdf">D.C. Law 1-76</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 1185</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-76, the “District of Columbia Consumer Protection Procedures Act,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-253, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 6, 1976 and April 20, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 14, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-118 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>I D.C. LAW In the Council of the District of Columbia July 22, 1976 To provide consum~rs in the District with procedures for the redress of improper trade practices, and for other purposes. EE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF TS2 DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA e i t may be cited as the "District of Columbia ConsJmer Protection Procedures Actn i.u.·o~i ii lL:ii 31 2- DEFINITIONS AND PURPOSES Sec. 2 a) As us~d in this actr the term 1) 11 person 11 means an individual, firmr corporation, partnership, cooperative, association or any other orqanization, legal entityr or group of individuals however organized 2 consumer" means a person who does or would purchase, lease {from or receive consumer qoods or services, including a co-obliger or surety, or a person who does or would provide the economic demand for a trade practiCei as an adjective consumer" describes an}•thinq without exception. which is primarily :for personal, household, or family use 3) 11 merc!i.ant 11 means a person who does or would sell, lease (to or transfer, eit:i.er directly or indirectly, consumer goods or services, or a person who does or would supply the goods or services which are or would be the subject matter of a t=ade practice 4 complainan means one or more consumers who took part in a trade practice, er one or more persons acting on behalf of (not the legal representative or other counsel of) such consumers, or the successors or assigns of such consumers or persons, once such 3- consumers or persons complain to the Office about the trade practice 5 respondent" means one or more merchants alleged by a complainant to have taken part in or carried out a trade practice, or the successors or assiqns of such merchants, and includes other persons who may be deemed legally responsible for the trade practic 6 trade practice" means any act which does or would create, alter, repair, furnish, make available. provide information about, or, directly or indirectly. solicit or offer for or effectuate, a sale, lease or transfer, of consumer goods or services 7} "goods and services 11 means any and all parts of the eco~omi= output of society, at any stage or related or necessary point in the economic process, and includes consumer cre1it, franchises, business opportu~ities, and consumer services of all types 8) 11 0f fice 11 Director 0 General Counsel 11 Advisory committee" and other such ter:ns mean the Office of Consumer Protection, and certain senior officials and organizational structures thereof, established in section 3, and further specified in other parts of this act J fl,t"t1 4 b) The purposes of this act are to 1) assure that a just mechanism exists to re~edy all improper trade practices 2} promote, through effective enforcemen fair business practices throughout the community 3) educate consumers to demand high stanCards and seek proper redress of grievances. OFFICE OF CONSUMER PROTECTION sec. 3 a) T!'lere is established an Office of. consumer Protection, which shall be the principal c~nsume= protection agency of the District of Columbia Gove~Dment, and shall ca~ry out the purposes of this act and ot!:ter duties assigned to it bi {ll The Di=ector o: the Office shall be appainted by t ie 1ayor. Th~ Director may hold no other public c·fiice except ex officio as Director 2) The Director shall be chief of any section cf ad~inistration wi~hin the Office, and shall have dixect control of all general a~~inistrative and personnei e:nploye~s ithin the Office. The Director may Plake administrative orders, not inconsistent with this &amp;amp;c::t, for the operation of the Office and to facilitate and foster consumer protection in the District c s 3) Consistent \·1it:1 tl1is act in&amp;lt;l ot-"1 er Di gt;tric lil"&amp;gt s, the :Jircctor :nay hire cni'loyccs, a ign \,,re anc1.dclc&amp;lt;Jz.to functions, of t:1c o ice anti tl1e Di=cctor C e lirccto: o the Directo i:i. section. G of tl1i:3 act. t ouv~1 a Section o= Investigations, and shall a:1?0in a Dc?uty Director-C!"iie! of Section o vestigatio:i.s lo n11y car y out. i;i-.restigati ~e, conciliato!"y anC. ot er lu"t.ie assii cC Cy the Director Director ram ar.iong active l.J r.fC te:-i grs of tho uni icrl Dist=ict c olum~ia ~ar o ic U~lic of=ice, e:~ce c o::icio as Ge.i.eral Counocl e e ayer sl1all ap::oint one Jll-tir.e Suc!1 C:~aniz~tion O:em a. 4 C.O. 73-2lS. October 3 cpealc J.ncJ suc?-1 o ice .i.!3 &amp;lt;'\ o 1 is::c:l. All the l"l01 rcrs, anr3. a: its 0ircctor, a.re t=a cr=ctl to 1e Office of alloca ion 3ncl ot!1e:r f l:i.&amp;lt;ls i•1.:ii~&amp;lt ilc or to e r.i.:i.de l ns'~rr re "Ut~o.-izcC to be t=~n~!crrcd ~o thC Of~icc c o gt; of Cons~mer ~rotcc~ion. re ai:i. sue st.:it".J.s a lt;l conti:i ic to ic subject to· all Jl~s and rc;-ulations gover::1i:i.g sue~ co:.1 gt;ctitive servict U ltil such tine as the :Oistrict Go·1er:i 7le:it r&amp;gt;ersonnel s:l tern is establis!ied i:i. acccrda~ce it~ section 422 of t!!e District C!iai cr Such OSi":ions and gt;~rsonnel ~ay be =e4!=o.n gt;!errccl accordo.nca 7it:1 t~is ilct or an ac i."li!:itrativa c=cier o the (g) C'n le eftective cl.:i.t~ a is act or soon Directer c! t~e o::ic o= Co:i.~u e ctec ior Invcs is;a io \.cnc i.l Coun I n c i o 11.e ec-t.ior o~ Consur.« 1c.:iticn Sf1~ll ic r i.tic solcl y t:C:.a :J.irecto1 of Sec. 4 al Of!'icc r ly l} receive anr! in·;nsti'j.J.tc com~&amp;gt;laL ttS ancl unlat~·f:Jl tr&amp;lt;:1.&amp;lt;!c r ic iccs .l'Jilin:&amp;gt;t consur.icrs; issua 7- summonses, hold hearings, compel the attendance of witnesses, administer oat."is, and take the testimony ·of any person under oath, concerning any trade practice or practices 2) issue subpoenas to compel. the pr0duction of documents, papers, books, records and other evidence concerning any trade practice 3) issue cease and desist orders with respect to trade practices determined to be in violation o·f &amp;lt; District law by the Office 4) report to appropriate 9ove:rnmental agencies any information concerning violation of any lav 5) present the interest of consumers before· administrative and regulatory agencies and leqislative bodies 6} assist, advise and cooperate with pcivate, local and federal agencies and officials to ~otect and promo~e the interest.of the District of Colur=.ia consum r public 7) assist, develop and conduct programs of consumer education and information through puhlic hearings, meetings, publications or other materia1s prepared for distribution to the consumer public of the District of Columbia e 8) undertake activities to encoura9e local business and industry to maintain hiqh stan4ards of &amp;gt; honesty, fair business practices and public responsi- bility in the production. promotion and sale of consumer g_ods and services and in the extension of credit; {9) exercise and perform such other functions and duties consistent with the purposes or provisions of this act which may be deemed necessary or appropriate to protect and promot~ the welfare of Distric~ of Columbia consumers 10) publish rules and regulations gove:ni.n·q the Office's FrCCedwres. developed by ~be Director in accordance with the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act co.c. code, sec. 1-1503-06} 11) implead and interplead persons who are properly parties to a case before the Office under section 6 of this act 12} negotiate agree to, an sign consen decrees 13) determine whether a person has executed a trade practice in violation of any law of the District of Columbia, and provide full remedy for such violation by Znrollcd Cr1eioa1 -9 A} damages in contract, and orders for restitution, rescission, reformation, repair .and replacement Bl stipulations, conditions and direc:ry.iVes, both temporary and permanent of all kinds C) enforcement of orders and decrees, collection of civil penalties, and other activities, in the courts D) and other lawful methods; and 14) maintain both confiden~ial and public records, and publicize its own actions, in accordance with section 6 of this act b) The Office shall: {l) perfor:n the functions of the Mayor, Office of Consumer Affairs or Department of Economic Development in A) the District of Columl ia C~nsumer Credit Protection Act of 1971 (D. c. Code, Title 28, Chs BJ the District of Columbia Con Sm\ er Retai1 Credit Requlation (Regulation 71-18; SP OCRB C) and the Cistrict of Columbia consumer Goods Repair Regulation (Regulation 7~-3 10- C2l render annual reports to the council and the Mayor as to the number of complaints filed and .the nature, status and Cisposition th~reof, and abou~ the other activities of the office undertaken durinq the previous year c) The Office ~ay not 1) order damages for personal injury of a tortiou~ nature 2} apply the provisions of section 6 to A} landlord-tenant relations BJ persons subject to regulation by the· Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia C) professional services of clergymen, lawyers, practitioners of the healing arts and Christian Science practitioners engaging in their respective professional endeavors; {D) a television or raCio broadcasting station or publisher or printer a: a newspaper. maga%ine, or other form of printed advertisinq, which broadcasts, publishes or prints an advertisement which violates District law. except insofar as such station, publisher or printer engages in a trade practice which violates District law in sellinq or offering for sale its own goods or services, or has knowledqe of the advertisinq being in violation of District law E) an action of an agency of government. ON AWFUL TRADE PRACTICES sec 5. It shall be a violation of this act, whether or not any consumer is in fact misled, deceived or damaged thereby, for any person to a) represent that goods or services have a source sponsorship, approval, cer~ification, accessories, characteristics, inqredients, uses, benefits or quantities that they do not have b epresent that the person has a sponsorship approval, status, affiliation. cer~ification or connection that the ?erson does not have c) represent that goods are original or new i~ in fact ~hey a~e deteriorated, al~ered, reconditioned, reclaimed or second ha~a. or have been us~d d1 represent that goods or services are of particular s't.an~arc. quali~y, grad style or model, if in fact they are of another e) misrepresent as to a material fact which has a tendency to mislead 12 f) fail to state a material fact if such failure tends to mislead g) disparage the goods, services or business of another by false or misleading representations of mate.rial facts hl ·advertise or offer goods or services without the intent to sell them or without the intent to sell them as advertised or of!ered; {i) advertise or offer goods or services without supplying reasonatly expected public demand, unless tbe advertisement or offer discloses a limitation of quantity or ot.~e= qualifying condition which has no tende~cy to i.slead; {j) make false or misleading representations of fact concerni~g the reasons for, existence of, or amounts of price redu=tior.s, or the price in comparison to price 0£ competitors or one's own price at a past or future time; {kl falsely state that services, replacements or repairs are ne~ded l} falsely state the reasons for offering er supplying qoods or services at sale or discount ~rices m} harass, or threaten a consumer with any act other t an legal process, either by telephone, cards or letters n) cease work on, or return after ceasing Y:&amp;gt;rk on. an electrical or mechanical apparatus, appliance. c!atte1 or -13- other qooes or merchandise, in other than the condition contracted for, or to impo3e a separate charge to reassemble or restore such an object to such a condition without notification of such charge prior to beqinning work on or receivinq such object o) replace parts or components in an electrical or mechanical apparatus, appliance, chat~el or other qoods or merchanli se when such parts or components are not defecti e, unl~ss r~quested by the consumer p) falsely state or represent that repairs, alterations, modifications or servicing have been made and receiving remuneration therefor when they have not- been made q) fail to supply to a consumer a copy of a sales or service contract, lease, promissory note, trust agreement or other evidence of indebtedness which the consume.r may execute r) make or enforce unconscionable ter~s or ?rovisions of sales or leases; in applying this su~section, considera~io~ shall be given to the following. and other factors l} knowledge by the person at the time credit sales are consummated that there was no reas.cc.able Zarclicd Ori~iD,QJ probability of payment in full of the obligation by the consumer 2) knowledge by the person at the time of the sale or lease of the inability of the consumer to/ receive substantial benefits from the property or services sold or leased 3) gross disparity between the price of the proper~y or services sold or leased and the value of the property or se ices measured by the price at whi-ch similar property or services are readily obtainab1e in transactions by like buyers or lessees ti) that the person contracted :for or received separate charges for insurance with respect to credit sales with the effec~ of making the sales, considered as a whole, unconscionable 5) that the person has knowingly taken advantage of the inability of the consumer reasonably to protect his i~te~ests by reasons of ager physical or mental infirmities. ignorance, illiteracy or inability to understand the languag~ of the agreement, or similar factors s) pass off goods or services as those of another t} use deceptive representations or designations of geoqraphic origin in connection with goods or services nr.ollod' orisi.:iil1 -15 u) represent that the subject of a transaction has been supplied in accordance with a previous representation when it has not v) misre?resent the authority of a salesman, representative or agent to negotiate the final terms.of a transacti"on w) offer for sale or distribute any consumer product which is not in conformity with an applicable consumer product safety standard or has been ruled a banned h~zardous ?reduct under the federal consumer Product Safety Act (15 s.c. ss 2051-83 without holdinq a certificate issued in 3ccordance with section l4(a) of that Act to the effect. that such consumer product conforms to all applicable consumer product safety rules (unless the certificate holder knows that such consumer product does not conform or without relying in good faith on the representation of the manufacturer or a distributor of such product that the product is not subject to a consumer ~reduct safety rule issued under th.at Act x) sell consumer goods in a condition or manner not consistent with that warranted by operation of sections 28:2-312 through 318 of the Dis~rict of Columbia Code, or by operation or requirement of federal law E olled Ori~ual -16- COMPLAINT PROCEDURES Sec. 6 a) A case is bequn by filinq with the Office a complaint plainly describing a trade practice and stating the complainant's (and, if different, the consumer's name and address, the name and address (if known) of the respondent, and such other information as the Director may require. The complaint must be in or reduced by tbe Director to writing b) The Director shall investigate each suc!t: complaint and deterrn.ine l) what trade practice actually oc~w and (2) whether the t~ade practice which occ:cnrred violates any statute, regulation, rule of camnon law, or other law, of the District of Columbia. In carrying out such investigation and determinatton, the Director shall consult th~ respondent and such O'l:ber available sources of information, and make such c:Cher efforts, as ar~ appropriate and necessary to car~ out such duties c) I! at any time the Direc~or finds that t:a.e trade practice complained of may, in whole or in part, Ble a violation of law other than a law of the Districto£ Columbia or a law within the jurisdiction of the ~££ice, the Director may in writing so inform the complainant 17- respondent and officials of the District. the United States, or other jurisdiction, who would properly enforce such law d) Within 60 days after the complaint is filed, the Director sha1l deter.nine that there are. or that there are not, reasonable grounds to believe that a trade practice. in violation· of a law of the District of Col.umbi-a within the jurisdiction of the Office, has occurred in any part or all of the case. The Director may find that there are not such reasonable grounds for any of the following reasons l) any violation of law which may have occurred is of a law not of the District of Columbia or not \-litl i he jurisdiction of the Office or occurred more than three years prior to the f ili.ng of t.~e complaint 2) in case paragraph (1) does not apply, no trade practice occu==ed in violation of any law of the District 3) the respondent cannot be identi=ied or locatedr or would not be subject to the personal juris- diction of a District of Columbia court Q) the complainant. to the Di:ector's ;c owledqe, no longer seeks redress in the case 5) the complainant and respondent, to the Director 1 s knowledge. have themselves reached an agreemen~ which settl~s the case 10 6) the complainant can no lonqer be located. The Director may dismi~s any part or all of a case to which one or more of such reasons apply he Director shal1 inform all parties in writinq of the determination. ar;id, if any part or all of the case is dismissed, shall specify which of the reasons in this subsection applies to which part of the case. and such other detail as is necessary to explain the dismissal e) The Director shall attempt to settle, in acc;:ordance with subsec~ion (h each case for which reasonable grounds re found in accordance with subsection (d Within IJS days after determining the reasonabl~ g=ou.~ds provided for in subsection (d}~ and in no event later than 105 days a£ter the complaint is filed, the Director sball l) effect a consent decree 2) dismiss the case in accordance with paragraph (h 2 3) through the General counsel, present to the section of Hearings. with copies to all parties. a brief and plain stat~~ent of each trade pr~ctice which occurred in violation of District law, the law it violates, and the relief sought from the Section of Hearings for the violation 19 q) notify all parties of another action taken, with th~ reasons therefor stated in detail and supported by fact; such reasons may include only A) any of those in paragraphs (1) through (6) of subsection (d and I (B) that the presentation of a charge to the Section of Hearings would not serve the purposes of this act, or 5) refer the case, with recommendations·for disposition, to the Board of Consu~er Goods Repair services f} When the case is transmitted to the Section of Hearings, the General Counsel shall sign, and serve the respondent, the Office's summons to answer or appear before the section of Hearings. Not less than 30 nor more than 90 days after such transmittal, the case shall be heard. The case shall proceed under section 10 of the District of Columbia hd~inistrative Procedure Act (D.C. Code, sec. 1- 1509 The Sec~ion of Bearings may, without delaying its hearing or decision, attempt to settle the case pursuant to subsection (h and has discretion to permit any stipulation or consent decree the parties agree to. The Director shall be a party on behalf of the complainant. Applications to intervene shall be decided as may b roper or required by 20- law or rule. Reasonable discovery shall be freely ailowed. Any finding or decision may be modified or set aside, in whole or part, before a notice of appeal is filed in the case. or the time to so file has run out g) If. after hearing the evidence, the section.of Hearings-decides a trade practice occurred in which tl:l.e respondent violated a law of the District of Columb~a within the jurisdiction of the Office, such Section shall issue an order hich 1) shall require the respondent to cease and desist from such conduct 2) shall, if such Section also decides that the consumer has been injured by the trade practice, Order redress through contract damages. restitution for money, time, property or other value received from the consumer by the respondent. or through recission, reformation, repair. replacement, or other just method 3) shall state the number of t=ade practices the respondent performed in violation of law U) shall, absent good cause found by the Section. require the respondent to pay the Off ice its costs for investiqation. negotiation, and hearing 5} may include such other findings, stipulations, conditions, directives, and remedies as are reasOllable -21- and nece~sary to identify, correct, or prevent the conduct which violated District law 6) may be based, in whole or part, upon a violation of a li'.w establishinq or regulating -a type of business. occupational or professional license or permit, and may refer the case for further proceedings to an appropriate board or commission, but may not suspend or revoke a license or permit if there is a board or commission which oversees the specific type of license or permit h 1) At any time after reasonable grounds _are found in accordance with subsection (d the respondent the Office (r~presented by (i) the Director prior to transmittal to the section of Bearinqs and after an order issued pursuan~ to subsec~ion (f) has been appealed, and (ii) the Section of Hearings after transmittal to that Section and prior to such appeal and the complainant, may aqree to settle all o art of the case by a written consent decre~ which may A} include any provision described in paragraphs (2) through (5) of subsection (g B) not contain an assertion that the respondent has violated a law 22 C) contain an assurance that the respondent will refrain from a trade practice D) bar the Office from further action in the case. or a part thereof E) contain such other provisions or ·considerations as the parties agree to 2) The representative of the Office shall administer the settlement proceedings, and may utilize the good offices of the Advisory Committee on Consumer Protection Al.l &amp;lt; settlement proceedinqs shall be informal and include all interested parties and such representatives as the parties may choose to represent them. Such proceedings sha11 be private, and nothing said or done, except a consent decree, shall be made public by the Office, any party, or the Advisory committee, unless the parties agree thereto in writing he r~presentative of t e Office may call settlement conferences. For pe=sistent and unreasonable failure by the complainant to attend such conferences or to take part in other settlement proceedings, the Director, prior to transmitt.al to the section of Hearings, may dismiss the case 3) A consent decree described in paragraph {l) may be modified by agreement of the Office, complainant and respondent 23 i 1) An aggrieved party may ap~eal to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals after A) the Section of Hearings decides a case pursuant to subsection (f CB) all parts of a case have been dismissed by operation of subsections (d) or (e C) the Director dismisses an entire case in accorda~ce with paragraph {h 2 such appeals shall be conducted in accordance with the procedures and standards of section 11 of the District of colu~~ia Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Code. sec. 1- L510 and take into account the procedural do.ties p1aced upon the Off ice in t~is section and all actions take by the Office in the case. {2) An aggrieved party may appeal any ruling of the section of Hearings under subsection (j) to the Superior court of ~he District of Colwnbia 3 A) Any person found to have executed a t=ade practice in violation of a law of the District of Columbia within the jurisdiction of the Office i) shall be liable to the Off ice for a civil penalty of not exceeding Sl000.00 for each violation enumerated in an order pursuant to paragraph (9 3 24 ii) may be assessed and made liable to the office for a civil penalty of not exceeding SlOOC.00 for each violation or failure to adhere to a provision, of an order described in subsections (f g) or (j) or a consent decree described in .subsection (h B) The Off ice, the complainant, or the respondent may sue in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for a remedy, enforcement, or assessment or collection of a civil penal~y, when any violation, or failure to adhere to a -provision of a consent dec:ee described in subse~ion (h or an order described in subsections (f g) or (j has occurred. The·of=ice shall sue in that Court for assessment of a civil penalty when an order described in subsection (g) has been issued and become final. A failure by the Office or any person to file suit or prosecute Wlder this subparagraph in regard to any provision or violation of a provision of any consent decree or order, shall not constitute a waiver of such provision or any right under such provision. The court shall levy the appropriate civil penalties, and may order, if supported ~y evidence, temporary, preliminary or perrnanent injunctions, damages. treble damages, reasonable attorney's fees, consumer redress, or other remedy 25 4) The Corporation Counsel shall represent the Off ice in all proceedings described in t.~is subsection j) If, at any time before notice of appeal from a decision made accordj.ng to subsection (f) is filed or the time to so file has run out, the Director believes that legal action is necessary to preser?e the subject matter of the case, to prevent further injury to any party, or to enable the Office ultimately to order a full and ~air remedy in the case, the General counsel shall present the tter to the section of Eearings, which may issue a cease and desist order to take ef=ect immediately, or grant such oth~ relief as will assure a just adjudication of the case, in accordance with such Ce.liefs of the Director which are substantiated by ~vidence. The Section 1 s ruling may be appealed ~o court within 7 days of notice thereof on the ~irector, respondent, and complainant kl 1 J Any =onsumer who suffers any damage as a result of the use or employme~t by any pe=son of a trade practice in violation of a law of the District of Co1urr.bia within the jurisdiction of the Office may bring an act.ion in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to recover or obtain any of the following A) treble damages B) reasonable attorneys 1 fees 26 CJ punitive damages D) any other relief which the court deems proper 2) Nothinq in thiS act shall prevent any pe.rson·who is I injured by a trade practice in violation of a law of,the District ·of Columbia within the jurisdiction Of the Office from exercisinq any right or seeking any remedy to which the person rn.iqht be entitled or from filing any complaint with any oth~r agency 3) AnY written decision made pursuant to subsection (f} is admissible as prima facie evidence of the facts stated therein Q) If a merchant files in any court a suit seeking to collect a debt arising out of a trade practice from which has also arisen a complaint filed with the office by the defendant in the suit either before or after the suit was filed the court shall dismiss the suit without prejudice, or remand it to the Office. Q.l The Director and Section of Hearings may use any power granted to the Off ic2 in section q of this act, as each reasonably deems will aid in carryinq out tbe functions assiqned to each in this section. Each, while boldinq the primary responsibility of the Office for decisi011 in a certain case, may join such case with others then before the 27- Office. No case may be disposed of in a manner not expressly authorized in this section. Every con1plaint case filed with the Office and within its jurisdiction shall be decided in accordance with the procedures and sanctions of this section. notwithstandi~g that a given trade practice, at issue·in the case, may be governed in whole or part by another law which has different enforcement procedures and sanctions m l) Whenever requested, the C£fice will make available to the complainant and respond~nt an explanation. and any other information helpful in understanding, the ~revisions of any consent decree to which the Office agrees. and any order or decision which the Office makes 2) The Director shall maintain a public index for all. the cases on wtich the Office has made a final action or a consent decree. organized by A) name of complainant B} name of respondent 28 C} industry of the merchant involved D} nature of the violation of District law alleged or found to exist (for example, subsection of section 5 of this act involved, or section of a licensing law involved} E) final disposition n) All of the moneys paid to the Office by operation of this section shall be paid to the General FUnd of the District. {o} Every complaint case that is before the Office in accordance wit this section shall proceed in confidence, except for hearings and meetings before the Section of Bearings, until the Office makes a final action or a consent decree p) The Director may file a complaint in accordance with subsection {a on behalf of one or more consumers or as complainant, based on evidence and in~ormation qathered by the Off ice in carrying out this act. Persons not parties to but directly or i~directly intended as beneficiaries of an order described in subsections (f {g) or (j}, or a consent decree described in subsection (h arising out of a complaint filed by the Director, may enforce such order or decree in the manner t=rovided in sut:paragraph (i 3 B 29 q} At any hearing pursuant to subsections (f) or (j a witness has the right to be advised by counsel present at such hearing. In any process under this section, the complainant and respondent may have legal or other counsel for representation and advice. CONSUMER EDUCATION sec. 7. {a) The section of consumer Education shall 1) info.rm the public and the business community of existing laws, regulations and qui6elines concerning consumer rights and stanCards of fair treatment 2) coordinate consumer education programs With. and use consumer education programs to help. carry out, the consumer protection programs of the Office; {3) handle publicity for the Office concerning cases under section 6, whe~ the Director requests 4) aid the Director in the for~ulation of consumer ~rotection plans ar.d recommend legislation and regulatio~s related to consumer education; {5) cooperate with con.su:ner-related agencies. groups and individuals in the D.C. area to improve consumer education efforts. {b) The Section Chief shall be appointed by the Director 30- ADVISORY CO!-l!UTTEE ON CONSUMER PROTECTION sec. a a) There shall be an Advisory Committee on consumer Protection consisting of 11 members appointed by the Mayor for three-year terms. The non-governmental' I members, immediately prior to the effective date of this act, of the Advisory Committee on Consumer Affairs established in Organization O::der No. 40 (C.O. 73-225~ October 3, 1973 shall carry out their terms. No District Govern~ent employees shall be members. Four members shal.1 be Dist=ict merchants. seven members shall be persons with \ demonstrated and current records of activity on behalf of consumers h) The committee shall 1) recommend priorities in, and, at the Committee's discretion, carry out, investigations and research, which concern broad, developing, or frequently encountered consumer problems 2) assist ~he Director as the Director may request 3} monitor the performance and organization of the Off ice, by quantitative and qualitative methods, and make recommendations and criticisms, based thereon 4) cooperate with consumer-related agencies, groups, and individuals in the District and in the 31- metropolitan area to improve city-wide and area-wide consumer protection and ~ducation efforts c) The committee.shall elect one of its members as Chairperson and another as Vice-Chairperson, each .to serve at the pleasure of the Committee, and such other officers and subcommittees as it determines d} The Office shall provide staff support for the Advisory Committee. Appropriate expenses incurred by the committee as a whole, or by individual members, may. be paid when authorized by the Director e) The Committee shall meet on call by the Chai:person s frequently as required to perform· its duties, but no 1ess than once each.month, and it shall submit an annual report to the Mayor, council, and the public f) The Committee shall hold public hearinqs as deemed necessary. SEVERABILITY Sec. 9. If any provision of this act, or the appli- cation thereof to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of this act, and the application 0£ such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances, shall not be affected Oocke1for1he81ll i:i:\I 1 2 ~3 Fint Vote O RECORD OF COU'NCIL. VOTE T cov•C cov c T C~V CI" OflMOI TCCJCIR x Dt:&amp;lt;ON x SPAUU&amp;gt;t x ~DOR D, x l!ARDY x WILSON x BARRY y HOBSON v I WtNTr.R x CLAR~ x KlOR J. x COATES y SHACICJ'.ETON x x IMko Yole A U lf.Y V f. n .71-n 111 .Ml !Secretary ot th• Councill Fin• Vote 1n Council 4-2Q-Zfi 10-0-3 lobol RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE t T f cou ca TUCICEI x 'l'AllUlllC x ltlOl D, x l!AIDY IX 1111.SOR x y HDISON fX I WIWT!R x ci.wa. y ltlOl J I v llW:CZTnr J i t L COo\TU X n• v A y 10 oaldl D' Ji oaldl lw lien Sec of the c:o..tlcilJ IScmorv of C:0 11 I I J c c c c c </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
