<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-79">
  <num type="law">1-79</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1976-09-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-79.pdf">D.C. Law 1-79</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 2050</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-79 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-120, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 3, 1976 and May 18, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 18, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-131 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act L 93 -198 the Act the C ouncil of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-120 on first and second readings May 3, 1976 and May 18, 1976, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 18, 1976, this legislation was assigned Act No. l-131, published in the Tune 29, 1976, edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to boLii Houses of Congress for a 30-day review in accordance with Section 60 2 {cT(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Col umbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and therefore, cites the legislation as D C. Law 1- 79, ffective September 2, 1976 J STE RUNG T~f C)r..EJ{ Chairman oef the Council (Ref: 22D.C.Reg.718 3,June 29 1976 D.C. LAW ll In tbe Council Of the District of Colwnbia September 2, 1976 To organize the Boa.rd of Elections and Ethics of the Oistrice of Col-wnbia, and for otber purposes. BE I'I' ENACTED .BY TB.£ COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Ttiat th.is act may be cited as the "Distr.ict of Columbia Election Act Amendments of 1976 11 TITLE I ORGANIZATION OF BOARD OF ELECTIONS Sec. 101. This title may be cited as t.be "Elect.ions Organization act of 1976 Sec. 102. The District of Columbia Election Act (O.c code, secs l 110 1 et seq is amended as fol.lows l) Section 2 (11) of sucil Act {D.C Code sec. l-1102 (4J) is amended by striiting out "Board" under section S (a 4) and inserting in lieu thereof •counci.J..11 2 Section 3(c) of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. l-ll03 (c is amended to read ae f ollows c) A 1uun.ber may be reappointed t.o one additional term. No member shall serve beyond the expiration of the term to whico such i: r:Oil Or 2 member was appointed unless such member is reappointed 3) Section 4 of such Act (O.C. Code, see. l•ll04 is a.mended by inse.rtinq at the end thereof the tollowinq d l} The Mayor may. remove a.o.y member of the Board who enqages in any activity proh.il:iited by subsections (a or (b and appoint a new member to serve until the expi:ation o! the term o! the member so removed. When the Mayor believes that any me.m.ber ~as engaged in any such activity he shall notify sueh member, in wri ti!lq, of the charge aqainst him and t lat sueh member has seven days in wllieh to request a heari:lq before the Council on suc:h ~harqe. I! suc:!l member !ails to reques~ a hearing within seven days after reeeivinq S\lch notice then the Mayor may re.move such member and appoint a new member 2) The hearing requested by a member may be eit er open or elosed, as reCIUested by suc:h member. In the event such hearing is closed, the vote of the Council as a result of such hearing s ha.ll be t aken at an open meeting o! t!le Council. The Council sha.ll begi.!l such hearinqs within seven calendar days after receiving notice from the Mayor i.ndicati.nq that a 1:t1ember has requested such a hearinq. If two-thirds of the CoWlcil vote t o re.move such ineinber then such member shall be removed. 4 (e An.y vacancy occurring on the Board .shall be fil l ed withj or~y-five days after the occurrence of such vacancy excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays nrol.led· origillal 3 4) Section 4 of such Act (O.C. Code, sec. 1•1104 is further amended by redesiqnatinq subsection (b) as subsection (e and by insertinq the following immediately after subsection (a b) No person, while a member of the Board, shall (l campaign for any other public office { 2) hold any office in any political party or political committee 3 participate in or contri.h.ute to any political campaign of any candidate in any election held under this Act 4) a.et in his eapaci ty as a member, to directly or indirectly attempt to influence any decision of a District government agency, department, or instru- mentality relating to any action which is beyond the ju:is- dictiQn of the Board, or (5) be convicted of .having committed a felony in the District of Columbia; or if the e:i.me is committed elsewhere, conviction of such offense as would b&amp;amp; a felony in the Oistrict of Columbia 5 Section 5 of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. l-1105 is amended by (A) striking out ~and" in paragraph (8 thereof B} redesignating paragraph (9 as paragraph (ll and (C) inserting the following paraqraphs immediately after paragraph 8 thereof 9) take all reasonable steps to inform all residents and voters of elections and means of casti ng vo tes therein 10 take all reasonable steps to register overseas ci t i2en voters as provided by the Overseas Citizens Voting Rights Eu.oiled Origiil.al 4 Act of 1975 P.t. 94-203)1 and 6) Section 5 of suc:h Aet (O.c. Code, see. l-1105) is further amended by insertinq at the end thereof the followinq h) Notwithstanding provisions of the Oistric:t of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Code, see. 1-lSOl et seq.}, the Board may hear any challenge ~rouqht to it Wlder this Act by one member panels. An appeal. from a decision of any such one member panel may be ta.ken to either the full Board or to the District of Col\llllbia Court of Appeals, at the option of any adversely affected party. If appeal is taken directly to the Oistri~t of Columbia Court of Appeals, the decision of a one meml;)er panel shall be, for purposes of such appeal, considered to be a final decision of the Board. If an appeal is ta.ken from a decision of a one member panel to the full Board, the decision of the one member panel shall be stayed pending a final decision of the Board. The Board may, upon a vote of the majority of its members, hear de novo all issues of fact or law relating to an appeal of a deeision of a one member panel, except the Board may decide to eonsider only the record made before such one member panel. A final decision of the full Board, relating to an appeal brought to it from a one member panel, shall be appeala..ble to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals in the same manner and to \ the same extent as all other final decisions of the Board 7) Section SCp) of such Act {D.C. Code, sec. l-1108 (p 2 is amended by striking weiqht" in the fourth line thereof and inserting in lieu thereof "fifteen 8) Subsections (a} (l B} and (o) {A) of Section 8 of such Act (O.C. CcC.e, secs. 1-1108 (a} {l B o} (A)} are each amended 5 by strikinq •sixtieth" wherever it appears in those subsections and inserting i8 lieu thereof L-i each subsection •sixty ninth 9 ubsections Ci} (l} (B i 3 and (o) of Section 8 o f such Act (O.c. Code, secs. 1-1108 Ci l B i 3 Co }) are each amended by striking •one hundred fourteenth" wherever it appears in those subaec1:ions and inserting in lieu thereof in each subsection "one hundred twenty third 10 Subsections i 3 and {o of Section 8 of such Act (D.c. Code, secs. l-1108 (i 3 o a.re each amended by striking "eighty fifth" wherever it appears in those subsections and inserting in lieu thereof in each subeection "ninety fourth 11 Subsection j ll (B) of Section 8 of such ~ct (O. C. Code sec. 1-llOS (j Cl B is amended by ·strikinq "one hundred fourteen" and inserting in lieu thereof "one hundred twenty three 12 Subsections Ci l A i 2 A and j 1 A) of Section 8 of such Act (D.C. Code, secs. 1-1108 Ci 1 A i 2 j 1 A are each amended by striking "sixty" wherever it appears in those subsections and inserting in lieu thereof in each subsection "sixty nine Sec. 103. The provisions o! this title shall take effect at the end of the thirty day period of review P.rovided for acts of the Council in section 602 (c o! the District o! Columbia Se lf- Go vernment and Governmental Reorgani:ation Act D. C. Code, sec 1- 14 7 c Em-oUod OrigillaJ 6 TITLE II CONFLICTS OF INT!:REST AND DISCLOSURE Sec. 20l. This title may be cited as the wconfliets of Interest and Disclosure Amendments Act of 1976 Sec. 202. Section 601 of the Oistrict of Coluzn ia Conflict of Interest Act (D.C. Code, sec. l-ll8l) is amended as follows l) Subsection (c) o! such section (D.C. Code, sec. l-llSl (c)} is amended by stl:'iking out •or which would =ause the total value of such things received from the sazne person not a member of such public official's household to exceed $100 during any single calendar yeaz 2) Paragraph Cl) of subsection (i) of such section (D.C. Code, sec. 1-llSl(i) {l is amended to read as follows c1 public official' means (A) the Mayor of the District of Columbia, a memt&amp;gt;er or the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia, or a member of the District of Columbia Board of Education~ {B) an officer or employee of the Oistrict of Columbia government who holds an appointment in the General Service schedule classified as a GS-15 or higher C) any person holding an appoint- ment of the Oistrict of Columbia Board of Education as a Class 3 or higher; or (D) any person who is otherwise empl~yed by the District of Columbia government entitled to receive compensation at an annual rate of $29,818, or more Enrolled origiDJl 1 Sec. 203. Section 602 of the District of Colwnbia confli~t of Interest Act {O.C. Code, sec. l-1192) is amended a.s follows: {l) Subsection Cb) of such section 602 (D.C. Code, sec. l-llB2 (b is .amended by inserting •c1&amp;gt immediately after o J and by redesignatinq pa.raqraphs Cl 2 and (3) thereof as (A S and (C) respectively 2) Subsection {b) of such section 602 (D.C. Code, see l-ll82(b}) is further amended by insertin or any other employee who makes field decisions listed i.n s\ll:lsection Cb 2) of this section" immediately after •or any higher grade or position 3) Subsection (b) of such section 602 (0.C. Code, sec. l-ll82 (b is further amended by adding the -followi.ng at the end thereof 2 A) Any District of Columbia government employee who makes decisions in areas of contracting, procurement, administration of grants or subsidies pla."lning or developing policies inspecting, licensing, requlating, auditi ng, or acting in areas ot responsibility involving any potential conflict of interest as the Board may determine, shall also file a Confidential Financial Statement containing the infonnation specifi ed in para- graph (l of this subsection, PROVIDED, THAT th Board of Elections and Ethics shall cause to be printed in the District of Columbia Reqist er a list of all posi~ions by job classification involving field decisions, as defined in this subsection, within one hundred 8 twenty days of the effective date of this act, and that no person shall be required to file under the provisions of this paragraph until ninety days after the list has be~n published in the District £!Columbia Reqister B) An individual or class of individuals may be exempted from the filinq requirements of subsection G02 (b} (l only upon a determination by tha Boa.rd that the duties of the individual or ~lass of individuals do not involve decisions in areas specified in pa.raqraph (2 A} of th~s subsection 4 Subsection (d of such section 602 (D.C. Code, sec l-ll82 (d is amended by inse.rti.nq at the end thereof t he following The Board shall publish, in the Dist=ict of Columbia Reqister, not later than the fi=st day of June each year, the names of the c andi- dates, o~ficers, and employees who have filed. a report \lllder t s section. Any paper which has been filed with the Boa.rd for longer than seven years, in accordance with the provisions of this section, shall be returned to the person who filed it or his leqal representa- tive. In the event of the death or termination of service of the Mayor Chai r.nan or member of the Cou.~ciJ. o f the Distric~ of Columbia, or Chaixman or member of the Board of Education of the District of Columbia, or officer or employee of the District of Columbia, such papers shall be returned unopened to such individual, or to the surviving spouse or legal representative of such individual wi thin one year after such ceath or 'termi nation of service 5) Subsection (g) of such section 602 (D.C. code, sec l-l l8 2 (g is amended to read as f ollows w(g For the purpos es o f any report r equired by this section, any indivi dual sha ll be considered to have been ~oiled Origi.aal 9 a public official, if he has served as a public official for more than thirty days durinq any calendar yaar 6) Subsection (h) of such section 602 (O.C. Code, sec. l-ll82(h is amended by inserting at the end thereof the following 7 gift' means a payment, subscription advance, forebeara.nce, rendering or deposit of money, services or any thing of value, unless ·consideration of equal or greater value is received, for the purpose of influencing the actions of a public of!icial in making. or influencing the making of an adJni.nistrative decision or l egis l ative action~ and shall not include a political con~:ibution otherwise reported as required by law, a commercially reasonable l oan made in the ordinary course of business, or a gift received from a member of the person's i.mznediate family 7) Such section 602 (O.C. Code, sec. l-1182 is fu~~er amended by inserting at the end thereof the following j) No person shall ur.lawfully disclose or use for any purpose other than in accordance ~ith the terms of this Act any information contained in financial statements required by this Act 8) Such section 602 {b D.C. Code, sec. 1-1182 (b l) is further amended by inserting at the end thereof t;he following J Before the first day of February of each year, the chief executive o f the Executive Branch of the District of Columbia Government, the District o f Columbia Court of Appeals, the District of Columbia Superior Cou t, the Council o f the Distric~ of Columbia the Board o f Educat~on, and any independent agency or ~olled orig 10 instrumentality of the District of Columbia· shall submit on behalf of their respective aqe.ncy, the names and current mailinc; addresses of all person5 required tc file a Confidential Personal Financial Di.1closure Statement with the Director of Campaiqn Finance. It shall be the responsibility ot each chief executive to maintain the currency of the names and current mailinq addresses of all persons required to file under this A.ct, and to advise the Director of Campaign Finance within twenty-one days of such person's apt)ointment, election, resiqnation, termination, or death Sec. 204. The provisions of this title shall take effect at t.~e end of the thirty day period of review provided for acts of the Council in section 602{c) of the District of Columbia Sel Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (D.C. Code, sec. l-l47 (c PROVIDED, THAT the provisions of section 203 (8) of this act shall not become effective until. t.~irty days after the provisions of the amendment made by that section are implemented. TITLE !II LOBBYING Sec. 301. This title may be cited as the Lobbying Amendments of 1976 Sec. 302. Title V of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform. and Conflict of Interest A.ct D.C. Code, sec. l-1171--1-1180 is amended to read as follows sec. Sol. DEFINITIONS As used in this title, unless the context requires otherwise a The term 'administrative decision' means any action by an executive agency to: {1) formulate or promulgate a rule lled OrigiDal ll requla.tion, or order 2) issue a written official. opinion reqardin9 a. matter within the competence of the executive asency; or (3) expend more than $5,000 in a contract which is let with two or less bidders b) The term 'compensation' means any money or thi.'19 of value received or to be received from a person acting as a lobbyist, whethe~ in the form of a fee, income orebearance, toregiveness, reimbursement, or any other form of recompense, or any combination thereof, except where compensation is to be reported by or for a person whose lol:lbyinq is incidental. to his regular employment it sha1l be sufficient to report a prorated aJnount based on the percentage of the time devoted to lobbying c) The te.rm 'executive agency' means a eomm.ission board, depar"t.ment, aqency, office, or other body or official in t.~e executive branch of the District of Columbia government and any independent body of the District of Columbia government that is not a part of the legislative or judicial branch d) The term 'gi!t' means a payment, subscription advance, forebearanee, rendering or deposit of money, services or anything of value, unless consideration of equal or greater value is received, for the purpose ot influencing the actions of a public official i n ma.king or influencing the making of an administrative decision or legi slative action; and shall not include a politi al contribution otherwise reported as required by law, a commercially reasonabl e lean made in the ordinary course of business, or a gift l2 received from a member of the person's hou•ehold a• defined by section 60l(i 4) of this Ac:t (O.C. Code, see. l-ll5l (i 4 ce&amp;gt; The term 'leqislative action' includes any activity conducted by an official in the le&amp;lt;Jislative branch in the normal course of carrying out his duties as such an official, and relating to the introduction, passage or defeat of any le&amp;lt;Jislation in the Council, or to any action with respect to a matter which is within th• jurisdiction of the Council f) The term 'lobbying' zneans communicating directly or soliciting others to communicate with any official in the legis- lative or executive branch of the District of Colwnbia governmen~ with the purpose of influencing any legislative action or administra- tive decision. For the purposes of this title, the appearance by a person in his own behalf or representation by an attorney on behalf o! any person in a rule makinq, rate ma.kine; or adjudicatory hearing before an executive agency or before the tax assessor; or before the Council of the Oistric.t of Columbia or one of its standing or special committees if a public record is made of the proceeding; before the Council of the District of Columbia or one of its stand.il1q or special committees 1! invited by the Council or committee during &amp;amp; public meeting, shall not be considered lobbying. All other activities boy person.s or attorneys, including ex parte contacts to public officials, shall be consid~red lobbying g 13 cq) The term 'lobbyist' means any person who enqaqes in lobbying. Public officials communieatinq directly or soliciting others to communicate with other public officials shall not be deemed lobbyists for the purposes of this Act, so long as such public officials do not receive compensation in addition to their salary !or such communications or sol.icitations and made s uch communications and so licitations in their official capacity h The term 'official in the executive branch' means any candidate for public office in the executive branch or any member, official, or employee of an executive agency i The ter?ll 'official in the legislative branc mea.~s any candidate for Chairman or member of the Council in a primary, special, or general e l ec-cion, the Chairntan or Cha:irman-el ect or any member or member-elect of the Council, any member of a commission established by a.nd responsi.ble t o th• Counc i l, and any officer staff person assistant, o r employee of t.~e Council whether or not he receives remuneration and regardless of t.~e source of the income r eceived j The term 'public offici al means any official in the eY.ecutive, judicial, or leqislatj,ve branch of the Dis~rict of Colwnbia government k The t erm 'substantial economic interest means holding stock worth SS,000 or more, or 30 percent or more owner- ship of any bus i.ness corc:ioraticn, par~ership proprietorship fi=m enterpri s e ranchise association, organi zation, or o~~er l egal entity a 14 Sec. 502 PERSONS REQOIRED TO REGISTER £xcept as provided in section 503, a person shall reqister with the Director pursuant to section 504 of this Aet if such person ca&amp;gt; receives compensation of $250 or more in any three consecutive ealend&amp;amp;r month period for lobbying, whether that compensat:ion is solely for lobbying or the lobbying is incidental to that person's regular employment, except the provisions of this paragraph shall not apply il the person required to file hereunder is the only person requ.red to tile under paragraph (b of this section and the person only receives compensation of S2SO or more in any such period for lobbying from the person filing under paragraph (b) of this section or Cb expends $250 or more in any three consecutive calendar month period for l obbying unless such funds are expended as bona fide political contributions authorized under this Act Sec. 503 EXCEPTIONS A person need not r egister with t.~e Director pursuant to se~-ion 50 4 it such person is a a public official or an employee of the United States acting in his official capacity ft(b) a publisher or working meml gt;er of the press, radio or television who in the ordinary course of business disseminates news or editorial comment to the general public; ft c any entity specified in section l (d) of Title II of the District of Columbi a Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 (D. C. Code, sec 4 7 -1 s 5 4 d activities of which is carryi ng on propaganda, o r otherwise attempting to influence l egis lation o r 15 admi:U.strative decision; or •cd) any canclid.ate, member, or member-elect of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission sec. 504. REGISTRATION Ca&amp;gt; Each registrant shall file a registration form with the Di.rector, siqned under oat..l\ on or before January lS of each year, or not later than fifteen days after becominq a lobbyist (and on or before January 15, of each year thereaftar} If the registrant is not an individual an authorized officer or agent of the registrant shall sign the form. A registrant mu.st file a separate registration form f or each person from whom he receives compensation cb) Such registration shall be on .a form prescribed by the Directer and shall include 1 the registrant's name, permanent address, and temporary address while lobbying ft (2 the name and address of each person who wi ll lobby on the registrant's behal f 3) the name, address, and nature of the business of any person who compensates the regi strant and the terms o f the compensation; and 4 the identification, by formal desiqnation if known, of ma.tters on wnich the regis1:rant expects to l obby. The Director shall publish quarterly a l l i nformation requi red t o be submi tted under this subsection in the District of Columbia Reg i ster 16 See. SOS. ACTIVITY ~PORTS a Each registrant shall file with the Director between the first a.nd tenth day of July and Janua.ry of each year a report signed under oath concerning his lobbying ac:tivities durinq the previous six month period. If the registrant is not an individual an authorized officer or agent of the registrant shall sign the form. A registrant must file a separate activity report for each person from whom he receives compensation. Such reports shall be public doci.unents and shall be on a form prescribed by the Director and shall include the following A) A complet~ and eurrant statement of the infot:lllation required to be s~pplied pursuant to section 504 of this Act B} Total expenditures on lobbying broken down into the follow.L~q categories i office expense!s cii) advertising and publications ciii) compensation to otilers civ) personal sustenance, lodging, and travel, if compensated cv&amp;gt; other expenses. £a.eh expenditure of SSO or more shall a.lso be itemi2ed by the date, name, and address of the recipient, and the amount and \ purpose of such expe~diture cc) Each political expenditure, loan, gift, honorarium, or contribution of $50 or more made by the registrant or anyone acting on behalf of the registrant to benefit an official in the 17 legislative or executive branch, a member of his staff or house- hold or a camp&amp;amp;iqn or testimonial eommittee established for the benefit of th• offieial amp;nd shall be itemized by date, benefieiary, amount, and eircumstanees of the transaction: ineludin9 the a99re9ate of .all such expenditures that a.re less than SSO O) Each business, in wh.ieh the reqist:ant knows or should know that an official in the executive or leqislative branch is a proprietor, partner, director, officer, manager, employer, employee, or has a substantial economic interest and with which the registrant has enqaqed in an exchange of money, goods, services, or any thi.nq of .value if the total of such ex- changes is $500 or more in a six month period shall be identified by its name and address, the officia.1 the date amount, and natu:e of each such exchange E) Each ot£icial in the executive or legislative branch and any member of such official.'s staff who is compensated in any manner by the regis~rant shall be identified by name and nature or employment Fl Each official in the ~xecutive or legislative branch with whom th• registrant has had written or oral communications (during the reporting period) related to lobbying activities conducted by the reqistrant shall also be included in such report, ideneifyi ng the official with whom the communication was mace and the nature of the communication 18 cG&amp;gt; Each person whom the reqistrant has asked to lobby on his behalf sha.ll also be listed in such report b) Each registrant shall obtain a.nd preserve all accounts, bills, receipts, books, papers, and doc:uments necessary to sub- stantiate the activity reports required to be made pursuant to this section for five years from the date of filing of the report contai.ninq such items. These materials shall be made available for inspection upon requests by the Director after reasona.ble notice c) Each person about whose activities a reqistrant is required to report unde~ subsection Ca } of this section shall provide a full account of such activities to the registrant at least S days before such registrant's report i s due to be fi l led d) E~ch reg istrant who does no~ f i le a r eport require~ by this section f o r a given period is presumed not to be receivi~g o r expending funds which are required to be reported under this title Sec 506. RESTRICTED ACTIVITIES a No registrant or anyone acting on behalf of a registrant shall offer, give, or cause to be given a gift to an official in the legi slative or executive branch or a member of his staff or househo ld, t hat exceeds $100 in value in the aggregate in any calendar year b No official in the leqislative or executive branc o r a member of h i s staff or househol d shall so licit or accep t anything of value in vio l ation o f s ubsection (a of thi s s ection c No person shall kn owingly o r will f ully make any false or misleading statement or misrepresentation o f the facts 19 relatinq to pending administrative decisions or leqislative actions &amp;gt; to any official in the legislative or executive branch or knowing a document to contain a false statement (relating to pending administrative decisions or legislative actions cause a copy of such document to be transmitted to an official in the legislative or executive branch without notifyinq such official in writing of the truth cd&amp;gt; No information copied from rec;istration forms and activity reports required by this Act or from lists compiled from such forJnS and reports shall be sold or utilized by any person for the purpose of soliciting eampaiqn contributions or selling tickets to a testii;non.ial or similar fund raising a£f air or for any commercial purpose e No public official shall be empl oyed a lobbyis t while acting as a public official Sec. 507. PENALTIES, PROHIBITIONS, AND CITIZEN SUITS a Any person who violates any of the provisions of t is titl e, shall be f i ned not more than $5,COO or imprisoned for no l onger than twelve months, or both b) In addition. the penalties provided for in subsection (a of thia section, any person convicted of the misdemeanor specifi ed therein may be prohibited, for a period of three years from the date of such conviction, from servinq as a lobbyist c Any person who files a report or registration form required under this title in other than in a timely manner, shal l be assessed a civi l penalty of $10 per day f or each day (exclusing Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays the report or registration form 20 is late. The Board may waive the penalty imposed under this section for good cause shown cd&amp;gt; Shou.ld any provision of this title not be enforced by the Board, a citizen of the District of Columbia may .bring suit in the nature of mandamus in the Supe~ior Court of the District of Columbia, directing the Boa.rd, to enforce the pro- visions of this title. Reasonable attorneys fees may .be awarded to the citizen against the Oistric:t should ne prevail in this action, or if it is settled in substantial c:onfootity with the relief sought in the petition, prior to order by 'th~ Court Sec. 303. The provisions of this title shall take effect at the end of the thirty day period of Congressional review provided for acts of the Council in section 602(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Gover:n.ment a.nd Governmental Reorganization Act O.C. Code, sec l-147 (c TITU IV MULTILINGUAL ELECTION MATERIALS See. 401. This titie may be cited as the "Multilingual Elections Materiai act of 1976 Sec. 402. As u.sed in this title, the term "non-English speaking person• shall mean a person whose native speaking language is a language other than English, and who continues to use his native languaqe as his primary means of oral a.nd written communication. Sec. 403 a) In election wards in the District of Columbia in which non-English speaking persons who speak the same language constitute five percent or more of the eligible Enrolled 9rigin 21 voting population, as determined by the statistical office of the District of Columbia government, the Board of Elections and Ethics (hereinafter in this title ret•rred tQ u the •aoard sha.ll cause all election materials, includin9, but not limited to ballots, voting instructions, and voter pamphlets, to be supplied in both the native language of suc:h non-Enqlish speaking eligible voters and English b) The Board may by requlation adopt lesser percentages of non-English speaking persons in a particular ward or precinct who would be sufficient tc obtain election materials in a language other than English, and may by requlation, establish procedures to allow non-English speaking persons to participate in the electoral process where such non-English speaking persons do not constitute five pe~cent or more of the eligible Voting population in one ward or precinct. Sec. 404. The provisions o! this title shall take effect at the end of the thirty day period of review provided for acts of the Council in section 602 (c of the Oistri ct of Columbia Self- Goverruneot a.nd Governmental Reorganization Act (D.C. Code, sec. l-l47 (c or on July l, 1976, whichever last occurs. TITLE V PRESIDENTIAL PREFERENCE PRIMARY Sec. 501. This title may be c i ted as t.A~e •Presidential Preference Primary Amendments of l9 76 Sec. 502. Section S(b) {5 of the District of Columbia El ection Act (D.C. Code, sec. 1-llOS (b S is amended to read as follows 5) The de l egates and alternates, of each pol itical J:Jlr.olled .Orig 22 party in the District of Columbia to the national convention of that party convened for the nomination of that party for President, elected in accord.a.nee with this chapter, shall only be obliqed to vote for the candidate whom he has been selected to represent in accordance with property promulqated rules of the political party, on the first ballot east at the convention for nominees for President, or until such time as such candidate to whom the delegate is eommitted withdraws his candidacy, whichever first occurs Sec. S03. Section S(b 4) ot the Oistrict of Columbia Election Aet co.c. Code, see. l-llOS(b 4}) is amended by inserting the following at the end ot the subsection or name of the person who sha.ll manaqe an uncommitted slate ot delegates, and the Board shall publish a. eopy of the ba.llot required under this sub- section in the Distriet Colum}:)ia Recister 45 days prior to the primary election Sec. 504. The last sentence of section lO (b) of the District of Columbia Election Aet {D.C. Code, sec. 1-lllO (b is amended to read as follows Candidates receivinq the highest number of votes in elections held pursuant to th~s Act, ot er than candidates tor election a.s political party officials or delegates to national conventions nominating candidates for the Presidency and Vice Presidency of the United States, shall be declared the winners Sec. SOS. The provisio of this title shall become effective at the end of the thirty day period of Congressional review provided for aets of the Council in section 602(c of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental 23 Reorganization Aet D.C. Code, sec. l-l47(c TITL! VI ENFRANCB.ISEMENT OF EX-FELONS sec. 60.l. This title may be cited a. th Enfranchisement of Ex-Pelons Votinq act of 1976 See. 602. Section 2 (7 A) of the District of Columbia Election Act O.C. Code, sec. 1•1102 (7 is amended to read as follows 7 A) Any person in the District of Columbia who ha$ been convicted of a crime in the United States which is a felony in the District ot Columbia, may be a qualified elector, if otherwise qualified, at the end of his incarceration, or completion of his sentence, whichever last occurs Sec. 603. The provisions o this title shall become effec- tive at the end of the thirty day period of Conqressional review provided for acts of the Council in section 602 (c of the District o f Columbia Self-Government and Government~l Reorganization Act. TITLE VII CONSTI~ SERVICES AND REPEAL OF EXPENDITURE LIMITATIONS Sec. 701. This title may be cited a s the ~constituent Services and Repeal of Expenditure Limitations act of 1976 Sec. 702. section 402 of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act (88 Stat. 461; D.C. Code see. l-1162) is amended to read as follows i •sec. 402 a Each member of the Council elected by ward may establish citizen-service activities within his/her ward. Each member of the Council elected by ward may finance the operation of such activi ties with contributions from persons, PROVIDED, THAT contributions received by each such member do not exceed an ~rolled Orig 24 aqgreqate amount of $10,000 in a.ny one calendar year. Each member of the council elected by wa.rd may expend a maxjmum of $10,000 in any one calendar year tor such programs. No persons shall make a.ny contri.bution whic;:h, and no member of the Council elected by ward shall receive any contribution from any person which, when aggre- gated with all other contributions received from that person exceeds SSO per calendar yeu, PROVIDED, THAT such SSO limitation shall not apply to contributions made by any member of the Council elected by ward for the purpose of funding citizen-service programs within his/her ward. Each member of the Council elected by ward shall file with the Director of Campaign Finance, a quarterly report of all contributions received and monies expended in accordance with this subsection. No eampaiqn activities shall be conducted nor shall campaign literature or paraphernalia be distributed as part of citizen-service programs conducted pursuant to this subsection b The Mayor the Chairman of the Council, and each memoer of the Council elected at large may establish citizen-service programs within the District of Columbia. The Mayor, the Chairman of the Council, and each member of the Council elected at large may finance the operation of such programs with contributions from persons, PROVIOEO, THAT contributions received by the Mayor, the Chairman of the Council, and each member of the Council elected at large do not exceed an aggregate amount of $20,000 in any one calendar year. The Mayor, C.'lairman of the Council, and each member of the Council elected at large may expend a maximum of S20,000 in any one cale da.r year for such programs. No person shall make any contribution which, and neither the Mayor, Chairman of the woiJ:ed .original 25 council, or a.ny member of the Council elected at larqe shall receive 4Z1Y contribution from a:ay person which, when aqqraqated with all other contributions re~ived from such person, exceeds $100 per calendar year, PROV!DEO, THAT such $100 limitation shall not apply to eontributions made by the Mayor, the Chairman of the Council, or aJJ..Y member of the Council elected at large for the purpose of funding his/her own citizen-service proqrams within the Oistrict of Columbia. The Mayor, the Chairman of the council, and each member of the Council elected at large shall file a quarterly report of all con~ibutions received and monies e.xpended in accordance with this subsection with the Oirector of Campaign Fina.nee. No campa.i.qn activities shall be eonducted nor shall campaign literature or paraphernalia ba distributed as part of citizen-service proqram.s conducted pursuant to this subsection c Contributions of personal property f:rom persons to the Mayor or to a.ny members of the Council or contributions of the use of personal property shall be valued, for purposes o f this section at the !air market value ot such property at the time of the contribution. Contrit&amp;gt;utions made or received pursuant to this section shall not De applied against the limitation on political contributions establi shed in section 401 ot this Act d) All contributions a..nd expenditures made by persons to the Mayor Chairman of the Council, and each Member o f the Council as provided by subsection (a o! th.is section, and all expenditures made by the Mayor, Chair.nan of the Council, and each Member of t 1e Council as provided by subsection {a of this section, shall be ~olled Origi:i&amp;amp;i 26 reported to the Director of Campaign Finance quar~erly on f o rms whieh the Director shall prescribe. All of the record keeping requirements of this Act shall apply to contributions and expendi- tures made under this section. At the time a program ·of services as authorized in subsection (a of this sect~on is terminated any excess funds shall be used to retire· the debts of the program, or shall be donated to an organization operating in the District of Columbia as a not~for-profit organization within the meaninq of Section 501 c of the Illte lal Revenue Code of 1954, as amended TITLE VIII MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS Sec. 801. Section 305 of the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act (D.C. Code, sec. 1-1155 is repealed. Sec. 80 2 Sect ion 401 of the District o f Colwnbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conf lict of Interest Act (D.C. Code, sec 1-1161) is amended by {l striking the paragraph which f ollows "a member of &amp;gt; an Advisory Neigfiborhood Counci l $25 2 Striki~g subs ections (d 2 d 3 and (d {4 and (3) striking (1 in subsectio n (d Sec. 803. Section 201 of the Dist~ict of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act (D. C. Code, sec. l-11 31 is amended by deleti ng •s10" and inser~inq in l ieu thereof SSO Sec. 804. Section 7 (a of Title VI of Article I of the District o f Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 (D. C. Code, sec 47- 1 56 7 f (a is amended by striking "Sl2 .SO, or $25 and inse rting in lieu thereof 25, or $50 Sec. 805. Section 703 of the District of Co lumbia Campaign Finance Re form and Conflict of Interest Act (D.C. Code, sec l-1192 27 is amended by adding the followinq at the end of the Section AA individual defeated or elected to office as Member of the Board of Education under this Act shall be authorized to transfer any surplus, residue, or unexpended c:ampaiqn funds to any charitable, scientific, literary, or educational orqanization or or~anizations which meet the requirements of section 47-1SS7b(a 8) of the o.c. Code; and an individual elected to an office under this Act and authorized to ·establish a program of constituent services under sec- tions 402(a) of this Act (C.C. Code, sec. l•ll62(a) shall be authorized to ~ransfer any surplus, residue, or unexpended campaign funds to his or her program of constituent services.w Sec. 806. Section 102(hl of the Cistriet of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Aet (0.C. Code, sec. l-ll2l (h is a.mended by deletinq •or group of persons and inserting in lieu thereof a "period Sec. 807. Should a cou of competent jurisdiction decl are any portion of this act to be invalid, the remaining provisions shall remain in etfect. Sec. 808. The provisions of this title shall become effective at the end of the thirty day period ot Congressional review provided for acts of the Council in section 602 (c of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. Docket for ttie em a1 1 1 _1 12 o Considerad in Council s 3 7_5 First Vo111 13 o RECORD OF COUNCIL. VOTE C OUl'ICU. OlllUotalUI N.'tl COUleClL Malllt v COl,IMC~ MllM•ll H.v. TUCKEX x DIXON IX SPAO'LDI?i x K&amp;gt;ORE, D. y HARDY y ~ON x BARRY y HOBSON x Wil'n:ER x CtA.RXE Iv ~RE, J. y COATES IY stlACJJEI'ON y :1 1..i1a1. v A. ll A.tr..a lfA V-Mot Yod.Dg t'J J1J1tJO Secretary of the Council) Fina.I VoUt In Council r 1s 1 s 13-0 RECORD OF COUNCIL. VOTE c:ou11c11 c I A.L C:OIJ \. MllMa&amp;amp NAT N V lt OUNC:l L N.&amp;amp;Y TUCKER x DD:DN x SPAIJll)I!oe x K&amp;gt;ORE, D. x HARDY x W!I.SON x BARRY x HOBSON x WINTn x CL\RKE Ix KX&amp;gt;RE I. x COATES x SHACKLETON x X-ta.d1c.as• Vot• A.B N. v-Mot Vo lt;lWUb Secretary of the Council) Presented to the Mayor _J\JN m_6_ 1.o.w l'.L .w J I A Mayor's Action v6 JUN ms Approved Disapproved Enac1Bd without Mayor's Signature Secretary of the Council) l*rMary of the Council A.a I I JUH ReconsidtrWd by Council Bi.If Docket B 1 ll N o 1 1 2 0 P1geT'WO Votm RECORD OF COUNCii VOTE c:ou y c:ou TS NAY TUC1tlll DIXON MJOR D. HARDY BARRY HOBSON CU.U! MJORE, J. COATES SHACKLETON X--lalflliaal• Vot. A.a Pnmnted to the President Sustain Mayor's Vt10 Not Susujn Mayor's Vno 1t1!11S Submitted to me Congnm Sena~ Action Resolution Number Secretary o f the Senate) En8Cted without Congressional aet1on Secretary of the Co\;ncil C:OUHCI 11111a11i Tt N V SPAULDIK: tnl.SON WINrER I v-M• v.a Secretary of tht Council S.:rttlrY of the Council P~dent of ttie U. S S.Cnrtary of tti• Counci l) House Action Resolution Number Clerk of the House </search-text>
  </meta>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>IV</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>402</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1031.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>403</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1031.02"/>
    </section>
  </container>
</document>
