<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-83">
  <num type="law">1-83</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Aging Act Amendments</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1976-09-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-83.pdf">D.C. Law 1-83</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 2462</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-83, the “District of Columbia Aging Act Amendments,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-249, which was referred to the Committee on Human Resources and Aging. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 6, 1976 and May 20, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 18, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-132 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT Or COLUMBIA NOTICE D C Law 1- 83 Dis trict of C gt;lumbia Aging Act Amendments September 24, 19i 6 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reoganization Act, PL 93-19 8 (the Act the Council oi the Dis trict of Columbia adopted Bill No 1- 249 on :irst '3nd second readings May 6, 1976 and May 20 1976 respectively F gt;llowing the Mayor's signature on June 18, 197 6 this legislation was assigned Act No 1-132, published in theJU~E 29,1979 edition of the D.C. Reaister, and transmitted t gt; both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in a ccordance with Secti::m 602 (c 1) of the Act The Cou:1cil of the District of Columbia hereby g ives notice that the 30 day Congressional review period has expi ed and herefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law L-83. effective September 14, 197 6 lt;Li J I STERLING T:~CK Cliairmar. ctf;he Council (Ref. 22, D C Reg 7237 JU~E 29 1976) D. C LAW 1-83 In the Council ot the District of Columbia September 14, 1 976 To amend D. C. Law No 1-24 the District of Columbia Act on the Aging. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA That this act may be cited as t he "District of Columbia Aging Act Amendments Sec 2. Section 303 of the District of Columbia Act on the Aging (D.C Law No 1- 24} is amended as follows a) In subsection S insert after "Office the following phrase and an analysis of the needs of the aged b} In subsection 9 after "Commission insert 0 for comment c) Add the following new subsection 11 Review and comment on proposed District and Federal legislation regulations, policies and programs and make policy recommendations on issues affecting the health, safety, and welfare of the aged Sec. 3 Section 410 of the District of Columbia Act on the Aging (D C Law No 1-24) is amended by deleting 2- subsections B C D and H. and r ep l ac i:i.g thee with t e following new subsections 13 e1Jiew and subr.iit to t ile layo the Counc i l of t!1e District of Colunbia, and the Office on Aging an ann~al r e2ort including conments on t~e analysis of the needs of the aged in the District of Colu.~bia made in the re~ort o: the Director C \dvise t he i)i=ec t.o on coo9er ation with Federal, state and ?rivate agencies concer~ed with activities pertaining to t he ~ged D Review and cor.in1ent on che annual state i?lan required under the Older Arr.ericans 11.ct The statenent of the Commission shall be transnitted to t he De~ar~~ent of Realt Educat i on and relfare wi t'.1 t he pla :i P evicw ar:d cor ler:t on i e Dir ector s review of ?ro~ose&amp;lt;l Di3trict anc F~cral les isla t ion reg~~atio~s Olicies and gt;r o gr ams and c::x:ment. on t r.e Director s polic y recommendations on i ssues affecting t l e ealth sa.:ety, and wel::are of the aged Sec 4 r.is ac t sha e ef c i ve i nr.\ediate l::t a te e nd o the t~irty day period e~cl~ding Saturdays Sun~ays ol i,~afs a:-ic ca~rs on whic~ ei t:i.cr :1oune o f Co:igr s3 is no~ t he Co:10=ess, as ~rovi~ed in section 6~ 2(c of the Dis ic 3- oE Columbia Self- govern tent a:1d (overnr.ental eo c;ani io n Act. I t 11 1 1.9 Docket for the Bill 0 Considered in Council 4 6 7_6 First Vote 12 0 l a _b_s RECO R D O F COUNC I L VOTE COU N Cii. ME M8 A YC NAY N .\I COUNC I MC:MSCrt A Y E Nl&amp;gt;'I' N .V. A.O. C OU N Cii. Ml aER TUC!&amp;lt;ER x 'DL'&amp;lt;ON x SPAULDING x }()ORE, D, x HARDY x WILSON x BARRY HOBSON x WIITTER x CL\Rl&amp;lt;E MOORE, J. x COATES x SHACKLETON x X-lndica lft Vole A. B.-Ah:sent N. 11- Nol Voling 1~1-t Se&amp;lt;:retary of the Council) Final Vote in Council 4 0 76 10- 0-3 (abs) RECO R D O F COUNCI L VOT E COUN CI\ M l aC:ft AYC N A Y N V COUNCii M£~SCR AY r-.A Y NV C OUNClL 1rro41 C 1ri4a£1t 4YC TUCKE x DIXON j x SPAULDING x I moRE, D HARDY x I WILSON 1X BA!lRY x HOBSON x WINTER x CL\RKE x !1JOR.E I J I x COATES y SHACKI.ETOH x X-lndlca lft Vore A. B.-A.bsent M. V-Mot VoJing (Secrecary of the Council 4 ~71 Presented to the Mayor Q.MW.ly:w Mayor 's A ct ion £/ 11 8 JUN 1970 Approved Disapproved Enacted without Mayor's Signature Secretary of t he Council Secretary of the Council o A Y A .9 I H V A 8 I t'"\ I Bill Docket B i=l l h l 2 3 Page Two Reconsidered by Council REC O R D OF C OU N CI L VOT E COU H Cll 41Mll E l AYI! H AY H .V A 9 COUHCll EM 9 CR .AYI' H AY TUCKER DIXON MOORE, D. HARDY BARRY HOBSON CLARKE HJORE J COATES SHACKLETON X-lndic&amp;amp;les Vote A. B A.bsent Presented to the President Sustain Mayor's Veto Not Sustain Mayor's Veto Submitted to the Congress J_Ull 8 i9 76 Senate Action Resolution Number Secretary of the Senate) Enacted without Congressional action Secretary of the Councill N V. A.a COUNCIL. M£ ll El'I AYl N AY N,\I. Sl'A.ULDI NG WILSON W1NTER N. V.-Nol Voting (Secretary of the Council Secretary of the Council President of the U. S Secretary of che Councill House Action ResoJut.ion Number Clerk of the House) A.8 .</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
