<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-89">
  <num type="law">1-89</num>
  <heading type="short">Condominium Act of 1976</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-03-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-89.pdf">D.C. Law 1-89</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 9532b</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-89, the “Condominium Act of 1976,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-179, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Urban Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 29, 1976 and June 20, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 6, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-151 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> }·} I i-t COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE ch 31, 1977 D.C LAW l-8 condominium Act of 1976 I Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Salf-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill ro. 1~179 on fiJ;"st and second readings June 29, 1976, and July 20, 1976, respe~tively. Following the siq~ature of the j i:\yor on August 26 1976, this legislation .was assigned Act No 1 ] p.ublished in. the September 2 1976, edition of ~e D.C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a .30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 cc {l) of the Act The Council of the District .of Columbia hereby gives noiice that-the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation ~s IJ. c. Law 1-89, effective Ma}:'Ch 2 lg.77 \J.t \ \ \ gt Fl 1 gt gt gt c~ef. 2·3, DCReg. 2141, Septt!mber 24 1976 \ I 11 I t E li L I j\ lt D. C AN l-89 !War 29, 1977 To amend the District of Colombia Code and Requlati.o s to enact a statute providing for the creation and governance of condominiums and regulating the offering of condominium units BE ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OP .THE. OISTRJ:CT. OF COLOMBIA That this act may be cited as the "Condominium Act of 1976 Title I Definitions and Eminent Domain Sec. lOl. Application a) This act shall apply to 1 1 condominiums and to a1l horizontal property regimes ·or c1ndominiam projects. I (b) For the 'purposes of this act l) the terms ~horizontal property regime" and "condominium project• shAll be deemed to correspond to the "condominium 2) the term •co-owner• shall be deemed to ccrresp~nd to the term •unit owner i (31 the teJ:m council of co-owners• shall be ·deemed to correspond to the .term t owners' association 41 the term eveloper• shall be deemed to correspond to. the ten "declarant and 5} the. term •general common elements• shall be deemed to co~espond to the te::m •common elements 1 z 4 I I 2- i { c) This' act shall be deemed to supersede the I Horizontal Property Act of the District of Columbia, sections S-901 throuqh 5-933 of the District of Columbia code (D. c. Code, secs. 5-901 5-933 tbe.Requlation 74- 26 of the Districe of COlumbia City cound.l, and no condominium shaJ..l be established excep-e pursuant to .this ·a.ct on or after the effective date hereof. But this ·act shal:l not be construed to a·ffect the va1idity of any provl.sion of any condominium in~ent recorded, or of any horizontal property regime complying with the requirements of the Horizontal Property Act and registered prior to the eff eC1:ive date of this act Nor sba.l.l lit.le IV of this ac:t deemed applicable to any c:ondominiwns established prior to the effective date hereof, except as t=rovided in section 1n1 ·of-this act. i j sec. 102. Definitions Eor the purposes of this act a Common Elements• shall mean all portions of the condominium other than the units b Common Expenses" shall mean all lawful expenditores made or incurred by or on behalf of the unit owners• association toqether with all lawful assessments for the creation and Ma.i.nt~nance of reserv~s pursuant to .the provisi ons of the condcmi.nium instruments future common \ I 3 expe~ses" shall mean common expenses for which assessmen~s are not yet due and payable c Common Profits" s.ball mean a..ll income collected or accrued cy or en behaJ..f of the unit owne.rs• association, other t.ba.n income derived by assessment pursuant to sec tion 3.12 of this act d Condoininium11 sha.l.l mean real property and any incident thereto interests tbere{n laWflllJ.y submi tt~d to this act by the recordation of condominimn inst uments pursuant to the prcvisi_ons of this act. No projec t shall be deemed a condominium within the .zneaninq of this act unless the Wl.dividt!'d int-e:ests in the ccaunon elements are vested i n the unit cwners. \ (e Condominium Instruments~ shal1 mean the declaration, byla•s, and plats and plans, recorded pursuant to the provisions of this .act. Any exhibit, schedule, or certification accompanying a condominium instrument and recorded. simultaneously therewith sha.ll be deemed an illtegral part of that condominium instrument Any amendment or certification of any condominium irist::ument shall, from the tilrie of the recordation of such amen9ment or certification, be deemed an integraJ. part of the affected c:.ondominium inst;rument, so lonq as such amendmen.t or JI l \ certification was made in accordance with the provisions of this act f condominiuzn Unit" shal.l. mean a unit toqether with the undivided interest in the connon elements appertaining to that unit lt;£ the de.f i.ni ti on of "unit, n infra g Contractable condominium" shall mean a· consiomiili.wsr from which one ~r more portions of the submitted land may ~e withdrawn in accordance with the provisions of ~e declaration and of this act. If such withd:awal can occur only by the expiration or termination of one or more leases, then the condominium shall not be deemed a contractable ccr.dominium-witbirt tjle meaning of this act h Conversion Condominium" slla ll mean a condominium \ c~ntaininq structures which before the recordinq ·of the declaration were wholly, or partially occupied by persons other than those who have contracted for the purc ase of condominimn units and those who occupy wi~h the conse.~t of such purchasers i} "Convertible Land" shall mean a build.in; site; tha~ i is to say, a portion of the common el.ements. within ·wb.ic:h additional units or limited common el.ements, or both, may be created in accordance with the provisions of tllis act j Convertible space" shall mean a portion of a structure within the condominium, which portion may be \ I I -s- conv~ed into one or more units or common e..leme~ts1 or both, in ~ccordance witb the provisions of this act. {~ the definition of "unit infra k Declarant" shall mean all pe ons who execute or prot:ose tc execute the dee.la.ration or on whose behalf the declaration is executed or proposed to be exec:tlted From the time cf the .recordation of any amendment to the dec.laration eipa.ndinq an expandable condozni~um all p~~sons who execute the amendment or on whose bebali th.at a endment is executed shall also come within tll.is definition. Any successors of the perscms referred to in this subsection •ho come to sta d in -tb~ same relation to the condominium as their predecessors did sha.l1 also come withiri this def.£.ni ti-Orr l Jispose" or "Disposition" shal-J. mean any voluntary transfer of a le9al or equital::le interest in a condominium l.!r.i t, other than as security for a debt m Executive Organ" shall mean an executive and administ-~tive entity, by whatever name .denominated and designated in the condominium instruments to act for the ur.it owners' association in governing the condom.in.ium n Expandable Condominiwn" shall mean a condominium to wb.ich additional land may be acided in accor&amp;amp;a.:ice with the provisions of the declaration and of this act r \ \ y \ 6 o dentifying Number" shall mean one or more letters or numbers, or both, that identify only one ur.it in the condominium p Institutional Lender" shall mean one or more commercial or savings banks, savings and loan associations trust companies, credit unions, industl:ia1 loan associations, insurance companies, pension funds, or business trusts, incl udinq bat not tiMited o, real estate i nvestment trusts, any other entity regularly engaged directly or indirectly in financing the purchase~ construction, or improvement of real estate, or any combination-Of an~ of the foregoing entities q Land" is a three-dimensional concept and includes parcels with upper er lower boundaries, or bo~h parcels ex endinq usgue eoleum, and any imp:ovements thereto. Parcels of airspace constitute land witnin the meaning of this act. Any requirement in this act of a legally sufficient description shall be deemed to include a requirement that the upper or lower boundaries 1 if any, of I the parcel in question be identified with reference ·tp esta~lished datum r Leasehold Condo.mini UM" means a condominium all or any portion of which is subject to a lease, the expiration \ \ -7- or termination of •hicb will te=m na~e condo::ti um o= exclude a portion therefrom s Limited Common Element" shall mean a portion. of :he co.rra:aCl:l elements reserved. for the e%C.lus ve use of those entitJ.ed to the use of one er more b.ut iess than all, of the units t Mayor shall mean the Mayor of the Oist:iet; of Co.lumbia a Non!:inding ~eservation Agreement" shal.l mean an aqreement between the declarant and a prospective purchaser which is in no way binding on the a rospec-eive purchaser and which may c:anC"elled withoat penalty at the sole discretion of the ~rospective purchaser by writ~n notice, i hand-delivered or sent by Oni.ted States mail, return receipt requested to the ceclarant at any time prior to the execution of a contract for the sale or lease of a condominium unit or an interest therein. Such aq=eemen shall net contain any provision for waiver or any other provision in derogation of the rights of the prospective I purchaser as contemplated .by this subsection, nor shall any such provision be a part of a?ly ancillary aq:eement v Offe shall mean any inducemen solicitation, or att~znpt to encouraqe any person or persons to acquire any legal or equitable inte.:est in a condominium unit, other I l -s- than as security for a debt: Provided however, that "off2r11 shall not mean any advertisement of a condominium not located the District of Columbia in a newspaper or other periodic~l of general c:ircul.ation, or in any public broadcast medium if such advertisement states that it does not constitute an offer of sale and that an o£fer may be made only in cCDtpliance with the condominium act of the state or terri.tory in which the condorilinitiln ·is l~cated w Officer" shall mean any member· of the executive organ ·or official of the unit owners• associatioa x Par Valtie" shall mean a number of dollars or points assi ned to each unit by the declaration Substantially ~dentical units shall be assiqned the same par \ val.ue, but anits located at substantially different heights above the ground, or ha.vinq substantj.ally different views, or having substantial.ly different amenities or other characteristics that might result in differences in market value, may, but need not, be considered substantially' identical within the meaning of this subsectioi:i If par value is stated in terms of dollars, that statement ·shall not be deemed to reflect or control the sales price ~r fair market value of any unit, and no opinion, appraisal, or fair market transact.ion at a different figure shall affect the par value of any unit, or any undivided interest in the i I I 9- common elements, voting rights in e u it owne =s association, lia~ility for common expenses, or rights t o common profits, assigned on the basis thereof {Y Pezson" shall mean a natm:'a.l person corporation. pa.rtnershit association, trust, or other entity capable of holding ut.le to real. property, or a.ny ·cOD\bination Of any of the fore.&amp;lt;;c:inq PUrc:ha.ser shall mean any. person or perso~ who acquire by means of .a voluntary transfer a legal or equitable interest in a condomini11m unit, other than as security for a debt aa} "Registered I.and Surveyor" shall mean any person or firm pe.rmi ted to prepare and certify surveys and subdivision plats in the District of Columbia, including but not limited to, registered civil engineers bb Si zea shall mean the nwnber of cubic feet or the number of square feet of ground or f.loor space, or both within each unit as computed by reference to the plats and plans and rounded off to a whole nwnber. Certain spaces within the units including, without limitation, attic, basement or garage space, may, but need not, be omitted from such ca.lc:ulaticn or pa tia.lly discounted by the use of a ratio, so long as tbe same basis of calculation is c I r -10- employed for a.l.l units in the cor..dominiwn, and so long as t hat basi:s is described in the declaration cc Surveyor" shall mean the Office of the surveyor of the Oist:ict of Coltm1bia dd Onit" shall mean a portion of the condominium designed and intended for individual ownership £ the definition of "c.ondominiuzn unit supra For the purposes of this act, a" convertible space sball .be treat~ as a .unit in accordance with section 218(d) of this act ee Unit owner• shall mean one or more persons who own a condominium an.it, or, in the case of a leasehold Ondominium whose leasehold interest or interests in the c ondominium extend for the entire balance of the unexpired te=m or terms. Sec. 101. Separate. Titles Each condominium unit shall constitute for all .purposes a separate parcel of real property, distinct from all ·other condominium units. A~y condominium unit may be owned by more than one person' as joint tenants, as tenants in common, as tenants by the I entirety (in the case of husband and wife or in any: oth~r real property tenancy relationship recoqni.zed ander the laws of the District of colmnbia. sec. lO separate Taxation. If there is any unit owner other than the decla:ant, then no tax or assessment 3ball be levied on the condominium as a whole, bu~ only on the individual ccndom.inium ur.i.ts. Each concorrJ ium unit shall be~carried on tbe records of the Dist=ict of Colwnbia and assessed as a separate and distinct taxable tity. Sec. 105. Ordinances and Regulations No ~oning or other land use ordinance or requlation shall prohibit condonz:l n iums as such l::y reason o£ the £orm cf C»tne.rship ·inherent therein. Nei~ber shall any condominium be t:ceated diffe.:ently by any :oning or other land ~e ordinance or regulation which would permit a physically identical project or development under a different form of ownership. No subdivision ordinance or regulation shall apply to any -condominium. er to 1y subdivision of any convertible .land, convertible space, or unit unless such ordinance or regulation is by its ext=ress terms made applicable thereto. Nothing in this se&amp;lt ion shall be construed to permit ·application cf any provision of the building code which is not expressly applicable to c6?idorniniums by reason of. the form of ownerstti.p inherent therein, to a condominium in a manner different from the manner in which such provision is applied to other buildings of similar physical fo=m a~d nature of oc:cupanc:y. Sec. 106. Eminent Domain a) If any portion of the common elements is taken by eminent domain, the award r 12- therefor shall be aJ.located to the unit owne=s in propor~ion to their res~ective undivided interests in the common elements, except that the portion of ·the award attributable to the· taking of any permanently assigned li~ted common element shall be allocated by the decree to the unit owner of the i;nit to which that limited common element wa~ so assigned- at the time of the taking. If that limi-ted· coinmon element was permanently assigned to.more than one unit at the time of the tak~g, then the portion of the award attributable to the taking thel:eof shall be allocated in equal shares to the unit cwners of the units to which it was s~ assigned· or in such other shares as the condcminium instruments may specify for this express purpcse. A permanently assigned limited common element is a limited common· element which cannot be reassigned or which can be reassigned only with the consent of the unit owner or owners of the unit or units to wbich it is assigned b) If one or more units is taken by eminent domain, the undivided interest in the common elements appertaining to any such unit shall thenceforth appertain to the remaining units, being allocated to them in proportion to their respective undivided interests in the common e.lements. The cou shall enter a decree reflecting the reallocation of undivided interests produced thereby, and the a•-ard shall 13- include, without limitation, jnst compensat~on ~o t he uni.t owne= of "any ur.it taken for his ondivided interest in the common elements as well as for bis unit c) I.f pcrticns of any unit are taken the court shall determine tbe fair market value of the portions of such ur.i. t not takenr and the undivided· iJ'.l.tere~t in the common eJ.ement.s appertaininq to any such a its s~al.l. be reduced in the case of each Slleb ·Wu.tr in· prcportion: t .o the diminuticn in the fair market value of such. unit· resulting from the taking. The portions of undivided interest in the common el.ements thereby div~sted from th~ i-:n'it owners-c-£ any si:tch units shall be reallocated among those units and tbe other u.ni·ts in tbe condominium in p~oportion tc their respective tindivided intereses in the common elei:n~nts, with any units partially taken pa=ticipating in such reallocation on the basis of their undivided interests as reduced in accordance with the preceding sentence The court shall enter a decree, reflecting the reallocation of undivided interests produc.ed I thereby, and the award shall include, without lim.i tation just compensation to the "U.nit owner of any unit partia1ly taken for that portion of his und:i. vided inte:est in the common elements divested from him by operation of the first sentence of this subsec-:ion and net revested in him by 1 1 11 14- operation of the following sentence, as well as for that portion of bis unit taken by eminent domain d) If, however, the taking of a portion of any unit makes ·it impractical to use the remaining portion of 1;llat unit for any lawful purpose permitted by the condominium instrum~nts, then the entire andivided ~nterest in the common eiements appertaining to that unit shall thenceforth appertain ·to 'the rema.ining units ing a1located to. them in proportion tc their ~espective undivided interests in the common elements, and the remaininq portion of that unit shall thenceforth be a common element. The court shall enter a decree reflecting the reallocation of undivided interests prcduced thereby, and the award shall include r without limitation, just compensation to the unit owner of r such- unit for the unit cwner• s entire undivided interest in I the common elements and for the unit owner• s entire unit e) Votes in the unit owners• association, riqhts to future common profits, and liabilities for future common expenses not specially assessed, appertaining to any unit or units taken or partially taken by eminent domain, shall thenceforth appertain to the remaining units, being allocated. to them in proportion to their relative voting strenqt.h in the imit owners• association, rights to future common profits, and liabi.li.ties for future common expenses I I i s- r.ot spec~ally a~sessed, respectively, witil any ur.its partially taken rticipating in such reallocation as thoug h the voting strength in the unit ·owners• association, right to futuTe common profits, and liabilities for future common expenses not ·specially assessed, respectively, h~d been reduced in oporticn to the reduc ion·in thei undivided ·interests in the common eJ.ements. But in any case where ~otes in the -anit owners• associa-:icn were originally assigned on the basis of equality subject to the exception for converti~le spaces) votes in the anit owners• associaticn shall not be real.located. The decree of the court shall ~rovid accordingly f) The decree of the court shall require the reco=dation thereof among the land records of the Oist--ict of Columtia. Title II Establishment of Condominiums Sec. 201. Creation of tbe-condominium No condominium shall come into existence except by the recordation of condominium instruments pursuant to th~ recorded unless all units located or to be located on any port.ion of the submitted land, other than within the boundaries of any convertible lands, are depicted on plats ~nd plans that comply with the provisions of section 2l4 {a) c G I J 16- and (b) of this act he foreclosure of any mor~qage, deed of trust or ~ther lien shall not be deemed proorio vigo~e, to terminate the condominium. AJ.l units sha.ll be contiguous, or on the same square, or on contiguous squares, except that common elements need not be en con~guous squares. Sec 202. Release· of Liens a) At the time of the conveyance to the fii-st purchaser 0£ each condo.idniwn unit following thE recordation of the declaration, every mortgage, deed of trust, any other perfected lien, or any mechanics• or material.men's liens, affecting all of the I condominium er a greater portion thereof than the r· condominium unit conveyed, shall be paid and satisfied of record, or the declarant shall forthwith have tbe said condominium unit released of record from all such liens not so paid and satisfied. The provisions of this subsection shal~ not apply, however, to _aAY withdrawa~le land in a contractatle condominium, nor shall any t=rovision of this subsection be construed to prohibit the unit owners• association from mortqaginq or causinq a deed of trust to be placed on any portion of the condominium wit.bin which no units are located, so long as any time limit specif.ied pursuant to section 302(a) has expired. and so long as the bylaws authori%e the same. I I I/ I -11 b} No labor performed or materia1s furn i shec wi t e consent ct or at e request of a un 0 e or s u c .h uni t owner's agent or contrac:tor or \ s contract.or shall be the basis for the fi.linq of a lien pur nt to the provisions of se~ion l23i of 'the Act of Marc:h '3, 1901 (D.c. Code, sec. 38-101 againSt the property of .any un"t owner n t expressly consenting to the same, except that -sucn consent shall be deemed to be given by any unit own~ in th.e case of emergency reµirs to his an.it. I.a.bor per.formed or materia ls furnished for the common elements, if duly autbori:ed by the unit owners' association or its executive organ subsequent to any pe:io_.d of ~ev~loper control pursuant to section 30 2 {a shall be d ed to be performed or furnished with the express consent of every unit owr.er and shali be the basis for the filing of a lien pursuant to the provisions of section 1237 cf the Act of Ma:cb 3, 1901 (D.C. Code, sec. 36-101) against all of the condominium units. Notice of such lien sha11 be served on the principa1 of£icer of the unit owners• association or any member of the exeuctive organ C) In th~ event that any lien, other than a deed cf trus: or mort~aqe. becomes effect:ive agair.st two or more condominium uni ts subsequent to the creation of the condomir.ium, any unit cwner may remove such anit owner's c is- J condominiUin unit from that lien by paymen~ 0£ the amount attributable to that cor.domiIU.um uni.t, or. in the case of any mechanic• s o.r mate.rial.man• s lien by filing a written undertaking for s~ch amount with surety approved by the cou.rt as provided in section 125~ of 1:.he Act of March 3, 1901 co.c. code, sec. 38-118 such amount shall be computed by refe~ence to ·the liability for ·couunon expense5 appertaining ·to that condo~ium t pursuant to section 312 (C Subsequent to such payment, discharge o.r other satisfaction, or filing of bond, the unit owner of that condominium unit shall be entitled to have that lien leased as· to such unit owner's condominiwn ur..it, and the 'Jni t owners' association shall not assess, or have a valid r lien against that condominium unit for any portion of the f I common. expenses incurred in connection with that lien, notwithstanding anything to the contrary in sections 312 and 313. sec. 203. Description of CondoDliniwn Units After the creation of the condominium, no description of a ~ondomi.niwn unit shall be deemed vague. uncertain, or otherwise insufficient or infirm wbi.cb sets forth the identifyinq nwnber of that unit, the name of the condominium and the instrument number and date of recordation of the declaraticn and the condominium book and page number where I i I j I I -19 he plats and plans a=e =ecorded. A~y such descr~ption shall be deemed to include the undivided i.~te:es't. in the common elements appertaining to such uni't. even if such interest is not de£ined or referred to there.in. sec. 2ou. Executioc 0£ condcminium Ins't.rwnents The declaration ·and bylaws, and any amendments Of either' made pursuant to section 228, shail be execi:ited by o~ on behalf of all. of the owners and lessees of ·th~ submitted land But the phrase •owners. and lessees" in the preceding se~ence and in section 219 does r.ot icclude, in their capacity as such, any mo:-tgagee, any t.-ustee or beneficiary ll.nder a deed of trust, ar.:t ot~r lien holder, any person having an i~=noate dower or curtesy interest, any person havinq an equitable interest under-any contr-act' for the sale c::iease ot a condominium unit r any lessee whose leasehold i~terest does not extend to any portion of the common elements. sec. 205. Reco.rdation of Condominium Instruments~ All amendments and certifications of the condo~um I instruments shall set forth the instrument number ar4 date of record.a ti.on of the declaration and hen necessa:y, sna.l.l set forth the c:ondcminium :book and page r.umber where the ?lats and plans are recorded A.ll condominium instruments and all amendments and ce:tifica ions thereof sha.ll set r f \ i I I I I I I i amp 20- for~h the name and address of the condominium and sha1l be sec. 206. Construction of Condominium Inst:.rmnents Exct!pt to the extent otherwise provided by the condoininium instruments a) The terms defined in sectj,on 102 shall be deemed t~ have t _he zneaninqs therein specified wherev-er they appear in ·the co~doati.nium instruments unless the conte:xt otherwise requires b) To the extent that walls, floors, or ceilings are designated as the boanda.ries of the an.its or of any specified anits, all doors and windows the:einr and all lath, wall~oard, plastering, and any other materials [ constituting any part of the finished surfaces thereof, r s l1all be_ dee~ed a _pa.rt of such uni ts, while all other portions of such wal1sr floors, or ceilings shall be deemed a part of the common elements c) If. any chutes, flues, ducts, conduits, wires, bearing walls, bearing columns, or any other apparatus lies partially within and partially outside of the designated boundaries of a unit, any port.ions thereof serving only that unit shall be deemed a part of tbat unit, wb.i.le any portions c thereof serving more than one unit or any portion of the I j i I I I 21- com~on elements sbali be deemed a pa=t o! t~e ccmmor. elements d) Subject to the provisions of subsec:ion (c) hereof, all space, interior partitions, and other f~ures and improvements within the bounda.iies of a unit shall. be deemed a part of that unit e) AnY. shutters, awnings, window boxes doo:steps, porches, talconi.es; patios, and any ·ct.tier a Pa.ra~us de~igried to serve a single unit, but located outside the boundaries thereof, shall be deemed a limited common element appertaining to that unit exclusively. sec. 2o c~struction of condominium !nst.~ents T:ie condominium instruments sball be construed together and '1 shall be deemed to incorporate one another to the extent t at any requirement of this act as to the coctent of one shall be deemed satisfied if the def ic:iency can be cured by r~f erence to any of the others. If any conflict exists -among the coodom.inium instruments, the declaration controls, except that a cons t:ruction consistent wi tl:l the .act, control.s in all cases over a.Dy inconsistent construct.ion Sec. 208. Validity of Condominium Instruments. {a) Al1 ~ovisions of the condominium i.o.st uments shal.l be deemed severable, and any un.lawfu1 provision thereof shall l:e void 22 i b) No provision of the condominium instrume ts shall be I J eemed void l:y reason of the rule against perpetuities c) No restraint on alienation shall discriminate or be discriminate on the basis of religious conviction, race, color, sex or national origin. The condominium instruments may ~rovide, however, for ·restraints on .use of some or .all of tjle uni ts ·restricting the use of !iuclr units to persons meet~9 requirements bas~ upon a-ge, sex marital status, physical disability or, in connection ~ith programs of the federal or District of Colmnbi.a government income levels. {d) Subject to the provisions of subsection (c) hereof, the rule of ~roperty law known as the rule restricting gt;j I I unreasonable restraints on alienation shall not be applied I I to defeat any provision of the condoaWtium instruments I { restraining the alienation of condominium units not restricted exclusively to res~ential use. sec. 209. Compliance with Condominium Act and Instruments. Any lack of co111pliance with this act or with any lawful provision of the condominium instruments shall be grounds for an acti.on or suit to recover sums due for damages or injunctive relief, or for any other available remedy, maintainable by the unit owners• association. or by its executive or9an or any managing agent on behalf of such f I i j I I I l -23- l jas s ociation, I or, in any proper case, by one or more I aggrieved ersons on their own behalf or as a class ac i on Sec. 210. Contents of De&amp;lt;:laration a} The dec.larat.ioo. for every condominium sba.ll contain l) the name of the eondoati.nium, wh.ich name shall include the word "condominium" or be followed by ·the ~wor·ds a condom.ini um 2) a leqclu_y sufficient desCti?tiC?n of. the J.and submitted to this ac {3) a description or· delineation of the boundari es of the uni~s, inclnding the hori%ontal (upper and lower cur.daries,-if any, as wel.1 as tbe vertica1 (lateral or imetric) toundaries; I (U) a description or de1ineation o'f any l imited common e1ements not covered by section 206(e) of this act, s howing or designatinq the unit or units to which each is assigned 5) a description or delineation of all common elements not within the boundaries of any convertible lands I which may subsequently be assigned as limited common e l ements, together ~ith a statement that they may be so ass i gned and a desc:r~ption of the method whereby any such assignments shal be i:nade in accordance with the provisions of section 213 of this act f~\ i l i" C\ I ~y j i I I I I \ -24 6) the allocation to each unit of an undivided in-:erest in the common elements in accordance with the provisions of section 211of this act; and {7) such other matters as the declarant deems appropriate b) If the condominium contains any convertible· 1and .the declara ticn shall also contain 1) a legally sufficient esc:-iption of each convertible land within the condominiw:n 2) a statement of the maximum nwnber of units tha m.ay ce created within each such convertible land 3) a stutement, with respect to each such converti~le lan of the maximum percentage of the aggregate land and flocr area of all units that inay be created therein that may l::e occupied by units not restricted exclusively to residential use a statement of ehe extent to which any structure erected on any convertible land wi1l be compatibie with structuxes on otbex portions· of the submit~ed land in terms of quality of constr"OCtion, the principal materials to. be used ·and architectural style 5) a description of all other improveinents that may be made in each convertible land witl:U."l the condominium i I j I i l I i i l 25 6) a statement that any ur s c=eated wi~~in eacn converti:le land will be substantia.l1y identical ~o the units on other pert.ions of the submitted land, or .a statement describing i.n detail what other types of units may be created therein; and 7) a descri;:tion of the declarant's =eserved right, if any, to create ·limited common elements :within any convertitle land·r or ~o desiqna-te c:ommon eJ.ements there.in whic.h may sul:sequen~y be assigned as llmi ted cemmon elements, in terms of ·the types, sizes, and maximum number of such elements within each such convertible land rovided, that the pJ.ats a.nd plans recorded pursuant to section 21~(a) and {b) of this act may be used to supplement infc=ma~ion furnished pursuant to items {1 4 S} 6 [ and 7 Of this su.l:section, and that item (3) of this j j I 3ubsection need not be_c:omplied with if none of 1:.b.e units on other portions of the submitted land are restricted exclusively to residential use c) If the condocdnium. is an expandable condominium t.he declaration shall al.so contain 1) the expi..r-cit reservation of an option to expand the condominium 2) a statement of any l.im.itations on that option eluding# without limitation. a sta~ement as to whether the l I 26- consent of any unit owners shall be required, and if so, a statement as to the method whereby such consent shall be ascertained; or a statement that there are no such limitations 3) a time limit, not exceeding five years from the recc:&amp;gt;rding of the declaration. upon "Which the opt;.ion to expand the condominium shall expire, together with a statement of the cireumstances, if .any, which wilJ ermi.nate I that opticn ~rior t~ the expiration of the time limit so specified 4) a lega.l.ly sufficient description of all land that may be added to the condominium, hencef ortn ref erred to as "additional land J (5) a statement as to whether, if any of the additional land is added to the condominium. all of it or I any particular portion of it must be added, a."\d if not, a statement of any limitations as to what portions may be addecr-or a statement that there are no such limit3tions 6) a statement as to whether portions of the I i additional land may be added to the condominium at different times together with any limitations fixing the boundaries of those portions by legally sufficient descriptions -regulating the order in which they may be added to the condominium i I J I i I I r i I c -27- {7) a statement of any limi~ations as to the l ocations of any improvements t at may be made on any por~ions ·of the additional land added to the condominium, or a statement that ~o assurances are made in that regard 8) a statement of the maximum number of units• that may l:e created on the additiona.l land. If portions of the additicnal land may be added to the condominium ~nd the boundaries of those po::tions are fixed in accordance wi-t;h item (6) of this subsection, the de la.ration shall also: stata the uaximum number of units that may be czeated on each porticn added to the condominium. If portions of the additional land may be added to the condominium and t.he ouncaries O"f these portions are not rixed in accordance i't!J. item (6) of this subsect·ion, then the declaration shall also state the maximum number of units per acre that may be c::rea ed on any such portion added to the condo.mini um; t 1 (9) a sta~ement, with respect to the additional land and to any portion or portions the.reef that may be added to the condominium, of the maximum percentage of the aggregate land and floor area of all units ~hat may be I created thereon that may be occupied by units not res±.ricted exclusively to residential use 10) a statement of the extent to which any structures erected on any portion of the additional land t \ 17 28- acded to the condominium will be compatible with s~ructu:es on the submitted land in terms of qua1ity of construction, the· p:incipal materials to be used, and architectural style, or a statement that no assurances are made in those regards; {11) a description of all other improvements that will be· made on any portion of the add±tional land added .to the condominium or a statement of any limitations a-s to what other improvements may be made. thereon, or a st.atement that no assurances are made in that reqard 12) a statement that any units created on any portion of the additional land added to the condorniniwn will be substantially identical to the units on the submitted· lane, or a statement of any limitations as to what types of r units may 1 e created thereon, or a statement that no assurances are made in that regard; and I 13) a description of the declarant•s reserved right, if any, to create limited common elements ~ithin any -portion of the additional land added to the condominium, or to designate· common elements therein which may subsequently be assigned as limited common elements, in terms of the types, sizes, and maximum number of such e1ements within each such portion, or a statement that no assurances are r made in those regards; Provided, that the pla~s and plans sccrded pursuant to section 214(a) and (b) of this ac:t may I I I I I I 29- be used to supplement information furnished pursuant t o items {5 6 7 10 11 {i2) and (13) of t his subsection, and that item (9) of this subsection need not be complied with i£ none of the units on the subnitted land is restrict.ed exclusively to residential c.se d) u the condom.iniam is a contr~ctable condo'm±nium the declaration sha.J.l al.so contain 1) the explicit reservati:m of an option to contract the condominium 2) a statement of any limitations on that option, including, without limitation. a statement as to whether .the consent of any uni owners shal.l be required, and if so, a statement as to the method whereby such consent shall be I as·cert.ained; or a statement that there are no such l imitations 3) a time l.imit, not exceeding five (5) years f =om the recording of the dec~rat.ion, Ul=Qn which the op~ion to contract the condoininium shall expire. together with a statement of the circumstances, if any, which ~l terminate that opticn ~ri.or to the expiration of the time limit. so specified; {4) a lega.J.ly sufficient description of ali land that may te withdrawn from the condominium, henceforth ferred to as ithdrawable land T J I /I 30 5) a statement as to whether po~ions of tbe withdrawal::le land may be withdrawn from the condominium at. different times, together with any limitations fixing the boundaries of those portions by leqally sufficien~ descriptions clearly delineating such portions and p regulating the order in which such portions may be withdrawn from the condominium; and (6 a -legal:1y sufficient ~escription of all of the submitted land to which the option to c:on1:ract the condominium does not extend; Provided, that the plats recorded pursuant to section 214(a) may be used to supplement informatior. furnished pursuant to i~ems (4 5) and (6) of this subsection, and 4:.hat item (6) of this subsection shall not be construed in derogation of any right the dec1arant mar bave to terminate the condominium in accordance with the provisions of section 227 of this act e) If the condominiam is a leasehold condominium then with respect to any ground lease or other leases the expiraticn or termination of which will or may terminate or contract the condominium, the declaration shall set forth 1) the instrument number and date of recordation of each such lease I I I I I I 31 2) the date upon which each such lease is due to and the rights, if any, to renew such lease and the conditions pertaining to any such renewal 3) a statement as to whether any land or improvements, or l:oth will be owned by the unit owners in £ee si.mp1e, and i£ so, either (A) a description of tpe same, including without limitation a legally sufficient description of any such land. o.r (B} a statement of any rights the unit C Ilers sba.ll have to remove such improvements within a reasonable time after the expiration or termination of the lease or leases involved, statement that they sha1.l bave no such rights; and (ii) a statement of the rights the ur.it owners ·J 1 shall have to redeem the I J reversion or a~y of the reversions r or a t~tement that they shall have .no such rights; j Provided, that a~er the ~ecordj.ng of the declaration, no. I I l~ssor who executed the same pnd no successor in interest to such lessor, shalJ. have any right or power to terminate any pa rt of the leasehold interest of any unit own er who makes timely payment of his share of the rent to the person or persons designated in the dec~ation for the receipt of such rent and who otherwise complies with all covenants which, if violated uld entit.le the lessor to terminate t~e lease. Acquisition or reacqcisi~ion of such a leasehold 32 1.interest by 1 /not cause a r the cwner of the reversion or remainder shall merger of the leasehold and fee simple in~erests unless all leasehold interests in the condominium are th\lS l acquired or ~eacquired. {f) Wherever this section requires a leqally sufficient descrip~icn of land tbat is submitted eo this act or that may be a~ded to .or withdrawn from the condominium, such I requirement shal:l be deemed to require a legally suffi~ient Ii I I i I I l i I t it i l I 7 I I r I description of any easements that are submieted -c.o this act or that may be added to· or withdrawn from th~ condominium as the case may te the case of each such easement, the ceclaratiori shall contain 1 2) a description of the permitted use or uses: if less than all of those entitled to the use I 'f J 11 I 0 l: all the units may uti.lize such easement. a statement of I I 11 1 i J1 the relevant restrictions and limitations on utilization; and 3} if any persons other than those entitled to the use of the uni ts may utilize sucb easement. a s~atement of the rights of others to utilization of the same g) Wherever this section requires a legally sufficient description of land that is submitted to this act or that may be added to or withdrawn from the condominiwn an added requirement sha11 be a separate legally sufficient -33- desc=iption cf all lands in which the unit owners shall or may be tenants in ccrunon or joint tenants with any other persons, and a separate leqally snfficient dese--iption of a.ll lands in which the unit owne.rs shall or may be li.fe tenants. No units shall be situated on any such lands, however, and the declaration shall describe the nature of the unit c:wners estate therein. No such lands shall be shown on the Ame pl.at ox plats shoWinq ctll~ port.ions i the condominium, l::ut shall be shcwn inst.ead on separate plats. Sec. 211. Al.1ocation of Interests in the Common l. er.tents {a} The declaration may allocate to each unit depicted on plats and plans that comply with section 214 ca&amp;gt; and b) of this act an undivided interest in the coznmon elements p portionate to either the size or par value of each an.it. {b) Otherwise, the declaration shall allocate to e~cb sucb unit an equal undivided interest in the common elements, subject to tbe follewinq exception each I convertil:le space so deE=icted shal.l be allocated an und.ivide_d interest in the common el.ements proportio~te to c e ize of°· e~c vis-a-vis t.he aggregate size OL all un; ts so ~epic:t.~d m the remaining U ldivided lt \ gt lt;\E 7 { 7 f I in~e=est in the common elements shall be allocated equally to the other units so depicted c) The undivided interests in the co1JU11on elements allocated in accordance with subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall add up to one if stated as fractions or one hundred per centum i£ stated as percen1:a.ges d I.f, in .accordance with subsection a} or lj) of thissectJ..on; an .equal undivided interest in the common elements is allocate!i to each unit, the declaration may simply state that fact and need not express the fraction or percentage so allocated e) Otherwise, the undivided interest allocated to each unit in accordance with subsection (a) or (b) of this section sha1l be reflected by a table in the declaration or by an-exhibit or schedule accompanying the declaration and =ecorded simultaneously therewith, c:onta.in.inq three columns. The first column shall identify the units, listing them serially er grouping them together in the case of units to which identical undivided interests are a1located. Corresponding figures in the second and third columns shall set forth the respective areas or par values of those units and the fraction or percentage of undivided interest in the common elements a~located ~ereto 35 f £xcept to 't e extent otherwise expressly p r ov ided by this act, the undivided interest in the common elements a l located to any unit shall not be a1-:ered, and any purported transfe encumbrance, or othe.r disposition of that i iterest without the unit to which it appertains shal l be void 9 he common elements shall not be subject to any suit for pa.rtition mltil and unless ·the con~o~um is erm.inated. sec. 212. Reallocation of Interests in the common Elements a) II a condominium contains any convertibl~ li::i.nd or is cm ex?ndable condominium, then the declaration s:~all not alJ.oca te undivided interests in the common \ e l _ements on the l:asis of par value c.nless the declaration 1 rohil::i ts. the ciea ti on of any uni ts not sl!bstantialJ.y identica1 to the units depicted on the plats and plans recorded pursuant to section 214(a) and (b) o~ this act, or (2) i:rohil:its the creation of any units not i described pursuant to section 210 (b 6) of this act in the case of convertitle lands) section 210(c 12) of this act (in the case of additionai· land and contains from the outset a sta temen p~ valo.e that sha.l.l be assigned ~o every such unit tbat may be created o:m 11 1 I I 36 b) No allocation of inte=es~s in the co~.mor. elcmer.~s to any ur~ts created within any conver~itle land o= within ar.y additional land shall be effective until ~la~s and plans depicting such units are recorded pursuan~ to section 214(c)of this act. The declarant shQll :ealloca~e the undivided interes'ts in the common elements so tha the u?iits within the convertible la~d or additional land shall he allocated undi°vided interests in the co"11non elem~!ltS o~tbe same basis as the uni ts depicted on the t:iats ~nd plar.s recorde~ pirsuant to section 21~(a) and (b omptly upon recording the amendment to the declaration, the declaran~ shall recorO. an a-me~dment to the plats and plans depicting t~e ur.its created within the convertible land or a~di~ional land c f all cf a convertible space~is converted into common elements. then the ur..divided interest i~ the common elemen~s appertaining to such space shall ther.ceforth appertain to the remaining units, being allocated among the~ in ~ropo ion to their undivided interes~s in the common elements. The principal officer of the ur.i t owners association, or such other officer or officers as the condominium instruments may specify, shall forthwith prepare, execute, and record an amendment to the declaration 37 fl ec~i~g tne reallocation of undivided L~te=es~s educed t.hereby d) In the case of a leasehold condominium, if ~he expi:aticn o: termination of any lease causes a con~-ac~on of the condominium which reduces the number of ir.its, then he ur.diyided interes~ in the common. elements ap9ert~ining to any ~nits there.by wi.thdrawn from the condotnini~im shall thencef~rth appertain to the remaining ur..its; being allocated amor.q them ;in proportion to their undivided inte:es":s in the common elements. The principal offic~r of the ur.i t cwners' association, or such other office or ~f ficers as the condominium instruments may specify, shall f~rthwith prepare, execute, and record an amend~P-~t to e d;cla=atic~ reflecting the reallocation of undivided interests produced thereby. sec. 2i3. kssigr.ments of Limited Common ~lements a) All assic;nme~ts ar.d reassignments of limited cor.~on elements shall be reflected by the condomi.r.ium instruments o limited ccmmon elemer.t shall be assigned or reassigr.ed except in accordance with the provisions of this act. No amendment to any eondozn.inium instru:nent sh3.ll alter any rights or cbligations with respect to any limited common elements •ithout the consent of all unit o·.m.ers adve:sely a=.ieC ed thereby as evide::ce by their execution of such 36- a~endme~t, except to the extent t.~a~ the condo~ir.ium ir.strument expressly ~roviaed otherwrise prior to the first assigr.ment of that limited common element b) Onless expressly prohibited by the ccndomi:liwn instruments, a limited common element may be reassigned upou wri~ten applicaticn of the unit owners ·concerned to .the prir.cipa·l officu of tile unit owners• association o·r to such other officer· or officers as the condo:ninium ins~=uments may spec~fy. The officer or officers whom such ap~lication is duly made shall forthwith prepare and ex·ecute an airendment to tb.e condominium ir.serumer s reassig~ing all rights and obligations with respect to the limited ccmmon ele~ent involved. Such ~mendmen~ shall be delivered forthwith to the unit owners of the uni~s concerned upon payment by them of all reasor.able costs for the preparation and acknowledgement thereof. Such amend.~ent shall become effective when the unit owners of the units conc~rned have executed and recorded it c) A ccmmon element not previously assigned as a limited ccmmon element shall be so assiqned only in pursuance to section 210(a 6 The amendment to the declaration making such an assignment shall be prepared and executed cy the principal officer of tr.e unit owners• as.sociaticn, or by such other officer or office::s as the -39- ccndomir.ium i~struments may specify. such a~e~dment sh~ll be celiv~red to the unit owner or owners of the uni~ or ~i~s concer~ed u~on payment by theln of all reasona~le cos~ for t.he ep:srat:.ion and acknowledgement thereof Such amendme~t shall become ef£ective when the aforesuid un.it owner or cwne:rs have @xecuted aJ:d recorded it, and tiie recordation thereof shall be conclusive evi.cence that the met:Ood· prescril:ed pur$uant to section 210 a 6 was a·q.hered o. Sec. 214. Content of Pla-:s and Plans a here shall :e recorded _frcmpt.ly upon recordation of the declara~ion, one or more-~lat~·of survey showing the location and ¥' dimensions of the sutmitted land, the locatior. and dimensions of any cor.vertible lands within the sUbmitted land, the location and dimer.sions of any ex!s-ei imp=ovements, the intended location and dimensions of any cor.templateo improvements wh.ich are to be located on any por~ion of the suhnitted land other tban wi~r bour.da:ies of any conver~ible lands, and o tbe ;extent l feasible, the location and dimensions of all easements appu enar.t to the sul::mi tted land or otherwise su9mi t"t:ed to ~his ac~ as a part of tbe common elements. If tile submitted l and is not contiguous, then the plats shall incicate the c ~s~~nces be~~een the parcels cons itu~ng tr.e submi~ted land. The plats shall label every conver:.ible land as a convertitle land, and if there be more than o~e such ~ar.d the plats shall label each such land with one or more letters or numl:ers, or .both, different from tilose desigr.ati~g any other convertible land and different also from th~ iden~ifying number of any uni The plats shall sho"1 .the. locatior. and dimensions of any wi~!ld:rawablf! lands, and shall. laf:el ·each such land with. one or more letters or num~ers, or coth, d~fferent from those designatL~g any other convertitle land and different also trom the identifying ~umber of any unit. The plats shall show the location ~nd dimensions ·of any withdrawable lands, and shall label each su~h lar.d as a witr.drawable lar.d. If, with respect to any portion or portions, but less than all, of the submitted land, the unit cwners are to own only an estate for years, the plats shal1 show the location and dimensions of any such portions, and shall label each such portion as a leased land. If there is more than o~ withdrawa.ble la~d. or more than one leased land, the plats shall label each sucb land with one or more letters or numbers, or bo~h, different from those designating any convertib"l:"e land or other withdrawable or leased. land, and different also from tile iden~ifying number of any unit. The plats shall show all easements ~o which the suomitted lar.d or any portion thereof is subjee anc shall show the location and dimensions of all such ea se~en~s to the extent feasible he pla~s shall also s h ow all. encroachmer.ts by or on any portion of the condo~~nium the case of any improvements located or to be located on any poreion of the sul:mitted land other than witnin the bounda=ies of any convertible lands; th~ plats shall ind:.cate h.ich, if any~ have not been begun by ~e Se ot the pr ase OT ET BEGUN and whi~h, if any, have been begun but ha~e not been substantially completed by the use of the phrase "NC'I Y.ZT COMPLETED I:i the case of any units the ve=tical boundaries ot which lie woolly or p~:tially outs~de of ·structUl:'es for which plans purStla~t to subsectior h) 3.re simultaneously recorded, the plats shall show the loca~ion and dimensions of such vertical bou da.ri~s to th~ ex~ent th3.t they are not shewn o~ such ~lans, and t he units or por":ions thereof thus depicted shall tear ~eir i~en~i!ying r.umbe~s. Ea.ch plat shall b~ certified as to its accu~dcy and com~liance with the provisions of ~his subsecticn cy a registered land surveyor, and tr.e said su veyor shall certify that all units or portions the~eof depicted tiJt reOil fursuar.t to the preceding er.tecce of ~his subsection have been substan~ially completed. The specifica~icn within this subsec~ion of items tha~ shall be s~oi n on the lats st.all r.o be construed to uiea.r at &amp;lt he I •42- plats shall not also show all ot~er items s~o~a:ily shown or hereafter required for land title surveys. {t) There shQll also be recorded, promptly upo~ reco:dation cf the declaration, plans of eve.ry structure which cont3.ins or constitutes all or part of any unit or uni~s, and which is located on any portion of the su~mitted land other thar within the boundaries of any convertible lands The t=lans shall show the location· and d~ansion,s of the vertical cour.daJ:ies of each unit to the extent that such boundaries lie within or coincide with the boundaries 9f such structures, and the units or porcions thereof thus depicted shall bear .their identifying numbers. I!'l addition, each cor.vertil::le space thus depicted shall be labeled a I c~nverticle space. The horizontal boundaries ot ·each unit having horizontal boundaries shall be identified on the plans wi~h reference to established dat:Jm. Unless the condomi:-iiu:n instruments expressly provide otherwise, it shall be presumed that in the case of any unit not wholly. contair.ed within or constituting one or more sue structures, the horizontal boundaries ehus identified extend, in he case of each such unit, at the same elevation with regard to any part of such unit lying outside of such st:uctures, subject to the following exceptior in the case of any such unit ~hich does not lie over any other unit 4.J other than casement uuits, it shall be ~resu~ed tnat che lowe= horizon~al coundary, if any, oi that unit lies at the level of he qrou.~d with regard to any par~ of ~h~t un it lying ·ou~side of such structures. The plans shall be certified as to their accuracy and compliance witil the provisions of this subsection by a re9i~tered arcnitect or regi s t.e:.ed engineer, and the said archi tee~ o: engi~er shall c·er~ify t~t al:l. uni ts or po~ons the:-eof dep_icted ~hereon have =een su~stantially completed c hen converting all or any portion of any convertitle land, or adainq additional land to 4n expandable ccndominium, the declarant shall reco:d new pla~s of survey co~forming to t.~e requirements of subsection {a In a::y case •here less than all of a convertible lar.d is beittg conve:ted, such ~lats shall show the locatio~ and dimensi ons cf the reJM.ininq pcr~ion or portions of sue~ l and in addi~ion to ctherwise conforming with the re-;uire~er.ts oi subsection (a At the same time, the declaran~ shall record i~h reqard to ar.y st:r::uctures on the lar einq conver~ed, or added, either plans conforming to the requirements of subsection (b or certifica~ions, conforming tc the certification requ.iremen1:s of said sucsection, of plans previously recorded pursua~t to sectio~ 2 15 uu d hen cor.verting all or any portion or any co~ver't.i~le space into one or more ur.its or limited com:non elements, the declarant shall record, with rega t~ the structure or portion thereof constituting tr.at conve~ible space, plans showing the location and dimensio~s of the vertical t:oundaries of each unit or limited common elements formed out of such space. such plans shall be certified as to their accuracy and compliance with the provisions of. this subsection t:y a registered architect or registe:ed engineer e) For the purposes of subsections (a b and (c ll provisior.s and requirements relatir.g to uni~ s~all be deemed equa~ly aF?l1cable to limited coi:nmon ele~ents. The limii;ed common .elell'.er.ts shall be labeled as such, and each I li.mi ted common element depicted on the plats and ·plans shall =ear the identifying nu.mDer or numbers of the u t or units to which it is assigr.eQ if it has been assigned, u~less the p~ovisions of sect:ion 206(e) make such desiqnations unnecessary f) The Office of the surveyor shall receive plats a::id tJ!.ans filed pursuant to this act. Unless such plats and plans are filed pursuant to section 215. the Office ~f the surveyor shall ascertain whether such plats and plans contain the certification required by subsec~ions (a) and (b) of this section. If plats and plans a:e filed pursuant tc sectio~ 21 5 or if ~lats and plans a=e fi l ed ~ith ~he required certification, t.r.e Off ice of the Survey~r sh~ ll record such ~lats and plans without further cer if ica~ion or rav-iew. I£ t=lats and i:J.ans filed pursuant to section 215 are thereafter certified as required by this section e Office Qf the Su veyor shall record sucb certification wi th such .pia-ts a id plans without further ce:tificatior or review. Sec. 215 Prelin-;ina:y Recordation of Plans l ar..s previously reccrded porsuar.t to the 'provi~ set forth i n section 210(t) and (c) may be used in lieu of r:.ew plar:.s to satisfy-in 'whole or in part the requiremen~s of sec~ion 212 b section 217 (l ar.d section 219 if certifica ions t hereof are recorded cy the declarar.t in accordance wi tn section 21~(c and if such certifications are so recor ded, the plar.s which ~ey certify shall be deemed recorded pursuant to section 21ij (c ithin the mea.-iir.g of the three secti ons aforesaid. sec. 216. Easement for Er..croachments and Suppo a) To the extent that any unit or cotnD'\On element er.croaches on any other unit or common element, whether by reason of any deviation frcm the plats and plans in the const uction, repai renovation, restoratior or replacement of any improvemer.t, or cy reason of the settling or shi~ting of a~y l 46- land or improvemer.t, a valid easement for such er.croac!unent. shall exist: Provided, however, such easemer shall not reli~ve tmi t owners of liability in c·ases of willful and inte~tional misconduct by them or their agen~s or employees, nor shall the deciarant or any contractor, subco~~ractor, or materialman te relieved of any liability which ar.y of them may have· cy reason of any failure to adhere stric ly.to tne plats and ~lans b) Each unit ar.d common element shall have an easement for support from every otr.er unit ar.d common element. sec. 217. Conversion of Convertible Lar.ds a} The decl~rant ay convert all or any portion o: ar.y c~r.vertible l~nd .into one or more units or common elements, or bota, subject: to any restrictions a:ld limitaticns which th~ condominium instruments may specify. Any such conversion shall be deemed to have OC!=\lrr~d at the time of the =ecc=daticn cf a~propriate in~ruments pursuant co subsection {t) hereof and section 21q (c b) The declcil"ant shall prepare, execute, and record an amendment to the declaration describing the conversion. Such amer.dment shall assign an identifying number to each unit formed out of a convertible land a.~d shall reallocate undivided interests in the common elements in accordance wit~ sec~ion 212 (b Such amendment shall desc:ibe or celine:~e the limited common elements fo=mec ou~ o e conver~itl~ land, showing or designating the u::i~ or uni~s to which each is assigned c) All convertible lands shall be deemed a pa~ of the common elements except ior such portions thereof as a:e converted in accordance with the provisicns of th.is se~ion Until the expiration of the period during which conversion may occur er until actual conversiori which~ve:i 9ccurs first, re3l es~ate taxes shall be assessed agai~st he declaran~ r3ther thar. the unit owners as to both ~he co:'l.vertibl"e land and any aprovements thereon. t-to such conversio al.l ~ci=ur after five years from U-4e record.a'C.ion o: tbe declaration, or such s-horter period of ti:ne 3.S the \ de_clar3.ticn may specify. Sec. 21S. COL.version of Convertibie S~aces a} The decla:ant may convert all or any portion of ~hy conve~tible space into one or more units or common elements, or bot i~cluding without limitation, limited common elemer.~s, subject to any restrictions and limitations which the condominiu~ instruments may specify. Any such co~ver~ion shall ce deemed to have occurred at ehe time of the cordaticn of a~propriate instruments pursuant subsect.icn (b) hereof and section 214 (d 48 b) Si~ultar.eously with the recording of pla~s ar.d plans pursua~t to section 214(d the declar~nt shall prepare, execute, and record an amendment to the declaration describing the conversion. such amendment shall ~ssign an identifying number to each unit formed out of a convertible space az:.d shall allocate to each .unit ·a portion of e undi~ded interest in the common elements appert~ining to that space such amer..dment shall d~sc:ibe o= de:lineate the limi~ed common eleme~ts formed out of the cor.ver~ible space, showing or desiqr..atinq the unit or units to which eac:h is assiqned c} !f all or any portion of any convertible space is converted into one or more anits in accordince h this section, the declarar.t shall prepare. exec~te, and record simultar.eously with the amendment to th~ decla:atior an amendment to the bylaws I!le amendment to the bylaws shsll reallocate votes in the unit cwners• association, rights ~o future common prcfits. and liabilities for future commo~ expenses net specially assessed, all as in the case of the subdivision of a unit in accordance with sec'tion 226(d} d) uny convertible space not converted in accordance with the ovisicns of this section. or any portion or portio~s thereof r.ot so converted, shall be trea~ed for all pur~oses as a single unit until and unless it is so -49- co~ver:ed, and tr.e previsions of this act s hall ~e deemed ~pplicab~e to any such space, or por~icn or ~or-:i o s thereof, as ~hough the same were a unit. sec. 219. Expansion of the Condominiu:n No condominium shal.l ce expanded except in accc=Ca::ce with t.,e provisions Of the declaration and Of this ac't 1 y ~uch expansion shall .te deemed to have occurred at e time of the recorda ticn of plats and pla s pursuar::t t:o s~ctio:i 21~(c} and the recordation of an amendmen't. to the declaratic duly executed by t.~e decla=ant, including, without limitation, all of the owners and lessees of ~he addi~ional i and a~ded to the concominiu s~ch amendment shall con~ai~ a legally sufficient desc=iptior. of ene land \ add~d to the cor.dominimn, and .shall reallocate andivided- inte=es~s in the common elements in accorda ce ~ith the provisions of sectior: 212(b such amer.dme~t m.ay creat:e convertible er withdrawable lands within the la~d added to the condominium, but this provision shall no~ be construed i~ derogation of the time limits imposed by or .pursuant to sections 210 (d 3) and 217 (c sec. 22C. cont:ac:t.ion of ~e Condomir~iUJ:n No condominium shall be contracted except in accorda~ce with the p=ovisions of the declaration and of this act A."ly such ~on~rac~~cn shall be deemed to have occu:red at the ~ime of .r re t so h e recordation of an amendment ~o the declaratio execu~ed by the dec l arant, containing a legally sufficieL~ description cf the land withdrawn from the co~dominium. If por~ions cf the ~ithdrawable land were descri~ed· pursuant to section 210(d 5 then r.o such portion shall be so withdrawn after the conveyance of any nni t on Sl:Ch s:inion. If no such pc~ions ~ere described, then none ct ~he wi thd amp;wa.ble land shall. be wi tlldrawri. after t::he f~rst conv~yance of any unit thereon. Sec. 221. Easement to Facilitate Conversion a~d Expansion subject to any restrictions and l.izni.t:'l tions he cor.dominiurn-instr.imer.ts may specify, the declaran~ shall have a transferatle easement .over and on the co:nm~n elements \ for ~he pur~cse cf making improvements on the submi~~ed land and any additional land pursuant to the provisions of those i nstruments and of this act. and for th~ purpose of doir.g all things reasonably necessary and proper in connection -therewith. sec. 222. Easement to Facilitate Sales The declarant and the declarant's authorized agents. represent-ative_s, a~d employees may maintain sales offices, managemer.t ~ffices, and model units on the submitted land if and only if the condominium instruments provide for the same and specify the rights of the declarant wit:.h regard to the nwnber, size 51- location, and relocation thereof. Any such sales of:ice, ma~agement office, or model uni~ which is not designa~ed a unit cy the co4dcminium ir.s:.ruments shall become a common elemerit as soo.o as the dec.larant ceases to be a U 1i owner, and the declarant shal.l cease to have any rights wit regard thereto unless such sales office, management office~ or model. un.it is removed forthwith from the submii;~ed 1-and in accordance with ·a ·right reserved in. the condominium· instruments to make such removal sec. 223. Oeclarant•s Obligation to com;le~ and Restore {a) No conver.ants, restrictions, lim.ita~ions, or other representa~ons or commitments in the condo~inium ins~:uments ith rega:d to a.nythinq that is or is r.o~ to be done on the ~dditior.al land, the with.drawable la d, or any portion of either, shall be bir.dir.g as to any por~ion of ~ither lawfully withdrawn from the condominium or ever added thereto except to the extent that the condominium inst::iJments so provide. But in the case of a~y cover.~n"&amp;amp;-r restriction, limitation, or other represent.ation or commitment in the condominium instruments, or in a~y other agre~ment requiring the declarant to add all or any portl.On of the additional land or to withdraw any portion of the wi~hd=awa~le land, or imposing any obligations wi~h regard to ar.ything that is or is not to be cone on or wi regard £ 7 52- to the condominium or ar.y portion thereof, this subsection shall no~ be cor.strued to nullify, limit, or otherwise affect any such cbliqation b he declarant shall complete all improvements labeled "NO YET CO}~L.ETED" on plats recorded pursua.n't. to the requi:ements of this act unless the condominium· ins~ruments exp~essly exempt the declarant from such obligation, and shall, in the case of every. impr9vement. labeled "NOT YET BEGUN" on such plats, s1:a te ir. the declar~ticn either the extent of the obligation to complete the same or that there is no such obligation c Io-t le e teht that damage is ir.flicted on any part of the condcmin.iwn ty any person or perscr.s ut:i.li iq· the I a.sements reserved by the condominium instrwnena or creat·ed by sec't.ions 221 and 222, the declarant together wi.th ~he person or persons causing the same shall be jointly and severally liatle for the prompt repai: thereof and for ~he -restoration cf the same to a condit"I"On-c.ompatible with the remainder cf the condominiwn Sec. 224. Alterations within Onits a) Except to the extent prohitited by the condominium instruments~ and subject to any restrictions and limitations specified the~ein, any ur.i~ owner may make any improvemen:s or al~era~icns ~i~hin his unit that do not impair the 53 supt:c:;r of ar.y portion ot the condo6niniu:=t. 3 it r.o u i owner shall do anything whieh would char.ge the e~terior a-ppeaTance o~ his unit or of ar.y other portion of the condominium excet:t to such ex-tent and sul::jec~ to such condit i or.s as the condominium instrwne~ts ~ay specify b) Except to the .exten~ prohibited by ~he condominiu i~st=uments, and subject to any res: rietio:i.s a.r.:c l i mitations specified therein, if a ur.it cwner acquires ar. adj ~in nq unit, or an adjoining part of an adjoining u it he~ such ur.it owr.er shall have the right to re~ove all o: part of any inte:veni lg partit5 n to create do~.way'S or other a r- e~tu:es therein notwithstanding the fac~ that such \ pa~ti~ion may in ~hole or in part be a common e~ement, so l vr.q as nc pcrtion of any bearinq wall or cea:ing column i s 3 k ~r.ed er r'!moved and no port.ion of any comr.o:l elemen"t. ot he: than t.~at ~artition is d.;unaged, dest:oyed, or endangered. Such creation of door ays or o"t.her apertures shall not ce deemed an alteration of boundaries ~ithin the meQr.~ng of section 225. Sec 225. Relocation of soundari es t:etweer. tJni ts. {a If the condominium instruments expressly permit the =elocation of boundaries between adjoining uni then t he 54- boun 5aries between such units may be relocated accordance wi h l) the provisions of this section and (2) any restrictions and limitation no ot."lerwise ur.lawful which the condominium in.s4:.ruments may sp-?cify. The boundaries between adjoining units shall not e located unles$ the condominium instruments expressly permit· it. {b) If the unit cwr.ers. of adjoining ur.i ~s whose mutual bour.daries may be relocated, desire to relocate such boundaries, then the principal officer of the uni~ owners• associati0:'4'7" or sue~ other officer or officers as the ccnnomir.ium instru~ents may specify, shall, upon written \ a~plication or such unit owners, fortbwith prepar~ and execute the a~pro~riate instruments pursuan~ to subsec ions (c d) and (e} {C) An amendment to the declaration shall id~ntify the units involved and shall state that the bour,daries between those units are ~eing relocated by agreement of the u Ut owners thereof hich amendment shall contain words ·of conveyance between those ani.t o~ners. I! the uni~ owners of tile Wlits involved have specified in their w itten application, a reasona~le reallocation as between the units involved of the aggregate Wldivided interest in t.~e common ss lements 3ppertaining to those unies, the amen~~e~t to ~he declara~io~ shall reflect that reallocation d) If the unit C'ftlners of the units involved have specified in their writter. application reasonable allccat.ions as between the units involved of the ~ggregate number of votes in the anit owners• association, ri~hts to fUtur.e C.OtTlmOn profits I Or liabilities for fu~e eOr."i.nCn expenses ri spe&amp;lt ial.l:y assessed, th~n an amendment ~o the bylaws sh~ll reflect. ar.y soc:h =eallocations e) Such plats and plans as may be necessary to show ~he ~l~ered toundaries between the units involved together with ~heir ·other coundaries shall be prepared. and ~he units d~picted ~he=eon shall bear their identifyir.g nu:nbers. such plats and plans shali indicate the new dim~nsio~s ot th a~i~s involved, and any change in the horizontal bo~~daries of e~t~er as a result of the relocation of their boundaries shall be identified with reference to establish d t:um. Sucb plats and ~laus shali be certified as to their accuracy and com~li~nce ftith the provisions of tl:lis subsection l} by a registered land surveyor in ~he case of a~y lat, and (2) by a regis~ered architect or registered engineer in the case of any plan. r &amp;lt \ 56 f hen a~;ropriate ins~uments in acco::c:ll:-ice wit.h he pr~ceding sutsections hereof have been prepa::ec, execu~~d, a~d ackr.owledged, i:hey shall ce deliver2d for't:.hwi~h to the u~it owr.ers cf the units involved upon payment :y ~hem of all reasonable costs for the preparation and acknowledqeme hereof. Said instruments shall become effective ~h~n the unit owners of the units involved have execu~ea a~d record~d ~hem, and the ·recordation thereof shall be conclµsive evidence that the relocation of bound~ries ~hus eff2ctuated did not violate any restrictions or limitations specified by ~he condominium instruments and that any realloca~ions made pursuan~ to-sul:s ecti·ons (C) and (d) were reasonable g) Any reloca ti.on of boundaries be~we~n adjoi!ling \ units shall be governed by this section and not by section 226. Sec. 226 shall apply only to such subdivisions of units as are intended to result in the creation of two or more uni S in place of the subdivided unit Sec. 226. sucdivision of Units a) If the condominium ins~ruments expressly permit tr.e subdivision of any units, then such units may be sul divided in accordance with (l) the provisions of this section, and (2} any restrictions and limitations not otherwise unla~ful •hich the condominium ir st:uments may specify 57 o u~i~ shall ce sucdivided unless the eondo i i~s~=uments expressly permit it {b) If the unit owner of any unit which :nay be subdivided desires to sa.bdivide such nr..it1 then the principal officer of tbe unit owners• association, or such other officer or office:s as the ccnd6miniwn ins~ru~ents may Specify t Shall Upon Written application Ot the SUbdi Vider I as such· ur.it cwn-er· shall henceforth. be refe:red to i .n this section, forthwith p~epare and execute appro~riate ir.s~ruments pursuant to subsections (c d) and (e c) An a~endment to the declara~ion shall assig~ r.ew identifying numbers to the new units created by e subdivisicn of ·a unit and shall allocate to these units, on a =easor.acle casis acce~table to the subdivider, all of the undivided interest in the common elements appertaining to the subdivided unit. The new units shall jointly share all rig~~s, and shall be equally liable jointly ar.d severally for all ocligations, with regard to any limited common eleme~~s assigned to the subdivided unit except to the extent that the subdivider may have specified in ois written application ti'.at all or any portions of any l.imi~eci coaur.cn elements assigned to the subdivided unit exclusively shouid be assigned to one or more, but less than all of t.he new uni~s, in which case the amendment to the declara~ion shall -sa- reflect the desires of the subdivide= as ex ssed in such (d) An amendment to the bylaws shall alloca:e to the new units, on a reasonable basis acceptable to the subdivider, the votes in the unit owners' associaeion allocated to the subdivided unit, and shall reflect a p:oportiona~e allocati~n to the new units of the liabil~ty for coinmon expenses and rights to c mmon profits formerly ap~~rtaining to the subdivided unit e) such plats and plans as may be necessary to show the boundaries separating the new units together with th~ir other boundaries shall be prepared, and the new u~its depicted the:eon shall bear their new identi!yi~g numbe:s. Su.ct plats and plans shall indicate the di:ie.nsions of the new U lits, and the horizontal boundaries thereof if any, shal l be identified thereon with reference to ese~blished datum. such ~lats and plans shall be certified as to their accuracy and com~liance with the provisions of this subsection l) by a registered land surveyor in the case of any plat and (2) by a registered architect or :egistered engineer in the case of any plan 59 J f hen cppro iate instruments in accorda~ce i t h i:.he pr.ec'l!dir.g su sections hereof have been prepared, e x ecui:.ed, and· ackr.owledged, they shall be delivered forthwii:.h to the subdivider upon paym~r.t by the subdivider of all reasonable costs for the prepara'C.i.on and acknowledqment ~e:eof. Such i~st um~nts shall become effective when t.,e subdivider h3s executed· 3nd recorded them, and the reco.:datior. the eof shall be eon'Ciusive ev.idence that the subdivision th.us e ftectua ted did not ;violate any restrictions or Umitations specified by t e ccndominium instruments and thae a~y reallocatior.s made pursuant to subsections (c) a.~d (d) were =easonarle CJ No-thwithstar.dinq the provis!.ons of sections 103 (28) and 218(d this section shall have no applicatio~ to converti=le spaces, ar.d no such space shall be deemed a u it f or ~e t;:ur~oses of this section. However, this seceion shal l apply to any ur..its formed Cy the conversion of all or any ~or-eicn cf any such space, and ar.y such unit shall be deemed a unit for the purposes of this section. sec. 227 I e rm.in.a ti on or Amendment before conveyance of any Unit. If the:e is no uni~ CWT.er ae.her ha he decla:ant, the declarant may unilaterally termina~e the condominium er amend the condo:ni:Uum instruments, a nd any UCh termi~ation or amendment shall beco~e effective u pon r 60 e =ecordation thereof if the same has bee~ executed by ~h~ declaran But this section shall not be construed to nullify, limit, or otherwise affect tbe validity or enforceability of any agreement renouncinq or to rer.ounce, in wbole or in pa:t, the right hereby conferred. sec. 228. Termination or Amendment after conveyance of any Unit a) If there is any unit owner o~her than the declarant, then the condominiwn shail be termina~ed only by ~he agreem~nt cf unit cwners ot units to· which four-fifths of the votes in the unit owners• association appe=tain, or such larqer majority as the condominium instrume~~s may specify b) If there is any unit owner other ~ha~ the de.clarant, then the condominium instruments shall be amended only by agreement of unit owners of units to whi.ch two- thirds of the votes in the unit owners• association appertain, or such larger majozity as the condominium instruments may specify, exceE=t in cases for which this act provides different methods of amendments c) If none of tbe units in the condominium are restricted exclusively to residential use hen the condominium instruments may specify majorities smaller than the minimums specified by subsections (a) a~d (b 61 d) Ag=eement of the required majority of unit owr.ers to termi:witicn -of the condom.i:U.um or to any amendment of the co~ciomir.ium instrwnents shall be evidenced by execution of the termination agreement or aaendment, er of ratifications thereof by such unit owne.rs or their attorneys-in-fact, and the same shall become effective only when such aqre~nt is so evidenced of record~ For the purposes of thi section and section ·227 an i"nst ument terlaj.natinq c:ondomi_nil.un shall be deemed a co;idominiwn instrument subject to the provisions of section 205, and for the purposes of this sec~ion, any ratification of such an amendment shall also be deemed such an inst.rumer.t. Such recorded instrwnent sha·ll ~lso be recorded in the office of the Surveyor e) Except to the extent expressly i:ermitted or exfressly required by other provisions of this act, no a~endment ~o the condominium ins-eruments shal.1 change the ~oundaries of any unit, the undivided interest in the common elemen~s appertaining thereto, the liability for common exr-enses er rights to common profit:.s appertaininq thereto, or the number of votes in the uni~ owners• association appertaining thereto f) Upon recordation of ar. instrument terminatinq a condominium, all cf the property constituting the same shall be cwr.ed by the ur.i t owners as tenants in common in 62- proportion tc their respective undivided interests in the common e!ements iaunediatel.y p.rior to such recordation. But as long as such tenancy in common lasts. each unit owner or the heirs, successors, or assigns thereof shall have an exclusive rigbt of occupancy of that portion of such proE=erty 1i11hich fonnerly constituted such unit OW ler·•s unit g) Open recordation of an instrument terminating condominium, the rights of the unit ·owners to the net assets of the unit cwners• association shall in pro?Jrtion to their respective liabilities for common expenses as set forth in the bylaws pursuant to section 312(c) prior to ~uch recorda ticn h) No provision of this act shall be cons~ued in \ de.roqation of any requirement of the condominium ·instruments that all er a specified. number of the beneficiaries of mortgages or deeds of trust encumbering the condominium units approve specified actions contemplated by the unit -owners association. sec. 229. Requirements for Residential Leasehold Condominiums a) The declarant of a leasehold condomi.niwn sha11 record with the condominium instruments any lease pursaant to which tbe condominium is a leasehold condomi."lium (u condominium lease Provided, however, it shall be 63 sufficient for the declarant to record a statement of the book, page and date of recordation of such lease if such lea-se has previously been recorded amonq the land records of the District of Co.lumbia. condominium instruments establishing a leaseho.ld condominium containinq more than three residential units sha.l.l not be effective unless the condominium lease (s) comply with the requirements of subsect.icns b c and (d) of thi.s section. {b) If a condominium is a leasehold condoutini wn subject to the provisions of this section, any condominium lease shall be for a term of not less than 99 years with a right of renewal ·for consecutive additional terms of not less than 99 years. Th.e lease shall provide for level periodic payments which may not be increased du.ring the first lO years of the lea·sehold term If provided in the lease, the lessor may ~etition the Mayor for an incr~se in leasehold payments to be effective be-;inning with the el.eve~th year of -the leasehold term, and the Mayor shall approve such increase if he finds that: {l) costs borne by the lessor in connection with the lease have increased, or (2) costs of livin.q, as measured by a standard statistical index computed and poblished by the Onited 7 r.c a -64- States Government and available for the period of the leasehold term, have increased, and (3) the increase in the lease payments is in reasonable proportion to such increased costs An increase in lease payments shall· be effective for .a minimum eriod o.f lO years, after which the lessor may again petition for an increase subject to ·the provisions of this subsection. The lessor shall not require or accept lease payments which do not meet the requirements of this paraqraph c) A essor of: a condominium lease may sell or assign· the lease only .after offerinq the unit owners• association I 0£ the condominium the right to purchase the leasehold estate at a price and on terms offered to any other prospective purchaser. The lessor shall give the unit owners• association a period of at least 60 days within which to accept or reject the offer d) The lessor of a condominium lease shall give the· I lessee of such lease a statement not less than five ·years. prior to the expiration of such lease o~ whether tbe _lease is to be renewed and on what terms the lease is to be renewed. If the lessor offers to renew the lease, the 65- lessor shall give the lessee a period of at leas~ 180 days withi n which to accept or reject the offer. Title III control and Governance of Condominiums. Sec. 301. contents of the Bylaws a) There shal.l be recorded simultaneously with the declaration a set of bylaws providing for the self-govel:mnent of the condomi.n;·um by association ot all the unit owners. The unit owners• associaticn may be incorporated. {b) The bylaws shall provide whether or not the unit owners• association sha11 have an executive organ. The executive organ, if any, shall, subsequent ·to the expiration of the period of declarant control specified pursuant to section 302(a be e1ected by the unit owners unless the unit owners vote to amend the bylaws to provide otherwise. If there is to be such an orqan, the bylaws sha.ll specify the powers and responsibilities of th·e same and the number -a~c terms of its numbers. The bylaws may delegate to such organ, inter any of the powers and responsibilities assigned this act to the unit owners' association. The bylaws sball also specify which, if any, of its powe s and responsibilities the unit owners• association or its executive organ may delegate to a managing agent lt r 66 \ (c) The bylaws shall provide whether or not there shall be offic~s in addition to the members of the executive orqan. It there a.re to be such additional officers, the bylaws shall specify the powers and responsibilities ot the same, the manner of their selection and removal, their number and their teDls. The bylaws may delegate .to uch additional officers, inter ll any of the powers a.nd responsibilities assigned by this act 'to the uni~ owners association d) In any case where an amendment to the declaration is requirea :y section 2l2(b c or (d the person or rsons req~red o xecute the same shall also prepare and \ \ te, and record simultaneously with such amendment, an \ amendment to the ~ylaws. The amendment to the bylaws shall allocate to the new uni~s votes in the unit owners• a ssociation, rights to future common profits, and liabilities. for future common expenses not specially assessed, on the same bases as were used for such allocations to the units depicted on plats and .plans recorded t=nrsuant to section 214 (a) and (b or shal:l abolish the votes appertaininq to former units and reallocate their rights to future co~mon profits, and their liabilities for future ccmmon expenses not specially assessed, to the remaining units in proportion to the 67 elative r i ght s and liabilities of the ~elraining units immediately ~rior to the amendment e he bylaws shaJ.l be so worded as to indicate by whom the deducti.l::le, if any, or any policy insurance on the common elements, will be paid sec. 302. control by the Oeclarant a) The condomi.nium inst~ents may authorize the decla.ra.nt, or .a m~.naqinq agent or scme other person :or .pers&amp;lt gt;ns s~l ected or to te sel ected by the declarant, to appoint ar.d remove som~ or a1l of the officers of the unit owners• association or members of its executive organ, or both, or to exercise powers and ~spon~ib~1ities other se assigned by the i condominium inst~ents and by this act to the tt:1i t owners• \ association, the officers, or the executive orqan~ But no amenciment to the condoutiniaxn instruments shall inc=ease the scope of such autbori%ation if there is any unit owner other t han the declarant and no such aathori:ation shall be lid -after the time set by the condominium instruments or a£tez- uni ts to which three-fourths of the undivided 'interests in I the common elements appertain have been conveyed, whi-&amp;lt hever occurs first. For the purposes of the precedinq sent~nce only, the ca.lculaticn of the fraction of andi vided inter'!st shall be l:a.sed upon the tota.l undivided interests assigned or to be assigned to a1l units registered with the Mayor 68- according to section ~01. The time limit initiall.y set by the condominium instruments shall not exceed: three years ir. th~ case of an expandable condominium or a condominium containing convertible land, or two years in the case of any other condominium containing a.-iy convertible lar.d, or two yea:s in the case of any other condominium. such p~riod shall cQ.D!Dlence upon settlement of the first uni to be sold in ahy ·portion of the condcminiun b 1) If ent~red into at any time prior to the expiration of the period of declarant control contemplated by subsectio a no contract or lease entered into wi~h th~ declarant other than leases subject to section 210 (e or any entity affiliated with the declarantr management co:ltract, employment contract or lease of rec:-eational or parking areas or facilities, which is directly or indirectly made by or on behalf of the unit owners• association, or the unit owners as a group, shall be entered into for a period in excess of two years. Any such contract or agreement may be renewed for periods not in excess of two years: however, at the er.d of any two year period the unit owr,ers association or its executive organ may terminate any further renewals or extensions thereof 2} If entered into at any time prior co the expiration of the period cf declarant control con~emplated -69- b y subsection (a any contrac lease or ag~ee~e~t, other ~han those subject to tr.e "provisions of subsec on (b 1 may be er.tered ir.to by or o~ behalf of the un!t o~ne:s• association, its executive orqar or the uni4= o lers as a group, if such contract, lease o.r agreemer:t is bona fide and is co:nmercially reasonable to the unit owners' association at ~he ti~e entered into under the circumstances c) If the unit cwners• assoc:.i;a.Ucn ~s not ·i~ e:ci.S.te~ce o~ does not have officers at the time Of. the cre~tion Of the condominiuu, the declarant shall, until there is such an association with such officers, have the power and the ~esponsi"l:il!"ty tc ct in all instar.ees where th.is chapter or the condomini\:%1\ instruments r ·eq'lti.re or permit. action by 't:he \ c unit owne:s' assoc:ia tlon, its exec:u'"f"ive organ, or any officer or of ficexs d) Notwithstanding subsection {a) of this sec~ion, the bylaws shall provide that 1) not later tr.an the time that units to which t~enty-five percent of the undivided interests in the common elements appertain have been I conveyed, the unit owners• association sha1l cause a spec~al meeting to te held at which not less than twenty-five percent of the members of the executive orqan shall be selected by unit owners other than declarant; and (2) not later than ~he time units to which fifty percent of the ® I ii 10- u~divided interests in the couunon elements a9pe=ta have been conveyed, the ur.J.t owners• association sr.all cause a special meeting to be held at which not less than thirty- three ·and one-third percent of the membe=s of tile executive o=gan shall te selected by ur it cwners other than d~clarant e) A person or entity is "affiliated with" t:.h~ declaran.t for the purposes of this section if; Ci) such pe~son controls .qr- ha"s a substantia;l financi·al i:ite=est in the declarant or (2) the declarant controls or has a subs~antial financial interest in such person or en~ity. [f) This section shall be strictly cons~rued to protect the rights of the unit owners. sec. 303. Meetings Meeti.~g of the unit a•r.~rs• association sr.all be held in accordance with the provisions of the condomir.ium instruments at least once each year after the formation of such association. The bylaws shall specify an officer who shall, at least twenty-one days in advance of any annual or regularly scheduled meeting, and at least seven days i~ advance of any other meetinq, send to each unit owner notice of the ti111e, place, and purpose or purposes of such meeting. Such notice shall be sent by United States mai1, to al1 unit cwners of recor:i at the address of their respective units and to such oth~r addresses as any of them may hAve designated to such officer; or such notice may be hand-delivered by ~he sai d o: f icer rovided he obtains a receip-e of ac=ep-t.a:.ce o: such notice frcm the unit owner. sec. 30'l. Qaoruzns a} Unless the concominiwn inst:uments cthe ise frovide, a quorum shall be deemed to j be pr~sent throughout any meeting of the U."lit O'w\ners a:ssocia"tion until adjomed if -persons -enti"tled. to ~st more than the thirty-three and one-third"p~ceri.t of t~e vot~s are p:-ese?r at the beginning of s.uc:h meeting The byla-.s may provide for a larger percentage, or for a s~.aller percentage not l~ss than ewenty-five percent b) O~ss the ondoD'tir.ium instrumer.ts speci!y a larger ,I majority, d quorum shall be deemed to be present ~nrougnout \ an_y meeti lq of the executive orqan if t=ersons er.titled to cast one-half of the votes in that body are present at the begincir.q cf such meeting. Sec. 305. Voi:in9 a) The bylaws may allocate t each unit de;icted er. plats and plans that C?mply with section 21 tl (a) and {b) a number of votes in the U li t owne·rs' association f:roportionate to the liabil.i ty for common b) Cther se, the bylaws shall allocate to each such unit an equal num.t:er of v.otes in tbe unit o""n ers' association, subject to the followi~q exce ion: each 7'2- conver icle space so depicted shall be allocated a numbe= o: vo~es in ·the unit cwners• association propor~ona~e to the size of each such space, vis-a-vis the aggregate size of all units so de~icted. while the remaining votes in the unit owners• association shall be allocated equally to the o~her units so depicted c) Since a. unit owner ina.y be more 1:.har, one person if· only one cf such persons is present 'at ·a meeting of the unit owners' association, that person shall be entitled ~o cas~ the vo~es appertaining to that unit. But if more th:ln one of sue persons is present. the vote appertaini.'g to that unit shall t"e cast only in accordanc·e with their unanimous agreement unles.s the condominium ins~ru:ne~"t.s expr9ssly \ provide o&amp;lt;:herwise. and such consent shall be conc:'iusively presumed if ar.y C»e of them purports to cast the votes appertaining to that unit without protest ~eing m~de fo~thwith by any of the others to the person presiding over the meeting. Since a person need not b~ a natural p~rson, the word "person" shall be deemed for the purposes of .this I subsection to include. without limitation. any natural person having authority to execute de~ds on behalf 0£ any person, excluding natural persons, which is, either alone or in conjur.ction with another person or persons, a unit owner 73 d) The votes a?per-tai.nir.g to ar.y u t may be cas~ p~=suant tc a proxy or proxies duly executed by o= or. beha lf of the or.it c:wner, or, in cases where the ur.i or«ne: is more ~n o~e person, by or on behalf of a.ll such persons. No such proxy shall be revocable except by aeeual notice to the person presiding over the meetinq, by tne unit owne~ or by any of such persons, that it be revoked. Any proxy ·shall be void ii i-e: is not dat·ed, if it purpor-:s to be evocable wi thout nctice as fo~esaid, or if the signatures of ~ny of those executing ti':e same has not been duly acknowledged. 7he oxy of any ~erson shall be void if no~ sig~ed by a person haV rig anthon:ty, at -the time crf th~ executior. thereof, to execute deeds on behalf of t!lcit person. Any proxy shall terminate automat.ically upon the ajournmer::t of t h e first meeting held on or a.fter the da e of ~hat pro"¥ e If fifty percer.t or more of the votes in the unie owners' association appertain to twenty-five -percent or less of the units, then ir. any case where a m~jority vote is required by the cor.dominium instrwner.ts or by this chapter, the requirement for such a majority shall be deemed to. include, in addition to the specified majori~y of the votes ssent by the unit owners of a like majority of the units f) Anything in this section to the contra--y ~otwi hstanding, no votes in the unit cwners• associatio 714- sh~ll be deemed to appertain to any condominium u~it duri~g such time as the unit cwner thereof is the unit owners• association. sec. 306. Officers a If clle condominium instruments l Ovide that any officer or officers must be unit owners, then any such officer who disposes o all of his units ir. fee or for a term or terms of six mo~ths or more shall ce deemed to have disquaiifi:ed hi:nself fro:n continuing in office unless ~he condomin~um instruments otherwise i:rcvide, or unless he acquires or contracts to acquire ancther unit in the cCll.dominium under terms qivi~q hi m a right-Of oc~upancy thereto effective on or befo:e the termination of ~is right of occupancy u.~de: such disposi~ion or. disposi 'tions b) If tile condominium instrumer.es ~rovide that any cf ficer or officers must be unit owners, then notwithst3ndinq the provisions of section 206(a the term unit owner" in such context shall, unless the condominium instruments otherwise provide, be dee~ed to iriclude, ti4thout I limitation, any director, officer, part.~er in, or trtl,Stee. of any person, which is, either alone or in conjunction .with another perscn or persons, a unit owner. Any officer who would not be eligible to serve as such were be no~ a cirector, officer, partner ir or trus~ee of such a person 1s- s hall be d ee rr.ed to have disqualified hi~self fzo~ cor.~inuing in office if he ceases to have any such affilia~ion w:.th that person, or if that person would itself have b~e~ deemed to have disqualified itself from continuing i~ such office under subsection (a) were it a natura1 person hold i ng such oft.ice Sec. 307 Opkeet: of the cor,domirµum a) Except to the extent othe~~se ~ovided by the con~ominiu ins-trumen~s, all ~o~rs and responsibilities wi~n rega:d to intenance, repair, renovation, restoratio and repl~ceme:rt of tr.e c?ndominium shall belong (ll to the unit OW ers' associatior in the case of the common elements, and {2 to the individua1 ur..it ·O ler in t he case of Y uni~ or any part ~hereof. Each unit owner shall afford to the othar unit owners and to the unit owners• association and to a.~y agen~s or em;loyees of either such access through such unit a..me:s' ur.it as may be reaso~a1lly necessary to en: ble em to exercise and disci:arge their respective po•ers ar.d responsibilities. But to the extent that damage 'is inf lic~ed on the common elements or any unit through which access is taken, the unit owner causing the same, or the unit ow-r~ers• association if it caused the same, shal l be lia~le for ~he prompt repair thereof 76 b) Notwithstandir.g anything in ~his sect.ion to the contrary the declarant shall warrant agair.st structural defects, each of the units for one year from the date each is conveyed and a..ll of the common elements for two years. The two years ref erred to in the preceding ser.ter.c~ shall begin a~ to each of the common elemen~s, wher.ever the same has beer cOmFleted, or if later l) as to any common element with·in any· additional land pr portion the:eof at the time the fixst unit ~herein is conveyed 2) as ~o any common element within any convertible land or portion ~hereof at the time the first unit therein is conveyed, and {3) as to any· common element wit:hin any ether por~ion ot tbe concominium at the time the first unit therein is conveyed. For e purpcses of this subsection, no unit shall be deemed conveyed unless conveyed to a bona fide purchaser. For the pur~oses of this subsection, struc:t.ural defects shall be those defec~s in ccmponents constituting any unit or co~mon element which reduce the stability or safety of the structure celow accepted standards or res~rict ~he normal intended use of a.l.l or part of the structure and which require repair, renovation, restoration, or replacement. No't.hing in the sul:section shall be construed to make the declarant responsible for any items of maintenance relating to the ur.its or common elements. No action to er.force the -77 arr~nty created cy this subsection may c~ brou~h~ after one year from the da~e such warranty period has expired, except for structural defects which occurred within the warranty period cut which are latent and undetected in fact; in the case of such latent defects, no action sha.ll be brought after six months from the date such defect is detect~d. {c The declarant sha11 post a bond with the syor in the sum of io percent of the estimated .construC"t.ion or conversion ccsts, or shall provide such other securi~y as ~he Mayor shalJ. prescribe. Such bond or other security shall be avai.lable to meet the costs arising from the declarant' s-failu.:e to meet the requirements of this sectio Such land or other secll:ity shall be posted or \ given prior to cor.veyance o~ the first unit and shall be continued until· the end of the warran 'ty period on each U l.i 't ar.d on the common .elements. Sec. 308. Powers of the Unit ~ers' Association {a Excep to the extent expressly prohibited by the condocnir.ium instruments, and subject to any restrict.ions ar.d limitations specified therein, the an.it owners' association sha~l have t.hc l) power to govern all matters re.lat.L'"lq to the condocnir.ium 2) power to sue on beha.l.f of all unit owners e amp 78 3) power to employ, dismiss, and replace agents and empleyees who exercise and discharge the powers and responsitilities of such association ·arising under section 307 power to make or cause to be inade additional improvements on and as a part of the eommon el.ements 5) po,wer to manage the common elements ami to provide for the .use rental or oper~tion of common elements or limited ccmmon elements 6) right to any income derived from payments, fees or charges for the use, rental or OFeratiou of the common elements of the condominium 7) right to grant or withhold approval of any action ty cne or more anit owners or other persons entitled to the occupancy of any unit which would .change the exterior appearance of any unit or of any other port~on of the condomir.iwn, or elect to provide fer the apFointment of an architectural control committee, the members of which must have the same qualifications as officers, to grant or withhold such apFroval 8) right to acquire, hold, convey and encwnl:er title to real property, including .but not limited to condominium units; and (9) right to make contracts and incU liabilities 79 b) Except to the extent .prohibited by the condominium i~s~=uments, and subject to any restriC i ons and limitations specified therein, the executive organ of the ur..it ners' association, if any, and if not, then the u.-Ut owne=s• association itse.l.f, shall bave tbe irrevocable power as Sec. 309. Tort and cor.tract I.ia.bility cal An action for tort alleqin9 a wronq done (l) by ar.y ac;ent or e~loyee of the declarant or of the unit owners association, or 7r in connection with the condition of any port~on of the condominium which the declara.nt or the I association has the responsibility to mai~~ain s hail be brought against the dec:.larant or the association, as the cas~ may be. No .J,tr.it owner shall be precluded from bringing such an action by virtue of pwnership of an undivided interest in the common elements or by reason of membership i 1 the asscciatiqn or status as an officer b) Cnit owners other than the declarant sha.l.l not oe liable for torts caused by agents_ or employees oi the declarant within any convertible land or using any easement so- reserved in the declaration or created by sec iocs 221 and 222 c) An action arising from a contract ~ade by or on behalf of the unit cwners• association. its executive organ, or the unit c-wners as a group, shall be brcr.:ght against the assccia-ticri, or agair.st the declarant i:f the ca.use of action arose. during the exerc~se by the declaram of cor\-:rO'l reserved pursuan~ to :section 30 2 (a No unit owner· sh:all be preciuded frcm tring~r.g soch an action by reason ~f memtership in the association or status as an officer d) A judgment for money against the uni~ aw~ers• association shall be a lien against any property owned by the association, and against each of the condominium units in ?report.ion to the liability of each unit o rner for common expenses as established pursuant to se~ion 312 (c but no u ii t owner shall be otherwise liable on account of such judqment. Any such judgment shall be satisfied first ou~ of the property of the association. Such judqment shall be otherwise subject to the provisions of title 15 of th~ District of Columbia Code. sec. 310 ns a.~ee hen a.ny policy in.:iuranca has been ·obtained by or on behalf of ~he ur.ie owners• association, written notice of the procurecent Q:iereof and ct any subsequent changes therein or te:~ination thereof -81- shall be ~romptly furnished to each unit owner by the officer required to send notices of meetings of ~he unit owners• association. Such notices shall be sent in accordance with the provisions of the last ser.ter.ce of section 303. sec. 3.11. Rights to common Profits The common prof its shall be applied to the payment of common expen~es or O the creation and maintenance Of l!'eSe~es Qr shall be distributed to the ur.it owners in proportion ~o ~he liability for common expenses as established pursuant to ~ection 312(c as the bylaws .shall provide. Sec. 31'2 Liatiillties for Common .Expenses a) Except to ~he ext~nt that the condominium instrum~r.ts provide \ otherwise, any ccnunon expenses associated with Ui~ maintenance, refair, renovation, restoration, or replacement of any limited ccmmcn element sha1l be s~ecially assessed against the condominium ur.it to which that: limited commc;:in element was assigned at the time such expenses were i:nade or i curred. If the limited corrunon element involved was assigned at that time to more than one condominium un;i.t however, such expenses shall be specially assessed against each such condominium unit equally so that the total of such special assessments eqmls the total of such expe~ses C' i y -82 exc~pt to t h e extent that the condomi.nium i~s e~~s provide other~ise b) To the exter t that the condominium inst lments expressly so t=rovide, any other connon expenses benefiting less than all of the condominium units, or caused by the conduct of less than ail those entitled to occupy the same or by ~eir licensees or invitees, shall be specially assessed against t!le condominium unit or tin~·ts i~volved, in accordance -with such reasonable provisio·ns as the condom.iniu:n instrumer.ts may make for such cases c he amount of all common expenses r.ot specially. assessed pursuant to: subsections (a) or (b) shall be assessed again.st the condominium unit, including those un~ts o~ned by the declarant, in accordance ~i't.h the provisions of the condcminium instruments. The bylaws may est.3.blish the frac~ion or percentage of liability for such expenses a?pertainir.g to each condominium unit proportionate to either the si%e or par value of such condominium unit. Otherwise, the bylaws shall allocate ~o each s~ch condominium unit an equal liabi.lity for such expenses subje CO ~he fol.lowing exception: each conver~ible space shall be aJ.lccated a liability for common expenses proportionate to the size of each such space, vis-a-vis the agg=egate size of all units, while the remaining li3tili~y a.3- f o= common expenses shall be alloeated equally to the o~h~r units. Such assessments shall be made by the u.~it owners• association annually, or more often if the condoati.niwn instr'\iments so provide. No cbanqe in the number of votes in the u Ut cwners• association appertai.n.inq to any condomir.ium unit shal.l enlarge, diminish, or otherwise affect a~y liabili1:.ies arising from assessments made prior to such change d) If the condominium instruments ~rovide for any comm~n e~ense assessments to be pa.id in. installments, such instruments may further provide that upon default in the paym~nt of ·any one er more of such insta.J.lmenu the balance thereof shall be accelerated, or that the said balance may be accelerated at the option of the unit own~rs• association its executive orqan, or the managing agent e) Onless the condominium instruments provide otherwise, unpaid assessments for common exper.se and unpa~"il -installments of such assessments shall become past due en the fifteenth day from the day such assessmer.t or installment thereof first became due and payable, and any past due assessment of instailment thereof shall bear interest at the lesser of ten percent per annum or the maximum rate permitted to be charged in the Oistric~ of J s.u- Columbia to natural persons on first mort9ag~ lo~~s at ~he time suctt assessment or inst3llment beca~e past du sec. 313. Lien for Assessments a) All assessmen~s levied aqains-c a condomir..ium unit in accorda~ce with the provisions of this act and a11 lawful provisions of the condominium instruments shall, from the time such assessmen~s teca~e due and payable. constitute a lien in favor of the unit owners• associatinn on the con~omi~ill.!n unit to which such assessments pertain If an assessment is payable in installments, the full amount of sach assessment shall be a lien frcm the time the first ins~allment ther~of becomes due-and raya.ble. Such lien shall be ~rior to al.l ocher liens ar.d encumbrances except l) lie:l.S and \ encumbranc s recorded prior to the recorda.tion of the decl~ratior 2) liens of any first priori~y mor:gage or deed of ~rust on such unit recorded prior to t.~e due data of such assessment or the due date of the first ins~~llmen payable on such assessment: and (3) liens for real estate taxes and municipal assessments or charges against th~ uni \ The provisions of th.is subsection shall not affect ~he prio=ity cf ~echanics o= mate:ialmer.s liens b he recording of the condominium instrum~nts pursudnt to the provisions of this ac~ shall constitute =ecorc nc~ice of the existence of such lien and no further as recordation cf ar.y claim of lien for assessment s h all be required c) A lien for assessments against a condominium unit may be enforced against such condominium unit by a power of sale in favor of the unit owners• association if ·assessments are ~a!f1 due, unless the condaninium instrWnents pr~vide otherwise. A unit owne= shal.l have the right to .cure an~ defaW.t in payment of· assessments at any time prior :to the foreclosure sale cy ~endering payment in full of past due assessments, plus any late c:barqes and interest due thereon and reasonable attorr~ey•s fees and costs incurred in connection with the enforcement of the lien for such assessments. Suc;:h power of sale may be exercised by the executive organ on behalf of the unit owners• association and the executive organ shall have the authority to deed a unit sold at a forecJ.osure sale by the unit owners' association to the purchaser at such sale The recitals in such deed shall be prima faeie evidence of the truth cf the sta~ement made therein and conclusive evidence in favor of bona fide purchasers for value. No foreclosure sale shall .be held until thirty days aner notice is sent ty certified mail to a unit owner at the mailing address of the an.it and at any other address de.signated by a unit owner to the executive orqan for c i \ 86 ur~oses of such a notice The notice shall specify ~he amour.t of ~he assessments past due, togethe: with any accrued interest thezeon and late charges, if any, as of the date of the notice ar.d shall further ~otify the anit owner that if such past due assessmen~ and accrued i.~terest and any late charges are not paid within thirty days after th~ date such notice is ma~led, the executive organ shall _s~ll the unit at a public sale at the tir'\e ana pl'ace ·and on ;a date stated in the notice. Such date of' sale shall not be sooner than thi.rty-or.e days from the date such no~ice is mailed. The executive organ shall qive public notice of. the f o~eclosure sale by advertisement in at least one newspaper of general circ:nlation in the Distric~ of Columbia a.~d by \ such other means it deems r:.ecessary and appropriai:e to qi ve notice of sale, if any Such newspaper advertisement shall afpear on at least three separate days during the fifteen day period ~rior to tbe date of the sale. The proceeds.of sale shall te applied [i) to c.npaid assessments with interest th~reon I and later charges, if any ii) to the cost ~f foreclosure including but noc limited to, reasor.able attorney's fees; r~d (iii) tbe balance to the person or perso~s legally entitled thereto 87- {d) Unless the condominium instruments provide otherwise, the executive organ shall have the power to purchase on behalf of the unit owners• association ar.y unit at any foreclosure sale held on such unit. The executive organ may take title to such anit in the name of Uie unit owne=s• association and may bold, lease, encumber or convey the same. on behalf of the uni. t owners. association ce&amp;gt The 'lien fa assessments provided herein sh.all l apse and J:e of no ~rther effect as to unpaid assessmen~s (or installments thereof) together with interest accrued thereon and late charges, if any, if such lier. is not discharged ·or· if foreclosure or other proceedinqs to enforce the lien have not been ins~tuted thin three years from the date such assessment (or any installment the:-eof) became due and payaJ:le f) The judgment or decree in an action brouqht pursuant to this section shall include, without limitation reimbursement for costs and attorneys• fees g) Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit actions at law to recover sums for which subse~ion (a) creates a lien, maintainable pursuant to section 209 h) Any unit owne.r or purchaser of a condominium unit shall be entitled upon request to a recordable st3tement se~ting fcrth the au.cunt of unpaid assessments currently c 1 es levied against that unit. Such request shall be ~n writing, directed ·to the ~rincipal officer of the unit owr.ers association or to such other officer as the condominium instruments may specify. Failure to furnish or make available such a statement within five business d~ys from the receipt .of such request shall extinguish the· lien created l:y subsection (a) as to the condominium unit involved. Such statement shal.l be binding n th~ unit owners' association, the executive organ and every .unit cwner. Payment of a reasonable fee may te required as a prerequisite to the issuance of such a statement if tbe condominium-instruments so provide Ci) Upon any volunta-ry transfer of a legal or equitable i i~terest in a condominium unit, except as security for debt, all unpaid ccmmon expense assessments or instal.l.ments thereof then due and payable from the gTantor sball be paid or else the grantee sball become jointly and severally -liable with the granter subject to the provisions of subsection (h Opon any involuntary transfer of a l~gal" or equitable interest in a condominium onit, howeve e~e tz-ansferee shal.l net l::e l.iC&amp;amp;.ble fur such assessments or instal.lments thereof as became due and payable prior to ll.is acquisitio~ of such interest. To the extent not collected f:crn tb.e edecessor in title of such transferee, such 89- arrears shall be deemed common expenses, collec i.ble fro~ all unit cwners (including such transferee) in proportion to their liabilities for common expenses pursuant ~o seC"Cion 312 (c sec. 314 Financial. Records The unit owners' association shall cause to be kept books with detailed accounts. in cbronoloqi~l order of the associatiqns inc0.in.e and expenditures Said books and ~e vouchers accr~ditinq the entries therein shall be made available for examination by the unit cwners and their attorneys, accountants, and authori%ed agents during reasonable hours on business days. such books ·shall be kept in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and shall be subjected to an independent audit at least once each year. Sec. 315 estraints on Alienation If the condominium instruments create any rights of first refusal or other restraints on free a1ienabiiity of any of the condominium units, such riqhts and restraints shall be void unless the condominium instruments make provisions for promptly furnishing to any unit owner or purchaser requesting tbe same a recordable statement certifying to any waiver of, or failure or refusal to exercise, such rights ar.d restraints, in all cases where such wai er, failure, or refusal does in fact occur. Failure or refusal to fu:nish J 90 promptly such a statemeri~ in such ci=cumstances i n accordance ~ii:h the provisions of the condo~inium instruments shall make all such righ~s and restraints inapplicatle to ar.y dis~osition of a condominium unit in contemplation of which such statement was requested. Any such statement shall be binding on the association -of unit owners; its executive organ, and every unit owner PaYn:tent of a reasonable fee may }:)e required ·as ·a prerequisite tc:&amp;gt; the issuance of such a statement if the condCminium· i~s~ruments so p=ovide. Ti~le IV eqistration and Offering of Condominium~ Sec 0 Ex~~ptions Unless the method of ofier· or cl disposition is adopted for the purpose of evasion of this ac.t, the p-rov-isions of sections 403, 40&amp;amp 405 amp;i06, 407, 408, 409, and 412 of this act do not apply to a) dispositions in a condominium in which all. u~its are restricted to couunerciai, indust=ial, or othe nonresidential use b) dispositions pursuant to court order: \ (c) dispositions by any government or goverp.inen~ ager.cy; er (d) solicitation and acquisition by the declara.nt of nor..binding reservation aqreements 91- Sec. 402. Prohibitions on Dispositions of Onits. Unless exempt by section 401 a) Neither declarant nor any person on behalf of declarant may of£er or dispose of any interest ir. a condominium unit located in the District of Columbia, nor dispose in the District of Columbia of ·any interest in a condominium ur.it located without the District of .coJ.:wnl:lia prior to the.time the condominium including such uni.t is registered in accor~nce with this act; and (b) No declarant may dispose of any interest in a condominium unit unless there is delivered to the purchaser a current putlie offerinq statement by the time of such di sposition and such disposition is expressly and without qualification or condition subject to cancellation by the purchaser within fifteen days after the cont:aet date of such disposition, or within 15 days after delivery of ~e current public offering statement, whichever is later. A public offering statement is not current unless any necessary amendments are incorporated therein or attached thereto. Unless otherwise stated herein, the foreclosure of lien provisions should be in accord with o.c. Code, sec. 45- 615(b 1973 edition If the purchaser elects to cancel, he may do so by notice thereof hand-delivered or sent by United States mail, return receipt requested, to the decl arant. { 92 such cance.lla tion shall be without pe:i.al_ty, and any det:osi t made by the ~urchase.r shall be i:romptly refunded in its entirety c) The public cff~.rinq statement and sal.es contract shall contain a clause and its Spanish equivalent in a form presc:ited ty the Mayor which shall clearly state the purchaserts right to cancel. sec. 40 3. Application fo.r Reqi ~Uat:ion a) The application for registration of the condc:ni.nimn shall be \ fi l ed as prescri~ed by the Mayor's· rules and shall contain the following documents and information {l) An-1.rre~ocable appointment of an agent in the Di strict of Colamtia, and in the absence of such an aqent, I the agency to receive se::vice of any lawful pr~cess in any nonc:iminal ~roc~ed.ing arising under this act against the applicant or ap~licant•s personal representative 2) The states or jurisdictions in which an applicant for registration or similar document pertaining to the condomir..iwn has l:een filed, and any adverse order, juc;iqme'nt, I or decree l:y any regulatory authority or by any coun en~ered aqains~ declarant or any other person ref err~d to in parag:aph (3) in connection with (A) any :egistration, offer of sale of any ccndominiwn or condominium units B) any violation of any condcminiwn statute or a.~y lack of 93 compliance with a condominium instrument; and (C) any breach of contract, fraud or misrepresentation perpetrated against any· unit a-mer, unit owner association or unit purchaser 3) The name, address, and principal occupation for tbe past five years of every officer of the appl.ic:ant or person occupyil'.lg a similar status or performinq similar fu~ctions; the extent and nature of such person• s interest in tbe applicant ·or.the .condominium as of a specified date within thirty days of the f~ling of the application 4) A statement, in a form acceptable to the Mayor, of the condition of the title to the condoatiniwn project including encwnl:rances as of a specified date within hirty days of the date of application by a title opinion of a licensed attorney, not a salaried employee, o£ficer or director of the applicant or owner, or by o~ber evidence of ~itle acceptable to the Mayor 5) Copies of any management agreements, emplo}'Dlent A'9 contracts or other contracts or aqree~ents affecting the use or maintenance of, or access to, a1l or a part of the condominium 6) Plats and plans of t.he condominium that comply with the provisions of section 214 other than the certification requirements t.bereofr and which show all u.~ts and buil.dings containing onits to be built anywhere within the submitted c 9U land other than within the boundaries of any cor.ve ie lands; except that the Mayor may by regulation or order waive or modify this requirement or the requirements of section 214 for ~lats and lans of a condominium located outside the District of colwnbia 7) The proposed public off erinq s.tatement. {8) Any other info:;mation, including any curre.nt financ~al statement, which the Mayor. by.his reguiations requires fer the protection of purchasers. {b} If the declarant registers additional units to be offered for disposition in the same condominium he may c~nsolidate ~e sUi5s~quent registration with any earl.ier registration cfferir.g units in the condominium for d~sposition under the same promotional plan c) The declaraz:t ·shall maintain a copy of tbe a?plication for registration at the declarant•s principal office at the condominium. The application for reqi$t.ra~ion shall be made avail.able for public inspection upon request at ·reasonable times, Provided, howeve that the ~ayor may grant confidential status to any information required Ursuant to ~ection 404(a ll}. The declaran~ sha1l promptly repcrt any material changes in the infor~ation contained in an application for regis~ration and amend the application accordinq1y 95 d} Each application shall be accompanied by a f ee in an amount determined by the Mayor. The amount of such fee shall be esta~lished at a rate adequate to cover the costs related to processing such application and to provide additional funds to be available to defray the costs of administering this act. sec 404. Pu.l:lic Offering Statement a A public of£erinq Sta't:eme~t sh·au disclose fully and accurate:ly· the characteristics of the condominium and the units therein offered and shall inake known to prospective purchasers all unusual and material circumstances or features affecting the condominium. The proposed public offering statement s ubmitted to the Mayor shall be in a fc m prescribed by his rules and shall include 1) the name and principal address of the declarant and the condominiwn 2) the applicant's name, address, and the form, date, and jurisdiction of organization, the address of each of its offices in the District of Columbia, the names and addresses of all general partners if applicant is a partnership, a.nd a1l. directors and owners of ten percent or more of the beneficial interest in the stock of applicant if aP.plicant is a corporation 96 3) to the extent that such information is reasonabl"y available to applica·nt the names and addresses of the attorney primarily responsible for ~he preparation of the condcminium doc:tmtents, the 9eneral contractor, if any, all. contractors who are primarily responsible for the construction, reconstruction or renovation of the electrical, plwnl::ing or mechanical systems or the .roof of the condominium, and the architect. a·nd ·engil'.leer. prima.ri;].y responsible fer the design, construction or renovation of the condominium 4) a general narrative description of the condominitmf Statir.q .the tota.l number of er.its in the cff ~rinq; the total r.umber of units planned to be sold a id I th.e number of units to be rented; the total ouzr.be·r of units that !l'lay be included in. the condominium by reason of future e:cpansion or merger of the project by t."le declarant 5) a copy of the declaration and bylaws, wit~ a -brief narrative statement describing each and including (A iniormaticn en declarant control 3) a projected budget for I at least the first year of the condominium's operat~o {including projected common expense assessm~~ts for each unit [C) previsions for enforcement of ~ens for assessments D provisions for reserves for capita1 expenditures E) the estimated amount of any initial or 97 special condominium fee doe from the purchaser on or before settlement of the purchase contract and the basis of such fee and (F) a description of any restraints on ali enation 6) copies of the instruments which will be delivered to a purchaser to evidence his interest in the unit and of the contracts and other agreements witi.cb a purchaser will be required to agree to or sign 7 a copy of any management contract, lease of recreational areas nd any other conttact or agreement substantially a£fecting the use or maintenance of, or access to all or any part of the condominium with a brief narrative statement of the effect of each such agreement upon a f r=haser, tbe condominium unit owners and the condominium, a nd a statement of the relationship, i£ any, between the declarant and the managing agent or firm 8) a general statement of (A) the statas of cons~ruction B) the project's compliance with zoning, site plan and building permit requlations, {C) source of financing availacle and the estimated amount necessary to complete all improvements shown on the plats and plans as "NOT YET COMPLETED· or "NOT YET BEGUN" which decl.arant is obligated .to complete and (D) the projected date of completicn of construction or renovation of the major amenities of the condominium 98 {9) the significant terms of any encwnbrances, easements, liens ana matters of title affecting t~e condominium 10) the significant terms of any financing offered by or th:rough the declarant to purchasers of units .in the condominium 11) t.be provisions and any significant limita'1;-ions of any warranties provided by the dP.ciararit on the unit~ and the common elements, other than the wa:r·anty p escribed by section 307 (l 12) a statement that the contract purchaser of. a coodomin.iml-imit the dec1arant may cancel the purchase transaction within. fifteen days following the date of \ e~ecution of the contract by the purchaser or the receipt of a current pucl.ic offering statement, whichever is later 13) a statement as to whether or not the condominium satisfies, er is expected to satisfy, the -special requ:U:ements pertaining to condominiums estal:ll.ished by federal, fede:ra1ly chartered or District of Columbia institutions -Which insure, guarantee or maintain a se.condary marke-e for c:cmiominium unii inortqages 1 additional information requi:ed by the Mayor to assure full and fair disclosure to prospective purchasers; and 99 15) plans of the condominium which c l ear ly locate al l ur.its and buildings and all common elements b) The public offering statement shall not be used for any promotional ~urposes before :registra-eion of the condominium t=roject and afterwards only if it is used in its entirety. No person ~y advertise or ·r-epresent that the Mayor aP.proves or recommends the condominium or cµsposit.i."on thereof No po~ion ;of the public ?f£erin9 ·statemen.t inay be underscored, italici~ed, or printed in larger or heavier or different color type than the remainder of the statement if such empiasis is intended to mislead the prospective purchaser or to otherwise conceal material facts, except that there- may be a cover she~t for such public offerinq statement using such design, pictures and words as the Mayor may deem reasonal:le. The form, content, and layout of the public offering statement shall be subject to approval by the Mayor c) The decla.rant shall file with the Mayor a statement of any material change in the information contained in ttie public offering statement. Such statement shall be filed within fifteen days after the date on which the declarant knows or should have known· a.bout the change. The Mayor may require the declarant to ainend the public offering statement i f necessary to assw:e full and fair disclosure to 1004 prospective purchasers. A public offering s ate~e is ~ot current unless any necessary atrendments are incorporated therein or a~tached thereto. Such amendments must be maiied by United States registered mail turn receipt requested. such receipt shall 't:e kept on file for review d) The provisions of this section shall be deemed to be complied ~ith if the public offering statement filed pursuant to the provisions of sect.i~n 404 ·ta&amp;gt 9 is for offers of units currently registered as securities with the Securities and Exchange Commission. sec OS. Inquiry and Investigation Open receip~ of an applicati"on f cr registration in proper form, the Mayor J may forthwith initiate an investigation to determine a) that there is reasonable assurance that the declarant can convey or· cause to be conveyed the units offered for disposition if the purchaser complies with the terms or the c£f er b) that there is reasonable assurance 'that all proposed improvements will be completed as represented c) that the advertising material and the 'gene~~l promotional p~an are not false or misleading and comply with the standards prescribed by the Mayor in its rules and afford full and fair disclosures 101 d) whether the declarant has, or if a corporation its officers and p:incipa1s have, been convicted of a crime involving condominiUDt unit dispositions or any aspect of the land sales business in the Onited States or any foreign country within the past ten years, or has been subject to any inj~nction or administrative order restraining false or misieadinq promotional plan involving land dispositions; and e} the puplic: offering statement requirements of this act have been satisfied. sec. 406. Notice of Filing and Registration a) Open receipt of the application for registration in proper fo~m, the Mayor shall, within five business days, issue a no~ice of filing to the applicant. Within sixty days from the da. te of the notice of filing, the Mayor shall enter an order registering the condominium or rejecting the registration. If no order of rejection is entered within sixty days from the date of notice of filing, the condominium shall be deemed registered unless the applicant has consent in writing to a delay b) If the Mayor affirmatively determines, upon inquiry and examination, that the requirements of section LlOS have been Dlet, be shall enter an order registering the concominium and may require any additions, deletions, or 102 modifications i n ar.d to the publ ic offering s~atement in order to assure full and fair disclosure c) I.f the Mayor determines upon inquiry and examination, that any 0£ the rei;Juizements o:f section 405 have not been met, he shal.J. notify tbe applicant that the application for registration must be corrected ir:i tne particulars specified within fifteen days or such longer. period ·as he may prescribe. If the equiiements are not met within the time allowed the Mayor shall enter an order =e j ~ctinq tile registration which shall include the findings of fact u~on which the order is based. The order rejecting the registr~ion ~al1 not become effective for twenty days ii fte= the la·~se .of .the aforesaid period during which twenty \ day period the applicant may petition for reconsideration a~d shall ee entitled to a hearing to contest the particulars spec.ified in the Mayor• s notice. S\:Ch order of rejection shall not take effect during the pendency of a hearing, if ~equested Sec. 407. Annual Report: Termination of Regis:tration he declarant shall, during any period of control of ·the condominium ty the declarant pursuant to section 302 file a report in the fo:cm prescribed by the rules of the Mayor within thirty days of each anniversary date of the order registering the condominiwn. The report shall reflect any 103- material changes in in£ormation contained in the original application for ~egistration. In the event that the annual report reveals that a.ll of the units in the condominium have been disposed of, and that a.ll [:eriod for conversi on or expansion have expired, the Mayor shall issue an order termina't:-ing the registration of the .condominium. s_ee o 8 c .onversion condominiums; Special P.rovisioris a) °Any decla-rant of a conversiop condominium shall° include in his puclic cffering statement in addition to t he requirements of section 404 l) A descr; ption of any provisions made in the budget for reserves for capital expenditures, contingencies and i provements and an explanation of the basis for such reserves, or, if no provision is made for such reserves, a statement to that effect; and (2) a state.iner.t by the declarant based upon a report of a qualified architect or engineer as to the present -condition of al1 structural compqnents and major uti1ity installations in the condominium. The statement shall include A) the approximate dates of construction, i nstallation, and major repairs of structaral components and major utility installations and a general description of \ ~f 104 each instal led system as particularly suitable or unsui~able for use in a conversion condominium B) an evaluation of the adequacy of each system to perform its intended function both before and a!ter completion of the condominium conversion; and (C) the estimated life of the system components and tbe estiuated cost (in current dol1ars) of replacin~ each com~onent that has· a rat,ed lif that is evaluated .to be less than the rated life of the entire structur·e. The architect•s or enqineer•s report upon which the statement required by this subsection is based shall be filed with ~he Mavor as a part of the application for J' re c;i str3 ticn b) In the case of a conversion condominium l) The declarant shall give each of the tenants or subtenants of the building or buildings -hich the declarant submits to the provisions of this act at least one hundred twenty days notice of the conversion before any such tenant. or subtenant may ~e served with notice to vacate. su~b I notice of conversion shall be given no later than ten da after clle date the decla.rant' s application for registration of the ccndominium. units is approved. The notice shall- be in such form as the Mayor may require and sl:lall set forth generally the rights of tenants and subtenants pursuant to 10s- this section. such notice shall be hand-delivered or sent by United States mail, return receipt requested. such notice shall contain a statement inclicatinq that such notice shall ·not be construed as abroqatinq any rights any tenant may have under a valid existinq written lease 2) Durinq the first sixty days of the one hundred twenty~day notice period; each of the tenants who emered into· an: agreement ~ith declarant or; de.cla.rant s predecessor in interest to lease the apartment unit shall hav~ the j exclusive riqht to contract for the purchase of such apartment unit. If the tenants do not contract for the ?Urchase of their apartment unit, durinq the seccr.d sixty d~ y~ of such one hundred twenty-day period, each of the subtenants, if any who occupy the apartment unit under an agreement with the tenants shall have the ex cl usi ve right to contract for the purc:.hase of sucb apartment unit. The exclusive right to contract for the purchase of such apartment units shal1 be on terms and conditions at least as favorable to the tenants or subtenants as those being offered t:y declarant to the general public. The right to contract for purchase granted to the tenants and subtenants, if any, of an apartment unit shall be granted only where the t~nant or subtenant has remained, and on the date of the notice is, in substantial compliance with the terms of the 0 -106 l ease or sut:lease agre12ment, and if such apartment ur.i t is to ~e retained in tbe conversion condominium wi~,out subsi:antial renovation or alteration in its physical layout If tbere is .more t.ban one tenant, then each such tenant shall be entitled to contzact for the purchase of a proportionate share of the apartment unit and of. a ortionate share of the share of any tenant ~o elects not to purchase. If the tenants do not contract for t~.e purchase cf the apartment unit and if the:e is mere .than one subtenant occupying the apartment unit, then eacb such subtenant shall be entitled to contract fo: the purchase of a proportio~ate shar:e of the apartment unit occupied, ar.d of a proportionate share of .the .share of any subtenant who \ elects net to purchase. In no case shall this subsection be deemed to authorize the purchase of less than the enti:e interest in the apartment unit to be conveyed {3) If the notice of conversion specifies a dat by which the apa:rtlr.ent unit shall be vacated, then such notice shall constitute and be the equivalent· of a valid 1 statutory notice to vacate. Otherwise, the declarant Sha.ll give the te~an~ or su=~enant Oc lo.o apa e z s be vacated the statutory nOtice to vacate where required by law in com~liance with the requirements applicable thereto Sec. 409. Escrow of Deposit. Any deposit ma de in r~gard to any disposition of a unit, including a nonbinding reservation agreement, shall be he1d ·in escrow until either delivered at settlement or returned to the prospective pu.rchaser. Such escrow funds shall be deposited in a separat~ account for each condominium .in a financial L-istitut.ion the .acccants ·of which are insured by :a. federal or state agency These deposits s~ll bear ·interest: at the passbook rate then PFevailing in the District of Columbi a beginning with the ~irst business day after the date deposited with declarant or declarant•s agent. Earned interest shall be credited to the prospective purchaser's de Fosit~ Such escrow funds shall not be subject to a~tachment by the creditors of either the purchaser or the declarant. sec lO. Oeclarant to Deliver Decl~ration a.nd Bylaws to Purchaser Onless previo'1sly furnished, an exact copy of -the recorded declaration and bylaws shall be furnished to each purchaser l:y the declarant within ten days of recordation thereof as provided for in sections 201 and 205. sec. 4ll. Resale by Purchaser a) In the event of any resale of a condominium unit by a unit owner other than the declarant, such owner shall obtain from the unit owners 3.ssociation and furnish to the purchaser, prior to the os cont=act date of the disposition, the following, o= else the contract -shall be enforceable only at the option of the purchaser [1) apt=ropriate statements pursuant to section 3l3(h) and, if applicable, section 315 2) a statement of any capital expenditur·es anticipated ty the unit owners• association within the curren~ or succeeding two fiscai Ye rs 3) a statement of the status and amoUri~ of any reserves for capital expenditures, contingencies, and improvements, and any portion of such reserves earmarked any specifi~d pro'ject by the executive orqan for a copy of the statement Of financial condition for the unit ~ners• association for the then most recent fiscal year for which sucb statement is available and the cur=ent o~erating budget, if any 5) a statement of the status of any pending suits or any judgments to which the unit owners' association is a. party 6) a statement setting forth what insura.-ic.e coverage. is ~rovided for all unit owners by the un.1.t owners• association and a statement whether sucb coverage ir.clades public liability, loss or damage, or fire and extended 109- coverage insurance with respect to the unit and its contents: C 7) a statement that aey improvements or alterations made to the unit, or the limited common elements assigned thereto by the prior unit owner are not in- viola tion of the condominium instruments~ and 8) a statement of the remaininq term of any leasehold estate af£ectinq the condomiii.ium or the condominium unit and the provisions qoverning any extension or renewal thereof. {b) The principal .officer of the unit owners' a~sociation or such other officer or officers as the condcminium instrul:lents may specify, shall furnish t le statements prescribed by subsection (a) hereof upon the written request of any unit owner or purchaser within ten days of the receipt of such request c) Subject to the provisioms of section 401, but notwi t lstanding any other provisions of this act, the provisions and requirements of this section shall apply to any such resale of a condominium unit created under the provisions of the Horizontal roperty Act. Sec. 412. General Powers and Duties of the Mayor a) This ·act shall be administered by the Mayor or his desiqnee. Th~ Hayer shall prescribe reasonable ru1es ~ich shall be c II o adopted, amended or repealed in accordance with the provisions o~ the District of Col umbia Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Code secs. l-lSOl et seq The rules shall include but not be 1imited to prov.is.ions £or advertising standards to assure full and fair disclosure provi sions for operating procedures; and such other rules a.s are necessary and. proper to accomplish .tl;ie purposes of th~s act. The initial such requJ.ations s!la..L..l be. promulc;ated by the r~yor within 120 days after the effective date of this act l b) The Mayor by regulation, ru1e or order, a.£ter gt;le notice and a.ring may require the filing of ~ing materi l relating to condominiums prior to t..li.e distr.ibution of such material c The Mayor may by .regulation, r .ule or order. approve the filing and use of an abbreviated public offering state~~nt if the agency determines that the pt,lblic inter~st and the interests of purchasers would best be served there.by. The Mayor shall determine whether or not such abbreviated disclosure will be permitted based upon cons i deration of the following factors among others {l) the total number of units being offered is small, which shall mean generally less than ten 9 111 2} adequate. disc::J.osure of relevant inf ormati9n will otllerwise be readily available to pro~pecti purchas~rs 3) the class of purchasers will be comprised substantially of per5ons havinq the ability to protect their own interests (such as the present tenants and (4) in the case of a caiversion condominium, no s bstantial renovation or remodelling of the ur.i-t:s will be done d) If it appears that a person bas engaged or is about to engage in an act or practice constituting a violation of a provision of this act, or a rule, regulation o~ order hereunder, the Mayor, with or 1'ithout prior administrative proceedings may bring an action in the Superior court of the District of Colwnbia to enjoin the acts or practices and to enforce compliance with this act or any rule, regulation or order hereunder Open proper showing, injunctive-relief or te:nporary restraining orders shall be granted. The Z ayor is not required to post a bond in any court proceedings or prC?ve that any other adequate remedy at l~w exists. {e) The Mayor may intervene in any suit involving the rights and liabilities of declarant with respect to the condominium being r _egistered and any transactions related thereto. The Mayor may require the declarant _to notify the 112 yor of any snit by or ·against the declarant involving a condomin~um estatlished or sold by the declarant f) The Mayor may l) accept req.istration.s filed in other jurisdictions or with the Federal Government 2l contract with similar agencies in this .or othe ju:risdicti_ons to perform i.nvestiga ti ve functions; and (3) accept grants in aid from any gov~nmenta~ source g) The Mayor shall noti.fy the .Rental Accommodations commission whenever an application is made to register a conversion eondom:inj.:wn and !llt such time as any application o register a conversion condominium is approved. \ sec. II 13. Investigations and Proceedinqs a) The Maj•or may make necessary public or private investigations in accordance with law within or outside of the Oist:rict of Columbia to determine whether any person has violated or is -about to violate this act or any rule or order hereunder, or to aid in the enforcement of this act or in the P:resc::ibing of rules and forms hereunder b} Eor the pu:pose cf any investiqatio~ or proceeding uncer this act the Mayor or any officer designated by rule may administer oaths or affirmations, and upon the Mayor's own motion o:r upon request of any party 113- shall sub~cena witnesses, compel their attendance, take evidence; and require the production of any matter which is relevant to the investigation, including the existence, description, nature, custody, condition, and location of any books, documents or other tanqible tilings ·and the identity and location of persons having knowledqe of relevant: fad:.s or any other matter reasonably calculated to lead to the discov-ery of material evidence c) Open failure to obey a subpoena or to answer questions propounded by the investiqatinq officer and upon reasonable notice to all persons affected thereby, the Mayor may apply t$ the -SuP,erior Court of the District of Columbia for an order e~~ellinq compliance. \ sec. 4lq. cease and Desist orders a) If the Mayor determines after notic and hearing that a person has (l) violated any provision of this act 2) directly or through an agent or employee knowingly engaged in any false, deceptive or misleading advertising, E=rOinotional, or saJ.es method to offer or di spose of a unit 3) made any substantial chanqf in the plan of disposition and development of the condominium subsequent to the order of regist.%ation without notifying the agency r [ t c 4) disposed of any ur.i~s ~hich have not been registered with the ·agency; or (5) violated any lawful order or rule of the agency; the Mayor may issue an order requiring the person to cease and desist from the unlawful practice and to take s~ch af£inati"'le aetion as -in -hi'S -judgment wi11 carTy oa the pur~es of this act b) I:f the May~ 11lakes a finding of fact in writing that the public interest wil1 be irreparably harmed by delay in issuing an order the Mayor may issue a temporary cease a~d desist ·order. Prior to issuing the temporary cease and 2~sist order, the Mayor shall give notice of the proposal to issue a temporary cease and desist order to the person affected. Every temporary cease and desist order shall include .in its terms a provision that upon request a hearing will be held promptly to determine whether or not such order becomes permanent. Sec. 415. Revocation a) A regist=ation may be revoked after notice and hearing upon a written finding of tr.a. t the declara.nt has l) failed to comply with the te:cns of a cease and desist order 115 {2) beeD convicted in any court subsequent to t he filing of tbe apf:lication for registration for a crime invclving fraud, deception, fa1se pretenses, misrepresentation, false advertising, or dishonest dealing in real estate transactions 3) disposed Of, concealed Or diverted any funds or asset.s of any_ person so as to defeat the rights of uni·t purchasers failed faithfully to perform ar.y stipulation or agreement made with the Mayor as an inducement to grant any registration, to reinstate any registration, or ta a?prove any ~romotional plan or public offering s~atement; or (5) made intentional misrepresentations ·or concealed material facts in an application for registration. Findings of fact, if set· forth in statutory language, shal.l be accompanied by a concise and explicit statement of the -underlying facts supporting the findings b) If the Mayor finds a ~er notice and hearing that the declarant has been guilty of a violation for which revocation could be ordered, the agency may issue a cease and desist order instead. sec. Ql6. Judicial Review. Proceed.ings for judicial review of Maycral actions shall be subject to and be i n 116 accordance with the District of Columbia Administ=ative Procedure Act (O.c. Code, secs. 1-1501 et seq applicable to "rule-making Provided, however, that review of Mayoral actions pursuant to section 406 shall be subject to provisions applicable to "contested cases Sec. 417. Penalties Any person who willfully. violates any provision of this act or any Tule adopted ~nde-r or order issued pursuant to section: td2 or any person who willfully in an ap-plication for reqistration makes any untrue statement of a material fact or omits to state a material fact shal.l be fined not less than SlOOO or doub~e ~h~ amount 'O'f qai'h from the transaction, whichever is the i' larger but net .more than $50,000; or such person may be \ -imprisoned for- not more than si.x months; or both for each offense. Prcsecution for violations of this act shQll be brought in the name of the District of Columbia by the corporation Counsel or bis assistants Sec. 418. Severabi.lity If any provision of this act, or any paragraph, section, sentence, clause, pbr~se or I word or the application thereof, in any circumstances is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this ~C't, and of the application of any such provision, paragraph, section, sentence, clallSe, phrase or word in any circumstances shall not be a.f fected thereby and ~o th.is end, the provisions of th.is act are declared severable. Section Zll9 f fective .Date This ac:t shall take effect as provided for acts of the council of the District of Columbia. in Section 602(c) of the Di.strict of Colwnbia Seil-Government and GOVe.:n.Dlental Reorqan.1%ation Act sec. 1'20. Amendments to existing Law. Tbe Distric:t of c·ol.wri.bia Rental Ac:c:ommodation5 act of 1975 co.c. Law, No. l-33} .is a.mended as follows 1 Sec 213 (b 4) of such act is amended by insertinq "and such renta.J. unit or housing ac:c:ozrunodat.ion is not bein9 converted to a c:ondozninimn immedia.tely after "another person 2) Sec 213 (c of such act is amended by inserting 1 immediately after e and by insertinq the f ollowinq at the end thereof 2) in any case where a la'llCUord s.eeks to recover possession of a rental unit or housing accommodation to convert such rental unit or bousinq accommodation to a condominimn, notice shall be given acccrdinq t:o the provisions of section 503 of the C.cndomin:f.am act of 1976 {3) Sec 302 of such act is amended by (A) striking out "condominium or B) st.rilcinq oat 1 8 0" and inserting in lieU: thereof "120 cc&amp;gt; striking out "1501! and inserting in c 11 a lieu thereof "90" and (D) striking out "condotni.r..ium units" and inserting in lieu thereof "cooperative units Title V cor.domi.niwn Conversion; Housing Assistance Pa:rt A Condominium Conversion sec. 501 a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no person may convert nor shall the Mayor permit the conversion of any housing accommodation or rental -unit ~n the Oistr.ict of Columbia into a c:onci"outi:niuin except as provided in this title b l) A housing accommodation or rer.tal unit in the District of Columbia may be converted into a condominium A i£ that housing accommodation is a high rent housing ac.commodation or if that rental unit is located \ i n. a high rent bousing accommodation, at any time· after tbe eff ectiv~ date of this title; or (B) except as ~ovided in paragraph (2 if that housing accommodation is not a high rent housing accommodation er if tbat rental unit is located in a housing accommodation which is net a higb rent housing acccmmodation, at any time afte:r the effective date ·o this title at whien t.ne most recently compu~ed vacancy ra~e (computed according to the procedure set forth upon the er.actmer.t of the condominium act of 1976, Bill 1-179, a dopted cy the Council July 20, 1976 effective at the end of 119- t he thirty day period, provided for congressional review o f acts of the council under section 602(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act) higher than 3 percent. For the purposes of this tit1e, the term "high rent housing accommodation includes any housing ·accommodation i~ the Distric:t of Columbia for which the total monthly rent exceeds an amount computed for such housing accarunod~tion as follows i) multiply the number of rental units in the following categories by the corresponding rent I 212. 51 for or.e bedroom rental uni ts II) S2 6 7 for two bedroom rental units III) S375 for three or ~ore bedroom rental units: and (IV} Sl62 .50 for efficiency rental units; and (ii) totai the results obtained in phase (i 2) Any housing accommodation which is not a high -rent housing accommodation may be converted to a condominium, notwithstanding a vacancy rate of 3 percent or less, if at least a majority of the heads of households actually residing in such housing accommodation, as of the first day of the month in which the application re1atinq to the registration of such housing acco111D1odation is filed, ha,,e signed a written agreement consenting to such c €£ \ 1der m t ·cen is s a ~J i I zted I :ipJ l .i :orJ j s i I I I j l I. j 1g I o n: l I :dil irij 0, I I 120- conversion. If a majority of t~e heads of households in such housing acccmmodation have signed such written agreements, but the conversion has not taken place, then the landlord of that housing accommodation sha1l notify each prospective tenant of tbat housing accommodation that a majority of the heads of households in that housing acccrrunodation ha.ve signed such agreements. No landlord or declaran t shall use any means W'hatsoever to coerce any person into signing such an agreement. sec. 502 ~ithin ninety days after tbe effective date of this act, the Mayor shall, according to a procedure developed him ·whi.ch may include the use of. a scientific random sample compute and certify the percentage of all I pr_ivately o.,ned rental units in the District of Colwnbia l ocated in hcusing accommodations which are not high rent hcusinq acco~modations At least once every twelve months thereafter the Mayor shall, according to such procedurer compute and publish in the District of Columbia Register a prelimir.ary ~ercentaqe. During the immediately foll~ing· 30 1 days the Mayor shall conduct hearings on that perce~ge and based upon the record of those bearings, he shal~ certify a final Fercentac;e. When certified tbe percentage («. so certified by the Mayor shall be the vacancy rate for tbe 121- 9u=;oses of section 501 until another percentage is computed and certified by the Mayor. Part B Housing Assistance Sec. SU a) In addition to all other requirements of ~his act, and to all other applicable provisions of law, e ach declarant of a conversion cendominium shall pay housing assistan.ce, in a.n amcu.z:it ·caicula.ted according to section 512 to· any ~ligibie ecipient who {l) makes application for such assistance 2) has been living, for at least one year immediately prior to the first day of the month in which the lication for registration relating to such conversion is fil ed, in the rental unit from which be i.s beinq displaced 3) is displaced from a rental unit because such renta.l-wli.t is being converted to a condominium by the declara.nt; and (ti) relocates in the District of colwneia. such housing assistance shall be paid in one lump sum payment within 30 days after the date such recipient relocates. Beginning with the twenty-fi£th month occurring immediately after the month in which such recipient relocated; and for tbe immediately succeeding 35 months thereafter, housing assistance payments to such recipient shall be made cy the Mayer of the District of columbia if 7 0 f th a s l a ti ~1 1c I I n~ I -122- as of the f i=st day of the twenty-fifth month occur=ing after his relocation the recipient is eligible for such payment. In lieu of monthly payments, tbe Mayor may make a lumi sum payment to an eligib1e recipient equal to the amount to which.he is entitled to receive under this title. {b) In .addition to all other requirements of this aC:t, and to all otbe~ applicab1e provisions of law each declarant of a conversion condomin~um shall ·pay ~eioc~t;ion conq~ensation to any e.liqible recipient i ·n each rental unit in the building converted if such rental unit is occupied primarily for residential purposes on the date tbe notice rei;uired CY subsect±on ~03(b) is given~ Such relocation assistance scall be calculated according to the provisions \ of section 513 c) No ~art of any housing assistance payment or any relocation com~ensation made under this title shall be considered income to the. recipient for the purposes of the District of Columbia .Income and Franchise Tax act of ·1947. Any such housing assistance payment or any relocation I compensation made to any person or family entitled receive any other paywent from the Distr~ct of Columbia government related to paying the costs of housing or shelter shall be in addition to and .shall not affect the amount of entitlement to such other payment Of th bia s .e P Oda ti :t Of 123 sec. 512 a) The amount of each housing assistance payment to be made under this title shall be calculated as follows 1) If the amount of an applicant• s average monthly hcusing expense, during the twelve consecutive month period ~nding with the month preceding 'the month d~ing which he. relocated as a result of his rental unit bej.nq converted· to· a condoaiinium, is an amount which is le.ss than 25 percent of the av~rage net monthly family income, computed for such ·period, then the amount of the monthly f oliJ housing assistar.ce payment to such applicant shall be in an i amount equal to tbe difference between an amount equal to 25 .5 rJ fl i percent of such average net monthly family ir.come and the )O~ rJ· amoant of the monthly housinq expense to be paid by the .om r l un4 j 2) 4 :ig ad nJ lea th applicant for the first full month after such relocation excluding security deposit, if any 2) If the amount of a recipient's average monthly housing expense, during such period, is an amount which is more than 25 percent of such average net monthly family income, then the amount of the monthly housing assistance payment payable to such applicant shall be in an amount equal to the difference between such average monthly housing expense during such period and the amount of the monthly housing expense to be paid by the applicant for the first c c irt Of th :Jia s dati j t Of I I an 2ti full month after such relocation (excluding security deposit, if any 3) To ol:tain the total housing 3.ssistance payment to be made by a declarant to any eligible recipient, multiply the figure obtained under either paragraph (l) or 2 as ap~rcpriate, by twenty-four o obtain the total housing assistance payment to be made by the Mayor to a~y eligible recipient, mult.i~ly such aripropriate figure by. thirty-six b) The Mayor shall determine, from time to time and at least once every twelve months, the range of rents being 1=ha.:ged in 'f:he Di~ct of Columbia by landlords of ,f privately owned housing accommodations for generally \ a ailable one bedroom, two bedroom, three bedroom or more, and efficiency rentaJ. units. The Mayor shall publish his preliminary range of rents in the District of. Colllmbia Register and, during the next immediately ocurrrinq 30 ~ays 8 hold hearings on that preliminary range. Based on the record of tbose bearings, the Mayor shall certify a final I .range of rents to be used by him for the purpose~ of is title. The figure obtained under either paragrapb or (2) of subsection (a as appropriate, shall not exceed the difference between the highest rent in the range of rents of comparable rental units of suitable size, as determined by -125 he Mayor at the time of the housing assistance payment is ade to such recipient, and the amount of the recipient• s average monthly housing expense for the twelve month period refe red. to in section (a) [l Sec. 513 a) The amount of relocation compensation payable sllall be ca1culat~ as follows 1) Re.location compensation in the amount of one hundred twentY..five dollars for each oom· i tbe. apartment unit shall be payable to the tenants if ·the tenants are occupying the apartmeat unit or if the tenants are not occupying the apartment unit, to the tenants or subtenants bearinq the-cost ~f .removing the majority of the f nishi.ngs or the puri;:oses of the preceding sentence a \ "room" in an apartment unit sbaJ.l mean any space sixty square feet er larger which has a fixed ceiling and floor and is subdivided with fixed partitions on al.l sides, but shall not mean bathrooms, balconies, closets, pantries kitchens, foyers, ha1lways, storage areas, utility rooms or the like 2) The Mayor shall adjust the amounts to ·be pa.id as relocation Compensation from time to time solely ~o reflect changes in the cost of moving within the Washington Metropolitan Area. Such adjustments shall be ·made no more £ F 7 7 t v ° c c 126 j t han once in any calendar year and sball be made only after prior notice and hearing b) Relocation compensation shall be paid no later than 24 hours Frier to the date the apartment unit is to be vacated by the tenants or subtenants if the declarant bas r receive~ at least ten days advance written notice of the date upon which :the apartment unit is to be vacated If no such ·notice has ~een received, then. relocation compe~sation shall be t=aid within. tb.irty days a£ter the apartment unit is vacated. {c} If there is more than one person entitled to re icaticn ·compensation with respect to an apart:nent unit such person shall be entitled to share equally in the a:ncur.t of relocaticn compensation. In any case in which there is a dispute as to whether relocation compensa~ion shall .be f:aid for an apartment unit, or the proper amount of such compensation or the persons entitled to such com~sation, the declarant may pay to the ?o'.ayor the maximum possible relocation compensation allowable for such apartment unit and shal.l thereby be relieved of any fur~her obl~ation under this subsection (d} with respec~ to such apartment unit. The Mayor shall hold such payment and shall determine whether relocation compensation is payable with pect to the a~r"tment ·unit, the amount of relocation 127 compensation payable, if any, and the person or persons entitled thereto I'be Mayor shall refund any remainder of such payment to the decla.rant d) Payment of relocation compensation shall not be required with respect. to any apartment unit which is the subject of an outstanding judgment for possession obtairied by the declarant or declarant•s predecessor in interest against the tenants or subtenants f~r a cause of action. whether such cause of action arises before or after the service of the notice of conversion. I£, however, the judgment for possession is based on nonpayment ar.d arise~ after the n?ttice bf .Conversion has been given, then i:elocation compensation shall· be required in an amount re.duced ey the amount determined to be due and owing to declarant by the court rendering the judgment for possession. Sec. 514(a Each declarant of a conversion condominium, in addition to and at the same time that be sends tenants in the building to be converted the notic.es I required under section ~OS(b shall send to each sucp tenant the necessCU'y application forms (with instruci;:ions} provided by the Mayor for making app1ication for the housing assistance paym~nts and relocation compensation payable under the provisicns of this title. Each applicant c· 0 128- for such assi~ance or compensation shall give to the Ma yor such reascnable information as he may require in order to determine whether such applicant is eligible for ~he payments for which he applied. All information provided to the Mayor under this section shall be confidential and shall not be disclosed to any person or goverrunenta.l or pdvate entity in such a manner as to identify the applicant to whom the inf orma ti on relates b) If the inf o:rmation provided by an applicant on the form filed with toe Mayor indicates that sueh applicant is eligible for the relocation compensation payable under s-:c~ion Sll""f-b tnerr sttch applicant shall be presumed to be J' a e l igible recit=ient and the Mayor shall notify the \ appropriate declarant of the aa:otmt. of payment dUer to whom i t shall l:e paidr ar..d t .he address at which such payment s hould be delivered. Each declarant shall make each =elocation compensation payment in a lump sum payment egual -to the total amount of the payment for which be is liable to t iat recipient c) In the event that a declarant believes that ith~r tile recipient is net an eligible .recipient, or that t:.he payment to that recipient ·should be lower than the amount in~icated cy the Mayor, for either housing assistance ?aymen~s or for relocation compensation, he may seek review 129~ of both the eligibility of the recipient and the a moun~ of such payment by (l) ma.king the payment as indicated by the Mayor, and (2) filinq a notice of appeal and reques~ for a hearinq with the Mayor within lO days after ma.king such payment. The Mayor shall conduct such requested hearing as soon as ,possible after such request is made. Based .on the record ·of the bearinq held as requested by .a dec:iarant. t.ne Mayor shall aete:mine· whether t~e recipient is actually eligible for the pa~ent received, or whether the amount of such payment is correct, as appropriate. In the event. the Mayor determines that the recipient is not eligible, or that the amount of the payment made should be reduced, he shall i ~sue an order to that effect, requirinq the recipient to return to the declarant any payment received to which he was not entitled d) The eligibility of a recipient for housing assistance payments shall be reviewed by the Mayor biannually. Sec. 515. The Mayor znay enter into contracts with any bank or other financial institution in the District of Columbia ~ov.idinq that such bank or other financial i~stitution shall make the monthly payments of housing assistance for which the District of Columbia is liable (if the Mayor elects not to make a lump sum payment) from sums 30 cf money deposited in such bank or financial institution by the Mayor for that purpose sec. 516. A new section 5-732 (b is hereby added to the District of Columbia Code to read as follows benever a Cuilding in the District of Columbia is converted from rental to condominium units, the Relocation Assis_tan.ce Offic.e shall Pr-ovide relocation a.dvisqry -services for tena n-ts 'tiiho .u:iove from the conve~ed tuilding. This includes: Ascertaining the relocation needs fo: each household; providing c:arrent inf orma~ion on the availability of equivalent su~stitute housing; supplying information concerning ·Federal and District housing ·programs; and ?rovidinq ctber advisory services to displaced persons in order to minimize hardships in adjusting to relocation Sec. Sl 7. [a) For the purposes of this title, t e term suitable size" means for a one person family, an efficiency rental unit: for a two person faznily, a one bedroom rental -unit; fo: a family of three or foar persons, a two bedroom rent~l unit; for a family of five or six persons, a three bedroom rental unit; and for a family of seven or more persons, a four c~droom rental unit; except, adjustments shall. be made to all.ow children and unmarried adults of the opposite sex, to have separate sleeping rooms. In d ermi~ing suitable size for a eomparable rental unit, one -131- person living in a one bedroom rental unit before rel ocation as a resu1t of condoi::Li.nium c::cnversion sha.ll. be eligible for assistance at the level of a one bedroom comparable rental unit b) An eligible recipient, for the purposes of this tiUe, means the head of household in ,which the household has a combined annuai inc:cme tc~linq s than the following percentages of the median ann'1al. family ~come {.for a household of four persons) for the District of Columbia, as such median is d.etel:mined by the United States Bureau of the Census and adjusted yearly by historic. trends of that median, and as .o ay be further adjusted by an interim ceus-.is of District of Columbia incomes collected under cont=act by local or regional qovel:nment aqencies one-person household two-person household three Person household or a one-or-two person household containinq any person who is 60 years of aqe or older or who is handicapped as defined by the Mayor four-person household five-person household mere than five-person household SO percent 60 percent 90 percent lOO percent llO percent 120 percent Cc) For the purposes of this ti tie housinq .z accommodation• means m:iy structure or building in the o:.st.rict of Columbia containing one or mere rental. units G 132- and t he land appurtenant thereto. Such term sha.ll not include any hotel, motel, or other structure, i.~cluding ar.y room therein, used primarily for transient occupancy and in which ·at least 60 percent of the rooms devoted to living quarters for tenants or guests are used for transient occupancy, any rental on.it in an establishment whic~ has as its pri11tary purpose the providing of diagnostic care and treatment ·of diseases, including blJ:t not limited to hospitals, conva1esc.ent homes, nursing homes, and personal care homes; or any dormitory of an institute of higher education, or a ~rivate boarding school, in which are provided for students d) Eor the purposes of this title, the term "housing project" means a. group of housing acconunodatior.s which are IT'.a.naged as a single business entity e} For the purposes of this title, the term "head of household" means an individual who maiat.ains a rental unit -as his principal place of abode, is a bona fide resident and domicil l iary of the District of Columbia~ and contributes more than one half the cost of maintaining such rentai unit. An individual may be considered a head of household without regard as tc whether such individual would qualify as a head of household for the purposes of any other law 133 f) For the purposes of this title, the term "comparable rental units" means rental units of corresponding facilities and with the same or sim.i.lar benefits or services inc.laded in the price of the rent 9 For the purposes of this title, the term ntotal monthly. rent" shall inc1ude the rents asked for vacant units sec. 518 a The 1=rovisions of this title shall not apply to any housing accommodation, any housing project, or any rental unit in any housing accommodation, if l) the i.ni tial condominium instruments relating to the conversion of the housing accommodation, the housing oj~ct (inc.ludinq ar.y housing acconunodation which is part of the housing project or the rental unit was filed with the Recorder of Deeds in the District of Columbia .before the beginning of the first moratorium on condominium conversions in tbe District of Columbia; and 2) the actual conversion process for not less than SO percent of the units in the proposed condominium was begun befcre June l, 1976; or (3) the bousing acco1DD1odation or housinq project has been vacant for tbe twelve consecutive Months ending on June l, 1976 f s-r 13&amp;amp;J b) In addition, this title shal..l net apply to a housing accommodation owned by a cooperative association c) The provisions of this tit1e shall net apply to any h~usinq accommodation or build:Lnq owned .by the government of the Oist:ic:t of Co1umbia € Docket for the sm _l i7_9 June 29, 1976 Considered n Council rune 29 t 1976 First Vote RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE I COIJNCI MCMaKJll AYC NAT N.V COUNCIL. NllMall" AYC NAT N.V COUNCIL. MCMaCR AYC NAT \ !UCKZR )C D'IXON x SPAut.DING x MJOR D. x BAB.DY x ~N X" BARRY x HOBSON x WIN'rD. x CI.ARKE x MX&amp;gt;RE, J. x COATES x SBACKIEroN x X Z11diC11S• Vote A. B-Abseat M. v-Hoe Vottq. Llluif 1 UJ,1J A Final Vote in Council 1uly 20 t 1976 SecmJ_rv of the ~ncil) i RECORD OF cou NC IL. VOTE. COUNCIL. MllMaCR ATC NAT N.v COUNCii. MCMaCR ATC HAT N.Y COUNCU. N&amp;amp;MaC ATC NAT TUCKZR x DIXON x SPAtJT DL"C x I ~DORE, D. x HARDY x WllSON x -R y x HOBSON x t.ln"Tn I x I Lt~:\i:Z x M:&amp;gt;ORE 1 x i Ci S x \ SHACl\I.ETON x &amp;gt lndlcal" Vose A. B.-A.bMGt H V-"fot Votmg Secretary of the Cauncil Presented to the Mayor Secretary of the ·Council Mayor's Action ed 2 6 AUG 1976 pprov Disapproved acted vithout Mayor's Signature Secretary of the Council) 4 4 S fl r 1 C"\ N.Y H.V \LL~Y j I I i j i I e.m Ooc:ket B 1 11._N o 1 17_9 Page Two Recori gt; idered by Council RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE C:Ol.:NCIL MltM81t A'l'll: NAT N.V. A.a. COUNCIL MEM•E ATll: NAT H.Y COUNCIL Mll:M•C A.Tit NAT N.Y. TUCKER DDroN SPAUI.DING HDORZ, D. BARDY WII.SON BARRY HOBSON wnrrER CUR.KE M&amp;gt;OBE, J ATES SBACXI.E:TON 1 X-lndlca1 Vole A. 1 Ahsem N. V-Not Voting Presented to the President in Mayor's Veto t S sU?in Mayor's Veto JAN l 0 1977 1~lm i tt d to the Congress Senate Action Resolution Number Secretary of the Council Secretary of the Council President of the U. SS ~O.W 2 Secretary of the Council) HouseAc~on ResolJtion .Number I I A.a .J I I h Secretary of the Senate cnactcci. without Congressional action Secretary of the Council Clerk of the House)</search-text>
  </meta>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>I</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>101</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1901.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>102</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1901.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>103</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1901.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>104</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1901.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>105</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1901.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>106</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1901.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>107</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1901.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>108</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1901.08"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>201</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>202</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>203</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>204</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>205</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>206</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>207</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>208</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>209</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.09"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>210</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.10"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>211</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.11"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>212</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.12"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>213</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.13"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>214</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.14"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>215</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.15"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>216</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.16"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>217</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.17"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>218</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.18"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>219</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.19"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>220</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.20"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>221</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.21"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>222</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.22"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>223</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.23"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>224</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.24"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>225</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.25"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>226</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.26"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>227</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.27"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>228</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.28"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>229</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.29"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>230</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1902.30"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>III</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>301</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>302</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>303</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>304</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>305</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>306</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>307</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>308</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>309</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.09"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>310</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.10"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>311</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.11"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>312</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.12"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>313</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.13"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>314</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.14"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>315</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.15"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>316</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.16"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>317</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.17"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>318</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.18"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>319</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.19"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>320</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.20"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>321</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1903.21"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>IV</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>401</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>402</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>403</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>405</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.04"/>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>406</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>407</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>408</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>409</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.09"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>410</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.10"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>411</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.11"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>412</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.12"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>413</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.13"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>414</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.14"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>415</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.15"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>416</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.16"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>417</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.17"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>418</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-1904.18"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>V</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>516</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-333.02"/>
    </section>
  </container>
</document>
