<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-93">
  <num type="law">1-93</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-03-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-93.pdf">D.C. Law 1-93</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 9532b</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-93 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-307, which was referred to the Committee on Education, Recreation and Youth Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 27, 1976 and September 15, 1976, respectively. Enacted without signature by the Mayor on October 20, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-162 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBL'\ NOTICE March 31, 197 7 D C. Law 1- 93 "Distr ict of Columbia Youth Services Act of 1976" Pursuant to S e ction 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Gove rnment a nd Gove r nmental Reor ganizati on Act {PL 93-198}, the Act, the Council of the Di strict of Columbia adopted Bill No 1 3 0( on first and second readings J u ly 27, 19 76 a nd September 15, 1976, respectively Followin g the e} piration of the ten-day per iod p r ovided the Mayor in which no actio n was taken, pursua nt to Section 404(e of th e Act, thi s legislation was assigned Act No. 1-162 published in the Novembe r 12, 19 76 edition of the D. C Register a nd transmitted to both Houses of Cong ress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Sec tion 602(c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Con g r essional review p e r iod ha s expired a nd, therefore, cite s the following legislation as D C La w 1- 93 effective March 29 1977. 2 ] s TERLINGTtrCKER Chairman of fue Council (Rei. 23, DCRe g 3 056, November 12 1976) D. C. LAW 1-93 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MARCH 29 1977 To reorganize the youth services programs of the District of Columbia government, and for other purposes. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OP THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Youth Services Act of 1976 Definitions Sec 2. As used in this act the term a youthn means those residents of the District of Columbia between the ages of thirteen and seventeen, inclusive b} "children" means those residents of the District of Colwnbia ages twelve and under c Neighborhood Planning Council" means the structure designated for adult and youth participation in the development, implementation, and evaluation of programs for children and youth, pursuant to Commissioner's Order No 68-219 March 25, 1968 2 rl) 11 councilmember 11 means any ~erson thirt.een ye a r s a nd o v e r who lives with in the qeoaraphic area of a Neiahbor~ood Pl anninn Council who has registere d h i s/~er name 31d re~s and t e l ephone n umber with that particular council e} 11Co1mci 1 of Chair p ersons" means the body of assembled c hai r persons of ~ach of the N~ iqhborhood Planning councils f Of: i c e 11 Di r ector" and ot~er s u ch terms mean t h e Of fice of You t h Advo ca cy e ~tatlisheu in section 5 and fu r ther specified in otber pa r ts o f t h is act; and g division 11 t'iirector a nd other such terms mean t ie (l ivision of community- based f r o qrams fo r children and youth of t h e Departmen~ of ~ecrea~ion established i n section u and f u t~er specifie d in o+.her parts o f t his act. Purpos es S ec It is ~he ?Urpose of this act t o a) P r omote and support pro~rams for c~ildren and yo uth in P.xis t.ing a qencies of t.~e Distric~ o f Co lumb i a governme nt h eorga:iize i"he current pattern of procp:ams and s 1 ic s for c hilcr.en an·i outh cf f~red thi::o11qh the Office o f Youth Oypo~tunity S~rvices 3 C l Ensur~ t~at 30 effective mechanism e xis ts ~o facilitate youth ~mployment d) Pr ovine a revie w and evaluation mechanism :or existing s~rvices and pro~rams for c hi ldren and youth an1 (e) P romo te anrl suppo r t p r ograms for His9anic youth in o.c. 1v1encies Reorqanization sec 4 a) Th~ commi ssione'C S Orr'ler )lo 70- 93 (aooroved ~arch 17, 1q7 0 t es ~ablishing the Of fice of Youtb Oppor tunity se r vices, is h~reby repeal ed and that Off i ce i5 ~ereby abolishe1 All of the powers duties and func tions assi~ned t.o t hat off ice unoer any frov ision of law are hereby tr3ns~err~ to the departme~ts and a gencies as in~ica ted in the following provisions of this ~ct b) There are her~hy ~ransferred to t ~e nepar ent of Pecr~atio Orqani za~ion Or~er 1 0 Commiss i oner s o r ier .lo 68 -4 11 0 lune 27, 1q59~ a mP.nded Au J$ t S 1&amp;lt;3'5 8 Cc r.o e r 3 1 968 in.j :1rl c!'l l4 1970) the followino f• rn ct i ons p r eviously performei by the Office o f Youth Opportunity .SP.rvices l l ~ssist and facil i tate proqrams for children and youth can:ied on by Me.ighborho oi Pl3nni na Councils {Commissioner s Or~er ~lo 5B- 2 i q arch 25 1968 anci ot~er communiry o r ganiza t i ons inclu~inq ut not l imi I 4- to any and all organizations p r oviding services to Hispanic youth pursuant to pr ograms, unde r programs, pr eviously funded by the Office of Youth Opportuni ty Se rv ices providing maximal commun ity pa rticipat ion in decision -making } As direc t ed by t he Mayor conduct spec i a l a nd citywide youth -programs 3) Operate juvenile delinquency prevention programs c l} There is hereby established in t he Depa rtment o f Recreat i on a division of community- ba sed prog rams for children and youth which shall provide administrative anc ope r a t ional support for programs tor children and you t h conducted by the Neighborhood Planning Counci ls and other community organi zation s 2) The division of communi t y-based programs for children and youth will have t he r esponsibility t or t he administration of community recreational educationa l cultu r al and economic development progr ams of the Neighbo rhood Planning Councils Al l appropriated and grant funds fo r the operation of such programs will be adminis t ered separately with in the division under the aUS?ices of the Departoer.t o f Recreat i on All yo uth deve lopment block g rant funds received by the Dist r ict I 5- \.overnment fro he fe1eral Community services ~oministrntion, as desiqnated for such r-urFoses, shall be obliaated in ~ro~rams for childr en and youth canducted by t he Neiqhborhoon Planninq cooncils 3) Local proqr am planninq project selection, and tlesiqnation of project g rant s wi ll be Ferformeo by the Neiahborhood Planni no Coimcil s There wi l l he an P.quitable allocation of funds has~d on c hi ldren and you population, fo r e~ch Neighborhood Plannincr Council U) The authority and fiscal res~onsitility to mana9e community elect i ons for the Neighborhood Planninq Councils will he assicrn to the division of community-basPd oroqrams fo r c~il~ren and you th under the iirection of the Department of ?ecreation 5) The director o~ t he division of community- based proqrams for chiljren and youtb shall b~ d~~o1nted by t e L&amp;gt;i rec o r of tt lt Depa tmen~ of rtecr eation n he •iivision of community- tased roo rams for childre n and yonth shall in consultation \~ir.h t:he council of Chair?ersons prepa r e an oper ational man~nl for the developm~nt and i mplRmentation cf programs 7 hP. director of r.he division of co~munity- base rog r3~s for childr~n and youth ~ill te responsible fer CJorjinati 311 com~unit!-bnsed proqrams f e r cr.ildr~n 6- and youth. Decisions on community program priorities will be made by each Neighborhood ?lanning Council, according to criteria specified in the oper ational manual developed by the division The dir~ctor of the division of community- based programs for children and youth will serve as liaison to the Neighborhood Planning Councils and the Council of Chairpersons, and be accountable to both the Neighborhood Planning Councils and the Department of Recreation for the effective administration of community- based programs for children and youth The director of the division will insure that adequate technical assistance is available to the Council of Chairpersons and each Neighborhood Planning Council 8) The Neighborhood Planning Councils shall continue to abide by their uniform Constitution and By- laws, consistent with this act and othe r District laws. Changes and amendments to the uniform Consti t ution and By-laws shall be made only by the consent of the Council of Chairpersons d) There are hereby transferred to the Department of Manpower (Organization Order No 46 Commissioner's Order No 74 144, June 29 1974) the functions of the Office of Youth Opportunity Services r elating to the coorcination of p rograms designed to provide jobs for youth \ I f4 t 7 e) Ther e are hP.reby transferred to t~e school ot Continuinq Education, Federal City Colle~e Universi~y of the Oistrict of Columbia (D. c. Law 1-36) the functions of the Office of You t h Oppurtunity Services with r espect to the administ:.ration and supervision of the Distric~ of Columbia Street c"idemy f) Ther e ar~ her~by assiqn~d to the aoa rd of Ef.ucatior. of the Di st=ict of Colu~tia the ~unctions ~f t he Office of Youth Oc;Jportuni~y S~ rvices with respect -to t11e summer lunch p~oqram for childr en ana youth Off i ce of Youth Advocacy Se c S a here is hereby established in tr.e execu+-ive cranch an Office of You Advocacy which sh~l l f e rform a pl~nning rPview and evaludtion functio n for a l l ~roqrams operated by t he District of columtia ~overnment i~pact inq on c lildren and yout h, includino eme;loymen health, counselin1 recreation and traininc { T~e Direc~or o f the Office of Youth Advocacy shall be appointed by the ~ayor he Cirec~or may holJ no other public office { The followina 9ositions and their sociat~a funninq are ~ereby au ho i7.ed to be transfe red frorn tr Office of Ynn~h Opportnni ty gt;rvices to thP Office af vout.h Advocacy: 1 Special Assistant to the Ma yor 35- 1 6 l l 1 1 l l 1 8 Subj~ct to t~e prior approval of the Ci vil service Commiss i on pu rsuan t to 5 u s c 5108 1a~t&amp;gt;Ower S9ecialist. GS 14 Recreation specialist GS-14 £ducat.ion Specialist GS-12 Pro-,ram .Analyst Officer GS- 13 Comt=uter Analy:;t GS-13 Secr etary GS- 7 Secretary (Typist) GS- 6 (d) Con~istent with ~his act. and other District law t~e Direccor may hir mployees assinn wo r k a nd &amp;lt;lelega~e t le duties e xercise t he owers an:l ca rry ou the f ur.ctions of the o t':ice 11 positions and personnel so transferred shall cont inue to be qoverned ~Y p e rsonnel leqisla~ion enactej by Con~ rPss and r ul 0 s ~n AgulatLons ~rc~ulgat ursuant thc e r o unti l suc"l time as the District Governm~nt personnel system is established in accordance wi~h sec~ion 422 3) of t~e Cistric~ of Columbia Self- Go~ernment and Gov e rnmental or9ani zation Pct. Such positions and pP.rsonnel may tP. reclassified realiqned or founn in excess snd separntP.(1 fro:n the So?rv i ce in a cr:ordancP. wir~ tt'is ac~ o r an ad~inistrative order o: t~e ~irPccor 9- Powers of the Office Sec. 6. The Director of t he office shall a) systematically review and evaluate the full array of programs operated by the Dist rict of Columbia impacting on children and youth, as specified in section S(a) above b) plan and develop demonstration youth programs for transfer to other operating agencies upon their validation after no more than three years of operation c) present the interest of children and youth before other administra t ive and regulatory agencies and legislative bodies of the District of Columbia government d) assist, advise, and cooperate with local, federal, and 9rivate agencies to pro~ote the interest of children and youth in the District of Columbia e) develop criteria for the validation of programs for children and youth which shall be widely disseminated and utilized in the review and evaluation of programs f) issue an annual report on the cur rent status of programs fo r children and youth on a city-wide bas is, both governmental and private and (g) 9erform such other functions and duties consis tent wi th the purpose o f this act which may be deemed necessary and appropriat e to p r omote the welfare of children and youth I 1 ransf ~r of Positions and Funds sec 7 al 'the fol lowing posit.i ons and thei r as~ocia+-en fund in are her~by t.ransfe rea from t~e Cf~ice of Youth Opoortunit:y Si:&amp;gt;rvic'?s to t he r:epa rtment of lanpower: l eputy Director GS 15 1 Proq r 3.m Analyst Offic~r GS- 12 1 social Scienti st Analyst GS 11 1 compu ter Proc;rram 1\nal yst G3- ll l Rese3 c~ Assist:ant GS-1 1 l Resea r ch Assistant GS- 9 2 Pr ogram Analysts GS 9 1 ~esearch Assistant GS 7 2 Cl~rks (Typist) GS 4 The followinq positions an rl their assnciaten fundinq initially transfe ed in t~e Sudq t Act o f 1977 o t.h i'?Partment. of 1 an~ower are hereby r1nsferred f:-om th~ Office o f Youth Opportunit.y serv i ces to thP ~Ppar~ment of R'9creation foe the support of Ne i qhhorhuod l anninq Co rnc i l pro qr ams 1 Proqr3.m Malyst Off i cer GS- 12 1 Pr oqram Director s 11 ield cl'-nical \ s si sta n s GS 0 2 Cl ks GS u -1 1 c) T~e fun~s availatle t o the Of~ ice of Youth ~dvocacy Department of Manpower rye partment o~ Recr eation, Federal City Colleqe anrl Di strict cf Colum.cia Public Sc lools to ca~ry out t hP. purposes of this ac will te as deli nea~e~ in the "Budqet Act of 1977 11 Act 1- 94 1arch 9 i cn6) exceFt as aJ tP.red i n sections 7(a) and (b) of this ac d) Al l position s ani personnel so ~ransfpcred shall continue to be ~ovPrn@d by pers onne l leqislation enacted by Coniiress an ii rules ano reaula tions pr o:nul•ra eri ~m:suant t hereto until such time as the Di s trict of Columbia qovernment personnel system is establis hed in accordance with .sect.i on 422 (3) of t~e Cistrict of Colu:nti a Sel f- r..o v~rnment an1 Gove rnmental ~eorganization Act Such positions ann ~rsonnel may te reclassified or found in excP.ss and seo~rated fro~ t he service in acco dance with th iq act or an aimini~trative o rd e r of the Directors o r ?resident of th~ afor~mentioned agencies and de~artrnen~s i scellan~ou Provisions Sec S The ~ayor shall instruct t he Office of Budge~ and Mannoement Systems to coordinate with the CP.~a rtment of ~ecreation th~ estahlislunent of a bookkeepino a~c accoun~ino syste~ to al.low for timely allocati on o: r.onies f r o;n the Di strict of Columl:ia· govermrent o Neighborhood lannin'1 Counc il gt;r oq rarr.s an•1 shall estahlish a r.?quli3 I l 12- voucher system to facilitate the swift transfe r ence of funds f r om the District of Col umbia government to the Neighborhood Planning Councils Conflicts of I nte rest Sec. 9. The Neighborhood Planning Councils shall, with the assistance of the Department of Rec r eation, establish proc edures in thei r By- l aws and Constitution to handle conflicts of inte r est in the awar d of subg r ants to 9rograms when any Councilmember has e ither a structural or fiduciary relationship with a grant applicant or g r a nt ee. Ru les of Operation Sec 10 The Neighborhood Planning Councils shall establish under the auspices of the Director of the Department of Recreation, uniform r ules governing their operation and internal structure The se ru les shall include a statement of Neighbo rhood Planning Council responsibilities, voting procedur es the establishment of standing committees the manner of selecting chairpersons and other o fficers, proc edures f or p rompt r ev iew and action on committee r ecommendat ions and p rocedures for recei?t and action upon community recom~endations a t both the local ~eighborhood Planning Council and city-wide Council of Chairpersons levels Said rules shall be filed with the 4 13- Director of t Depart:n lt: of rtf!cre" t-ion and ubl.lshe1 ir. t~e c Reqister Budq~t Request Sec. 1i. Th~ nepartm~nt of Recreation sha ll develop an annual fiscal ye3r budqet request to administer and support proqrdrns of the Neighborhood Planning counci l s such budq~t r equests shall be suhmitt~d t o the Neiqhtor~ood Pl,nn inc council s each ye~r for t hei r review and commen The budget sba ll he submitted hy t!1~ Mayor to the Council CCOmpanied y such comment:s on such date which may b~ required to conform with· the Distric t of Col umbia Eudqet schedul e Severatility sec 1 2 If any provisi on of this act is held i nvalid the remainde= of ~his act sha ~l not be affecten Sec 13. This ac t shall become effective according to t ~e ~revis ions of sec tion 602(c) o f t~e Cis tric~ o f Colu~bi lt e l f C.iovernmen t nn l Gov~rnm~nt.al eora an iz :i ic:1 Act \ I \ Docket for the BilJ l 3_0_7 Considered in Council Ju ly 27, 1976 Fi~t Vote J_u_l_y_2_7 1_9_7_6 R E CORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCIL M C:M9ER AYE NAY I N A I COUNCIL EMBER AYE NAY N .v A ,B COUNCIL M E MBER AYE NAY TUCKER x DIXON x SPAULDING x 'MOORE, D. I x HARDY x WILSON x BARRY x HOBSON x WINTER x CLARKE x MOORE, J x COATES x SHACKLETON x X-In.dicai~ Vote A. B.-Abseru V.-Nct Voting a.w·1 00 A Final Vote in Council September 15 197 6 (Secretary oi the Council} RECORD OF C OU N C IL VOT E COUNCIL MEMBER I A YE N A Y I N V a COUNCIL M£MB£ y j l'f .V a. C OUN CIL ME BER AYE NAY TUCKER x DIXON x SPAL'IDING x UJCRE, D. x HARDY -x WIISON x BARRY x HOBSON x WINTER x CL-\RKE X· I MOORE, J x I COATES x SHACKLETON x Y.-tndka1es Vote A. B.-A.bsent N V.-Nct Voting ~QWJ.Uu1~/J (Secretary of the Council) Or:T 19i5 Presented to the Mayor w Secretary of the Council} I HEREBY CERTIFY THAT Council Bill No 1-307 was presented t o the Mayor o f the District of Columbia on Oct o ber 5, 1976, and t hat the Mayor neither approved nor disapproved the Bill wi t hi n the t en-day period specifi ed in Sec tion 404( e of the Di s tr i ct of Col~~bia Self- Government and Governme ntal Reorg anization Act (Public Law 93- 98) of December 24, 1973 v a c fi4 d-ei~ Date: 2 0 r! C 1976 K Schaller Executive Secretary, Di s t rict of Columbia H .V A .a N ,V \ Reconsidered by Council Bill Docket Bill No. 1-307 Page Two RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCii. ME:MBCR AYE NAY f'j ,V, A.8 COUNCIL. ME:Mllltfl AYI NAY TUCKER DIXON MOORE, D. HARDY BARRY HOBSON CIARKE MJORE, J. COATES SHAClCT.ETON X-tndleat" Vole A. B.-A.bst:nt Presented to the President Sustain Mayor's Veto Not Sustain Mayor's Veto t Submitted to the Congress Senate Action Resolution Number Secretary of the Senate} Enacted without Congressional action Secretary of the Council) N ,V. A.B. CO UNCii. MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. SPAULDING WIISON WINTER N. V Not Voting (Secretary of the Council) {Secretary of the Councill (President of the U.S Secretary of the Council) House Action Resolution Number Clerk of the Housel </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1501"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1502"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1503"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1503.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1504"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1505"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1506"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1507"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1508"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1509"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1510"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>12</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1511"/>
  </section>
</document>
