<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
    <prefix>§</prefix>
    <num>1-1163.32d(Perm)</num>
    <heading>Base amount payments.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Within 5 days after a participating candidate is certified under <u>§ 1-1163.32c(b)</u>, the Director of Campaign Finance shall direct the Office of the Chief Financial Officer to disburse to the participating candidate half of the base amount described in paragraph (2) of this subsection. The Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall disburse the funds within 5 business days after receiving direction to do so from the Director of Campaign Finance.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Within 5 days after the participating candidate qualifies for the ballot, the Director of Campaign Finance shall direct the Office of the Chief Financial Officer to disburse to the participating candidate the other half of the base amount described in paragraph (2) of this subsection. The Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall disburse the funds within 5 business days after receiving direction to do so from the Director of Campaign Finance.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The base amount shall be:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>$160,000 for the office of Mayor;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>$40,000 for the office of Attorney General;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>$40,000 for the office of Chairman of the Council;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>$40,000 for the office of Councilmember elected at-large and from a ward; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>$10,000 for the office of State Board of Education elected at-large and from a ward.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>In an uncontested election, the participating candidate shall:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Not receive the base amount described in subsection (a) of this section, except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Be eligible to receive matching payments for qualified small-dollar contributions pursuant to <u>§ 1-1163.32e</u>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>If an uncontested election becomes a contested election after a participating candidate is certified under <u>§ 1-1163.32c(b)</u>, the Director of Campaign Finance shall direct, no later than 5 days after the uncontested election becomes a contested election, the Office of the Chief Financial Officer to disburse to the participating candidate, and the Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall disburse, within 5 business days after receiving direction to do so from the Director of Campaign Finance:</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>If a contested election becomes an uncontested election after the participating candidate has received the first, but not the second, half of the base amount, the participating candidate may retain any unspent base amount funds to repay:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Any authorized expenditures or the proper debts that were incurred in connection with the participating candidate's campaign; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Personal funds of the participating candidate or the participating candidate's immediate family contributed under <u>§ 1-1163.32f(a)(6)</u>.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>If a contested election becomes an uncontested election, a participating candidate who has not yet qualified for the ballot shall not receive the second half of the base amount upon ballot qualification.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Funds shall be distributed to participating candidates under this section through the use of an electronic funds transfer or a debit card.</text>
    </para>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History" path="§332d">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 332d</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-94" type="History" path="§2|(b)|(5)">as added May 5, 2018, D.C. Law 22-94, § 2(b)(5), 65 DCR 2847</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" type="History" path="§1042|(k)">Sept. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 23-16, § 1042(k), 66 DCR 8621</annotation>
  </section>

