<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-325.351(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Housing Preservation Fund.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-325.351">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Housing Preservation Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Department of Housing and Community Development in accordance with subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In Fiscal Year 2018, $10 million from local appropriations shall be deposited into the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to provide debt or equity to finance housing preservation activities, including acquisition bridge loans, predevelopment expenses, environmental remediation, critical repairs, and other activities necessary to preserve the affordability of housing units; provided, that for any property benefited by an expenditure of funds pursuant to this subsection, a covenant shall be recorded with respect to affordability, the terms and conditions of which shall be determined by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In Fiscal Year 2025, $2.5 million of the Fund shall be used to support existing projects with outstanding Fund loans.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Recipients of funds under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not be required to provide matching funds.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall not be used to provide debt or equity to finance housing preservation activities involving any property identified in <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-223" path="§2|(a)">section 2(a) of the Historic Preservation of Derelict District Properties Act of 2016, effective March 11, 2017 (D.C. Law 21-223; 64 DCR 182)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" type="History" path="§2032">Dec. 13, 2017, D.C. Law 22-33, §  2032, 64 DCR 7652</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§2122">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, §  2122, 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
