<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-350.04(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Delinquent Debt Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established within the General Fund of the District of Columbia a special fund known as the Delinquent Debt Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Central Collection Unit in accordance with subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Revenue from the following sources shall be deposited in the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Funds allocated to the Central Collection Unit through the District's annual Budget and Financial Plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All delinquent debts collected by the Central Collection Unit, except those amounts described in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-350.02|(a-1)">section 1043(a-1)</code-cite> and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-350.02|(a-2)">(a-2)</cite>, and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-350.02|(a-3)">(a-3)</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All fees authorized by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-350.03">section 1044</code-cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to conduct the authorized activities of the Central Collection Unit.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>After all operational and administrative expenses of the Central Collection Unit have been paid, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer in the year-end close, the lesser of $2.5 million or the remaining cash balance in the Fund, in excess of the amount certified as local funds in the most recent revenue estimate of the Chief Financial Officer, shall be transferred from the Fund to the Arts and Humanities Enterprise Fund, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-205.01">section 6a of the Commission on the Arts and Humanities Act, effective October 21, 1975 (D.C. Law 1-22; D.C. Official Code § 39-205.01)</code-cite>; provided, that any cash balance remaining in the Fund after the transfer to the Arts and Humanities Enterprise Fund shall revert to the unrestricted balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History" path="§1045">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 1045, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 7032(c), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, § 7132, 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" type="History">Sept. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 23-16, §§ 2203(a), 4012(b), 66 DCR 8621</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 7031 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle C of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Delinquent Debt Recovery Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7032(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7032(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added “except those amounts collected by the Central Collection Unit described in <cite path="§1-350.02|(a-1)">§ 1-350.02(a-1)</cite> and (a-2)” in the second sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-350.01">§ 1-350.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
