<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-515.01(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="1|5|I-A">this title</code-cite>:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The definitions set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-603.01">section 301 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-603.01)</code-cite>, shall apply.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"District government" means the government of the District of Columbia, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any department, agency, or instrumentality of the government of the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any independent agency of the District established under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="1|2|IV|F">part F of title IV of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 811; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.91 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any agency, board, or commission established by the Mayor or the Council and any other agency, public authority, or public benefit corporation which has the authority to receive monies directly or indirectly from the District (other than monies received from the sale of goods, the provision of services, or the loaning of funds to the District); and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The Council.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Highly compensated appointee" means an individual appointed to a position in the Career, Educational, or Management Supervisory Service, except for individuals appointed to a position as an employee of the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia, for which the starting annual salary is not less than $150,000 or the threshold figure established by the relevant personnel authority pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-515.03|(c)">section 103(c)</code-cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-108" type="History" path="§101">Feb. 6, 2008, D.C. Law 17-108, § 101</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-315" type="History" path="§2">as added May 23, 2019, D.C. Law 22-315, § 2, 66 DCR 1983</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
