<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-611.08(Perm)</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Compensation — Members of boards and commissions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each member of any board or commission who receives compensation or reimbursement of expenses on January 1, 1980, shall receive such rates of compensation or reimbursement of expenses as are provided in existing law, rule, regulation, or order, or in this chapter, except as may be modified from time to time by rules and regulations published pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, members of boards and commissions shall not be compensated for time expended in the performance of official duties except as authorized by subsections (b), (c), (c-1), (c-2), and (c-3) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to establish by rule and regulation the standards for, and rates of, compensation or reimbursement of expenses for members of any board or commission, including any board or commission established after January 1, 1980. Any such rules and regulations proposed by the Mayor shall be transmitted to the Council of the District of Columbia for a 30-day (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days on which the Council of the District of Columbia is on recess) review period. Such rules and regulations shall become effective only if the Council of the District of Columbia does not adopt, within 30 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days on which the Council of the District of Columbia is on recess) from the date of the Mayor's submission, a resolution disapproving such rules and regulations in whole or in part. Notwithstanding the provisions of § 1-604.05, rules and regulations published under this subsection shall be effective no earlier than 30 days after their publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Members of the following boards and commissions shall be entitled to compensation in the form of a salary as currently authorized by law:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Public Service Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Contract Appeals Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Rental Housing Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Board of Ethics and Government Accountability; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Full-time members of the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <text>Members of the following boards and commissions shall be entitled to compensation in the form of an hourly rate of pay as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Board of Zoning Adjustment members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $12,000 for each board member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Office of Employee Appeals members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $6,000 for each member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Retirement Board Members shall be entitled to compensation as provided in § 1-711(c);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Police and Firefighters Retirement and Relief Board members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $8,000 for each board member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Public Employee Relations Board members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $6,000 for each board member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Zoning Commission members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $12,000 for each commission member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Historic Preservation Review Board members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $3,000 for each board member per year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Alcoholic Beverage and Cannabis Board members shall be entitled to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Compensation at the hourly rate of $50 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings, not to exceed $18,000 for each member per year; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A stipend of $250 per week for each member for their service on the board, except for the Chairperson, who shall be entitled to a stipend of $350 per week;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Part-time members of the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $50 for time spent in performance of duties at meetings; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Board of Elections members shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $40 while actually in the service of the board, not to exceed the $12,500 for each member per year and $26,500 for the Chairperson per year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-2)</num>
    <text>Members of the following boards and commissions shall be entitled to compensation in the form of stipend as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each Commissioner, other than the ex officio Commissioner and the Chairperson, of the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia Housing Authority shall be entitled to a stipend of $4,000 per year for their service on the board; the Chairperson shall be entitled to a stipend of $6,000 per year. Each Commissioner also shall be entitled to reimbursement of actual travel and other expenses reasonably related to attendance at board meetings and fulfillment of official duties. Stipends and reimbursements shall be made at least quarterly; provided, that all stipends shall be paid from non-District funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each member of the Higher Education Licensure Commission shall be entitled to a stipend of $8,000 per year for their service on the commission. Each member also shall be entitled to reimbursement of actual travel and other expenses reasonably related to the performance of the duties of the commission while away from their homes or regular places of business;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Community representatives of the For-Hire Vehicle Advisory Council shall be entitled to compensation of $50 per meeting, up to a maximum of $1,350 per member per annum;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Each member of the Interagency Council on Homelessness ("Council") appointed pursuant to § 4-752.01(b)(5) may receive compensation in the form of a stipend of not more than $50 per meeting of the Council, meeting of a committee of the Council, or meeting of a formal working group of the Council, in accordance with standards the Mayor may establish by rulemaking;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Each member of an advisory panel appointed pursuant to § 39-204(6) may receive compensation from the Commission in the form of a stipend of up to $250 for each day the panel convenes to review applications[;]</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Each member of the Concealed Pistol Licensing Review Board, except members who are District or federal government employees, shall be entitled to a stipend of $250 per week for their service on the board[; and]</text>
    </para>
    <aftertext proof="needed"><strong>[(8)]</strong> Each member of the Food Policy Council ("FPC") appointed pursuant to § 48-313, may receive compensation in the form of a stipend of not more than $100 per meeting of the FPC or meeting of a formal working group of the FPC, in accordance with standards the Mayor may establish by rulemaking.</aftertext>
    <aftertext proof="needed"><strong>[(9)]</strong> Not Funded.</aftertext>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-3)</num>
    <text>Chairpersons of the boards and commissions specified in subsections (c-1) and (c-2) of this section who are public members shall be entitled to an additional compensation of 20% above the annual maximum.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Members of boards and commissions shall not be entitled to reimbursement for expenses unless specifically authorized by law; except, that transportation, parking, or mileage expenses incurred in the performance of official duties may be reimbursed, not to exceed $15 per meeting or currently authorized amounts, whichever is less.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall conduct a comprehensive study of the compensation and stipend levels of the District's boards and commissions, recognizing the different characteristics of these entities, and examining the best practices in the compensation and stipend policies of surrounding and comparable jurisdictions. Based on this study, the Mayor shall provide a report to the Council by December 31, 2002, with recommendations for a rational compensation and stipend policy applicable to boards and commissions, including any recommendations for changes in specific compensation and stipend levels that could be addressed in the FY 2004 budget and financial plan.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§1108">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1108, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-81" type="History">Aug. 7, 1980, D.C. Law 3-81, § 2(k), 27 DCR 2632</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 801(b), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-60" type="History">Mar. 20, 1998, D.C. Law 12-60, § 101, 44 DCR 7378</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 106-113" type="History">Nov. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 1515, Pub. L. 106-113, § 119(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-38" type="History">Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-38,§ 302, 46 DCR 6373</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 201, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, §§ 2403, 2502, 2603, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 102(b), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1212, 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 5(b), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91" type="History">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, § 120(b), 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-159" type="History">Sept. 19, 2006, D.C. Law 16-159, § 3, 53 DCR 5385</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-361" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-361, § 3, 56 DCR 1204</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-363" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-363, § 3(b), 58 DCR 963</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 1132, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-198" type="History">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-198, § 2(b), 61 DCR 12450</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-271" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-271, § 241, 62 DCR 1884</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 2202, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-74" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-74, § 3, 63 DCR 252</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-124" type="History">June 22, D.C. Law 21-124, § 501(b), 63 DCR 7076</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" type="History">Dec. 13, 2017, D.C. Law 22-33, §§ 1032, 1052, 64 DCR 7652</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, § 1082(e), 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-224" type="History">Feb. 22, 2019, D.C. Law 22-224, § 3, 66 DCR 187</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-250" type="History">Mar. 13, 2019, D.C. Law 22-250, § 4(d), 66 DCR 985</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" type="History">Sept. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 23-16, § 5012, 66 DCR 8621</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-51" type="History">Feb. 21, 2020, D.C. Law 23-51, § 3, 67 DCR 13</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§1102">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 1102, 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" type="History" path="§1102">Nov. 13, 2021, D.C. Law 24-45, §§ 2003, 3022, 68 DCR 010163</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History" path="§1102">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 2093, 69 DCR 009223</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-238" type="History" path="§1102">Apr. 21, 2023, D.C. Law 24-348, § 4(d), 70 DCR 937</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" type="History" path="§1102">Sept. 6, 2023, D.C. Law 25-50, § 6002, 70 DCR 10366</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
