<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1052(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Establishment of working group and public restroom facility pilot.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1052">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 45 days after October 1, 2019, the Mayor shall solicit recommendations from BID corporations, as that term is defined in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1215.02|(4)">§ 2-1215.02(4)</cite>, Clean Team grantees, as that term is used in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-602.01">§ 9-602.01</cite>, and Advisory Neighborhood Commissions ("ANCs") on locations in the District that are in need of a public restroom facility.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 180 days after October 1, 2019, the Mayor shall transmit to the Council, the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority ("DC Water"), the District Department of Transportation ("DDOT"), the Department of General Services ("DGS"), the Department of Human Services ("DHS"), the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development ("DMPED"), the Metropolitan Police Department ("MPD"), the Department of Public Works ("DPW"), the Department of Health ("DOH"), and the Department of Parks and Recreation ("DPR") a report that includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A list of sites in the District where, during the preceding fiscal year, the Mayor received 10 or more reports of human urine or feces, resulting in the dispatch of staff to the area; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A summary of the recommendations provided under subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 30 days after the transmittal of the report required by subsection (b) of this section, the Mayor shall establish a working group to assess the need for public restroom facilities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The working group shall be composed of the following individuals:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Director of each of the following District agencies, or the Director's designee:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>DC Water;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>DDOT;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>DGS;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>DHS;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>DMPED;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>DPR;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>MPD;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(viii)</num>
          <text>DOH; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ix)</num>
          <text>DPW; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Five members, appointed by the Mayor, as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Two representatives from nonprofits incorporated in the District with a focus on issues affecting individuals experiencing homelessness;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>One representative from a nonprofit incorporated in the District with a focus on issues affecting seniors;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>One representative from a nonprofit incorporated in the District with a focus on public health; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>One individual with expertise in urban planning.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Within 30 days after the establishment of the working group, the working group shall hold its first meeting. Thereafter, the working group shall meet monthly until the date that the working group transmits its recommendations to the Council and the Mayor under paragraph (4) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Within 150 days after the working group's first meeting, the working group shall transmit recommendations to the Council and the Mayor, which shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The number and type of public restroom facilities that would best serve the District's needs; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Two sites in the District that the working group recommends as pilot locations for the installation of public restroom facilities.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The working group shall consider the following criteria when recommending the 2 sites under paragraph (4)(B) of this subsection:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Whether the site was identified in the report compiled pursuant to subsection (b) of this section;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Pedestrian traffic in the site's surrounding area;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The cost of installing, maintaining, policing, and repairing the public restroom facility;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The effect that the installation of a public restroom facility at the site would have on nearby residential and commercial spaces;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Proximity of the site to services for the homeless;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Increased availability of restrooms available to the public as a result of the Community Restroom Incentive Pilot Program established under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1053">§ 10-1053</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>The availability of existing restrooms available to the public near the site;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Input from ANCs, BIDs, or other similar community organizations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>The ability of individuals experiencing homelessness to access the site;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Proximity of the site to MPD facilities or personnel; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>The potential use of the site for criminal or nuisance activities.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Within 30 days after receipt of the working group's recommendations, the Mayor shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Publish online the working group's recommendations and information on how members of the public may submit comments regarding the installation of a public restroom facility at the sites recommended by the working group;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Transmit the working group's recommendations to the ANCs in which the sites recommended under subsection (c)(4)(B) of this section are located and solicit a resolution from those ANCs in favor of, or in opposition to, installing a public restroom facility at the sites; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Post conspicuous signs nearby the sites recommended for a public restroom facility under subsection (c)(4)(B) of this section, which shall include:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Notice of the working group's recommendation to install a public restroom facility at the site;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Directions on how to access a digital copy of the working group's recommendations; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Information on how members of the public may submit comments regarding the installation of a public restroom facility at the site.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Not Funded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Not Funded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Not Funded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Not Funded.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-280" type="History" path="§3">Apr. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 22-280, § 3, 66 DCR 1595</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
