<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1382(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Office of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Questioning Affairs; Advisory Committee.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevent) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1382">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established within the Executive Office of the Mayor, the Office of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Questioning Affairs (“Office”). The Office shall administer such programs as shall be delegated to it by the Mayor and the Council to promote the welfare of the lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and questioning community.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish an Advisory Committee, consisting of not more than 25 public members, whose members shall be representative of the diversity of people and ideas within the lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and questioning community. The Advisory Committee shall include, at a minimum, representation from the lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and questioning community organizations representing health, social service, religious, and human rights issues and its members shall be representative of the diversity in the community with regard to socioeconomic status, religion, race, ethnicity, gender identification, age, and families. The Advisory Committee shall advise the Director and the Mayor on issues relating to the lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and questioning community and on issues relating to the mission of the Office.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-89" type="History" path="§3">Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-89, § 3, 53 DCR 1084</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 1022(b), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1022(b) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “Office of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Questioning Affairs” for “Office of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Affairs” throughout the section; and substituted “lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and questioning community” for “gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender community” throughout the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§2-1381">§ 2-1381</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
