<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">

    <num>2-534(Perm)</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Exemptions from disclosure.</heading>
    <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current. To see the current law, click this link <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-534">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The following matters may be exempt from disclosure under the provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|II">this subchapter</cite>:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Trade secrets and commercial or financial information obtained from outside the government, to the extent that disclosure would result in substantial harm to the competitive position of the person from whom the information was obtained;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Information of a personal nature where the public disclosure thereof would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2A)</num>
        <text>Any body-worn camera recordings recorded by the Metropolitan Police Department:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Inside a personal residence; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Related to an incident involving domestic violence as defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-551|(1)">§ 4-551(1)</code-cite>, stalking as defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-3133">§ 22-3133</code-cite>, or sexual assault as defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§23-1907|(a)|(7)">§ 23-1907(a)(7)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Investigatory records compiled for law-enforcement purposes, including the records of Council investigations and investigations conducted by the Office of Police Complaints, but only to the extent that the production of such records would:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Interfere with:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Enforcement proceedings;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Council investigations; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Office of Police Complaints ongoing investigations;</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Deprive a person of a right to a fair trial or an impartial adjudication;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>Disclose the identity of a confidential source and, in the case of a record compiled by a law-enforcement authority in the course of a criminal investigation, or by an agency conducting a lawful national security intelligence investigation, confidential information furnished only by the confidential source;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>Disclose investigative techniques and procedures not generally known outside the government; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(F)</num>
          <text>Endanger the life or physical safety of law-enforcement personnel;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Inter-agency or intra-agency memorandums or letters, including memorandums or letters generated or received by the staff or members of the Council, which would not be available by law to a party other than a public body in litigation with the public body.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Test questions and answers to be used in future license, employment, or academic examinations, but not previously administered examinations or answers to questions thereon;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>Information specifically exempted from disclosure by statute (other than this section), provided that such statute:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Requires that the matters be withheld from the public in such a manner as to leave no discretion on the issue; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Establishes particular criteria for withholding or refers to particular types of matters to be withheld;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>Information specifically authorized by federal law under criteria established by a presidential executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy which is in fact properly classified pursuant to such executive order;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(8)</num>
        <text>Information exempted from disclosure by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-4505">§ 28-4505</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(9)</num>
        <text>Information disclosed pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-417">§ 5-417</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(10)</num>
        <text>Any specific response plan, including any District of Columbia response plan, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2301|(1)">§ 7-2301(1)</code-cite>, and any specific vulnerability assessment, either of which is intended to prevent or to mitigate an act of terrorism, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-3152|(1)">§ 22-3152(1)</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(11)</num>
        <text>Information exempt from disclosure by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2851.06">§ 47-2851.06</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(12)</num>
        <text>Information, the disclosure of which would reveal the name of an employee providing information under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="1|6|XV-A">subchapter XV-A of Chapter 6 of Title 1 [§ 1-615.51 et seq.]</code-cite> and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2|XII">subchapter XII of Chapter 2 of this title [2-233.01 et seq.]</code-cite>, unless the name of the employee is already known to the public;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(13)</num>
        <text>Information exempt from disclosure by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2271.04">§ 7-2271.04</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(14)</num>
        <text>Information that is ordered sealed and restricted from public access pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="16|8">Chapter 8 of Title 16</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(15)</num>
        <text>Any critical infrastructure information or plans that contain critical infrastructure information for the critical infrastructures of companies that are regulated by the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(16)</num>
        <text>Information exempt from disclosure pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2615">§ 38-2615</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(17)</num>
        <text>Information exempt from disclosure pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-301.29a|(13)|(C)|(i)">§ 50-301.29a(13)(C)(i)</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(18)</num>
        <text>Information exempt from disclosure pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-481.07|(a)">§ 24-481.07(a)</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(19)</num>
        <text>Information exempt from disclosure under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="41|1A|XIV">subchapter XIV of Chapter 1A of Title 41</code-cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(20)</num>
        <text> Information withheld from disclosure under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-551.07e|(e)|(2)">section 1028e(e)(2) of the Department of General Services Establishment Act of 2011, effective September 21, 2022 (D.C. Law 24-167; D.C. Official Code § 10-551.07e(e)(2))</code-cite>; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(a-1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Council may assert, on behalf of any public body from which it obtains records or information, any exemption listed in subsection (a) of this section that could be asserted by the public body pertaining to the records or information.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Disclosure of any public record, document, or information from a District of Columbia government agency, official, or employee to the following persons or entities shall not constitute a waiver of any privilege or exemption that otherwise could be asserted by the District of Columbia to prevent disclosure to the general public or in a judicial or administrative proceeding:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>The Council;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>A Council committee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>A member of the Council acting in an official capacity;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>The District of Columbia Auditor;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>An employee of the Office of the District of Columbia Auditor; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(F)</num>
          <text>The Ombudsperson for Children or an employee of the Office of the Ombudsperson for Children.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num >(b)</num>
      <text>Any reasonably segregable portion of a public record shall be provided to any person requesting the record after deletion of those portions which may be withheld from disclosure pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. In each case, the justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing, and the extent of the deletion shall be indicated on the portion of the record which is made available or published, unless including that indication would harm an interest protected by the exemption in subsection (a) of this section under which the deletion is made. If technically feasible, the extent of the deletion and the specific exemptions shall be indicated at the place in the record where the deletion was made.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>This section does not authorize withholding of information or limit the availability of records to the public, except as specifically stated in this section. This section is not authority to withhold information from the Council of the District of Columbia. This section shall not operate to permit nondisclosure of information of which disclosure is authorized or mandated by other law.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c-1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no document or information described in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-536|(a)|(6A)">§ 2-536(a)(6A)</code-cite> that was created on or after December 7, 2004, shall be exempt from disclosure pursuant to subsections (a)(4) and (e) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text><strong>[(1)]</strong> The provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|II">this subchapter</cite> shall not apply to vital records covered by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="7|2">Chapter 2 of Title 7</code-cite> or <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="7|2A">Chapter 2A of Title 7</code-cite>.</text>
      <text><strong>[(2)]</strong> The provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|II">this subchapter</cite> shall not apply to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Violence Fatality Review Committee, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1431.01">§ 5-1431.01</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Child Fatality Review Committee, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1371.03">§ 4-1371.03</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The Maternal Mortality Review Committee, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-671.02">§ 7-671.02</code-cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The Domestic Violence Fatality Review Board, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§16-1052">§ 16-1052</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d-1)</num>
      <text>Not Funded.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d-2)</num>
      <text>Not Funded.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>All exemptions available under this section shall apply to the Council as well as agencies of the District government. The deliberative process privilege, the attorney work-product privilege, and the attorney-client privilege are incorporated under the inter-agency memoranda exemption listed in subsection (a)(4) of this section, and these privileges, among other privileges that may be found by the court, shall extend to any public body that is subject to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|II">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-614" type="History" path="§204">Oct. 21, 1968, Pub. L. 90-614, title II, § 204</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-96" type="History">as added Mar. 29, 1977, D.C. Law 1-96, § 2, 23 DCR 3744</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-169" type="History">Mar. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 3-169, § 3(c), 27 DCR 5368</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-34" type="History">Oct. 8, 1981, D.C. Law 4-34, § 29(i), 28 DCR 3271</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-119" type="History">June 19, 1982, D.C. Law 4-119, § 2(f), 29 DCR 1952</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-283" type="History">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-283, § 3(d), 48 DCR 1917</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-194" type="History">Oct. 17, 2002, D.C. Law 14-194, § 302, 49 DCR 5306</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38" type="History">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 3(b), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-256" type="History">Mar. 17, 2005, D.C. Law 15-256, § 2(b), 52 DCR 1158</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 83(a), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91" type="History">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, § 132(b), 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-152" type="History">Sept. 19, 2006, D.C. Law 16-152, § 2, 53 DCR 5371</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-262" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-262, § 231, 54 DCR 794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-307" type="History">May 5, 2007, D.C. Law 16-307, § 3(a), 54 DCR 868</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-176" type="History">June 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-176, § 5, 55 DCR 5390</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353,§ 174, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-119" type="History">Mar. 11, 2010, D.C. Law 18-119, § 3, 57 DCR 906</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-160" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-160, § 2(a), 61 DCR 10735</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 4063, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-83" type="History">Mar. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-83, § 2(b), 63 DCR 774</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-118" type="History">July 3, 2018, D.C. Law 22-118, § 201, 65 DCR 5064</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-164" type="History">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-164, § 201, 65 DCR 9324</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, §§ 3053, 6143, 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-197" type="History">Dec. 13, 2018, D.C. Law 22-197, § 222, 65 DCR 9554</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-270" type="History">Apr. 5, 2021, D.C. Law 23-270, § 207, 68 DCR 1510</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" type="History">Nov. 13, 2021, D.C. Law 24-45, § 7094(b), 68 DCR 10163</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-147" type="History">July 12, 2022, D.C. Law 24-147, §§ 154(c), 161(b), 69 DCR 3386</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 1042(a), 69 DCR 9223</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-345" type="History">Apr. 21, 2023, D.C. Law 24-345, § 134, 70 DCR 953</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§1033" type="History">Sept. 6, 2023, D.C. Law 25-50, § 1033, 70 DCR 10366</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-175" path="§5" type="History">June 8, 2024, D.C. Law 25-175, § 5, 71 DCR 2732</annotation>
  </section>


  
