<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-4234(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Duties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Criminal Justice Coordinating Council shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Make recommendations concerning the coordination of the activities and the mobilization of the resources of the member agencies in improving public safety in, and the criminal justice system of, the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Cooperate with and support the member agencies in carrying out the purposes of the CJCC;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Define and analyze issues and procedures in the criminal justice system, identify alternative solutions, and make recommendations for improvements and changes in the programs of the criminal justice system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Receive information from, and give assistance to, other District of Columbia agencies concerned with, or affected by, issues of public safety and the criminal justice system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Make recommendations regarding systematic operational and infrastructural matters as are believed necessary to improve public safety in District of Columbia and federal criminal justice agencies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Advise and work collaboratively with the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice, Justice Grants Administration in developing justice planning documents and allocating grant funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Select ex-officio members to participate in Criminal Justice Coordinating Council planning sessions and subcommittees as necessary to meet the organization’s goals;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Establish measurable goals and objectives for reform initiatives; and</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The CJCC shall also report, on an annual basis, on the status and progress of the goals and objectives referenced in subsection (a)(8) of this section, including any recommendations made by the CJCC and its subcommittees to the membership of the CJCC, the public, the Mayor, and the Council. The report shall be submitted to the Mayor and the Council within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year and shall be the subject of a public hearing before the Council during the annual budget process. The CJCC’s budget and future funding requests shall also be the subject of a hearing before the Council during the annual budget process.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>The CJCC shall also conduct a public opinion survey of police-community relations in the District of Columbia and submit an analysis of the results in a report to the Mayor and the Council by January 31, 2017.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-2)</num>
    <text>By October 1, 2018, and every 2 years thereafter, the CJCC shall conduct a voluntary survey of individuals under 21 years of age currently committed to the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services or incarcerated at the Department of Corrections on their perspective on the causes of youth crime and the prevalence of adverse childhood experiences, such as housing instability, childhood abuse, family instability, substance abuse, mental illness, family criminal involvement, or other factors deemed relevant by the CJCC.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-3)</num>
    <text>On October 1, 2018, and every 2 years thereafter, the CJCC shall submit a report to the Mayor and the Council containing an analysis of the root causes of youth crime and the prevalence of adverse childhood experiences among justice-involved youth, such as housing instability, childhood abuse, family instability, substance abuse, mental illness, family criminal involvement, or other factors deemed relevant by the CJCC that incorporates the results of the survey conducted pursuant to subsection (b-2) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The CJCC is designated as a criminal justice agency for purposes of transmitting electronically to local, state, and federal agencies criminal-justice-related information, as required by CJCC to perform the duties specified under this section and in accordance with the terms and conditions regarding data sharing approved by the agency that is the source of the information for transmission.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History" path="§1505">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 1505, 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 3072, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-125" path="§204" type="History">June 30, 2016, D.C. Law 21-125, § 204, 63 DCR 4659</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-238" path="§304" type="History">Apr. 4, 2017, D.C. Law 21-238, § 304, 63 DCR 15312</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 3071 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle H of Title III of the act may be cited as the “Criminal Justice Coordinating Council Criminal Justice Designation Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3072 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3072 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 1405 of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added (c).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
