<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>23-1912(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Limitations on law enforcement actions against sexual assault victims seeking medical treatment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A sexual assault victim, when the sexual assault victim is seeking emergency medical treatment or medical forensic care related to a sexual assault, or a victim, as that term is defined in § <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§23-1904a|(a)|(4)">23-1904a(a)(4)</cite>, when the victim is seeking emergency medical treatment or medical forensic care at a hospital related to an intentionally inflicted gunshot or stab wound, shall not be subject to a custodial arrest by a law enforcement officer unless a warrant for the sexual assault victim's arrest or the victim's arrest has been issued by a competent court of jurisdiction for the commission of a:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Dangerous crime, as that term is defined in § <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§23-1331|(3)">23-1331(3)</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Crime of violence, as that term is defined in § <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§23-1331|(4)">23-1331(4)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A law enforcement officer who is prohibited from making a custodial arrest under subsection (a) of this section may issue a field arrest form to the sexual assault victim or victim in lieu of making a custodial arrest; provided, that the issuance of a field arrest form does not at that time pose health or safety risks to the sexual assault victim or victim.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-341" type="History">Apr. 6, 2023, D.C. Law 24-341, § 110(d), 69 DCR 14698</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
