<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-481.05(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Eligibility for a clemency recommendation.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-481.05">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All individuals convicted of violating District laws or regulations shall be eligible to apply for a clemency recommendation from the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No application for a clemency recommendation shall be filed pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="24|4A">this chapter</cite> if other forms of judicial or administrative relief are available based on existing law and already-discovered evidence.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The application criteria developed by the Board, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-481.03|(b)|(1)">§ 24-481.03(b)(1)</cite>, for applicants seeking a pardon shall require the applicant to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Before applying, wait 5 years after the date of the release of the applicant from confinement or, in case no prison sentence was imposed, wait 5 years after the date of the conviction of the applicant;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Not have been convicted of any other criminal offense that is relevant to the conviction for which the applicant seeks clemency, as determined by the Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Not be subject to any pending criminal charge that is relevant to the conviction for which the applicant seeks clemency, as determined by the Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Not be a party to a past or pending civil case that is relevant to the conviction for which the applicant seeks clemency, as determined by the Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Except for cases of actual innocence, demonstrate that the applicant has been rehabilitated; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Describe how the receipt of a pardon would help the applicant achieve the applicant's goals and contribute to the community.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The application criteria developed by the Board, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-481.03|(b)|(1)">§ 24-481.03(b)(1)</cite>, for applicants seeking a commutation shall require the applicant to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except for cases of actual innocence, demonstrate that the applicant has been rehabilitated; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Describe how commutation would help the applicant achieve the applicant's goals and contribute to the community.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An applicant shall be given special consideration if the sentencing scheme, including a mandatory-minimum sentence, for the offense for which the applicant was convicted was changed to provide for less severe penalties after the applicant was convicted under the sentencing scheme.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-197" type="History" path="§205">Dec. 13, 2018, D.C. Law 22-197, § 205, 65 DCR 9554</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-344" type="History" path="§23|(d)">Apr. 21, 2023, D.C. Law 24-344, § 23(d), 70 DCR 635</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
