<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>[25-113.01](Perm)</num>
  <heading>License endorsements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All license endorsements shall be placed on the applicant's license.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The licensee under a manufacturer's license, class A, B, or C, holding an on-site sales and consumption permit or a retailer's license, class C/R, D/R, C/H, D/H, C/T, D/T, C/B, and D/B, shall obtain an entertainment endorsement from the Board to be eligible to have entertainment, a cover charge, or offer facilities for dancing.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The licensee under a manufacturer's license, class A, B, or C, holding an on-site sales and consumption permit shall only provide entertainment between the hours of 8:00 a.m. and 12:00 a.m., 7 days a week.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The licensee under a manufacturer's license class A, B, or C holding an on-site sales and consumption permit or an on-premises license, class C/R, D/R, C/H, D/H, C/T, D/T, C/N, D/N, C/X, D/X, C/B, and D/B, shall obtain a sidewalk café endorsement or summer garden endorsement from the Board to be eligible to conduct business operations on a sidewalk café or summer garden, which may include the sale, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages on outdoor public or private space. The licensee under a manufacturer's license class A, B, or C holding an on-site sales and consumption permit may be authorized to conduct business operations on a sidewalk cafe or summer garden only between the hours of 8:00 a.m. and 12:00 a.m., 7 days a week.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The license under an on-premises retailer's license, class C/R, D/R, C/H, D/H, C/T, D/T, C/N, D/N, D/X, C/X and class Arena C/X or a manufacturer's license class A or B holding an on-sites sales and consumption permit, shall obtain a sports wagering endorsement from the Board to be eligible to offer sports wagering.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num codify:value="[(e)]">(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Effective April 1, 2021, a licensee under an on-premises retailer's license, class C/R, D/R, C/T, D/T, C/H, D/H, C/N, D/N, C/X, or D/X, including a multipurpose facility or private club, shall obtain a carry out and delivery endorsement from the Board to be eligible to sell beer, wine, or spirits in closed containers to individuals for carry out, or deliver beer, wine, or spirits in closed containers to consumers in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Carry out sales and delivery shall be authorized under paragraph (1) of this subsection only between the hours of 6:00 a.m. and 1:00 a.m., 7 days a week.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each carry out or delivery order of an alcoholic beverage pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be accompanied by one or more prepared food items.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The annual fee for a carry out and delivery endorsement shall be established by the Board in an amount not less than $200.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>An on-premises retailer licensee that has registered with the Board under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-113|(a)|(3)|(C)">§ 25-113(a)(3)(C)</cite> before April 1, 2021 ("registered licensee"), shall not be required to apply with the Board for an endorsement under this subsection, and the registered licensee shall be granted the carry out and delivery endorsement upon request to the Board, if the registered licensee makes the request and pays the annual fee required by paragraph (4) of this subsection by March 31, 2021.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num codify:value="[(f)]">(g)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Effective April 1, 2021, a Convention Center food and alcohol business that has registered with the Board under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-112|(h)">§ 25-112(h)</code-cite>, shall obtain a carry out and delivery license from the Board to be eligible to sell beer, wine, or spirits in closed containers to individuals for carry out, or deliver beer, wine, or spirits in closed containers to consumers in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Carry out sales and delivery shall be authorized under paragraph (1) of this subsection only between the hours of 6:00 a.m. and 1:00 a.m., 7 days a week.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each carry out or delivery order of an alcoholic beverage pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be accompanied by one or more prepared food items.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The annual fee for a carry out and delivery license shall be established by the Board in an amount not less than $200.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A Convention Center food and alcohol business that has registered with the Board under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-112|(h)">§ 25-112(h)</cite> before April 1, 2021 ("registered Convention Center food and alcohol business"), shall not be required to apply with the Board for a license under  this subsection, and the registered Convention Center food and alcohol business shall be granted a carry out and delivery license upon request to the Board, if the registered Convention Center food and alcohol business makes the request and pays the annual fee required by paragraph (4) of this subsection by March 31, 2021.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Beginning June 30, 2022, and each year thereafter, ABRA shall submit an annual report to the Council on the outcomes of this section, including the number of on-premise licensees participating in the carry-out and delivery option, and the number of on- and off-premise retailer licensees that may have closed after the carry-out and delivery option was implemented</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 301(c), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">designated § 301(d), Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 102(a)(1), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-270" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-270, § 2(a)(5), 62 DCR 1866</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 2062, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-84" type="History">Mar. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-84, § 2(a)(5), 63 DCR 781</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-260" type="History">Apr. 7, 2017, D.C. Law 21-260, § 2(a)(5), 64 DCR 2079</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-165" type="History">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-165, § 2(a)(6), 65 DCR 9366</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-51" type="History">Feb. 21, 2020, D.C. Law 23-51, § 2(a)(4), 67 DCR 13</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§6052|(a)|(3)">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 6052(a)(3), 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
</section>
