<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
    <prefix>§</prefix>
    <num>25-723(Perm)</num>
    <heading>Hours of sale and service for on-premises retail licensees and temporary licensees.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The licensee under a hotel license may make available in the room of a registered adult guest, and charge to the registered guest if consumed, miniatures as defined in <u>§ 25-101(32A)</u> at all hours on any day of the week.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in <u>§ 25-724</u> and subsections (c) and (e) of this section, the licensee under an on-premises retailer license, a manufacturer's license that holds an on-site sales and consumption permit, or a temporary license may sell, serve, or permit the consumption of alcoholic beverages on any day and at any time except between the following hours:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>2:00 a.m. and 6:00 a.m., Monday through Friday, excluding District and federal holidays; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>3:00 a.m. and 6:00 a.m. on Saturday and Sunday, excluding District and federal holidays.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b-1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in <u>§ 25-724</u> and subsection (c) and (e) of this section, the licensee under an on-premises retailer license or manufacturer license that holds an on-site sales and consumption permit may deliver alcoholic beverages to the home of District residents, or provide to customers for curbside delivery at any time between the hours of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>6:00 a.m. and 1:00 a.m., Monday through Friday, excluding District and federal holidays; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>6:00 a.m. and 1:00 a.m. on Saturday and Sunday, excluding District and federal holidays.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b-2)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, a holder of a commercial lifestyle center license may operate and permit the sale, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages on the licensed premises between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and 11:00 p.m., Sunday through Thursday, and 7:00 a.m. and midnight, Friday and Saturday.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num >(1)</num>
        <text>Except as provided in <u>§ 25-724</u>, the licensee under an on-premises retailer's license, a manufacturer's license that holds an on-site sales and consumption permit, or a temporary license may sell, serve, or permit the consumption of alcoholic beverages until 4:00 a.m. and operate 24 hours a day during the following times:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>On a District or federal holiday;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>The Saturday and Sunday preceding Martin Luther King, Jr.'s Birthday, Washington's Birthday, Memorial Day, Labor Day, and Indigenous Peoples' Day, as set forth in <u>§ 1-612.02(a)</u>;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>The Saturday and Sunday adjacent to January 1 (New Year's Day) and July 4 (Independence Day); except, that if the holiday under this subparagraph occurs on a Tuesday, Wednesday, or Thursday, this subparagraph shall not apply;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>The Friday, Saturday, and Sunday following Thanksgiving Day, as set forth in <u>§ 1-612.02(a)(9)</u>; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>The Saturday and Sunday adjacent to Veterans Day, Christmas Day, and District of Columbia Emancipation Day as set forth in <u>§ 1-612.02(a)</u>; except, that if the holiday under this subparagraph occurs on a Tuesday, the extended hours shall occur on the preceding Saturday and Sunday and if a holiday under this subparagraph occurs on a Wednesday or Thursday, the extended hours shall occur on the following Saturday and Sunday.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A licensee operating under an on-premises retailer's license or a manufacturer's license that holds an on-site sales and consumption permit shall not be required to obtain Board approval to sell, serve, or permit the consumption of alcoholic beverages and operate in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>This subsection shall not apply during Inaugural Week, as defined in subsection (e) of this section.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>No fewer than 30 days before the first holiday on which a licensee seeks to extend its hours of operation pursuant to this subsection, the licensee shall provide written notification to the Board and the Metropolitan Police Department of its intent to extend its hours of operation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c-1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Except as provided in <u>§ 25-724</u>, the Board may extend the hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages during postseason games in which a District professional sports team is a participant for licensees registered with the Board to participate in the extension of hours program under subsection (c) of this section.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>If the Board extends the hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages during a postseason game pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, a licensee registered with the Board in the extension of hours program under subsection (c) of this may sell, serve, and allow the consumption of alcoholic beverages until 4 a.m. and operate 24 hours a day for the postseason game day.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The Board shall provide written notification to the Metropolitan Police Department at least 48 hours before extended hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption under this subsection will take effect. The written notification shall include the list of establishments eligible to participate in the extended hours under this subsection.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>To the extent feasible, the Board shall provide notice of its decision to extend the hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption pursuant to this subsection in the District of Columbia Register. The Board shall also post notice of its decision on ABRA's website within 24 hours after its decision.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>"District professional sports team" means a professional baseball, basketball, football, hockey, soccer, or tennis team that plays its home games or matches in the Washington-Arlington-Alexandria, DC-VA-MD-WV Metropolitan Division as defined by the Office of Management and Budget as of January 1, 2020.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>"Postseason game" means a professional baseball, basketball, football, hockey, soccer, or tennis playoff or championship game.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num >(d)</num>
      <text>[Repealed].</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Every 4 years, beginning in 2013, the week of January 15 through January 21, shall be designated "Inaugural Week"; except, that in 2021, January 9 through January 24 shall be designated "Inaugural Week." Except as provided in <u>§ 25-724</u>, during Inaugural Week, a licensee under an on premises retailer's license, a manufacturer license holding an on-site sales and consumption permit, or a temporary license may sell, serve, or permit the consumption of alcoholic beverages until 4 a.m. and operate 24 hours a day if the licensee:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Provides written notification no later than January 7, to the Board and the Metropolitan Police Department of its hours of operation; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Pays the following fee for each day it will serve alcohol pursuant to this subsection:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>$250 for a CN licensee;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>$100 for a CR or CT licensee;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>$100 for manufacturer license holding an on-site sales and consumption permits, class A, B, or C; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>$50 for any other licensee.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A licensee operating under an on-premises retailer's license or a manufacturer's license shall not be required to obtain Board approval to sell, serve, or consume alcoholic beverages until 4:00 a.m. and operate 24 hours a day during Inaugural Week.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>[Repealed].</text>
    </para>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-361" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-361, § 2(c)(1), 56 DCR 1204</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 8142, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-45" type="History">Dec. 2, 2011, D.C. Law 19-45, § 2, 58 DCR 8937</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2042(a), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(z), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-270" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-270, § 2(e)(5), 62 DCR 1866</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" type="History">Oct. 8, 2016, D.C. Law 21-160, § 2012, 63 DCR 10775</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-165" type="History">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-165, § 2(f)(5), 65 DCR 9366</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, § 2052, 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, §§ 1093, 6052(b)(3), 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-236" type="History">Mar. 16, 2021, D.C. Law 23-236, § 2, 67 DCR 14409</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-127" type="History">June 30, 2022, D.C. Law 24-127, § 2(f)(6), 69 DCR 005071</annotation>
  </section>

 