<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28-5404(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Exceptions.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§28-5404">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>The provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="28|54">this chapter</cite> shall not apply:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To retail sales made via mail, phone, or internet;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To parking facilities that do not already accept cash as a form of payment as of December 1, 2020;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To a food store or retail establishment that provides a device on premises that converts cash, without charging a fee or requiring a minimum deposit amount greater than 5 dollars, into a prepaid card ("cash-to-card device") that allows a consumer to complete a transaction at the food store or retail establishment; provided, that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Upon request, the cash-to-card device shall provide each consumer with a receipt indicating the amount of cash deposited onto the prepaid card;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The prepaid card shall not be subject to an expiration date and there shall be no limit on the number of transactions that may be completed on the card; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>In the event that the cash-to-card device malfunctions, the food store or retail establishment where the cash-to-card device is located shall accept, in accordance with this chapter, payment in cash from consumers during the time period in which the cash-to-card device does not function; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>During a period of time for which the Mayor has declared a public health emergency pursuant to [<cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2304.01">§ 7-2304.01</cite>].</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-187" type="History" path="§2|(c)">Mar. 16, 2021, D.C. Law 23-187, § 2(c), 68 DCR 1031</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
