<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-153(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Code Revision Advisory Group.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall establish a Code Revision Advisory Group ("Advisory Group") to review and provide information and suggestions on proposals prepared by the Commission related to the comprehensive criminal code reform recommendations required by <u>§ 3-152(a)</u>. The Advisory Group shall consist of 5 voting members and 2 nonvoting members as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The voting members of the Advisory Group shall consist of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The United States Attorney for the District of Columbia or his or her designee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Director of the Public Defender Service for the District of Columbia or his or her designee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia or his or her designee; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Two professionals from established organizations, including institutions of higher education, devoted to the research and analysis of criminal justice issues, appointed by the Council;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The non-voting members of the Commission shall consist of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Chairperson of the Council committee with jurisdiction over the Commission or his or her designee; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice or his or her designee.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Meetings of the Advisory Group shall be conducted by the Commission's Executive Director, with meetings scheduled by the Executive Director as necessary to fulfill the statutory responsibilities of the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall provide drafts of its recommended reforms to criminal statutes to the Advisory Group in the form of reports. Advisory Group members may provide to the Commission written comments in response to those recommendations within a reasonable period of time, to be determined by the Executive Director, but not less than one month.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall consider all written comments that are timely received from Advisory Group members under subsection (c) of this section and propose all final recommendations to the Council based on the comments received.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The voting members of the Advisory Group shall vote to approve the final recommendations proposed by the Commission, with a majority of voting members necessary to approve the recommendations, before their submittal to the Council and the Mayor under <u>§ 3-152(a)</u>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall compile and make publicly available a record of all written comments received from Advisory Group members under subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" type="History" path="§3124">Oct. 8, 2016, D.C. Law 21-160, § 3124, 63 DCR 10775</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§3002|(c)">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 3002(c), 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
</section>
