<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-154(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Reporting requirements.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-154">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Until March 31, 2021, the Commission shall file quarterly reports with the Council that provide a summary of activities during the prior quarter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Before March 31, 2021, the Commission shall file a report with the Council that includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A summary and copy of all recommendations for reforms to criminal statutes developed by the Commission during the previous calendar year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A summary and copy of comments received from the Advisory Group during the previous calendar year and their disposition;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A summary of other Commission activities during the previous calendar year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A description of any problems discovered with prior Commission work or changes to prior work that are necessary due to legislative changes or court rulings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A description of any issues that could delay or prevent the Commission from timely fulfilling its statutory duties; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A work plan and schedule, or revisions to an existing work plan and schedule, for carrying out the responsibilities of the Commission to meet statutory requirements.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Beginning November 15, 2024, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall file a report with the Council detailing its activities during the previous fiscal year and its preliminary work plan for the new fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" type="History" path="§3125">Oct. 8, 2016, D.C. Law 21-160, § 3125, 63 DCR 10775</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§3002|(d)">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 3002(d), 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§3012|(b)">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 3012(b), 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
