<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1691.05(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Memoranda of Understanding.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No later than November 1, 2021, and by November 1 annually thereafter, the WIC shall execute Memoranda of Understanding ("MOUs") with UDC and the University of the District of Columbia Foundation, Inc. ("Foundation") for the purpose of implementing the Program through UDC-CC, including WDLL, and authorizing the intradistrict transfer of funds in accordance with the terms of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The MOU with UDC shall, among other things, include funding from the WIC to support the following purposes in amounts to be determined by the parties:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Tuition, required fees, equipment, supplies, tools, and memberships for Program participants who are full-time or part-time students enrolled at UDC-CC to obtain a UDC-CC degree;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Required academic fees, equipment, supplies, tools, and membership fees for Program participants who are students enrolled in WDLL courses, and the salaries and fringe benefits of faculty and staff directly engaged in the provision of such courses;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Reasonable costs of facilities and equipment upgrades necessary to provide Program training offered through UDC-CC, including WDLL;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Marketing and recruitment activities to attract District residents to the Program; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Development of dual enrollment guidance and policies for the expansion of dual-enrollment programs.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The MOU with UDC shall, among other things, include funding from the WIC to provide Program participants enrolled in WDLL courses monthly stipends to defray living expenses in amounts to be determined by the parties. UDC will disperse the stipends in a timely manner and apply criteria for providing stipends, which may include amounts for the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Fees associated with occupational licensing exams;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Reasonable transportation costs to and from classes; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any other expenses considered appropriate by the WIC.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" path="ยง4096" type="History">Nov. 13, 2021, D.C&gt; Law 24-45, ยง4096, 68 DCR 10163</annotation>
</section>
