<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1252.01(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Office of Cable Television, Film, Music, and Entertainment; Director; General Counsel.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established within the executive branch, as a subordinate agency, the Office of Cable Television, Film, Music, and Entertainment. The Office shall be responsible for:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Oversight of cable television services, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Regulating cable service, cable service providers, and the cable television industry;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Protecting and promoting the public interest in cable service; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Executing the policies and provisions of the cable television laws and regulations of the District;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Producing content for the government and educational channels and managing those channels and producing video content for District government agencies and residents; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Fostering the development of a sustainable creative economy and entertainment and media industry in the District, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Marketing and promoting the District to the entertainment industry as a prime location for productions and events;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Stimulating employment and business opportunities related to the entertainment industry;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Creating a workforce-development program for the training of District residents on entertainment industry skillsets;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Serving as a clearinghouse for information regarding government requirements affecting the entertainment industry within the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Assisting producers and companies in securing permits and other appropriate services connected with the entertainment industry, including entertainment industry projects;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Facilitating cooperation from the District government, the federal government, and private sector groups in the location and production of entertainment industry projects[;]</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Administering the Film, Television, and Entertainment Rebate Fund established by <u>§ 2-1204.11</u>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Issuing, upon delegation of authority from the Mayor, motion picture and television production permits authorized by <u>§ 2-1204.11d</u>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Office shall be administered by an Director who shall be appointed by the Mayor and shall be subject to confirmation by the Council pursuant to <u>§ 1-523.01</u>. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director shall become a bona fide resident of the District within 180 days after the effective date of confirmation by the Council and shall remain a District resident for the duration of the appointment. Failure to become a District resident or to maintain District residency shall result in forfeiture of the appointment. The Director shall not have, or have had within 2 years preceding his or her nomination, any ownership or business interest of over 5% in, or a substantial business affiliation with, any cable operator in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The duties of the Director shall include the general administration of the Office, the preparation of the budget, hiring of staff, maintaining records, administering and enforcing the provisions of this chapter and regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter, and such other duties required by law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Director shall establish an Office of the General Counsel within the Office. The Office of the General Counsel shall be headed by a General Counsel appointed by the Director with the approval of the Director of the Mayor's Office of Legal Counsel. The General Counsel, with the consent of the Director and the approval of the Director of the Mayor's Office of Legal Counsel, may appoint Assistant General Counsels. The General Counsel shall have significant experience with cable regulation matters.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-1)</num>
    <text>There shall be established within the Office a:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Cable Television Division that shall oversee matters related to the regulation of the cable television industry; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Film, Music, and Entertainment Development Division to support the development of an entertainment industry in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-2)</num>
    <text>The Director may establish other offices and divisions as the Director determines are in the interest of the Office and the purposes of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Director may appoint a Director of Programming, or an equivalent position, to be the station manager of the government channels.</text>
  </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-142" type="History" path="§201">Aug. 21, 1982, D.C. Law 4-142, § 201</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-193" type="History">as added Oct. 9, 2002, D.C. Law 14-193, § 2(b), 49 DCR 7334</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 2072(d), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" type="History">Oct. 8, 2016, D.C. Law 21-160, § 2052(a), 63 DCR 10775</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" type="History">Sept. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 23-16, § 2032, 66 DCR 8621</annotation>
</section>
