<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>36-601.12(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Lottery, Gambling, and Gaming Fund.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§36-601.12">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as an enterprise fund the Lottery, Gambling, and Gaming Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Chief Financial Officer. Revenue from the following sources shall be deposited into the Fund or a division of the Fund, as established by the Chief Financial Officer:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All funds generated by gambling activities operated or licensed by the Chief Financial Officer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All fees collected pursuant to §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§36-641.06">36-641.06</cite> through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§36-641.08">36-641.08</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any monies of the Office, from whatever source derived (including gifts to the Office), shall be for the sole use of the Fund and shall be deposited as soon as practicable in the Fund and shall be disbursed from the Fund according to the terms of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="3|13">Chapter 13 of Title 3</cite>. Disbursements of up to $500 from the Fund shall be paid out in checks signed by the Executive Director or designee. Disbursements in excess of $500 shall be paid out in checks signed by the Executive Director and the Treasurer of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>From the Fund, the Chief Financial Officer shall first pay for the operation, administration, and capital expenses of the specific forms of gambling and gaming operated and licensed by the Chief Financial Officer as authorized by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="36|6">this chapter</cite>, including the payment of prizes to winners of the games, as specified in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="36|6">this chapter</cite> pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Chief Financial Officer. The remainder shall be paid over by the Chief Financial Officer, on a monthly basis promptly after the 1st of the month for the preceding month, into the General Fund of the District of Columbia as general purpose revenue funds of the District of Columbia or as otherwise directed by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="36|6">this chapter</cite> and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="22|17|II">subchapter II of Chapter 17 of Title 22</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-172" type="History" path="§4">Mar. 10, 1981, D.C. Law 3-172, § 4, 27 DCR 4736</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" type="History" path="§7072|(l)">Oct. 8, 2016, D.C. Law 21-160, § 7072(l), 63 DCR 10775</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-312" type="History" path="§2">May 3, 2019, D.C. Law 22-312, § 2, 66 DCR 1402</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§6022|(d)">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 6022(d), 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-280" type="History" path="§7|(a)|(2)">Apr. 27, 2021, D.C. Law 23-280, § 7(a)(2), 68 DCR 1156</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-332" type="History" path="§6|(a)">Mar. 22, 2023, D.C. Law 24-332, § 6(a), 70 DCR 1582</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
