<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>36-621.15(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Taxation of Sports Wagering.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§36-621.15">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>On or before the 20th day of each month, an operator shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>File a return, on forms and in the manner prescribed by the CFO, with the CFO indicating the amount of its gross sports wagering revenue, including revenues remitted by registered sports governing bodies, for the preceding calendar month; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pay to the District of Columbia Treasurer:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>20% of the gross sports wagering revenue from the preceding calendar month, in the case of a Class A operator;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>10% of the gross sports wagering revenue from the preceding calendar month, in the case of a Class B operator; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>30% of the gross sports wagering revenue from the preceding calendar month, in the case of a Class C operator.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All funds owed to the District under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="36|6">this chapter</cite> and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="22|17|II">subchapter II of Chapter 17 of Title 22</cite> shall be held in trust within the boundaries of the District for the District by an operator until the funds are paid to the District of Columbia Treasurer. An operator shall establish a separate bank account into which gross sports wagering revenue shall be deposited and maintained until such time as the funds are paid to the District of Columbia Treasurer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, beginning October 1, 2024, all revenues remitted under subsection (a) of this section shall be transferred directly to the Child Trust Fund, established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-681.02">§ 4-681.02</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Years 2025, 2026, 2027, and 2028, the first $2.583 million of revenues remitted under subsection (a) shall be deposited in local funds.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-172" type="History" path="§315">Mar. 10, 1981, D.C. Law 3-172, § 315</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-312" type="History" path="§2|(e)">as added May 3, 2019, D.C. Law 22-312, § 2(e), 66 DCR 1402</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" type="History" path="§7052|(c)|(1)">Sept. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 23-16, § 7052(c)(1), 66 DCR 8621</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-332" type="History" path="§6|(a)">Mar. 22, 2023, D.C. Law 24-332, § 6(a), 70 DCR 1582</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" type="History" path="§7022|(a)|(2)">Sept. 6, 2023, D.C. Law 25-50, § 7022(a)(2), 70 DCR 10366</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§7172|(h)">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 7172(h), 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
