<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>37-103(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Enterprise Fund.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§37-103">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Eastern Market Enterprise Fund (“Fund”), pursuant to <cite path="§47-373|(2)|(C)">§ 47-373(2)(C)</cite>. The Fund shall be operated by the CPMO in accordance with general accepted accounting principles.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The CPMO shall deposit into the Fund all revenues, proceeds, and moneys from whatever source derived that are collected or received by the CPMO on behalf of Eastern Market.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used for the following purposes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To fund all expenses related to the management and maintenance of the Eastern Market Special Use Area; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Up to $5,000 per fiscal year to fund the operating expenses of the Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee, including the creation and preservation of meeting records, printing, copying, and other direct expenses related to their duties.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund may not be used to fund capital expenditures for Eastern Market and the Eastern Market Special Use Area.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-228" type="History" path="§4">Apr. 16, 1999, D.C. Law 12-228, § 4, 46 DCR 1066</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 22(b), 46 DCR 1066</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1192(d), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-143" type="History" path="§9">Aug. 17, 2016, D.C. Law 21-143, § 9, 63 DCR 7589</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History" path="§1112">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, § 1112, 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1192(d) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1192(d) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “biennially” for “annually”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 10-303.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§37-111">§ 37-111</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
