<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>37-131.08c(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Street vending amnesty program.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§37-131.08c">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an amnesty program for any person applying to be a street vendor who is liable for delinquent:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fines for violations of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="37|1A">this chapter</cite> and rules from 2010 to July 1, 2023, including any accrued interest or penalties; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Minimum sales tax payments owed pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2002.01">D.C. Official Code § 47-2002.01</code-cite> from 2010 to the July 1, 2023.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The amnesty program shall be available for 5 years following its establishment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person may participate in the amnesty program by filing an application for amnesty with the Mayor that includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A basic business license application;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A vending site permit application for a sidewalk vending location;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A copy of each unpaid citation received by the applicant, and the amount owed by the applicant for each citation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Documentation verifying the amount of delinquent minimum sales tax, interest, and penalties owed to the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>While the amnesty program is accepting applications, the Mayor shall publicize the terms and conditions of the amnesty program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term "street vendor" means a person licensed to vend from a sidewalk, roadway, or other public space pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§37-131.02">§ 37-131.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-71" type="History" path="§9c">Oct. 22, 2009, D.C. Law 18-71, § 9c</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-21" type="History">as added July 1, 2023, D.C. Law 25-21, § 3(f), 70 DCR 6762</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
