<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>37-131.08b(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Columbia Heights-Mount Pleasant Sidewalk Vending Zone.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§37-131.08b">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Columbia Heights-Mount Pleasant Sidewalk Vending Zone, comprised of the geographic area bounded by a line that begins on the southwest corner of the intersection of 16th Street, NW, and Fuller Avenue, NW, then north along the west side of 16th Street, NW, until the southwest corner of 16th Street, NW, and Harvard Street, NW, then north along the west side Harvard Street, NW, until the northwest corner of the intersection of Harvard Street, NW, and Argonne Place, NW, then east along the north side of Argonne Place, NW, until the northwest corner of the intersection of Argonne Place, NW, and Mount Pleasant Street, NW, then north along the west side of Mount Pleasant Street, NW, until the northwest corner of the intersection of Irving Street, NW, and Mount Pleasant Street, NW, then west along Irving Street, NW until the southwest corner of the intersection of Irving Street, NW, and 17th Street, NW, then north along 17th Street, NW, until the northwest corner of the intersection of 17th Street, NW, and Park Road, NW, then east along Park Road, NW, until the northwest corner of the intersection of Park Road, NW, and 14th Street, NW, then north along the west side of 14th Street, NW, until the northwest corner of 14th Street, NW, and Ogden Street, NW, then north on the west side of Ogden Street, NW, until the northwest corner of the intersection of Ogden Street, NW, and Oak Street, NW, then east along the north side of Oak Street, NW, until the northwest corner of Oak Street, NW, and 14th Street, NW, then north along the west side of 14th Street, NW, until the northwest corner of the intersection of 14th Street, NW, and Spring Road, NW, then south along the east side of 14th Street, NW, to the northeast corner of 14th Street, NW, and Newton Street, NW, then east along the north side of Newton Street, NW, until the northeast corner of the intersection of Newton Street, NW, and Holmead Place, NW, then south along the east side of Holmead Place, NW, until the northeast corner of the intersection of Holmead Place, NW, and Park Road, NW, then east along the north side of Park Road, NW, until the northeast corner of the intersection of Park Road, NW, and 13th Street, NW, then south on the east side of 13th Street, NW, until the southeast corner of the intersection of 13th Street, NW, and Girard Street, NW, then east along the south side of Girard Street, NW, until the southeast corner of the intersection of 15th Street, NW, and Girard Street, NW, then south along the west side of 15th Street, NW, until the southeast corner of the intersection of 15th Street, NW, and Fuller Street, NW, then east along the south side of Fuller Street, NW, until the southwest corner of the intersection of Fuller Street, NW, and 16th Street, NW[.]</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Columbia Heights-Mount Pleasant Sidewalk Vending Zone shall contain the following areas for the siting of vending locations:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Sidewalks surrounding Reservation 309, and public space in Reservation 309;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Sidewalks surrounding Reservation 309G, and public space in Reservation 309G over which the District has jurisdiction;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Sidewalks surrounding Reservation 310B, and public space in Reservation 310B;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Eastern and western sidewalks of Mt. Pleasant Street, NW, between Harvard Street, NW, and Park Road, NW, including all sidewalk space on:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The southeast corner of Mt. Pleasant Street, NW, and Lamont Street, NW, and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The southeast corner of Mt. Pleasant Street, NW, and Park Road, NW;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Eastern and western sidewalks of 14th Street, NW, between Columbia Road, NW, and Monroe Street, NW;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Western sidewalk of 14th Street, NW, between Parkwood Place, NW, and Perry Place, NW;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Northern sidewalk of Park Road, NW, between 14th Street, NW, and Holmead Place, NW;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Northern sidewalk of Monroe Street, NW, between 14th Street NW, and the public alley located between Lots 21 and 144 of Square 2836;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Southern sidewalk of Monroe Street, NW, between 14th Street, NW, and the public alley located between Lots 76 and 79 of Square 2837;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Northern and southern sidewalks or Irving Street, NW, between 14th Street, NW, and Mt. Pleasant Street, NW;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>Civic Plaza in Lot 834 of Square 2843, bounded by 14th Street, NW, Kenyon Street, NW, and Park Road, NW;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(L)</num>
        <text>Southern sidewalk of Columbia Road, NW, between 14th Street, NW, and 15th Street, NW; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(M)</num>
        <text>Southern sidewalk of Lamont Street, NW, between Mount Pleasant Street, NW, and 16th Street, NW</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For each area listed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Mayor shall, in coordination with a sidewalk vending zone manager and pursuant to an approved vending site plan, establish vending locations at which sidewalk vendors may locate. Vending locations within the Columbia Heights-Mount Pleasant Sidewalk Vending Zone shall not violate the restrictions of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§37-131.08a|(a)|(1)">§ 37-131.08a(a)(1)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may add additional areas within the boundaries of the Columbia Heights-Mount Pleasant Sidewalk Vending Zone established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section for the purpose of siting additional vendor locations; provided, that any additional areas shall be established pursuant to an approved vending site plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall issue a request for proposals ("RFP") for a sidewalk vending zone manager for the Columbia Heights-Mount Pleasant Sidewalk Vending Zone no later than 60 days after July 1, 2023.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In the process of developing the RFP, the Mayor shall solicit input from sidewalk vendors and community-based organizations and non-profits providing technical assistance or legal services to vendors.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall execute a contract with an entity selected through the RFP process set forth in subsection (c) of this section no later than 120 days after July 1, 2023.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a contract with a sidewalk vending zone manager is not executed within 120 days following July 1, 2023, sidewalk vendors shall be able to locate and operate in areas of the Columbia Heights-Mount Pleasant Sidewalk Vending Zone.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-71" type="History" path="§9b">Oct. 22, 2009, D.C. Law 18-71, § 9b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-21" type="History">as added July 1, 2023, D.C. Law 25-21, § 3(f), 70 DCR 6762</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
