<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1631.05(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Institution, conference, and athletic association involvement.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current. To see the current law, click this link <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-1631.05">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An institution, conference, or athletic association may assist a college athlete:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In evaluating the permissibility of name, image, or likeness activity, including compliance with the law and institution, conference, and association rules;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>With the disclosure requirements of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-1631.06">§ 38-1631.06</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By providing a good-faith evaluation of a name, image, or likeness agent or third party; and</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An institution may permit a college athlete to use the institution's facilities for name, image, or likeness activity under the same terms and conditions as other students at the institution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An institution, conference, or athletic association shall educate a college athlete about name, image, or likeness compensation, agreements, and activity by offering financial literacy and life skills programming to college athletes. At a minimum, the programming should include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Information concerning student loan, financial aid, and debt management;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Time management skills necessary for success as a college athlete and an overview of available academic support services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Budgeting based on cost of attendance, living expenses, and scholarship resources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An explanation of services offered by and guidance for accessing banks and basic banking products;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>An introduction to income taxes, including income earned as an independent contractor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Warnings about payday and predatory lending practices.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This subsection shall not be construed to place an obligation on an institution to provide individualized tax or legal guidance to college athletes seeking or earning name, image, or likeness compensation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, an institution or conference and its employees, agents, and independent contractors may not:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provide compensation to a college athlete for the athlete's name, image, or likeness;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Assist with selecting, arranging for, or providing payment to a name, image, or likeness agent; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Assist with selecting, arranging for, or collecting payment from a third party engaged in specific name, image, or likeness agreements with a college athlete or athletes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-245" type="History" path="§215">Feb. 23, 2023, D.C. Law 24-245, § 215, 70 DCR 174</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
