<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2801.01(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"At-risk" shall have the same meaning as provided in <u>§ 38-2901(2A)</u>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1A)</num>
      <text>"DCPS" means the District of Columbia Public Schools, established by <u>§ 38-171</u>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1B)</num>
      <text>"Educational specification" means a description, complete to the degree that an architect may use it as the basic document from which to create a school facility design, of the educational program that a proposed school facility and grounds are intended to support and the types of spaces needed to accommodate those educational program requirements.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Excess" means no longer needed for operational purposes for DCPS or another District agency.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2A)</num>
      <text>"Feeder pattern" means the collection of DCPS elementary, middle, and high schools to or from which a student enrolled in a DCPS school may matriculate, by right, due to the student's geographic attendance zone.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2B)</num>
      <text>"Full-funded cost estimate" means all projected costs over a capital project's entire active period, not limited to 6 fiscal years, including costs for necessary swing space and soft costs such as architectural design, engineering, project management, project contingency, moving expenses, and other pre- and post-construction expenses.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2C)</num>
      <text>"Local education agency" or "LEA" means the District of Columbia Public Schools system or any individual or group of public charter schools operating under a single charter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2D)</num>
      <text>"Major construction" means a capital improvement to a school facility that is not limited in scope to the ordinary repair or replacement of an element of a school facility's central mechanical and electrical systems, water systems, building structure, physical plant support spaces, hard and soft landscaping, or building envelope, including walls, floors, roof, windows, and doors.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2E)</num>
      <text>"Neighborhood cluster" means an apolitical geographic boundary made up of 3 to 5 neighborhoods defined by the Office of Planning for use in budgeting, planning, service delivery, and analysis purposes by the District government.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2F)</num>
      <text>"Rough order of magnitude estimate" means an estimate of a specific project's level of effort and cost to complete based on preliminary observations, quantities, and a reasonably foreseeable scope of work. These estimates are subject to change as specific project scope is established based on educational specifications.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"School facility" means a structure or real property that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is under the control of DCPS; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Was previously under the control of DCPS or the Board of Education and is now under the control of the Mayor or another agency of the District government.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Significantly underused" means a DCPS facility that is used primarily for administrative purposes and uses less than 25% of the property's available square footage on a daily basis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Swing space" means a school facility reserved for future classroom instruction or DCPS administrative use during planned renovation, modernization, or construction of another school facility.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Utilization" means the ratio of current enrollment to the total number of students that can be served in a space based on programmatic and scheduling requirements.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175" type="History" path="§1102a">March 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1102a</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-114" type="History">as added June 21, 2014, D.C. Law 20-114, § 3(a), 61 DCR 4669</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-219" type="History">Feb. 18, 2017, D.C. Law 21-219, § 2(a), 63 DCR 16023</annotation>
</section>
