<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2242(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Early Childhood Educator Equitable Compensation Task Force establishment.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2242">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established by the Council an Early Childhood Educator Equitable Compensation Task Force ("Task Force") to provide recommendations on how to implement an employee compensation scale for early childhood development providers.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Following the submission of the report required pursuant to subsection (c)(3) of this section, the Task Force shall reconvene every 4th calendar year, or as deemed necessary by the Chairman.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Task Force shall be comprised of the Chairman of the Council, or his or her designee, the State Superintendent of Education, or his or her designee, and 12 District residents, appointed by the Chairman, representing the following entities or groups:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Families whose children are receiving or have received childcare services from an early childhood development provider in the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Community-based organizations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Early childhood advocacy organizations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Operators of child development facilities who participate in the childcare subsidy program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Operators of child development facilities who do not currently participate in the childcare subsidy program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Operators of home-based child development facilities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Educators of child development facilities; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>An individual with an expertise in economics or policy, who has an understanding of the District's early childhood development and education sector.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At least 2 members of the Task Force shall be employees of child development facilities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Chairman, or his or her designee, shall serve as the Chairperson of the Task Force.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Review the findings and recommendations of the Early Childhood Educator Compensation in the Washington Region study completed by the Urban Institute and any completed employee compensation scale and other relevant materials provided by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Submit a report to the Mayor and Council by January 15, 2022, that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Assesses the potential impact of implementing an employee compensation scale on early childhood development providers that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Do not provide childcare services to children eligible for subsidy; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Serve a minimum number of children who receive subsidy;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Proposes an employee compensation scale for early childhood development providers that accounts for employee role, credentials, and experience; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Provides recommendations for implementing the employee compensation scale, which at a minimum considers:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Equitable implementation that accounts for different staffing models, types, and sizes of early childhood development facilities;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Long-term implications of the District providing funds to early childhood providers to implement the pay scale, including how to allocate funds for new early childhood development facilities that open after legislation is enacted; provided, that recommendations do not exceed the $70 million appropriated in the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Fund, plus any amounts adjusted for inflation in years beyond Fiscal Year 2023; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Oversight, reporting, and accountability mechanisms for the use of funds allocated to early childhood development providers from the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Fund; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Following the adoption of the Fiscal Year 2025 budget and financial plan, submit a report to the Mayor and Council by September 30, 2024, that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Recommends changes to the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Program established pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-402|(b)">§ 4-402(b)</cite>, including recommendations for limiting fiscal pressures on the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Program through Fiscal Year 2028;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Proposes a new compensation scale for employees of early childhood development providers that takes into account the compensation and benefits of individuals employed by the District of Columbia Public Schools and District public charter schools who teach pre-kindergarten and kindergarten; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Provides additional recommendations for the allocation of monies available in the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Fund.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" type="History" path="§1103">Nov. 13, 2021, D.C. Law 24-45, § 1103, 68 DCR 10163</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§4084">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 4084, 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
