<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2905(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Supplement to foundation level funding on the basis of the count of special education, LEP/NEP, summer school, and residential school students.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2905">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to grade level allocations, supplemental allocations shall be provided on the basis of the count of students identified as entitled to and receiving:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Special education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>English as a second language or bilingual education services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Summer school instruction for students who do not meet literacy standards pursuant to promotion policies of the DCPS or Public Charter Schools as defined in <cite path="§38-1804.01|(b)|(3)|(B)|(ii)">§ 38-1804.01(b)(3)(B)(ii)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to section <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2905.01">106a</code-cite>, supplemental allocations shall be provided on the basis of the count of students identified as at-risk.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Supplemental allocations shall be provided for each student in full-time residence at a residential DCPS or Public Charter School.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The supplemental allocations shall be calculated by applying weightings to the foundation level as follows:</text>
    <text>
      <text>Special education add-ons:</text>
      <table>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <th>Level/Program</th>
            <th>Definition</th>
            <th>Weighting</th>
            <th>Per Pupil Allocation in FY 2025</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Level 1: Special Education</td>
            <td>Eight hours or less per school week of specialized services</td>
            <td>0.97</td>
            <td>$14,228</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Level 2: Special Education</td>
            <td>More than 8 hours and less than or equal to 16 hours per school week of specialized services.</td>
            <td>1.20</td>
            <td>$17,602</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Level 3: Special Education</td>
            <td>More than 16 hours and less than or equal to 24 hours per school week of specialized services.</td>
            <td>1.97</td>
            <td>$28,896</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Level 4: Special Education</td>
            <td>More than 24 hours per school week of specialized services which may include instruction in a self-contained (dedicated) special education school other than residential placement</td>
            <td>3.49</td>
            <td>$51,191</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Special Education Compliance</td>
            <td>Weighting provided in addition to special education level add-on weightings on a per-student basis for special education compliance</td>
            <td>0.099</td>
            <td>$1,452</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Attorneys' Fees Supplement</td>
            <td>Weighting provided in addition to special education level add-on weightings on a per-student basis for attorney's fees</td>
            <td>0.089</td>
            <td>$1,305</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Residential</td>
            <td>District of Columbia Public Schools school or public charter school that provides students with room and board in a residential setting, in addition to their instructional program</td>
            <td>1.67</td>
            <td>$24,496</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </text>
    <text>
      <text>General education add-ons:</text>
      <table>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <th>Level/Program</th>
            <th>Definition</th>
            <th>Weighting</th>
            <th>Per Pupil Supplemental Allocation FY 2025</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Elementary ELL</td>
            <td>Additional funding for English language learners in grades PK3-5</td>
            <td>0.50</td>
            <td>$7,334</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Secondary ELL</td>
            <td>Additional funding for English language learners in grades 6-12, alternative students, adult students, and students in special education schools</td>
            <td>0.75</td>
            <td>$11,001</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>At-risk</td>
            <td>Additional funding for students in foster care, who are homeless, on TANF or SNAP, or behind grade level in high school</td>
            <td>0.30</td>
            <td>$4,400</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>At-risk High School Over-Age Supplement</td>
            <td>Weighting provided in addition to at-risk weight for students who are behind grade level in high school</td>
            <td>0.06</td>
            <td>$880</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>At-risk &gt; 40% Concentration Supplement</td>
            <td>Weighting provided in addition to at-risk weight for the percentage of at-risk students above 40% enrolled in a school where at least 40% of the student population is at-risk</td>
            <td>0.07</td>
            <td>$1,027</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>At-risk &gt; 70% Concentration Supplement</td>
            <td>Weighting provided in addition to at-risk weight for the percentage of at-risk students above 70% where at least 70% of the student population is at-risk</td>
            <td>0.07</td>
            <td>$1,027</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </text>
    <text>
      <text>Residential add-ons:</text>
      <table>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <th>Level/Program</th>
            <th>Definition</th>
            <th>Weighting</th>
            <th>Per Pupil Allocation in FY 2025</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Level 1: Special Education - Residential</td>
            <td>Additional funding to support the after-hours Level 1 special education needs of students living in a DCPS school or public charter school that provides students with room and board in a residential setting</td>
            <td>0.37</td>
            <td>$5,427</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Level 2: Special Education - Residential</td>
            <td>Additional funding to support the after-hours Level 2 special education needs of students living in a DCPS school or public charter school that provides students with room and board in a residential setting</td>
            <td>1.34</td>
            <td>$19,655</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Level 3: Special Education - Residential</td>
            <td>Additional funding to support the after-hours Level 3 special education needs of students living in a DCPS school or public charter school that provides students with room and board in a residential setting</td>
            <td>2.89</td>
            <td>$42,391</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Level 4: Special Education - Residential</td>
            <td>Additional funding to support the after-hours Level 4 special education needs of limited and non- English proficient students living in a DCPS school or public charter school that provides students with room and board in a residential setting</td>
            <td>2.89</td>
            <td>$42,391</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>LEP/NEP - Residential</td>
            <td>Additional funding to support the after-hours limited and non-English proficiency needs of students living in a DCPS school or public charter school that provides students with room and board in a residential setting</td>
            <td>0.668</td>
            <td>$9,798</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </text>
    <text>
      <text>Special education add-ons for students with extended school year ("ESY") indicated in their individualized education Programs ("IEPs")</text>
      <table>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <th>Level/Program</th>
            <th>Definition</th>
            <th>Weighting</th>
            <th>Per Pupil Allocation in FY 2025</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Special Education Level 1 ESY</td>
            <td>Additional funding to support the summer school or program need for special education Level 1 students who require ESY services in their IEPs</td>
            <td>0.063</td>
            <td>$924</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Special Education Level 2 ESY</td>
            <td>Additional funding to support the summer school or program need for special education Level 2 students who require ESY services in their IEPs</td>
            <td>0.227</td>
            <td>$3,330</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Special Education Level 3 ESY</td>
            <td>Additional funding to support the summer school or program need for special education Level 3 students who require ESY services in their IEPs</td>
            <td>0.491</td>
            <td>$7,202</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Special Education Level 4 ESY</td>
            <td>Additional funding to support the summer school or program need for special education Level 4 students who require ESY services in their IEPs</td>
            <td>0.491</td>
            <td>$7,202</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="38|29|I">this act</code-cite>, the above weightings shall be applied cumulatively in the counts of students who fall into more than one of the above categories.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The summer school weighting of 0.17 shall apply to DCPS and public charter school students enrolled for at least 6 weeks for the purpose described in <cite path="§38-2901|(13)">§ 38-2901(13)</cite>. Summer school students enrolled for a lesser period shall be funded for the number of days in that period on a pro-rata basis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To receive funding, a DCPS or public charter school summer school program must offer at least 60 hours of instruction outside the regular school year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To receive full funding, a summer school program must offer at least 4 hours of instruction per day, 5 days a week, for 6 weeks, or its equivalent, for a total of at least 120 hours of instruction outside the regular school year for the purpose described in <cite path="§38-2901|(13)">§ 38-2901(13)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The fully funded summer school weighting of 0.17 shall apply for summer school programs that meet the requirements of paragraph (3) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Summer school programs that enroll students for less than 120 hours but more than 59 hours shall be funded on a pro-rata basis.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Funding for special education students enrolled in summer school whose Individual Education Plans require extended school year or summer school services shall be calculated using the add-on weights corresponding to their special education service levels as defined in subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Special education add-on weights for summer school shall apply only to summer programs that deliver the specialized services required by the Individual Education Plans of their enrolled special education students.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-207" type="History" path="§106">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-207, § 106, 45 DCR 8095</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 2702, 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 502, 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 3402(d), 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-307" type="History">June 5, 2003, D.C. Law 14-307, § 102(c), 49 DCR 11664</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 312(c), 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 4002(c), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-348" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-348, § 101(b), 52 DCR 1991</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 4012(c), 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-192" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-192,§ 4002(d), 53 DCR 6899</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20" type="History">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 4002(d), 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-219" type="History">Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 4016(c), 55 DCR 7598</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 4002(b), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 4022(c), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 402(c), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 4003(d), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 4002(c), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 95(a), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 4002(c), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  4002(c), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 4002(b), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" type="History" path="§4002|(c)">Oct. 8, 2016, D.C. Law 21-160, § 4002(c), 63 DCR 10775</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" type="History" path="§4002|(c)">Dec. 13, 2017, D.C. Law 22-33, § 4002(c), 64 DCR 7652</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-124" type="History" path="§201|(c)">July 3, 2018, D.C. Law 22-124, § 201(c), 65 DCR 5091</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History" path="§4002|(c)">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, § 4002(c), 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" type="History" path="§4003|(d)">Sept. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 23-16, § 4003(d), 66 DCR 8621</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§4002|(c)">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 4002(c), 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" type="History" path="§4002|(e)">Nov. 13, 2021, D.C. Law 24-45, § 4002(e), 68 DCR 10163</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History" path="§4002|(d)">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 4002(d), 69 DCR 9223</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" type="History" path="§4002|(d)">Sept. 6, 2023, D.C. Law 25-50, § 4002(d), 70 DCR 10366</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§4002|(e)">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 4002(e), 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 4001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title IV of the act may be cited as the “Funding for Public Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 4002(b) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 4002(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 4002(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 4002(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 4002(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 4002(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(c) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(c) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4003(d) of Fiscal Year 2012 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-93, June 29, 2011,  58 DCR 5599).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 402(c) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4022(c) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(b) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(b) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(b) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-187, August 26, 2009,  56 DCR 7374).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(d) of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(d) of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-1, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1165).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(d) of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-499, October 23, 2006,  53 DCR 8845).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(d) of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-477, August 8, 2006,  53 DCR 7068).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4012(c) of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4002(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 312(c) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 312(c) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 102(c) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3302(d) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 102(c) of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 102(c) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 502 of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Uniform Per Student Funding Formula For Public Schools and Public Charter Schools Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-18, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2691).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Special Education Student Funding Increase Non-service Nonprofit Provider Clarifying and Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-17, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2687).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-485, December 18, 2000,  48 DCR 20).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Special Education Student Funding Increase Non-service Nonprofit Provider Clarifying and Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-456, November 7, 2000,  47 DCR 9418).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2702 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2702 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Special Education Student Funding Increase Non-service Nonprofit Provider Clarifying and Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-282, March 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2026).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Special Education Student Funding Increase Non-service Nonprofit Provider Clarifying and Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-152, December 1, 1999,  46 DCR 10395).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of chapter, see note to <cite path="§38-2901">§ 38-2901</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§38-2901">§ 38-2901</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-6">D.C. Law 14-6</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The summer school weighting of 0.17 shall apply to DCPS and public charter school students enrolled for at least 6 weeks during the summer following the regular school year. Summer school students enrolled for a lesser period shall be funded for the number of days in that period on a pro rata basis.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-6">D.C. Law 14-6</cite>, in subsec. (c), in the chart, substituted “up to +0.17 pro rata” for “+0.10” and “up to $935 pro rata” for “$550”, and added a new subsec. (e) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-262">D.C. Law 13-262</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-227">D.C. Law 13-227</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The summer school weighting of 0.17 shall apply to DCPS and public charter school students enrolled for at least 6 weeks during the summer following the regular school year. Summer school students enrolled for a lesser period shall be funded for the number of days in that period on a pro rata basis.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(c)(1) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-262">D.C. Law 13-262</cite>, in subsec. (c), in the chart, substituted “up to +0.17 pro rata” for “+0.10” and “up to $935 pro rata” for “$550”. Section 2(c)(2) of that law added subsec. (e) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-227">D.C. Law 13-227</cite> amended subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">(c) These supplemental allocations shall be calculated by applying weightings to the foundation level as follows: Level/program Definition Weighting Supplemental per pupil FY 1999 Level 1 Special Additional funding to support +0.374 $2.057 Education the after-hours level 1 —Residential special education needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or Public Charter School that provides students with room and board in a residential setting Level 2 Special Additional funding to support +1.36 $7.480 Education the after-hours level 2 —Residential special education needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or Public Charter School that provides students with room and board in a residential setting Level 3 Special Additional funding to support +2.941 $16.176 Education the after-hours level 3 —Residential special education needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or Public Charter School that provides students with room and board in a residential setting Level 4 Special Additional funding to support +2.924 $16.082 Education the after-hours level 4 —Residential special education needs of students living in D.C. Public School or Public Charter School that provides students with room and board in a residential setting LEP Additional funding to support +0.68 $3.740 NEP—Residential the after-hours special instructional needs of limited and non-English proficient students living in a D.C. Public School or Public Charter School that provides students with room and board in a residential setting Section 3(b) of D.C. Laws 13-067 provides that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(a) of D.C. Laws 13-067 amended subsec. (c) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) These supplemental allocations shall be calculated by applying weightings to the foundation level as follows: Level/Program Definition Weighting Supplemental per pupil FY</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> rewrote the table in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> rewrote the table in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> rewrote the table in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> made a correction to the <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> version of subsection (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> rewrote (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite> rewrote subsec. (c) which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite>, in the chart in subsec. (c), substituted “up to +0.17 pro rata” and “up to $935 pro rata” for “+0.10” and “$550”; and added subsec. (e) relating to summer school weighting.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite> substituted “3.2” for “!.72” in the Level IV segment of the chart and added the Level V provision.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-2905.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§38-1804.01">§ 38-1804.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
