<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2955(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Reallocation and use of District of Columbia Public Schools funds.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2955">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to rules promulgated by the Chief Financial Officer, each school in the District of Columbia Public Schools ("DCPS") may reallocate funds between object classes within the school's non-personal services object category in the aggregate not-to-exceed amount of $100,000 within each fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>DCPS is authorized to spend appropriated funds to pay for DCPS-sponsored student travel, including the cost of transportation, lodging, meals, and admission fees for students and adult chaperones, to locations and venues outside DCPS facilities in accordance with rules promulgated by the Chancellor pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-174|(c)|(5)">§ 38-174(c)(5)</cite>; provided, that such travel be related to the students' curriculum or for the purpose of rewarding student curricular or extra-curricular achievement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the terms "object category" and "object class" shall have the same meanings as provided in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-361|(9)">§ 47-361(9)</cite> and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-361|(10)">(10)</cite>, respectively.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" type="History" path="§4012">Oct. 8, 2016, D.C. Law 21-160, § 4012, 63 DCR 10775</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" type="History" path="§4012">Nov. 13, 2021, D.C. Law 24-45, § 4012, 68 DCR 10163</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§4022">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 4022, 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
