<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-821.02(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Healthy school meal subsidies and healthy school grants.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-821.02">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In Fiscal Year 2025, $5,690,000 in local funds shall be used as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To provide additional funding for healthy school meals, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall reimburse public schools, public charter schools, participating private schools, and organizations participating in the Summer Food Service Program as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Twenty cents for each breakfast meal served that meets the requirements of §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.02">38-822.02</cite> and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.03">38-822.03</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Ten cents for each lunch meal served that meets the requirements of §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.02">38-822.02</cite> and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.03">38-822.03</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To eliminate the reduced-price copayment under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.03|(b)|(1)">§ 38-822.03(b)(1)</cite>, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall reimburse public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools, for each lunch meal that meets the requirements of §§<cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.02">38-822.02</cite> and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.03">38-822.03</cite> and is served to a student who qualifies for reduced-price meals, the greater of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Forty cents; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The difference between the U.S. Department of Agriculture reimbursement rate for a free lunch and a reduced-price lunch.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4A)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To provide resources to implement alternative breakfast serving models, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall provide an annual subsidy of $2 per student to public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools that implement an approved alternative breakfast serving model.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Schools shall use funds received pursuant to this paragraph to purchase equipment and supplies needed to operate the alternative breakfast serving model.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To encourage local foods to be served in schools, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall provide an additional 5 cents per day reimbursement to public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools when at least one component of a reimbursable breakfast or lunch meal is comprised entirely of locally grown and unprocessed foods; provided, that the schools report the name and address of the farms where the locally grown foods were grown to the Office of the State Superintendent of Education.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term "locally grown and unprocessed foods" shall not include milk.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>To increase physical activity in schools, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education may issue grants through a competitive process or a formula grants process to public schools, public charter schools, or organizations that provide technical assistance to public schools or public charter schools to increase the amount of physical activity in schools; provided, that a school receiving a grant pursuant to this paragraph shall seek to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Meet the requirements of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-824.02">§ 38-824.02</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Increase the amount of physical activity in which its students engage.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>To support school gardens or promote health education, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall make grants available, subject to the availability of funds, through a competitive process or a formula grants process to public schools, public charter schools, and other organizations.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>To increase nutrition education in schools, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall make grants available, subject to the availability of funds, through either a competitive grant process or a formula grants process, to public schools, public charter schools, and organizations that provide technical assistance to public schools and public charter schools to incorporate nutrition education into the school day.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>To increase cafeteria staff's abilities to provide healthy meals for students, the Office of the State Superintendent for Education may issue grants through a competitive process or a formula grants process to public schools, public charter schools, or other organizations for the acquisition of school kitchen equipment and for providing training sessions on cooking skills and nutrition for school cafeteria workers and school food service vendors.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>To decrease food and food packaging waste at schools and provide greater food access to those in need, the Office of the State Superintendent for Education may issue grants through a competitive process or a formula grants process to local education agencies, schools, nonprofit organizations, or partnerships developed among schools or with nonprofit organizations to support efforts to address food and food packaging waste, including implementation and management of share tables, purchase or provision of reusable food service ware, including from third-party reusable food service ware providers, and other food waste and food waste packaging reduction programs.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Office of the State Superintendent of Education may, by rule, increase the amounts, as set forth in subsection (c) of this section, to further improve the quality and nutrition of school meals.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Office of the State Superintendent of Education may withhold local funds provided by subsection (c) of this section from public schools and public charter schools that do not meet any or all of the requirements of §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.02">38-822.02</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.03">38-822.03</cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.05">38-822.05</cite>, and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-822.06">38-822.06</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-209" type="History" path="§102">July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 102, 57 DCR 4779</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 412, 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 4012, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-37" type="History">Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-37, § 2(b), 58 DCR 6841</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 4062(a), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-142" type="History">Dec. 17, 2014, D.C. Law 20-142, § 311(a), 61 DCR 8045</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" type="History" path="§6112|(b)">Dec. 13, 2017, D.C. Law 22-33, § 6112(b), 64 DCR 7652</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-124" type="History" path="§106">July 3, 2018, D.C. Law 22-124, § 106, 65 DCR 5091</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History" path="§4032">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, § 4032, 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-240" type="History" path="§2|(b)">Mar. 13, 2019, D.C. Law 22-240, § 2(b), 66 DCR 912</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" type="History">Sept. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 23-16, §§ 4142, 7160, 66 DCR 8621</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§4062">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 4062, 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-211" type="History" path="§4|(b)">Mar. 16, 2021, D.C. Law 23-211, § 4(b), 68 DCR 68</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" type="History" path="§4242|(a)">Nov. 13, 2021, D.C. Law 24-45, § 4242(a), 68 DCR 10163</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§4012|(b)">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 4012(b), 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(a) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(a) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Healthy Schools Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-143, August 9, 2011,  58 DCR 6814).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4012 of Fiscal Year 2012 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-93, June 29, 2011,  58 DCR 5599).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 412 of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§38-821.01">§ 38-821.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-142">D.C. Law 20-142</cite>: Section 502(e) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-142">D.C. Law 20-142</cite> provided that § 311 of the act shall apply as of December 17, 2014.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4063 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> provided that § 4062 of the act shall apply as of June 20, 2012.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4011 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle B of title IV of the act may be cited as “Healthy Schools Technical Amendment Act of 2011”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 411 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> provided that subtitle B of title IV of the act may be cited as “Healthy Schools Amendment Act of 2010”.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
