<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-823.02(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Programs.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-823.02">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall, in conjunction with the Department of Health, the Department of Parks and Recreation, the District Department of the Environment, the University of the District of Columbia, community organizations, food service providers, public schools, and public charter schools, develop programs to promote the benefits of purchasing and eating locally grown and unprocessed foods that are from growers engaged in sustainable agriculture practices. At minimum, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall conduct at least one program per year, such as an annual local flavor week or a harvest of the month program, in collaboration with other District agencies and nonprofit organizations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In Fiscal Year 2023, notwithstanding <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="1|3|XII-A|B">the Grant Administration Act of 2013, effective December 24, 2013 (D.C. Law 20-61; D.C. Official Code § 1-328.11 <em>et seq</em>.)</code-cite>, no later than November 1, 2022, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall issue a $1.6 million grant to a not-for-profit organization that currently partners with the District of Columbia Public Schools ("DCPS") to integrate farming, cooking, and nutrition education curriculum ("healthy food programming") into core academics for the purpose of continuing healthy food programming at DCPS in the 2022-2023 school year.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-209" type="History" path="§302">July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 302, 57 DCR 4779</annotation>
     <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History" path="§4102">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 4102, 69 DCR 9223</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
