<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>39-117(Perm)</num>
  <heading>DCPL Revenue-Generating Activities Fund.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-117">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the DCPL Revenue-Generating Activities Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Board in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall consist of the revenue from revenue-generating activities and services described in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-105|(a)|(14)">section 5(a)(14)</code-cite>, <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-105|(a)|(16)">(16)</cite>, and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-105|(a)|(17)|(A)|(ii)">(17)(A)(ii)-(iii)</cite> and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-107">(7)</code-cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used for the following purposes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Payment of any expenses associated with activities and services described in <cite path="§39-105|(a)|(14)">§  39-105(a)(14)</cite>, including expenses for space rental and special events associated with the activities and services authorized in <cite path="§39-105|(a)|(14)">§  39-105(a)(14)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Payment of any non-personnel costs related to the library services mission of the District of Columbia Public Library; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To support the operations of the District of Columbia Public Library, including programming and facilities improvements, and to purchase food, snacks, and non-alcoholic beverages for the general public, District of Columbia Public Library program participants, and District government employees.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text> The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 54-1-ch315" path="§15">June 3, 1896, 29 Stat. 244, ch. 315, § 17</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">as added Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 4112(b), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History" path="§4052|(b)">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, § 4052(b), 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" type="History" path="§4072|(d)">Sept. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 23-16, § 4072(d), 66 DCR 8621</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite>: Section 4113 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> provided that section 4112 of the act shall apply as of March 25, 2015.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 4112(b) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
