<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1802(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Civil legal counsel projects for eligible individuals or groups in covered proceedings.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1802">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Civil Legal Counsel Projects Program ("Program") for the purpose of providing legal services to eligible individuals or groups in covered proceedings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office of Victim Services and Justice Grants shall award a grant each fiscal year to the Bar Foundation for the purposes of the Bar Foundation administering the Program. Payment of the award shall be submitted by October 15th of each fiscal year in the amount specified in an act of the Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not be used to supplant funds made available pursuant to § 4-1703.01(a), or § 4-1704.01.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The grant shall be nonlapsing and interest earned by the Bar Foundation on grant funds shall remain available for use by the Bar Foundation for the purposes of the Program, without fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Bar Foundation shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Serve as the grant-managing entity for the Program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Adopt policies, procedures, guidelines, and requirements for the Program, including policies designed to permit designated legal service providers to limit representation to eligible individuals or groups in covered proceedings.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" type="History" path="§3053">Dec. 13, 2017, D.C. Law 22-33, § 3053, 64 DCR 7652</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History" path="§3082">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, § 3082, 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History" path="§3043|(b)">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 3043(b), 69 DCR 9223</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3032(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3032(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3032(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added (b)(3); added “Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection” in (c)(3); and added (c)(4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§4-1701.01">§ 4-1701.01</cite> and <cite path="§4-1702.02">§ 4-1702.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
