<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-2004(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Eligibility for payment.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-2004">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It shall not be a violation of this act for a direct care service provider to pay a direct care professional less than 117.6% of the District minimum wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1003">§ 32-1003</cite>, or 117.6% of the District living wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2|X-A">subchapter X-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2</cite> if the direct care service provider creates a tiered compensation schedule that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Considers a direct care professional's qualified experience in the field and their demonstrated competency; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Ensures that, on average, all direct care professionals were paid a wage that is equal to at least the greater of either 117.6% of the District minimum wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1003">§ 32-1003</cite> or 117.6% of the District living wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2|X-A">subchapter X-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>During Fiscal Year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter, a direct care service provider reimbursed by the District at a rate established pursuant to this act shall demonstrate to the Mayor that it paid its direct care professionals a wage that, on average, is equal to at least the greater of either 117.6% of the District minimum wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1003">§ 32-1003</cite> or 117.6% of the District living wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2|X-A">subchapter X-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2</cite> in the service provider's operating budget cycle, inclusive of overtime wages and bonuses, to remain eligible for payment for the current year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A direct care service provider who received a supplemental payment from the District in Fiscal Year 2025 pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-2002|(a-1)">§ 4-2002(a-1)</cite> shall demonstrate to the Mayor that it paid its direct care professionals a wage that, on average, is equal to at least the greater of either 117.6% of the District minimum wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1003">§ 32-1003</cite>, or 117.6% of the District living wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2|X-A">subchapter X-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2</cite>, in the service provider's operating budget cycle, inclusive of overtime wages and bonuses.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-77" type="History" path="§5">Apr. 16, 2020, D.C. Law 23-77, § 5, 67 DCR 2535</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History" path="§5102|(e)">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 5102(e), 69 DCR 9223</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§5002|(b)">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 5002(b), 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-232" type="History" path="§4">Dec. 12, 2024, D.C. Law 25-232, § 4, 71 DCR 12970</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
