<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-2002(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Payment.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-2002">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By Fiscal Year 2026, the Mayor shall determine the reimbursement rate that the District will pay to direct care service providers for the provision of direct care services so that the reimbursement rate is sufficient to support direct care service provider payments to direct care professionals of a wage that, on average, is equal to at least the greater of either 117.6% of the District minimum wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1003">§ 32-1003</cite> or 117.6% of the District living wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2|X-A">subchapter X-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>In Fiscal Year 2025, the Mayor shall provide a supplemental payment from the Home and Community-Based Services Enhancement Fund, established pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-771.07d">§ 7-771.07d</cite>, to direct care service providers for the purpose of supporting payments to direct care professionals of a wage that, on average, is equal to at least the greater of either 117.6% of the District minimum wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1003">§ 32-1003</cite>, or 117.6% of the District living wage pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2|X-A">subchapter X-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In determining the reimbursement rate to be provided to an eligible direct care service provider under this section, the Mayor shall consider:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If applicable, the then-current reimbursement rates paid by the District to direct care service providers under the District of Columbia Medicaid State Plan or waivers thereof;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The total cost, including wages, that the direct care service provider incurred during the previous year in providing direct care services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The additional operating support that the direct care service provider may need to allow it to pay its direct care professionals in accordance with the requirements of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any other factor the Mayor considers relevant to the determination of the reimbursement rate.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-77" type="History" path="§3">Apr. 16, 2020, D.C. Law 23-77, § 3, 67 DCR 2535</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History" path="§5102|(b)">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 5102(b), 69 DCR 9223</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§5002|(a)">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 5002(a), 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-232" type="History" path="§4">Dec. 12, 2024, D.C. Law 25-232, § 4, 71 DCR 12970</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
