<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-205.19f(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Sanctions.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-205.19f">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall not consider an applicant or recipient to have complied with program requirements until the individual participates satisfactorily for at least one week.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, if the Mayor cannot schedule the applicant or recipient for participation, by no fault of the applicant or recipient, the Mayor shall consider the applicant or recipient to have complied on the day the applicant or recipient notifies the Mayor that he or she agrees to participate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a sanction terminates because the TANF applicant or recipient complies with program requirements, the applicant or recipient shall not receive TANF benefits for the remainder of the month of compliance, and instead shall begin receiving TANF benefits again in the following month, for the following month, and for subsequent months so long as the recipient continues to comply and remains otherwise eligible.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A TANF applicant or recipient who is aggrieved by the Mayor’s action concerning a sanction may seek redress under <cite path="4|2|X">subchapter X of this chapter</cite>. A TANF applicant or recipient who has been sanctioned shall not be entitled to a conciliation process.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If a TANF recipient fails to complete his or her annual review or is otherwise terminated while under sanctions, and makes a new application for benefits, the TANF applicant shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Undergo an assessment and orientation pursuant to <cite path="§4-205.19|(b)">§ 4-205.19(b)</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shall remain under the same level of sanction until in compliance pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, an assistance unit's TANF benefits shall consist of the following portions:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>80% is designated for the child or children of the assistance unit; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>20% is designated for the adult member or members of the assistance unit.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No sanction under this title, or regulations implementing this title, shall reduce the portion of an assistant unit's TANF benefits that is designated for the child or children of the assistance unit.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Department of Human Services shall impose a 30% reduction of the portion of the assistance unit's TANF benefits designated for the adult member or members of the assistance unit when a TANF recipient is found to be in noncompliance with this title, or regulations implementing this title.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History" path="§519f">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 519f</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-241" type="History">as added Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 2(w), 46 DCR 905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 522(d), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" type="History" path="§5002|(d)">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 22-33, § 5002(d), 64 DCR 7652</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 522(e) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see note to <cite path="§4-205.19a">§ 4-205.19a</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(w) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-130">D.C. Law 12-130</cite>, July 24, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 6501).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(i) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-130">D.C. Law 12-130</cite>, July 24, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 6501).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(i) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-7">D.C. Law 12-7</cite>, August 1, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 4639).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> repealed subsec. (a); and added subsec. (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-205.19f.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§4-205.19a">§ 4-205.19a</cite>, <cite path="§4-205.19b">§ 4-205.19b</cite>, <cite path="§4-205.19c">§ 4-205.19c</cite>, and <cite path="§4-205.19e">§ 4-205.19e</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
