<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-410.02(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Payments to child development facilities for infants and toddlers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>OSSE shall establish payment rates for child development facilities providing care for infants and toddlers. The rate of payment shall be sufficient to provide a child development center and child development home with funding to operate based on a cost modeling analysis that incorporates costs incurred as a result of implementing the salary scale and schedule developed by OSSE pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-410.01|(b)">section 11a(b)</code-cite>. Subject to appropriations, the cost of care and teacher salary scale shall be increased as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By October 1, 2019, $4,298,064 of the projected fiscal impact of the full cost of care and teacher salary scale;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>
               By October 1, 2020, at least 25% of the projected fiscal impact of the full cost of care and teacher salary scale;
              </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>
               By October 1, 2021, at least 50% of the projected fiscal impact of the full cost of care and teacher salary scale;
              </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>
               By October 1, 2022, at least 75% of the projected fiscal impact of the full cost of care and teacher salary scale;
              </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>
               By October 1, 2023, and on an annual basis thereafter, OSSE shall reimburse providers at the cost of care as determined by its most recent cost modeling analysis; and
              </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>By October 1, 2024, and on a triennial basis thereafter, OSSE shall revise the payment rates based on the updated cost of care and teacher salary scale developed pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-410.01|(b)">section 11a(b)</code-cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Child development facilities receiving payments under <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="4|4">this act</code-cite> shall, at a minimum, compensate teaching assistants and lead teachers according to the salary scale and implementation schedule  developed pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-410.01|(b)">section 11a(b)</code-cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-16" type="History" path="§11b">Sept. 19, 1979, D.C. Law 3-16, § 11b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-179" type="History" path="§201|(d)">as added Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-179, § 201(d), 65 DCR 9569</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" type="History" path="§5143">Sept. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 23-16, § 5143, 66 DCR 8621</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History" path="§4073|(e)">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 4073(e), 69 DCR 9223</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
