<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-681.03(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Child Trust Fund Program.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is established a Child Trust Fund Program, which shall be administered by the Chief Financial Officer, under which an annual deposit amount from the Fund shall be designated to the child trust fund account for each eligible child enrolled in the CTF Program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>To meet the eligibility requirements for the CTF Program, the Chief Financial Officer, with parental consent, shall use the Medicaid participant information received annually from the Department of Human Services, or the Department of Health Care Finance, whichever applies (collectively "agencies") to determine if the household qualifies as an applicable family household.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Chief Financial Officer, or the designee, or employees of the Chief Financial Officer, or employees of the designee, shall not disclose information with respect to a child trust fund account maintained in the Fund; except that child trust fund account information may be disclosed, pursuant to rule, to the beneficiary of the child trust fund account or to another person at the beneficiary's request.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Upon enrollment, an amount of $500 shall be designated to the child trust fund account for the eligible child enrolled in the CTF Program.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>By October 1 of the subsequent year, the deposit amount designated to the child trust fund account for each eligible child enrolled in the CTF Program shall be as follows:</text>
        <text>
          <table>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Household's Federal Poverty Level (FPL)</th>
                <th>Annual Deposit Amount</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>0% to 100% FPL</td>
                <td>$1,000</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>101% to 200% FPL</td>
                <td>$800</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>201% to 300% FPL</td>
                <td>$600</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
        </text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>On October 1 of each successive year, the maximum annual deposit amount provided pursuant to this subsection shall increase in proportion to the annual average increase, if any, in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers, Washington-Baltimore Metropolitan area published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States Department of Labor for the previous calendar year; provided, that the Chief Financial Officer certifies that funds are sufficient.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If a household is no longer enrolled in the DC Medicaid program or if the household's income increases above the federal poverty guideline, the annual deposit amounts shall cease but the amounts credited to the eligible child's trust fund account during the period of deposits shall remain available for distribution pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง4-681.06">section 7</code-cite>.</text>
    </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-53" path="ยง4" type="History">Feb. 18, 2022, D.C. Law 24-53, ยง 4, 68 DCR 13227</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
