<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-681.01(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-681.01">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="4|6D">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Age of majority" means 18 years of age.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Applicable family household" means a household income that is 300% of the federal poverty guidelines or below and enrolled in DC Medicaid.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term "family household" means one or more persons, all of whom are, related by marriage, birth, or adoption.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Chief Financial Officer" means the head of the Office of the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia, established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.24a">§ 1-204.24a</cite>, or the designee of the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"CTF Program" means the Child Trust Fund Program established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-681.03">§ 4-681.03</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"DC Medicaid" means a joint federal/state Medicaid health insurance program that provides health care coverage to low-income and disabled individuals and families who are residents of the District and meet non-financial and financial eligibility requirements.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Disability certification" means a written certification, determined to be satisfactory by the Chief Financial Officer or rules issued pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="4|6B">this chapter</cite>, of a diagnosis from a licensed doctor and signed by a licensed physician that the eligible child has a medically determinable physical or mental impairment that results in marked and severe functional limitations lasting for a continuous 12 months or longer or that can be expected to result in death.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Eligible child" means an individual who:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Was born on or after October 1, 2021, whose birth was subject to medical coverage provided under DC Medicaid;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Is and remains a resident of the District; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Has a valid, unique, social security number, or other acceptable identification.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), the term "resident" means an eligible child that has been domiciled in the District for at least 16 years prior to the age of majority and who is continuously domiciled in the District for the 12 months immediately before reaching the age of majority.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this subparagraph "domiciled" means having a continuous physical presence in the District and that the District is the individual's fixed, permanent home.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Enrollee" means an eligible child participating in the Child Trust Fund Program who meets the requirements set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-681.06">§ 4-681.06</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Federal poverty guidelines" means the measure of income, based on the number of persons in a household, issued every year by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services used to determine financial eligibility for certain federal programs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Fund" means the Child Trust Fund established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-681.02">§ 4-681.02</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Home Rule Act" means<cite doc="D.C. Code" path="1|2"> Chapter 2 of Title 1</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Medicaid" means the medical assistance programs authorized by title XIX of the Social Security Act, approved July 30,1965 (79 Stat. 343; 42 U.S.C. § 1396 <em>et seq</em>.), or by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-307.02">§ 1-307.02</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-53" type="History" path="§2">Feb. 18, 2022, D.C. Law 24-53, § 2, 68 DCR 13227</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-323" type="History" path="§2|(a)">Mar. 10, 2023, D.C. Law 24-323, § 2(a), 70 DCR 869</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
