<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-754.36b(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Program exits.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current. To see the current law, click this link <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.36b">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A provider may exit a client from a housing program only when:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The housing program is provided on a time-limited basis, and the client's time period for receiving services has run;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Mayor determines that the client cannot be recertified to continue receiving services; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The client was assigned to the provider for substantially all of the client's time in the housing program; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-753.02|(b-1)">§ 4-753.02(b-1)</code-cite>, the Mayor determines that the client is no longer eligible for the services.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A provider exiting a client from a program shall provide the client oral and written notice of the program exit at least 30 days before the effective date of the program exit.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Written notice issued pursuant to this subsection shall conform to the requirements of notice issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.33|(d)">§ 4-754.33(d)</code-cite>.".</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any client who requests a fair hearing within 15 days of receipt of notice of a program exit shall continue to remain in the housing program pending a final decision from the fair hearing proceedings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A program exit is not considered a termination of services pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.36">§ 4-754.36</code-cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History" path="§22b">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 22b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-65" path="§2|(aa)" type="History">as added Feb. 28. 2018, D.C. Law 22-65, § 2(aa), 65 DCR 331</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
