<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-951.09(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Budget.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board shall submit its proposed fiscal year 2011 operating budget and each subsequent operating budget for the Corporation to the Mayor on the date that District departments and agencies are required to submit proposed budgets to the Mayor. Prior to submission to the Mayor, the proposed operating budget must be certified by the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia as being balanced.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If any of the conditions set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§44-951.04|(l)">section 5115(l)</code-cite> has been met<span codify:value=",">,,</span> the Fiscal Management Board shall meet no later than 30 days thereafter and approve an operating budget that supports the following services:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An emergency department;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Behavioral health (psychiatric) services; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The inpatient, outpatient, and support services necessary to provide services pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph, appropriately scaled to require a District operating subsidy equal to or less than $22.14 million in Fiscal Year 2020 or equal to or less than $15 million per year thereafter.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No later than 15 days after the approval by the Fiscal Management Board of an operating budget pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia shall determine whether the budget approved by the Financial Management Board can be certified as meeting the requirements set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The following requirements shall govern any reduction-in-force ("RIF") necessitated by an operating budget adopted pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Before implementing a RIF, the United Medical Center shall provide 30 days' notice to the affected unions.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In structuring a RIF, the Financial Management Board shall make utmost efforts to ensure that front-line care givers and support staff are affected the least and that all reductions comply with any existing collective bargaining agreement.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History" path="§5120">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 5120, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
     <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" type="History" path="§5092|(b)">Sept. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 23-16, § 5092(b), 66 DCR 8621</annotation>
     <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-147" type="History" path="§107|(g)">July 12, 2022, D.C. Law 24-147, § 107(g), 69 DCR 003386</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
