<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-368.07(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Workforce Investments account.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง47-368.07">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Workforce Investments account ("Account") shall be administered by the Mayor in accordance with subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Money in the Account shall be used for the following purposes only:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Costs related to financial, developmental, and other investments in the District government workforce, including salary increases or other items required by the terms of collective bargaining agreements and cost-of-living adjustments to salaries and hourly wages;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Payments to public charter schools authorized by section 204 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Clarification Amendment Act of 2018, passed on 2nd reading on April 10, 2018 (Enrolled version of Bill 22-466); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For such other expressed purposes for which funds previously may have been deposited into the account.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Account shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Account shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-124" type="History">July 3, 2018, D.C. Law 22-124, ยง 202, 65 DCR 5091</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
