<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-869(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Performing arts venue real property tax rebate.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2018, a qualified business that leases real property that is taxed under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|8">this chapter</cite> or under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|10">Chapter 10 of this title</cite> shall receive a rebate of that portion of the tax, if any, that represents the qualified business' pro rata share of the lessor's tax on the property if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The qualified business is liable under the lease for the pro rata share of the tax;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The qualified business applies for the rebate of the tax on or before September 15; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The real property tax was paid.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The application shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A copy of the lease with the lessor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Documentation that the real property tax has been paid; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Documentation that the qualified business met the requirements of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง47-802|(17)">ยง 47-802(17)</cite> during the tax year for which the rebate is being requested.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a proper application has been submitted, the Chief Financial Officer shall rebate the real property tax on or before December 31 of the same calendar year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The rebate provided pursuant to this section shall be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The lesser of the qualified business' pro rata share of the real property tax that was paid, directly or indirectly, by the qualified business or $15,000 per applicant per year; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax, financial, or development incentive, tax credit, or any other type of incentive provided to a qualified business under any District or federal program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-297" type="History">Apr. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 22-297, ยง 2(c), 66 DCR 2014</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
