<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-870(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Central Washington activation projects— temporary tax abatement – Definitions.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-870">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For purposes of §§ 47-870 through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-870.02">47-870.02</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Base year" means, for each property selected for a temporary tax abatement pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-870.01">§ 47-870.01</cite>:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Real property tax year 2025; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If the real property taxes imposed on the property increase between real property tax year 2025 and the real property tax year in which the property is certified, the real property tax year after 2025, and before the real property tax year in which the repositioning of the property is complete, in which the real property taxes imposed on the property are greatest.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Eligible area" means the Central Washington Area, as set forth in Volume 2 of the District of Columbia Office of Planning's 2021 Comprehensive Plan and the <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-40">Comprehensive Plan Amendment Act of 2021, effective August 21, 2021 (D.C. Law 24-20; 68 DCR 6918)</cite>, plus 1,750 feet linear feet in any direction beyond the planning area boundaries.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Repositioning" means a construction, reconstruction, alteration, or renovation to a property with a minimum of 50,000 square feet that results in the conversion of the property from a primarily office use to a use that is not residential or in an upgrade in the class of the office space to class A or higher from a class below class A.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Residential" shall have the same meaning as set forth in 11-B DCMR § 200.2(aa).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 2052|(b), 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
