<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-860.01(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Tax abatements for housing in downtown – Definitions.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-860.01">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of §§ 47-860.01 through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-860.04">47-860.04</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Certified business enterprise" means a business enterprise or joint venture certified pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2|IX-A">Subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Eligible area" means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The geographic area bounded by a line starting at the intersection of the center line of Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., and the center of Dupont Circle, N.W.; continuing southeast along the center line of Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., to the center line of North Capitol Street, N.W.; continuing south along the center line of North Capitol Street, N.W., to the center line of Constitution Avenue, N.W.; continuing west along the center line of Constitution Avenue, N.W., to the center line of 15th Street, N.W.; continuing north along the center line of 15th Street, N.W. to the center line of Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W.; continuing west along the center line of Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W., to the center of Washington Circle, N.W.; continuing northeast along the center line of New Hampshire Avenue N.W., to, and terminating at, the intersection of the center line of Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., and the center of Dupont Circle, N.W. (the starting point); and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any other portion of the central business district designated by the Mayor.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"First Source Agreement" means an agreement with the District government governing certain obligations pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-219.03">§ 2-219.03</cite> and Mayor's Order 83-265, dated November 9, 1983, regarding job creation and employment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Inclusionary Zoning Program" means the provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="6|10|II-A">Subchapter II-A of Chapter 10 of Title 6</cite> ("Inclusionary Zoning Act"), and Chapter 10 of Title 11-C of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (11-C DCMR § 1000.1 <em>et seq.</em>), and the regulations and administrative issuances promulgated under the Inclusionary Zoning Act.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Median family income" has the meaning set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-1041.01|(5)">§ 6-1041.01(5)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 7082(b), 69 DCR 9223</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
