<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-110.01(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current. To see the current law, click this link <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง50-110.01">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|1A">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Contact information" means the legal name, website, business address, and telephone number.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Crosswalk" means the part of a roadway at an intersection included within the lateral lines connecting sidewalks on opposite sides of the roadway.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Department" means the District Department of Transportation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Director" means the Director of the Department.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Eligible entity" means a corporation, partnership, association, firm, sole proprietorship, or other entity engaged in business.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Hazardous materials" means substances or materials in a quantity and form that may pose an unreasonable risk to health, safety, or property when transported in commerce.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The term "hazardous materials" includes explosives, radioactive materials, etiological agents, flammable liquids or solids, combustible liquids or solids, poisons, oxidizing or corrosive materials, or compressed gases.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Operator" means an agent of a permit holder who exercises direct physical control over, or monitoring of, the operation of a PDD.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"PDD" means an electronically powered device that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is intended to transport property on sidewalks and crosswalks;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Weighs less than 90 pounds, excluding any property being carried by the PDD;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Has a maximum speed of 10 miles per hour; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Is capable of operating both with and without the direct control of the operator.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Pedestrian" means any person afoot or who is using a wheelchair.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Permit holder" means an eligible entity that has received a permit from the Department, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|1A">this chapter</cite>, authorizing the operation of a PDD.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Traffic" includes motor vehicles, motorcycles, personal mobility device, pedestrians, bicyclists, and animals.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-137" type="History" path="ยง2">July 17, 2018, D.C. Law 22-137, ยง 2, 65 DCR 5959</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
