<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1731.04(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Restricted use of mobile telephone and other electronic devices.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1731.04">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No person shall use a mobile telephone or other electronic device while operating a moving motor vehicle in the District of Columbia unless the telephone or device is equipped with a hands-free accessory.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Emergency use of a mobile telephone, including calls to 911 or 311, a hospital, an ambulance service provider, a fire department, a law enforcement agency, or a first-aid squad;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Use of a mobile telephone by law enforcement and emergency personnel or by a driver of an authorized emergency vehicle, acting within the scope of official duties; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Initiating or terminating a telephone call, or turning the telephone on or off.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>No person shall use headphones that cover both ears or earbuds in both ears while operating a motor vehicle in the District, except if the headphones or earbuds are being used to assist a hearing-impaired driver.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-124" type="History" path="§4">Mar. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-124, § 4, 51 DCR 1541</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-158" type="History" path="§6|(a)">Dec. 23, 2020, D.C. Law 23-158, § 6(a), 67 DCR 13057</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§50-1731.05">§ 50-1731.05</cite> and <cite path="§50-1731.06">§ 50-1731.06</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
