<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-110.03(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Operation of a personal delivery device.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current. To see the current law, click this link <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง50-110.03">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A permit holder may operate a PDD that complies with <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|1A">this chapter</cite> on sidewalks and crosswalks in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To operate in the District, a PDD shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Obey all traffic control devices and signs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Operate in a safe and non-hazardous manner that does not endanger traffic or property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Not unreasonably interfere with traffic;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Not transport any hazardous materials or waste; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Clearly and conspicuously display the contact information of the permit holder operating the PDD.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A PDD shall have the same obligations and rights-of-way as a pedestrian under similar circumstances, except that a PDD shall yield the right-of-way to traffic.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other law, a PDD shall not constitute a vehicle or motor vehicle for any purpose.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a technology failure or loss of communication occurs during the operation of a PDD, the PDD shall alert the operator and, if the PDD operator is unable to assume direct control of the device, come to an off-roadway stop.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a PDD comes to an off-roadway stop under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the owner of the PDD shall promptly remove the PDD.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-137" type="History" path="ยง4">July 17, 2018, D.C. Law 22-137, ยง 4, 65 DCR 5959</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
