<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1501.03(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Fees classified and use of proceeds designated.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.03">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>There shall be levied, collected, and paid for each registration year for each motor vehicle or trailer required to be registered under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|15|I">this subchapter</cite>, the registration fee provided in this section, except that in the event the Council of the District of Columbia prescribes and the Mayor of the District of Columbia issues as the official identification tags for the District of Columbia tags treated with special reflective materials designed to increase the visibility and legibility of such tags, the Council may charge a fee not exceeding $.50 in addition to all other fees which may be required.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a tag with special markings unique to that person shall pay a one-time application fee of $100, and may obtain a replacement if a tag is lost or stolen upon payment of a fee of $25 per tag.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any person displaying a tag already approved for use by a member of an organization other than Disabled American Veterans shall pay a one-time application fee of $100, and may obtain a replacement if a tag is lost or stolen upon payment of a $25 fee per tag.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering Anacostia River Commemorative License Plates shall pay the fees as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-102.07|(b)">§ 8-102.07(b)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering veterans identification tags pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02a">§ 50-1501.02a</cite> shall pay the fees as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02a|(b)|(2)">§ 50-1501.02a(b)(2)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a women veterans identification tags pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02b">§ 50-1501.02b</cite> shall pay the fees as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02b|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02b(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering bicycle awareness identification tags shall pay the fees as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02c|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02c(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a "We Demand Statehood" identification tag designed and made available pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02d|(a)">§ 50-1501.02d(a)</cite> shall pay the fees established pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02d|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02d(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering an arts and humanities motor-vehicle identification tag issued pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02e|(a)">§ 50-1501.02e(a)</cite> shall pay the fees established pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02e|(b)">§ 50-1501.02e(b)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a breast cancer awareness identification tag shall pay the fees as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02f|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02f(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a parks and recreation identification tag shall pay the fees as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02g|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02g(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(L)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a Washington Capitals identification tag shall pay the fees as set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02h|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02h(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(M)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a Washington Mystics identification tag shall pay the fees set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02i|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02i(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(N)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a Washington Nationals identification tag shall pay the fees set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02j|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02j(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(O)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering an End Gun Violence identification tag shall pay the fees set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02k|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02k(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(P)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a Protect Local Wildlife identification tag shall pay the fees set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02l|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02l(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(Q)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a Washington Wizards identification tag shall pay the fees set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02m|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02m(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(R)</num>
        <text>Any person ordering a LGBTQ Pride motor vehicle identification tag shall pay the fees set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02n|(b)|(1)">§ 50-1501.02n(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Class A. — For each passenger vehicle, including a motor vehicle classified by the Mayor or his or her designated agent as a class F(I) historic motor vehicle that meets the criteria established under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.01|(10A)">§ 50-1501.01(10A)</cite>, except for passenger vehicles licensed under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2829">§ 47-2829</cite>, based upon the manufacturer's shipping weight, as follows:</text>
        <text>
          <table>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td colspan="2">Weight Class Registration Fee</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class I (3,499 pounds or less)</td>
                <td>$72</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class II (3,500 — 4,999 pounds)</td>
                <td>$175</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class III (5,000 — 5,999 pounds)</td>
                <td>$250</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class IV (6,000 or greater)</td>
                <td>$500</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class V (A new electric vehicle, other than a motorcycle and motorized bicycle, less than 5,000 pounds.) (This provision shall only apply to the first 2 years of the vehicle's registration, after which the vehicle shall be treated as Class I or Class II, whichever is applicable.)</td>
                <td>$36</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class VI (vehicles 3,500 pounds or greater that have been issued a disability license tag by the Department of Motor Vehicles pursuant to 18 DCMR § 2704, if the vehicle weight above 3,499 pounds is due to the accommodation of a disability)</td>
                <td>$72</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
        </text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>As of October 1, 2023, an electric vehicle with a manufacturer's shipping weight less than 5,000 pounds may subtract 1,000 pounds from its manufacturer's shipping weight for the purposes of this paragraph.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Class IV shall only apply after September 30, 2023.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Class VI shall only apply after September 30, 2023.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Class B. — For each commercial vehicle, tractor, and passenger carrying vehicle for hire, including vehicles licensed under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2829">§ 47-2829</cite>, based upon the manufacturer's shipping weight, as follows:</text>
        <text>
          <table>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td colspan="2">Weight Class Registration Fee</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class I (3,499 pounds or less)</td>
                <td>$125</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class II (3,500 — 4,499 pounds)</td>
                <td>$175</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class III (5,000 — 6,999 pounds)</td>
                <td>$250</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class IV (7,000 — 9,999</td>
                <td>$500</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>Class V (10,000 pounds or greater)</td>
                <td>$700 plus $50 per each additional 1,000 pounds over 10,000 pounds</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
        </text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>As of October 1, 2023, an electric vehicle may subtract 1,000 pounds from its actual weight for the purposes of this paragraph.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Class C. — For each trailer, based upon the manufacturer's shipping weight, as follows:</text>
      <text>
        <table>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td colspan="2">Weight Class Registration Fee</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Class I (1,499 pounds or less)</td>
              <td>$50</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Class II (1,500 — 3,499 pounds)</td>
              <td>$150</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Class III (3,500 — 4,999 pounds)</td>
              <td>$275</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Class IV (5,000 — 6,999 pounds)</td>
              <td>$500</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Class V (7,000 — 9,999 pounds)</td>
              <td>$700</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Class VI (10,000 pounds or greater)</td>
              <td>$850 plus $75 per each additional 1,000 pounds over 10,000 pounds</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Class D. — For each motorcycle, $52.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Class E. — For each motor-driven cycle, $30.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Class F. — For each motor vehicle classified by the Mayor or his or her designated agent as a class F(II) historic motor vehicle which meets the criteria established under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.01|(11)">§ 50-1501.01(11)</cite>, $25.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Class G. — For dealer's identification tags, dealer transport identification tags, and manufacturer identification tags, per tag, $75.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Class H. — For each motor vehicle propelled by fuel not subject to taxation under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|23">Chapter 23 of Title 47</cite>, and motor vehicles propelled by any means other than motor fuels as defined in said chapter, double the fees provided in this subsection for classes A through D.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>Non-resident taxi and limousine driver vehicle registration. — In addition to any fees that may be due under any other statute or regulation, a driver who was exempted from the residency requirements to register a vehicle within the District of Columbia under<cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02|(c)|(5)|(B)"> § 50-1501.02(c)(5)(B)</cite> shall be charged an additional fee of $100.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may prorate the fee for registration by an owner or dealer if the registration is issued by the Mayor for a period not to exceed 23 months.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The proceeds from fees payable under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|15">this chapter</cite> shall be paid into the General Fund of the District of Columbia as established by <cite doc="D.C. Law 1-42" codify:value="the Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975">the Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975, effective January 22, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-42; 22 DCR 6318)</cite>; provided, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The fees collected under subsection (b-1) of this section shall be paid into the Out-of-State Vehicle Registration Special Fund established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.03a">§ 50-1501.03a</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for Anacostia River Commemorative License Plates shall be deposited in the Anacostia River Clean Up and Protection Fund established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-102.05|(a)">§ 8-102.05(a)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for veterans' motor vehicle identification tags under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02a">§ 50-1501.02a</cite> shall be deposited in the Office of Veterans Affairs Fund established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§49-1004">§ 49-1004</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for women veteran identification tags shall be deposited in the Office of Veterans Affairs Fund, established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§49-1004">§ 49-1004</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for bicycle awareness identification tags shall be deposited in the Vision Zero Pedestrian and Bicycle Safety Fund, established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.20">§ 50-921.20</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for "We Demand Statehood" identification tags shall be deposited in the New Columbia Statehood Fund, established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-129.32">§ 1-129.32</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for arts and humanities motor-vehicle identification tags shall be deposited into the Arts and Humanities Enterprise Fund, established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-205.01">§ 39-205.01</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for breast cancer awareness identification tags under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02f">§ 50-1501.02f</cite> shall be deposited in the Community Health Care Financing Fund, established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1931">§ 7-1931</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for parks and recreation identification tags under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02g">§ 50-1501.02g</cite> shall be deposited into the Recreation Enterprise Fund, established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-303">§ 10-303</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for the Washington Capitals identification tags under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02h">§ 50-1501.02h</cite> shall be deposited into the General Fund of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for the Washington Mystics identification tags under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02i">§ 50-1501.02i</cite> shall be deposited into the General Fund of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for the Washington Nationals identification tags under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02j">§ 50-1501.02j</cite> shall be deposited into the General Fund of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for the End Gun Violence identification tags under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02k">§ 50-1501.02k</cite> shall be deposited in the Neighborhood Safety and Engagement Fund, established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2413">§ 7-2413</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for the Protect Local Wildlife identification tags under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-102.05">§ 8-102.05</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for the Washington Wizard identification tags under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.02m">§ 50-1501.02m</cite> shall be deposited into the General Fund of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>The fees collected for the LGBTQ Pride motor vehicle identification tag under § 50-1501.02n shall be deposited into the Office of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Questioning Affairs Fund, established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1385">§ 2-1385</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|15|I">this subchapter</cite>, special equipment mounted on a motor vehicle or trailer and not used primarily for the transportation of persons or property shall be taxed as tangible personal property as provided by law. For the purpose of determining the fees authorized by subparagraph (A) of subsection (b)(2) and subsections (b)(3) and (b)(8) of this section, the weight of special equipment taxed in accordance with the provisions of this subsection (e) shall be excluded in computing the weight of the vehicle or trailer on which it is mounted.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>No annual motor vehicle registration fee shall be required for a noncommercial motor vehicle owned by any veteran who has been classified by the United States Veterans Administration as having a total and permanent disability as a result of a service incurred or aggravated condition; provided, that no more than 1 such vehicle per qualified veteran shall receive this fee exemption.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall direct the Director of the Department of Transportation to design and provide application forms for the exemption provided in subsection (f) of this section. The application shall be accompanied by a statement that the veteran has been classified as having a total and permanent disability by the Veterans Administration so as to meet the requirements of this subsection, and that such disability is the result of a service incurred or aggravated condition.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>To synchronize inspection and registration due dates, the Mayor may declare that a vehicle's inspection or registration shall expire prior to the date originally established; provided, that the Mayor shall reduce the fee for the vehicle's next registration or inspection renewal by a percentage equal to the percentage of the reduction of the original time period.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may require a 2 year registration period for any registrant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may refund any portion of the registration fee if the registrant does not maintain the registration for the entire registration period established.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may allow any person to pay registration fees in installments, as determined by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may charge an additional fine of $100 for any motor vehicle whose inspection or registration is not renewed by the expiration date, unless the owner surrenders the tags on or before that date.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 75-1-ch690" path="§3">Aug. 17, 1937, 50 Stat. 681, ch. 690, title IV, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 16, 1938, 52 Stat. 359, ch. 223, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 17, 1939, 53 Stat. 1046, ch. 313, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Sept. 8, 1950, 64 Stat. 793, ch. 921, §§ 4, 5, 6</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 18, 1954, 68 Stat. 112, title VI, ch. 218, §§ 602, 603, 604</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-273" type="History">Sept. 2, 1957, 71 Stat. 598, Pub. L. 85-273, §§ 1, 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 86-716" type="History">Sept. 6, 1960, 74 Stat. 816, Pub. L. 86-716, §§ 1-3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-106" type="History">Oct. 31, 1969, 83 Stat. 174, Pub. L. 91-106, title IV, § 402</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-23" type="History">Oct. 21, 1975, D.C. Law 1-23, title I, § 101, 22 DCR 2091</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-42" type="History">Jan. 22, 1976, D.C. Law 1-42, § 6, 22 DCR 6317</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-70" type="History">June 15, 1976, D.C. Law 1-70, title I, § 101, 23 DCR 533</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-110" type="History">April 7, 1977, D.C. Law 1-110, § 5, 23 DCR 8740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-124" type="History">April 19, 1977, D.C. Law 1-124, title I, § 101, 23 DCR 8749</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-41" type="History">Feb. 25, 1978, D.C. Law 2-41, § 2, 24 DCR 3629</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-55" type="History">Mar. 16, 1978, D.C. Law 2-55, §§ 2, 3, 5, 24 DCR 5424</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-60" type="History">Mar. 16, 1978, D.C. Law 2-60, § 2, 24 DCR 5778</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-93" type="History">Apr. 3, 1982, D.C. Law 4-93, § 3, 29 DCR 749</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-206" type="History">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-206, § 4, 30 DCR 193</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-14" type="History">June 22, 1983, D.C. Law 5-14, § 802, 30 DCR 2632</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-30" type="History">Aug. 17, 1991, D.C. Law 9-30, § 2(b), 38 DCR 4215</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-239" type="History">Mar. 17, 1993, D.C. Law 9-239, § 2, 40 DCR 625</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-307" type="History">June 5, 2003, D.C. Law 14-307, § 1705(b), 49 DCR 11664</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-307" type="History">Apr. 8, 2005, D.C. Law 15-307, §§ 401(b), 501, 52 DCR 1700</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-129" type="History">June 16, 2006, D.C. Law 16-129, § 3, 53 DCR 4716</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-279" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-279, § 403(b), 54 DCR 903</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 78, 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-130" type="History">Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-130, § 2(b), 55 DCR 1655</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-219" type="History">Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 6007, 55 DCR 7598</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-315" type="History">Mar. 20, 2009, D.C. Law 17-315, § 2(b), 56 DCR 203</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-55" type="History">Sept. 23, 2009, D.C. Law 18-55, § 9(b)(1), 56 DCR 5703</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-309" type="History">Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-309, § 2(b), 57 DCR 12389</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-290" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-290, § 6(b), 60 DCR 2343</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-212" type="History" path="§2|(b)">Feb. 18, 2017, D.C. Law 21-212, § 2(b), 63 DCR 15326</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-279" type="History" path="§2|(e)">Apr. 15, 2017, D.C. Law 21-279, § 2(e), 64 DCR 966</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History" path="§2072|(b)">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, § 2072(b), 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-185" type="History" path="§2|(c)">Nov. 27, 2018, D.C. Law 22-185, § 2(c), 65 DCR 11404</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-234" type="History" path="§2|(b)">Mar. 16, 2021, D.C. Law 23-234, § 2(b), 68 DCR 1133</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" type="History" path="§6152|(b)">Nov. 13, 2021, D.C. Law 24-45, § 6152(b), 68 DCR 10163</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History" path="§6062">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 6062, 69 DCR 9223</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-44" type="History" path="§2|(b)">Aug. 24, 2023, D.C. Law 25-44, § 2(b), 70 DCR 9695</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-45" type="History" path="§3|(b)">Aug. 24, 2023, D.C. Law 25-45, § 3(b), 70 DCR 9697</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" type="History" path="§6032">Sept. 6, 2023, D.C. Law 25-50, § 6032, 70 DCR 10366</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-309">D.C. Law 18-309</cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Applicability: This act shall apply 6 months after its effective date.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975, referred to in (d), is the Act of January 22, 1976, <cite doc="D.C. Law 1-42">D.C. Law 1-42</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see §§ 2(c) and 4 of Non-Resident Taxi Drivers Registration Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-58, June 21, 2007,  54 DCR 6599).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2(b) and 4 of Non-Resident Taxi Drivers Registration Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-58, June 21, 2007,  54 DCR 6599).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Low-Emissions Motor Vehicle Tax Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-324, March 23, 2006,  53 DCR 2574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Low-Emissions Motor Vehicle Tax Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-239, December 22, 2005,  53 DCR 258).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 202(3) of Prohibition on the Reckless Operation of Recreational Motor Vehicles Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-462, June 23, 2004,  51 DCR 6750).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1705(b) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1705(b) of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1705(b) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Non-Resident Taxi Drivers Registration Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-29">D.C. Law 17-29</cite>, October 18, 2007, law notification  54 DCR 10699).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Low-Emissions Motor Vehicle Tax Exemption Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-88">D.C. Law 16-88</cite>, April 4, 2006, law notification  53 DCR 3347).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 106(b) of Omnibus Budget Support Temporary Act of 1991 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 9-19">D.C. Law 9-19</cite>, June 21, 1991, law notification  38 DCR 5786).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-290">D.C. Law 19-290</cite> substituted “motor-driven cycle” for “motorized bicycle” in (b)(5).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-307">D.C. Law 15-307</cite> added subsec. (a)(3); rewrote subsecs. (b)(1), (2), and (3); in subsec. (c), substituted “23” for “11”; and added subsecs. (h), (i), (j), and (k).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “$72” for “$55” and substituted “$115” for “$88” in par. (1)(A), and substituted “$52” for “$30” in par. (4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-103.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-104.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§8-102.07">§ 8-102.07</cite>, <cite path="§9-1111.15">§ 9-1111.15</cite>, <cite path="§50-1501.02">§ 50-1501.02</cite>, <cite path="§50-1503.01">§ 50-1503.01</cite>, and <cite path="§50-2201.03">§ 50-2201.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Taxation of personal property, exemption for motor vehicles and trailers, see <cite path="§47-1508">§ 47-1508</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">National Capital Region Transportation, revenues allocated to the Metrorail/Metrobus Account, see <cite path="§9-1111.15">§ 9-1111.15</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Multiaxle vehicles designed for auto-unloading, annual hauling permit fees, see <cite path="§6-703.01">§ 6-703.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Motor vehicle operators’ permits, fees, see <cite path="§50-1401.01">§ 50-1401.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Motor vehicle exhaust emissions inspections, collection and allocation of fees, see §§ <cite path="§50-1101">50-1101</cite> and <cite path="§50-1102">50-1102</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Motor fuel tax, see <cite path="§47-2301">§ 47-2301</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District of Columbia General Fund, see <cite path="§47-131">§ 47-131</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Department of Transportation, powers and duties, see <cite path="§50-2201.03">§ 50-2201.03</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
