<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2209.05(Perm)</num>
  <heading>ATE Reporting to Council.</heading>
   <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current. To see the current law, click this link <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2209.05">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning January 1, 2021, the District Department of Transportation, in consultation with the Department of Motor Vehicles, shall report to the Council on a semi-annual basis the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The top 15 automated traffic enforcement ("ATE") locations by value of citations generated in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The breakdown of the jurisdictions where those receiving ATE citations and with outstanding ATE citation debt have their vehicles registered;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The locations where cameras have been added in the last 6 months and the reasons why those locations were chosen; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The amount of ATE citations issued in total and by location.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Chief Financial Officer ("CFO") shall submit to the Mayor and Council monthly reports that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>State the amount of actual revenue deposited in the Fund established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-921.25">§ 50-921.25</code-cite> for the fiscal year to-date;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>State the CFO's current projections regarding revenue from fines generated from the automated traffic enforcement system, including whether revenue is projected to exceed the certified revenue included in the Fiscal Year 2024 budget and financial plan; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Describe the methodology employed by the CFO to project revenue from fines generated from the automated traffic enforcement system.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-198" type="History" path="§905">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-198, § 905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-155" type="History" path="§801">Oct. 8, 2016, D.C. Law 21-155, § 801</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§6092">as added, Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 6092, 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" type="History" path="§7023|(b)">Sept. 6, 2023, D.C. Law 25-50, § 7023(b), 70 DCR 10366</annotation>

  
  </annotations>
</section>
