<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2201.04(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Speeding and reckless driving.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2201.04">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No vehicle shall be operated at a greater rate of speed than permitted by the regulations adopted under the authority of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|22|I|A">this act</code-cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person commits the offense of reckless driving if the person drives a motor vehicle on any highway in the District:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At a speed of 20 miles per hour or more in excess of the speed limit; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In any other manner that displays a conscious disregard of the risk of causing property damage or bodily injury to any person.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person commits the offense of aggravated reckless driving if the person drives a motor vehicle on any highway in the District:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At a speed of 30 miles per hour or more above the speed limit; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At a speed of 20 miles per hour or more above the speed limit; and</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Causes bodily injury to any other person;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Collides with another motor vehicle; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Causes $1,000 or more in property damage.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person convicted of reckless driving shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For a first or second conviction of reckless driving, be fined no more than the amount set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-3571.01">section 101 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012, effective June 11, 2013 (D.C. Law 19-317; D.C. Official Code § 22-3571.01)</code-cite>, or incarcerated for no more than 90 days, or both; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a third or subsequent conviction for reckless driving within a 2-year period, be fined no more than the amount set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-3571.01">section 101 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012, effective June 11, 2013 (D.C. Law 19-317; D.C. Official Code § 22-3571.01)</code-cite>, or incarcerated for no more than one year, or both.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A person convicted of aggravated reckless driving shall be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For a first or second conviction of aggravated reckless driving, be fined no more than the amount set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-3571.01">section 101 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012, effective June 11, 2013 (D.C. Law 19-317; D.C. Official Code § 22-3571.01)</code-cite>, or incarcerated for no more than 180 days, or both; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a third or subsequent conviction for aggravated reckless driving within a 2-year period, be fined no more than the amount set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-3571.01">section 101 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012, effective June 11, 2013 (D.C. Law 19-317; D.C. Official Code § 22-3571.01)</code-cite>, or incarcerated for no more than 2 years, or both.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>When determining whether a defendant has a prior conviction for reckless driving or aggravated reckless driving, the Court shall include convictions for any offense from another state or territory of the United States which, if committed in the District of Columbia, would constitute reckless driving or aggravated reckless driving, respectively.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General may bring a civil cause of action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In personam, against any driver who is suspected of violating this section; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In rem, against any motor vehicle operated by a driver in a manner that violates this section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General shall not bring a civil cause of action as described in paragraph (1) of this subsection against any person or motor vehicle:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Regarding a violation of this section for which the fine imposed pursuant to regulations adopted under subsection (a) of this section:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Is being contested or appealed;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Is not yet due;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Has been paid by the defendant; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Is subject to a payment plan through which the defendant is making timely payments; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Who is currently serving or has completed serving the sentence imposed pursuant to subsection (d) or subsection (e) of this section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In civil actions brought pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Attorney General may seek:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Payment of any portion of the person's outstanding fines;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Reasonable attorney's fees;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>For a defendant with a driver's license issued by:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The District, the suspension or revocation of the defendant's driver's license; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Another jurisdiction, the suspension or revocation of the defendant's privilege to drive in the District; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The immobilization of the motor vehicle through booting or towing and impoundment.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If a court orders the immobilization of a motor vehicle through booting or towing and impounding pursuant to paragraph (3)(D) of this subsection, the court's order:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Shall include a procedure to have the boot removed or the motor vehicle reclaimed from impoundment that is consistent with the requirements of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|24A">Title I of the Parking Enforcement Modernization Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on December 17, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-435)</code-cite>, and District government policy; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>May state a date after which, if the order has not been complied with, the Mayor may auction or scrap the motor vehicle consistent with <span codify:value="§§">sections</span> <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2421.08" codify:value="50-2421.08">8</cite> and <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2421.10" codify:value="50-2421.10">10 of the Impoundment Act</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General may seek to enforce any final judgment in a case brought pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection in any court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General may retain outside counsel to perform any of the functions described in this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 68-2-ch443" path="§9">Mar. 3, 1925, 43 Stat. 1123, ch. 443, § 9</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 3, 1926, 44 Stat. 814, ch. 739, § 5</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 27, 1931, 46 Stat. 1427, ch. 317, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 24, 1936, 49 Stat. 1901, ch. 749</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Nov. 25, 1942, 56 Stat. 1023, ch. 642, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-104" type="History">Sept. 12, 1978, D.C. Law 2-104, § 601, 25 DCR 1275</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-145" type="History">Sept. 14, 1982, D.C. Law 4-145, § 7, 29 DCR 3138</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-289" type="History">Apr. 5, 2005, D.C. Law 15-289, § 2(c), 52 DCR 1446</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-266" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 102(c), 59 DCR 12957</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-316" type="History">June 8, 2013, D.C. Law 19-316, § 2, 60 DCR 1713</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 113(e), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-158" type="History" path="§8|(c)">Dec. 23, 2020, D.C. Law 23-158, § 8(c), 67 DCR 13057</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-161" type="History" path="§4|(c)">April 20, 2024, D.C. Law 25-161, § 4(c), 71 DCR 2248</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§6082|(c)|(3)">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 6082(c)(3), 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-325" type="History" path="§302|(d)|(2)">May 2, 2025, D.C. Law 25-325, § 302(d)(2), 72 DCR 1284</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Reckless Driving Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-75, May 23, 2013,  60 DCR 7597, 20 DCSTAT 1428).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 102(c) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013,  60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 113(e) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 102(c) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013,  60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (c), see § 102(c) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-508, October 26, 2012, 59 DCR 12774).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 102(c) of Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-429, July 30, 2012,  59 DCR 9387).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> added the subsection designated herein as (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-316">D.C. Law 19-316</cite> rewrote (b) and (c); added (b-1) and (c-1); substituted “aggravated reckless driving” for “reckless driving” in (d); and added (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite> substituted “$2,500” for “$1,000” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) Any individual violating any provision of this section where the offense constitutes reckless driving shall upon conviction for the 1st offense be fined not more than $250 or imprisoned not more than 3 months, or both; and upon conviction for the 2nd or any subsequent offense committed within 2 years from the date of any such previous offense such individual shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-289">D.C. Law 15-289</cite> rewrote subsec. (c) which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-605.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-712.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§4-501">§ 4-501</cite>, <cite path="§23-581">§ 23-581</cite>, <cite path="§50-329.05" proof="true">§ 50-329.05</cite>, <cite path="§50-2201.05b">§ 50-2201.05b</cite>, <cite path="§50-2201.27">§ 50-2201.27</cite>, and <cite path="§50-2302.02">§ 50-2302.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Traffic adjudication, violations prosecuted as criminal offenses, see <cite path="§50-2302.02">§ 50-2302.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Criminal procedure, warrantless arrests, see <cite path="§23-581">§ 23-581</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Compensation of victims of violent crime, “crime of violence,” “crime,” and “victim” defined, see <cite path="§4-501">§ 4-501</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Alcoholic beverage control, operation of trains, streetcars, and other vehicles by intoxicated persons, see <cite path="§25-1009">§ 25-1009</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 8 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-316">D.C. Law 19-316</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of June 1, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Definitions applicable: For definitions applicable in this section, see <cite path="§50-2201.02">§ 50-2201.02</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 5 of  46 Stat. 1429, ch. 317, effective Feb. 27, 1931, provided that all convictions under the Act shall be reported by the clerk of the court to the commissioners [Mayor] or their [his] designated agent.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
