<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-301.06(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Department of For-Hire Vehicles — Organization.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current. To see the current law, click this link <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-301.06">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established within the DFHV the following offices and divisions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office of the Director, which shall be responsible for the management of the DFHV, including the final approval of any rulemaking and ratemaking conducted by the ORPP. The Office of the Director shall include the Director, the General Counsel, and the Chief of Staff, with subordinate staff responsible for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Administrative support;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Human resources;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Budget and financial services;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Technology and information services;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Contracting and procurement;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Compliance with legislative directives, analysis, and opinions to ensure appropriate rulemaking and operational activities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Repealed.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G-i)</num>
        <text>Auditing public vehicle-for-hire companies and payment service providers to the extent authorized by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|3|I">this subchapter</cite>, and regulations issued pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|3|I">this subchapter</cite>, including review of vehicle records to ensure compliance with regulatory requirements, and private vehicle-for-hire companies to the extent authorized by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-301.29g|(b)">§ 50-301.29g(b)</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Providing updated facts pertaining to operations and rulemaking through various communication platforms, including press releases, testimony, speech, and the DFHV website; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Serving as a liaison between the DFHV and the District Department of Transportation on policies related to transportation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Not Funded.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office of Regulatory Policy and Planning, which shall be responsible for regulatory policy, and industry-wide research, analysis, and planning related to the regulation of the vehicle-for-hire industry. The ORPP shall be responsible for proposing ratemaking, rulemaking, and fee adjustments related to public vehicles-for-hire and submitting such proposals to the Office of the Director for final approval. The ORPP's subordinate staff shall also be responsible for analyzing industry updates, market data, and trends for the purpose of planning, assessment, and rulemaking.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Office of Client Services, which shall be responsible for communicating with and educating the public and the vehicle-for-hire industry regarding rules, standards, rates, charges, and orders issued by the DFHV. The OCS's subordinate staff shall also be responsible for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Administering all license examinations applicable to the public vehicle-for-hire industry;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Providing all training and refresher courses required by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|3|I">this subchapter</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Maintaining a system of electronic public records relating to licensed owners and operators of public vehicles-for-hire and public vehicle-for-hire companies, associations, and fleets, including:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Developing, maintaining, and keeping current a body of information relating to public vehicle-for-hire industry operations within the District, regionally, and nationwide; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Providing statistics, analyses, studies, and projections relating to matters such as revenue, operational costs, passenger carriage, profits, practices, and technologies pertaining to the public vehicle-for-hire industry;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Maintaining accurate records of in-service public vehicles-for-hire and retaining those records for a minimum of 3 years;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Communicating with the vehicle-for-hire industry and members of the public to inform them of agency procedures and regulations and solicit feedback to enhance public awareness;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Accepting applications for licenses applicable to public vehicle-for-hire operators and vehicles and issuing new licenses and renewals;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Collecting fees to recover the actual costs of producing and distributing official DFHV vehicle decals, stickers, and information placards; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Collecting any other fees authorized and collected pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="50|3|I">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Office of Compliance and Enforcement, which shall be responsible for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Repealed.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Administering and enforcing all rules, rates, charges, and orders issued by the DFHV;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Repealed.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Repealed.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Inspecting public vehicles-for-hire for compliance with safety regulations established by the DFHV and the Department of Motor Vehicles;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Performing vehicle-for-hire inspections and issuing notices of infraction; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Providing street enforcement of the rules and regulations of the DFHV through the use of vehicle inspection officers.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Office of Hearings and Conflict Resolution, which shall be responsible for conducting all hearings, adjudications, appeals, and any form of conflict resolution, including mediation. The OHCR's subordinate staff shall also receive, document, and manage all complaints lodged against the owners and operators of public and private vehicles-for-hire, including taxicabs, taxicab companies, associations, fleets, and dispatch services, for the violation of any rule, regulation, order, rate, or law applicable to the vehicle-for-hire industry, and all complaints lodged against vehicle inspection officers.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-97" type="History" path="§7">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-97, § 7, 33 DCR 703</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-109" type="History">May 10, 1988, D.C. Law 7-109, § 2(a), 35 DCR 2181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-198" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-198, § 501(b), 43 DCR 4569</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-184" type="History">Oct. 22, 2012, D.C. Law 19-184, § 2(f), 59 DCR 9431</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-124" type="History" path="§401|(f)">June 22, 2016, D.C. Law 21-124, § 401(f), 63 DCR 7076</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-224" type="History" path="§2|(b)">Feb. 22, 2019, D.C. Law 22-224, § 2(b), 66 DCR 187</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-301" type="History" path="§2|(b)">Mar. 21, 2025, D.C. Law 25-301, § 2(b), 72 DCR 742</annotation>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Orders">Designation of District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Panel on Rates and Rules and Panel on Consumer and Industry Concerns: See Mayor’s Order 97-64, April 2, 1997 ( 44 DCR 2176).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 24(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-97">D.C. Law 6-97</cite> provided that sections 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 20, 21, 22, and 23 shall take effect 1 year after March 25, 1986.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-97">D.C. Law 6-97</cite>, § 7a, concerning industry panel review of modernization regulations, see § 3(a) of the Livery Class Regulation and Ride-Sharing Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-169, September 27, 2013,  60 DCR 14736).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 501(b) of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-302, July 25, 1996,  43 DCR 4181, § 501(b) of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-429, October 29, 1996,  43 DCR 6151, and § 501(b) of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-2, February 19, 1997,  44 DCR 1590).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 501(b) of Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-226">D.C. Law 11-226</cite>, April 9, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 2584).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § 50-306.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-1706.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7007 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 7001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§50-301" proof="true">§ 50-301</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
