<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-226(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Rent Supplement Program: establishment of program and distribution of funds.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-226">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Rent Supplement Program is established to provide housing assistance to extremely low-income District residents, including those who are homeless and those in need of supportive services, such as elderly individuals or those with disabilities. The funding of this program is subject to appropriation. Rent Supplement Program assistance shall not constitute an entitlement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in this act, the Authority shall award the funds appropriated for the Rent Supplement Program's sponsor-based voucher assistance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development shall award the funds appropriated for the Rent Supplement Program's project-based voucher assistance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Authority shall award the funds appropriated for ongoing tenant-based Rent Supplement Program voucher assistance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Authority shall award the funds appropriated for new tenant-based voucher assistance, including funds transferred by the Department of Human Services to the District of Columbia Housing Authority for the purposes of providing tenant-based voucher assistance.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in District law, the Authority shall administer the Rent Supplement Program according to the same policies and procedures as the federal Housing Choice Voucher Program, including any administrative plan regulations that the Authority promulgates pursuant to federal law, as applicable. The Authority shall promulgate any additional rules, which are specific to the Rent Supplement Program and are needed to conform to District law, including the eligibility requirements in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-229.04">section 26d-4</code-cite> and the limitation to extremely low-income households. Such additional rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved. Nothing in this subsection shall be interpreted to limit the applicability of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-229.04">section 26d-4</code-cite> prior to the promulgation of such additional rules.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-105" type="History" path="§26a">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-105, § 26a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-192" type="History">as added Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-192, § 2142(b), 53 DCR 6899</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2241(a), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 2032, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" type="History">Nov. 13, 2021, D.C. Law 24-45, § 2042(b), 68 DCR 10163</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§2022|(c)">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 2022(c), 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-261" type="History" path="§2|(b)">Mar. 7, 2025, D.C. Law 25-261, § 2(b), 71 DCR 14504</annotation>
    <annotation type="Resolutions">Resolution 18-453, the “District of Columbia Housing Authority Rent Supplement Proposed Rulemaking Emergency Approval Resolution of 2010”, was approved effective April 20, 2010.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2241(a) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2241(a) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2142(b) of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-1, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1165).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2142(b) of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-499, October 23, 2006,  53 DCR 8845).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2142(b) of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-477, August 8, 2006,  53 DCR 7068).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> added subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> rewrote subsec. (b), which had read as follows: “(b) The Authority shall allocate the funds appropriated for the program annually toward project-based and sponsor-based voucher assistance, as described in <cite path="§6-227">§ 6-227</cite>, and tenant-based assistance, as described in <cite path="§6-228">§ 6-228</cite>.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§4-753.04">§ 4-753.04</cite>, <cite path="§4-756.01">§ 4-756.01</cite>, <cite path="§6-201">§ 6-201</cite>, <cite path="§6-227">§ 6-227</cite>, <cite path="§6-228">§ 6-228</cite>, <cite path="§6-229">§ 6-229</cite>, and <cite path="§42-2802">§ 42-2802</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2031 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle D of title II of the act may be cited as “Rent Supplement Prioritization and Funding Act of 2011”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2240 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle Y of title II of the act may be cited as the “Local Rent Supplement Amendment Act of 2009”.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
