<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-229.03(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Tenant-Based Rent Supplement Program quarterly reporting.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-229.03">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department of Human Services shall submit to the Council, within 30 days after the end of each fiscal quarter, a report on the Tenant-Based Rent Supplement Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each report shall include the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amount of money transferred to the Authority for each tenant-based voucher assistance program during the reporting period, listed separately by the program</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In which the household is currently participating, including the Permanent Supportive Housing, Targeted Affordable Housing program, and the Rapid Rehousing program if applicable, and categorized by individual households and family households; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To which the household is being referred, including the Permanent Supportive Housing and Targeted Affordable Housing program;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The number of households, categorized separately as individual households and family households, matched with a tenant-based voucher assistance program during the reporting quarter, listed separately by the program in which the household is participating, including the Permanent Supportive Housing and Targeted Affordable Housing program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The amount of money expended by the Department of Human Services during the reporting period on administrative costs related to the Tenant-Based Rent Supplement Program, which shall contain a breakdown by category of expense.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-105" type="History" path="§26d-3">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-105, § 26d-3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" type="History" path="§2042|(f)">as added Nov. 13, 2021, D.C. Law 24-45, § 2042(f), 68 DCR 10163</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§2022|(i)">Sept. 18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 2022(i), 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
