<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1141.06a(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Superior Court mental health urgent care clinic.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1141.06a">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Department shall:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By October 1, 2024, the Department shall contract with a non-governmental organization for the purpose of establishing and operating a mental-health urgent-care clinic in Fiscal Year 2025. The clinic shall be located within the Moultrie Courthouse, at 500 Indiana Avenue, NW, location of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To qualify, the non-governmental organization shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Have experience operating a mental health urgent care clinic within the Superior Court that provides behavioral health and substance use disorder services to individuals;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Possess no less than 2 years of experience in establishing and managing free-standing mental health clinics;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be certified by the Department to provide mental health rehabilitation services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Have previously been awarded a contract by a local, state, or federal agency to conduct mental health and substance abuse assessments and treatment, conduct housing need assessments and referrals, and deliver brief therapeutic interventions for individuals within the justice system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Possess no fewer than 3 years of experience working with individuals with behavioral health needs involved in the legal system, including the ability to collaborate with Superior Court personnel, criminal justice agencies, and community-based providers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Possess expertise in providing comprehensive mental health and substance use disorder services to diverse populations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Possess knowledge of local laws and regulations related to mental health crisis support and hospitalization; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Possess a commitment to person-centered care and evidence-based practices in mental health and substance abuse disorder treatment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The mental health urgent care clinic established by this section shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Employ an evidence-based or evidence-informed care management model that provides individualized support and referrals to resources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Ensure that one or more staff members are qualified to respond to a petition to conduct an emergency evaluation and observation when there is concern that an individual poses a significant risk to themselves or others due to a severe mental health condition. A staff member is qualified to conduct an emergency evaluation and observation if the staff member is certified by the Department as an Officer Agent or otherwise permitted by law to conduct an emergency evaluation and observation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Maintain staffing sufficient to provide services to no fewer than 600 individuals;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Conduct assessments, diagnose mental health and co-occurring disorders, and conduct substance abuse screenings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Maintain an electronic health record system that collects uniform information that meets at least the following criteria:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Maintains and keeps track of an individual's health history;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Provides a method for clinic communication and treatment planning among providers and practitioners serving individuals visiting the clinic;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Serves as a legal document describing healthcare services provided; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Serves as a source of data for the behavioral health services and outcomes that are rendered;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Provide care coordination and intervention management services for high utilizers of the District's behavioral health and justice system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Provide evaluations for juveniles who are court-ordered for emergency evaluation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Conduct housing assessments;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Provide immediate mental health clinical interventions, as required;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Coordinate with organizations certified by the Department to provide behavioral health services, if necessary; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Refer individuals to community-based treatment and resources.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History" path="§5117a">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5117a, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" type="History" path="§5152">as added Sept.18, 2024, D.C. Law 25-217, § 5152, 71 DCR 9990</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
