<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1409(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Reporting requirements.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1409">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning October 1, 2018, and on an annual basis thereafter, the Mayor shall submit a public report to the Council that shall include, for each of the last 12 months, the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees required to recertify;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees required to recertify who successfully completed recertification;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The number of DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees who did not recertify;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The number of DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees who re-enrolled in DC HealthCare Alliance within 30 days after termination and the number of enrollees who re-enrolled within 60 days after termination;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The number of DC HealthCare Alliance enrollees required to recertify who completed interviews, whether face-to-face or over the telephone, disaggregated by interview type.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The number of recertification interviews conducted at each location where interviews are offered;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The number of requests made before, or during, an interview for an accommodation due to disability, disaggregated by interview type;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The number of requests made before, or during, an interview for service in a language other than English, disaggregated by interview type; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>The number of requests for waivers of face-to-face interviews that were:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Made;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Granted; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Denied, and the grounds for denial.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within one year after October 30, 2018, the Mayor shall submit a public report to the Council that shall include, for each of the last 12 months, the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The average time enrollees waited in line at each location where interviews were offered in order to complete a face-to-face interview with an explanation of how the data was collected, with wait times measured both from the point the enrollee first checks in at the service center and from the point the enrollee gets in line outside the service center if there is a line to enter the service center; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The average time enrollees waited on the telephone before being served in order to complete interviews over the telephone.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-18" type="History" path="§7d">July 12, 2001, D.C. Law 14-18, § 7d</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-35" type="History">as added Dec. 13, 2017, D.C. Law 22-35, § 2, 64 DCR 10929</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" type="History" path="§5022">Oct. 30, 2018, D.C. Law 22-168, § 5022, 65 DCR 9388</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
