<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1671.05(Perm)</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Medical cannabis program.</heading>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevent) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.05">Current Version</cite>*
      </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a medical cannabis program, which shall regulate the cultivation, manufacture, distribution, dispensing, purchase, delivery, sale, possession, administration, and testing of medical cannabis and the manufacture, distribution, purchase, sale, possession, and use of paraphernalia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Program shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Require the registration with ABCA of all:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Qualifying patients, except qualifying patients enrolled in another jurisdiction's medical cannabis program pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.02|(c)|(2)">section 3(c)(2)</code-cite>, and the caregivers of qualifying patients; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Non-resident cardholders;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Require the licensing with ABCA of all cultivation centers, manufacturers, retailers, internet retailers, couriers, and testing laboratories, including all directors, officers, members, incorporators, agents, and employees of those facilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Create a self-certification form that may be used by qualifying patients ages 21 and older as part of the registration process, which shall contain the following statement:</text>
      <text>"I will only use cannabis purchased from a District retailer as a qualifying patient  for the treatment of a qualifying medical or dental condition or for the side effects of a qualifying or medical treatment. I understand my rights and obligations as set forth by the Medical Cannabis Program and agree to these requirements. I certify under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct.</text>
      <text>"_______________________________________________</text>
      <aftertext proof="needed">"[Signature Here]</aftertext>
      <aftertext proof="needed">"Willfully making a false statement that is in fact material, in writing, directly or indirectly, on this application is a violation of District of Columbia law and subject to criminal penalties of a fine of not more than $1,000 or imprisonment for not more than 180 days, or both. (D.C. Official Code § 22-2405).".</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>As part of the registration process, permit a non-resident qualifying patient visiting the District of Columbia to apply to ABCA to receive a temporary non-resident registration identification card, which shall be valid for 30 days; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>After the expiration of a temporary non-resident registration identification card, permit a non-resident qualifying patient to apply to ABCA to be issued another 30-day temporary non-resident identification card.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Issue nontransferable registration identification cards to persons and entities registered pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection; provided, that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>With respect to registration identification cards issued to persons and entities registered pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) and (C) of this subsection, such cards expire every 2 years:</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The cards may be presented to and used by law enforcement to confirm whether a person or entity is authorized to cultivate, manufacture, distribute, dispense, deliver, sell, possess, test, or administer medical cannabis or medical cannabis products, or manufacture, possess, deliver, purchase, sell,  distribute, or use paraphernalia; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The ABC Board may, by rule, establish license and registration periods and fees under the section that are valid for one year, 2 years, or 3 years.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Require all cultivation centers, manufacturers, retailers, internet retailers, couriers, and testing laboratories to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Maintain true, complete, and real-time electronic records of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The name, address, home telephone number, and date of birth of each employee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Each transaction conducted by the facility, including:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>The quantity of medical cannabis tested, processed, distributed, delivered, or dispensed;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>The consideration given for the medical cannabis, if any; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(III)</num>
            <text>The recipient of the medical cannabis;</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The quantity of medical cannabis or medical cannabis products at the cultivation center, manufacturer, retailer, internet retailer, or testing laboratory;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The disposal method used for any medical cannabis that was cultivated, processed, or acquired but did not meet the requirements for sale established by the ABC Board through rulemaking pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.13">section 14</code-cite> or that was not sold for any other reason, including evidence of the disposal of the medical cannabis; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Any other information required by ABCA; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Notify ABCA and the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department in writing and within 24 hours of the loss, theft, or destruction of any medical cannabis;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Require all retailers and internet retailers to maintain true, complete, and real-time electronic records of the name and address of the qualifying patient or caregiver authorized to obtain medical cannabis;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Upon the licensing of at least one testing laboratory pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, require that cultivation centers segregate all harvested medical cannabis into batches before manufacturing any medical cannabis products, or packaging dried medical cannabis for sale to a manufacturer, retailer, or internet retailer, and hold the harvested medical cannabis from sale until:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The medical cannabis has been tested by a testing laboratory;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The cultivation center has received the information required pursuant to paragraph (9) of this subsection; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The cultivation center has determined that the medical cannabis meets the requirements for sale established by the ABC Board through rulemaking;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Require testing laboratories to provide cultivation centers with the following information after testing harvested medical cannabis samples:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The concentration of tetrahydrocannabinol and cannabidiol in the testing material;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Whether the tested material is organic or inorganic;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The presence and concentration of fertilizers or other nutrients;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The presence of mold, mildew, or pests;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Whether the medical cannabis samples contain mycotoxin, pesticides, or heavy metals above a threshold determined by the ABC Board through rulemaking; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Any other information that the ABC Board may require through rulemaking;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Upon licensing of at least one testing laboratory pursuant to paragraph (2) of this section, require that manufacturers segregate all processed medical cannabis products into batches, and hold the processed medical cannabis products from sale until:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The medical cannabis products have been tested by a testing laboratory;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The manufacturer has received the information required pursuant to paragraph (11) of this subsection; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The manufacturer has determined that the medical cannabis products meet the requirements for sale established by the ABC Board through rulemaking;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Require testing laboratories to provide manufacturers with the following information after testing medical cannabis product samples:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The concentration of tetrahydrocannabinol and cannabidiol in the testing material;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Whether the tested material is organic or inorganic;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The presence and concentration of fertilizers or other nutrients;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Whether the medical cannabis product samples contain mycotoxin or residual solvents above a threshold determined by the ABC Board through rulemaking; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Any other information that the ABC Board may require through rulemaking;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Develop educational materials about:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The potential adverse drug interactions that could occur from using medical cannabis concurrently with other medical treatments;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Harm reduction strategies for qualifying patients who use medical cannabis; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The importance of informing health care providers and pharmacists of the use of medical cannabis to help avoid adverse drug interactions;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Revoke or suspend the registration or license of any person or entity if the ABC Board determines that the person or entity has violated a provision of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="7|16B">this act</code-cite> or the rules issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.13">section 14</code-cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>Conduct announced and unannounced inspections of cultivation centers, manufacturers, retailers, internet retailers, couriers, and testing laboratories;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>Establish sliding-scale registration and annual renewal fees for all persons and entities required to register or obtain a license pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="7|16B">this act</code-cite>; provided, that the licensing and annual renewal fees for cultivation centers, manufacturers, retailers, internet retailers, couriers, and testing laboratories and for the directors, officers, members, incorporators, agents, and employees of cultivation centers, manufacturers, retailers, internet retailers, couriers, and testing laboratories be sufficient to offset the cost of administering <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="7|16B">this act</code-cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>Establish a system to provide for the safe and affordable dispensing of medical cannabis to qualifying patients who are unable to afford a sufficient supply of medical cannabis based upon the qualifying patient's income and existing financial resources that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Allows qualifying patients to apply to the ABC Board to be eligible to purchase medical cannabis from retailers and internet retailers at prices set on a sliding scale based upon the qualifying patient's income and existing financial resources; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Requires each retailer and internet retailer to provide medical cannabis at prices set on the sliding scale described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, as determined by the ABC Board, to qualifying patients determined eligible pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>Establish standards by which applicants for cultivation center, manufacturer, retailer, internet retailer, courier, or testing laboratory license are evaluated for licensing or license renewal, which may include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An applicant's knowledge of District and federal law relating to cannabis and rules issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.13">section 14</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A security plan that has been assessed by the Metropolitan Police Department; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A cultivation plan;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(18)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Provide electronic notice to the Councilmember and all Advisory Neighborhood Commissions in the affected ward at least 45 calendar days prior to the approval of a location for a cultivation center, manufacturer, retailer, or internet retailer; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Accord great weight to input provided by the Advisory Neighborhood Commission regarding the proposed location of a cultivation center, manufacturer, retailer, or internet retailer when approving or rejecting an application for a license;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Establish procedures by which Advisory Neighborhood Commissions can protest new and renewal applications for a cultivation center, manufacturer, retailer, or internet retailer when approving or rejecting an application for a license; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Establish procedures for an Advisory Neighborhood Commission to enter into a settlement agreement for a cultivation center, manufacturer, retailer, or internet retailer.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(19)</num>
      <text>Require caregivers and qualifying patients to notify ABCA within 48 hours and in writing of the loss, theft, or destruction of a registration identification card; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(20)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Council an annual report that includes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The number of qualifying patients participating in the medical cannabis program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The number of qualifying patients and caregivers registered;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The number of registration identification cards suspended and revoked;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The number of authorized practitioners providing written recommendations for qualifying patients;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The number and location of cultivation centers, manufacturers, retailers, internet retailers, and testing laboratories;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The amount of cannabis harvested by cultivation centers;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>The dollar amount of medical cannabis or medical cannabis products sold by cultivation centers, manufacturers, retailers, and internet retailers; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>The number and types of violations of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="7|16B">this act</code-cite> and any applicable rules, taken against licensed cultivation centers, manufacturers, retailers, internet retailers, couriers, and testing laboratories.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-315" type="History" path="§6">Feb. 25, 2010, D.C. Law 13-315, § 6</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-210" type="History">as added July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-210, § 2, 57 DCR 4798</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-209" type="History">Feb. 18, 2017, D.C. Law 21-209, § 2(e), 63 DCR 15291</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§5012|(d)">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 5012(d), 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-229" type="History" path="§2|(d)">Dec. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-229, § 2(d), 69 DCR 13901</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-332" path="§3|(e)" type="History">Mar. 22, 2023, D.C. Law 24-332, § 3(e), 70 DCR 1582</annotation>
</section>
