<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-1671.08a(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Medical Cannabis Administration Fund.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.08a">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Medical Cannabis Administration Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by ABCA in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All funds received from medical cannabis licensing, permitting, and registration fees shall be deposited into the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money deposited in the Fund shall be used by ABCA for the purpose of administering the medical cannabis program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Funds received from penalties and fines imposed under <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.08">§ 7-1671.08</cite> shall be credited to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-315" type="History" path="§9a">Feb. 25, 2010, D.C. Law 13-315, § 9a</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§5012|(g)">as added Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 5012(g), 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-332" type="History" path="§3|(k)">Mar. 22, 2023, D.C. Law 24-332, § 3(k), 70 DCR 1582</annotation>
</section>
