<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2510.08(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Termination of extreme risk protection orders.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>Any respondent against whom a final extreme risk protection order, including a renewal of the extreme risk protection order, was issued may, on one occasion during the one-year period the order in in effect, submit a written motion to the Superior Court for the District of Columbia requesting that the order be terminated.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>Upon receipt of the motion for termination, the court shall set a date for a hearing, and notice of the request shall be served on the petitioner. The hearing shall occur at least 14 days after the date of service of the motion upon the petitioner.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>In determining whether terminate a final extreme risk protection order pursuant to this section, the court shall consider all relevant evidence, including:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Any history or pattern of threats of violence, or acts of violence, by the respondent directed toward themselves or others;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Any recent threats of violence, or acts of violence, by the respondent directed toward themselves or others;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The respondent's acquisition of any firearms, ammunition, or other deadly or dangerous weapons within one year before the filing of the petition;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The unlawful or reckless use, display, or brandishing of a firearm by the respondent;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>Respondent's criminal history;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>Respondent's violation of a court order;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>Evidence of the respondent experiencing a mental health crisis, or other dangerous mental health issues; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>Respondent's use of a controlled substance, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-901.02">section 102 of the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, effective August 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-29; D.C. Official Code § 48-901.02)</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The court shall, before terminating a final extreme risk protection order, examine any witnesses under oath.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>The court shall terminate a final extreme risk protection order if the respondent establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that the respondent does not pose a significant danger of causing bodily injury to self or others by having possession or control of, purchasing, or receiving any firearm or ammunition.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>If the court grants a motion to terminate pursuant to this section, notice of the termination shall be personally served upon the petitioner by a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department and sent to the petitioner by electronic mail.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The court shall submit a copy of the order issued under this section to the Metropolitan Police Department on or before the next business day for service upon the respondent. Service of a notice of termination shall take precedence over the service of other documents, unless the other documents are of a similar emergency nature.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>If the Metropolitan Police Department cannot complete personal service upon the petitioner within 5 business days after receiving an order from the court under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Metropolitan Police Department shall notify the court.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>Within one business day after service, the Metropolitan Police Department shall submit proof of service to the court.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History" path="§1008">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title X, § 1008</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-314" type="History" path="§2|(e)">as added May 10, 2019, D.C. Law 22-314, § 2(e), 66 DCR 1672</annotation>
</section>
