<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2510.04(Perm)</num>
   <heading>Ex parte extreme risk protection orders.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>When filing a petition for a final extreme risk protection order, a petitioner may also request that an ex parte extreme risk protection order be issued without notice to the respondent.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>The court may hold a hearing on any request for an ex parte extreme risk protection order filed under this section.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(c)</num>
              <text>In determining whether to issue an ex parte extreme risk protection order pursuant to this section, the court shall consider all relevant evidence, including:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>Any history or pattern of threats of violence, or acts of violence, by the respondent directed toward themselves or others;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>Any recent threats of violence, or acts of violence, by the respondent directed toward themselves or others;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>The respondent's acquisition of any firearms, ammunition, or other deadly or dangerous weapons within one year before the filing of the petition;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The unlawful or reckless use, display, or brandishing of a firearm by the respondent;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>Respondent's criminal history;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>Respondent's violation of a court order;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>Evidence of the respondent experiencing a mental health crisis, or other dangerous mental health issues; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>Respondent's use of a controlled substance, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-901.02">section 102 of the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, effective August 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-29; D.C. Official Code § 48-901.02)</code-cite>.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(d)</num>
              <text>The court may grant a request under this section based solely on an affidavit or sworn testimony of the petitioner.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(e)</num>
              <text>The court shall issue an ex parte extreme risk protection order if the petitioner establishes that there is probable cause to believe that the respondent poses a significant danger of causing bodily injury to self or others by having possession or control of, purchasing, or receiving any firearm or ammunition.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(f)</num>
              <text>If the petitioner requests that the court issue an ex parte extreme risk protection order pursuant to section, the court shall grant or deny the request on the same day that the request was made, unless the request is filed too late in the day to permit effective review, in which case the court shall grant or deny the request the next day the court is open.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(g)</num>
              <text>An ex parte extreme risk protection order shall state:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(1)</num>
                <text>That the respondent is prohibited from having possession or control of, purchasing, or receiving any firearm, ammunition, registration certificate, license to carry a concealed pistol, or dealer's license while the order is in effect;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(2)</num>
                <text>The date and time the order was issued;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(3)</num>
                <text>That the ex parte extreme risk protection order will be in effect until the court rules on whether to issue a final extreme risk protection order;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(4)</num>
                <text>The grounds upon which the order was issued;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(5)</num>
                <text>The time and place of the hearing to determine whether to issue a final extreme risk protection order;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(6)</num>
                <text>That following the hearing, the court may issue a final extreme risk protection order that will be in effect for up to one year;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(7)</num>
                <text>The procedures for the:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(A)</num>
                  <text>Renewal of a final extreme risk protection order pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2510.06">section 1006</code-cite>;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(B)</num>
                  <text>Surrender of firearms, ammunition, registration certificates, licenses to carry a concealed pistol, or dealer's licenses in the respondent's possession, control, or ownership pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2510.07">section 1007</code-cite>; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(C)</num>
                  <text>Termination of a final extreme risk protection order pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2510.08">section 1008</code-cite>; and</text>
                </para>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(8)</num>
                <text>That the respondent may seek the advice of an attorney as to any matter connected with <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="7|25|X">this title</code-cite>, and that the attorney should be consulted promptly so that the attorney may assist the respondent in any matter connected with the ex parte extreme risk protection order.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(h)</num>
              <text>An ex parte extreme risk protection order issued pursuant to this section shall expire 10 days after the date and time the order was issued, unless the court set a new hearing date pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2510.03|(b)|(2)">section 1003(b)(2)</code-cite>, in which case, the court may extend the duration of the ex parte extreme risk protection order to not exceed 15 days.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>The court shall terminate an ex parte extreme risk protection order in effect against the respondent at the time the court grants or denies the petition for a final extreme risk protection order.</text>
            </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History" path="§1004">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title X, § 1004</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-314" type="History" path="§2|(e)">as added May 10, 2019, D.C. Law 22-314, § 2(e), 66 DCR 1672</annotation>
</section>
