<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-1319.01(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Hazardous Waste and Toxic Chemical Source Reduction Fund.</heading>
  <text>
  *NOTE: This codification is <u><b>not</b></u> the most current, due to recent law changes. To see the current law (including emergency and temporary legislation, if relevant) click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1319.01">Current Version</cite>*
  </text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Hazardous Waste and Toxic Chemical Source Reduction Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Department of Energy and Environment in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All fees, fines, and penalties received from compliance with and enforcement of <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="8|13">this chapter</cite>, and all interest earned on those monies, shall be deposited into the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to pay for the costs of implementing <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="8|13">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-64" type="History" path="§21a">Mar. 16, 1978, D.C. Law 2-64, § 21a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§6044">as added Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 6044, 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
