<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1181.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For purposes of this chapter, the terms:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the District Department of Transportation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Director” means the Director of the District Department of Transportation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Private structure” means a fixture or other structure built on public space or in the public right of way constructed by a private person or entity, with or without the permission of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Public right of way” means the surface, the air space above the surface (including air space immediately adjoining and above a private structure), and the area below the surface of any public street, bridge, tunnel, highway, lane, path, alley, sidewalk, or boulevard.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Public space” means all the publicly-owned property within the property lines of a street, park, or other public property as such property lines are shown on the land records of the District, and includes any roadway, tree space, sidewalk, or parking within such property lines.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History" path="§6022">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 6022, 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle C of title VI of Law 15-205: Section 6021 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> provided that subtitle C of title VI of the act may be cited as the Abatement of Dangerous Conditions on Public Space Act of 2004.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 6022 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 6022 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
