<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-118</num>
  <heading>Tasting permit requirements and qualifications.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A tasting permit shall be issued only to a licensee under a manufacturer’s license, class A or B, or a retailer’s license, class A or B, to utilize a portion of its licensed premises for the tasting of products as listed in subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Containers of alcoholic beverages used for sampling purposes shall be labeled as such and may not be sold.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not provide to a customer, in one day, samples greater than the following quantities:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>3 ounces of spirits;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>6 ounces of wines; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>12 ounces of beer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A tasting permit shall be valid for 3 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The holder of a manufacturer’s license, class A, may utilize a portion of the licensed premises for the sampling of wine and spirits, and the holder of a manufacturer’s license, class B, may utilize a portion of the licensed premises for the sampling of beer, between the hours of 8:00 a.m. and 12:00 a.m., 7 days a week.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 101(d), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-201" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-201, § 2(e), 55 DCR 6289</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-25" type="History">Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-25, § 2, 58 DCR 6513</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2112(b), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-82" type="History">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-82, § 2, 61 DCR 175</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-270" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-270, § 2(a)(6), 62 DCR 1866</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-84" type="History">Mar. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-84, § 2(a)(6), 63 DCR 781</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-187">D.C. Law 15-187</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “class A, or an applicant which is a full service grocery store and meets the requirements of § <cite path="§25-303">25-303</cite>(c)(1), (2), and (3)” for “class A”; and added subsec. (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-201">D.C. Law 17-201</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “class A and B” for “class A”; and, in subsec. (d), substituted “3 years” for “2 years”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-25">D.C. Law 19-25</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “manufacturer’s license, class B, a retailer’s license, class A and B, or an applicant” for “retailer’s license, class A and B, or an applicant”; and added subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> substituted “class A and B” for “class B” following “manufacturer’s license” in (a); and in (e), added “The holder of a manufacturer’s license, class A, may utilize a portion of the licensed premises for the sampling of spirits, and” and added the comma following “sampling of beer.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-82">D.C. Law 20-82</cite> substituted “7 days a week” for “Thursday through Saturday” in (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-270">D.C. Law 20-270</cite> rewrote (a); and substituted “of wine and spirits” for “of spirits” in (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-84">D.C. Law 21-84</cite> substituted “8:00 a.m. and 12:00 a.m.” for “1:00 p.m. and 9:00 p.m.” in (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-17">D.C. Law 19-17</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “manufacturer’s license, class B; retailer’s license, class A and B; or an applicant” for “retailer’s license, class A and B, or an applicant”; and added subsec. (e) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The holder of a manufacturer’s license, class B, may utilize a portion of the licensed premises for the sampling of alcoholic beverages between the hours of 1:00 p.m. and 9:00 p.m., Thursday through Saturday.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-17">D.C. Law 19-17</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Brewery Manufacturer’s Tasting Permit Amendment Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-71, May 19, 2011,  58 DCR 4235).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Brewery Manufacturer’s Tasting Permit Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-148, August 9, 2011,  58 DCR 6830).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
