<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>25-126</num>
  <heading>On-site sales consumption permit.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The holder of a manufacturer’s license, class A or B, may apply for an onsite sales and consumption permit to use a portion of the licensed premises for the on-premises sale, service, and consumption of beer brewed by the brewery, wine manufactured by the winery, and beverages with spirits distilled by the distillery.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The holder of an on-site sales and consumption permit shall only sell, serve, and permit the consumption of beer brewed by the brewery, wine manufactured by the winery, and beverages with spirits distilled by the distillery and purchased by the customer between the hours of 8:00 a.m. and 12:00 a.m., 7 days a week.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The on-premises sales and consumption permit shall not obviate the requirement of the holder of a manufacturer’s license, class A or B, to obtain a tasting permit pursuant to § <cite path="§25-118">25-118</cite>, to be authorized to provide samples of beer, wine, or spirits.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A violation of this section shall constitute a primary tier violation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Any additional spirits that are added to beverages primarily containing spirits distilled by the distillery shall be purchased from a wholesaler or manufacturer licensed under this title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e-1)</num>
    <text>The holder of a manufacturer’s license class A or B that holds an on-site sales and consumption permit may sell or serve beer, wine, and spirits purchased from a licensed wholesaler or licensed manufacturer at private events not open to the public for on-premises consumption.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “beverages” means brandy, cordials, fortified wines, liqueur, and non-alcoholic beverages.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 2002(c), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-270" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-270, § 2(a)(7), 62 DCR 1866</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-84" type="History">Mar. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-84, § 2(a)(9), 63 DCR 781</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-270">D.C. Law 20-270</cite> rewrote (a); added “wine manufactured by the winery, and beverages with spirits distilled by the distillery” in (b); rewrote (c); and added (e) and (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-84">D.C. Law 21-84</cite> substituted “8:00 a.m. and 12:00 a.m.” for “1:00 p.m. and 9:00 p.m.” in (b); and added (e-1).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2002(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2002(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2002(c) of the  Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
