<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-205</num>
  <heading>Board record-keeping responsibilities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board shall maintain complete and accurate records of all action taken on:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Applications for licenses; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Recommendations for, and remonstrances against, the granting of licenses.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board shall maintain the records in a manner readily accessible for inspection by the public during normal business hours.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Board shall provide to the Director and the Council annual reports detailing the activities of the Board for the previous year regarding the following items:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Licenses, including the number of licenses outstanding; the number of new  alcohol licenses and permits issued; the number of alcohol licenses and  permits renewed; the number of licenses suspended; and the number of licenses revoked;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Enforcement, including the number of regulatory inspections performed and the number of investigations conducted;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The workload of the Board, including the number of adjudicated cases processed; the number of hearings conducted; and the number of show cause cases pending;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Community notification efforts, including the number of ANC notifications issued; the number of ANC meetings attended by Board members; and the number  of community meetings attended by Board members; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Revenue generated by Board actions, including revenue generated by the Board from permits and licenses and from fines.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board shall provide to the office of each ANC, on a quarterly basis, a list of all licenses due to expire during the ensuing 6 months.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Jan. 24, 1934, 48 Stat. 322, ch. 4, § 6</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 27, 1935, 49 Stat. 897, ch. 756, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-157" type="History">Sept. 29, 1982, D.C. Law 4-157, §§ 3, 15, 29 DCR 3617</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-51" type="History">Mar. 8, 1984, D.C. Law 5-51, § 2(b)(2), 30 DCR 5927</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-217" type="History">Mar. 7, 1987, D.C. Law 6-217, § 3, 34 DCR 907</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-122" type="History">May 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-122, § 2(c), 41 DCR 1658</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 101(f), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 25-205.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 25-106.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-187">D.C. Law 15-187</law-cite> rewrote subsec. (d) which had read as follows: “(d) The Board shall provide to each ANC office, on a quarterly basis, a list of licenses due to expire in the areas that the ANC will represent during the ensuing 6 months.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
