<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-303</num>
  <heading>Restrictions on holding a conflicting interest.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before issuing, transferring to a new owner, or renewing a license, the Board shall determine that the applicant is not disqualified because of a conflicting interest in another license, as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No licensee under a manufacturer’s or wholesaler’s license shall hold a  license of any other class or kind.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No licensee under an on-premises retailer’s license, class C or D, shall  hold any other license except an on-premises retailer’s license, class C or D,  or a caterer’s license.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>No licensee under an off-premises retailer’s license, class A or B, shall  hold an interest in any other license.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board shall not reject, solely on the basis of this section, the application of a franchisee who controls, or will control, the entire interest in the receipts, profits, inventory, purchases, pricing, and sales of beverages under the license, if the franchisee held a license, or had an application for a license pending, on June 22, 1982.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The requirements of this section shall not apply to an applicant for an off-premises retailer’s license, class B, for the sale of alcoholic beverages in an establishment if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The primary business and purpose is the sale of a full range of fresh,  canned, and frozen food items, and the sale of alcoholic beverages is  incidental to the primary purpose;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The sale of alcoholic beverages constitutes no more than 15% of the total  volume of gross receipts on an annual basis;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The establishment is located in a C-1, C-2, C-3, C-4, or C-5 zone or, if located within the Southeast Federal Center, in the SEFC/C-R zone;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The establishment is a full service grocery store which is newly  constructed with a certificate of occupancy issued after January 1, 2000, or  is an existing store which has undergone renovations in excess of $500,000 after January 1, 2000;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The opinion of the ANC, if any, has been given great weight; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The applicant does not hold a manufacturer’s or wholesaler’s license.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A manufacturer, or its affiliate, licensed under this title, may hold an interest in a limited partnership providing financial assistance to a general partner wholesaler as described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, but shall only exercise such control of the limited partnership business as is permitted by this chapter. The limited partner shall not have or exercise managerial control or decision-making authority with respect to daily operations of the limited partnership. Upon a default by the general partner wholesaler, the limited partner shall not acquire or assume additional control, ownership, or financial interest in the limited partnership. The manufacturer, or its affiliate licensed in the District shall not have a financial or ownership interest in the general partner wholesaler.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The only financial assistance allowed pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be the initial financial assistance to the limited partnership to acquire a licensed beer wholesaler. In that arrangement for financial assistance, the wholesaler license issued under this title shall be issued in the name of the general partner wholesaler on behalf of the limited partnership, and shall not be issued in the name of the limited partnership nor in the name of the manufacturer, or its affiliate.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The limited partnership providing the financial assistance described in this section shall not exist for more than 10 years from the date of its creation, and shall not be recreated, renewed, or extended beyond that date.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>This section shall not amend or otherwise alter this title, except for the limited purpose of allowing a manufacturer, or its affiliate, which is licensed in the District, to provide financial assistance to a limited partnership for the exclusive purpose of acquiring a licensed beer wholesaler. A manufacturer or its affiliate shall not require the wholesaler to use the financial assistance as described above.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall prohibit a wholesaler or other licensee under this title from obtaining, perfecting, or enforcing a security interest under Article 9 of Subtitle I of Title 28 in any personal property or fixtures of a retailer or other licensee, including inventory and accounts and other rights to payment.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Jan. 24, 1934, 48 Stat. 327, ch. 4, § 12</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-157" type="History">Sept. 29, 1982, D.C. Law 4-157,§ 7, 29 DCR 3617</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-217" type="History">Mar. 7, 1987, D.C. Law 6-217, § 7, 34 DCR 907</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-40" type="History">Aug. 17, 1991, D.C. Law 9-40, § 2(c), 38 DCR 4974</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298,§ 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1702(e), 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 101(i), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-361" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-361, § 2(b), 56 DCR 1204</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-23" type="History">Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-23, § 2(b), 58 DCR 6509</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 2162, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§25-112">25-112</cite>, § <cite path="§25-118">25-118</cite>, and § <cite path="§25-722">25-722</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 25-303.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 25-113.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “during the preceding 12 months” for “in the calendar year” and made a nonsubstantive change in par. (4), made a nonsubstantive change in par. (5), and added par. (6).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-187">D.C. Law 15-187</cite> rewrote par. (5) of subsec. (c); and added subsec. (d). Prior to amendment, par. (5) of subsec. (c) had read as follows: “(5) The opinion of the ANC in which the establishment is located has been given great weight as specified in Chapter 4; and”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-361">D.C. Law 17-361</cite>, in subsec. (c)(4), substituted “after January 1, 2000” for “during the preceding 12 months in which an application is made”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-23">D.C. Law 19-23</cite>, in subsec. (c)(3), substituted “or, if located within the Southeast Federal Center, in the SEFC/C-R zone;” for a semicolon; and, in subsec. (c)(5), substituted “weight; and” for “weight.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> added (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-145">D.C. Law 13-145</cite> added subsec. (d) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d)(1) The requirements of this section shall not apply to an applicant for an off-premises retailer’s license, Class B for the sale of alcoholic beverages in an establishment:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) Where the primary business and purpose is the sale of a full range of fresh, canned, and frozen food items, and where the sale of alcoholic beverages is incidental to the primary purpose;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Where the sale of alcoholic beverages constitutes no more than 15% of the total volume of gross receipts on an annual basis;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) Where the establishment is located in a C-1, C-2, C-3,C-4, or C-5 zone;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) Where the establishment is a newly constructed, full-service grocery store with a Certificate of Occupancy issued after January 1, 2000; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) When the decision of the Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which the establishment is located has been given great weight.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The exemption in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to a grocery store which has its structure replaced or has substantially altered its structure as the result of a renovation.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-145">D.C. Law 13-145</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-346">D.C. Law 18-346</cite>, in subsec. (c)(3), substituted “or, if located within the Southeast Federal Center, in the SEFC/C-R zone;” for a semicolon; and, in subsec. (c)(5), substituted “; and” for a period at the end.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-346">D.C. Law 18-346</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Alcoholic Beverage Control New Grocery Store Development Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-306, April 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Alcoholic Beverage Control New Grocery Store Development Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-369, July 10, 2000,  47 DCR 5834).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1702(e) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Southeast Federal Center/Yards Non-Discriminatory Grocery Store Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-674, December 28, 2010,  58 DCR 130).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2162 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
