<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-344</num>
  <heading>Special restrictions for off-premises retailer’s license in Mt. Pleasant.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “Mt. Pleasant” means the area defined as ANC-1D, delimited by Piney Branch Parkway to the north, 16th Street to the east, Harvard Street to the south, and Adams Mill and Klingle Roads to the west, on [December 24, 2008].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A licensee under an off-premises retailer’s license in Mt. Pleasant, class A or B, shall not:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Divide a manufacturer’s package of more than one container of beer, malt liquor, or ale, to sell an individual container of the package if the capacity of the individual container is 70 ounces or less; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sell, give, offer, expose for sale, or deliver an individual container of beer, malt liquor, or ale with a capacity of 70 ounces or less.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-287" type="History">Dec. 24, 2008, D.C. Law 17-287, § 2(b), 55 DCR 11993</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-287">D.C. Law 17-287</cite> provided: “Sec. 4. Rules. ”The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code <cite path="§2-501">§ 2-501</cite> et seq.), may issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution, within this 30-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
