<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-332</num>
  <heading>Moratorium on class B licenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>After [May 1, 2013], the Board may issue new off-premises retailer’s class B licenses, if the Board finds that the number of retailer’s class B licenses is less than the quota set forth in § <cite path="§25-331">25-331</cite>(b). A condition of the license shall be that the sale of alcoholic beverages for consumption off-premises shall constitute no more than 25% of the total volume of gross receipts of the licensee on an annual basis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No more than one retailer’s license, class B, issued under this subsection shall be issued to the same applicant or to an individual with an ownership interest in another license issued under this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The issuance of new retailer’s licenses, class B, under this subsection shall be audited by ABRA and subject to the reporting requirements set forth in § <cite path="§25-112">25-112</cite>(e).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The moratorium shall have a prospective effect.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This moratorium shall not apply to an applicant for an off-premises retailer’s license, class B, for the sale of alcoholic beverages in an establishment if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The primary business and purpose is the sale of a full range of fresh,  canned, and frozen food items, and the sale of alcoholic beverages is  incidental to the primary purpose;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The sale of alcoholic beverages constitutes no more than 15% of the total  volume of gross receipts on an annual basis;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The establishment is located in a C-1, C-2, C-3, C-4, or C-5 zone or, if located within the Southeast Federal Center, in the SEFC/C-R zone;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The establishment is a full service grocery store which is newly  constructed with a certificate of occupancy issued after January 1, 2000, or  is an existing store which has undergone renovations in excess of $500,000 during the preceding 12 months in which an application is made; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The opinion of the ANC, if any, has been given great weight.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An exception to the moratorium shall be granted for 4 new class B licenses on Connecticut Avenue, N.W., between N Street and Florida Avenue, N.W., after October 22, 1999; provided, that no licensee shall devote more than 3,000 square feet to the sale of alcoholic beverages.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1702(g), 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 101(l), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-23" type="History">Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-23, § 2(e), 58 DCR 6509</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(k), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§25-112">25-112</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite>, in subsec. (c)(4), substituted “during the preceding 12 months” for “in the calendar year”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-187">D.C. Law 15-187</cite> rewrote par. (5) of subsec. (c) which had read as follows: “(5) The opinion of the ANC in which the establishment is located has been given great weight as specified in Chapter 4.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-23">D.C. Law 19-23</cite>, in subsec. (c)(3), substituted “or, if located within the Southeast Federal Center, in the SEFC/C-R zone;” for a semicolon.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-310">D.C. Law 19-310</cite> rewrote (a), which read: “No new off-premises retailer’s license, class B, shall be issued.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(e) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-346">D.C. Law 18-346</cite>, in subsec. (c)(3), substituted “or, if located within the Southeast Federal Center, in the SEFC/C-R zone;” for a semicolon at the end.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-346">D.C. Law 18-346</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1702(g) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Southeast Federal Center/Yards Non-Discriminatory Grocery Store Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-674, December 28, 2010,  58 DCR 130).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (a), see § 2(k) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-597, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1001).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(k) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
