<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-340.01</num>
  <heading>Special restrictions for Ward 4.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“ANC 4C07” means the single member district area in Ward 4, established under § <cite path="§1-309.03">1-309.03</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Ward 4” means the area defined as Ward 4 in § <cite path="§1-1041.03">1-1041.03</cite> on September 30, 2004.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, no class A or B off-premises retailer’s license shall be issued in or transferred into Ward 4; provided, that this section shall not prohibit the transfer of a class A or B off-premises retailer’s license within Ward 4.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to any application for a new or transferred license pending on September 30, 2004.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An exception to the moratorium imposed by subsection (b) of this section on the application of a Class B license shall be granted for a full service grocery store or substantially renovated full service grocery store located within the boundaries of ANC 4C07, with a certificate of occupancy issued after [March 21, 2009]; provided, that no licensee shall devote more than 3,000 square feet to the sale of alcoholic beverages.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to [subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2], may issue rules to implement the provisions of this section. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution, within this 30-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-324" type="History">Mar. 21, 2009, D.C. Law 17-324, § 2(c), 56 DCR 239</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-270" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-270,§ 2(b)(5), 62 DCR 1866</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-270">D.C. Law 20-270</cite> substituted “class A or B -premises retailer's license” for “class A or B license” twice in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-288">D.C. Law 17-288</cite> added a section to read as follows: “§ <cite path="§25-340.01">25-340.01</cite>. Special restrictions for Ward 4. ”No class A or B license shall be issued in or transferred into Ward 4; provided, that this section shall not prohibit the transfer of a class A or B license within Ward 4. For the purposes of this section, the term ‘Ward 4’ means the area defined as Ward 4 in § <cite path="§1-1041.03">1-1041.03</cite> on September 30, 2004. This section shall not apply to any application for a new or transferred license pending on September 30, 2004.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-288">D.C. Law 17-288</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(a) of Targeted Ward 4 Single Sales Moratorium Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-509, September 25, 2008,  55 DCR 10878).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
