<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>25-361</num>
  <heading>Involuntary transfer.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board may transfer a license upon the request of a bona fide purchaser of the license who made the purchase at any of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A marshal’s sale;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A trustee’s sale under foreclosure of a chattel deed of trust;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A trustee’s or receiver’s sale in bankruptcy proceedings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any other sale conducted upon the order of a court of competent  jurisdiction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A sale under Article 9 of the Uniform Commercial Code;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Upon the death of an individual who is a licensee or who has a stock  ownership or partnership interest of 50% or more in the licensed business; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A tax sale under Chapter 13 or 13A of Title 47.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in this section, transfers made under this section may, because of their involuntary nature, be approved by the Board without an initial inquiry, as required by §§ <cite path="§25-311">25-311</cite> through <cite path="§25-314">25-314</cite>, as to the appropriateness of the establishment, and without the notice provisions contained in subchapter II of Chapter 4.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Bona fide purchasers whose transfers are approved under this section shall, at the time for renewal of the license, meet all of the requirements of § <cite path="§25-313">25-313</cite> regarding the appropriateness of the establishment and shall at that time have notice of their renewal application given under subchapter II of Chapter 4.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Bona fide purchasers shall, before an approval of the transfer, submit to the Board an affidavit stating that no change which could be considered a substantial change to the business under § <cite path="§25-762">25-762</cite> will occur before the expiration of the license period during which the transfer takes place.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a change which could be considered a substantial change will occur before the expiration of the license period, the transfer application shall be considered under §§ <cite path="§25-404">25-404</cite> and <cite path="§25-762">25-762</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
