<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-354</num>
  <heading>Board review of moratorium request.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board shall hold a public hearing to review a proposed moratorium. The public hearing shall be in the nature of a rulemaking hearing under § <cite path="§2-505">2-505</cite> and not in the nature of a contested case under § <cite path="§2-509">2-509</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>At the public hearing, any interested person may appear to give oral or written testimony in support of, or in opposition to, the moratorium request.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to receiving testimony from the public, the Board shall request formal comments from the following persons or agencies:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Councilmembers within whose wards the requested moratorium area is located;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The ANCs within whose areas the requested moratorium area is located and any other ANC abutting the proposed moratorium area;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Assistant City Administrator for Economic Development, or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Office of Planning, or its successor agency; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The District Commander of the Metropolitan Police Department in which the requested moratorium zone is located.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In deciding on a moratorium request, the Board shall consider the extent to which the testimony and comments show that the requested moratorium is appropriate under at least 2 of the appropriateness standards set forth in subchapter II of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Board may grant the moratorium request in one or more of the following ways:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In whole or in part;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By enlarging or decreasing the moratorium area; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By limiting the moratorium to no more than one class of license.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Board may deny the moratorium request in its entirety.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The decision of the Board shall be final and shall be issued in writing, including each member’s vote.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 101(q), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-187">D.C. Law 15-187</cite>, in par. (2) of subsec. (c), substituted “is located and any other ANC abutting the proposed moratorium area” for “is located”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
