<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>25-446.01</num>
  <heading>Settlement agreements — enforceable provisions.</heading>
  <text>A settlement agreement enforceable by the Board under this subchapter may include:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Provisions allowing or prohibiting entertainment and the hours that entertainment would be allowed;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Specific methods to mitigate the level of noise outside the establishment, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Sound attenuation elements;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Requiring that the doors and windows of the establishment remain closed (except for ingress and egress) during hours of entertainment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Restricting indoor entertainment to a specific area of the establishment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Specification of physical attributes to mitigate noise emanating from an outdoor facility.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of this subparagraph, the term “physical attributes” may include architectural features, sound barriers, and placement of speakers;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Descriptions of reasonable efforts that the applicant or existing licensee will take to control litter and other debris in the immediate area surrounding the establishment, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The frequency that the applicant or existing licensee will monitor the area;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The days and time that the applicant or existing licensee will remove trash; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The efforts to be made by the licensee to limit rat and vermin infestation;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Descriptions of parking arrangements, including the use of valet service contingent on proper permitting by the District Department of Transportation;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Requirements that the applicant or existing licensee maintain an incident log and that the incident log be made available to ABRA and the Board, upon request;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>A notice to cure provision;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Restrictions on hours of operation and sales and service for a new or existing licensee’s facilities;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Descriptions of how the licensee will address specific issues in determining the hours of operation, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The licensee’s history of previous violations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The proximity of the establishment to residences; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The hours of operation and sales and service of alcohol for other existing licensed establishments in the area;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Restrictions on the utilization of floors, occupancy, and the number of seats for existing licensees and address specific issues in determining occupancy issues, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The licensee’s history of previous violations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The proximity of the establishment to residences; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The hours of operation and sales and service of alcohol for other existing licensed establishments in the area; and</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>Stipulations that the establishment will comply with existing District statutes and regulations, or will comply with privileges granted by ABRA or any other District agency.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(s), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2(s) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
