<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-441</num>
  <heading>Hearings — Continuances.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A hearing may be continued for good cause. A written motion for a continuance shall be filed with the Board at least 6 days before the scheduled hearing date and served upon all parties at least 6 calendar days before the hearing. To be granted, the motion shall, in the opinion of the Board, set forth good and sufficient cause for continuance or demonstrate that an extreme emergency exists.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A continuance shall not waive the requirements of this chapter governing the time in which to file objections, petitions, or other pleadings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Board may, on motion of any party or on its own motion, continue a hearing to permit an ANC to vote on a material issue in the hearing or upon a determination that the interests of justice will be served by the granting of the continuance to any party.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board may waive the provisions of this section if all parties agree to a continuance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1702(j), 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</law-cite> rewrote subsec. (c) which had read as follows: “(c) The Board may, on motion of any party or on its own motion, continue a hearing in order to permit an ANC to vote on a material issue in the hearing.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1702(j) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
