<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-446.02</num>
  <heading>Settlement agreements — unenforceable provisions.</heading>
  <text>The Board shall not enforce the following provisions if included in a settlement agreement covered by this subchapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Restraints on the ability of an applicant or existing licensee to operate its business, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Requirements that the ANC or other community members approve future ownership changes;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Requirements that the ANC or other community members be notified of intent to transfer ownership;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Prohibitions against the applicant or existing licensee applying for a change in license class;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>A requirement that the applicant or existing licensee change the license class before selling the license;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Requirements that prohibit the licensee from applying for changes to licensed operation procedures, including applications for summer gardens, sidewalk cafes, rooftop decks, entertainment endorsements, and changes of hours:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Mandates regarding specific brands of alcohol or pricing for alcohol;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>Restrictions on the age of patrons; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(H)</num>
      <text>Requirements that the applicant or existing licensee use a specific company for services;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Statements that create administrative procedures in addition to those required by ABRA or any other District agency;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>A requirement that the applicant or existing licensee attend ANC meetings or other community meetings;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Statements or requirements that the applicant or existing licensee:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Provide money, special considerations, or other financial benefits to the community;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Join any group; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Hire local individuals; and</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Any requirement that contracts, incident logs, or similar documents, be made available to the ANC or other community groups or members.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(s), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§25-446">25-446</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 2(s) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
