<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-601</num>
  <heading>Standing to file protest against a license.</heading>
  <text>The following persons may protest the issuance or renewal of a license, the approval of a substantial change in the nature of operation as determined by the Board under § <cite path="§25-404">25-404</cite>, or the transfer of a license to a new location:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>An abutting property owner;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A group of no fewer than 5 residents or property owners of the District  sharing common grounds for their protest; provided, that in a moratorium zone  established under § <cite path="§25-351">25-351</cite> (or in existence as of May 3, 2001), a group of no  fewer than 3 residents or property owners of the District sharing common grounds for their protest;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>A citizens association incorporated under the laws of the District of Columbia located within the affected area; provided, that the following conditions are met:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Membership in the citizens association is open to all residents of the area represented by the association; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A resolution concerning the license application has been duly approved in accordance with the association’s articles of incorporation or bylaws at a duly called meeting, with notice of the meeting given to the voting body and the applicant at least 7 days before the date of the meeting;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>An affected ANC;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>In the case of property owned by the District within a 600-foot radius of  the establishment to be licensed, the Mayor;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>In the case of property owned by the United States within a 600-foot radius of the establishment to be licensed, the designated custodian of the property; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The Metropolitan Police Department District Commander, or his or her designee, in whose Police District the establishment resides.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-42" type="History">Oct. 26, 2001, D.C. Law 14-42, § 6(d), 48 DCR 7612</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 101(x), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 47(a), 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(u), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§25-211">25-211</cite>, § <cite path="§25-351">25-351</cite>, § <cite path="§25-421">25-421</cite>, § <cite path="§25-601.01">25-601.01</cite>, § <cite path="§25-602">25-602</cite>, and § <cite path="§25-609">25-609</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-42">D.C. Law 14-42</law-cite> validated the previously made technical correction in par. (2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-187">D.C. Law 15-187</law-cite> deleted “, or initiate a referendum as set forth in § <cite path="§25-604">25-604</cite>” following “new location” in the lead-in language; and rewrote par. (3) which had read as follows: “(3) A citizens association incorporated under the laws of the District of Columbia located within the affected area;”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</law-cite>, in the introductory language, inserted “or” preceding “the transfer”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-310">D.C. Law 19-310</law-cite> deleted “a new owner license renewal” following “§ <cite path="§25-404">25-404</cite>” in the introductory language; and substituted “meeting given to the voting body and the applicant at least 7 days before the date of the meeting” and a semicolon for “meeting being given at least 10 days before the date of the meeting” and a closing period in (3)(B).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6(d) of Technical Amendments Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-108, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7622).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(u) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-597, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1001).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of a section designated as § <cite path="§25-601.01">25-601.01</cite>, concerning certain documents to be made available, see § 2(v) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-597, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1001).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(u) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority to the Director of the Office of Property Management to Protest the Issuance or Renewal of Alcoholic Beverage Licenses Pursuant to D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§25-601">25-601</cite>(5)(2001), see Mayor’s Order 2004-182, November 9, 2004 ( 51 DCR 11351).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
