<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-733</num>
  <heading>Delivery and payment records and reports.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A delivery of an alcoholic beverage to a licensee shall be accompanied by an invoice of sale or delivery which shall bear the date of delivery of the alcoholic beverages.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Before the 26th day of each month, each manufacturer and wholesaler shall file with each other manufacturer or wholesaler within the District, on a form prescribed by the Board, a statement under penalties of perjury showing the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name, including trade name, and address of each retailer who has been  required to make payment in cash for alcoholic beverages under § <cite path="§25-731">25-731</cite>(c);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All delinquent accounts; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All checks, drafts, or other orders for payment received from any  retailer, which, since the previous report, were dishonored when presented for payment, when such dishonored checks, drafts, or other orders for payment exceed $15,000.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A manufacturer or wholesaler who, after receiving notification of delinquency by a retailer under § <cite path="§25-731">25-731</cite>(c), extends credit to any retailer, shall be deemed to have violated § <cite path="§25-731">25-731</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-361" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-361, § 2(c)(4), 56 DCR 1204</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-361">D.C. Law 17-361</cite>, in subsec. (b)(3), substituted “presented for payment, when such dishonored checks, drafts, or other orders for payment exceed $15,000” for “presented for payment”; and repealed subsecs. (d), (e), and (f), which had read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(d) Before March 2, June 2, September 2, and January 2 of each year, each manufacturer and wholesaler shall submit to the Board, on a form prescribed by the Board, a list of the following:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) All retailers that have been required to make payment in cash for alcoholic beverages under 25-731(c), during the preceding 90 days; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) All accounts that have been delinquent during the preceding 90 days, including the amount of the delinquency.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(e) Each manufacturer and wholesaler shall, within 24 hours of receipt from the bank or other depository of notice of dishonor of a check, draft, or other order for payment which the manufacturer or wholesaler received from a retailer, notify in writing the Board of the notice of dishonor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(f) Failure to file timely a report required by this section shall constitute a violation of this chapter.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
