<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>25-736</num>
  <heading>Gifts and loans from wholesaler prohibited.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A licensed wholesaler of alcoholic beverages, whether or not licensed under this title, shall not engage in the following transactions with a retail licensee:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Lend or give any money;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sell equipment, furniture, fixtures, or property, except merchandise sold at the fair market value for resale by the licensee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Rent, loan, or give any equipment, furniture, fixtures, or property; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Give or sell any service.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A retail licensee shall not engage in the following transactions with a wholesaler:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Receive or accept any loan or gift of money;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Purchase equipment, furniture, fixtures, or property, except merchandise purchased at the fair market value for resale;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Rent from, borrow, or receive by gift equipment, furniture, fixtures, or property; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Receive any service.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, with the prior approval of the Board, a wholesaler may sell, give, rent, or loan to a retail licensee any service or article of property costing the wholesaler not more than $500 and a retail licensee may purchase from, rent from, borrow, or receive by gift from a wholesaler any service or article of property costing the wholesaler not more than $500.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section, with the prior approval of the Board, a wholesaler may sell, rent, give, loan to a retail licensee computer equipment for the purpose of tracking the sale or delivery of alcoholic beverages.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section, employees or agents of a wholesaler, whether licensed by this title or not, may work or serve alcoholic beverages at a licensed establishment during an event promoting alcoholic beverages sold by the wholesaler without Board approval.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section, a wholesaler, whether licensed by this title or not, may donate alcoholic beverages to the holder of a temporary license or a festival license or a nonprofit organization that does not hold a retailers license without Board approval.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Jan. 24, 1934, 48 Stat. 331, ch. 4, § 19</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 27, 1935, 49 Stat. 903, ch. 756, § 16</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-157" type="History">Sept. 29, 1982, D.C. Law 4-157, §§ 11, 15, 29 DCR 3617</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-51" type="History">Mar. 8, 1984, D.C. Law 5-51, § 2(b)(7), 30 DCR 5927</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 101(bb), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-84" type="History">Mar. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-84, § 2(e)(3), 63 DCR 781</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 25-736.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 25-120.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-187">D.C. Law 15-187</cite> added subsec. (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-84">D.C. Law 21-84</cite> added (e) and (f).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
