<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>25-785</num>
  <heading>Delivery, offer, or otherwise making available to persons under 21; penalties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who is not a licensee shall not, within the District, purchase an alcoholic beverage for the purpose of delivering the alcoholic beverage to a person who is under 21 years of age.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who is a licensee shall not, within the District, offer, give, provide, or otherwise make available an alcoholic beverage to a person who is under 21 years of age, except if necessary to allow the person to perform lawful employment responsibilities that require the person to have temporary possession of alcoholic beverages.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person who violates any provision of this section shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon conviction for the first offense, be fined not more then [than] $1,000, or  imprisoned up to 180 days, or both;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon conviction for the second offense committed within 2 years from the  date of any such previous offense, be fined not more than $2,500, or  imprisoned up to 180 days, or both;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Upon conviction for the third or any subsequent offense committed within  2 years from the date of any such previous offense, be fined not more than   $5,000, or imprisoned up to one year, or both.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person alleged to have violated this section may be issued a citation under § <cite path="§23-1110">23-1110</cite>(b)(1). The person shall not be eligible to forfeit collateral.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The fines set forth in this section shall not be limited by [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Jan. 24, 1934, ch. 4, § 30a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-122" type="History">as added May 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-122, § 2(k), 41 DCR 1658</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 113(c), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-403">7-403</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 25-785.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> added (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 113(c) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
