<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>25-791</num>
  <heading>Temporary surrender of license — Safekeeping.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A license which is discontinued for any reason shall be surrendered by the licensee to the Board for safekeeping. The Board shall hold the license until the licensee resumes business at the licensed establishment or the license is transferred to a new owner. If the licensee has not initiated proceedings to resume operations or transfer the license within 60 days after suspension, the Board may deem this license abandoned after giving notice to the licensee. The licensee has 14 days to respond to the Board’s notice to request continued safekeeping.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board may extend the period of safekeeping beyond 60 days for reasonable cause, such as fire, flood, other natural disaster; rebuilding or reconstruction; or to complete the sale of the establishment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Licenses in safekeeping beyond 60 days, as extended by the Board, shall be reviewed by the Board every 6 months to ensure that the licensee is making reasonable progress on returning to operation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as proved by paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Board shall assess licenses in safekeeping a fee of 25% of the annual license fee for every 6 months that the license remains in safekeeping. The initial 6-month fee shall be paid by the licensee at the time the license is placed in safekeeping. Each additional 6-month safekeeping fee shall be paid in advance by the licensee.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>After 4 consecutive 6-month periods of safekeeping, the safekeeping fee shall be 50% of the annual license fee for every 6 months that the license remains in safekeeping.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The safekeeping fee required by this subsection shall not apply to a licensee serving a suspension.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section shall not relieve a licensee from the responsibility for renewing the license upon its expiration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a licensee notifies the Board that the licensee has ceased to do business under the license or if the Board cancels the license under this section, the license shall be marked as “canceled.”</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Licenses which are restored after being held in safekeeping for longer than 2 years shall be subject to the license renewal process set forth in Chapter 4.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A license suspended by the Board under this title shall be stored at the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 104(a), 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(dd), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-310">D.C. Law 19-310</cite> added (c-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of (c-1), see § 2(dd) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-597, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1001).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(dd) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
