<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>25-421</num>
  <heading>Notice by Board.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon the receipt of an application for the issuance or renewal, for a substantial change in operation as determined by the Board under 25-404, or for the transfer of a license to a new location, of a retailer’s license, the Board shall give notice of the application to the following parties:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any ANC within 600 feet of where the establishment is or will be located; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A citizens association meeting the requirements of § <cite root="25-601">25-601</cite>(3); provided, that the citizens association has, at least 30 days before the Board’s receipt of the application, registered with ABRA by providing a copy of its charter, and an e-mail or other electronic address in a form consistent with ABRA’s procedures.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The notice shall contain the legal name and trade name of the applicant, the street address of the establishment for which the license is sought, the class of license sought, and a description of the nature of the operation the applicant has proposed or the proposed change in operation. The description shall include the hours of sales or service of alcoholic beverages.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The notice to the Board of Education shall state the proximity of the establishment to the nearest public school of the District and the name of the nearest public school.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The notice shall state that persons objecting to approval of the application are entitled to be heard before the granting of the license, and shall inform the recipient of the final day of the protest period and the date, time, and place of the administrative review in accordance with subchapter III of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Board shall give notice to the ANC by first-class mail, postmarked not more than 7 days after the date of submission, and addressed to the following persons:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The ANC office, with a copy for each ANC member;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The ANC chairperson, at his or her home address of record; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The ANC member in whose single-member district the establishment is or  will be located, at his or her home address of record.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Board shall publish the notices required under this section in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Within 180 days after May 3, 2001, the Board shall implement a procedure by which it will provide additional notification, via electronic media, to the public and ANCs, of these notification requirements, and the publication of proposed and adopted regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The requirements of this section shall not apply to applicants for a caterer’s license.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Jan. 24, 1934, 48 Stat. 327, ch. 4, § 14</annotation>
      <annotation>Aug. 25, 1937, 50 Stat. 802, 803, ch. 766, §§ 1, 2</annotation>
      <annotation>June 15, 1938, 52 Stat. 691, ch. 396, § 3</annotation>
      <annotation>June 29, 1953, 67 Stat. 103, ch. 159, § 404(e), (f)</annotation>
      <annotation>Aug. 2, 1968, 82 Stat. 616, Pub. L. 90-450, title IV, § 404</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-146">Mar. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 3-146, § 4, 27 DCR 4753</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-157">Sept. 29, 1982, D.C. Law 4-157, §§ 8, 15, 29 DCR 3617</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-51">Mar. 8, 1984, D.C. Law 5-51, § 2(b)(4), (c), 30 DCR 5927</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-97">June 29, 1984, D.C. Law 5-97, § 2, 31 DCR 2556</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-217">Mar. 7, 1987, D.C. Law 6-217, § 9, 34 DCR 907</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-7">June 5, 1987, D.C. Law 7-7, § 2, 34 DCR 2640</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-174">Oct. 3, 1992, D.C. Law 9-174, § 2(b), (c), 39 DCR 5859</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-122">May 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-122, § 2(f), 41 DCR 1658</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(q)(2), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-39">Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-39, § 2, 46 DCR 6548</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, §§ 101(s), 201(e), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(o), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="25-353">25-353</cite>, § <cite root="25-423">25-423</cite>, and § <cite root="25-446">25-446</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 25-421.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 25-115.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-187">D.C. Law 15-187</cite>, in subsec. (a), repealed pars. (2) and (3) and rewrote par. (4); and added subsec. (h).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-310">D.C. Law 19-310</cite> added (a)(5); and made a related change.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary addition of (a)(5), see § 2(o) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-597, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1001).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(o) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
