<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>25-432</num>
  <heading>Standard review procedures.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If no protest has been received by the Board during the protest period, the Board shall consider the application within 10 days after the end of the protest period.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a protest has been received by the Board during the protest period, the Board shall take the following actions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Board shall schedule a protest hearing, to be held within 75 days of the end of the protest period, for new license applications to receive testimony and other  evidence regarding the application in accordance with §§ <cite root="25-442">25-442</cite> and <cite root="25-444">25-444</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The parties shall be informed of their obligation to attend a settlement conference under § <cite root="25-445">25-445</cite> for the purpose of discussing and  resolving, if possible, the objections raised by the protestants.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The parties shall be informed of their rights and responsibilities with respect to reaching a settlement under §§ <cite root="25-445">25-445</cite> and <cite root="25-446">25-446</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>At the request of all parties, and if a settlement conference would be   unlikely to succeed, the Board may waive the parties’ obligation to attend a   settlement conference.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Board shall issue a decision in accordance with § <cite root="25-433">25-433</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(p), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-270">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-270, § 2(c)(1), 62 DCR 1866</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-310">D.C. Law 19-310</cite> inserted “to be held within 75 days of the end of the protest period, for new license applications” in (b)(1).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-270">D.C. Law 20-270</cite> substituted “the Board shall consider” for ” the Board shall schedule an administrative review to consider” in (a).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of (b)(1), see § 2(p) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-597, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1001).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(p) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
