<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>25-827</num>
  <heading>Request for suspension or revocation of license by Chief of Police.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police may request the suspension or revocation of a license if the Chief of Police determines that there is a correlation between increased incidents of crime within 1,000 feet of the establishment and the operation of the establishment. The determination shall be based on objective criteria, including incident reports, arrests, and reported crime, occurring within the preceding 18 months and within 1,000 feet of the establishment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police may close an establishment for up to 96 hours, subject to a hearing and disposition by the Board under § <cite root="25-826">25-826</cite> if he or she finds that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is an additional imminent danger to the health and welfare of the public by not doing so; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>There is no immediately available measure to ameliorate the finding in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The order of the Chief of Police to close an establishment under subsection (b) of this section shall terminate upon the disposition by the Board of the matter under § <cite root="25-826">25-826</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police may, without a hearing, summarily revoke, suspend, or restrict a licensee’s privilege to extended hours of operation under subsection § <cite root="25-723">25-723</cite>(c), (d), and (e) if the licensee’s operation presents a demonstrated danger to the health, safety, or welfare of the public. A licensee may seek review of the summary revocation, suspension, or restriction pursuant to § <cite root="25-826">25-826</cite>(c) and (d).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Jan. 24, 1934, 48 Stat. 330, ch. 4, § 17</annotation>
      <annotation>Aug. 27, 1935, 49 Stat. 900, ch. 756, § 9</annotation>
      <annotation>Aug. 25, 1937, 50 Stat. 803, ch. 766, § 3</annotation>
      <annotation>Apr. 26, 1950, 64 Stat. 88, ch. 106</annotation>
      <annotation>Dec. 8, 1970, 84 Stat. 1393, Pub. L. 91-535, § 3(a)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-157">Sept. 29, 1982, D.C. Law 4-157, §§ 9, 15, 29 DCR 3617</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-51">Mar. 8, 1984, D.C. Law 5-51, § 2(b)(5), 30 DCR 5927</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-217">Mar. 7, 1987, D.C. Law 6-217, § 11, 34 DCR 907</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-12">Sept. 11, 1993, D.C. Law 10-12, § 2(b), 40 DCR 4020</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-122">May 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-122, § 2(h), 41 DCR 1658</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-97">Apr. 30, 1998, D.C. Law 12-97, § 2, 45 DCR 1517</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-20">Sept. 23, 2005, D.C. Law 16-20, § 2(b), 52 DCR 6575</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2042(b), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="25-832">25-832</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 25-827.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 25-118.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-20">D.C. Law 16-20</cite>, rewrote subsec. (b) and added subsec. (c). Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “(b) The Chief of Police may close an establishment for the remainder of the business day if he or she believes that continued operation presents an imminent danger to the health, safety, or welfare of the public.”.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added (d).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Inaugural Celebration Extension of Hours Public Safety Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-616, December 19, 2008,  56 DCR 44).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
