<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 6-160">
  <num type="law">6-160</num>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/6-160.pdf">D.C. Law 6-160</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 6-160 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 6-488. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 24, 1986 and July 8, 1986, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 16, 1986, it was assigned Act No. 6-205 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>thei bent RC, LAW 6 1 6 0 Tsta" SEP 2 31986 AN ACT D.C. ACT 6 205 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUL 1 6 1986 Enrolled Ori oun, rom (c) xemj ecri f a: To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act of 1979 to provide for procedures ear. for administrative exemptions from prohibited transactions lace ubl: BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA f That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia n of Retirement Reform Administrative Exemptions Amendment 1-7 Temporary Act of 1986 rope Sec. 2. Section 181 of the•District of Columbia •C• Retirement Reform Act of 1979, approved November 17, 1979 xemj (93 Stat. 866; D.C. Code, sec. 1-741 is amended as •f t follows: Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase hat "subsection (f and inserting the phrase "subsections (f) and (h) of this section" in its place; Subsection (d) is amended by striking "A" and inserting the phrase "Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, a" in its place; and (c) A new subsection (h) is added to read as follows: 1 M yor District APPROVED: July 16, 1986 Columbia Chairmah Council of the District of Columbia C X X R I q UNCIL M MN. CLA ITH, JR. AWFORE RVIS NE X X Rec I NCIL ME MN. CLAR ITH, JR. WFORD VIS E 11 C A V Recc R COUNCIL MEN CHMN. CLARK WITH, JR. CRAWFORD JARVIS KANE Enrolled. Original period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 b) This act shall expire on the 180th day of its having taken effect. 3</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
