<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 6-172">
  <num type="law">6-172</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1987-02-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/6-172.pdf">D.C. Law 6-172</citation>
      <citation type="register">33 DCR 7211</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>Enrolled proceed. or ref u: person, of the I appear other eN order st Sec Any design c other wo purpose without shall be Sec Thi review p event of District section Self-Gov a) The board may revoke, suspend, or deny a license in accordance with the procedures established by this Act and rules issued pursuant to this act if the board determines from the evidence that: The license was obtained through fraud or misrepresentation; The licensee has been convicted by a court of any offense involving fraud or deceit in the licensee's professional practice; The licensee has manifested gross incompetence or recklessness in the practice of interior design; or The licensee has violated any provision of this act or rules issued pursuant to this act b) The board may begin proceedings to revoke, suspend, or deny a license upon receipt of a written complaint or on its own initiative by majority vote. The board shall provide the person who is the subject of the proceedings with notice of the allegations and an opportunity for a hearing in accordance with the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq c) The board may administer oaths and compel the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, papers, and other evidence in connection with any 11 Enrolled Original "toceeding under this section. In the case of contumacy by refusal to obey a subpoena issued by the board to any person, the board may refer the matter to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, which may order the person to arand give testimony or produce books, papers, and er evidence bearing on the hearing. Refusal to obey the er shall constitute contempt of court. Sec. 12. Penalty for illegal practice or use of title. New, D.C. Code sec. 2-3411 Any person who engages in the practice of interior (1987 supp design or who uses the title "interior designer" or any ether words, letters, figures, or other device for the perpose of implying that the person is an interior designer iiithout having complied with the provisions of this act shall be subject to a civil fine of not more than $200. Sec. 13. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day Congressional iew period following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the strict of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia If-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 16` 12</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2201"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2202"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2203"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2204"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2205"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2206"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2207"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2208"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2209"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2210"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>12</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-2211"/>
  </section>
</document>
