<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-103" flag="true">
  <num type="law">7-103</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Board of Parole Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1988-04-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-103.pdf">D.C. Law 7-103</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 8279</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-103, the “District of Columbia Board of Parole Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-133, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Nov. 10, 1987 and Nov. 24, 1987, respectively. Deemed approved without the signature of the Mayor on December 14, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-122 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF TKE DISTRIC T OF COLUMBIA NOT ICE O.c. LAW 7- 103 istr ic t of Co\ulIlbh Bo ard of Parole Ame~dme~t A ~t of 1987 Pursuant to Settion 41 Z of the Ojstri~t of Columb ia Se lf- Government and GoverOllental Reorganization Act L 93 19B the Act the Council of the Distri ct of ColUlllbia adopted Bill No 7-133 on f i rst 6nd seco nd readings. November la 1987 4nd Novemb e r 24 1987 respectively. This l e gislation was deemed appr oved wit hou t the Signature of the Mayor o n December 14 1987 ilu r suan t to Section 404 (e) of 't he Att 4nd was ilssi 9 ned Att No 1 -122. published In the Oecellber 25, 1987 edition o f the D.C. Register Vol 34 pdge 8279) and tr ansmitted to Con gress 0 0 December 21, 1987 for a 50- day review. in 4t c ordilnte with Sect io n 602(c 2) o f the Act The Counctl o f the Cistrict o f ColumbIa hereby gives noti ce t ha t tlle 60 day Congressl0R41 R.evie w Perio d has e ~pir ed. and therefo re cites 'th i s enactment amp;·s· D. C. Ld W 7- 103, effective Aprl1 Z8, 1988 ha i r:1lan C 0 u n i 1 Dates Counted During the 50 day Coo gressiona l Review Period: De cember ZI 22 January 25, 26 27,2 8, 29 Februa r y 1.2 3 ,45, 8 9,15 17 18 19,22 23,2 4,2S, 26 ,2 9 Mar I Z. 1 .4.7 8 ,9.1 0 .11.14,1 5 16,17 ,lS ZI .22 n 24 25, 28,29. 30 31 Apr il 11,1 2 ,1 3 ,14.15 18 ,19,2 0 ,21, 2 2,25,26, 27 D.UJ\W 7 -1 0 ·8 a&amp;gt I APR Z S 1988 AN ACT I.C.ACT 7-122 IN THE COUllCIL OF THE DIS'i'RICT OF COLU~iBIA DEC1 41SS'] TO repeal sections 1 and 2 of An Act TO reorganize the syst~ of parole of prisoners convicted in the District of Columbia; to abolish the current Board of Parole; to reestablish a Board of Parole for the District of Col~mbia; and to require that all members of the Board of Parole be appointed with the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia BE 1 ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUHBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Board of parole Amendment Act of 1987 M Sec 2. Creation; term of I'lel&amp;lt;lbers a) A Board of Parole Board for the penal and correctional institutions of the Distric~ of Columbia District"l is establiShed to consist of 5 mer:lbe r s appointed by the IJayor of the District of Columbia Jayor with the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Colur:lbia Council"l The nomination of a Board member Shall be submitted to the Council for a 90-day period of review excluding days of Council recess. The Council may approve or disapprove the nomination by resolution within 90 days of the date the nomination is transmitted to t he Council. If the Council does not ac t within the 90- day ~eriod, the nomination 1) Sha ll be deemed disapproved; or (2) Shall be deemed approved if the Council has not acted on the J prior nominations for the same vacancy b) One member of the Board shall be designated a s Chairperson of the Board Chairperson by the ~layor. Each me mber of the Board sha l l be a resident of the Di£trict selected on the basis of his or her broad experience in responsible positions in the fields of corrections social sennces, reha bilitation, or law or education in related fieldS of behavioral science ne(;\bers of the Board shall be 1 New, D.C. Code, sec, Z4- 201,l (1988 supp compensated at a r a te determined by the ~tayor in accordance wi th app li cab le t a ws c) Initial appointments t o the Board shall be a~ foll ows: The Chairper son shall be appoint.ed tor 5 years 2 member s shall be appoint.ed for 3 year s; and 2 ~e~ber s s hall be aPPoin t. lld for .2 years hereafter, all appoint.ments shall be tor 5 years In the event of a vacancy on t.he Board, t.he yor shall appo~nt. a successor t.o co~plete e unexpi r~d t. erm of t.hat member a) The ~Iayor shall Submit. to the Council a ncmina ti c r. for each pOSi tion on the SOar d within 60 days Of the effective date of t.his act Ie he Doar d of parol e as est.ablished by Organi:at.ion Order No. 6, effect ive Oecer.'lber 26, 1967 {C O. 67- 95: 14 DCR 152 is abolished. If ach Pember at the lioard of Parole est.ablished pur suant. t.o Or9an1:at.ion Crder ~o. 6, effect.ive December 26, 1967 {C O. 67- 95; 14 OCR 152 serving as a membe r as of the ef fec t.ive date of this act. shall serve as an interim member of t he Board established by th is sect.ion until a replace~ent e~ber, appoin t ed pursuant t.o this s ect.ion is sworn in. Sec 3 Powers and duties 0 the I:oa rd a) The Board shall: D.C Cod 1) Cet.errHine i: and hen it. is i:'l the best sec 4·~Ol int.erest of society and t.he offender t.o releas e him or her (1988 S\!Op on parole or en condi tional rel ease in t.he case of com~i tt ed youth of!enders 2 Oct.ermine the t.rr.'ls and conditions of parol e or conditional r elease 3) Supervi se pa rol ees in t he comr.lunity; a nd (4) Determine it: and whl'!n t o terminate Farole o r conditional rel ease o r to mod~!y the terms o r c onditions of Farole o r conditional release. Ib) A quorum s hal l consi s t of J me~ber s o f the Eoa r d. All decis lons regard ing aFprova l, denial, or revocation of ?lIrole shall be b'j mlljorlty vot.e of the Boar&amp;lt Ic he Chairperson sh a ll preside a t r.'Ieetings of the Boara and provide tor and supervise the administra tive a nd minister ial a ctiv~ties and per sonnel of t.he Board Id he Chalrpe fson shall insufe t.hat all Board policies, pilIns ru les, and standardS are coordinatec with the Depar tment o f Correc t ions in o rder to provide for an effect.ive and integrated correctiona l syster.'l and for continu ity in treatr.'lent and training of of fenders that 1S geared t o t.heiI: roadjustlnent as p roouctive and useful memcers of socie ty { supplies, the Board ~he e~ployees, official records, furniture, ar,d a ny unexpended balance of any appropriation of Parole shall be transferred to the Board. of Sec. 4. RulemaJdng. The e'layor shall o:rol:1ulgate proposed rules co implement the provisions of this act he proposed rules shall be submitt ed to the CQ~ncil for a 60-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess If the Council does not approve or disaPrrove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by reSOlution within this 50-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved. Nothing in this section shall affect any requirements imposed upon the Mayor by title 1 of the District of Columbia Adcinistrative Procedure Act, apOlroved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C Code, sec. 1-1501 et seq Sec. 5. Repealers a) Sections 1 and 2 of An Act to reorganize the system of parole of prisoners convicted in the District of Columbl.a, approved July 17, 1947 (61 Stat. 378; D.C. Code, sec. 24 -2 01a and 201b are repealed b) Organization Order NO 6, effective December 26, 1967 (C O. 67-95; 14 DCR 152 is rer-ealed. Sec. 6. Effective date This act Shall take effect after a 60-day period of Congressional review follOwing approval by t he Mayor or in the event Of. veto by the Ilayor, action by the Council of the District of COlumbia to overrl.de the veto) as provided in section 602{c 2) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code sec. 1-233(c 2» L Chairnan Council of the District of Cclur:obia DEEMED APPROVED WITHOUT SIG::ATURE UPON EXPIRATION 8F IO-DAY i1AYGRAL REVIEW BOARD mT STG}lED layor District of COlumbia DECDIBER 1 1987 3 ll ew, D.C. Code, sec. 24-201 98S supn Repeal, D. C. Cod sec. 24-201 a 20lb 09R8 SUP COUNCIL or THE DISTRICT or COLUMB IA COWlcil P t riod Seyell RECORD OF OFfICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOC KH NO 1 C Item Coo.ont C&amp;lt;&amp;gt;Io r a C TI ON &amp;amp; CATE A~d.o."o d FC R d i gC,~l l~oC-"eL U U 3 OICE VOTE 01 u. 01 all prese nt X ACT ION &amp;amp; OATE o u,o F M"'L u Lu'u C'L'l.o-"L g VO ICE VOTE OM"Cico"rc y Ml,'ern r..2'"h"o"m a-'v"o d n"O C'd vcr OYo a ll pre sent ROC. CALL VOTE I; ACTION &amp;amp; OATE VO ICE '10TE lt;O d Yote on COQ Ab.on RESULT</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-401.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-401.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-401.03"/>
  </section>
</document>
