<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-104">
  <num type="law">7-104</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1988-04-30</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-104.pdf">D.C. Law 7-104</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 147</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-104 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-346, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 24, 1987, and December 8, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 22, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-124 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NC IL Of tH E DI STRICT or COlU MB IA OT IC£ D.C. lAIi 10( NC 3 46 on f jr ~t ond Se cond rt,dlngs. Kowe.be. 24. 1987 nd De~ t. bt r 8 1981 r esprctlye l fol l o.ln, t ~f s l,n,l urt o f Ih t Klyor on Dece.be. 22. 1981 t~ls I,glsl,ttan VIS .ss ign ed A~t NO 12 published In th e Jl nu y Ig!a. e d ttl on of t~f Regls u Vo l 3S gl I'll 4 trans.HIt" to Co n"e u 0 602( c){ 2 of tht Ac t. The Cou llen of the DIH.le l of Colu.bl, henbl ,Ius notic i th,t the 60-4 0"9 lon.1 R,wlt. Per io d h e.ptr,d nd April 0 1988 L thl Cowllctl J .nu 2S.26 21 28.29 febru.ry 1. 2 3 .4 5.8 9 .1 6 17.1 8 19 22 .2 3 24.25.2 6 .29 M c ll 1.2. J .4 .1.8 ,9 .1 0 ,11.14, 15 .16 .17 .1 8 .21 Z.23 24 25 28. 29 30.31 Apr II 11 .1 2 l l. 14 15 18 .19 20.1I .2Z 25 .26 .Z1. 28.29 tAW7·104 APR 3 0 1998 DC. ACT7-124 IN Th e Ctllllle n o r Tlte DISTRlC 01" CGLIII:BI aCI'r Cwl f l u t !oD I 'III~ S"I'Ph 0 Dlst.l c t 01 Cnl".bla Cod 0 lInend tit. lo 12, 14, 16, 1 21, and 2) of the Ohulct o f Col uobi. Code to ~ko vr~tlc.l correctlO G, correc t r e forenco correct typoqrephlc al vrrore, end a~nd Gec tl on 21-)07101 of the Dietriet of Col~l. Code to clarity that the e ace.ent of soction 21-)0710) crcatad a QXcuption to acetlon 11-120(b) of ~c Diatrict o Columbia Codo, to aa-nd tho eo end t~r ConacrvetiOn Dietrlct Re tebl1IhAent ~ondoont ACt of 1967 to clarity tho term of oftlco tor Council appoin tceo lind to doloto a ndDOnt to provisions already ropo.lad, to &amp;amp;Aend the Diatrlct of Colu&amp;amp;bla Cro Receipts Tax IlDendnent ACt of 19.7 to correct Diotrict Of Co lusbl. Code eator.nee, to aaend the Di5 teict o f Uolu~t. Covornaant Co-prehon.tvo noeit Peeaonnel ACt of 1'18 CDployeo &amp;amp;enetlta ~ndDOnt Aet o f 1981 t o roduaign5tc 1 o f it. Bact Ion. and to correct on incorrect roference, to ~end the Huraee 7r.lnin9 Corps &amp;amp;.tebllthmont Act of 1987 to expand tho .it where ~rovr~ par ticipant Y bo em~loyed, to &amp;amp;aend the DistriCt of Columb ia CQnMl ion on Judici al Disobilitl0' end Tonuro Betto L. Catoe Reappointment Re .olut~on a t 1911 to corr.ct the date the tCrQ o t o ffice e nd to Ogend the con.la.lon on Art nd HUlaonltieg kowland J. neortl n Contlr.otlon R*.olution of 1981 to co rrect the doto the tor. ot o ffice ood t o aJ:Oena the COIIIllio.ion on Art nd lIu".nitl0. Dougla. Arthur Dailey ContirQOtion Ro.olution of 1~87 to corruct the dote the ter o f o ff ico ends, to 4I:IOnd the commhsion on 1Irta and lIumonitio. Charles c. Stephenson Jr Conflt'n\atl Qn Resolution of 1987 t o correct the late the term of office end to ar:\end the COI:lmis8ion on Artll and lIu niti Patricio I thoehy Confir~ation Hesolution of 1987 to correct tha dace the tero o f o t fice on.:l to ~end the C~ission on ArtS and Hu~ n itioo Volerie Eichelberge r ConfirD4t~on Hoso lut l on o f 1'87 to correCt the dllte tho t oro 0 1 U!!lCO ~nd.1 to ~nond ~ho conniss ion on Art$ and liu",anitl cS ni c tl"nl H. Levy Con flrDation R"solut ion of 1~87 to co r r~c t ttlo date ttle ter~ a t off ice ends; to "meno t~e COI'II:1I.,10n on Art a lind U nltle ll I nice J. Locktl "n o Con fi.-a lltion Re,o l taon o f 198 7 t o co rect ttlc date t tle teng of o (£lC end t o ar.end the LOil rd o f Consume r Clai~s Ar b i tra t i on fo r the D i~ tric t of col lia I:d ard l c9\1an. Con fi ation Resolu t i on o f 1987 to co rrect. the dll te the tera o f offi.ce el\dll to md the OrU9 bua l cotlol b c and t:ental tllne s Insuranco coverll90 Act of 198 6 t o correct a tYVOq.-aphlcal error, to ~end the 01.t,let of Columb ia PubliC Poa t s econd ary education lIeor9.nizatlon C:t to ins ert ~lt ted words, to amend ttle Diatric t of Co lumbia Ctl li d ~u~~rt t nfo r c eacnt Anend~ent Ac t o f 198 t o correc t II referen ce I to end tho IIlatorlc Pre.ery.tlon Rcvlew Doa rd Ra-alne D h0D4. COnflroatlon Reao lution o f 1916 t o corr~c t the date tho t ora o f of I Ice enda; t o anend the Diatr ict o f Colu~ le Unlfo r. COnaervation ta5cne nt Ac t ot 1986 to correct a referonce, t o ~end the Dia t rict o co lumbia Health Occuplltiona Rovia ion Act of 1985 t o co rrect refereneo" to «DOnd the District ot Columbh Re910nd Inteutete Benkin9 Ac t a t 1985 t o correct refarence end to delete a r epe.ted ph raae to ~end the Di et rlct of Columbl. Funer.l serVI C"5 1I."ul.tory Act of 198 4 to conlora tho le"9t.h o f te n of the OfUce a! tn yor'a repreaentative to est.biiatled prect l ce to nd tho Diatrict of CoIUAbI. Public AS ltl tll nce Act of 1912 to ~eke gra~tlcal correc t i on, to ~nd t he Stroot .nd Alley Cloain9 and Acquisition Procedures Act o f 1'82 to ko the t 11:01 nol09Y ua d throu hout conai.tent, to Ulend the Closin9 of Po rtion of II North-South Public Alley in Square 830 and Council of the Diatrict of ColwMlia C~ntral Sta tf emp l oyeo Pereonnol Appeals Rules Au thorization Act of 1981 t o correct a reference, t o amend the Dt 'trict o f Colu~i. Offi ce of [nor9Y ACt of 198 0 t o nllke inor c lar ifyin9 "endQent, to &amp;amp;Dend the Independent Peraonne l Sy'tems Imple.untation Act of 1980 to re5tOr e lan~u.gc contained i n t.he cn9 r ola.d v~ r ion o£ tnta logislatlon, to .nend t he ho~roqre~lng Fo licy Act of 198 0 t.o c larify t hat followin9 no tice o f i ntent to di'$ppr oVe a rcprog ra~in9 request. tn" Council ~y disapprove or IIp~royo the rcpr09ram~ ln9 request by rosolution, to end the Residential Real Prope.-ty r nafer excise Tax Ac t o f 1978 to nak" it gender neu t ra l .nd to delete refer ences to the e xpired e xcisc tax on deale r s of residontl.1 real P'-0VCrty, t o end th~ Cis tr ict o f col umbia Cover nncn t co~~rehsn. lv. f:eri t Pcn.onnel Act o f 1918 t.o cn.n II word ifl th~ Dlst r ic t of Colu~bia 90ver nment emv10yees o.t.h o f lDrolled Orl.i~ of1. ce tu COnl OTm t o th~ fedc~a l ~ove~n~ont en~l oyeca oat h f o t ti c to co rrce t rcferene Ii u,d to rcdc llatc th I;ub c t iona .n aac tion 1111 o f tile act t o con{on" with the filbert ya tL UQed i n the Di t ,i t of I:o lu",b h Codel t o lt;1 th AC!vi "ory i~hborhood Counc i15 ~c t o f 1~7 S to corree t a ty~o&amp;lt rQl'h i"a l orror a nd t o con tom a noti require,"cnt t o tho District of Co lumbia Al COhol i c Ucvorage Cont r ol Ac t ~eforD Amendoent Ac t o f 198b t o ~nd the Dlatrict o f Colu"bia &amp;amp;al gt;ax ~c t t o del ete I of 2 definition. of th" Io'Ora yon to 4IM!nd the IncOl:le and franch i so Ta~ Ac t of 1947 to rofl "et chan90" in tho federal Tax RefoeM Act of 199 6 that hav boon adoptod by ~le Dis tr ict o f Col obia t o nd the District of Co l umbia Un~ploymcnt COQfen.stion Ac t to rol lec t the csta b llQ~en t of a new D15t r ict of Col Gbla Uncnployr.umt ComFenaAtion lIoard l to a/:lend the Dhtrle t of Columbia R venuo Ac~ o f 19)7 t o removo A redunda~cy and to co rre" t a ~YV09ra~hlcal error I t o ~nd An Act ~o further r egulAte benkin9, benke, truet cOQpanies, and bulld ing and loen e ochtlone 1n the Distric t of Columbia, and f or other ~rpose to aAko 1,1 gramaatic al "orrectionl to &amp;amp;Qend An Act MAking Appropriations ~o ~rovide for the expons.s of the 9over~nt of the DistrIC t of Col unble for tho f i ecel yOAr endin9 ~unc t hi rt ieth, nineteen hundred end three, A04 t o r oth.r pu r polee, to delete rotorences to prOVi810ne of law that havo bee~ repaaled/ to amend An Act to eatAblieh a code of lew f or tho DI.trict of Col~la t o reflect that the Offi ce of the ~upcrintend nt of Banking and FinAncial InstitUtionG hae been ere.ted and t o ropeAI c tlon 11 1d) of the Di.tric t o f Col mbta Reel £stGte Licunau re Act of 1992 DE IT I:"AC O DY U£ l OO NCI L Of 11 1: IH~TRICT or C(J l.VtIBIA, Tha t thlS ACt ~y be c i t ed as the eehnical ~endcent8 Act o f 196 1 Sec 2. Title t2 of thu Distric t of columbia Code Is a~nded al follows: tal ~ect ion 12-)0 1 i. aceoded by strikin9 the Fheaae "6-1611 and inser ting the ph re.e 2001 in its ~lace b) Se" t ion 12- 309 10 &amp;amp;.r&amp;gt;e.nded by s teiloin! the word "Cornr.lia.loncr and inlierting the word "ilayor" n i ts plac e Sec. J, Sec tion 14- 307 o f th~ Ci~trict of Col umbiA Code is amended by s triking t he nu~r 6-1611 and I n5e r t ing the n Qbc r "6- 2001" in it. vlace G.,c HI 16 of t h Dl tri t of Col ur:tbi a Coo h nded o I1 uw I Gec tlon 16-1 0 1 I ended by str l kin9 thO! word S 1 \11 1 "Coc&amp;gt;mt laion.c «nd i n rti n9 tho word 04YOr In It" pl ace bl f..c tlon 16-l04 i anendc&amp;lt;l by strlUn9 t h. word. S I H Conm l'li~nQr and "So«rd wherever they a r and l noc r t in'ij th wo r d ayor I n their I'lace. lei !O c tion lft-3 0 5 11 ar.oended by Itrild n9 t he word SN 1 lOS CO~~iD 0ncr wh r evcr it a~~e«rs and inS.,rtln9 t hc word liayor in its 1' lace. lu) Gett l on 16-301 i.D Mended al followa Se 1 lO1 (1) Uy Itrikinq the wotd "C~lllloner and l Ge nill t hl: wonl "nayor In it. plaeel and (2) Uy Itrikln9 the word "a nteee ndentl and l ns rti n9 the word "ontee &amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;le nta In Its 1'1«ee. 1.,1 !OcetlOn 16-l14 la aDO~ed by "trlkin9 tha word "COQDia. ionor whorever 1t appears and lna.rtin9 Lh. word I«yor O in ita pl.ce f) Sec tion 16-512 la _nded by atrlk1n&amp;lt;J t/'Ie word "Commissioner wh.rover It pP".ra and Inaertin9 tha werd O~L ayor in it pl.eD 91 !Oe~ tion 16-1311 ia onded by atrikln9 the \.lOrd "commiosionor nd insertln~ the werd \foyOr" In ita pl.ce hI Go~ t.lon 16-1314 10 &amp;amp;Danded by atrikin&amp;lt;J the werd Co~~10.loner" wherever it epl~aro end In.crtin9 tho word yor" i n it.s ploco. ti l !Oeet ion I ft-lll9 1s a.endod by strit ln&amp;lt;J the rd "COQrnisaione r nd Insertin9 the werd yor" in ita ~leee I i Ce~tlon 16-1) 31 1a naed by atrikinq t/'Ie word Commissioner" «nd lneertln9 the WQrd yor in itl pl«ee kl !Oection 16-1332 1a amandod by str ikinq the werd "commis l i oner and inlertln9 tha word o".yor 1n ito place 1) Ce e tlcn 16-13l6 i and.d «a follow tl) Uy Itrikin9 the word ·C~i.s lcnar ond insert! n'J t ne word loyc r" in ita Vlaeel (2) Dy atr ikl n9 the ~h e "subchdl'ter I whcr~vcr it eppears and inser tin&amp;lt;J the I'hr.sc s~beh.ptcr II in its plac e Il) 8y st rildn9 the n be r 1- 214 e nd Insertlnq t h e n~mb~ r 1- 2Il in its p laee 4 By 8trikinq the n~mber "1-215 and inlertinq the number "1- 21 4" in Ite p laeo l IS) By strikin9 th~ numbe r "7-323· wherever it a ppears and lneer tin9 the n~mbor "1-322" In its pl ace and 6 lIy IIt rikin'J the number 7301 anj inserting the n~mber "i- 30 1" in its piaee lt 1 1' S L 12 S~c 11 13 11 S.&amp;lt 1&amp;gt 1114 S.t 16- \)\9 Sec. Ift-I n l Sec. 11&amp;gt;_l ll2 s c I Ce c tl0n 16-1lSI i s aJ:Iendlld al tallo w£ S~ c Lb I3\1 tIl by strikin9 t ho word "OO11din9 end i n,ert in9 t he wo rd "buildings in Itll 1'loco end 12 1 lIy s tril:in &amp;lt;,i the word wo rk a nd i n sert i n tile rd o rks in i tli \- I c e n c tlon 1'-1101 I ended 1,.1 trB l n th phU S 16- 11111 ch~vter. 1 t o 10 o f Tltl 28 nd In rtin the plica eo uctl t l o 1 of Title 28" 1" it pla c 0) S ctlo n 1'-2316(d) I iI!:Iend d by Itr1l 1"9 the wo rd 5 lt 1 2)1 is and in e rtl th wo rd c" 1n it l. c II e c tie n 16-2320 I I nded by Itrlkln9 the "ord 5H. 1~-n211 0 ls. 10"er nd In rtln'l the word yo r" I n 11 I""c e I ect l o n 1'-2336 1 ended by Itrlklnq the hUlle Sn. 1~-n)6 "s"ctl on o iG-23 30 throuqll 16-2334' and in.crtln I:he 1,lIra c "Bec tion. 1 6-~J31 throu 11 16 115' In It. plac Ie c tlon 16-~14J II _ndN by Itrlklnq I:he phr s 11&amp;gt 214 Oe~ r tDOnt o f Public H lth" and In,,ertln the phr o J.ep4r tllle n t o f HUlII, n Sorvl In 11.1 I'lac I) Sectio n 16-2348 I ended by "trlkln the "lIra.e Su. 16-21'.8 Director o f PubU lIe"Ith" and Inlertln til. phra Di rc tor o f tho o.partaont of ~u n Servl o In ltl place. It gt;&amp;lt;tc t lon 1'-1102 h _ndlld by IItrlklnq the n..abor s 11&amp;gt 10 2 "16- 3112" and In rtln tho nuaber '1'-3111" In It" place u octlon 16-4309 11 nde&amp;lt;l a" follow S~ c. 1~-4)(}9 (1) Dy .triklnq tho phrs ctlon 14" and insertin9 the phrs.e octlo n 13' 1n 1t. plsc nO 121 I::y strlkin9 the .mrs.1t tlon" l 1) and 14" a nd in"c rtln\! the phn ectlon" 11. 12 nd IJ- In I t p lac e S.c 5. Title 19 of tho District of Col~la Cod. I. s~endcd a. follow ta) Sec tio n 19-107 Is _n4od by .Ulkln tho s 19- 101 nuaber '45-402' and inlortln tho nuaber '45-'02' 1n 11 hc(O b ectlon 19-JOI is ended by nr1klnq the werd s JO\ lIub6e t l on and i rtln the word tiO In it lace. l c Sect ion 19-7 0 1 1. aoonclcd by "Ulkln the word s.-c. 1'-10 i ·Co~1 10ne r nd i ftln the "Ord 't~yor' in it laee, Sec Titl o 21 of tile 010trlc t of Colwobia Codo i s emended 8S foll ows a Se c tion 21-3 0 is nded by nri.kin the WQrd Se l1 O cooa ny a nd i n. e r t 1 n9 t ho word "c a.pany· 1 t" plAc e. lb) Sec t ion 21-30 7 1 ndod by .trlkln tho word s.c 1 }lH "It nd I n"ertin; tho phra \llth the oxceptlon of e tion 21-120( c i f" In it. plac e. I c l l,;ect lon 21-5 01 is 4llIend",d by Strik1n9 the 1'IIf11 S.t. 21 50 1 by t he Mayor unde r t h Prac t ice o f P"ychol09Y Ac t 184 StAt. 19551 1I.C. Cod lt c 2-1704.1 et .eq and I n5cning the hr "se "purlua n t t o section SO l o f the D1 5tric t o f Col umbi lc::a lth OCcupa tions Revis ion Ac t of 19a 5. effective MardI 25 19116 (D.C. Law 6-99, D.C Code, Bee. 2-3J05 1 111 in i, h c H hill the defi.nitloll of qu.lified pByc hglo i"t d) Zec tloll 21-50 1 1 ia nded by lI ul I the s I-~nl.l I'hr pn.ctice 0 1 P'~Cholo y Ae t 184 Ut. U~51 0.&amp;lt Code c. 2-1 704.1 "t 011"'1 and Inae.-tln9 the ~h sc OlBt d ct ot Colu",bi. Ite.lth OcCUp. t!OIlB Rcvhlon Act of 1~1I5 effective rch 25, 19S6 I D. C La" 6-'191 D. C COO stle 1-3301.1 et se In its h.ce e) Z c hon 21-503 is Mended by strB in9 t"e ord S" e 21- S01 b~~I1 a nd In"ert l1l9 the word ub~oena in ita ~lace, I f ct l on 21-521 i nded by atrikin the phr e 'ir e. H-H I Dcl'art~nt ut Public Hea lth lt;ond inaertlnq t he ~hra.e Department o f IhJr.&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1l 5.nvicc in Ita place g) ZCCtlOn 21-541 i. II ended by strlkln'l the phra S~c 1-~41 OcpA rl",ent o f Public llealth" and In.ertlng th" phrase U rtm" n t of UUr.lan Zc rvlce in its place h Zectlon 2l-5 1&amp;amp I'Mi'd by Urlktn9 the phra Src. 1I H6 Dcpa r t~n t ot Public alth" whareve~ it a ppear. a nd ins"rt.n9 tht! Vhrll O rtoen t of lIu n G vlc In it. pl.ce. I cti&amp;lt;m 21-'06 is anend¥ by atrlkln~ the phra.e S~c. ll -90 crcta ry o f llealth, t:dUClition, and ~elfa lind inaertin9 the l'hraG c "Zecretary o f lle a 1th and. U an rvice£" 1n ttl p llicOl olC. 1 Title 2) o f thOl Di.trlet of Colu.hl. Code 1. a~endc6 as f o llowa, la) Zoction .23-521(t)15) 11 ended by nrlkin9 tho Src. B-SH ~ord as and ina"rtinq thOl word "hava" in ita pl a ce. It Soction 23-544 la &amp;amp;lendad by IItrlkin9 the word S~C. ll 44 Col lisll1oner and In'ertin9 the word yer 1n ita phce. I C ctlon 2)-546 ia fLI:Iendcd aa follova n 1) Uy atriking the number "33-40.2' and inlertl1l9 the Ilu~ber 3 50 2" in its pl a ce 2) 8y strikln9 the number "J3-41 and inaa rtin9 the number 33-516 in it. place 1) By IItr i kln9 the number "1]-1 0 2" and i nlertinq the nuQbe r 31- 602 i n it. place d ection 2)-5 8 1 of the Dla triet of ColUl:lbia Code is Se H-)81 amended by atriking the wo rd "whom wherever it appears and inserting tho word ·who 1n its plac e) Soction 23-582 of the Ohtrict of Columbia Codo is Sec. 23_~82 amenued by s triking the ward "wh wherev r it appear l .nd i n.e rt i nq the word whO in i ta pl aco Ifl eetion 23-903 of the Diltr i ct o f Colulllbia Code 1. s ll- 911J amend ed by 8t riking t he word "wh wherevOlr it appellrl and inserting t h a word who in its place q) Suction 23-1301 is amended by strik1n9 the \lOrd Se 23-1307 COf:u:lis siontlr hcrever it appear. lind inserting the \lOrd Mayor in it. place h) 1::ection 23-1126 in amc&amp;gt;nded by &amp;amp;t.uking the word UbI"Jrl and in rtin9 the wo rd "subpoena in its lace. Sec. 9 he fio il and ~tvr Conaorvation DiSt r ic t ~ce6 tabli6hment ~nd~nt Act o f 1987. effective October 9. aS7 (D. C Law 7- 39; to be cocUtied al D.C. Code, sue. 1 80 1 ct ace I s ar:.f!nded a talloW I gt;ection 1 W. C. Code, 6ec 1~2IO i r h,d t.y strilan'l subsection. Cb c and (d b) 1::cction 17 W.C. Coda, ace. 1-2614) is Donded t o read as f o llow Se c. 17. each be r o f th au ;ond 'later Co~.ervntion Board appOinted by th Council of the Di.trict o r Col umbia ahall rvo 2_y."r tora. which "hall expire at the conc lu.lon ot the Counc il period durin9 which the Counc i l DCP~r Wa. appointed Sec fie c tion S o( tho Di.trict of Colu.bla Cro Receipts Tax Amendment ACt of 19.7 ffective Octo~r I l9_8.L.lD_C W&amp;gt;I 7-25, H OCR sns" h _nded Ly IIUlkln9 t he phra"e oc. 41-2 20611 and In".rtlnq the phra oc. 47-2206fl in it" placo. Soc. 10. Section of tho Dietrict of columbia Government CoMprehen"lve hartt Poraonnel Ac t of 1971 tml'loyeo DeneUn Amendr»nt Act of UI7, cUectivo October 1, 1987 (D C. La 7-27, t o be co&amp;lt;l1floc1 at D.C. Code. eec. 1-627.2 is aaended a. tollowe, f a) Thc .econd aoction ~tfl h utde.i9natod a.,ction 2(f-l b) I;cction 2(9) ill Mlended by .triltin9 the Fhrllle -4 U.S.c. 301 t g.] and Ineertln9 the phra.e "42 u.S.C 01 er seg 1n ltX pi ece. Sec. 11 Section 2(c] of the ~ur.e. Trainin9 corps l:"ubl1ahmant Act of 1987, effective October 9, UI7 (D.C. La 7-32, co be coditiod at D.C. Code ec. 1l-~601tcll, is amended by strikin9 the phraa or the DepartQent of Hu~an Sorvices- and in.erting the phras the Department of Human s~rvicc5, the Office on A9in'l. o r other District a9cncies or tac li it ici as dc.iqnated hy the Hayor in it. pl ace. Sec. 12. section 2 of the Di.trtet of Columbia c~rnission on Judicial Oisabilities and Tenure Bette L. Catoe Re.p~int_nt R".ohition of 1981 effective October n, 1987 R IH; H DCI( 6900 i s ended by Itrikin9 the phrago "m,y 5 1993- and in.erting the phra April 20. 19 93 in itl plac s"c. 2l-IJZ6 S 1~22n c. 1-611.l Sec 26nl O.C R. see. 1 3 Seetlon 2 o f the CODQ1.,ion on Arts and U a niti&amp;lt gt;1 ROwla nd J. Harti n Contir-atiun Relo lution ot 19U7 e tlee tive Ju l y 14, 1981 (Rei. 1-119; H OCR 4,)21, is ,u,ended b erik inq t he date June )0 I 'Be and inilertinq the date June 30, I S9 in It I Iliac e. s e e 1 4. See ti on 2 o t thl OQDIr;e&amp;gt; o n on IIrt a and Uumanlt.i l.Iou91al Ar t hur Dalley Conf1nu.t!on flClo l tion o f 1987, effec tive Ju l y H, 1987 (ltu. 7- 118 H D(;ft 4' ll 11 nded loy a triki nq the dlte June JO, 1988 a nd lnlettlnq the dat June 30, 196 1n B .i1 ~lace. Sec. 15. Sec tion 2 of the C0Ma111!on on Arts a nd IlU"'oI nH.leG harlel C S te!'henlon Jr Cont1n tlon kGlolutlon of 1981, dfectivG July 14, 1')11 KGI. 1- 117; H DeK 49 301. iii /H:lend&amp;lt gt;d b str1k1nq the date Junc 30, 1~88 lind ingertinq th" date June )0, 1990" in it v laee. Se e. 16. Cccelon 2 of the Ccatll ion on Artl a nd Hllr,wonlti Patric ia Sheehy Con tin:LIUon I olution o f 1987, effective July 14. 1981 (Rea. 1-1161 H OCR 49nl, 11 a",ended by .teikin, the date June 30, 1988" Ind Inlertin9 the date June 3D, 1989" in ltl pllee Soe. 1 7. Section 2 of the CoeDi'l!on o n Artl Ind Hu~.nit~o. Valerio t le~elbar~e~ Confl~tlon Relolu tlon of 198 t:tfoc tive July 14, un (It 7-115; 34 OClt 49281. is amonded by Itrikin9 the date "June )0, 1988" and lnlertln~ t.he d a te June 3D, 1990· in it.1 place. soc. 18. Suc t ion 2 of the COD~llllon on Art a and !lumanit iu Richard ll. Levy Con Ur;o.atlon Itelolut.ion of 1987, effective July l 198 ReI ll H OCII ~921J. is I~Qnded by etr ikin the date "JunO 30. 1988" and in.ertin~ t ~e dolt.e June lU, 1990 1n itl v 1aeo c 19 Sec tion 2 o t t he COI:IIII18.io n On Art l .nd ll man it.i."1 Lun i ce J LClck".rt o~5 Con flrma.tio n Resolution o f 1987 Uec tive J ly 14, 1981 (Rei. 1-11]1 H OCR 4926 1 ended t.y Iit rikill&amp;lt;,1 the d"t June 30, 1988 and inaertln9 the date June )0, 1990 in it" place ec 20 Section 2 o t t Board o f Con lume r Ci alol Arui tr~ tiQn for the Clltr iet Of Columbia Edward L, Feg9ans Confirpati o n RelOl u t ion of 19 8 1, effec tive pril 10 1987 Ro 1 01 34 UCR 2338 1, i" l gt;endcd by Itr i king the date July 19 19 81 nd in~e rt in9 the da te Ju l y 19 19 8 i n its place D.C.R. n. e n. e D.C D. C D.C D.C.R. D.C e. 21. Section llh) of t he Dnl&amp;lt;j Abu Al cohol Abu8 and n tal 111ne.s Insurance Coversge Act of 1986, uf{ecti ve February 28. 19117 (O.C. Law 6-195, D.C. Code, tee. J5w 230 2(h ill lIJ&amp;lt;Iended by .trlkln the phra.e "lnplltient lind inplltient lind" lind in.e rtin9 the phr lnpatl.nt snd in it. plAce. sec. 22. The District ot Colunbts Public Po.ts eond.~y t;duestion Reorqanhation Ac t, efr-ct1ve Pebruary 24, 1987 (D.C Wow 6-177, D. C. Code see. 11-1 ~0 1 et .eq .I, h ame nded f ollow a) Section 501111 (D. C. Code, He. 11-1541UII h aaended by sddi~ the word "tftereart.r" before the phr e y not b l S. e tion 503(1)(21 li U. And ol (D. C, Code e ]1-154)(jll2 11 41. and 511 i ended by adding thO word 'thu" before the word "elo.o' wh.,rever it sppesrs. Ie) Section 5041d D.C. COd a 31-1544(4 h Amend.d by ,trlking tho phra I .hall eho n" and in r_tl"~g hll phra.e "I 'hdl be eho,en" In It' phe s.c. 23. C.,etion 23(s)(1) ot the District at Coluab1. Ch1ld &amp;amp;upport ~ntorcoaent nd nt Act of 19.5, effective ebruary 24, un (D.C. LIow lU, D.C. Cod e. 30-522(al( 31 is &amp;amp;Dendod by 'triklng the numbel "II" and Inaelting tho number "10' In its piece. See 24. Section 2 at the "htorte PnaervaelOfl bvi Board R~alne 6. tno Confi~tlon Me.olution of itl effectiv. Dee boIf H. nn tU, 14 DCR 1601. 1a nd.d by strlkln, tfte pftfs,e uly 21. 1'11" and In.erting th hu July H. lUI" 1n its place. S.c. 25. S~ction 3(al(21 of the D1etrlct of COlu.bls Unifo~Q Conaeltvetlon Ea,emant Act ot 1"6 ffectlv. KAy 16. 1986 (D.C LIo 6-113, D.C. Coda, eoe. 45-2602(al(211. Ie s~ended by .trlklng the phra,e ubeectlon 2 of thi, section and in,erting the phra.e ubsoetion (s)(ll of thi, s,etion" 1n ita plac Sec 26. The Dilltrict of COlur.lbia lJealth Occupation. Ac t of 1985. effective tlarch 25, 1986 (D.C. La 99, D. C. Code ee 2wlJ Q1 .1 Ie cnded a. folleN 1 toeetion Code ec. 2-3311.21 i nded by s t~ lklng the 1101' and In.erting cr phta.o "s.,e tion (bl &amp;amp;eet!on a.Ondsd by .trlking th~ phra ,u 3ee tlon .oc. 2-3311.1(all Ie 1101" and in.'ttlng in its plece D.C He. 2 11 n. l w31 11. 1 Sec. 27. Th. Di.t~lct of Coluabia Regional Int.r.tat. lIa"ki"q Act ot 1915 tt.etive Nove.be~ 23, 1985 tD.C. La 6-6J, D.C. Cod e 6-'01.t .eq.I, 1 nd.d t o llo a) C.ctlon ~1201 (D.C. Cod c 6-'0l(2011 h 5 1I 1 amtinded by .trlklnq the phra I,etlon 6 nd 1nletting the ~hraae uetton 5" in tta ~lac b octlon 5(c111lUlI (D. C. Code ec. Sec 2 I04 26-804Ie)IIIID il aaended by Itrlklng the ~hrale "accordance With the Itand.rdl let forth In both the Diltrlct" tho I.cond time it .ppearl c. 28. S.etlon 41el(1) ot the Di.trict of COlulDhla Sec. 1-1801 nol'.l ervie bqulator-y Act of 1984, effectiv yy 22, 1984 l O.C La 5-84, D.C. Cod I.e UOJCeIC1I1, 1a ndcd by addtn9 a ntenc. at the and to read a. followl Thi l .ublect1on Ihall not apply to the r.pr nt.tly. of thu Dapar~nt of Muaan S.rvlc Sec.L_29. CecUon 406(b of the olntict of ColuAble Sec 204.6 Public AI'i.t,nc. Act of 19 ffectlv. April 6, 1982 (D.C. L.w 4-1011 D.C. Code ec. J-204.6(bll, 18 nded by Itriklnq the phral throughOut any monthl- and inlertin9 the ph~a.o ·th~ouqhout any conth" in itl piece. SIC. 30 ction 20'lb1UI or the Str.et and Alley s~«. 1_'16 Clolinq Ind Acqullitlon Proc~ur.1 Act of 1"2 frectlve rch 10, un lO.C. Lav 4-201, O.C. Code, He. 7-'26(b)(1 II anended by Itriklng the ph~al alley Iy.tem Ind inl~rtlnq the word lley" 1n itl pllce. sec. 31. S.ction 6 of the Clodn of Portlon of s 1-606 No~th-south Alloy in SQuare 830 .nd Council of thQ Dtltrict of Co lumb!« Centrll St.ff ~ploy.e Perlonnel Appeall Rul.1 Authori~ltion ACt of I,SI, effactivo October J4, 1"1 ID.C. LlW 4-4H; D.C. Cod ec. 1-606.5 il amended by Itrik!ng the phra S.ction fi O'13 a nd Inl.rting the phrl.e Ilct ion 6041«1" in itl place. Sec. 32. 6ection 7(dl(11 of thl Dilttict of Coluabia k,« 1-1906 office of tn.rgy Ac t of 198 0 effectlve Harch 1"1 ID.C. Law 3-132, D. C. Code ec. 1-19Q6(d)(1 11 Ulend.4 by .trlkinq the phra.a "the Co~ncil'l Committ on Sec. 33. S.ction J(&amp;lt;&amp;lt of the Independent Penonnel Sec. 1 8 SYltem. Impl.mentltion Act of 1~80 ffective SopteDber 26, 1980 (D.C. r 3-10'1 D.C. Cod I.e. 1-338(&amp;lt;&amp;lt iI nded by Itriking t he ph~llo "illue lubpoenal for" I"d in rting the ph ra.o "i.lu. lubpeen«1 to co.pcl" in itl plac Sec. H Sect.1on' 01 tn" Roy~0IjI~_1n poHcy ~t 01 1')80, effec tive lieptelilbcr 16, 1980 (D.C. t 100, D. C. COc aee. o-l6)I, 18 anerlded af f olio a lt;lIbaection (e)(2) ia .wended by atrikin9 tho phra. e tho COllncil ahall dia~ac or au eh notice o f eli.approval" and inaertln the phraae "the COuncil ~ay approve Or diaapprove tho re~roqr~inq reqlleat ty rC501 tion in ita pl ace b) subacedon (e h _nded by au1Unq tho ph r~s adop t od II rcaol ut i on 01 dlaapproval" and Inae rtlnq thO pheate "adopted a rc~lutlon of dlcllppeoval or apyeoval" in i ts p loco. [ c 35 rho Roald ntla1 Real Pcoparty Tranaror t"ctae 'ra Act o f 19711, eflectiv July 13, 1918 (D.C. l.Io\l 91' O. C Code eC 47-1401 t aro 18 _ended aa f ollow e ac tlon 101(f1161 ID.C. Codo ce 47-1401(6)tF i. amonded by .tcl~l09 tn. 101low109 a.nt.nc e l rhe teanafor DII.t Include auffl c lent Into~tlorl on tile rotucn, filed pursu.nt to a.ction ~05 of titlc 11 of tlll a act. t o rebut aaid yceauo~tion b amp;lIbaectionll (b) and (d) of a.ction 303 rD.C Cod cc 47-1Ul(bl and (dll aCII cllp"ded cl S.ction. 401(~I, 403(cl(3I, lind 405(c D,C. Code ce 47-14410 1, 47-14431c:lClI amp;ncI 47-1 445(ell aea oed by trikin the word al"lIGan" vh"rev"e it appeac. arid tnao etlnq tho th" vord l"aperllOn" 1n ita pl.ce d) t:lle tion 4051e D. C. Codo IIC. 4'-1445( e )1 111 amended by .trikinq tho word alo~.n and in.eetinq ~e WQed alo'p"caon in ita ~laca. ie) Cubllcetlona (bill 131, and 151 o f .ection 407 (D t Coda, lee 47-1447 (blil 3 lind (5)1 ace c.pllaled. if) Saetion 409 iD.C. Cod IIIC. 47- 1"9 1 1 nded a ollQ\lal 11 By Btritlnq thlll phrll ha a f.lled to Cl1e a c~ turn nd pay the axcl tax and oth"r aaounts related the~eto a, pr ovided i n title II of thi. lIet oC"J and By Itrlkinq th" phr e "oc exei.e ta iq cCtion SOl(a O. C. Cod e. 47-14611ell 111 .mended by s trikin the nu~erel "II" fca. the le.t .entence. Sec. J6 The aiatrict of Coluebia Govecnmcnt Compeehcnaivo l\erit Peraonnel Ac t o f I 'H8. effeetive t1.are h 3 19 79 (D.C La\l 1l9 D.C. Codc lIee. 1-601.1 et aeg iB .mended aa follo\l G.et lon 408 ID.C. Code c. 1-604.81 111 nded by atrikin the pllcase "end \lill faithfll11y diachafy" the duties of tho office Qf which nd inaertin the phra and will feithfully dilehaeye the duties of the o ffice on which" in i ts place. u ~c .41 _14I'I1 Itepe.l.d See 47-1'1l( b d) Soru .U-IUI IU 45 pul d. Sec 47 144I(b l 01. lSI s.c n ·lu, S.,c l lO 8 Ib eet l an 1114la)(2 D.C. COde. l ee. 1- 612.11(a Il2 h _ended by nriking tI'I fhrne J06In) ot title 5 of t he United !ita tel COde" and ine.rt ing t he ~hra le "5 U.S .C. 53C5IQ in itl ~laeo. Ic) Section 1717 (D.C. Coda. lec. 1-618.17) 18 nded by delitn tint t he exl. tint introductory text a. aubaection (al and redellgn ting iltin, a baectlona tal through tl balletion, Ibl through I. re'J"'ctlvaJy d) Soc tion 3202(e) 121 (D.C. Code ae. 1-63 3. 2(a 3) 1I1I) h &amp;amp;.III.nded by atrlking the phra 5 U.S .C. see. HOta)(lItC) and (a)(2 and In.erting the phra .e 5 U.S. C. JI 02(b 1)tC) a nd (bl( 2 1n ita place. Sec. 37. SectiOn 13 o f the Advlaory Neighborhood Councilll Ac t of 197 5, offective Harch 26, 1976 (D.C. Law I 58, D.C. Code ec 1-2611, i, UlflOOed a' follO'llIl (a lly ,triking in baoction IclUI tho n\Ultler "lO" a nd In,erting tho nu~r -45" in It. plac" and ,b) By .trikin\l In aub.eetion (g' t.ne phra or pr oh ibit any co..i i on" and In rting the phra or ~rohlbit any C~mla.lon.r· In it. place. S.c. l S.etlon 101 01 the DI.tric t ot Colu.ola Sal Tax Act, ap~roved Hay 27, 1 53 Ctat 112, D.C. Code c 47-2 001(a ll h repealK. Sec 3 The Income end Franchl.e Tax Act o f 1947. approvod J uly 14, un 16l Stat. lll, D.C. Coda ec. U-1801 .t I. 1&amp;amp; MOnded a. 1011011a TiC. 1, aec U o" llal12) IO.C. COde. Utc 47- 1803 3 2 i a ~endod by .trikin9 the ph~a.e a" 11~lted by a.ction 189 of the Intern"t Revenue COde of U86 tb itle J, aeetion ll"ll D.C. Code aoc. 47-180l.l, a i. ADendod by "triklng the ph ra II. 1 1~ited by action 1~9 of tha Intarn"l Revenue Code of UUi c ltle 1 eetion 3(b)14) ID.C. Code c 180l 3tb)t 4 i, amended by atriking the phra.e "Interna l R.venue Code of 1986" and in.erting the phrase "Internal Revenue Coda at 19S i" I t a p lace Id) Title 6 etlan 8(b)(1)(1;I D. C. Code lee 47-te06 6Ib)(l)(flll 11 llIIIended by s tr lkin9 the phrne ub,eetion (b of !iection 2 of Title Ill" and in'ertin9 t he ~hrale "a.ction 12)la) o f ~itlc Ill In it~ place. Ie) Ti tl e 6 etlan 8(e1l1l (D .C. Code, lJ,ec 4 1806.6 1 il &amp;amp;A4nded by tr i king the ph~a Sec tion. 47- 655 o~ 47-6 56" end In.crting the phr".e ·sec tion 435 at the Oiatr ict at Columb le Reel Pr operty Tax RC!viaion Act at u s lt 1- 612. 11 Sec. 1-6 111 .17 S&amp;lt;re. 1· 6H. 2 hp..I 5 41-:1'001 See. U-JSO].J Sec. 41-1803. 3 Sec. 47_ 11103.1 Sec 47_11106.6 Sec 1-11106.6 1974, ap",rovod S.p~.aber 3, 1974 188 SUt. 1058, D.C. Code, a.c. 47·845 in ita plac Sac. 40. C.c tio" l(h, ot the Oi.trict of Colwabia Uneoploy.ent Co.penaation ACt pproved ~u,uat 28, l'3S (4' Stat H D.C Code c. 46·101(1 01 I, ia _nded by .trik!n, the phrea Cmp1or-ent Security &amp;amp;oard" and inaerti the phraa D1etric t ot COluabla Un~ployaent Corn",en .a tion Board· in ite plac s 6-'0' Sec 41. T~o 011tr1ct of Coluebia Reva nue ACt of 1'37. approved Kay 16, I'll (SO Stet. 67 D.C. Code, eec. 40-101 at la _nd.,t .a f a ll a S.ction a o f titl. I (D.C. Code. Me. 47- 1702) i. s.c. U-1701 amond.d by .trlking the phr.a to the H.yor of the D1.triet o t col~bla" att.r the phr'ae very diatra1nt end e,le of pe r.onal property Cb) The definition of "pereon" In .ectiOll 1 of title s.c 47 HU IX to.C. Cod 41-llOllS11 1 tid b1 atriUn phra joint adventur nd 1"a.rtln9 the phr jo tit venture" 1n it. placo. S.C. 42. Section 61a) of An ACt To turther r'9ulato s 26-107 banking nka. truat eo.paaiea, and bu1lding &amp;amp;ad l~ aa.ocl.tlon. in the Di.trict of eolu.bi and for othor pur po approved KArch 4. I'll 147 St.t. 1567, D.C. Code c. 26-1071')1, 1 nded follow e' By .trikl the word "or" In pera,reph ell, and tb l By .trlkl the period et the on4 ot para9raph 121 and lnaertlng t he phra or" I" it. plaee. soc. U. An ACt Neking eWE"Opl:ieUona to p lde for t he expen a of the 90v.rnae"t of the Dl.trlct of COlu.ble for the fl.c.l 1*.r ondin9 Jun. thirtioth. ninot n hundred .nd three. end tor other purpo pprov.d July 1, 1'02 112 Stat. 622/ D.C. Code oe. 47·2801 ot S.I, 1a nded a. follow.1 la aragnph 1 of etlon 1 lO.C. Code. aoc. 41·28011 SK. 41-21101 i nded by .trlking the phl:a.e ·or chapter 30 of thi. titl her$Vor It appear b) Paragraph 4 of a.ction 7 (D. C. Code ec. 41-28B41 See. 41-21104 i, am.nded by etrlk1n9 the phra or Ch.pter 30 of thi. tltlo hel:ovor it oppeor tc oragraph' of .ec tlon 7 10.C. Code ec 47·28061 lt;te. U_71106 la nded by .trlklng the phro.o "ond Chapter 30 of thl. title d) Paregraph 7 of eection 7 (D.C. Code c. 47-2807 See. 41_21107 i endod by ctrlking the phroo nd Ch.ptor 3D o f thi. title" wherevor 1t appeara. Ie) Paragraph 46 of etion 7 ID.C. Code e. Se 1-1~U 7- 2a 44 i.1 lIr.lenaed loy Itriking the ~r.ue ~and Chapter 30 at th15 t i tl tl Pa uQuph 47 o f a.,c tlon 7 (D. C. Code, IICC. Sec 78.4~ 4 7- 28 45, 1. amend d by atrikInQ th. phr or Chapter 30 of thi.s titlo hor v r it appearl QI ParaQraph HI o f aeetion 7 CD.C. Cod aee. Sr c. 41-2I1U 7-264 6) i&amp;amp onued by atrikinq the phrale or Chapter 30 o t this title who rev.r it appearl h) Pll rllQraph 49 of lection 7 (D. C c.:ode, sec. Sec. 47-28.41 47-28 7) io a~unded by 'tri~inq tho phr and Chaptor 30 at this titl whar.v r it appelau. UI Para9raph SO ot etion 7 (D .C. Cod e. Sec. 41-2128 4 7-10 48 1 ia ~nd.a by .trikln9 the phr or enapt'r )0 at tht tIt le' wharevar it a~ara Ijl Paragraph Slot aoc:t1on 7 ID.C Cod e Sec. 41-1349 4 7 28(9) i a ~ndod by .trlkinq tha phraa or Ch'ptar )0 of tnt, titl s c 44 aetlon '9llb) of An Act tQ a,tab11ah a c~e at la~ for tha Di.trict ot Colu.ola pproved ~rch 3, 1'01 (31 SUt. 1119, D. C. Coda ac. 26-S06(b ia ndad a. t o llow a by .tri~ln9 tha word "SOard" and in.erting the wor d amp;uperint.n4.nt" 1n itl ploea, Cb By atri~ln9 tha phr i'lua ita nd 1n,.rting the phra.e IU. a Superintand nt in itl plaea nod Ie) By "rlkln, th phra prOVided. it nd lna.~tin9 ttl. phral provlded. the .uparintandant" In iea ~laco amp;ec 45. Saetion llld) ot til. Dbtriet of COluabl. Ree l ElIute Licenlura Act of 1982. affactive IMrch 10. 198 D C. Law 4-2 09, D.C. Cooe ec. 4S-lt)Otd)l. i repaaled. See 46. Thi. ae t I hell taka affaet .fte~ a '0-4.y porlod at Cony rcillonal review followlft9 Ipproval by the yor lor in tn. ev nt of veto by th heror. actio n by tn. COUncil o f tha Dl.trict o f Columbia to ova rrid th. veto) al p r ovided in a.ction 602teJ 12) of tha Dl. trlc t of Col uftbi Sllf-Govcr~cnt lind Gov r~entll Reor9anization Ac t, RePNh Sic. 45-19lO(d PfQV.d. DeC f 24, 1911 In Cut Il, D. C. Code c. 1-2J3(e)(2 o Col\lllb1. APPROYE Oeceillber 22. 1987 COUNCIL or TlR DumlCf or COLUMBIA. c P..wS COM! Of Of.1C1Al. CCIUMCIL YOTI 87-)46 OOCI&amp;lt;£T 0 I I Co CaI lI WOOl a OAT M~PUd r1u_~d.i.n9.o._1l-2 o"lL It VOle. YOf UnanlD u L 110&amp;lt It ACTION OATt C!i.~c!o lli~1 t 4!_M.J 1.11 It V01CI VOtf In L p 1 -0-7 I' II C&amp;lt;:vI 0l e .o.CTION I14T VOICE VOll o.!IM'1 i'£ 4 ,\z eM C gt;i I'tftM B </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
