<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-135">
  <num type="law">7-135</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Minor Theatrical Employment Permit Amendment Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-07-12</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-135.pdf">D.C. Law 7-135</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 4114</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-135, the “District of Columbia Minor Theatrical Employment Permit Amendment Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-397, which was referred to the Committee on Education and Libraries. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 19, 1988, and May 3, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 19, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-185 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NCIL OF TH [ DISIRICT OF CO LUMBI A NOTIce D. C. LA~ 7-135 "District o f Columbia Minors Thutr ical EmploYllel\t Pt.&amp;gt; Tlll it Amen(lmen t Act of 1\1 88 Pursu~nt t o Se c tlon 412 o f the Dis tri ct of Columb ia Se lf Go ~ern ent ftnd Govern menta l Reorg a nlation A.ct, P. L. 9 3-198 t he AU the Council o f t he Dlstrht o f Col ulllbia adopted Gill No 7-397 on f ir st and second re a d ln9s April 19. 1988 and May 3 1 988 respectively Foll owi ng the signHure of the M~yor on Hay 19 19 88 this legislation WJS Hs i gned Act No 7-1 85 publtsh d In the Ju ne 3, 198 8 edition o f the D. C. Register Vol ]5 pJge 4 11 4 and transmitted to Con gress 01\ May 24 1988 for a 30 -d ay re~iew, in acc or dance with Se ction 602(c)1 I) of t he Ac t he Cou ncil o f t he Distr ict of Col umbia he re by 9ives no ti ce that the 30 day COl\g r esslon a l Revie w Per iod has upired and t here f o r e c ites th 1s e nac t Jll ent a s D. C. La w 7~t:l5, ef ft ctt.e Jul y 12. 1988. Chairman of th e Co unc i l Da les Counte d During t he 3D-da y Con qr essl on al Revie w Pe r iod M~y 24. 25 26 .27 June 1 2 3 6 7 8 ,9,10.1 3 14,15 16.1 7 20 21.22,2 3 24.27 28 29 .3 0 July 6.7.8.11 AN ACT D.C. ACT 7-185 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE OISTRICT OF COLUMBIA pr 191m :0 a~end ~he prov!s!ons 0 he D i 5~ rict 0: Colu~ia E:nploymer'l o t1inors Act to provide ro the isscance or ~heat:rl c al employr.,er.t perni':s !o mino rs under the ~andatory school attendance age. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNC o r TEE DISTRICT or COLUMBIA, That this act may be ci ted as the "Distric 0: Coll:rr.b:il t~l no rs Theatrical Employment Permit Amendment Act or 1988 Sec. 2. The Distr c~ o! CoLumbia E;r.ployment o f: r11:-1or" }'C approved l':ay 29, 1928 (45 Stat 996; D.C. Code, sec. 3 501 e"t seg ill amendec as follows a) Sectl.on 7a (D.C. Code. lIec.3G S06) is amended to read as folI o Sec.7a.(il) The Board of Education may issue a theatri ca l employment permit to minor under 16 yea rs of age permitting the minor to 1) Perform on the staqe of a Licen s ed theatre 1 thin the Oistrict of Columbia in il professional theatrical production; conCert 2) Perform in a musical Or dance recital or 3) P r~ici.pate in a radiO o r television program 4) Participate in a motion picture 5) Appear as a fashion model; or 6) PartiCipate in a professional spOrta activity Or cl rcUS b) An application for a theatrical permit sha ll be made by the parent o r guardian, and by the agent if applicable, o f the minor to the Board of Educ ati on. The So ard o f Education ma y issue a theatrical empl oyment per~i t if the Board is sa ti s f i ed that adequate prov isions have been mad for the educa tl on" l instruction o f the minOr, f or s afeguarding the minor's health, and for the proper supervision o f the m~nor The Board of Educati on may 1 B. C, Ctlde sec. 36 506 (1989 sU!=9 require t he emp loyer to provide the necessary resources ~o sa t i sfy t~e requirements of t h i s subsection. w{c) A minor shlll i not appea r in more than 2 live pe rforma nceS i n 1 day or more than a live per f Ormanees in 1 week A mino r shall not appea r in a live perfo rmance or o therwi se be required t o work, before 7: 00 a.m. or after 11: 30 p.m A licensed practical nurse with sukllstantial pedia~r ic e xperi e nce, o r a regi s tered nur se who ie a ?edi a ric Nurse Practit ione r shall be provided fo r each 3 or f e wer infants unde r the age o f 30 months d A theatrica l emplo yment permit shall limit the l rr,e durinq hich a mlnOr 7 year s of age or youn&amp;lt;;ler is permi c~ed at the pl ace Of employment Within a 24 hour per~ od acco=ciing t o age as foll o s 1) Ar infant under the age o f 6 montbs may be pe'-T i tte(i to remiil~r. a the :pl ace of employrr.ent f or a max l:\utD of 2 ~eurs, which sr.all consi st o f not more thar. 20 minutes of work 2 A mino r be tween the age of 6 months and 30 ~on~hs may be permitted st the p lace of emp l oyment f or a max~rnum of 4 hour which s~all con e i s t of not more han 2 eu rs of work, with the balance o f t he 4-hour period being =es t er rec=eatior 31 A minor between the age o f 30 months and 7 yea~s may be perm:tted at the place of ern~ioyment fo~ a maXlmum of 6 hour Wh ich shall consist o f r:.o t more tha n 3 hou rs of work wi th t he balll.nc e of t he 6 hour perlod b eing rest, re c reation or ed1,leati on e f o r the pu rposes of thi s s e ction, the term "t!1eatrical employment permit" mean s an Authori t at ion to perform or appear in any of the a c t i vities 1isted in eubsection (a) o f th1 c tion f o r J:lonetary remuneration. a gi !t, or other form of valuable consideration b) Section 15 (O.C. Code, sec. 36 -5 13) is amended to read as follows S ec.15 a) A persor. conunit s an o ffen s e unde r thi ac t if tha t person 1) Empl oys a minor or permits a miner to work i n vtoi at~ on o f t hi s Act. of any regulat ion proll'.ul ated by the Board o f ~ducation pursuant to s ec tion 29, or of any orde r ~ssued under the provisions o f section 3; or 2 Interferes wi th the Soard of Educatlon, its of f i cers or agents, or any other p erson authorized by the Distr ict t o in spect places of empl oyment of minors b) A person convicted of a 1st o ffense under this s e ctien shall be fine d not le ss than Sl,OOO nor more t~an S3,000, or lmpri~oned not les s than 10 d ays nor more t~an 30 days, or both. A person convic t ed o f a s e cond o r subse~Jent offense u nder this s e ction shal l be f ined not ie ss t h an 53,000 nor more than $5,000, or ~mprisoned no t I eee than 30 2 D.C. Ccrle, sec 36- 513 (1989 su days :1,or more than 90 days, or both. a violation of thi s a c t occur s shall o ffense Each day dUring hieh constitute ill sepa rate Sec 3. rhi l act shall take effect after a 30-da y period o f Congressiona l reviev f o l lowi ng approval by the Ma yor (o r i n t he event of veto by th. Mayor a c t ion by the council of the 018tr1c t of Columbia t o override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) o f the D1strict of ColUmbia Sel f Government a nd Gove rnmental Reorqani~ation ACt, approved December 24, 1973 (87 St t e13; D C. Code, s ec. 1- 233(c 1», and pub lication ir. e l t her the Di strict of Columbi a Reqiste r the Di stric t of Columbi a Stat~ te a Large o r the Distri c t of Columbia Municlpal equl atcions. Mayer Di:st r ict APf'ROYED \ « L lt rrr,an Council o! the Di s trict of Col uIT~ia O lUmbia ~1a y 19 19B8 J COU~CIL OF THE DISTR ICT Of' COLU:"ofB l A eo dl I'uiud SeVeD X Co Col RECORD OF OFfIC IAL COUNCIL VOTE OOCk H 0 B7 -397 x ACllON OAn VO!C( VOTE Ad opted !J Et Reading 19 SB Ap proved Ato 1 Rola rX, Wilson a:1 d Win ter x lie eon n x ACl IO N3 DATE Adop~ed rinal Read ing 5 88 x VOiCE VOTE A.EEE0ve~ fl o ole &amp;lt;;II 'eQU05 Ol_ CAll IIOTE RESULT :OO e em 0 0 Cen,.nt CaiMda, AcnOtl to OATE VOICE VOlE RQoo e on Qu y \ j</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
