<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-130">
  <num type="law">7-130</num>
  <heading type="short">Income and Franchise Tax Amendment Act of 1986</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-07-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-130.pdf">D.C. Law 7-130</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 4104</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-130, the “Income and Franchise Tax Amendment Act of 1986,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-468. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 19, 1988 and May 3, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 19, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-180 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COJ NC(L aF THE OISTRIC T OF C~L U M 8 OTlCE D. C. LA 7-130 Pur su~ nt t o Secti on 412 of the Dis trict of Columbid Self Goyernll1ent .nd Go ve r n.ent~1 Reo r ganization Ac t. P L. 93-198 the Act th e Council of th e Oistrict o f Colu bh adop ted 6111 No 7-4 68 on fi rst and SHond readings Aprll 1 9 1988 and Ma y 3 1988 r espe ctiv e }j. Follo wi ng t he s i gna tu r e o f the Ma l1Jr on May 19 1988 this leqisl at io n as assigned Ac t No 7- 180 pub lis hed in the June 3, 1988, edit ion of the D. C. Regis ter vol. 35 p~ge 41 04 a nd tr ansmitted t o Congress on May 20 1988 f o r d 30- day revle in &amp;lt;lccordan c e i th Section 602 c ){ l o f the Act. The Coun c i l o f the Dist r ic t o f Co lu mb i a he r eby g i ves no t ice that t he l D- day Co ngress lon l Rev i e Per iod ha s e.pired a nd there for e cites this enactment U D. C. Law 7-1 30. J uly 8 19a 8 r D ~AI C.tLA~R \j'k i~.irla~n of the Co unci l Oa t es Co unted Our iMg th e 30 -d 1 Con ,r essio n~l Re.ie Period M ~y 20,23, 24,25.26.27 J ulie 1 ,2. 3,6 7 ,8 9 10 13 14 15 J6 11 20 21 22 23 24 27 28 2 9, 30 J ul y 6,7 AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 -1 80 IN THE COUNCIL OF TH~ DISTRICT OF COLUMBI A MAY I 1998 o !I I I:.C, o r. a el:l?o a y a s1s e l i st ict o [ Columb a r.come a nd :ra l:.c~ise ~ax Ac &amp;lt c 19 47 ~o rcv i de al exclus~on fr~1:l g ross nco me, BE I T ENACT! D BY THE COUNCI L. or THE DI STRI Ct or COLU~lB I A That this act ma y o e ci t ed as the I nc ome and Fr anch is Ta x n llndn':ent Tempora r y Ac t of 1989 Se c 2 Ti t le II I o f t le Di. t 1:ic t of Columbi a Income and F ranch 1se Ta x Ac o f 19~7, a p p rov ed July 1 6, 194 7 61 S ~at. 335 D. C Code Sec 47 1803 1 e t seq is amended.ls f 110 a) Sec ti on 2 1 2 (D .C Code, s ec 47 1803.2( a 2 \) is ame nded by a d d ing a ne subparaqraph P t o r e ild .I S f o:l o P I Fo r tilX ye a rs beginning i1 ft a r December 31 1986, in t he case of any p e r son e ntitl e d to I. shar e in t he inc ome of I. corporation sub j e c t t o tax u nd er t he p r ovi s i ons o f titl e VI I tha t i Is II &amp;amp;/I'la ll business corpo rat i on a s defi ne d i n section 1371 of the Inte1:na l Re v e nue Code o f 1954 h .lvi ng a n elec tion in e ff e ct u nd e 1: s e c tion 1372 (a o f the I nte rnal Reve nue Code o f 195 4 o r ii Is a n S co rpora ti o n as d e fine d ~n sect ion 1361( a) of the Int e r nill Reven u e Code o f 1966; a n amount equ.l l t o the propo r t i onat e s hare o f t h e per s o n in t h e i ncome to the e xtent tha t the propo rtionate s ha re of t he i nc ome sO e xc luded is repo rted b y a nd taxed a9ai nst the co rporat ion u nde1: the provi s i o n s o f ti t le VI I b Section 3( b D.C. Code, s ec. 47 1803 3(b» i amended by ad d 1nq .I ne w p a r agra ph (5 t o r ead a s f o llo ws 5 for t a x yea r s b eqi n n ing a ft e r Dec ember 31, 1986 a n y d educt i on p a s lng to a s t o ckholder i n a c orpo r a tlo n sub jec t t o tax unde r the p rov ision s o f ti t l e v II that A) Is a s ma ll bu s i nes s c orpora t ~o n as de f i ned i n s e c ti o n 1371 of t he Inte rnal Revenue Cod e o f 1954 1 O. C. Cede 47- 11103 1989 sup D.C. CCde 47 1303 {l989 StOp having an election in effect under aect on 1.3 72 (a) of the :r.te r al P1sr.ue :ode of 1954; cr C S III an S corporati o n as def!t:ed i n s e c t ion 13 GI Ca } of t~e Inter::l 1 Reven Ie :cde o f B a G: if the deduction is othe ~ise a llowable under the prov isions of lIubsection Cal of this sect ion in determininq the tax ble income of the corpo ration Sec. 3 a) This ot Shall take effect after a 30-day pariod of Congressional revi e w following approv l by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Counc il of the Dlatrict of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in sect ion 602 c of t he Dis"trict of Col&amp;gt lI",bia Self -Government and Gover~ental R.or~anization Ac approv ed Dece:nbe 2 19 7 3 8 7 Stat. 813; D.C. Code eC. 1- 233(c », and publicati o n 1n el the the Distric t of Columbia Reqiater, the Distri c t o f Co 1u!llbia Statutes at Large, or the District of Co1u~ia MUnic i pa l lt;1I9\l-1I1t ions b) This set shall expirll on the 225th day o f its having taken e ffect. 13 L C1l of the Oistr1ct o f Columbia ayor Di st r ic t of Columbia At't'ROVEO, Hay 19 1988 2 No D.C. Cede, sees 47- 1803 amp; 47- 1003 3 (1989 su?p ij 'OICE 'Jor AKo x&amp;gt;I~ en ·OCueS; COl NCll Of THE DIST RICT or COLU~[lH ,\ C"ullell Pe"od Seven RECORO OF OFFICIAL COUNCil VOTE DOCK(T 1'10 AO oe"t 30 11 r k, Win s l d 3c h·"a :r L S ACTIO N &amp;amp; DU E X ~OICE ~OTE Adopt ed Fi'l;ll Read i n q 5-3 88 ApE rov d roed vote on ,eQIIOSI nl Thomas, WinteF Ka n e, Schwa r tz and Wilson c OlCE von RKOl&amp;lt;leo&amp;gt gt;-01. on col RESUlT 'C 8 Oal L l 1</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
