<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-168">
  <num type="law">7-168</num>
  <heading type="short">Zoning Commission and Board of Zoning Adjustment Compensation Amendment Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1988-09-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-168.pdf">D.C. Law 7-168</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 5747</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-168, the “Zoning Commission and Board of Zoning Adjustment Compensation Amendment Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-512, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 28, 1988 and July 12, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 15, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-224 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU MBIA NOTICE o. C. LAW 7- 168 ·Zonl ng COIII. lss io n and Bo~ r d o f Zo ning Adjustlllent Co.pe nsatl o n Allend lllent Act of 1988 Pursuant to Section 4 12 of the Dis trict o f Colu.bia Self_ Govern.ent and Go.ern~ental Reorginlzation Act P. L. 93-198 thf Ac t the Ccuncll of the DistrIct of Columbia adopted 8111 No. 7-!i12 on f i rst and second readings J une 28. 1988 and July 12 1988 respectively. Follo ing the signature of the Mayor on Ju l y 15 1988 thls le91$Iation "a s as sig ned Act 140 7 224, pllbl l shed In the J\lly 29 1988 editi o n of the.2 S. Register Vo l. 35 page 5747) and tr a nslrlltted to Congress on J\lly 25, 1988 for a 30-day rev l e in a cco rda nce ith Sect i on 602{c I of the Act. The Cou ncil of the Distr i ct of Co lu. bh hereby 9hes no t ic e th a t the 30 -day Cong ressional Revie w Period has exp i red. dnd there f ore, cites thI s enactment dS C. La 7- 168 effective i RH \ the Council Dates Counted Ourln9 the 3D-day Congressional Review Period: 2!i,26 27 28 29 1,2 ,3 4 5 8 9,10 11 Septe.ber 7 ,8.9 12,13 14,15 16 19,20,21 22 23,26 27 28 o.euw 7 -188 SEP 9 t988 Codification ANAC"f District of Col uIIlb la Code (1 989 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA -ii.;iI" JUl1 IS88 To amend An Act providing for the zoninq o( the District of Columbi&amp;amp; and thf! requlation of the location, heiqht, bulk and ueea of buildings and other 'IItt"uctureB and of the uses of l and 111 the Dlstrict of Co lulllbia and for other purposes to allow for compensa t i o n of ci tizen members of ti,e Zoni ng' Commission f,or the District of Columbia and the Board of Zoning Adjustment who are employees of the federal gove rnment but who do not serve as federal government representatives. BE l'r ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DI STRICT OF COLUMB IA, That this act may cited aa the "Zo n ing Commission and Board of Zoning Adjustment Compensation Amendment Ac t of 1988 Se c. 2. Section 14 of An Act providing for the ~oning o( the Oi et~ 1ct o( Columbia and e regulati o n o f the location heiqht, bulk, and u sa. of buildings and o ther structure and of the uses of land in the Dis t rict of Coll1mbia, and f or other purposes, effective J une 20, 1938 (52 Stat 802; D.C. Code sac. 5 430 is amended by strikinq the last sentence and i nsert inq the follow i ng 2 ntence MMembers of the Zoninq Commission for the District of Columbia shall recei ve compensation in accordance with section 492(b of the District of Columbia Sel f Government and Governmental Reor9an1~ation Act approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 810; D.C. Code, seC. 5- 4l2(b » No compensation Bhall be paid to a member of the Soard of Zoning Adjuatme nt who is al.o full time officer or e~ployee of the District o f Columbia gove rnment o who .e~ve on the Board of Zoning Adjustment .s federa l government r epreaentat ive purluant to .ection 8 of this act in its pl. ce. Sec. 3 The com~nsation provided for i n sec tion 2 shall be' paid for setvicea rendered on or after May L 1988. 1 Section 5-430 Se 4. Thie a~t shal l take .f!e~t after a 30- day period o! Congressional r evi e w foll owi~9 approva l by the Mayor (or in the event o! veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the Oistrict of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in seetion 602(c){1) o f the Distri c t o! Columbia Sel f Government and Governmental Reorqanization Act approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat 813; D.C. Code, 1-233(c 1 and publication in either the District ColumDia Re qieter the District of Columbia Statutea -at-Larqe, o r the Di a tric Columb Requla t iona Chairman Council o f the Di etr ict o f Columbia 2 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Pe od SeveD RECORD OF O FFICI AL COUNCIL VOTE OClCKe T NO: B7 -51 C J(I II 0tI ColI cal T ACTION a CAn Adopted Fl rs t Mead i 1'19 6- 28.8.8 VOICE OTE Appmved AeeoOlO&amp;lt Wle On r.QU 11 present J II en C()I'IM nl GaI.ndar J}ACTIQ amp; OATE: Adopted Fi nal R~ad i ng C7_-Cl0Z_-88 [j: vOice VOTE A.Cproved IIo!co&amp;lt;dcd t. on _I A Thomas and Winter Secrel ra Irw eou 1 c Ilem CoIIoet1l Co_ o ACno amp; 0 TE; 15 I amp r V~E ~E c RO( or&amp;lt;!ed VOte on 'eGuefl r I'IOLL C LL VOTE RESULT s.c'elary to tne Co el l</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
