<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-173">
  <num type="law">7-173</num>
  <heading type="short">Supermarket Tax Incentive Amendment Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-09-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-173.pdf">D.C. Law 7-173</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 5758</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-173, the “Supermarket Tax Incentive Amendment Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-124, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 28, 1988 and July 12, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 15, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-229 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCil OF Tlf E DlSTRIC T OF CC LU~ SI~ i\ OTICE D. C. LAW 1-1 13 SupefKldfket Tn Incent i ve Amend rcen t Act of IgS8 ursuant t o S@ctlon 412 of tn e Dis tri c t of Co lum bi~ Se l f- Government Hd Gove rnllle nt!l Reorganization Ac t, P. l. 93-196 the Ac t the Counc i l o f the Distri c t Of Co lu mbia ddop teo Bill No. 1-124 on ftr st and second re adtn g Ju ne 2B 198 8 and Jul y 12. 198 6 respe c tively Follo wing the signature of the May or o n Jul y IS 1988 this legisl atio n was 4Ssl gn ed Ac t 11 0 1-22 9, publi s hed in th e July 29 1988 edi t ion of th e Reg i s ter Vol. 3 5 page 5758 n d tr a nsmitt ed to Congr e ss on July 2 5. 19 88 f o r a 3D-day r hlew, In acco r d a nce with Se ction 6D2 (c)(lj of the Ac t. The coun cn of tne Di stri ct of Colulllbh hereby gh es notic e t hat the 3D -da y Co ngreBi ona l Review Pe r io d has e;&amp;lt;pire 4 and ther e f o re. cI te s this ~n ac t. ent as D. C. L~w 7- 173 e ffective Sept ember 29, 1988 th e Coun e! l O~tes Co unted During th e 30 -da y Congress i on a l Re j ew Peri Od Ju I y 25.26, 21 28, 29 1, 2 3 4,5.8,9,10,11 Sept embe r 7 8 .9,1 2 11 4 15 16,19.2 0 .2 1 22 23.26 27 28 D.UAW 7 -173 i;i" S EP 2 9 1988 COdification AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 -22 ew c11apter 38 of Title 4- District of Colmhia Cc&amp;lt;,e (19R9 SUppl~~t l IN THE COUNC IL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUL! 51966 To provide tax exe~ptions, and other incentives for t he location of supermarkets i n under served area s of the Di s trict of Columbia and to ame nd An Act To d t!!£ine the real property exempt from taxation in the District of Columbia and An Act Making appropriations to provide f or the eXpenses of the gove rnment of the Distr_tc"o of Columbia tor the fiscal year ending June thir t i eth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other pur poses to make conforming a~endments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT m- COLm-lEIA, That this act may be cited a s tne "Supermarket. Tax Incentive Amendrnen-t Act of 1988 Sec Defini tions. For the purposes of Cbis act, the term 1 Fair market re:lt" means an amount a" de ermined by the Mayor with reference to t he ave rage rent charged to tenants for occupancy of comparable SpaCB in othe r bUildings in the underserved area 2)(A Supermarket" mean" a sel f -servic e re&amp;gt;:ail establishrr,ent, independe:ltly owned or part of a corporati on operating a Chain of 5uperrr,arkets under the same name, that i) Is lic e n sed as a grocery store pursuant to paragra ph 27 of section 7 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the Di trict of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thir ieth, nineteen hundred and thre e, and for other purposes, approved July 1, 1902 (32 Stat. 620; D.C. Code, Sec. 47 2827 ii) O!:fers for sale a full line of meat, seafood, fruits, vegetab l es, d ai ry products, and dry groceries, household prodUct s and sundries iii) Occupi e s at least 6,000 square fee of space B) The term "supermarket shal l include related service departments such as kitchens, bakerie s Section 47-3801 phar~aci.s, or f lower shops of a retail establishment t~at meets the cri teria set by paragraph A) of tni&amp;amp; subsecti on 3 Supermarket deve l opment" means a new ~upermarke t for which c on~truction besins on or afte r the effective date of thia act or an expans ion or modernizati on of an exi s ting supermarket if the expansion or mode rnization begins on or after the effective date of this act 4 Under.erved area" means an area of no more tha n on. square mile within the Di strict having a rat !o of less than 2 supermarkets per 10,000 res1dents or having less than 1 supe rmarket. Sec. J. Identifi ca tion of underserved IIre.l a) The Mayor ,hal l, wi t hin laO days of the e ffective date of this act, submi t to the Council for its approval by r eso lution, a listing of all u~~erserved area s ranked in ord er ranging from the mos t underserved to the least underserved. The Hayor may, fr olT. t!me to ti1l\e, submit to the Council fo r its apj:lroval by resolution, a 1:.1 ing o! a cidi ti or.al unde rserved area s ranke&amp;lt;:l in order ril!'lginq fr.om the mo st underserved to the l east underserved. Sec. 4. Tax a nd license f ee incentives tor supermarkets developments i n underserve~ areas. Any supe r~arket &amp;lt;:Ievalopmeot in an u!'Iderserved area approv e d by the Council. by re solutlon, shall be eligible for 1) A 5-ye. r r ea l propart y tax exemption as provi&amp;lt;:led in section l (w) of An Act To define the rea l prope rty exempt from t ilxlltion in the District of Col~mbia, approved Decembe r 24, 1942 (56 Stat. 1 089; 0 C. Cod sec. 4 7 1002( 101» and (2) A 5 year exemption fr om the licens e fee as provided in paragraph 27(b) OI aec ion 7 of An "et r1aKinq appropriil iona to provi de for the e xpenses of the qovernment of the Dis trict of ColUmbia for the f iscal y ear en&amp;lt;:l1ng June thir t ieth, nineteen hundred and three and for other purposes approved July 1 1902 (32 Stat. 626; D.C. Code, sec. 47 2627{b See. S. Se ction 1 of An Act To d enne the r eal prope rty exempt fro~ taxation in the Oistrict of Colu~~ia, approved Oecember 24, 1942 (56 Stat. 1069; D.C. Code sec 47- 1002) i&amp;amp; arnende&amp;lt;:l by addin&amp;lt;;l a new $Ubsecti on (w) to read as f olloWI: ft(wJ(lJ Subject t o the provisions of paraqraph (2) of this subsec ti on. a supe~arket devel o pment, as thst term is defined in &amp;amp;act~on 3 of the Supermarke t Tax Inc entive Ac t of 1988, in an underserved arll'4 ot the Dilltrict approved Section 47-38C2 Ne Se&amp;lt;;tio 47- 3803 Section 47-1002 pursuant to section 4 of the Supermarket Tax Incentive Act of 1988 I(2) The real property tax exemption granted by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall apply A) Only for the first 5 real property tax years beginning after the date of issuance of the final certificate of occupancy for the supermarket B) Only during the time that the real prope rty is used as a supermarket e) In the case of a supermarket development on rea l property not owned by the supe=roarket only if the owner of the real property leases the land or structure to the supermarket at a rent reduced from the fair market rent by an amount equal to the amount of the real property tax exemption D) Only during the time that the supermarket development is .i. n cClmpliance with the requit'ements of the First Sour'ee Employmen Agreement Act of 1984 effective June 29 1984 (D.C. Law 5 93; D.C. Code sec. 1-1161 et i3ecr Ii (E) In the case of a supermarket development that is a new supermarket, only i at the time construction 0 the n e w supermarket commenced no other supermarket, as that t e rm i s de!ined in s e ction 3(2) o! the Supermarket Tax Incentive Act of 1988, existed within a 1 mile radiu s of the new supe rl1Oarket Se c. 6, Paragraph 27(b) of section 7 of n Act making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Co l umbia for the fi scal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes, approved July 1, 1902 (32 Stat. 626; D.C. Code, s ec. 47- 2827(b i s amended to read a s follows b 1) O.mers or managers of bakeries, bottling e s tablishments, candy-manufacturing es'tablishments, grocery store s, marine products or fish sold a t r e ta!l, meat shops and market, stands handling fcod Or food products shall pay a license fee of $11 1 per ann Im 2) If any licensee under this paragraph shall conduct upon the same prem!ses more than one calling l i st ed in sub-subpa ragraph (1) of this subparagraph, no addit ional fee shall be r equired 3 A) Subject to the provisio:1s of subparagraph (B) of this paragraph a grocery store that is a supe rmarket deve lopment as that term is d e fined in section 3 of the Supe~arket Tax Incentive Act of 1988 in an underse rved are a of the Di strict approved pur suant to sec tion 4 of the Supermarke t Tax Inc entive Act of 1988, shall be exempt from the license f ee imposed by t his subp aragraph for 'the fir s t 5 Secti.on 47- 2827 years beqinnlog after the date of issuance of the final certificate of occupancy for the supermarket lB) The license fea exemption granted by subparaqrlph (A) of this paraqra~h shall apply 1) Only durinq the time that the real property 1s used as a supermarket 11) In the case of I supermarket development on real property not owned by the supermarket only if the owne r of the real property leases the l and or structure to the supermarket at I r ent reduced fr om the fair market rlnt by an amount equal to the amount of the real property t lX e xemption provided by sec tion lew) o~ An Act To define t he rea l property e",empt fJ;"om tax tion in the District of Columbia, approved December 24, 1942 (56 Stat. 1089; D.C. Code, sec. 47·100 2 iii) Only du d nq the ti:ae ~h;at the ~uperm&amp;amp;:ket oeve lopment ia in coroplianc e with t he requi:emen~e of the f irst Source Employme~t Agreement Act of 1984, e ffactive June 29, 1984 (D.C I:.aw 5-93: D.C. Code, aec. 1 1l6l et seg a no 1v) in the CI"e of &amp;amp; sUl'e:market developmen~ that i a &amp;amp; new aupe~;arket, only if at the time c onstructi on o f e new eupermarket co~~e~ced no other supermarket. a~ that te rm is de~ined in section 3(2) o f e Superma rke t ~a~ Incentive Act of 1988, exi ~ted within a o~e mile radiue o f the new eupermarket Sec 7. Rules he Mayor sha l l l'ursuant to ti tle 1 of the District of Columbi ;a Admini~tr;at ive P r ocedure Act, approved Oc tober 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code, aec. 1-1501 e t seg issue rule s t o i mplell'.e:lt the provisiona of this act. See. 8 Effectiva date. Thi s act shall take effect after a 3a- day period of Congre !5d onl l review following approval by the ~tByo r (or in the ev~nt of veto by the Mayor, action by the Co~n=il of t r.e Distric t o f Columbia t o override the veto) as provioed n s ect ion 602(c)(1 o f t he District o f Columbi a Sel f- Government and Covernmental Reorganization Act, approved Decembe 24, 19 73 (S7 Stat 813; D.C. Code, seC. 1-233, c I», and publication in ei ther the Di stric t of. Columbi a Ragi ater, the Di!5trict of Co l~mbia New, Se&amp;lt; 47- 3804 ~o118d Or!g1nel Statutes-at- Large, or the District of Co lumbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Colurrbia Columbia APPROVED: July 15, 1988 5 COl:NCIL OF THE DISTRICT or COLU~IBIA COllocil Period eo RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B7· 124 OOCK£T NO it II 0" Co 1 C;Jj Adop t ed first ~eading, 6-28-88 :2 ACTION &amp;amp; DAT VOICE VOTE 1\PIlCill« R. cord l d V010 0i1 rlQy e .1 all present Absen Se&amp;lt r~t to t he CoU 11 P.em 0&amp;lt;\ C I Colon dv III ACTION &amp;amp; DATE. Adopted F ind] Re od i ng 7- 12- 8 i VOI CE ~OTE Alul.rove Rocorde&amp;lt WIt. on u t T~md S and Winter SK re1"'Y 10 In. CounCil n ec n' COionaao: Act iON &amp;amp; DATE r ~olce ~QTE gt;'G te 0&amp;lt;1 ~eat</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
