<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-198">
  <num type="law">7-198</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-198.pdf">D.C. Law 7-198</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 1</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 7-198 "D.C. General Hospital Records Amendment Act of 198B Pursuant t o Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. l. 93-198 the Act the Counci l of the District of Columbia adopted Bil l No. 7-436 on first and second readings November 29, 1988, and December 13, 1988 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 21, 1988 this legislation was assigned Act No. 7-263 published in the January 6, 1989, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 36 page 1) and transmitted to Congress on January 23, 1989 for a 3a-day review, in accordance with Section 6a2(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 7-198 effective 1 f-GJ:r/'X n~fIO A t6RKE March 16, 1989 Chairman to the Council Dates Count ed During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January 24,25,26,27,30,31 February 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,21,22,23,24,27,28 Marc h 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,13, 14,15 o.ClAW 7-198 MAR l. 1988 &amp;amp;ar~lled Dr1siDLC Cod i ficat ion MI ACT Dist~ ict o~ Columbi a Code (l9fl9 Supp b.C. Acr 7 263 IN THE CO UN CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU M81A OEttl_s TO allend ttl~ D.C. Genera l Hos pita l Cor..m i ss i on Act to a ll ow t he disclosu re of hospi ta l re co r ds fn certain pr oc e edings affe cting the public interes t. BE IT ENA CTED BY THE COU NCIL OF THE DI STRICT OF CO LUMBIA. Th at th is act may be cited as the "D istric t of Colu~bf a Gene ral Ho sp ita l Rl!Cords Am endment Act of 1988 Se c. Z. Sect i on 50S of the D.C. Gener il l Hospital Comlnissio n Act effective Hay 13 19 77 (D.C l aw 1- 13 4; D. C. Co de, sec. 32 255 s a me nded H fOllows al By s trHing the word "Medical" a nd insertin g the ph rase "Ex cep t as prov ided by subsecti on (b) of th is s ection or by oth e r s tltut es of t he District of Colum bl l or the Uni t ed St ltes, medic~ l· In Its p l~ ce b) 8y deslgn"ting the ui s tin g p ar~ g r" p h as subsec tion a and c By insertinQ a ne~ subse ctio n b to read as follo ~s b) Med ical rec ordS and other Info rmation or mate ria l s may be disclosed In r es ponse t o a subpoena or cou rt pro ceeding or depositi on in a crimina l. juven I le delinqu ency IIlglect chlld in need of supervisi on or Medl c" ld fr .ud a tter Sec, 3, Thts act s hall taKe effe ct after a 3D day period of Co ngre ssional r eview foll owing apprOY&amp;lt;ll by the Ma yo r (or In the event of we to by the Mayo r, act io n by the Cou ncil of t he Di stri c t of Columbia t o ove rr id e the vet o) as pr ovided I n se c t i on 602(c)(1} of the Dist ri c t of Co lumbi a Self-Govern ment "nd Gove rnmenta l Reorga niza tio n Act. app r ov ed Dec em ber 24, 19 13 (8 7 Stat, a 13; D.C, Code sec 1-233(c)(I)I, and publication in e i th e r the Dis tr ict of Columbia Re g i s ter, the District of Col umbia Sectio!'l 3 2- 25 5 4Drolled Origlnat Statutes-at-Large. or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. ayor District APPROVED: the District of Columbia Col umbi a w COUNCIL Of' THE DISTR ICT OF COLU:MBIA Council Period eD RECORD OF OFFICIA.L COUNCIL VOTE DOCHT NO K Item on Con n! Cal or K ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted First Reading, 11 29 -8 8 1 VO ICE VOTE A,pep CCo"v"e.d Recordod vo!o on request Ab nj Rolark RO LL CALL VOTE RESULT B7 436 D.t~ X. Item on Co&amp;lt;1.ent C enct..r l[ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE lA"d"O"pc,&amp;lt d-"ji"n",1LBR&amp;lt dCi"n,qu L3;-0 x: VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vole On quest Wilson and Smith RES ULT Item on Coos ont C.aj or L' ACT ION &amp;amp; DATE: VO ICE VOTE Record ed &amp;gt;'01&amp;amp; on roquest RESU LT CERTIFICATION RECORD</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
