<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-208" flag="true">
  <num type="law">7-208</num>
  <heading type="short">Prohibition of Discrimination in the Provision of Insurance Amendment Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-208.pdf">D.C. Law 7-208</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 471</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-208, the “Prohibition of Discrimination in the Provision of Insurance Amendment Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-364, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 29, 1988, and December 13, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 6, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 7-279 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE OISTR:CT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LA~ 7-208 ·Prohibition ~f Discriminat i on l tne ~rcvisiJn of :nsur ance Amen dment Ac: of 1988 P~rsuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governm~ntal Reorganization Act L. 93-198 the Act the Council of th e District of Columbia adooted Bill No. 7-364 on first and s~cond readings Nov~mber 29, 1988, and December 13 1988, respective ly Following the signature of the Mayor on January 6, 1989, th is 18gislation ~as assigned Act '0. 7-279 publis~ed in the January 20 1989, edition of the D.C. Regist~r {Vo l. 36 page 471) and transmitted to C~ngress ~n January 23, 1989 for a 30-day review, in accordance wit~ Section 602{c){l) of the Act. The Council- of the District of Co lumbia hereby gives notice that the 3~-day Cong ressional ~evjew Period ~as expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 7-208, effective i~arch 16, 1989 [/U amp;'J f1AVI1l A. CLARKE Chairman to the Council Dates Count~d During the 30-day Congressiona l Review Period: January Z4,25,26,27,30,31 February 1,2,3,6,7, 8 ,9,21, 22 23,24,27 ,23 March 1,2,3,6,7,8,9 10,13,1 4 ,15 DClAW7-208 Enrolled Original D.C. ACT7-279 Codificar on, cis't:c=-c~ of CoLTlbiil c 989 Su!"p III THE COUNC:L ~F 7HE DISTRICT OF COL UM ~IA JAN 0 6 1989 To amend the Prohibition of Discrimination in the Provision of Insurance Act Of 1986 to allow testing for exposure to the probable cau5~tive agent of AI DS, 5trengt~en co~fidentiality requir~lT'erts nd r~v js&amp;lt the pena lty provis ions. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUIICIL OF THE DISrQ]CT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Prohibition of Discrimination in the Provision of :nsurance Amendr:1ent ct of 1988 Sec. 2. The Proh i bition of Di scrimination in the Provi.,iOfl of Insurance Act of L986, effective August 7, 1986 (D.C. Law 5~132 D.C. Code, sec. 35-221 et_seq 1 986 A.ct is afTlended as follows Section 2 (D.C. Code, sec. 35-2211 is a~ended by amending paragraph (5) to read as follows 5 HI means numan imr:1unodeficiency virus b) Section 4 (D C. Code, sec. 35-223) is a~ended as follolO 1) By repealing subsection (a and (2) By striking the phrase "HTlV -III" IOh er v er it appears and lnS rting the phr~s HIY" in its plac c) Section 5 (D.C. Cod sec. 35-224) is amend d to read as follows Sec. 5. AIDS testing standards, protocols, and app als al(I) Within 30 days of the ffective date of the Prohibition of Discrimination in the ?rovision of Insurance Amendment Act of 1988, the District of Columbia Commissioner of Public Health Commissi oner sha l l certify the testin9 protocol that is the most reliable and accurate in identifying exposure to the probable causative agent of AIDS ARC, and the HIV infection. The notice of certification shal l incl ude an estinate based on scientific 1 2ection j5-22 olled Original ev i dence of the Jrop orti on of false pos i: ive sul t5 expec:ed n use of t~e test i ng Drotocol 2) Withi ,l 12 ;1 0nths from the da:e o~ t~e initia l certHicat i on and at least annually tner edfter, tne Commissioner shal l putllish a new or renewal certification based upon an ongoing review of scientHic ev i cence regarding the accuracy ~nd reliability of the testing protoco l bill) A named i nsured ~ho tests posit i ve ~nder th e testing protocol cert if ied by the Commissioner I~ ay apoeal t o the Superintendent of Insurance Superintendent to rev ie w the test i ng procedures and results, dnd ~ay present additional medical evidence, including the results of similar tests for exposure to the probab l e causative agent of A.IDS that the named i nsured independently obt a'ns to rebu t the positive test results. I~ t he Superjn~en 1 en: determines t at the resu l t of the test of t he nr ouosed in su red is not a tr~e posit ive t ~e Super'ntende~t s ha or d er t he insurer from ~hic h the ap p;i cant sv ugh: cD'Ierag2 to disre ga ~d the positive test result. The Super in tendent Shil.ll, when necessary, request the advice of the CommiSSioner in mak ing this determination 2) Hearings related to t he appeal pr ovided for in pdragraph 1 of this section shall be held in accordance Ilith the District of Co l urnbid AdMin is trative Procedure Act, a pp roved October 2 1 1958 (82 Stat. 1203; D.C. Code, se c 1~15 01 et sl 3) An insurer shall a pply stdndard u nde rwriting p ractices, in accordance with ap p licab le l aws and r~les of the Di str ict. to all life, nedlth, ar d~sil. bility incJ':le insurance pol i cie, or contracts f Dr i ndividual&amp;gt gt;lho test positive under the testing protocol certj&amp;amp;ied by he Gommi ssi oner d) Section 6{b} (D.C. Code, sec 35~225{b)} is repealed e) Section 7 (D.C Code, sec. 35 22 5) is amended to read as follows Sec. 7. Informed consent re'I~1 re r e~ts; restrictions on disclosure a) No insurer shall request Qr r eq uire a proposed insured to take the testing protoco l cert i :ied pursuant to section 5 without first obtainin g t he signature of the propos·ed i.nsured or the legal guardian of the named insured on a standard informed consent sta te'1 ent prepared and furnished by the Superintendent {b} An insurer sha l l pro v ide in fo rmation ab o ut t he availdbi l ity of counse l ing at pub li c and priva te health facilities to each proposed in sured who t he insurer requests or requires to take the testing pro to co l 2 Section 05-225 SeCticR 15-226 Ecrollo4 Or1g!nal c: Bef ore dry Jrap cse d inSJred o r ~i5 r ~er legal 9u~r:.li d n is reQueStec to s ign aM inf~r"e.j consent Hdtem e t 'le in ~urer ~nall p r 'l1(d e t he ;J r opose1 (n 'iure·j or "i$ or her l egal guaroian an eXJ~a1ation o~ t he natJre o f JS, lR and t e HI~ infec ion an e~ plan atl on 1f t~e test'ng protocol l11cluoin9 lti purpose potentIal ~ses limita t ions a no a n Jp&amp;lt;hted perce nta ge of fa lse posi ves an d notic e of t he right of t h e proposed insur e d t o appe~1 tJ the Sup er intendent of Insurance. a n e x?ldnat10n of he ~eani ng of te s t re s ults, and a d@ sc r lpti on of t he di sc l o s ure reH r i ctions es t a l)l i$hed by tMi s act d) Once an ins urer ha s r!Q ue s ted s igna t ure on an i nf o r me d co nse nt stateme n t pursuan t to e ara gra ph a a nd has coapl ied wit h parag ra phs b) and (cl of this s ect ion the pr opo sed Insu red or l e ;al nua ~didn a f t "e proposed Ins u r ed a y "M it 14 d a ys before Slgnl1 ·] t 1e informed COn5er gt;ta:~p;] e'1t 1 l.n ins'~rer 1a 10 s c·,ose he f a tn~t ro posed in su r ed ~as tes t ed or the ~es ul t5 of e t est e~ c @pt to 01.1 The jlro~o sed insured or th e le gal g uardi a n of t he propos ed insur ed 8) A co urt of comDetent ju r isdiction jlur suan t to 3 lawful court orde r o r "je) Any person na~ed In 1 wr i tten aut l"lo r j zat ion executed by the p r opos eo insu red o r th! l ega I guardian of the pr opos ed insur e d 2) I n i 'l $u re r that r eQuI res estjn g o f a pr opos ed i nsu r ed s ha II rna I nt~ i n r ecor~s a~d e s ta b l 5h pr oc ed~ res in a manne r th~t prot eCt S :h e priva cy of !h e pro ~osed in s ~r ed a nd t h e confiden tiality of tMe test r esults 3 ){ 1 The Sup er intende n t o f In ~uranc e Ill a y. by ru l e re qu i re an i nsure r to r! port n lIe Tic a l d ata r ega rd ing test r! 5u l ts t o tne Commi ss i on er f or t1e li"i ted pu r pose of performi n9 epide~ i olog tca l studi e s e 1 e. add r e ss o r o t her i nformati o n t h.t rev ea l~ tne l.:1ent y of the indiv Id ual tested s ~all not be re po r d tJ t ne Sup e rin t end!nt 8) An insurer sha l I rep ort num er ica l data r eg ard i ng test re s ults to actu ari e5 e ay e d o r consulted by t he I nsur e r for t he l l ml t@d purp 05e o f ~e rf o rmin9 actu~ri al s t udies re l ated t o the ~usiness o f l~S'HanC e. The na m address o r othe r info r ma tion that r e edl~ t h e ide nt ity o f the an individu al tested sha ll no t be r e po rted t o t he a ct ua r i es f) Sect io n 8 (O.L Cod e, s e c. 35 -227) is a men·d e d t o r ead dS fol10 \0 5 Sec. 8 Con testabi l ity. J seetic:l 15-22 r. hsu rer y ntest tn~ Hlldi ty of a p'll~Cl o r con t c f o r J vears f r J~ t1e da t e o~ i5suanc er.~me~ t r renewal of :he policy or C'ln tract if tne basis f~ r con t esting the va, i d ity is t~at t~e i ns ur e d owi ng1} fa;ied o r refuSed to d i s c 1o sI! to the I nsurer t hat he or Sil l! had AID S a t the time of i ss uance amendmen t, or ren lll,a l of any ;lo11Cy issued unde r t he 1986 Act. and th e i nsura nce compa ny wa s prohibited by law fro~ conduc t Ing a t es t to de tern i ne t he posur e of t~e i nsured t o the _IDS virus on he dat e t he ln~ urer and ins ured entered in to a contract 9) Section 9 (D .C. CGde. set. 35 228) is a men ded t o read a s fol1o\ols {. l An i nsu r e r o r a n gent. br oke r or employ e e of t he i nsurer who viol a tes dny pr ovision of this act or r u le issu ed pu r suant to t hi s act shall be subject to the suspe nsion or revoc~tioo of i t s licens e or c e rt ifica te of tllority t o tr~n,act business 1" th e DiS trict, as ~ppropriate, in acco r dance with t ile provisions o f iec l0ns 6 Jnd 27 Of tne Lif e In s ur ance Act app r oved Ju ne 19, 193 4 (48 Stat. 1131, 1140 D.C Cod e seCL 35 405 and 35-42 6 a nd sections 3 a nd 36 of t he Fi re and Cas lt y Act, app r oved October 9, 19 40 (5 4 Sta t, 1066, 1079 D. C. Cod e sees 35 \506 and 35- \5 40 or ot he r applicabl e Di s trict la ws b) Any person who viol ates the r e strictions on disclosure in section 7(d) shall be fined not less than S500 or mo re tha n S5,O()O for eac h disclosu r e. In t ile case of an I nsure r or an agent, br oker or e~ploy ee of an insurer, th e fine shall be 1n add i ti on to the penalties provided in subsection (a of this section c Any perso n inju red as the result of a viol a t i on of th is ac t or a ru l e issued pursuant to t his act, may bring fn ac t ion fo r civil dam a g~s and othe r approp r i at@ r@ 11 e f in t l1 @ Supe r i or Cou rt of t he Dis t rict of Colu mbia wi th out f ir s t pur sui nl ad~ in is trative reme die s 11 8y adding a new s ec t io n 11 t o read as foll ows S e c. 11. Prohibit io n aga in s t di sc r i mination i n th e use of AID S te s t s a) No insu rer shull 1nqu i re about t" e s e~ ual or ientatio n of an up plic a nt in an app li cat io n fo r hea l t h li f e or dis ab ili t y i ncOQe i nsur ance cover ag e or I n an i nvest i gat io n co nd uct ed by an in su r e r or i nsu r anc e suppo rt o r gan izatio n on be ha lf of an i ns ur e r in connect i on wi th an dPplication fo r th e cove ra ge b) Se xual ori e nt a t i on sh a l l not be used as a facto r in the underw r i ting pr ocess or In th e deter~ina t jon of i nsurabi li ty e) Insuranc e support or gan i l a t ions sh a ll be di r ec t ed by insu r e r s not t o inve s t iga t e di r ectly or ind i re c t ly the se xua l or ie ntation of a pr oposed insured sec:;lcr. 35- 228 ew Sec~io 5- 2 d) 4n InS Jr c c~p a ny sr~1 1 no t use se~u J l cr~e ntdc lo n, l ifes :J~e. I t'lin g a~ rd ngemen:5, QCC~p~t T O gend er, o e~ e flcl r l des ign! ti0 1 t o de t!r~tne w~~t\1~ r t t est an i n11 vi dual nOJ o plies fo r lif e 1eal~h or dt$d.bil y inco"!e insu r ance Sec 3 7 is act sn al 1 t l k~ e f fect afte r a 30 day oeriod of Congression al r eview following a pp r ov al by t he r·l o!1y o r (or in the even t o f veto by t he Mdyo r detion by tne Co unc il o f the Dist r ;ct of Colu mbi a t o ov e rride t he vetoj a s p r ovided In se c tion 6 02(c I) of t~e Dist r ict of Colu mbia Self Gover nme nt a nd Goye r nme n ta l Re org an i zat ion Act, a pp r oved O~ c em t)er 2 4, 197 3 (8 1 5tClt. 813; D.C. Code. s ec 1- 23J{c)(I a nd puolica t io n I n e ith er t he Dis tr ic t o f (Ol umbia Reg i st er th e ~i stri ct of Colunbia S: atu te Lar ;e or tne Dis t rict of :ol umb1 a Municlp ~l Re'J·J 13t iolns. Chd irman Councll of t tl e Dist rict ~f ColU Mbia ay o r Distr 1c t of Co lu r:1bla APPROVED: January 6, 1989 I COI;CoICIL or THE DISTRICT or COlt.;MBIA Coundl Period Sevon RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE x 'C'C lt;,O- E 0'0 00 10 "n rt" j lt;o l a lt; X "en C e C" t ACTION I. DAr j\c.opt ec L:f',31 lC OIC E VOlE Approved fIo-co lt;"Ol ut!1 ~OLL C ll VOTE RESUlt DocKn 1&amp;lt;0 B7 i.2:l l t&amp;gt;Hn ROll C~lL VOTE RESUlT </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
