<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-214">
  <num type="law">7-214</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Spouse Equity Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-214.pdf">D.C. Law 7-214</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 513</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-214, the “District of Columbia Spouse Equity Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-389, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 29, 1988 and December 13, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 6, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 7-289 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRI CT OF CO LUMBIA NOH CE D.C. LAW 7 214 "D. C. Sp ouse Equit y Ac t of 1988 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columb i a Self Govern~ent and Govern.tntal Reorg anizati o n Ac t, P. L. 93- 198 the Act th. Counci l of the District of Colu~bia adopt t d Bil l No. 7- 389 on first .nd second readings Novuber 29, 1988, an d Oece~ber 13, 1988 respectively. follow i ng the signat u re of t he Hayor on January 6 1989 this leg islation has assigned Act No 7-28 9 publish. d In the J anury 20, 1989, ed 1tl on of tlte D. C. Register Vo l 36 page 513 and trl.n$llitted t o Congr~ss o n January 23 1989 for a 3~-day review in accordance W'Hh Sect io n 602 c II of the Act. The CounCil of the District of Columbia hereby gives not ic e th.t the 3D- day Congressi on. l RevieW' Per iod has npired, a.n d t heref ore cites th i s tn.ct.ent H D. C. law 7-2 14 effe c tive March 16 1989. DAVI D A. CL ARKE Chairman t o the Co uncil O.te s Co unted Dur i ng the 3D-day Congressi ona l ReV i ew Pe ri od: January 24 25 26 27 30 31 Febr uary 1,2,3,6,7,8,9 ,2 J ,22.23,24,27,28 Marc h 1 ,2,3,6 1,8 9 10,13,14,15 D.C.lAW 7-214 ~rolled Or1s!~e! OXIification. AN ACT New Olapt:er )0 of title 1. District 01; CblUlbia ctxle (19R9 SUw D.C.ACT 7 2 89 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUM BIA JAN 1989 To provide that the Mayor s hall ho nor quali f ying co urt orders reg'l"'dln9 reti r ement henefiC$ under c erta in DiHrl ct ret l·rement 5yste~s and t o al low f o rmer spouses of Dis trict govlrn~ent employees to enroll i n ce r tai n hea lth henefit plans. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRIC T OF COLUMBIA. That th ls a ct I)'Y be cited IS t he "Ohtrlct of Col umb ia Spouse Equ ity Act of 1988 Sec. 2. App licati on. This act slla! 1 apply t o any Distr ic t employ ee or Dis trict ret i ree wh o is covered by the retiremen t pr ogram defined under se c t i on l 02(7 A) or sect i on 102(7 C) of the Distr ic t of Cnlumbia Retire~ent Ref or m Act ppr o ~ed NQ~emb er 17 1979 (93 Stat. 866; D.C. Cod e, sec. 1-702 (J)(Aj and (C ar the retireme nt program es t ab lished by s ect io ns 2603 through 2612 of t he Dis t ric t of Col umbia Go~ernme nt Co~pre hen $lve Mer i t Personnel Act of 1978 e ff ective October I, 1987 (D.C. l aw 7- 27 D.C. Cod e secs. 1- 627.3 t o 1-62 7.1Z Sec. 3. Definitions 1 Court order" means any j ud gment dec ree or property settlement issued by or a pprov ed by any cour t of a ny State t il e District of Coiur.lb i a, the Common wealt h of Puert o Rico Guam the No rther n Hariana Isl an ds or the Virgin Isl ands, and any Na tive Am e r ic an cou rt I n connect io n with, or Inci dent t o tile divorce annulmen t of mar riag e or legal separation of a Distri ct employ ee or retiree 2 E~pl oye e· mean s a n indi vi dual wh o performs a fu nc ti on or t he Dist r ic t gover ngent and who receives compensati on for the perf orfllan ce of th e ser vices, a s provided I n secti on 301(7) of t he Dis tr Ic t of Columbia Government Comp r ehe nsive Mer i t Pe rs onnel Act of 1978, I N,w, Section 1-3001 New don l 1nn2 Enrolled Origical effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code, sec. 1-603.1(7 3 Qualifying court order" means one that by its terms awards to a former spouse all or a portion of an employee's or retiree's retirement benefits, a payment from an employee's or retiree's retirement benefits, or a survivor annuity. The court order must state the former spouse's share as a fixed amount, or a percentage or a fraction of the annuity, and shall indicate hether the former spouse should receive the amount awarded directly from the District. For purposes of awarding a survivor annuity, the court order must also either state the former spouse's entitlement to a survivor annuity or direct the employee or retiree to provide a survivor annuity. Sec. 4, Compliance with court orders a) For purposes of this section former spouse" means a living person whose marriage to an employee or retiree has been subject to a divorce, annulment, or legal separation resulting in a court order, except that with respect to an award of a survivor annuity, it additionally means a living person 1) Who was married for at least 9 months to an employee or retiree who performed at least 18 months creditable service in a position covered by 1 or more of the retirement slstems in section 2; and (2 Whose marriage to the employee or retiree was terminated prior to the death of the employee or retiree b) The Hayor shall comply with any qualifying court order that is issued prior to the employee's retirement. Any qualifying court order that awards the entire amount the retirement system is responsible for with respect to that employee bars recovery by any other person c) The Hayor shall comply with any qualifying court order that is issued after the employee's retirement only to the extent it is consistent with any election previously executed at the time of retirement by the employee regarding that former spouse. Any qualifying court order that awards the entire amount the retirement system is responsible for with respect to that employee bars reco~ery by any other person d) The Mayor is not Obligated to comply ith qualifying court orders issued prior to the effective date of this act e 1) Any reduction in an employee's annuity, made pursuant to the relevant retirement system in order to provide for a survivor annuity awarded by court order, s~al1 cease upon remarriage of the former spouse if the re lnarriage occurs before age 55. 2 New, Secti on 1-3001 &amp;amp;Qrolled Orlg1~al (2) Payment of a survivor annuity to a former spouse pursuant to court order shall cease upon the remarriage of the former spouse if the remarriage occurs before age 55. Sec. 5. Conforming amendment. Section 17 of An Act for the retirement of public-school teachers in the D1strict of Columbia, approved August 7, 1946 (60 Stat. 882; D.C. Code, sec. 31-1238 is amended by striking the word "None" and inserting the phrase E~cept as provided in the District of Columbia Spouse Equity Act of 1988, none" in its place. Sec. 6. Enrollment in Health Benefits Plan a) For purposes of this section former spouse leans a living person 1) Who was married for at least 9 mont hs to ~n employee or retiree who performed at least 18 months creditable service 1n a position covered by 1 or more of the retirement systems referred to 1n section 2 of this act 2) Whose marriage to the employee or retiree was terminated prior to the death of the employee or retiree 3) Who was enrolled as a family member in a health benefits plan approved under the Federal Health Benef i ts Program or in a plan approved under sections 2105 through 2113 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive ~lerit Personnel Act of 1978, effective October I, 1987 (D.C. law 7-27; D.C. Code, secs. 1-622.5 through 1-622 13) at any time during the 18-month period before the dissolution of the marriage by divorce, annulment, or legal separation; and (4) Who is receiving any portion of an annuity or survivor's annuity or is ent i tled to receive an annuity or survivor's annuity pursuant to an election by the employee at the tirne of retirement, a qualifying court order, or the provisions of the retirement system b) Any former spouse of an employee or of a retiree may enroll in a health benefits plan approved under the Federal Employee Health Benefits Program or in a plan approved under sections 2105 through 2113 of the District of Columb i a Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective October I, 1987 (D.C. Law 7-27; D.C. Code, sees 1-622.5 through 1-622.13 e) Any former spouse IO"ho enrolls in a health benefits plan pursuant to subsection (b) of this section may elect to enroll either as an individual or for self and family, subject to an agreement by the for mer spouse to pay the full subscription charge of the enrollment, including any amount set aside for the ad ministration of the health benefits plan and any necessary reserves as determined by the Mayor. 3 5ec icn 3l- 12lfl New, Section 1- 300'\ ADroll~d Origiaal (d Only fo rmer spou ses whose m r ri ge s we~e dissolv e d after t he e ff ec t ive d t e of th is act t h r ough d i vorce, a nnul me nt o r leg al sepa rati on s ha ll be e ligi ble t o e n r oll in the health benefit plans. Sec. 7 Ru l es. The May o s hal l pu ~s llant t o t i tl e 1 of the Di str ic t o f Colu mbia Ad ~inis trat l ~e Proc ed ure Act pp~o ved Oc to be r Zl 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D. C. Cl)de sec. I-1S 01 et se q APA is s ue prl)posed rules t o implement the provisi o ns of th is ac t. The propose d r ules s hall be Sub mitted t o t he Cou ne ll of th e Distri c t of Cohmbia Co une ll fo r a 45- d4y peri od o f review, u clu dlng Saturdays, Sundays. l eg al hol i day s and days I)f Counc i l recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed r ules, In whole or in part, by re so lution wi t hi n t his 45 day rev i ew peri od, t he propose d r ul es sh all be deemed approv ed Noth i ng i n thi s s ec t io n s ha l l affec t any re quire_ents imposed upo n t he !layo r by t i tle 1 of the APA Sec. 8. Effective Date. This ac t s ha ll take ef f ect dfte r a 3D- day peri od of Co ngres s io na l re v i ew f oll owing I pprOH I by the Hlyo r (o r i n t he event of ve t o by tl'le Mayor, ac tion by t he Cou nci l of the Dist r i c t of Columbia to override the veto)as provid ed in se c t i on 602 (c 1) of the Di stri c t of Columbia Se lf Go vernment an d GovlrnEle n ta l Re o r ganizaU on Ac t, a ppr ove d De cem be r 24 19 73 8 7 Stat. 813 D. C. Code, s ec 1- 23 3(c I Ind publi cation I n either t he Di stri c t of Columb i a Regi s ter, the Distri c t of Columbia Statut e s-at- La rge or the Di str ic t of Col umbia Muni cipa l Regul ati ons IL'l1~;Z h Ir.,an Cou nc i l of t he Dis tri c t o f Col u~b j of Colu mbia January 6, 1989 4 New ion 1- 3006 COliNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLlIl'tffilA c r.DciI Period SeVtD RECORO OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE OOCKU NO c Ill. It on CQn n' c.r » cOON' D TE A".0I1l'P1t U'C r t R i"n,'u.~1,'C 2"c-1 L VOICE voTE A""p r'o"yo·,d F\oocofUO&amp;lt;I On 1'1&amp;lt;1 D~I O r"k c C l,L VOT E RESULT 2l "CTION &amp;amp; DUE Ad o 1t ClP n l'e-lR d""i"n.qu.~lL2 1'c L VOICE VOTE A lt r"o"y d on'_1 Wilson and Smith C CT ION &amp;amp; O"T VOIC~ vone RKOn:lo&amp;lt on 01 OLl c,o,LL VOTE RESULT 1 1 l S:;O ory!O Coun&amp;lt;:i l</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-529.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-529.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-529.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-529.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-529.05"/>
  </section>
</document>
