<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-217" flag="true">
  <num type="law">7-217</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-217.pdf">D.C. Law 7-217</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 523</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-217 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-86, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 29, 1988, and December 13, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 6, 1989, it was assigned Act No. 7-292 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>• COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTIC E D.C. LAW 7-Z17 Ed ucatlon~l Institution Licensure CommIssion Amenaraents Act of 1988 Pu rsu ant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self Governlilent Ind GQyernmtntal Reorganization Act, P. L. 93 19B the Act th e Council of th e Dls trict of Columbia adopted 31 11 No. 7·86 on f f rs t and second readings Nov e llbe r 29 19B8 and December 13 1988 respecthely. Ftlll owi ng the s ignat ure of the Mayor on J anuary 6. 1989 this leQislation was a ssign e d Act No. 7-292 pub lls hed In the Ja ll uary 20. 1989 ed H lon of the D. C. Registe r Vol 36 page 523) and tran SMitt ed to Co ng r es s on JanuHY 23, 198 9 f or a 3D day reyiew, ill i ,cord.,nc e wit h Section 602(e)(I) of the Act The Counc i l of t he Dis tr ict of Columbia hereby give s not ice th at the 3D day Congr e ssion al Revi ew Period has e~pfred, and there f ore c i tes th i s enact.ent as D. C. l aw 7-2: 17 effective March 16, 1989 DAVID A. CLARKE Ch a irman to the Council Oates Counted Ou r lnq the 3a -day Co ngre ssion il Review Peri od Ja nuary Z4,25 26 27 30 31 Febru ary 1,2,3,6 7,8 ,9 .21,2:2:,23 24, 27,28 Harch 1,2 3,6,7,8,9 ,1 0 ,13, 14,1 5 D.C. lAW 7 211 MAR 1 6 19S5 ~polled Original Codification. District. of COlunbia Code (19A9 SUpp A~ ACT 1M THE COUNC IL OF THE DIS TR ICT OF COLUMBIA JAN 0 &amp;amp; lUg To ame nd t~e EdUCat ion licen sur e Commissi on Act of 1976 BE IT NA CT ED BY THE COU NCIL OF THE DISTRICT Of COLUMBIA That tllis act may be cited as the "Educ ati onal Ins t i t u t io n licensu r e Commissio n Ame ndme nts Ac t of 1988 Sec. Z. The Educat io n Llc ensu r e COllm iss io n Ac t of 1976 efhct ive April 6 1917 (D. C. La w 1- 10 4 D.C Code. sec. 31 -1 60 1 et seq 1s amended lS follo w Sect i on 10 1 (D C. Code sec. 31 1601) 1s amended to r ead as follo ws The ou rpe St af t hts act s t o provide for t he protectio n education, and we l far e of the c it iz e ns of the Dist r ict of Colu~bid dnd its s tu de nts, by 1) Establtsh l ng mi n imu m s t and a rd s con ce r nin 9 the quallty ot pos tseco ndary educ,Hion ethic a l and busin ess pra c ti ces hea l t h and ufety, a nd fis cal r esponsibi li ty, to pr otect agai ns t Substandar d tn nsi ent, une t hi cal deceptive o r f r audu1en t posts eco ndary educational Ins titu t iOns a nd pra c t Ic es 2) Pr ohIb i ting the grantin g of fa l se o r ~l s1 e adin g post secondary educ a tional cred e nt ials 3) Prohibit i ng mi s l eading l iterature, ad~ert j slng, solicita t io n, or r ep r ese ntation by postsec ondary educ a ti o na l in s tituti o ns o r t!alr agen ts 4 Providing for the p r e s ervat ion of es sent i al academiC re co rd S 5) Provid i ng f o r a co~ml s slo n t o advise the r~ayor and (o un cl1 of the 01s t ri ct of Col umbia as to th e postsecondary eduoti on a l needs of the Di stric t of Columbia d 6 Prov iding fo r a commi SS ion t o se r~ e as the State Approvin9 Agenc y f o r veterans benefits b) Sect io n 201 (O. c. Code, s ec. 3 1- 1602 5 a ~ended as fo llow S: 1 lt;ion 11- 1601 Section 11- 1602 rolled Original (1) A new subsection (a-I s added to read as follows a-I Accredited e~ns approved by an ac c rediti ng association recogn i zed by the United States Oep art~ent of Education 2) Subsection (d D.C. Code sec. 31 1602 (4 Is a mended to read as follows d Educational I nstitut i on" means 1) Any ent'ty or person organized or chartered in the District 2) Any branch, extens i on o r faclllty of an entity operat1l1g i n the Distri c t, but o r qanized or chilrtered outside of the District that furnishes or offers to furniSh in the Dis trict instruction or educational services hading toward a postsecondary degree, diploma, or certificate; or 3 An en t ity that I s o r qantzed or chartered and that operates outs ide of the District of Columbia, but thr ough dgents offers Instruction or educational services to res idents of the Dis trict 3) A new subsection (d-I D.C. Code, sec. 31-1602) is added, t o read as follows: Old_I Certificate" or "diploma' me~ns a document, designation, mark appellation ser i es of lette rs or word s academic o r honor.ry t i tle, o r o ther symbol t hat signifies, purports or I s generally t a ken t o Signify s~tlsf~ctory comple t io n of the requirellients of an academi C, education 1 vocational or professional program of st udy at the postsec ondary l eve l but does not includ e completion of d program for a degrae 4 Subsection e o.c. Code, set 31·11)0 2( 5 is a mended to re~d as fo ll ows e Oegr ee eans a document, designation, mark app ellation, series of letters or words, academic or honorary titles, or ather sYl:lbo l that signifies, purports or Is generally takell to s i gnify uthfactory compl e t io n of the requirements of an acade~lc, educat iona l or professional program of study for the Assochte, Bachelor, Master or Doctor leve l of co l lege or univers ity educati on 5) Subsec t io n g D. C. Code, sec. ]1-1602(7 is amen ded t o rea d a s follows g Education edUcational se rvice s or a like term lII eans c l ass, course or progra m of tralnill9, s upervision, I nst ru ction, o r study at the po s tsec ondary l evel I n what ever form, manner or mediu m provided 6) Subsection (j O.c. Code, se c 31-16 02( 10 is aPlended by striking t he phrase "Edu cat i ona l 1'15tltu11on" a nd i nserting the wo rd "Education" in its pl ace 7) Subsection k D.C. Code, sec 31-1 602(11 Is amended by addin g the phrase ·org~n l ~ed or" be fo r e the wo rd "chartered z Enr ol led ori ginal (s) Ne~ su bsectIo ns (1 1) and (1- 2) are added, to read as f ollo ~s I-I Non profit means an organizatIon or In stitution that IS exempt from federal Income tax under the provisions of section 501(e)(3) of the lnternal Revenue Cod e of 1986 (IOO Stat. 2085; 26 U.S.C. 501(c)(l and thlt meets the requ i rements of the District of Col umbia Nonprofit Co rporation Act approved August 6, 1952 (76 Stat. 265 D.C. Code sec. 29-501 et seg 1- 2 Postsecondary" mea ns the level of ed uca t ion beyond h i gh school 9) SectIon 2Dl(m D.C. Code, sec, 31-1602(13 is a.ended as follo~s A) By inurting t he phrase 'operated f or. profit" after the phrase eans 4 pr'v4t~ l y-o~ned sChool 8) By striking the word "or' before the lt;lord "clerica l' and by i nserting the phrase "or ot her" after the lt;lor d c ler lcal and (el By striking the perIod and add ing at t he end the followIng phrase or an entity or ganized or chartered and operating outs ide of t he DIstrict, whi Ch through agents offers i nstructi on or education~1 serv I ces to resIdents of t he District c Section 3 (D.C Code, sec. 31-1603) Is am end ed to read as f ollo s s ~c 3. There Is established for the District of Col umbia an E4ucat ion Licensure Com~is$ l on CommisSion wh i ch shall lice nse postsec ondary educat i ona l fnstitutions subj ect to this act lnd the ir agents, ensure authenticity and legitimacy of tht educational institutions, serv~ as the State Approving Agency f or veterans educational ben~f1ts, provide standards and crit~r j a, and ad mi n is t er rules and r egu lat Ion s, Including rul~s of procedure f or the Commission to ensure adequate public notice af ea ch meeting of the Commi 5$1 on d ){ l) Sec ti on 4 (b D.C. Code, s ec. 31 160 4(b is amended as fo110 s A) By striking the phrase 'five ye a rs" and Insert ing the phrase "3 years' in Its place; and (S) 8y strik i ng Ute second, th i r d and fourth sentences and i nser t ing in their place the fol10 ing sen tences Members may not be a ppointed to se rve f or more than 2 c onsec ut i ve t~rms. Any person appointed to f i ll a vacancy on tne CommiS Sion sha ll be appointed to serve the remainder of the term In the sa me manne r as t he origi nal selection. Persons ~ppolnted to fill the r elll.lnde r of a tera her~ t he re~ain der is less than one half of t he original ter m, gay be reappointed to 2 full te rms J Sect.ior. 31- 1603 Se=ioo 31- 1604 Enrolled Original (2) Section 4 (c D.C. Code, sec. 31 16D4 (c I s amended to r ead as f o llows cl Any membe r of t ~e Commis s ion w~ o 1$ or ha s been with in 12 ~on th s of appo i ntment. an offic er, emp loyee s tudent trustee. or member of t he go~ernin 9 beard of an edu cat io nal In s titution ope r at i ng I n t~e Dis tr i ct o f Columbi a t hat is subject to l i ce nsu re by t he Commission o r ha s a financ ia l intere st I n an educational insti t ution subj ect to licensure sh al l not pa rtic ipate In a ny ma t t er befo re the Comm iSs ion conce rning the i nstituti on e) Section 5(b D.C. Code, sec 3l 1605(b is amende d to read as fo ll ow s b) Personnel sh~ll be app oi nted and comp en sa tion f l ~ed In acc o r da nce wi t h the pr ovis i o ns of the Dis tr ict of Col umbia Gov ernment Co~p re h ens l ve Mer i t Personnel Ac t of 1978 effect ive March 3 1979 (D.C. Law 2-1 39; D. C. Co de, sec. 1- 601.1 et seq f l) Section (6 b D. C. Co de, sec. JI -1 606(a)} is aGe nded to read as f o llows b l) Th e Commi ss io n shall license degree gra nt ing Ins titutions a nd ins t i tut i ons that give instruction that result I n c r edit towar d a degree as f ollows A) A pr oY isionl l license shill be awarded to every institution upon i nitial lic ensu re, which shall be for such per i od as the Comllis s ion de e",s necesury before th e i nstitu tion Is eligible fo r a perma ne nt lic en s e The award of the pro~isional license sha ll be base d upon the Com mis s io n' s det rmination that the in s ti tut io n complies or can within a re aso nab l e ti llle comjlly with a ll r equirements of t his ac t a nd Shall be slIbject to cond itions that t he Commission deems necessary to achi eve full COmpli an ce wi t h th is a c t in Once a pr ovislo noll l license holl s been aWl rd ed the Commi ss I on s ha 11 I fit de ter~ i nes t he I nst i tution to be i n full com pl ia nc e with the pro vi s io ns o f this act. awa r d a pe rmanen t l i cense tha t shall be subj ect to pe r iod ic r ev i ew by t he COllmlssi on 2) In acco rd ance wIth p roc edUres consistent wi t h the p r o~isio n s of the Dist ri c t of Co lumbia Ad min tstrat'~e Pro cedur e Ac t ap pro ved Oc t ober 21, 1968 (8 2 Stat. 1204 D.C Cod e sec. 1- 1501 et uS t he COllmhston tlay s USjlend or r evo~e the lic e nse or an lnstit uti on f o r failu r e to comply with th e proviSions o f th ts act and r egulation s i ss ued pu r suant to t his act Qay r educe a perman ent lice ns e to a prOYisiona l lice ns e and refu se to issue a lic en se 3) Th e Hayor s h ~11, wi th in 180 day s of the eff ective date af t he Educationa l licensure Comm i ssion Alle ndme nt s Act of 1988 issue ru les t o Im plement th e pr o vis ions of the a ct pu r su a nt t o tit le I of tne DIs trict of 4 section 31-1605 3l -1606 Enrolled Origi nal Columbia Administrative Prot@dur~ Att approved Ottober 21 1966 (82 Stat. 1204, D. C. Cod e, set. 1- 1501 l. that shall in~lude, but not be limited to, a s~hedule of li~enslng fees and charge s and standa r ds and requirements for lic ensure of de gree granting and non-degr~e granting prog r ams. The pr opos ed r ul es shall be submitted t o t he Council for a 4S day pe r iod of r avi ew. u~luding Saturdays, Sun days, legal holidays and days of Council re~ess If the Cou n ~il does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules In whole or in part by resolution with in this 4S- day review period the pr oposed r ules shall be deemed approved 4 To the eXUnt consistent with the Eduutl ona l In s ti tution licensu r e Com~lssion Amendments Ac t of 1988, the CommiSSio n shall utilize the r ules of the 80ard of Hi ghe r Education entitled "Regu la tions Relating to the lic ens ing of Inst i tutions Wh ich Co nfer Degrees issued July 1. 1970 until the rules are amended or repea l ed 5) The Proprietary Scllool Regulat i ons, Issued October I 19 71 (Reg. 71 30; 16 OCM R 12 shall contin ue In eff ect unt il repealed or nended by ru l es adopted pursuant t o subsection (b)(3 Z) Subsection (c D.C. Code sec. 31-16 06(b Is ame nde d to read as follows; O{c){l The Commis si on ~ay make an independent eyaluatlon of an i nstitution's fa c il i ties and programs i n t he District for the purposes of initial licensure, the periodic review of a licensee that is not accredited, an d tile pe ri odic re iew of a branch or extension of an ac~red l ted licen see that is located outside of the Dis t rict o f Columbia 2) Tne Co mmi ssion may ma{e an Independent eva l uation of an institution's facilities an d prograllls outside the District for pu rpose s of init i al licensure of an institution that seeks to operate wi thin the District and the peri odic review of a l1censee thu is not accredit ed 3) The Comm is sio n 's periodl~ r eview of facilities and programs within the Dis tr i ct of an accred i ted licensee shall, e~~ept as specified in paragraph (1) of thi s s e~t io n, be made only by ~eans of a Commission obser~er of a n e~aluation by a regional ac c redit i ng assoC i ation, or, If t he programs In the Dist r ic t are limi ted to a specia l ty, by a specialized accrediting a sso~iati on 3) Subsection (d D.C Code, sec. 11-1506(c is amended to read as fo llows d) Nothin9 In thi s act slla1l be construed to I n~alldate a cu rrent licen se to op erate an edu~atl ona l institution held by I ny person In the District of Col umbi a on th e effect i ve date of the [duc.tiona l Institut ion licensure Commissi on Amendments Act of 1988, e~cept that eyery Institution operating in the District of Columbia, 5 lQrolled OT1g1~ with or without a license. on th e effective date of the act, shall come Into compliance with the provisions of the act and rules Issued pursuant to the act withi n a reas onab l e t ime, as provided In the ru l es 4) Subsection (e D.C. Code, sec. 31·1606(d is a mende d to r ead I S follows e) The Commissio n is author i zed t o charge any degree granting institution that 15 licens ed ~nder this act for the cos ts of the Commission's I ndependent evaluations of the i nst ituti o n 's fac ili t ies and the Commission's obse rva tions of eva luatio ns made by accredit ing a ssociatIons Any I nstitution ope rat ing an educational program within the Oistrlct shall establish, to the satisfaction of the Comm i ss ion t hat tile p r ogra. offe red will be I n accordan ce ith t ile education. l sundards of the Commiss io n g) Section 7 (D .C. Co de, sec 31 ·160 7) is amend ed t o rea d as follo 5 I n addit i on t o t hose duties specified in otller sec tions of th is act, the CommiSSion sha l l a) Advise the Mayor and the CounCil with respect to the posts econdary educat io nal needs of the Dist r ict of Co lulllbla b) Fi le Ith the ayo r and the Cou ncil quarterly reports relating to 1 The educationa l In~ t l tuti ons gr ant ed or de ni ed Ilcen~u under this act dur i ng tne report i ng period 2) Other mat t ers th at come unde r the COlrllllisslon's purv ie w c) Rece i ve and ca use to be maintained, copies of st udent academ i c records In conformfty with the f ollowing provisions I) In tile event an educational inst itution ope ratln9 in tile Distri ct, or any educationa l Inst it uti on licensed under this act operating outs id e of the Di st rict, proposes to discontinue its operation, the Chief Admi nis trative Office r, by hatever title desi9n a ted of tne institution sll a ll cause t o be f i led "Ith the Commiss io n the ori ginal or leg ible true co pies of all record s of the I nstitution s pecifie d by the Cor,.un\s s ;on. The r ~cords sllal l t nc I ude a t a mi n illlum, the acade.i c records of eacll for me r stud~nt 2) The Commi ssi on s hall maintain and disp ose of the r ecords in accordance ith th e prov i sions of the Dist r ict of Columbia Public Records 14a nagement Act of 1'185, ef fe c tive Septe~ber 5 1985 (D.C. La" 6·10; D.C. Code, sec. 1· 290\ et s~9 Acad emic records shall be maintained f or at least 50 years f r om t he date the student attended the Institution 6 Sectior H 1607 3 The Commission is &amp;amp;uth orized t o charge an i llst i tutlon for all costs i llv oived in the transfer of records d)(11 In th e event it a p p e~ rs to th e Commission th at the records of an Ins t i tution discont i nuing i ts operations are i ll danger of being de s t r oyed sec reted, mis la i d or otherwise made unavailable to the Comm i ssion t he Co~mi ssl o n may apply t o the Superio r Co urt of the Dis tr ic t of Co lUm bi a fo r an order authorizing the Commi ssion t o seize and tak~ possession of the rec ords 2) Any ch i e f office r or member of a governi ng bo ard of an i ns t itution wh o willfully fails t o comply with the pr ov i s i ons of this sub sec ti on or wil l fu lly ai ds a nd abets any pe r so n in a scheme t o av o id t he reQuirement s of this subse cti on may be held per sona ll y lia ble for all cos t s and da mages re sul t i ng fr om t he conduct, in addition to other pena lt i e s provided by t his act h) Sec ti on 9 Is r edesignated a s seetio ll 13 and the fol lowing new se c tio ns ar e added S ec 9. No pe rs on or postsecon dary edu cati ona l ins t itution i nco rpo rat ed in the Dist rict of Co lumbia or outside of t he District of Colu mb ia shall op erate a postsecondary educat i ona l ins t i tu ti on in the District of Col umbia. offer postsecondary educat i on have the power t o grant or co nf e r or offer to gran t or c onf e r a postsecondary degree or a diploma or certificate, offer postsecondary cou rse s for c redit or is sue t ran script s or other doc ~me nt s to r ef l ec t c r edit t oward a postsecondary degree diploma or ce r tificate unless 1) Tn e ins t itu tion is granted a l1cen se t o do so f r om the Commission or granted an exemp ti on by the Commiss io n i n acco rda nce wit h th is act; and Z) The ins tit ution Is eithe r organ i zed o r c hartered in the Di s tr ict of Columbid or or gani ze d or Char ter ed outs id e of the DistriC t of Col umbia and I s regi s tered a s a fo reign corp ora tion purs uant to s ection 64 of the Dis tr ic t of Col um b i a Nonp rofi t Co rporat ion Act. app r oved Augu s t 6, 1962 [76 Stat 290; D.C. Code, se c. 29 565 or s ectio n 99 of t he District of Columbia Business Corpo ra tion Act a pp r oved June 8 1954 68 Stat. Z19; D.C. Cod e, sec 29 399 or is othe r wise properly authorized to do bu siness in the Dist ri ct of Columbi a bl Ito person sh a ll stat e o r Im ply t hat its educati onal pr og ram or course of Inst ruction is approved for veteran 's t r a ini ng in t he Dis tr ic t by the District of Co lumb i a State Appr oving Age ncy or by t he Unit ed St a tes Vet e r an s Administ r 4 t lo n un le s s th4t pers on has ob tai ned pf up er app r ov a l fro m t he Comlll i ssion [c) Excep t dS provided f or I n th is act no pe r son sh a ll sell, barter or exchange f or any co nside rat ion, or 7 Ne'.oI. Sect ~on 31-1609 a ttempt t o se ll ba~te or exchange for a ny co nsi derati o n degre e, diploma o r c e r t lfic~te d Th e Co mmiss ion bef ore granting any l icen s e may ~e qulre utl sh c tory ev i denc e OI l That In the case Of an indiv i d ua l un i nco r po rated gro up of i ndivid uals, or Incorpora ted Ins titut io n t he Individual. a majority of th e Qroup, or a majo r ity of the t r us tee s direct ors, or man agers of the In co rpo ra t ed i nst i tu t io n a r e pe r so ns of go od repute and qua li fied to co nduct an institution of l ea r ning; a nd 2) That no deg r ee shall be awarded by an In s tituti on that Is not acc re di t ed i f more than one·half of the requ i reme nts fo r t he deg r ee are ear ned by cor re spond e nce o r extr.lllural study unless t hl$ fact is cons picuous ly note d upon the deg ree conferred e) No degr ee shall be gra nt ed In med ici ne or any healing art, or In dentist ry, f or stu dy pu r sued or work do ne by cor re spo ndence Sec. 10 The fo llowing t yp es of educati onal Insti tut io ns or acti vit l as ar e axc lu ded from the cov e r ag e of thi s act t) Cou rses of instructio n no t purpo r ting to l ead to a d eg~ee conducted by ny person so l e ly for the training of the empl oyees of the person, an d for wh ich no he Is char ge d 2) Educ ation of f e red by the Dis tr i ct o r Federa l gove r nme nt o r any instrur.len t allty of th e gover nmen ts exc e p t cou rse appr oH l fo r veterans under An Act to amend chapter 35 of title 38, United States Code to provide that afte r the exp i ~atlon of th e Kerean conflict veterans educat io n and training progra l'l pprov a l of cour ses under t he wa r o rph an s educat i on a ssi stance program sh a ll be by State "pprovi ng agencie s ap proye d Septelllber 23 1963 (77 Sta t. 158; 38 U. S .C. 3500 et s S 3) Educ'itTon s olely av oca tional or r ec r eati ona l In natur e a nd not l eadi ng t o a deg r ee and ins titutio ns off er in the edu cat ion ex cl ushely, OS det ermined by the Commission 4) Educ ati on off ere d by el ae~o syna ry o r no n.proflt i ns t i tution s org nltatio ns or agen ci es if no f ee is cha rged f o r the educat io n and the educ ati on Is not adver ti sed or promo ted as leading t owa r d a deg r ee diploma or certifi cate 5 Co urses o r pr ogra.s of instruc tion given by or pprov ed by a pr ofesSion a l body fraterna l organization, c ly i c club or benevolent order principal ly for the p~ of esslonal edu ca tion of its own rn emb ers o r advancerne nt or sl il ar pu r pose and for wh i Ch no deg r ee or degree credit is awarded and fo r whi c h th ere is no publi c advert hi n,]. and New, Seetic ,1-1610 scrolled Original 6) An educati onal Institution t~ut is org an ized or cha rte red outside of the Dis tri c t of Col umb ia and does no t operate I n the Di s tr ict of Colu mbia, except t ha t a ny agent of an Institution wh o ope rates in the District shall not be exempt and the COllml 55 lon may app ly the sta ndards of th i s act t o the Institut ion In determinin g whethe r t o lic en se an agent b) A degree gr anting institution shall be en t1t led to a co nditional exemp tion from all otller pr ovision s of this act if upon request to t he Co.mission I) It can show that It ha s been author iz ed by t he Congress of th~ United States to gr an t degrees; and 2) It i s now and has bee n continu ous ly an d unco nd itionally ac c re di t ed by an accred i t ing assoc i at io n recogn i zed by the United Sta tes Departmen t of Education; and 3) it f i les annu ally with the Commission t he fo l lowing AI A cu r rent aUdit ed finan cial s tatement of the institution 8) A certifi ed sta teme nt a s to the Institution s accreditati on status, i nclud i ng whe ther any condit io ns hav e been Im posed an d whether any action has been taKen toward reVOKing or l im iting that s tatu an d (C) A copy of ea ch course catalogue an d a response to th e Comr:li$ s ion's annual data survey 4 It maK e s pr ovision for a re pre se ntative of t~e Commissi on to ser ve as an ob se rver on all visit s to the Institution by eva luato rs from a regional accrediting association; a nd 5) It furnishe s t o t he Commission a copy of all reports submitte d t o and rece i ve d from the accredita t i on associat io n includ i ng the reports of an eva luat ion submi tted to the Institution by the accreditin g as soci at io n and notices of accrediting aSSO Ciation ac ti on regard i ng accreditation of the I nst i tution c) An I lIs tltut io n entitled t o a cOlldlt lonal e ~empt io n under subsection (b of thi s section that Is required by an accr ed1tl ng aSSO Cia tion to show caus e why I t s acc reditati on should not be rev o ed or that ~a s a d I t s acc reditation wi t hdr awn s ha l l not i fy the ComllllssiOIl I.mediately of the action by the accred it ing associat io n The e~em p tion s hall expi re and t he in s tituti on shall bec ome fully subject to the lic ensi ng r eq ui rements of t his act a s of t he date It receives no ti ce of t he withdra wa l of 4cc re dltatlon s tatu s d) The Commi Ss ion, upon reque st may reinstate an Ins ti tu tion 's cond iti onal e xemp t ion once ac cre ditation is re -establlshed and t he CO.llllsslon ha s de termi ned that it meets t he pr evis ion s of th is act app r op r iate t o th e e~ empt st atus 9 5Qrolled Original t) A con~ition~l e~e~ptlon authorized by this section e~tends only to programs or cou rses ~ithin the scope of the i nstitut i on's accreditation as certjfje~ by the accre~itlng as sociation f) The Coamtssio n shal l issue a co nd itiona l e~emption to an off-campus prog ram offered within the Distri ct of ColumbIa by an unconditIonally accred Ited degree granting institution or group of institutions. All other requirements of conditional exemptions under this section shal l apply t o the program s when the Co.mission determi ne s tha t O J The loca l offering Is for the institut ion's own students, regularly enrolled on its home campus and doe s not fulfill mor e than 251 of the normal degree requirement s 2) Th e 1 0c~1 of fering Is ope n onl y t o empl oy ee s of a per So n, and there Is no cost t o the employee g Nothing sha ll be stated or Il!Iplied in any diploma, degree, certificate, or document evidencing same, or elsewhere in th e publicatIons or correspondence of the institution that a program excluded from the requirements of this act has been re¥ie~ed, approved, or auth o rized by the C o I ion th e District go ¥ern~ent or any offi cer of the District go¥ernme nt Sec. 11. The Mayor may promulgate rules, subject t o revle~ by the Council as provided In section 6{b to establi s h a bond or surety requirement not to ex ce ed S25 0 000 pe r i ns titution ba s ed on th e number of student s an d cost of i nst ru cti on and $3, 000 per agent. The bond or security for the institut Io n shal l be for the purpose of protecting student s should an institut i on breach its contract with Its students, declare bankruptcy or other~l s e terminate its educatio nal program ~1t hout provlcling adequate student refunds. The bond or securit y for the agent sha l l be for t he purpose of pr otecting students fr om misrepresentation of the education or c redentials to be recehed Sec. 12(01) Any person or pers on s ~ho Irectl y or indirectly. parti c ipate In, aid, or a ssist In offering postucondary ed uc ation or the ope ra ti on of a post secon dary educati onal i nstitution by any unli cen s ed indhldua or i ndh i duais, ass ociat i on, or institution, or by any i ndiv id ual or i nd hldua l s assoc iati on, or i ns titut i on wh ose lic~nse has been revoked, wh o advertises or claims any authority to offer education, except pu r su ant to the prov Is i ons of th i s act, or wh o violate s a pr ovi sio n of th is act shal l be guil ty of a mi sdemeanor, and upon co nv i ction In t he Superior Court Of the Distr i ct of Col umbia s ha l l be punis hed by a fin e of not ~o re than $50 0. 10 New, Sect 31-1~l1. New, sect 31-1612 &amp;amp;nrolled Original b Each day of no n- compl i ance sh~11 constitute a s epa r a t e vio l ation of th i s ac t e) Violations of this act s hal l be pro sec uted in the Di s tr i ct of Columbia Superior Co urt by the Corporation Counsel of t he Distr ict of Col umbia d Nothing contained I n th is act shall pre clude a ny person fr oM being subject to a pena l t y unde r pr ovis i ons of the District of Columbia Consumer Pr ote c tion Procedures Ac t, e ffecti ve July 22 1976 (D.C, L~w 1-75; D.C. Code se c 28 390 4 if t he person enga ges in an unl awfu l trade practice Sec. 4. The amendments ~ade by sec t i on 2 d of t he 't:l~e Sect EducUio nal In s tituti on licen sure Comm issi on Ame ndment s Act 11'-D O&amp;lt;l of 1988 shal l be ef f ect Ive with respect to a ppOintmen t s made after the effec tive date of the Edu cational [n s t l tutl on Lic en s ur e Commi ss i on Amendme nts Act of 1988. Se c. 5. This act sh al l take effec t aft er a 30-day period of Congressional r ev i ew follo win g appr ov al by the May or (or I n the event of ve to by the May or a c t i on by the Cou nc il of the Dist ri ct of Columbi a t o override the vet o) as pr ovided in s ec tion 602(c)(lJ of the Distric t of Co l umbia Self_Governm e nt and Gover nm ental Reor ga nizati on Act, a pproved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 8ll D.C Cod e, s e c. 1- 233( c 1 a nd pub licat i on i n eithe r t he District of Col umbia Re gi ster, the Di strict of Col u~b j a St atutes -at-La rge or the Dist r ic t cf Col umb i a ~unicip a l Regul ati on s \ Ctl a 'l rman Council of t he Dis tr ic t of Columbia APPROVED: January 6 1989 11 Di s t r ict of Col u~bia COUNCIL OF THE OIS1'RICT OF COLUMBIA COUDcll P~riod Sevell RECORD OF OFFIC!AL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: 67- 86 l!l CTION' DUE AodOO"p"te'.d'cF",i,&amp;lt t R~e d",i L,~1,1 2~'C-o 5: VOICE VOTE A""P lt;'o"v"eod R""o d -ole req t Rolark :c It on ~I IICTlON D"rE ROd""o,p"teeOd F i 1 R"eo·,d i"n'g 1"2 ol.3 vOIce vore A"P"P"&amp;lt;eOcvce,d 1lec:0&amp;lt;ded &amp;gt;0" on Wilson ~n4 Smith on eons.n, c 0 ACTION I DUE VOlC~ VOTE 111 0 O lion 1 R&amp;lt;lLL CALL von RESULT l 0.,</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
