<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-221">
  <num type="law">7-221</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1989-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-221.pdf">D.C. Law 7-221</citation>
      <citation type="register">36 DCR 553</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>COUN CIL OF T~E DISTRI CT OF COlU "BIA ~OTICE D. C. LA II 7- 221 II~ r 'lency AS5htanc~ Progralll Act Of 1':188 Punuant to Sec t ion 412 of the Oist r ict of Col umbia SeTf- Go vern~ent dnd G;J ver nme ~t a l ~eorg4ni zatl on Act, P. l 93-198 the Act the Council of t he Dis t rict of (OlUllbid ad o~t e d Ei l 1 No. 7-6 8 on first and second r ud ings ~ove m ber 29, 1988, and D~ c eoaber 13 1988 respectively. Foll owing the slgn.stur e of the l~lyor on January 5 19a9 th is legislation S assi gned ct NO. 7-296 publislled in tile hnuHY 20, Ig89, editi o n of tile D.C. Register Vo l 36 Da ge 55J and transoaitted t o CongreH (In Ja~uary 23, 19a9 f o r a 30 -day re view, in ac cor dance it" Se ction 602 c 1) of the Act. P,e Cou "c ll of the Di str ict of Colu mbia hereby g ives no t ic e that the 30-day Congression a l Review Period ha s e~pir~d, tnd t he ef :l re, cites th is en a ctllent n D. C. t tW 1- 111, effe c tive r~ar c h 16 1989 DAVID A. CLARKE Ch a i r man t o th e Counc!l D ~t es Co un ted Duri n; the 3D-day Con 9reS Slon t l Revj e~ Pe r io d: J dn ua ry 24.25, 26,2 1,30,31 Feb r~t ry 1,2, 3 ,6.7,8,9,21, 22 ,23,2 4, 27,28 :1~rch 1, 2,3 6 1 8 9 10 13, 14, 15 D.C-LAW 7 -221 MAR 1 6 19sct inroll e4 Original Codi ica tion Kew Chapt e r to o t i t l Di!lt ri t of cL·.l",b~ a Co e :1&amp;lt 9 SU9 j AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 ·2 96 Jrl THE COU C IL OF Til E OIST RICT OF COLUMBIA JAN 6 Ina To es tlb ll sh an Eme r gen cy Asst s Unce Pr Qgr dr.l an d pr ovi de e li ~i bil1tJ crlter i d, payme nt lev e ls and Qt her admin istrdt l ve prQvls1Qns f or th e ef f ici ent ad li nist rat ion of t he pr ogra m. Bt IT ENACTED 3Y TIlE COIJK CI L OF TH E DIS TR ICT Ot CO LUM B I [hdt th is dc t m~ y ~e ci t ed a s t he "Em er genc, As si s ta nc e ro ~r dm .o,c t o f I !l SS Sec. 2 Def i ni tion s For t h e pur po se s of thi s dc t, the t e m I I Appl iC dnt mea ns t he i nd i vid ua l ~ho i s a pply Ing for elner g e~ c y 3ss i s t6n ce for hI s or her o ~n nee ds or t e needs of t hose i t h 1101"1 he or sh e l i ve s and t ho s e pe r son s s pec i fie d in s ec t i on 6 l A~t ho rized r epr es entat iv e" mean s a pe r s on wn Q Is a c t ing reS PQn si bly Qn bena l f of an a ppl i cant, is a t l edi t 18 yea r s of age, and h~ s suffi Ci en t kn owle dge of t~e c i r cu~s t n c e s of the cl ient t o pr o ~ide or obta i n necessary I nform ati on on the a pplic~nt or a pe rs on IO/ ho ha s l e g l th ori lat io n t o ac t on beha l f of the a ppl i cant 3 B as ic nec ss t i e s" me~ n non dis c ret Qnary li ving expens es limite d to the cost of shelte r, uti li t ie s f oo d medic al care nd ea s ona ble expen s es f o ro cl o thing, sc ho o l rel ated I tems, household i tem s or expenses r elated t o emp loyme nt, t nsportati on. or fa. ll rehted e:11erge ncles 4 Bud get month' means t he lO day period pr io r t o t he day i"m ed i dtely pre ceding ~pp l lcat lo n 5 Oepar tme nt" mea ns t he Distr ic t of Co lUMb I a D ep a rt ~ent of H u~a n Ser vi ces established by Re organizati on Pl a n No. 2 of 1919. approved February 21, 19 S0 (D. C. Code Vol I 6 Em e rgency medn s a s i t uation i n IO/ hi cn i mm ed i dte a c tion Is necess a ry t o aV Oi d destitution, es tablish or re· es tab l ish a home, or pr ovide for tne I C eC Cf l l~ Enrolled O~1g1oal imm~d ia te needs Of an eligible ap plicant to reli e, e or ~re 'e nt s eriOUS harm or prevellt displac er.len t fr OI!l a lIome l Equity mea lls the cur re nt larket vdlue of property le ss any lien indebtedness on n'e pr operty a nd re~ so ndbl e expenses necess ary t~ I iq uidat e the prop er ty 8 Ho usehold furnishill~s" mea ns pe r son al prope rty tustO'llarlly found in the hooe for use i n connectio it~ th e m~intenanc e, use or occupancy of th e premiH inl;ludinQ furnitur e, furnishi~9S, hous eh old appl1ance s or c"o ing and eHill9 utensils 9 Intome frllm a boa rder e&amp;lt;H1S any ,on ey paid to the appli c an t by a person 11.1 ng in the same househol d as tne d~p1icant, but wh o is not relu ed t o the applic a nt lO Personal belongings" mean s personal property in tended for per so nal use including c lothing j e"elry, watch es, personal gr ooming art i cl es, boo~ s or nusical instnments 11 SS me os t'le supple e nt~1 s e cu rity inCO"le bene f its est a blish ed punu a nt to the Sothl Security Ame d,n en t s Act of 197 2 appr oved Oc t ob er JO, 19 72 (86 St~ t. 1455 d 2 U.S C. 1381 12 Vendor· mea ns a provider of a ser1 ice or a produc t 13 Ve ri fl~a ti on" mean s docunen t a t ion or co)ll atera l ~roof use d to confirm the valid1t y of an applicant's ci c u l'ls tan Ces. Sec 3 Requ i remen ts a n application for emergency asSist a nce under tnis H sn ail be in wr i ting on a f o r M pr escrib ed by the Itayor dnd Signed by the app lic ~nt o r an a ut horized rep re sentative b) To be el ig iOle fer e mer gency assis tan ce th e a ppl iCdnt sll a l1 I Be presented with a n emergellcy 2) Appl y for e mergency assistanc e after us ing al I o the r av a ilabl e resour ceS, ex ce pt tno s e ex emp ted by sectio n s 10 and 12 i ncl udin9 res ources a ctu a lly a va ilable fr om a cOlllmunlty s ou rce, tha t wou l d allev iat e ttle ellle r gency 3) Meet the requ i rements of sec t io nS 5 t nrough 29; and 4 Demonstr ate ttl at the pro v ision of 1 or "lor e of the ava i l a ble categories of eg er gen cy as sis tan ce would I I B v i atB the emergen cy c If the em er gency will oecyr wi thin th e next 2 bUSiness ,hys, the Ma yo r shall take elll reel son a ble steps t o proc e ss the appli cat io n in ti Me t o resolve the em erge ncy, if the 6ppli c ant meets all of tne appropriate e l igibili ty criteri a and the d el~ y Is no t e au sed by the fa ll yre of th e a ppl ic a nt t o p r ov id e veri fic a t i on o r doc umentation r equi red t o I6 ke an e lig i b ility deterlllin&amp;lt;1t i on. 1 e Sect ~r:r 1-1 2 &amp;amp;nrolled Original Sec. 4 Emer qe ncy ~ssl~t~nc e J:l e rgency usls ta nce may be pr:!vided to d sin'Jle i ndi v1d ual, ch i ldl ~ss cou pl e, or a family wi th chi ld ren, I f ~l l ,onditl on o r t ne rece ip t of em er gency us ist~n c e I I'Ipo1 ed by thB a ct are le t e lt cept as pr ovided in s e ctions 29 ~nd 3 0 0 Jhe emergen cy mu s t be that of th e applicant c Til e Hpl i c ant must as sist fully in est atliish i &amp;lt;1g elig i b ili t y t he nature of t he emergenty. and tile eH~nt o f nee d d T~ e Mayo r shall not be ob li'Jated t o prov id e an amount for a re ques ted s e vl c e if a l es s costly a lte rnative is H ai la ~le e E"I1"rg e ncy as s istan ce ma y be in the f o rm of ca s h, c oupons 11. k ind be n1"f l ts, or dire c t vendor pa YI'l1" nt. Sec. 5. Ti me fr ames f o r emer ge ncy assistance and p rocedure s fo r applic a tion 6) Whe n an a ppllcation fo r el!lerge ncy a ssi sUn c e has be en d Ppr ov ed for c a sh o r direc t vendor pa y me&amp;lt;1t t he May or ~ha l l prov id e e~er~ e "c y assi s tan c e wit h i n 8 bu s ine ss day s frol'l t he date of co.,plet ed a pplic a tio &amp;lt;1 othin~ in t hh s ect ion s na Il pr ohibi t t h e prov ision of emer gency H~istance "Hh in a s no rter pe r iod whenever pOH ibl e b 1 lt;1 ~p plication f o r em e rgenc y Hsisunc e sh 11 b e con~i dered com plete "he n th e a pplication is co.,ple ted ~nd si gn ed by t ne appli cant and the a pp licant hH pr ovi ded ne ln f or tion nee ded t o p r oce ss the application Tile r~ayo r sh a ll pr ovide t ne ap p li c ant wit h a wr i tte n re qUes t sp ec i fy i ng th e informat ion needed t o co mplete t he application and dis c uss &amp;gt;lit n th e app lica nt ho w t o obt a in tll 1" inf o r~at lo n d Th1" May o r sh a ll no t requ est that t he appli ca n t provide do c umen tation that th1" Mayor can obtain ~o re easi l y than th e a pp licant when that determina ti on c an be la de. The Ma yo r may use docu~ent s, teleph o ne c on ver s a tio ns pe rs on al and collatera l interview s rep o rts, c orre s pondence, an d con ferences to verify information e) The "Iyor sh.ll luve an add i ti o nal business day t o proce ss a COMplet ed appl ic ati o n for each day o f delay caused by t he applicant's fatlyre to supply ~dditional infarl'lat lo n or doc ume n t.tlon, if the fa il ure aros e durin9 the ve i f l cat io n of Info r mation con ta i ned in the co~pleted appl;c~t ion and without wh i ch the Mayor cann o t ~er1fy tne f a cts n1"cesury t o eHablis h eligibility. Tile Ma yor snaIl have .n a dd Hi a na l busin ess day to pr oc ess tfle cOIII~l l!t 1"d appl ti on for each day of dehy due to an unexpla I ned los s of con tH t wi th the applicant, evidenc.e of l'1i s repre s entat lon In the conpleted appli c a t i on, r efusal o f a ve ndor to a ccept payme n t or de l ay by th i r d part y fr om whom th1" Mayor has J '1&amp;gt gt C Ct l OO~ l'ew, S ec r &amp;amp;grQll Or1ginal requested i nf o r mat ion a nd oyer wh om tn~ nayor ~H no con~rol f) The Mdyor sh a ll pr adde applicaUo o forms n d dC t e o t app li c a ti ons frolJl eyery pe r son wllo requests e:le rgency dSSl s unce at th e t i ne t nat ener~ency dHist a nce is ~vu ght. Eacll appl ican t 511a l1 be intervie wed fo r eme r gency ass istanc e on the dat e the emergency dSs ist ance i s req uest ed or, if t hat I s not pos s ible, on the ne~ t bHiness day. If th e d P p li~ant s emergenty WO'Jld !lccur I t.,in the ne ~t 2 busin e ss days, the Mayor shall inte r vi e th e appHcan t on the day er~e r ge ncy a s si stan ce is soug ht 9) r~e Mayor sh a ll pr ovide to e dCh app l icant at t~e i':le J f ap p l i cati o n, a c l ear, concis e Iritt e n notice ~Jn t ai ning t he rights a nd respons ill ilities of the app l i c a nt and the r espons i bi II t'es of the Mayo r i t~ re spect to thIS d ct Sec. I I f ollo,;i ng 6. App l icant un i t. Til! de fin i tion of dppli c a nt" sll a ll include t'"oe i n d iYid~als h o lt ve in th e sarr.e hou se ho l d I Pe rson s related by fu ll Qr half blood, but o t beyond first cousin nephew, o r niece includi ng those of IH!rsons o f pr Hl!ding ge ne r Hions as denoted by th e pr ef i ~es 9 r ~nd great, dn d g rea t gr eat 2 eroons related by legal adoption 3) Persons rel ated ~y ,na rri'ge including stepc h i ldren dnd unnarried pa r~ nts Of a CO r.l &amp;lt;"l !ln child h O live together a nd 4 I ndi~ld u a1s not r! lne~ a s def ined in par'9raphs I 2 or 0 ho hav a jo tnt legal respons i bility fo r ea ergency as sist an ce r equ ested under sen ion s 21. 22 23 24, 25 n o r 27 b The applicant may i~c lucte an SS t rec ipient hO mee ts t h e c rHHia Of s ubse c t ion a of nis s ection, if !Me 55! r l!cip il!nt cll!losl!s t o be part of the unit. The 55 1 recipi ent may ap ply separdte ly f o r e r.ler ge ncy a SS istance un der this act c) A person who meet s the c riter i a of subsec tion a) o f this sect ton 15 an el igible a pplic a n t if he or she IS tl'mpora rtly a."y from the home due t o emplOyl:lent, hos p i tal I zatIon, vac at io n, or a v isit A child IIh o i s a llay at ;c hool i s an el igi ble pplicant. if li e or she de ,no ns trat! S In i ntent t o rl! s umt li ~ing at hom e by return I ng on occ as ion l we tkend~ o r holiday s a nd du ring s umr.ler c at \on s Sec 7. Res idency r eq u i r eme ~t. An a pplic a nt ~us t live in the Ois trict of Colu~bi a Ols trict at the t i me o f a pplicatio n Mi gra n t orkers lew, Scc ti lC05 lt;e Sec ic l "r) fi tDroll~d Original li~ fng in the DI str ic t wh o meet 11 crit er i a fo r a ppl i can ts ir e el ig lbl e f o r emergency st stance. Sec. 8 £'pl"yment requir enent h e er'l er ge ncy ca nn ot be the r e lt of any adu l t a p?lic a n t refu sjng with ou t good c ause, t o accept e pl ~yneflt o r train ing f or emp loyment. Good c a use f o r refu~ing e loy ment or tr a inIn g is deMons tr ate d when the applIcant shows it n re li a bl e a nd c redibl e in f o r'l!tion tMt I rage to be pol d by t he prospect iv e employer ar e be l o~ the ,ninimum wa ge requirement 2) The appli ca n t is physically or nent!lly un~bl e t perf rm the ~mpl()y l en t or gai n access t o t he 3 or k lng con d Itions at t ne empl oy" e n t Of t rainlng sit e a re in v iol at ion of ap plic ,ble hea l t h safety or \lor ker's comp e nsa tio n laws, rules, or regulati ons dn d t he violations o f heol lt, or afety hw s r ul es, or re gu ht to ns ~re~ent a substa nt l el riSk t o lI ea l t h Dr ~afety 4) Oiscrlmination by dn employer ~9 a jn s t the ad ul t a pplic a nt is ba sed on age, race, se x, col or, handicap re ligiouS be i ief s, n~ti onal or i gin, o r polittc~l beiiefs 5) The requirements of the job fl o'Jl d be c on trary t i" or her re li&amp;lt;;lio u$ lIelief or (ii) C~j ld ure. which is ecessary f o r th e ~du \ t appl ic an t to a c c ept the \lork or trainin g 15 ot availab l e. Se c. 9 [nc ol'le elig j b il ity s ttnd~rd Egept dS pr~~id e d in se c tions 16 17 a nd 29 to be eligibl e fo r em ergency assist an ce se rvi c es, the dppJicant m ~y not n~ve net i nco llle i n the bud get f'Io n t h a s specified in ect l on 11, or resou r ces, as specif i ed 11'1 se c tIon 13 i n exce ss of the f ollo ltO ing le ~el s: 1lu mber f Pe"sons Haxi mu1 l-persor 2 persons 3 p.n ons 4 p.nons 5 person s 6 persons 7 pInons 8 persons 9 pe r sons or e ach add! tlonal per son Mo nth l tncom e h!.vel r/2t.2 966.25 $1,211.25 Sl,456.25 Sl,701. 25 $1.946.25 12, 191.25 $2 ,4 35.25 $2,646 .25 beyond 9, a dd H4S. Sec 10. t nco!lle exempt f r om the det e r f'll natt on of eligibility. The f o llowing in come of an applicant \O/ i ll not be count ed in c a lc ulat i ng income ,vai l ,b l e to the ap plic ant in the budget month: 5 ~e Scc~i 3 10J7 e ec:;i.o 3- 1 1" Se Sec t i&amp;lt; 3 09 iDrolled Orlg1nal 1) Ols c o nt ln u&amp;lt;!d in com&amp;lt unl&amp;lt ss 4V&amp;lt;1.i1oble In t h &amp;lt udget on t h [ 1) t o the va lue O&amp;lt l artment o f 'I a lue of FOOd (3 ost er c are; In c ot1e in kind, including, but not li~ited of food don dted by the iJni ted States lt;gr ic u l ture USDA o r a loc al age'lc}, o r t e Stamp coupon all otment s Payme nt s made t o an app licant f o r children I n 4 The val ue of Lo Income n"9Y ~ssistan ce l IEA Pdy ment5 ~s provided 1'1 th e low-Incom e Home Energy ist~nc e Act of 1981 ap proved AU 9ust 13 1981 9 5 St~t. 893 4 l U. S.c. 8~21 r.J dde t o th e applic.nt o r to a vendor on be hal f of thE dpp li cdnt unless t~e re quest for e~Ergen c y anistd nc e is spectfically f or ~ti1jty e::lergen cy Hsi s tance i'l wh lci'l Cd se t e totdl mount of lI EA dss istd nce cu r r ently eHilable i s app lie d t o the requ estea o unt 5) The Hlue of services png ram ben efi t s of th e J ePdrtfllen t pa td on be nd o f a ~li e n t wh o Is an a pplicant ncl d in9 bu t not lillited to nome::l4ke r assistance 61 The value of ~endor p~yments by t~e Feder~l o r Oistric t go ver nmen t o r it, agents, on beh a lf of t he p~;it a nt d irectly t o d vend o r, e c e pt t~4t Dep d rt ment-admin iste red Rent l Vend o r payment o· dn Aid t o Fd::lil tes ith Dependent Childr en d pl i c d t ill be co nSi dered H p~rt of d n Inco ma&amp;lt;l e 0'1 be half cl ient who is app l i e ant s (7) Tne value of supplemental food assis tan ce pro vi d ed under ~r 09 r~MS of WO"en I n fant s and Cntldren Ollr C establhhed pur su ant to Section 11 of the Child ~u trit ton Ac t of 1966. approved August 12. 1971 91 Stat. 825 42 U.S.C. 17 52 pr og raM S fo r chi ldr en under the 'IHion",l Scho ol Luncll Act eSUblished pursuant to se~tion 1) of Cflapter l8l of the National School lunch Ac t, a pp r oved May 8 1968 (82 5tH 11 1; 42 U.S.C. 1761 or o ther c ld nu tr i tI on pr09 ram5, or benef i ts re cei ved under t he Older A'TIeric a ns Act. estab lis hed pUrSUd 'lt to t ~e Older Americans Act of 196 5 pproved July 14, 196 5 (9l S t~t. 1525 42 U.S.C. 30 27 In cl ud ing Titl e Vll nutrition pro g ram s far the e l derly es t.bl1s h,cj pursuant to the Food "nd Ag ri culture e t of 1977 appr ov e d Oecember 22, 1981 (91 Stat. 1000 7 U.S.C. J175)j 81 The amount of court o rdered cnild s uppo rt requ i red t o b&amp;lt paid i n tne budget mO lltn by in applfunt t o anot~er ~ou seh old 9 The earned income of persons a ge 1 4 and (10) T~t earne d in co~e of jun io r or senio r hig~ school s tudents over ~ge 14 employed less than 20 hours per ee~ or el;lployed fu ll -tial&amp;lt i n the s ummer mo ntllS Cnr ollea Original ll) Wo rk t nc entht! oay t! nts mad by the Oistrtct of ~olumbh J epar t'lle o t of Employment Services or (12 he in CO&amp;lt;'l e of SSI re cipi en t unle ss t ~e 5S1 recipient choos es t o be a n app lic an t. Sec_ 11. Incom e co nsi1ered t n the de t~rm\n a! i o n of elig ibi lity. The f oll owing incoJ:le l'Iust be consi dered I" cal c ul&amp;amp;ttn g: t he tocone of th e appl !cant tn t he budget montn 1) The net a~ o unt of ongo in g i ncone re cei ved du rin g the !Iu d get month, inc l uding, but no t limi ted to, i oc ome f r om a b0 6r;1er, edrne d income, a n Aid to i li e s ~i tn De p~ndent CMild r en g r~nt, chtld support ?ay~e n ts rece ved Soc ial Security r e tireme nt su rviv or s and dis a b i li y iniu rance benef i t s a II 0 ny Vetera ns Aa~in'stration benefits wo rk er s compen$d t io benef i ts nemp lo yment benefi t s including unem pl oy n ent COl1 p e n s ~tion b~nefits a nd lIt er gilvern e nt al u" emp l oy r.lent ben ef it\ a}·r.en ts fro priHte ~1, k and c:hten inS;j a nce p l an pe nsions and r eti rem en t benefits, str1ke benefitS or mi l i tary a llo \e~t 2) Tn e val u e of Rental Vendo r Payment lII a de t o a vendor und er th e Aid to Fal~'lt es w i t~ Depende nt CMildren lIril9 r~m on beHlf of t~e applicant J) The net ano uot of discontInued, sporadic, or l p s ym income, if it 15 r ec e ived i n the budge t o nth or ha s been re c ei ved I n an earlier lt;1on th an d i s st ill aoilable to the appl tc ant; a nd 4 T.,e income o f a n SSt r ecipient, if t~e S51 r ec i?i ent q~al if ies a s ~n applicant. Sec t Z ae ter l!lln a tion (a) The co ns i de r~d In onth: AB e t s and res ources eltel'lpt frol'l of eligibility f ollo win g re sou r ces o r a ss ets hall c alc~ l at lng i ncome a.aila bl e in th e not be budget I The home and Surround in g la nd in wh iC h t he applic 4nt li Ve 2) Al l housetl old furnishings and per~ 0 n41 belongings I n th e home 3 6 000 equ ity of 1 mo t or vehi c le used f o r transpor tati on The e quity in I sp ecl d lly equ tpped l!Ioto r vehi cle used for transporting phys i cdlly d isab l ~d app l ica n t 5) Tools nacninery, o r o t her pr op e r ty us e d f o r e mpl oym ent or $elf- e ~ploynt!nt wn e t her or not I n th e home 6) A need-based 10 ~n nade t o a n appli c ant f o r scliool related e(p e ns e s 7 "e S ct io 1 01 ew e lc~ 1- 11)11 1) The v~lue of bu r l plans or ~ari~ l insurance unles s the r eques t for emergen cy dssistance is for the purpos e Of burial 1n whiCh case t he a ou~t co ered by l e bu r h l D l n o r i nsur a nc e will be apolied to tile re uested d r:'lOu~ t of e 'flergency usi s u nce; dnd 8 e s o urces of an applicant receivin9 551 benef it s, un less the 55l recipient has sp Hlfically request ed t o be a n applicant f or purposes of receiving eme r g e~cy a SS ista nc e. Sec. l :l Assets an d resources con s idered in th e deter"l inHion of el f~ibill ty. The fol10 w i n~ ass et s a nd reS Ol,lrces are c onsi de red aYl l b l e t o the app l1 unt and will be cons i de r ed i n c41 c ulat i ng j~ co r:le dva ilab le t o t ~e ~ppljcant in th e bud get on t h I T"e e'l~ity in all re a l pr oper ty e _cept t~e ho,e dnd su rr ounding l a nd I n which the app l ic ant l ive Z) The equi ty i n a l l moto r veh i cle~ o f the dP p l le ant not exe"'lp t e d under se c t ion 12(a 3) or 4 0) The equi t y In any interest i n r ec reati onal veh i c l es ncluding, but not li mited to, boats ca ,np er s. t r d l\ er mo to r cy c les not uemp t ed under Hcti on \2 {a l{ l snowl'1obile s o r a ircraft 4) Th e eq uity of ~ny Int er es t In ma c hinery, li ve s t ock, or 'ltlle r property or Items tlla t dr e not u~ed for e ,np loy me n t o r self emp l OYi:1 e n t 5 he lo an value available t o tne a pplicant i n lnsur~ nce pl ans or the cash or lo a n ~ill ue available t o th e d P~lltant pur su a nt t o a n agr eeMe nt In an esc r ow or tru s t fu nd 6) The ca sh va lu e of a n ind i v idu a l Ret i r ement ~c C,o unt or other deferred c o~pens at io n plan, o r pen sio n f u ndS that hdye been di st r ibut ed from a plan and a re I ctuall y availab l e to an a pplic a n t 7) The actual caSh vahe inchdi ng, but no t limi ted to, a checking ac coun t, 4 s avin gs acco un t, a certIfic ate of deposit stoc ks, and bonds 8) The Ictu.l c a sh va lue o f c ountab le resour c es t ha t h ~ve be en converted t o c a~ h in t he budg et mo nth and (9) The equity In nona~e mpt res ou r c es tha t were sold tran s ferred, o r traded for less than fair m~rket value withtn t ile pre~ioys 12 mo nth wh en tllere 1s r easen t o l:le l lev e that t he action lia s u~en f o r the pu rp ose of b e c o~ i ng el 1gibl e f o r emer gen cy a ssist ance pu r su an t to this act Sec er!1er gency \ 4 Com putation o f emergency assis ta nc e pay~ e n ts Fo r pu rposes of de termi ning the a ~ou n t of a ss istance Pdyment the May or sh al l c ons id er 8 e c i.or 2 Ne Sec ti 1 10t 1 torolled Origlual I) Inc oCl t r ec l' i vtd dur in g t he pre~t ou s 3 day per iod o/ hich sha ll beg i n on t he diy prior t o the date of o?plica ti on; an d (2) In come certdio t o be recej d durin'l th e 30 day- period foll owing the date of a pplicat io n 0 n,ome certain t o be r ece l~ed du rin g the 30-da y pe iod i.:lMe diately fol lO ljjn g application ill na t disq ua lify n indi vldUJI ho would be 1'1 iglble ba sed on t'le incotle of tne 33 day s pre ceding appllcatio fl e The emergen cy assi s un ce paY Cle nts s~ al1 be conpute d by I Estaol l shin g th e to tal amoun t of coun ta ble inco "e an d resour ces av~il a b l e t o the applicant Oe termi ntn t he appli cant S month ly e p en s es 'o r !l sl~ nec essiti es that a1'1 actua l 1'tasonat!1e a nd ap pr opri at e given the app lice nt 's ci rc ums ta nces and (3) Sub tra c ting Clonthly expe~ s es for basic necessi t i es f r(lm tile t otal amoun t of ava il able o::ount ab lt i nc o ~e nd resoure~ s ny i ncome thdt rtma lns i s d e e~e d d 'l~ i 1a~ le t o e et t'1e cos t s, in par t or total, of tne em e rge~cy ass istance r equ e st d) A~ eJnrge ncy a ssist nce pay men t r.Jdy !le authod ze d ~hi c~ refl ec ts ac tua l "eed Ij i tn th e app lic dti on of a pay ne nt nali Mu M a s a y be nece ss ary and as s ti pul at ed In each cat egory of e~erg ency assistance. Se c. \ 5 E~e rge nCJ related el igi bi lity. Eme rgency a ssis ta nc i$ a vai l ab l e for t he ca t egories o f eme r ge ncles enumerated i n s ec ti ons 15 thr ough 2 9 al I f t~e a pplicant h4S :ne t all other eligibili t y c rite ria; and b If I o r more Of the ava i lab le categories of e er g ency ass is tan ce will substant i a ll y, If not e ntir e ly alleviate t he emergency during t he 3 0 day period immediHely f o ll owi ng tne init i a l auth or ilati on of payment r e su l tin g from an appllc tion. Sec. 16 FGod emer gency a E.,rg,n cy aS$lstanct Is avai l able i n a food em e rgency t o In app liCant Ijh o hd S app li ed f or r egu l ar or e pedit,d food st amps or If a current rec ipi ent, who 1s compl et ely without food b Eme rge ncy aSSI stanct f or fo od Clay be in th e fo rm of cOllpon, c ash, or In-~lnd benefits at th e discretio n of the May or e The am ou nt of e~e1'9tncy assistance ~h a ll no t e xcee d the aMount of a 3_day food s tamo ~l l otment d Th~ May or may establish a la ss fet~ 1 n program pursu a nt t o this ac t e ec o 11 e Se t ~c 3 0~S ~rolled Or1S1nal Se c 11. Cl o thing eme r '1 ency a Any app li can t may f c e i ve emer ge nc y ass ista nc e t o repl~ c e clo t h in g lo st, da']! ged. or destr oye d du e t o fire. chil disor der natural o r chemical diS aHer, t he f t o Hl)d lis as verified by a oo li ce report, t nat oC Cur red i tnin 30 days of t~e appli c at io n. He pro vi sio n of em e rg e ncy as s ista nc e l ay be ln ~Und or in cHh at the di s c r eti On of th e Mayor b det rnl;ni ng eli gibil i ty f o r a clothin g request under thi s s ect i on, only the In c ome resour ce s an d a~ s e u of th ~t a ppljc~n t sh al l be co nsidered c) In addition to the condit i on s stat ed under s,Jb s ect;on j a an a pp l ic ant jth ch ild re n u nde r 18 yurs of a qe ma y rec e i·l e e ~erg e ncy a H istan c e f o r th os e Ch lld r e 'l, If t ~e l a c k of clo t h i ng wo uld co ns t i tute a th reat to healt h o r sa f ety or prevent s chool a tt e ndance. For t~ e purp ose s of thls ~ubsec t l o n fa mily Si ze me ans the number of chl1dr in th e ho use hol d ~ho He under 13 yeHs of a ge j Eme r ge ncy a ss i s tan c e in a c lo t h i ng e~e rg e n cy s hall be \im it ed to t h e fol\ O&amp;gt;llng mu i mum p~ym~nts. if the cloth in g eme r ge ncy as s istan c e i s in t he f o r~ of c a Sh tumber of Chi ld r en Unde r 18 Ar ount of Ass i s tan c e 1 p9":Q0 2 S94. 00 3 S11 4. 00 4 H34 00 5 515 4 .00 I f there are ,no re t han 5 child r en un der 18 year s of age add S25 f o r e a ch ad di t lo n.1 eligible ch il d i n t ne applica n t un i t. Sec 18. Essent 1 hous e hold items eme rgency a) Emergen~y assist ance for the purchase of any h ouseh o ld i tem, in c luding. but not limited to, linens a nd coo ~in g ute nsils is av a ilab l e 4S f ollows I To repl,ce a n item lo st, dam a ged, or destroyed due t o a fire, ci v i l disord. r. natu r a l or Chemical d isaste r, o r theft o r vanda lism verifi ed by a pol1ce report. that occurred wit hin 30 da ys o f app l i cati on; or 2 f o r the pur pose of purchasing of essen tial household items to re unite a ch i ld under }8 ye ars of age j th th e pare nts or prev ent family displa c emen t b) The ma~ i mum total em ergen cy as s l stance payment 5h.1 1 be the actu .1 cost up to Sl OO. Sec. 19 Essen t i al l arge app l i a nces emerg e ncy a) Emergency Hsist a nc e 1s ava il aO l e for th e r ep a i r or re p l a ceme nt o f a s t ove. refrigerat or or air condit i on er, whe n med ic a l l y necess.ry as ~erified by a physi ci an, or, washin g ma ch i ne owned by t he app l i c ant. 10 ew ec ion 10]6 Ile ectlor 101 7 e Se c tl c 3- 101='1 b A.ppliances May be rep l aced only if repa i r of t ne ~p ;11\ an ce o\olned and pre~jously used by tne app licant is not o r e tnan the paY"lI~nt fl1 a~ iMu"\ f o r th~t item PI as~ing mHn;n e may J nly be repa ired or replaced for a n appli can t ~j t Children under 18 year s o f age. An appliance rep oss essed for any reason can no t be rep lace d epa; r or replacement of an appliance &amp;lt;'lay be dutho r i zeo at actual cost up t o t he fol lo ing e~ergen c y »i$ t4 nc e p~ ym e n t ma~i m u s 1) stove \200.00 S250.00 200. 00 1200.00 2) refri ge ra t or (3 ash i ng "achine PJ a i condi ti oner Sec. 20. Essenti l f urni tur e emer gency Emergency ass is ta nce f o r the purc hase of furn i tur e may be g ranted as fcllo\ol 1) To reph ce ess ential furnitu re when lo st dd,1 dg ed or des troyed due to a f ire civil ~isorder na tur al o r cher1 i ol disas ter, or t heft or vandalism ~s v~rlfied by a pal ice r epo r t, t,at occurred w1thln 30 da y s of the dppl i cH;on or Z) If t he OUnO&amp;gt;1! o f t h e furnit u re purchase Is to r e uni te Chl1d under IS yea~s o f age wi tn ~ne p tre nts (l r prev ent I 1, displaceme" t b The inun emerg e ~cy a s~ls t~nce pdyn e nt sh a ll be 1 i-tt ed t o dctu d l cos t up t o S4 00.00 Se c immi nen t by a: 21 Rent emerge ncy. Emergency assi s tdn ce ;s .v~ t l'ble to evl'tton o f t h~ app l i c ant h ic h mu st pr event tile be dotunented (I) Landlord- T ~nant Co urt s ummo~s or r~fe rr al 2 jrit of Restitution 3) Notice t o Vacate or 4) Verlftable docu Menta t 10n th~t the appl ican t i s a teM4n t who ha s current r en t arre~ra;e b) I f the rent arre arage exceeds 6 mon t hs tne Ma, ar shall deny e.ergency as sist.n I f th e arrearage resul t ed fr om the e xpenditure of money f o r non S5en tial i tems rather than an e~pendftu r~ for ba sic necessit i es. I f emerge nc y a s s ls t.n c e Is gr ~n ted emergency a ssi~ tance p.yme nt s s ha ll be li~tted t o the a ctual 'ost of r e nt rrea rage up t o a ma~t ~um of S4 50 pe r month. A t ot a l paymen t ~n d l l not e~ceed S2 700 r ~g rdl es s of the number o f mon t h s of drr~ar.ge cl I f mltigatlRlI hctors are dete r min e d to uiH the M4y o r may grant emergency dssistance p.yments to pay t~ e r!~t, i ncl uding t he first Mont s re nt of a n app licant t o pr eve n t d family in w ~ich child r en under 18 year s o f age are present fro~ becoming hOr1ele ss o r disp laced. If eme r gen cy tl '\e o;e C~cn 1 1 lew, o; ec io' 3 l1)20 lstan ce is gra~ te d, the payments Shall ~e \Ini t ed t o the tual cos t of rent a~rearage up to SSOO pe r "onth. AtouI payml!nt shall not uCl!eol S3,600, regardl e ss of tne numbl!r of mon t of ar rearage SI!C. n. Mortgage emergency a E~e~ge" c y a sls ta nc e Ii ava il able t o prevent an I'1m ln e nt forecl05u r e of a mo rtgage, I f all of t he f ollowIng co nditions are met 1 Th e ap~l lcan t ow o r 15 purc ha sing a home I n the Dist rict 2) Tne owner or pur ch a se r has equity In the pr op erty of a t lea s t la percen t o f the aSiessed value of the p r uperty or has olIa d e at l east 12 co nsec",tive l&amp;lt;Io n thly pa Y l1e~ts on the property 3 The a pplicant is livl In t he ho~e; and 4 The ap pl ican t ha s applll!d fo r and e~hauHed al l benefits t o wh i c h the applicant is entitl e d unde r the Del inquen t ~ome Mor tgage jlne nt s r ogra as e st~ bl ished by t ne De li nq ue nt Home Io rtgage ?ay ~ent s Fund Act of 19 8 4, e ff e i e AU9u st l a, 198 4 (D.C. law S~98 D. C. Code s e c. 4 5- 2 40\ et seq before a deci s i o ca n be rende r ed on eli gjb ili ~1 for, and t h e amoun t of e!:1e r ge nc y assis t ance under t h is act D mergen cy a s s i st a nce payml!nts sh a ll be I \ ml tl!d t o tile d C Ja l co s t 0' the mo rt9d ge arrurage up to a I u l 1u!'\ of S600 pe r Plonth The total paY 1e nt sha ll not exceed S2 OO O re gar jl e~s of the number of mo nth s of arrea r a ge. Sec if dll of 23. tsse nt l !l home rep~ir s emergency. Emerge ncy assis tance f or home repa i rs is available the f o l 10 wl og co ndi ti ons are me t I) The app licant own s or Is p \,lrc h a ~i nQ a home I n the Dis tr ic t 2 Tne owner or pu r chHer ha i equ it y In the pr opl!r ty of at Il!ast 10 \ of t hl! usnse value of the pr operty or has lIade at l ea st 12 co nsecutiv e mon thly p y~ents on t he property 3) Thl! a pplic a n t is cu rre ntly l iving I n t h e home un le ss tempo rar ily ab s ent becau se of the conditio n o f t he p ro perty; a nd (4) me repa i r is ne cessary t o protect the health or safety of the app licant. The nome mus t be currently Jn i nh a bi t ab l e o r I s pro j e c ted t o be un inh ab it a b l e dur i ng CO ld wea th er Repa i rs ~us t re sto re the ho~e t o a ha bitable COl'ld lti on b The May o r s tu ll deny e lllerg, ncy U~ i stdn(e payme n ts, if t he prop.rty f or wh ich t he ap plic a n t re qu ests ene r ge ncy a$ si~t an ce for home repa i r s 1 Is for sal e; 11 ocet it 1- 1021 :le Sf.!C o 3- 10 22 Inrolled Orlstnal (zJ Is no t t h p r jnci l p l c e o f r e s id e nce o f th e ~ppliont; or (3) Is being f or ec los ed e) Emer g e ~c si\ st d nce is limi ted t o th e c osts o f re l rin g t he fal lo wi ng I) Th e plUf'lbi ng system 2) The Wdt tr supply s yst em 13 The a s te d is posal syste m 4 fh e elec tri c d l syste&amp;lt;l 5) Th e hea ting s yst em 6) 8 r o~e n lndows 7) Br Oken doo r s includi ng loc ks and I S} The ro of an d chi~ney d e p d i r of an e ss entia l h o~e item o r system" Shal l ~e li m e:l t o c t ual co s t up t o a payment maximum of SI. OOO SEC I aui la bl e 24. St or a ge dnd mov i ng eme r gency E~erge n cy a SS istance fo r s tarage and mov in g i s on ly if I o f the f o ll owi ng co nd i ti o ns is pre s e nt 1) Th e appllcant seeks t o o ~e from a dlle lling that is cond emned o r one that con st i tu t es a s ub st an t ia l ~hred t t o hea l t h o r safety 2) Tne appl1 cant i s face d &amp;gt;11th an im"\1n@n t @v 1c t i s spe(if i ed in sec t io n 21 3) The ~pp lt c~nt is re locat ing to o r f rom f amil y sni!lt e r 4 The pu rp o se f r elocati on is to p reve nt se paration of a f&amp;amp;ln l l y in wh lc h a C~i l d n d er 18 ye a rs o f a 'J e is pres ent b) Relo c t i o n or st o r~ge e~penses SMdll be limited t o the actu a l cost yp to a max l mYm of S500 Se c. I I o r d4m a ge 25 Se cy rity or da mage depos i ts. Eme rg e ncy ass i stance is availab l e for a se c ur i ty depo s lt if 1 The landlo rd 01 111 not wa ive t he deposit; and 2) 80t h the pp l1c an t an d t he l dlo r d s ign a rep ay men t agreement that provides t~ at the depO S i t, l ess 4ny d ~o u nt fo r d ge s shall be retYrne d t o tMe May o r b A secur1ty o r da~ lge dep osi t c an onl y be aYthor l zed I) If t h e ap p li c ant i s or lI i ll ae homel u s du e t o f i re, Civil diso rder, or natura l o r c h e mi cal disaster; or Z) Th e pu rpos e of the depos i t i s t o r e un i te a child under l8 years of age wi t h hi s or her pare nt o r pre ve n t fa mi ly b re.~d o ll n; or (3) In t he CHe o f a single indiv i d ual or c hildless co uple, tne upl10nt is homel es s an d th e pr ov ision of t ne e~er gency a ssistan ce lI ould al l eviat e the hom e l es sness. 13 ~ew ec&amp;lt i.O'"H 3 l 0 23 !1 c e c&amp;lt lC ­ 102d gt;.yr.t,nt 111 11 be "ad e di rectly t o tile landlord and sn a I l b@ t~e act ua l ~r:10un t of th e dep os it up to a d r:1u;n u spHifled by ve ndor. The ar.lount of t il e sec urity o r da l~ge deposit cannot be mo re tllan 1 Io nt ll's re nt. Sec. 26. Dep osit fo r hut or ut ili ty el'lerge ncy a) Ernergency dss !s tan ce is ava llabl e f or depos i t pay ents if reQuired by lIeHin g or utility vendor to r esto r e or I egin service. Til e deposit Sha ll be paid d tr ectly t o th e venaor wllO Mus t s ign an dgr e emen t t~ return a nf refund t o t fle t~ayo r b) The COSB of t e le ph one Installation deposi t for service, or co nnection, wi l l be paid only if a tele pho ne i s a me dic a l ne ces sity The ne cessi t y "lUS I e verified by tne ph ys i cian of UI Q ~p p l lcant. Telephone r elated costs Ill be paid d irec tl y to t ne ve ndo r ho I"Ust s ign .n d gre e ~ent t o r e turn a ny re f und t o the yor c) Th e a~ount of ~ny depos it or re co nne c ti on fee ~lIall be the c tU Gl cos t up t o r.I i"lUPl of S20 0 Sec 27. Util i ty e~ergency a Emerge ncy aHi~ta fl c e fo r u t ili ties i s ava il .b l e only if all of tile follo win g re qui re l'\e nt ar e met I lh e delinqu e n t 'J il l mus t be tll.t o f Uu a p?l i cant 2) T e terminati on of service mYSt be actual or immin eflt 3) Tile applicant r'1ust app ly for a ll benefits to nlen the app lic an t Ill ay be e n tit led und e r tile Lo w Income En e rgy Assistanc e P~ 09ram a nd otne r energy pr ogr.ms incl ~d ing bu t no t 11!'1ited t o, the Washington Are. Fuel Fu nd b) Emergency assistan c e for telephone b i l ls sh al l be pr Ov i ded i f the need for a telephone i s verified by the p ~ysicl.n of the .ppli c ant as a med ic al ne c eSS i ty. The eme rgen cy assistance is limited t o co s ts of the ba s ic i ns tr Ur.len t and service; no long dis t ance ch ar geS 511all be p a I d c l E.ergency assistan ce for ut ility arrearage i s lin lted to the ctull cost, bu t Shall not e~ceed SI, OOO for gH or 011. or BOO for electricity or ater. Sec. 28 ece ss itles Of emp l OY lent a Energency assistance Is available for the necessities of emplOy me n t If a l l of the fol lOwi ng condltiofl S are ,net I I The applica nt Is .n adu l t who is a r.lember of. and living with, a fami l y whe re a Ch il d under 18 yurs of a ge is present; and lew. Seccl" c 3 gt;2 3 l e w, Se r" t.io 1 r 6 'Ie e~i 3-10 7 Cnrolled Original (2) Th e ~m ploy er ver1fjes t kat the ~eed is legi tt -a te a nd th t the ne cessary ite&amp;lt;1S are not pr ovided by t he enployer b) Emerg ency Hsis ta nce is limlteO to 1) 5 pecial C loth i i nclu di ng un iforms no~ to ex ce ed 2 o~tf1ts; or (l) Tools w~ich mus t be the minimum in num be r dnd ~u a li ty ne cessary t o the employ ~ent el He eme r gency Bs is t ance payment s hal l be lil'lited to dct~~l co s t up t o a rn a~imu m Of $1 00 a) In det ermining eli gibi lity f o r em er gen cy a ssis~anc e to an indiyidU d l HIl a child under ta years o f d~e n der this s e c ~l on, onl y t e i ncor.le a nd re sourc es of t'lH dpp;;cant sn &amp;lt;l ll be consId ered SeC 29. Burial a s sis ta nce. Eme rg e ncy as~i t ance is aV d ll a ble for burial and cre:~lat io r: se rvices if the l iquid d~ sets o f t he deceased person a t t ne ti l"e of dea t h dO not e~ ceeO 58 01 f o r a decea s ed du l t 5641 f o r a deceas ed c~ila, or 5 53 4 ~or de ceased i ~fant. Sec. 30. Mul tip le eme r gency aBh tan ce req ue~ts wi t hin d lZ-tons ecJt\ ve Mo nt h pe r io d d) T~e ap~lican t r equesting emer ge ncy usis tan ce fo r o r e than one 3 0-d~y pe r io d du r i ng a 12- co nsecut i ve-mo "th pO!~i o&amp;lt;l r.lu st me et t ile follo wing eligihility c r i teri~ in ~aoit lon to t he cr iteria sp e cI f i ed in Se ttio n s th r ough Z8 I) Th e subsequen t r equ eU for el!le rg e ncy a~ 5 5t~nce r'lUH be f o r a different c d tegory of emergen cy dsststa nce tna n the pr io r re quest un less the eme rgen cy dssistanc e is r e qu e s t ed by an applicant unit whose members t"cl ude d clllld unde r 18 years of age. a tle r son oye r 6S year i o f g e. o r a reci pI ent o f genera l pub l i c a ssi stanc e or SSt and t he emergen cy as sist~nc e i s f o r f ood housing o r utilities 2) The a pplic ant flUst nav e a stable, ongoing ;ll dn o f r.tanag'lIenl i n whi c h i nCO;1e and resour c e s reaso na bly elpe c ted to be availabh eHeed or are equa l t o the cost o f ba sic neceSSities; and (3) The appll~ant must dem ons tr~te tllat the emer gency is the re sult of an e~penditure fer basic ne c eSS iti es b If em ergency a ss i stance is g ra nted unoer t h is se c t io n t he Mayor sllal l requ i re. as a co ndit i on o f re c e i ving emergency a ssist a nce, th dt the applicant att eno at l ed st t fin anc i al ~ounseling session befor e rece i ving emergency a ssis tance Se c. 31. WaIver by Mayor. 1 5 Kew Sec cr 1-:1)2'1 e lt;:c im 3 29 Ie £ec~l 1- 1 \ 0 SUrolled OrigiQal Notwithst~~ding any ot her provision of this act, tne Mayor may wnen tnere is evidence of e~traordinary ~jti gatjng factors 1) Authoriz e emergency assistance not spec ifically covered in this act, if the €Inergency ~ssist~nce is ne cessary to avoid or alleviate the emergency of an otherwise eligible applicant 2) Recognize certain emergenc ies that dre not specified in this act, hut hich pose a threat to the health or safety of an other ise eligible applicant 3) EHeed payment rnHimums as establiShed by tnis Ht if the additional emergency assistance is necessary to avoid destitution of an other'~1se eligible applicant b) Emergency assistance payments granted under this sect i on 1 dy not exceed 5750 and shall not be available through any ot he r Oi strict program ad~inistered by the )1ayo r c) The Mayor sh~ll report to t~e Councfl ~nnually, dn ta ke available to the public, an iteni;:ed accounting of any e~pendjture nade pursuant to this section. Sec. 32. Rules a) loIit hin 60 day&amp;gt; of the effecti~e date of th 1s act, t he l dyOr sh al l pursuant to title 1 of tne District of Colu"1bia Ad r:1in i&amp;lt;;trati~e Procedure A.ct District of Colu bia Administnthe Procedure Act approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; O.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 issue p roposed rules to i",plelne~t the pro~isions of this act. The proposed rules s~al1 be subm i tted to the Counci l for 4S-day period of revie eHluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal hol idays nd days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or d1sappro~e the proposed ru l es, i n whole or in part by resolution within the 45-day review period, the pro posed rules shall be deemed approved. The proposed rules s~~ll inc l ude pro~isions regarding an appeals procedure for applicants who have been denied emergency assist~nce b) Pursuant to subsection (a the Mayor r.1ay issue rules to adjust the dollar limits i~ this act to reflect a"nual changes in the cost of liv ing and to adjust the income eligibility st~nd~rds to reflect ch~nges in tne poverty line measurement, as prol'lulgated by the United St~tes Bureau of the Census. Sec. 33. A.ppeals a) A.n applicant for emergency assistance w~o has been formally denied emergency assistance shall be entitled to a revie of that denial pursuant to an appeal procedure est~blished by the Mayor, by rule, pursuant to section 32 b) Within 10 business days from the date of tne notice of denial, the applicant shall be pro~ided a clear, concise 16 '1e Sect n,l '1ew, Eectic Hl2 ~rt tt e n state ~ent ir,formin g t~e appl i ca nt 0 the r e a san~ fa r t he deni~l The wntten notic e sh~11 a lso tnfo r m t he a ppll"nt of his. or he r right to ap pe al t he den;&amp;lt;l l and the steps tMe a pp li c a nt l"1ust Uke t o appeal the den hl It) An dPp1ic~nt Sll d l1 ~He 30 busin e H da y; in IOhi ch to fi le an appea l lt;1) An a pplic l nt sh a ll no t be deni ed emerg e ncy us l~ Unee if t h e 4 1pli cant i s Ht ~m ?t1n g t o ob t~ i n and 'urnish required information and ha s i n fortled th e D e par t~len t accordingly. If an appHeant hdS no t f u rni Sh e d the requ r ed nf o rmui on a nd has no t con t Hted the De partl:le nt far 60 ay s the appliOtion shall be consi dered abandoned and he applican t s.hal 1 hHe no r ight of appe~ l e) The appeal pr oc e du r es pro vided by tht~ secUon and any Subsequen t judtc1al re view 50 u9~t pu rsuant t o sec ti on t of t he A d~t n is tr~t i ve Pr ocedu re Act ap proved October tl 1968 (82 Sta t. 1204; D.C. Code s e c. 15 10 s~al l ~e th e exclus h e r em e dy for iolatlons. of t hts !Ct. Sec. 34. Eff ect iv e dne This ac t Sh a ll ta e effect after a 3D -day ~eriod 01 Cong re $sion a l re w te~ fo llo jng appr oval by t he I~ayor (0 in t v e n t of e to by t he May o r, ac t ion by t he Counc il 01· the 5tr'Ct o f :ol umbta to o verr jde th e vet o) as pr ov i ded n senton 602(c){l) o f th e District o f Coluf'lbta Self Go ve rnmen t an d Go vern l'lent')l Reorgant la tton Act, a p~ roved De cember 24 19 73 (87 Stat. 8 13; D.C. Cod e. se c \-233(c)(I dn d (jublic att on in either the Dis t rict of Columbid Registe r, the 01s tr ic t o f Columbia 5 t a tutes H LH ge. or t e Distr ic t of Colu l a Hun ici pal Reg l at tons r (t i \ Ch a l rT!14n Co unci l o f tn e Dis tri c t o f Co lumbia o f Co lu mbh APPROV ED; Janua ry 6 19$9 \1 o,eE 'iCT R"oroe&amp;lt;J on COUSCIL OF T ilE DISTRICT OF CQU M81 Co~n.i1 P iod s.e"u RECOR D OF OFFIC IAL CO UN CIL VOT E B7- 6 8 Adop~ed F i~S t ~e~di ~q, 11 29- 88 Approved, MeMbe r Wi n t or voted Er e s e n t Rolark i~ d--J S- S I eo c l{ gt;'0 '1 I'OT O'd lt C 0 Adopted flnal ReaC!i~q 12- 13-88 ,\pp r o ved a ll pre s e n t Ql C&amp;gt;·V Tl 4SC 5M II Inac a AM II \ eE~r' F'C tECOO 1 C 0 lt;:r 77~-1 s M}" 0 Co O e en eo COIt CTlO 6 OUE 'J OICE VOTE: R r""o 'GI r I'J Ot- C. U VOTE Hu~ I J b </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1201"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1202"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1203"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1204"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1205"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1206"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1207"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1208"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1209"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1210"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>12</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1211"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>13</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1212"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>14</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1213"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>15</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1214"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>16</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1215"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>17</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1216"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>18</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1217"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>19</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1218"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>20</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1219"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>21</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1220"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>22</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1221"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>23</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1222"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>24</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1223"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>25</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1224"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>26</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1225"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>27</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1226"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>28</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1227"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>29</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1228"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>30</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1229"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>31</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1230"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>31a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1230.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>32</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1231"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>33</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1232"/>
  </section>
</document>
