<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-230">
  <num type="law">7-230</num>
  <heading type="short">Authorization to Enter an Interstate Corrections Compact Temporary Act of 1988</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1989-05-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-230.pdf">D.C. Law 7-230</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 7736</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-230, the “Authorization to Enter an Interstate Corrections Compact Temporary Act of 1988,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-542. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 12, 1988, and September 27, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 13, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-242 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. Law 7-230 became effective May 10, 1989.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NCIL OF TH[ OISTRICT Of COLUMBIA NOTICE C. C. LAII 7-230 ·Aytho. lutt~n t o £liter .n Intrrst.te Co rre t t l ons Coap.ct Tr.p~riry Ac t of 1988 t he Act the Co ynctl of the Ohtrltt of Calualll dol'led Sttl No. 1-5_2 o n fj r H and HCI'na fualn&amp;lt;JS, Jill n I98S n Septuher 27, i&amp;lt;JaS, respecthr l y Follo wing the slgniture of l he Mil0 r on Ot l ob .r il 19 Sa, thts NO. 1-2'2 pub li shed I n the Oe tob.r 28. IQSS. t&amp;lt;lltto~ at the RI gtster Y o l. 35 P'g' 1136 n6 1r,n'altted to Congr.ss o. J.nuary 23 1989 fo. I 60-4.y \tw, h Hu.dintl wUh 5ectlQft 602(c o f th, Act. The COlln,tl of t~r Olstrlct of Col abll h,reby gt.es notice thtt t he 60 -d Cong.tuton l Re.tew Pertod hu uptred, iIId th e refore, ctt,s thts ,n,etaent .s D.C. L.w 1-230 effectl.e H.y 1 0 1989. CLARK[ 4hllta.n of lh' Co "n 11 O.tes Cou nt e d Ou rlng the 60 lt;1'1 Co ni r,uhn.1 holt w eriod J i nYi ry 24. 25 ,26.27 30 31 or ry 1.2 3 6 7 .8 ll. 22,21 l 21.28 Hi rt h Apri l 1.2. l 6 7 ,8, 9 I 0 \ 14 \1.20,21,22.23 3,4 S 6 1 I 0 .1 \ .l l .l l .1 11 18 19 25 ,26.27 ,28 1,2, 3 .4.5.8,9 D.C. LAW 7 -230 IU,'I' I I 19ft AM ACT D.C. ItT 7 24 2 IU TK( COUNC IL Of THE DIS TRIC T Of COLU MBIA OCT I I TIa CtlDMrA1U)N fwo..pt 1 of tl t h 24 (1989 SI4'P To en.ct. on I ternpor.ry bUIS. hgtslttlon t o enlble tile Distr i ct of Colu~bl~ t o tnter ,n Interstlte Cor rf ctlo n atlp ac t BE IT EHACfEO BY THE COUNC IL OF THE OI ST RI CT Of COLUMBIA, TII.t t hl e t ~11 be Cit ed IS tft Authoril,tlo" to [ Rter In I nler1Ute Co rrec t ions C_PHt htlpo r lr Act o f 19815 Sec. 2. Th e 1'I or is luthorized to enter into d execute on beh.lf of the District of 'ol uab I coap. et with all sU te o r Stl tu l'j, I1 1 joltllng In the co.ptet In tht f o subs unth ll y U 0 110 s I NTERSTA TE CORRECTIONS CO HPA CT AR TICLE I. The PHt st lt U desiring by co on Htia" to fully utl11lt Ind l pr ove th e t r instltution.1 f,ctl lt les .nd proYl ~e .deq u.te prg 9 r s fgr the egnfln e.ent, tr e.t nt. and rrhlbilltatlon gf varlou types of off en d.r dltl. r e th~t It 1~ the poliCy of tlch of the plr ty slil es to provide fa c ilIties Ind progrlei on bas i s of cooper lt lon ith one &amp;amp; no t~er .nd ~lth t he fede r, I gover n e nt, th lHCby HrYlng till be~t Interf~t of offende rs a nd $oclety Ind effectln~ econ o~le$ In Cl pit e~pendlture$ a nd oper lt to n.l costs, The p~ rposr of thts COIlPHt is to prov id e fur the IIulU ll de. e lop. t nt and ecution of progra of cooperltion f o r t he con flne",ent trutllr nl, and habtlltttior Of ~ff endl1'5 1th th e ~os t conolll cl' use hu n nd lI.terl sourcrs. ARTiC LE II. 1 AS ed In tills COIllPHt UR IcH tile con tut eu11 requires otherwIse Stete e. ns state of the United Stites. the United St i tes of A~erl t I terrItory or possess to n of the United States, the Olstrlct of (o l uoabll, or t he C OQ~onwe l l t n of Puerto Ri c o b Stndhg s ut e muns I stUI plrty to tills com p'~t I n whtch conviction or court COMmitment WIS hid e R. c hln sU te elM. st,tr p.r t y to th is compl c t to whi ch In Inmlt t I s sent f or confi nemen t o ther thin I s t.te In whiCh conv Ic ti on o r cou rt co l t"ent .1 hid. d Inmate me.ns ma l or f l of f ender who Is commIt ted or under sent en ce to or con fi ned In I penal o r c orrect iona l IM.t Hl/ tton. t in s tllllllo Ins I lly penl' or correction. 1 hcllHy. Inc l ud i ng but no t 1I111H t d to I helllt for til c ellt.l1 111. In "lIlc~ lnm~ tu IS defined In &amp;lt;1 .t~OH 1 1."f~ ll be confined. ARTIClE [I I. I. [Hh p.rt tett II ke 1 or 1II0re cont cts "Itll ony 1 or mO e of the o t er plr ty ltlte5 or wi til the f,d,rll govt r nlllen t for the eonfl t of In.I\ 15 on behllf of I n n&amp;lt;1lng Hltl In I lIst H u t lon Hulted Ithln recehl"t Hites The c ontrl t t ,nll1 pro v id e for 1. It' durlt lon. 2 Iyments to be ml d e to th e receiving ,tlte or to tn. ftderll governMnt by the sending S titt fo r I~.ltl Int,n nee utr, o rdln,ry !le dl,,1 or dent.l upln5U, or I ny pertlclpltlon In or re" lpt by lU of r,lIlbllltathe o r co rr ec t iona l Il!r~lce 11Itle5. progr l s o r trutlllent no t r elson lbly In cluded 0\ pl rt of narlll.l I tlnlnce 3. Plrtl clpa tlo n In pr ai run of lnl1'te employment, If ~ny; the d ls po~l tl on o r ,redltlng o f Iny payment r e ceived by \nllli t es On I ccount of t _ploy nt I"d T~e c ~e dit ;no o f prot e~ d~ fro o r dlspaul o f I ny pro&amp;lt;1ucts r e SU lting fro. t he p l oyment. 4 Deli very a nd r etl kl ll' Of Inmates nl o t~er mlt t ers eeuHry to fh t hi! obllg l ti OIlS, repon 51 b ll1tl es nd rights o f the Hndln, IIId r e cehlng sutes b. Th e terms and pr OviSions of tills compac t Shall bt part o f I ny con trac t entered I~to by the a utho rity of o r pursuant t o the CI c t H d o t~ln 9 I" contrACt sh i l l be In c onsls ~e nt l t n tlot COllpact RTI Cl£ JY I Whenever thl .pproprl.te offlcl.l 1 In I st.tl p.rt, to this tcap.et and wh Ich h.s I~ttr ld Into, contr.ct p~r$ulnt to Artlc l l I I I. s ll dlCldl thlt (onfln e~e nt In 0' t r .nsfer of In In~lte tc In tn~tltutlon wi thi n the terrlt c ry of nother puty sUte Is "neH or desirable In ordlr t o prowld oequatl qUlrters .nd c,rt or In .pproprlate pro~rla of rehlbili tati on or t r elt~ent the .ppropr l,te offlcl. ls MIY ol re ct th,t the COnfinement be within .n Institution with i n the arrltory of t ne otht r part, SllU. tht rfCtltlng s tat t t o act I n th.t ,eg.rd solily IS gtnt f or the sending ilatt. b. The appropr\ltt offlchls of .n, Hue plrt, to th is c oap.ct Shil l h'te .CCt s s t I I "Isonlble tlael, to ,n, Institution In _hlch It h iS I cont ra ctull right to con fine ln~.tes for the pu'pose of Inspectl"9 the facilities In d yl s l tl n9 Its ,na.tts confln.d tht I nstlt~tlon. Co in,utes confln.d In In Instill/tio url nt to the te s ef thll COt&amp;gt;"lCt s ll .11 .t .1\ tla II. JUIIJlct to the Jur i sdiction of the sending ,t.tt d a t ,ny tlae be "aov ed fr~ the receiving st.t. for tr'ns'e, to a "rl,o" Or otlle r Institution "Ithln the sending IUU, f or tnn'hr t o no ther Institution _It blch the sending It.t h.ye contractu l or oth.r right to tonfl~e InlllllS, for leue on "roll.tlon or parol for dlsch ,rge. or for Iny other purpose per~ltted by the 11 of the sending statt rotld,d that t hl sendiftg state ,hall cont~ftU e to be olll1gaUd to p'ymtnt\ required pursu.nt to the ter of In, contrlct e nt ered into under the te"'1 of "rllcle III. d ['eh r.(elvln9 state sn,ll provide regul.r reports t o e,eh sendi ng stat, 0 the In~.tel of that lending Itlte i n I nstitutions pu rsuant to this co~p.ct Inc lu ding. conduct re co r d of uch 1 IIte .nd urtlf, the r.(ord t o the .ppropriit. offlcl,l d,s'gnlteo by the lending ,t.t In ord r th.t eh In ll.l Iy hi" offlcll\ tl of hIs or h.r r.e ord In d.ttrmlnln9 and It.rlng the dlspolltlon of the n te In Heord,nee I th the 1 wh ich obt,ln In tile s. nd lng st ate .nd I n ord.r lhlt the record ay be s ou r ce of InfOnftatlon for tne sending It.te. e 11 I ne lln confi ned I n n InH ltutlon pursu,nt to t he p r ot hl o~s of thH compHt I~11l be trllttd In" r e' ion b l nd hU~l n e nntr .nd th 11 li e tre.ted equal l wi t h tlmll'r Inm. te s of tne r eeel.ln g stlte confined In the s me I ns tituti on. Tn. flct of conrlne~ent In receiv i ng it a t sh il l no t deprl.e Iny Inm,te so confined of In, legal rlghti whic h tht In~lte wo~l d n~v~ hi d If confin ed In In I p pr oprh t nH utlon of the send Hate. f. Any h.arlng to whlCl' If t oMlntd pursu,nt to t h is CO~Plc t mlY be entitled by the II of thl ,ending state Mly b, c onduc ted before t he lo proorl ate offlcilis of the lending Itatl or of t he r.celtlng st.t e If lutnorlttd b l Hod'ng ~tltt. T~r receiving sua sh~lI proytde deq te lllt l es for the hear'n9' conduct.o by t he Ipproprlitr offlch ls of I sending Hlte. In the evrnt the hear'ng 1~ condu c ted before .ppr oprl.te offl c l.ls of lhe rec eIv i ng ~tate. the governing I sh,ll be 1h,t of the sendln9 st.te Inel I record of the helrtn r.serlbed by the sending stlte !tI,11 be de. Thl rec or d together Itft .n reccm~endot lon5 of the he.rlng offl c l.l sh,l l be Immediate l y tr.n l tted to the .pproprl.te offici before whom the he.rlng wou l d hIve been cond~cted If It h.d tl ke n pl ace In th e sud!"g s ute In .ll proceeding, conducteo PU r SUlnt to the prodslon~ of thh subsection tile .pprop.l.te offl c l.ls of the rece,.lng ,t.te 5h.11 Itt s ole l y .s 'gent$ of tnt stndlng stlte Ind ftO flnll determination shill be "de in Iny ttrr elcept by the .ppro prl ~te offlcills of tnr sending stlte g. Any i n~.te confined pursu.nt to thIs co_plct shill be r.lusrd Ithl n thr trrritory of the sending state \/nless the t nmlt nd the sending Ind r. cel.lng states Igree upon re l eue In so e oth er phce. The sending stlte sh.11 bur the cost of the retu rn to Its territory h. Any Inute confined pursulnt to the teMIS of th1$ CO~ Pl ct snl ll hl.e III rights to plrtlclpate in Ind derive Iny benefits or Incur or be re l hved of Iny obligltlons Or h~ve obllg.tlons modified or chlnge In stltus on Iccount o f a ny Ictlon or proceeding In whlen he Or she could h,.e partlclplted If confined In Iny .pproprllte Institution of the sending stlte locltrd ~It hln the sending stlte. 1. The plr.nts, gUlrdlln, trustee, or other p.rson .ntltled und er the llws of the 5.nd1n9 stlte to let for Idvlse, or otherwise function with respect to y In~lte shll\ not be deprived of or restricted In the e erclsr of a ny power In respe c t of Iny In"lte c onfined pursuant to tht t t~IIS of t h is COlllp.ct ARTICLE Y. I. Ant decis i on of the se ln9 st.te In respett of any IIltt,r over which 1t retllns ju rl ~6lc tl on pursulnt to thl$ cOllp. et Shill be conclu$lve upon ,nd not revlew.ble ~It hln the ~e(eh 'ng sttt but If It the time the sending sttt. s eeks to remo ve In jn~ate f ro an Institution In the ree e l ving state there is pe ndi ng .gl l nst the 'n lte within the retrtvlng stlte any crl11l1n.l charge Or If the InllHe I s for ll y ac cused of hlv l ll'l co tt within the recclvln'l stitt criml'\ ,1 offense. the Ino sh,ll not be returned wIth ou t the consent of tne re vln~ s t,t, until dlsc hlrge fr o~ prose cu tI on Or o ther forN of pro ceeding. IlIprisonlllent. Qr detention for the offense. The approp rl,te offlcl.ls of t he sending s tate sh ill be perNltted to trlnsport Inllitel pu rSU'"t t o this COl'tpact th r oyg~ all lUtes PHty to this COl!\ p~ct without interfe r ence b An I n u ho ttClPU 'ro n InHHuti on in h ie he h confi ned pursu a nt to this CO"'PHt sh.11 be. fU9lth' f rom the H!ndln9 s tlte and from the recehlng stitt. In He ca~e of an elc .pe to J urisd ic tion oth er thin the sen~tng or recelYi ng s tate the r espo nsibil i ty for InstItut ion of tradition or re ndi tio n proceedi ngs sh a ll be th't of the se nding s ta te but no thin g contained In this conp_ct shil l be c ons trued t o prev ent or a ffect th t c t i yltles of off ice rs a nd gencl es of y ju r isdiction directed t o d the a ppr ehe nsion .nd r etur n of In e s capee ART ICLE l. Any stit t party to thiS comp.c t Y a cc ept federal ltd f o r us. In connection with Iny instlt~tion or pr 09 rl tht u s of which 11 or Iy bt I"tcted by this CO.plct or Int &amp;lt;OtlOP Ht pursulnt to th is let I nd Iny Inlllit. In I r.e.ivlng s tate ~ursu~nt to this COIII~lCt lilly plrtlc lp.te In Iny federlllY -l lded pr og r u o r "thlty for whi ch the ffnd lllg Ind r.ce lvlng statu hIVe III l d. contr,ct ull pr01'15lon, provided t h l t If tht progr am or I cthl tt Is no t p.rt of the cus toma ry correctl o nl l ,egl en, the up rus cons.nt o f the appr opriate offlcl l l of the sending stlt e shill b. r.qu lr .d fo r p, rtlclp at lon In t n. feder.llt-alded progr A~T1CL[ VII. Thts co.pa c t sh i ll becOQe e ffectlv. I nd b inding upon the stite s so l'tln 9 wh en It hiS been enlcted Into l'N by any two H a US. The reafter, thh cOrl,let Shall become effective e nd binding a s to ny othe r of the Stlt.S upo n sl~ll ,r act ion by the stat ART ICL E VIII. Tnts CO lllp let Shill con ti nue In effect and re ln binding upon I party stlt e untll the Plr ty sta te tn,cts st.tute repe, l ing tht comp c t Ind prov iding for the sending o f fOrl':l l l written not Ie. o f wlt~d~lw.1 f roll t~e co.pac t to the a ppropri ate official of II oth er partt $tlt es. An aetuol withdrawal sh ll not t.ke eff.ct until 1 yelr .f te r the notice p r ovided I n the st.tute h a been lint Tne wltMr l shi ll no t re I live t hl wlthdr lw ln g stlte fr oll Its obll gltlons I Hu med under the COI'P~C Ior to the effective dat e of wlt~d r a" J Sefore ~he f c dlte of ~It hd r wlthdr' wlng $tlte s h.11 r e .o we to ttl te.rlto ry, a t I ts o n e.p.nH II I n tes of the l1tndra"jn~ sUte confined pur1u .nt to the prowhlons of t~h comp.ct. ARTIC LE Il. Nothing con tained In this (oapa c t shall be con~tr u ed to a br 09 ate o r 11I'p a l r a y agree nt o r o tner arrangement nlc~ d party stlte ouy have ith non~lrty sUte for t he con f jneQe nt rehab i li tati on o r trut"'e" t o f In tes nor to repeal dny other lI s of 4 PHty Hlte .utho rl zlng the 1I ki ng of coope r.t i ve I n~ tltut lon.l ,rr,ngeaents. A~T1CLE l. Tne p ro~lslons of this COIl PHt sllll1 be Ilber.lly co nHrul!d nd s ll bt sever' bl e. If .ny pnr.se, c line, sen ten ce, o r provision of this comp,ct Is dl!cl.rtd to be contr.ry to the constitution of ,ny p.rtlclp.tlng st .te or o f t he Unit ed St.tes o r tne ,ppll e .blttty of thl! CO"lpICt to any gove r nment gency. person, or ctreu.st,nee Is htld I nv.lId t he ul l dlty of the re lnder of thts CO~Pltt d t he ap plicabili ty of the comp. e t t o .ny govern_ent. Igency. person. o r clrcu"st ,ne e Shil l not be .ffected by t~e cOmplCt. If t h ts eOlllp .ct ,h. ll be held contr .ry to tht const itution o f .ny stlte p.rtlclpIUn\1 In the C;OIllPHt. the coapact sh.ll reB. t n In ful l force and effect IS to the r emaining Sl H e s and In full force and effect as t o the s t.te .fftcted 's t o ,I I sev er.blt BatterS. Sec. J. The H'yor shi ll GO .1 1 thln\1' neeesu ry Ind Inelden tal t o the execu ti on of t he CO,"PICt. Sec. 4 a T h t~ l et sh.l 1 tikI! e ff ec t ,fter 50- d1Y perio~ of Co n9ress10n,l rlvle follo lng .ppr OHl by the H.yor (o r In th l! event of Vl!t o by t he Kayor f c tlon by the Coun c il of t he Dhtrict of Columbia t o ourrlde the veto) as provided In ,e e tlon 602(t)(2) of t e Ols t rlct of Colulllbl. Self GOvern1l'ent and Governmental Reorglnlz.tlon Act, a pproved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813: O.c. COdt set. l ZJ3(c)(Z» and pub l ication Ir, t ne Distr i c t o f tO IUllb 11 Re9 lst er th e Di strict of Cclumbl. Statutes-lt _Large. or the Dis tr Ic t o f Co l u~bll "u nlc lp~l RI!gul l tlon f.ection ]4-1I1n2 b) Tnt t hill expire on n.v tny t'~fn eff. c t the 2Z5th.d.y Y of 1 U h,lt n Council of t he Ohtr tc t o f Co l u b t Iyor is trict of APP AO~ED: Dctober 13, 1988 Not s.cclonll 24·1001 11Yl2 &amp;lt o 8 o £ Q 0 o o g r3!l \~IY N 0 lt; 0 gt Z o 8 Q o N N o I o 0 0 o o lt 0 o o -o f o e o 0 0 Z 0 l 0 I i2 11'1 I 0 I 0, o 1::1 e 0 z 0 i &amp;lt 0 N N gt N N 0 0 0 0 lt lt 0 lt; 0 0 0 gt 0 0 o gt I e I 11 111 I p Ii i N lt; 1 c :tH J 0 i lt; 11 I I 0 0 0 I~U 0 l 0 lt o g 0 o gt;&amp;lt I i i 1 •</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-1001"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-1002"/>
  </section>
</document>
