<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-24">
  <num type="law">7-24</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Sales Tax Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1987-09-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-24.pdf">D.C. Law 7-24</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 4515</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-24, the “District of Columbia Sales Tax Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-243, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 16, 1987 and June 30, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 6, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-45 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NC I L OF THE DIS TRI CT OF COLU MBI A II OTICE D. C. LA~ 7· 24 "D i stric t o f Col u.bla Sal e s Tax Amend.en t Act o f 1987 P~rsu a nt to Sec t ion 412 o f th e Oistrlt t of Cul u.bf a S@lf Go verOlllent ~nd Gov"r nlllentlll Re organ i zatio n Ac t, P. L. 93·1 98 t he Ac t t he Cou nefl o f the Dist r ict of Columbia adopted 8ill No. 7· 243 on first n d second r dln 9 s, Jun e 16, 1987 and J une 30, 1981 r esp@ct i vel y. Follo wi ng the Sl9n atu re of th e Ma yor o n Jul y 6, 1987, thi s l egislat i on wao a5s l g~ed Act 7-45, publ i sh ed in t he J ul y }7 1987 editio n of th e Register VOl. 3 4 pa ge 45 15) an d transmitted t o Congre ss on July la, 1987 f o r 30 d ay r ev i ew. In ac co r dan ce wi th Sec ti o n 602(c)(1) o f the Ac t. Th e Coun c il of t he Di stri c t o f Co lum bia here by giv es not ice tha t the 3D day Congr essional Re v i ew Per iOd ha s u pl red and th ere fo re ci t e s t hi s e na c t ment as D. C. l aw 7-24, e ffec ti ve Se p temb er 22, 19B7 Dates Co unted During the 30 day Congress i on a l Rev ie w Peri od J u l y 10 .1 3 14 1 S 16 17 20 2 1 22 21 24 27 28 29 0 31 A.ug ust 3 4 5 6 7 Se p t elllber 9,1 0 11 ,14, 15 16. 17 18.21 D.UAVI 7 2 4 u SEP 2 2 1987 AN ACT D.C.ACT 7 -45 I N THE COUNCIL OF THE OISTRICT OF COLUMBIA TO amend the Dl ~trict of Co lumb i a Sa l e. Tax Act by exclud~ng f rom taxation the sale of e l igi b l e f oods purchas ed with tedera l food ItNflPs BE I T ENACTED BY THE COUNCI L OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA That this a ct may b e Cl. ted as the "Diu.rict of Columb i a Si'lle. Ta x Amendment Act of 1987 Sec 2 Section 12 8 of the Distri.c t o f Col um b i" Sa les Ta x Act, approved May 27, 194 9 6 3 Stat 115 D C Code sec. 4 7-200 5 i s amended by addi ng a n e w s ubsec tion (x) to read as foliololll x Sales o f "eligibl e food s as de fi ned in t .itle 7, section 27 1 .2 o f the Code o f Fed era l Regu lations pursuant to t he federal Food Stamp Ac t of 1977 appr oved September 29 1977 91 St,at 958; 7 U.S.C 20 11 Stamp Ac t a nd purch ased wi t;h f ood stamps t o the S t a mp Act Sec 3 Section 2 of t he Di stE'ic t of Columbia Sales Tax Ame ndmen t Act of 1987 shall apply t o sale s ma de afte r Septffrnbe r 30 1987 Sec 4. Th is ac t shall take e ff e ct aft e r a 3D-da y per iod o f Congressional rev i e w following approval by t he ~yoc (or in the e ven t o f ve t o b y t he Mayo r sctlon by the Council o f the District of COlumb ia t o o ve r ride the v eto) a s prov l ded in sec tion 602t c)(1) of the District o t Columbia Self- Governmen t and Governmental Reo r9~ni zat ion Act, L D. C. C(.oJ sec 47- 20 05 (1988 SlIFe te, D. C. Co&amp;lt; sec. 4 7-~005 (1988 sun lurolled Original approved Decemb r 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec 1- 223 (c) OJ Chairman Council of the Oi lit l-ict of Col umbia Col umbi a APPROVED July 6, 1987 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRI CT OF COLUMBIA CoWlcil Pto'M&amp;gt;d Se""D RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO 2~4~3 1 ClION &amp;amp; 0 TE o lt d lt d L c11 C'L o 'c YOrE Unanimous RROme&amp;lt \&amp;gt;c1 n reQu o" CrllwfOId A.b3erot CC Dlle ill 11 OIl eo c cr,ON DAn dopt ed fJ l Re~din9. 6- 30 lt;I VOICE VOTE Y.roanimous A or v&amp;lt gt;11 on 1 all p re sen I'IOU CALI. VOTE RE$ULT I o ACT ION 1 D"TE l VOICE VOTE A«:on:I$CI on _yetI 0 </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
