<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-25">
  <num type="law">7-25</num>
  <heading type="short">Gross Receipt Tax Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1987-10-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-25.pdf">D.C. Law 7-25</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 5068</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-25, the “Gross Receipt Tax Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-186, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 30, 1987 and July 14, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 17, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-47 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>CO UNC IL OF THE DI STRICT Of COLUMBIA NOTI CE O. C. LAW 7- 25 "Gr o s~ Receipts Tn Ame nd ment Act of 1987 Pursuant to Senton 412 o f the Dist ri ct o f Colum hi a Self Governm en t a nd Govern Me ntal Reorganization Act. P. L. 93- 198 t he Act t he Council of the District o f Col u.bl a od op ted 8111 NO. 7- 186 on f i rst and ~eco nd r eadings Ju ne 30. 1987 a nd J u ly 14.19 87 r espec t htly. Following the sign Uure Of the Nayor on July 17. 1987 tht s l eghlati on a ass i gn ed A~t 7- 47. publlsh ed i n t he August 1. 19 87 e dition of t he D. C. Registe r Vol. 3 p"gt 506B) and tra n s mi tted t o Con9re~s on Jul y 21. 19B7 f o r a 3D-day reyi@w, in Hcorda n~e lt h SH t io n 602( c)(I of the Act. The Co uncil of the Oist r lc t of Colu.bia here by gives notiC e t hat the 3 0- day Congressional Re v i e Per io d has expired fnd ther efore ci tes th is enac t ment ~s D.C La 1 25 ef fe ctive Octob e r l. 1987. Dates Co~n ted Ouri~9 the 30 d~y Congre~~ion~l Revie w Peri Od: July 21 22 2 3 2 2 7 28 .29. 30 31 Augu st J.4.S.6.7 Septelllber 9 10 ,1 1.1 4. 15,16 ,1 7.18.21.22,23 24 25.28 .29,30 D.C. LAVI 7 -2 5 It v&amp;lt; OCT 0 t 1987 AK ACT D.C. ACT 7 -47 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU~ BIA M. 1 7 1981 o ~end An Act Milking IIppropria t i ons to provide for the eKpense of the govecrur.en t of the District. of Col umbi'} for the fiscal year ending J une thirtieth nineteer. h ur.dro:&amp;lt;:l and thr e e. bnd t o r ot.her purposes to cla r i f y the sale of commodit.ies by telecommun ication compllni e~ in the Distt"ict of Columbi a fo r purposes of impo sing a gross r e ceip t s t ax and t o provide /I l imi ted exemptio n f rom and credit aq ains t. the personlll pr operty ta x t o amend the Dis tr ict. o f Columbia Sales Tax Act. to provide II limited exemption lind to amend the District o f Col~~bie Use TIIK Act to ~ke /I techn ical amendment. BE I1 Et1ACTED BY THE COUt&amp;gt;CIL or THE DIST RICT OF COLUMBIA, Thll t t hi$ act ma y b e cited as the "Gross Receip t s Tax Arnen&amp;lt;lrr,e"t Act of 1 987 Sec. 2, Section 6(S) of An ACt eoking a prroprillUons t o p~ ovide f o r the expotn.e Of the government of the Distr ict of Columbia for the fiscal \lear ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and t hree, and f or other purpose s approved July L 190 2 (32 Stat. 619: D.C, Code sec 47-2501 i s a mended to r ead as follo~s 5)(1 Before the 2 1s t day of e ch calendar month, ea ch gall, electric l ighting. and telephone company that sell s public u tility services or cOfl'lmod i t i es ithi" t he Diatri ct of Col\lmbi a s ha ll i File an affidavit ith t he Mayor i nd i ca t ing the amount of i ts grosll receipt s for the precedi ng calendar month from t he sale o f p ublic uti li ty .e rvi ce s and commod i tie ith i n t he Distr i c t o f Col umbia d ii) Val' to t he Mayo r 6. 7t of these gross r eceipts 8 ei) 1:Ie&amp;lt;;1nning July 1. 1986. each telecommunication company not s ubject t o the tax imposed b y subpa r agraph CA) of t ni s pllragraph shall 1 D.C. Code. n 41-2"&amp;gt;01 (1988 supp I) Report by affid av it filed with the Mayo r t he amount o f i t s mon t hly g r oss r ecei pts fr om the al e o f toll te lecommunication s erv i c es t hat o rigina te fr am or termina te On telecommunication equipmen t l o c a t ed i n the Distr ict and for which a t oll charge or peri od ic charge is bill ed t o an apparatus. teleph one or a ccount in t he Oi 6trict t o a customer l ocation i n the District. o r t o a per son res i ding in the Distr i c t dthout regard t o he r e the bill f or t he service i s phys ically recei ved and II Pay t o the ~layo r 6.7% o f t hese gros s receipts ii) Fo r each calendar month begi nn ing afte r September 3 0 1 987 each tel e cOJ\lJflunication COOlpa'1y s hall pay the g r oss r (C eipt~ ta ll imposed by t his subparag raph before the 21 s t day of the succeed ing c al enda r mont.h. The affidi!lvit s for e ach ci!l lenda r mo nth s h a ll be fil ed at the ti.me payment is made o r on the 2 0 t h day o f the s ucceeding calenda r month IOhichever il&amp;lt; e rlier iii)(I) Fo r t he period beginning July 1. 1 986 and end ing August 31. 1987 t he gro se r.ce i pts ta x i mposed by thi s subparagrsph sha ll be due on t he ate t hat th" Gr o Receipt s Tax Ame ndment Act o f 1 987 tak es effect The t.all f or t.h is period shall be paid in 2 equs l i nstal1me nu; be f o rlIO Kovember I 1987 ane before Janu&amp;lt;lry 1 1999 The Mayor ma y, upon written &amp;lt;lpplic tion made before the date pre sc r ibe d f o r pay ment o f t h e ta x. grant rea sonable extension o f time fo r paying t h e t&amp;lt;lX whe~ever good ClO use exists for the ext e n s i on The affid av its tor e a ch ca lend&amp;lt;lr month of this period s hal l be f il ed at t he t ime th e fir et installment paymen t is made or on Oc t.ob e r 30 1997 which ever is e arl i er II Fo r t he period beginnin9 September I, 1987, and ending September 30. 1957 the g r os" r eceIpts t a x i mposed b y t hi s subpa r agraph shllli be paid bef o re October 21, 1997 The required affidavit s h all be f iled li t t he time t h e pa yment i s made o r On Octo be r 2 0 1 9 9 7. Whiche ver is tarlier Il l) Each te l ecommunica t ion company SUb ject t o the g r o ss r ece i pts tax imposed by thi s s ubpa ragraph fo r t h e pe riod beginning July 1. 1996 a nd endi e g September 3D, 1987 hall be allo we d a credit aga i ns t t he gros s r eceipt s tall imposed by t.h is aubparagraph f or the amount. o f perlonal property ta x t ha t il al locable to t he period beginning J uly 1 1986. and end ing Septembe r 3 0 1997. and that i s paid pursuant t o An Ac t Mak ing apprOpriations to pr o vi de fo r the ellpenees of the g overnment. o f the Distri c t. o f Colu~hia f o r the fi scal year end ing June t h i rt ieth, ninetee n hundred and three, and fo r Othe r purpose a ppr oved July 1. 190 2 (32 Ste t. 611: D.C Code. s ec 4 7-15 01 and t.he Person al P ropert y Tax AmendJ:\en~ Act 2 of 1986, effective February 28, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-212; D.C. Code, sec. 47-1521 et se1 iv Gro ~s receipts from the sale by any telecommunic a tion company of toll telecommunication services for resale to any other telecommunication company subject to the gross receipts t a x under this subpa ragr a ph shall be exempt fram the gros~ receipts t a x under this subparagraph v) For purposes of this subparagr a ph r) The term "telecommunication cctllpany" includes and is not limited to every person, as defined in section 109 of the District of Colu~bi a Sales Tax Act, approved Ha y 27, 1949 (63 Stat. 113: D.C. Code, sec. 47-2001(i», and lessee of a person who provides for the transmission o r reception within the District of Columbia of any fornl of toll telecommunication service for a consid era t~on II The term "toll te leccromunication service" mea ns the tr a nsmission or receptior, of any sound, vision, or- speech communication for wr_ich there is a toll charge that varies in amount Idth the dist a nce or elapsed tr a nsmission time of each individu a l communication; or the transmission or reception of any souna, vision, or speech communic a tion that entitles a person, as defined in section 109 of the District of Col umbia Sales Tax Act, approved Ha y 27, 1949 (63 Stat. 113; D.C. Code sec. 47-2001(i» pon the payyc;ent of a periodic charge, wh ich is determine d a B a fl a t amount or uj)On the basis of tot a l elapsed tr ansmission time, to an unlin-,ited number of communicutions to Or from al l or a SUbstantial portion of the person s having telephone or radio telephone stations in a spec i fied area that i s outside the loca l telephone system area in which the station providing this service is located C) Notwithsta nding a ny other provision of l aw, each gas, electric lighting, telephone company, and telecommunciation compa ny subject to the tax imposed by this paragraph sh a ll pay, in addition to the gross receipts t a x, the franchi se tax imposed by the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947, approved July 16, 1947 (61 Stat 331; D C. Code, sec. 47-1801.1 et seg the real prop~ty t a x impo~ed by the District of columbia Real Property Ta x Re vi s ion Act of 1974, approved September 3, 1974 (88 Stat 1052: D.C. Code, sec. 47-801 et seg and the personal property tax imposed by An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for tne fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and tllree, and for ot],er purposes, approved July 1, 1902 (32 Stat. 617; D.C. Code, sec 47-1501 and the Personal Property Tax Amendment Act of 1986 e ffect. ive february 28, 1987 I I&amp;gt c Law 6 212; D. C. Code, eec 47-1 52 1 et sea t o the extent provi~ed in lleetion 6(10) of An Act'-Maldng appropril!ltions t o p rovide f or the expenses of the gove rnmen t of the Di.triet of Columbia for the f i$cal ye a r ending June thI rt Ie t h nineteen hund r ed and t h ree, anu fo r other pu r poses, a ppr ove-a July 1. 1902 (32 Stat 62 u D. C. Code sec. 4 7- 1508 0) Befor e February 1, 1988 the Mayor llhall i) Report t o the Council on the tax treatme nt o f telecommunciation and related service s in other ju rI sdic tions a nd ii) Make recommenda tion s as t o hat, if any, add itional telecommunication and related services should be subje c t to tax by the Distr i ct If) The Mayor shall l.sue r etroac tive "nd pros~ctive r ules n ee"llsary t o carry ou t the provisions 0 1 this pa rag r aph i n a ccorda nce with sec ti on 107 of the Distr ict o f Co lumbia Admin i st r a tive l' r oc ed u re ACt. a pproved October 21. 1968 (82 Stat 12(.13 D.C. Code, s ec. 1-1506 Sec. 3 Sect ion 6(10 of An Act Making appropria t ions to p r ov i de foe the e xpenses of the government of t he ll illt.rie t. o f Colwnbi a fo r t he fillcal yea r ending J u ne thictieth, nineteen hundred and three and foe Other pucpO~ es approved July 1, 190 2 (32 Stat 620; O,C. Code, sec 4 7 lS0S is amended as f o l lows a) llJ l.'l':lati"g t xisU g t o x o a s subparag r l&amp;lt;ph (A Cb) By adding a nll\o sub- su bparagraph TI:rRDC A) t o subpa rag raph (A) t o read as follo s THIRD(A The persollal pc_perty o f any gas elect.rie light ing, or t elephone compa~y regul ated under An Ac t making approp :r ia tions t.o provid e for the e Xpel1.el of the Oistriet o f Co l umbia f o r t he fisc al yea r ending June t hIrtieth. nin et.een hundred and fo urteen a n d f o r o ther p u r poses approved Ma rch 4, 1913 37 SUt. 9 74: D.C Co:ie, s£&amp;gt;&amp;lt 43 10 1 et aeg if the gas electric lighting or t elephone company is sub ject to a gross rec ei pts tax in for c e in th e Di strict for the pe riod of time or f or any portion of t he tilDe."cov er ed by any r e turn regu ir ed t o be filed by the Pe rsonal Pr operty Tax AI:1e ndlDen t Act. 0 1 19B6, effective February 2 B, 19B7 CD .C. La 6 212 D.C. Code ec 4 7 -1 521 et £eg c) By "dding II. new SUb- subparagraph TEIRO(B) to subparag rap h A) t o relld a. f ol lolo's TttlRO(Bl The personal p r op e rty o f any telecommun i cat. i on company, as de f ined in section 6(5 e)(v)(I u!ed or consumed in furnishing a .e r vic e if D. C. Cod S ~C 47-1508 (l988 surp Inrollod OTlg1D the r eceipts frail furnishing the s erv ice are subje ct t o a gross receipts t"x in f o rc 1n the Di s tri c t f o r t h e p&amp;lt r i od of time Or f o r a ny portion o f the time c overed by any r eturn required t o be filed by the Personal Pro pez-ty Tax Amendment Act ef 1986, eHective Februllry 28 1987 (D C. La 6-212: D. C. Cod e, s ec 47-1 5 21 et seq ex cept that if the persona l property is used both t o p r oduce receipts SUb j ect to II gross rec e i pts t a x in t he Dist ri c t lind receipts not subjec t t o II gross r eceipts tU; in the Oi5trict, then t he p ersonal pr oper ty t/iX e xempti on shall be al10Cllttld ~n accordance i th z-ul es ie~ ed by the Mayor and Id By ~H'ding a ne s ubperagraph (8) to read as f ollows B) The ~\ayo s hall i ssue r ules neces sa r y t o carry out the prov is ions of sub- s ubparag r aphs THIRD(A) and THIRD (a) in acco r da nc e with Titl e I of the Dist ri ct of Columbia Admin i strative Procedure Act. approv ed October 2 1 1968 (82 stat. 1203: D. C Coce ec. 1- 1 501 e t seq Sec 4. Secti on 128(f) ef the District of Columbia Sa l e s 'raJ&amp;lt; Act, approv ed May 27. 1949 (63 Sta t. 115; D.C. Code. s ec. 4 7 2005(5 is ame nd e d t o reed as f oUm,'ll: n(f) Sa les of p r operty purcha sed. by" telecommunication com~ny as defin e d in section (6)(S IB)(v I of An Ac t mak ing appro~ria t ionB t o provide fo r the e xpenses of the government of the Distri c t of Columb i a for t h e fis c l year end ing June thirtle th, nine t ee n hundreo ana t h ree, and f o r o t her p u rposes app r o ved July 1. 1902 (32 Stao 619; D. C Code, Utc lt 7- 2 50 1 utili ty o r public-aervice company for use o r con mptio n ill furniS hing II ervice or commod ity if the r ece ipt! from fur nish ing the servi ce or commodity are sub j ect to II. gro.s rec eipts tax or I[ile ag e t x in t o rce in the District for t h e per iod o f t ime covered by a ny retu r n r equi r ed t o be fil e d by the provi s i on s of t h i s tit le I f the property pu rcha sed is us ed bot h t o produce receipt 8 subjec t to a gros s r eceipts tax or mileage t ax in the District end rece i pts not subject t o a gross rece i p ts o r mileage tax in the Distric t, t h en th is s"les tax exe mpti on shall be a lloca ted i n accor dllnce ~ith r ul es i ssu ed by th l Mayor Sec 5 Sec tion 216(11 of the Dist r ict o f Columbia U"e Tax Aco app r o ved May 27, 1949 63 Stat. 127 D.C. Code, sec 4 7 220 6 1 i s 8mended t o re"d as fo l 10""5 Il) SaliS upon hich t8xee are p rope rl y collected unde r the District of Columbia Sales Tftx Act. IIpprove~ May 27. 1 9 4 9 (6 3 Stat. lIS; D. C. Cede, sec 47-2 001 et seq. h Sec 6 Applic"bility D. C. Code sec 47- 2005 (1988 .upp D. C. Code, SeC. 47- 2206 (1 988 sUl'P a) Sec ti o ns 2, 3{a 3(d and 5 shall apply a9 of the effective da te o f this act b) Section 4 shal l apply to t ll xllble period s beginn i ng after September 30, 1 987 c) Section 3 (b) and 3( e hall apply for the per Ianal property tax year as def ined under s ection 2( 5) of t h e Per sonal Prope rty Tax Mend ent Act of 1986, e f fec tive 28. 1987 (D.C. Law 6 212: D.C. COde sec lt 7 1521 or portion of a personal proper ty t a x yea r, after Septembe r 3 0 1987 Sec 7 This aCt IIhall take effect after a lD -d ay p er iod o f Congress i onal r eview f o llo wing approval by t he Mayor (or in the e v e nt o f veto by the Mayor a ction by the Co uncil. of the Di strict of Columbia t o override the veto) as provided in s ect ion 602(c I) of the Dis trict of Columb~a Sel f Gove rnment and Governmental ReOr9a ni zation Ac t, Clpp r oved Decembe r 24 1973 (87 St",t 813; D.C Code s ec 1-233(c 1 1 Cha rm"'n, by the Chairman Pro Tempore Counc il of t he Di ltric t of COl umbi a { j 1 ~or Distric of Col umbia AP July 17 1987 6 Note D. C. Cod s ec 47-2501, 47- 1508, 47_2206 (1988 supp Note. D.L Code lee. 4,-2Q{l l9B8 pp N~te O.C. Code s~c. 47- 1505 (1988 .upp COUSCIL Of THE DISTRICT Of COLUMB IA Cou il P.riod S.ve n n o. Co_ C RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE OOCII.ET 1110 Fir6 t Reading, 6 -3 0-87 B7 1 B6 1/1: ACTION 5 D~T£ IK VOiCE VOTE By RoocOl on l'OQutS I 1!-dopt ed Ma jority, Member Sc_h_w r~ z voted no lcl prese~t i 1.1 i tl &amp;amp c c Iu In eou II on eon ClI X ACTtOI&amp;lt amp; DUE Adopt ed. Pi nel Reading 7-14 -BC II VOICE VOTE ID' Majoray er Schwartz voteq no Ro 0 on IOQ AbSeni Ka ne Smith and Cl a r&amp;lt;k r OLL CAll VOTE AESUlT C lIem on Coo Clle ACTION' 0.0 TE to VOI CE VOlE R d to on ,tOo 0._0 o ROLt CALL VOTE ry I eo </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
