<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-30">
  <num type="law">7-30</num>
  <heading type="short">Tenant Assistance Program and Rental Housing Commission Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1987-10-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-30.pdf">D.C. Law 7-30</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 5304</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-30, the “Tenant Assistance Program and Rental Housing Commission Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-226, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 30, 1987, and July 14, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 21, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-58 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU~BIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 7-30 'Tenant Ass\5tance Program and Rent~l HousIng Co~mission Amend~ent Act of 1987 Pursuant to Se ction 412 of the District of Columbia Self_ Government dnd Govern lll ental Reor9~njution Act, P. L. 93_198 the Act the Council of the District of Colu lll bl~ ddopted Bill No. 1_226 on firH and second rudlngs, June 30, 1987, and July 14.1987. respectively. Following the signdhre of the Mlyor c on July 21, 1981. this leglshtlon was asslg-ned Act 7-58. publish_ ad 'n the, August 14.1987. edition of the £ egtster Vol. 34 plge 5304) and transmitted to Congress on JulYc 22. 19B7 for I 3D_day re~Iew. In accord~nce with SectIon 602 ll of the Act. The CouncIl of the District of Colu~bll hereby gives notice thlt the 30.d1Y Congreulonal Review Period haC"nplred. Ind therefore. cites this enactllcnt as D.C. Law 1_30. effecthe October 2, 19B7. LARKE of the Council Oates Counted Ourlni the 30-d~y Con~re§§lonal Review Period: July August 22,23.24,27,28.29,30,31 3,4.5,6.7 september 9.10.11,14.15,1&amp;amp;.11,18,21,22,23.24 .25.2B .29 .30 October 1 Enrolled Ort~1n~1 D.C. LAW 7 SO OCT 02 19B7 AN AC1' DC. ACT 7 58 IN THE COUNCIL Qj THE DISTRIC'I' Of' CO iJMIHA JUl 2 1 1987 To a mend the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to .aise the grade eL of members or the Rental ousing Commission, a uthor ize t enant a ssis tance for eligible families Io'ith emerg ency necds and for eligible families l"~sing their prese nt housing accocnmod"tions, authori~e multi-ye~r contract itll housing p~o"i&amp;lt;Jer fer r"ntal unit de.ignate&amp;lt;J for eli,)ible famili e pr""ide that appropri"tions for. the Tenant Assist"nce PI"&amp;lt;XJ 'rilm shall cen" t itu te B proprieta r y fund lind r emain available unt.il expended i thout r lard to fiscal ye~r l imit" tions cl"riCy pro"i s ions re'lanl ing housin'l code compliance, esta bl ish p.oe edu re s for adjusting fair m~rke t rent 1 1 a nd provide pen"lti"5 for discrimination ~gtlinst Tenant Assistance P'Dg.am recipient and to maXe a confo. ming ameml ment to th~ I)i,;trict of Columbia Fund Accounting Act of ISEIO. BE IT I;NACTl: I; Ii Ti lt JUNC'jL vr tilE DISTRICT Q' COLUMBIA, Tllat Chis act m~y be cited the "Te nan t Assi5tahce Program and Rentid lI ou i Corn,"is"ion An,pnd t Act of 191'17 Sec 2 Ti.tle &amp;lt;I of the Rental I!ousing Act of 1985, eHeel;v" July \7 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Code. s c. 45-2511 et seq i amended as fo 1 lolo's, C ection 201(c Il.C. Co&amp;lt;JC ec. 45-2511(c is "mended hy striking the phrase "grade 14 and inse.tin'l in it p1a the phr e "grade 15 b ctio)j 202(d lJ.e lt c C. 45-2512(d i9 am"n l to redd uS follows d) The Jlep~rt nt of COlle"me, and R"gul~tory Affairs ~hall employ HI" Hart nec ry lo ssi~t th&amp;lt;&amp;gt; Rental Ho usin com",i~~iDIl i" carryi l \It i t s (llnction Of tile ~taff employed, 3 Gh l be 1&amp;lt;1 L Ow whQ sh~ l 1 i t eh mOOr of t thmt.,l tta"Hin9 &amp;lt;:o i i "LL iLL U I'r.,p~r,\tion of d&amp;lt;!cisionfl lt;1 Dnl"ro D.C. Code, sec 45~2~il (19B8 upp l.C. C"d 45-2S1 1988 rr sec. 3. 1' i tl II I "f t ile en tn l ilou s ing Act of 1985 effective July 1i, 1~85 (D.C La 6 -10; I).C. Code ec. 4 5 Jl J b ~tneJl(ic io llol a Sec tlon 3UI(} D.C. Code, s c 4S-253i(3 nd cd by i '1Sertl n(,l the w"rd ub 5 tan iai" lJ ore t lw o ed coon p l] we b Secti on 301(l D.C. Code, sec 45 2531(12 i dm"nded to read a 5 fo11o 12 TeHant a istance contract weans a r i teen contra ct between the Department nd a housing prov~der, in tne form pre~c rib"d by th" Hayor, i n which the Department ag.ees to rna ] ten~nt sist"'nce payments to the hous ing p.ovid II) on beh~lf of &amp;lt;I specific ligible family; or (B) for specific units to be held for and leased to famili~s eligibl e for tena n t as~istanc fo~ tile du~"d.on of the cont ct c) S&amp;lt;&amp;gt;"t10n 302(b D.C. COde c. 4 5-2532) i mended by &amp;lt;ldding n e s e ntence s at the enu to d follow l'Ipp"opri"t ion~ for tile Te nt Assistanc e Program lla11 b classified and m"int" ined s propriet",ry fund and sh&amp;lt;l11 remain aVl1il&amp;lt;1ble unt:il expend d i t.hout rega rd to fi~c"l year limit&amp;lt;ltions. No money appropri &amp;lt;l ted for the Tenant Assista nce Progr&amp;lt;lm sh"ll be penderl for any purpos other th making tenant a ist&amp;lt;lnce payrnent~ a"d hen necessary, repayable a dvances f or security depOsits in a ccordance with t_his title d) Section 302(c P.C. Code, sec. 45-2532(c is amended by &amp;lt;lddil1g the ord lt;lvail"ble" before the ord "appropriatio her~ver it appear e) Section 3Q2(d D.C. Code, Sec. 45-2532(d is amen""d to read "s tOIIO d) The flayo r i uthnr i z"d to e xpe nd th mil a pp,opr1ations provided by this section in the [allowing man""r l)(A) Til e M" yor In"y e"ter into long-tel t&amp;lt;:n"nt assistance controcts ith hOUSing provld r P"yments oblig t"d by 10 term c'mtr~ct nay b mad on 1\ annu"l basis durin~ the period of e~ch ~ont~ac~ from the "nnu~l "ppropr i "tion~ for tl Tenant A ist"nce l'r"'lr t~cl o"L~"ct tC'rc&amp;lt;l Into l&amp;gt;urolldllL tu 1" 1 r 1'1l ahall l i 'J,,t{ h e ho",i I"ovi&amp;lt;l ilnnu,d I rO! th" dura tion of t l' e contra ct La "ffe, for Ie a nd to lo~se fi"ed number of r""tal urdt hIC shal t l)e ~p"clfied i n the contract, t o families receivinq tenant "s" istance. regardle s of he r th me t ily 1~a"es til ame unit U'roll~hoilt the cOntra ct period eh cont ct sh&amp;lt;lll otJlig t e the ~l"yor to ma ke to n n ssi t"nce p"yments t o the housin provide. for the duration of the contract in a. CCO'clnnc e with the term" of t h" cotltr"ct d th Il.r. \ 1 4\-2 » 1 1?3H fp P.c c p 1] 1988 upp D.C. C"d acc. 45-H32 (1988 5UPP D. C. Code. 9~C. 4S-2532 (1988 upp D.C. Code. see. 4~-2 5 32 (t9SS ~ur lt uro U &amp;amp;d 0,.1g10_1 r"qu ~r ~lI\"l\ t of lni~ ti U lt;0 l gt;n&amp;lt;J a t h e h Ol.l8in9 i~ ill lIub" t l&amp;gt il&amp;gt;[ gt r&amp;gt;lia"c i th the nousin&amp;lt r"'lull&amp;gt; t iool. The contr "ctll"i. obligatIO" of the yor h l l be b&amp;lt;lc~ed b tho fu l l i;)lth nu CTGiht of ~hc IH3tr i c t t o the me e ~t en t th/lt plies t o Uutrict co"tractlO g .mera ll II) I n th e of cont.n,ets fot t tal unit" i" exi'ting housi I&amp;gt C&amp;lt;lmlOdat i or the 1 1th of th COF. t r a w,y be fcOIn I to 5 y cs In the c a "e of CQutr"ct" Cor rcatlll unit s i.n ne"'Ly con .tructeu Or reh bUitated h o u ll in lt;Icc 1:oodfttlans the l e n&amp;lt;;1tl, of the co"tr""t ay he rrom I to 1 5 years i th optio to r new in 5 -year C) COHlli sten t with tn requirements Of ec tion 804(dl. d latrp.soed proper tlos &amp;amp;nd new O( re h b ili t&amp;lt;&amp;gt; ted vacan t tll l hOua i ng r c i vi n g a .i.ul pu r nt to tl t l Ill .hall hay" p rto rity 0'1 o ther propert i~s f o r the 10n9 -t~rm cont r~c t. autho riz d by this p rag raph W(2) Th Ma yor may expenu fundll fr om th annual appropri tion t o aS l ist eligible t"mil'e ith emerg.,ncy h o using ne eds dua t o fami ly s epar" ti o n by COurt o r dllr bee"use af inadequate housing. sudden unavoidable disp l acemen t fr om a d lling unit, spe ci" l hea lth or di.llbility p r obl e re'luirin imrn di te improv"ment i n ho i ng, or other eme r gency r.,a80n. appr o ved by the 091 r t lTlC!'n t JJ The Hayor may pend fund. fr om th. nnnun1 pproprilltion t o as.ist eligib l e f ili with c urrcmt valid lea of a r ta l unit that qua li! iell according t o t he prov i s icn of this aCt the o..p"rtln. nt IIhall announce th" 8v"i lability of thr lI, ei&amp;amp; tan ce authorized by thi p" rllgr~ph t hrough notice t o th e Di" trict o f Columbia Office on J in Qt h.,r lcY"n I l is ~r ;c t lt;Jenci lflnr1 p\'iY" t e or'1anl lt;lfltions r eprcec11tin e nior eit iz'lnG or tonlflnt, in genera l 4 tr.c HI'yor s hall not h I' ru le o r otheno'l"c al l oca te any fixea portion of th annua l IIpprop r iation Cot .lolly "I eif.c L"'go ry of c l i g.ble t i l i O r n sp ci f. c type of t n ant nS.istlfl nC eontrilc t author i d by t his l.tlc r t1 JUJ J C. \.:ode cc 4'&amp;gt;-25JJ ln In M,ncl &amp;lt I uy ~dcll L.,n 0 U e to .e ftJ a" t n t 100"'R The ])iSLtlrt at Cal l1m~i r'roc Llr n nt Prac t i ces /lC t o f 1985 effec:tiv(l Feotunry 21, 1996 (D C. La 6-85; D. C Code c. l_llfl 1 0 a.J h" ll t ill'rly t o t c ntrllct al.l thariz~ hy i-hl t i le g t 1&amp;lt t bj(lJ C I&amp;lt;l, e C ooI5-2 5J)(b 0&amp;lt;1,&amp;lt;1&amp;lt lt;1 t o e lt;1 ;a~ f ol i o b) I,;x c p \" othe r r r ovid lt;1 in tin lIubloct i o n. the r r 'n t r&amp;lt;lu tl "l'pl i c a ble to ~h" 7""ant A.,lata"C 11.\ lt 1 2SJ1 (L oUI&amp;gt;r ·l D.C. C I nJ \'11111 "uPI lt;Jr eh ll I th" f r gt;I e~ r""t tal&amp;gt;li~he T y by t 1i.1" 1 I"r t t of ;i J"J roll lIr'n cvclopn t lilll fnT n w &amp;lt;:otLstrucno:t an U)~e/lont i i r"h bil ~t"tlOll 1 AS IL""Jt lt L C ark,;1 rh o i.:er;\ tm€nt OJ r"l I' I il U e di r o nIL I it5 ~T\ ~i z 10 I\il'h ~I r lr. IOU i ll Lb l""iI \ hl 1C'&amp;lt;i i ,y nU I lt; II th lJ"p.,rtl nl ft" r Vi HJ 'nO' f~i.r rk" t r""t v t""li Ly fjU f r U J~I&amp;lt r d d,'tnr,.in th"t tl dmou"t lt;I lt t ly n,f l { m lt r ,Hlt. in til" Di str kt t ho l)&amp;lt I nm.,n y b}' r "I&amp;lt lt;JjUSt ll10 "lIU)un t f f ~h propolI lt;t r"tr r l r l ry fruor. th ta rkf't r"n t l'lillth by Ill;D h" 0 1'11 r t menl Sh" II 5ublu t resol Ut i on fo r "pprov l o f u p ope""d fai r :r.a rket r"ntH ~o t he Counc il of the' D l "tr t o f enl I Coun&amp;lt i l f o r d "y (l8r;O(I of [ e vi e x c l u"i"g Satu r d ays und"ys, 1"911 ho l iCl ys nd d"y" of Counci l reco If th" co,mci l does no t a ppr o or &amp;lt;:Ii8/1ol'P'-OVO the proposed r e o l ution In 1 0 1 or in pB rt ithiu this 45 _d"y r(!vi period the propos e d resolu t i on ell" ll be ,1 meJ approve(] h) Section 303(c D.C. Cod c 5-2S33(c is nde'l by II meml ing the 3nl aent n to r d as £0110 J I'r rity "h~ l l 00 'liv e to th c&amp;gt; ld"rly, tile 11 n,H c PI 1 i n'] 1 pa rent h Oll a lt;&amp;gt;\ u n&amp;lt;l "PI' Ii nt h&amp;lt I c pl ot ny CII1 p l oyroent t l'lIill l n&amp;lt OOu r s provid~ by M'y Ills l ric t ]""cy li) S"c tw" 303('1)(1 O C Cod O 4 5 2533(9 0 i lt;.1 lt;1 1) In the l~t ntence, by !lt rH: ing t h" nwnerai uM an&amp;lt;.l l"Certl ng i n its I' lac th n r 1 -90 nd 21 In t he Jr&amp;lt;l "en t@n'O&amp;lt by Stri k ing th I'hrRse M t ns,nnr; nnt to C.,oo Lotti I &amp;lt;&amp;gt; f oU day el i r tl n'J ill i pi th phr Mo U_ti y t""61oh~ to ,joy 11' tllilt &amp;lt;:nnll"\lO ly ,1 "moll t r t \100'1 { tth ffort$ t o loc&amp;gt;lt ti blc r'·Ht 1 "n lt. M s ti 31;4(0 In J S 3 4(f r" I I lt;I kl JU5 (l'J (ll C I gt;Sj51 I)i 1 1 r~.ld f 1 I L Il H icr ~n f~'I [~l Ilo i ny I'r lt;J r lt;lr 1'"1&amp;gt; 1 h n~ th r lcJ l&amp;gt;y til tli ~t.r.c v':r 5 4. Sc&amp;lt;:t i on &amp;lt;;05 of tnt· Ro l 110 9 i\'Ot O f 1')9 5 v Y l7, I Jfl5 D 11 D C lt;'e C 1 lt gt I r [o \ l&amp;lt;» II \ 1 1 f&amp;lt;&amp;gt;c c l.t r te h t lt r jll r I,'],bl&amp;gt r&amp;lt 1 i5t,"n C P r tM' C l rl) D.C Co,\c. 5~C 4j-ZS33 (J9RR UPI D,C, CO 5 2511 l 'IlIB .up Rep I 1\, r 10 H, 4 2~~4 (l urp.l 11 I c i rr,l 1 oJ ec H' { IIII t..nant o~ familia. wit.h chi l d r an wh.n rent.ing houe ing accomlllOdatione b) Subeec tion (c) I ended t.o r e"d u fo llows c) Allega t ions o f violat. ione of t h i a 'ect l on that ar de by fo",lliel tece i v i ng o r el i qi ble t o receive Tenant i"tance PrOiram a iatance by elderly tenant o r b y tamiliel with chlldran ahlll be pro~ptly lnyeat191tld I nd h a ndled by tha Depa rtmant ot Con .umar and Re'1ulatory Aft lre, whiCh Ihal1 proYide tha complain!n'1 p&amp;gt;lrty with a wrlttan raport upon t.he conclu.lon or t.he lnva.tlg,tlon Sec. 5. Saction 901(e) of the Rental Housing ACt at 1985 effective July 17, 198 5 (D.C. Law 6-10 D.C. Code ec. 4 5-2591 (e» h _ended i n t he ht aentence by Iddinq after t he worda "di.crl.1nat ag.lna1 t h e verda "a f il y r ece iv ing o r eligibla 1.0 r eceive Te na nt. Aaaiet.anoe Pr Og r aal i t.ance a nd b y i aert.i ng a c after t he verde "elderly ten.nt Sec. 6 SectiOn 4 (a 2) of the oi.trict of COlumbia Pund Accounting Act o t 1980. effective June 14. 19S0 (D. C. t.aw 3-70) D.C. Code c. 47-373(1 8» i, amended by a Strill ing the ~riod a t tha and of aubpare'1reph (E) anG Ineertin'1 tha phraaa a nd· 1n i plaCe) and b Addtng a new aubparailraph (0 D.C. Cod aae. 47-J 7J(l)(II yH t o read aa fo llOW G) Tenant Aaa iatanee Progr Sec 7 This a c t shall t.aka eff.ct lifter a 30 -day period of Con'1raa.iona l review followln'1 approval by tha Mayor (or 1n the eVlnt of vato by the Mayor, actiol1 by ~he Council of thl Diltriet of Columbia to override tha veto) aa provided in aae tto n 60l (c I) o f the Dl.trict of Col u~bla Sal f- Goyernment Ind GoYernmantal Raorgani ~ation Ait D.C. Code UC 4 2591 (191111 ~upp D.C. Codl c. 47-373 (l911B upp approved December ~4, 1973 (87 Stat. 81 D. C. Code ec. 1-233(c)(l Mayor District Chai~man, by the Chairman Pro Tempore Council of the Distr i ct of Columbia APPROVED: Ju1y 21, 1987 011 'sr I OF n i l 111 1("1' Of Cm .llMHZ A 1 1 K.d s RtCORD OF OHICIAl COUNC IL VOTE DOCM( l u A_dapt ed rirs~ Rea,Un 6-3 0 117 X ~O&amp;gt;CF. vo Dy gt;I~jori l Member Crawford voted p r esent r 01 c i L 0 Co 0" Con n, c I CTlON 5 o.n x oCt von Adopted Fi n!11 r,e a dil]'1 7_-14-S.I~ By Major ity Member Cr a ford voted p sent IIOLl CAll VOTE CT,ON OUE OtC~ vOH lt;I en 0 Kane and Clark e o;,i Oat i </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
