<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-32">
  <num type="law">7-32</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1987-10-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-32.pdf">D.C. Law 7-32</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 5312</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-32 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-146, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 16, 1987, and June 30, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 23, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-60 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NCIL OF 7HE DI STR I CT OF COLJ HalA Nor Ie O. C. l AW 7· 32 'Nurses Tr~i~ing Corps Es tabl ishme~t A't Of 1987 Pursuant to Senion (12 of tile Oi stri t o f Coi u.bia Self Go vern.ent and Gove rn lllentd \ Re o r 9anlld t ion Act, P. l 3 198 t he t the Counc il of the District of Colullbl. ad op ted Bil l ~o. 7·14 6 on f i r H ~nd second r eadings June 16 198 7. and J une 30 1987 r eSPletiYely Follo win g the s j~n u u r e of the Hay or on July 23 [987. th is l eg l slHlon as oUsigned Ac t 60 pu b lished In tile August 14. 1987 editio n of the D.C. Register Yol. 34 pag e 5312 and tr a ns itted t o Congress on Jul y 29. 198 7 for a 30 o.1Y revi ew. In Hc orda nce I th SlICtion 601{c I of the Act. Tne COl/nell of the Dist r ic t of Colullbi! hereby g i ves no t ic@ that th e 30 day Congres s i o na l Ru lew Per iod has uplred. a nd the refore. ci t es t his end c t llen t as D. C. La w 7· 32 effecti ve October 9. 1967. Dates oullted Dur I ng t ile 30 lIa1 Co ngressi on d l Revie w Per iOd; J ul y August 29 30 Jl 3. 4. 5.6.7 Sept ember 9 10 11. 14,15 .16.1 1 .1IL21.ZZ .23 24 .25 .2 8 .29 .30 Oc t ob er 1,2.5 6 7 .8 olled Ort g l O.C.L\W7-32 OCT 0 9 19a7 D.UCT 7-60 IN THE COUNC I~ OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMB A co:!ificatioo e Olapt.er 26 of Ti tle 11 JUL 2 I 1987 To increaae t.he avallab1lit.y of trained nurses at. D. C Ger.eral Hos pi tal t.hrough the es t. a blishment of a. nur ses t.r l n i ng corps. 6£ t 'r ENACTED BY Ttl COUNCIL OF THE DI STRICT Of' COLUMBIA. That t.his eet. m4y b e c i t.ed as t.he ~Nu r9"s Train i ng Corps Est bliaroment Act. o f 1987 Sec. 2 There .hall be eetabl ished HI the Distr ict o f Columbi a District M a Nurses Training Corp Co r ps hich shall provid e f inancial aid to Di st r lc t r a.id e nts desir ing ~o obta~n a Licensed Pr aCt i cal Nurse LPN c e rtificat.e or &amp;lt;In As soc i ate o f Arts deg ree o r a B&amp;lt;lchelo r o f Sci e nce degree in nur.ing b) The f i ndncial did provided by the Corps shdll inClude tuition a.nd may incl ude the fo llo ing ll The realonabl e co.t of text boOK! and 2) The r easonabl e tnon'po rt" tjon costs to "nd tran class s 3 he reaso nable cost of chi l d c"'re whil e dt t ending cla",se s; dn 4) A stipen~ to help defray t h e cost o f red on.,bl. living expenses for f u ll t i me enroll ed student c) In eJ:change for financial aid the studen t shall contrac t to work f o r D. C. Ge ner al Hospit al o r the De par tment o f lJuman Se r vices to r spec i fied n Ull'lber of years after completion of the ag r eed nu rs inq education d J The 1)a $ic c ri t.e ria fo r aelect ion t o the Corps Bha ll inClude the f ollo ing 1) Bona fide residency in the Di"trict fo r 2 years immedidtely prior to applica tion to the Corps 2) Stated inter e st in nuning and pub lic service in the held of nursing with i n the District: OJ Pinanclal need: and New. D.C. Cl sec 1:-260 1988 5Up 4) Admission to an accredited program of nursing study within the District. Sec. 3. The Department of Human Services shall be responsible for the administration of the Corps. Sec. 4. Within 120 days of the effective date of this act, the Mayor shall, pursuant to title I of the District of Columbia Admini strative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204 D.C Code, sec. 1-1501 et seg issue proposed rules to implement the provisions of this a ct. Th e proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 4S-day period of review, exclelding Saturdays, Selnd ays, legal holidays, and dd.ys of Council recess. If the Council does noe approve or disapprove ehe proposed relIes, in whole or ~n p",rt, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved. The proposed rul e s shall include provisions regarding the terms of the employment contracts, including the period of ~ervice required. Sec. 5. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of a veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1» {;:fL Clid.irman e,uncil of the District of Columbia APPROVED: JULY 23, 1987 O. C. Co: soc. 31-2602 (1988 supt New, D.C. eo sec 31-26G3 (1988 s 1 COU CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLCMBIA Council Period Seven RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE .67 14 6 DOCKET NO c&amp;gt 19 Item on Con nt CoI na ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted First Reading, 6-l6-§l Xj VOICE VOTE O~animous R. cOrd oto an roquo" Crawford and Wilson 7-1 7 Oat gt;Q ACTION&amp;amp;OAH A""d,oppted Final Reading, b- 30-§7 )jj VOICE VOTE: Unanimous Re cOrdod v01&amp;amp; on r~~u".t all present ROll CAW. VOTE RESU LT 7-6 07 Dal CTION &amp;amp; DATE C VO'C VOTE Aocaro&amp;amp;d v01e oQuo. t M n\: ROLL CAll VDT RESULT S f 10 Coooc,1</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-1501"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-1502"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-1503"/>
  </section>
</document>
