<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-51">
  <num type="law">7-51</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1987-12-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-51.pdf">D.C. Law 7-51</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 6889</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>CO UMCIL OF THE DIS TRlcr OF CDLU MB IA NOTIC E 0, C. Lil li 7- 51 路Olstri ct o f Co l u.bla Schoo l of La nter Board of G01ernors end~ent Act of 1987 PurSlu"t to Section 412 of the District of Colura bla Se lf the Act the Cou ncil of the District of Co l umbia a.d opted 6111 No 7_2 36 on first ,nd s eco nd readings, J une 30, 19B7. and Septe.tar 29. U8l. rup'ethely. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 16 1987. thl$ legls l'tlon was ,sslgned ct 7_84. published I n the October 30 1981. edition of the lIe9ister ol 4 pagl 6889 ud transmitted to Congress on October 21. 1987 for l 30_dlY reylew, In ac cord ln ce with Sectio n 602 (e 1) o f the ct. The Council of tht Distri c t of ColumbIa hereby giYas noti ce that the 3~-day Congresslon Review Period has nplree lt;lnd therefo re. cites thfs tnact.ent as D.C. Law 7-51. eftlctfYe Deet.btr la, 1987. CLARKE of tht COline! 1 Oates Count ed During thl 3D-d,y COngression al Rey!e. Perloe October 21 .2 2.23.26.27.28.29. 30 1I0~e.blr 2 .3,4,5,6,9.10.12,13.16,17 ,18, I 9,20 ,3 0 O.C.lJ\W 7 5 I amp;y&amp;amp; DEC 1 0 1981 AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 84 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCT 1 6 1987 To amend the District of Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act to expand the membership of, and to provide for the selection of, a chairperson of the interim Board of Governors of the District of Columbia School of Law and to make certain clarifying amendments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the 路Oistrict of Columbia Schaol of Law Interim Board of Governors Amendment Act of 1987 Sec. 2. Section S03(r) of the District of Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act, effective February 24, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-177; D.C. Code, sec. 31-1543{r is amended as follows a) By striking the phrase *4 members* and inserting in its place the phrase *5 members {b) By striking the phrase *1 of whOlll shall be the Mayor, 1 of whom shall be the COrporation Counsel for the District of Columbia c) By striking the phrase -LaW, and* and inserting in its place the phrase *Law 4S of the effective date of this title d) By adding the phrase *as of the effective date of this title after the word 路Bar e) By striking the phrase 路or the immediate past President's designee and inserting in its place the phrase *1 of whom shall be the General Counsel of the Leadership Conference on Civil Rights as of the effective date of this title, 1 of whom shall be the Executive Director of the Far East Community Services, Inc as of the effective date of this title, and 1 of whom shall be the Executive Director of the District of Columbia Association for Retarded Citizens, Inc as of the effective date of this title. The interim 1 D.C. Code Ie 31-154 3 (1988 supp Board ot Governors shall select a chairperson froo among its members I and (9) By addinq a new paragraph (2) to read as foll ows 2 The interim Board of Governors and any successor governing body shall not use funds appropriated by the District of Co lumbia f or the School of Law to sub.idira the tuition of persons who are not res idents of the Di s tric t o f Colull:lbia Sec 3 This act shall t ake effect atter oil 30- day period o f Cong res sional review fol lowing approval by t he Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the CounCil o f the District of Columbia to override the veto as pr ovided in .action 602l c ltl) of the Dis trict of Coluebia Self Government and Governmental aeorganizat ion Act, approved December 24, 1913 IS1 Stat. S131 D. C. COde, see. 1-233 IeI 11l 14ycr District APPROVED: Council of the District of Columbia o columbh October 15, 1981 COCNCIL OF' THE DISTRICT OF' COLLMBIA COllncil P~riod Sev~n RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOC KET NO C 2CJ Ite on Con n, C~I.no lI ~CTION DATE Auduoop dC'FC R do"o n&amp;gt;gc 6 J"O 8c7 lI VOICE VOTE J8'Y j;"0"'O Y o"b"w V"o"'t d~nUOL AMoint all present C ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT J ACTIOI 3. OATE AlI,&amp;lt;ld,O"p d F,i"n",lL&amp;gt;R d,,C' n""9 0 C7 fiG VOICE VOTE: By Majority. Members Schwartz and Kane voted no ADUnI: all present /L d-\.J o Item on eon 1 c.I,naar ACTIOI 3. nATE OICE VOTE A.cord yole on 1 1 </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
