<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-52">
  <num type="law">7-52</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1987-12-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-52.pdf">D.C. Law 7-52</citation>
      <citation type="register">34 DCR 6891</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-52 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-173, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 14, 1987 and September 29, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 16, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-85 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUKCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOT ICE D. C. LAW 7-52 'P ublic Defender Service Amend ment Act of 1987 Purs ud nt to Section 412 of the District of Columbi~ Self- Government ~nd GoYer nmenta1 Reorga nization Act P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the Di,trict of Columbia adopted Bill No. 7 173 on flrst and second readings, July 14, 1987, and September 29.1987. respective ly. Fol lowing the signature of the Mayor on Octob~r 16, 1987, this legislation was assigned Act 7-85. published in the October 30. 1987 d1tion of the.9 h Register ol. 34 page 6891) and transmitted to Congress on Oc tob€r 21. 1987 for a 3 day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Colu~bia hereby gives notice that the 3D-day Congressiona l Revie w Period has expired. and t her~ fore. cites this enactment as D. C. Law 7-52. effective Oece mber 10 1987. ut( CLARKE hair rnan of the Council Dates Co unted During the 30-day Congression~l Review Period: October 21.22,23.26.27.28.29.30 November 2.3.4.5.6.9.10.12.13,16.17,18.19.20.30 December 1,2.3.4.7.8.9 iurGilBQ Original D.C. LAW 7-52 DEC 101987 AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 85 IN THE COUr.CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF CCLUrmIA OCT 1 6 19r1 1'0 a!:lend Title III of the District of Columbia Court Reform and Criminal Procedure Act of 1970 to authorize attorneys of the Public Defender Service to represent inmates in District of COlunbia corrections facilities in administrative matters related to their incarceration BE I'i: Et&amp;lt;ACTED BY HE COUNCIL OF HE DISTRICT OF COLm!BIA, That this act lay be cited as the "Public Defender Service Afficndnent Act of 19B7 Sec. 2. Title III of the District of Columbia Court Reform and Criminal Procedure Act of 1970 approved July 29, 1970 (84 Stat 654, D. C. Code, sec 1-2701 et seq is amended as follows a S()ction 302(a D.C. Code, sec. 1-2702(a 1 is amended by adding a new subparagraph (8) to read a s follows 8) Persons incarcerated in District of Columbia corrections facilities, not including community residential facilities or community-based corrections facilities, in administrative matters related to their incarceration before any court or administrative body b) Section 302(a D C. Code, sec 1-2702(a)(2 is amended by inserting immediately before the sentence beginning with the word "Representation" the following The Service shall not represent an inmate in a suit for damages against the District of Colu~bia or its employees for conduct within the scope of their employment, nOr shall it represent an inmate in a suit in Which the payment of attorney's fees or costs is sought against the Distric t of Columbia or its employees for conduct within the scope of their employment e) Section 305(a D C. Code, sec 1-2705(a is amended by striking the word "defense" in the first sentence. 1 D.C. Code, sec. 1- 2702 (1988 sUPP D.C. Code. sec l-2702 (1988 supp D.C. Code, se&amp;lt; 1~2705 (1988 supP EDrGll~d Original Sec. 3 This act shall take effect after" 30-day period of Congressional revi£l following approval by the Ila yor (or in the event of veto by the Ciayor action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) a s provided in sec tion 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia S"lf-Govcrnment and Governmental Reorganization ~ct, al'proved December 24, 1973 (87 St at. 813; D. C Code, sec 1-233(c)(1 Council of the Distr ic t of Columbia APPROVED Oct"b" 16, 1987 COUNCIL OF THE DI STRICT 0 COLUM BI A C(lllDcil Pcri&amp;lt;/d Sf'Ven K ~CTIOH &amp;amp; oue' lI: VOlC~ von c Jlecor""O 0 eQu X 11em o~ CotI ColeP&amp;lt;lar RECORD OF OFFICI AL COUN Ci l VOTE OOC~ET NO: AdQpJ;ed FJ..Uit Reildi~~4-87 unanimous Kane and Cla rke X ACTIO cue x VOI C~ VOT E A ocQ O(1 vo on amp;Que" Adopt.e d Fi nal Reading 9- 29- 87 Un"nimo1,!s Kane I'om on Coo n! CoI.od or l CliO amp; DUE. vOice vore R&amp;lt;"co 0 O OQue J ROLL C.o.lL ~OTE RESULT e7-l7L \ 7 </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
