<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-88">
  <num type="law">7-88</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Public Hall Regulation Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-03-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-88.pdf">D.C. Law 7-88</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 164</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-88, the “District of Columbia Public Hall Regulation Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-220, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 24, 1987 and December 8, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 22, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-126 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU NCIL :IF TH[ DISTRICT OF COlUMSIA NOT LC[ Dist ri c t of Col~m bla Public H~ ll Re ul U o n A en(jlten l Ac t o f 1987 Pu n uoln t to Sectio n 4 12 o f t he Di stric t of Columbid Se lf Gove rnm ent dnd c.o ve rnmentdl Re o r d nj l~tion Ac t L. 93-198 t he Act th e Co un c il o f th e DIst.rid o f Colum bi a ~dop ted Bi ll Nc 7-22 0 on f i r;l dnd H co na r eddlng s Novembe r 2 4 1987, d nd Decemb e r 8 1987 r e5 pecti ve ly Followi ng th e s i g na t u r e c f t ne Ka ya r on December 22 1981 th is l e9 i s l at icn was ass igned Ac t 7 -126 pub lis hed I n the Jdn ua ry 8 ,1988, edIti o n of the D. C. Regh ter Vol. JS PJgE 164) a nd transmitted to Con~ress on J a nuary 2 2 1988 f o r a 30-day r e vi e w, in ac c u r da nc @ ith Se c t ion 602{c)(l) o f the Ac t. The Council o f the Di str ic t o f Col umbia he r eby 9iy e~ no ti ce th a t t he 30-d ay Congressio na l Re Y le Per io d ha s e x p ired and th e refo r e cites thl5 e nactment s D. C. La w 7- 88 effec tive MHCh II 19 88 DAVI D A. CLA Rt E C h~ir ma n o f the Co un c i l Oa tes Coun t ed D ~rin9 t he 30-d4y Co n9r~~sion 41 Re v ie w PeriOd; J anu ary 25 26 27 28 ,29 Fe b r udry 1 2 3 4 8,9 16 17 18 19 2 2 23. 24 25 26 29 )lar c h 1, 2 3 4, 7 8 ,9, 10 D.C. LAW 7 88 Anrolled Or181n&amp;amp;l MAR I I 19S5 liN ACT D.C. ACT 7- 126 Itl i CCU t:CIL Of' THE: OIZ RIC7 OF COLU~;SlA lIEC t 1967 70 r.\cnd An Act r:laking Appropriations to p r ovide for the expe nses o f tht Govern~ent o f t he District o f Co l unbi f o r the fis c al ye ar ending June thirt~ eth. n ine t een ho.:ndccd and three, and f o r o ther purposes, t o r egu l&amp;lt;1tc the 0F~ratlQn o f pub l ic halls. BE IT ENACT D BY TLE COUNCIL OF THe DISTRICT OF COLli/ lelA, That this act ~ay be cited as the Distric t of Colur..b ia Public lIall Regulation Ar.1endmcnt. Ac t o f 1987 Sec 2 Stlction 7 o f An ACt naking appropriatio ns t o D. C. CoJ c. p rOVide for the c&amp;gt;:pen"es o f Ie Covernf.'lent o f the D1S tric t 47-2S20 0 Coluoo ia f or the fiscal year cn.Hog June thirtieth I9RR gt;p ni neteen hund~ed and three, 3nd fo~ o ther purpose s approved July 1. 190 2 (32 Stat. 625; D. C Code sec 4 7-282 0 is amended by adding new subsec t ions (e) and (d) to r ead as follows e)(l) Excopt as provid ed 1n pa ~agr3ph o f this s ubsection after 11:30 p m. on Sundays through Thursdays except days ~recedinQ holidays and after 1 a m. on Sa t u rdays undays, and legal holldays until 8 a m. of each day, owners o r ~nagers of facilltles licensed und er the pr e visions of this section sha ll no t ~ermit any ~i nor t o be p r usent on the licensed pr emises 2 Paragraph (1) of th i s llubsection shall not app ly to owners o r managers A) Of theaters when displ ayinq movinQ I&amp;gt; l. c tures or "I S Of buildinqs 1n which fairs, carnivals, exh i bi tions, lectures and theatrical or dr&amp;lt;Un3tic pe rformances are belnQ conducted a) The Department of Consumer and Re gulato r y Affai r s shall suspend the l icense o f any llcensee determined t o have vio l ated the ~rovisions of s ubsection Ie) o f th15 secti on he period of sus ension sh311 not exceed 1 yea r f o r each violatl.on A licensee alleged to be 1n vio lation shall be 1 ~f' el lt" 0r1g 1=l n tit l ed to a hc~ c ~n9 i n ccu cd~nce wi th sect~on 109 o f t he Distr ic t o f Culumt i a Admin i s t r ative Pr ocedu r e AC t, apF r ove d October 21, 19 68 8 2 St~t 1206 D. C cooe, s cc 1- 1509 1 Sec J This a ct s hall t ake e ff ec t a ft e r a 30- day pe riod o f Cong r e ssional rev iuw fo l l Owing a.,pro v a l by the lIyor (or i n the event o f veto by the ~jI! Yo c, a c t ion to y the Counci l of t he Distric t of Co luBbi a t o o ve rr ide t he v e to) a s p r o v i ded ill suct i on 6 0 2( C 1) o f the Di s tric t o f C01UJ:lb~a e lf- Gov r nmcnt a n d eo" t&amp;lt; r nJ:l.c n t a l Reo r ql:tnizat ion Act i-&amp;gt;pr o vcd December 24 1973 (87 Stat S U D. C Code sec 1-233 c)(1I Chai r roan I L Coun c il o f t h e Di str i ct o f Columbia 0 District 0 c0 1 u~b i a A~PRO tD: De cember 22 1987 2 COLTSCIL OF Tn!&amp;gt; DISTRICT OF COLlJ\1IHA RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKE, NO X ACTI ON &amp;amp; DATE Adopte d Fj rs\ ReaG; ng B7 22 0 &amp;gt;I VOICE VOTE By Yla j ority, Me:ubers Schwartz und Thomas vo..i:.ed n~ R.cord ot all presen ROLL CALL VOTE RES ULT 2 i 6 D~t. Item 0" CO Men&amp;lt; Cal e"d~r X ACTION &amp;amp; OA TE A,d,02IP dc."C PO'"C1 R d qL c.'1 c'~c'8,7L X VOICE VOTE By Ma jority, Members Schwartz and T homa s vo t ed no R ecor"e oje 0 e que" Ab, en l~l pre s e nt R O ~L CALL vOTE RESULT o. C ACTION &amp;amp; D"-TE, vO ICE vOTE R. COrd cl~ on 'eq~.t Ab,"nt ROLL CALL vOTE RESULT IJ Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
