<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-91">
  <num type="law">7-91</num>
  <heading type="short">D.C. Unemployment Compensation Act Amendment Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-91.pdf">D.C. Law 7-91</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 712</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-91, the “D.C. Unemployment Compensation Act Amendment Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-256, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 8, 1987, and January 5, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 25, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-133 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU~CIL OF T~ E DI STR ICT OF C~Lj B!A HOTICt: D. C. LAW 7· 91 'Oistr i ct of Co lu lli bia Un e mpl oyment Co mpensat ion Act A.en d ~en t Ac t o f 19 87 Pursuant t o Section 412 of t he Dist r ic t o f Colu mbh Sel f Gove rnmen t a nd Gove rnmen ta l Re org in l uti on Ac t. P. l. 93 198 the Act the Cou ncil o f the Dist r ic t of Co lullbla adopted Sill No. 7· 256 on fir s t and seco nd rea di ngs Oe celllber B, 1 981 and Janua r y 5 1988 respe ctively Follo win9 the signatu r e of t he a yo r on J a nuary 25 198B this legisla tion was assiSned Act 7· 133 published i n the Feb ruHY 5 198 8 edition of th e Reg iste r Vol. 3S page 11 2 and t ransmitted t o Congre ss on J anu a ry ~8. 1988 f o r 30· d ay r e vie w, I n ~c co rd"nce wi t h Sect i on 60 2{c 1) of the Act Th e Co uncil of the Dis trict o f Columbi a hereby ;ive s notice th a t t he 3D·day Co ngressi on a l Rev ie w Pe r iod has ex pi r ed and th erefore cite s this enHtmen t as D.C Law 7· 91 effe c th e Har ch 16 19 88 Ch~l r l1an the Coun cil D"tes Cou nted Du ring the JO·day Cong ress iou! Review Perjod; Janu ary 28,29 Febr~a r y 1 2,3.4,5 8 .9, 15 17 18 19 22 ,23 24 25 26 .2 9 Ma r ch 1 2 3 .4. 7 8,9,10,1 1, 14.15 AN ACT D.C. ACT 7 13 3 IN THE COUNCIL OF THe DISTRICT OF COLUI~BIA JAN 2 5 19as To amend the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act to establish 3 new employer tax rate t ables to conform to federal requirements and to require the ~layor to submit to the Council of the District of Columbia al ternative measures to increase r eserves in the Distr i ct of Colu~ia Unemployment Fund and an annual report on the solvency of the Fu~d. Be IT eNACTCD BY Til CQUt;CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLmlBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Unemployment Compens a tion Act Amendment Act of 1987 Sec 2 The District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act, approved August 28, 1935 (49 Stat. 946; D. C. Code sec. 46-101 et seq is amended as follows a) Sect, ion 3(c 8 tI D C. Code, sec. 46-103(c)(8){A» is amended as follows 1) By amendi ng Tables I, II, and III to read as follows i) equals or exceedS 5.5% of payroll J "Table I 0.8% if the employer s reserve the employer's average annua l ii) 1.0% if the employer's reserve eguals or exceeds 4 5% but is less than 5 5% of the employer s average annual payroll iii) 1.5% if the employer's reserve equals or exceeds 4% but is less than 4.5% of the employer's aver'1.ge anm l payrolll iv) 2.0% if the e~ployer s reserve equals or exceeds 3.5% but is less than 4.0% of the employer's average annual payroll v) 2.5% if the employer's reserve equals or exceeds 0.0% but is less than 3 5% of the employer's average annua l payroll; 1 D.C. Code, sec. 46-103 {l9SS $Up~.} vi) 3 0\ if the employer s r eserve e xceeds ~inu s 0 5% bu t is less tha n 0 0% of the empl oyer's aversge annu al p~yrol1 vi i) 3 Sl if t~e empl oyer reserve exc eeds minus 1. 0\ but is less tha n o r equal t o minus 0.5\ of the egp l oye r average a nnua l payr oll viii) 4. 0\ if the e~ployer s reserve e xesec!s minus 1 5% but is less t illn c r equal t o :n H':s gt of the e~ployer' s average annual payrOll i)c 4. 5\ .i f t he El ployer r elerve e xceeds minus 2.0\ but .is less thlln o r eGual to m.inus 1.5% of t he emp loye r s ave r a ge annua l payrOl l x) 5 0\ if the employer's r eserve exceeds Qinus 2. 5\ but is less than o r e~ual t o minus 2 0\ o f t he employer s average a nnual payr ol l xi 5.4 \ if the ~ployer reserve is equal to Or less tha n minus 2.5\ of the empl oyer s ave r llgc annua l payr oll i) 0 5\ if the cl:1ployer s reserve equIIla or exceed s 4.0\ of the empl oyer s avera ge ~nnua l payroll Iii) 1.0' if t he er.\ployer s reserve equa ls or exceed s 3.0\ but is l eas t han 4. 0~ of t he e~ploye r s average annual payroll iii) 1.5\ i f t he employt!r s r eserve e~u4 1s o r exceed s 2.5\ but is l ess t han 3. 0 \ of the e~ployc r £ average IInnuIIl payrol l iv) 2.0\ if the er:Iployer s r eserve equa ls or exceeds 2.0\ but is l ess t han 2.5' of the employe r's average annual payrolll v) 2 5\ if the employer s reserve equals or exceeds 0.0\ but i s l es' th a n 2 0' of the employer s averllge IInnual payroll vi) 3 0\ if t he empl oyer s reserve exceeds ~inus 0.5\ but is less t han 0 0\ o f the e~ploye r' s IIver llge annual payr o l l v ii 3 5\ if t he elilp l oyer rOllerve exceeds minus 1 0\ but is less th~n o r equal to minus 0 5\ of t he employer' s averllqe annual payroll vi i i) 4. 0\ if the empl oyer s r eserve e xceeds minus 1.5 \ but is le Bs tha n o r equal to minus 1.0% of the employer s average IInnual payroll ix 4 .5% if the employer's reserve exceeds minus 2.0\ but is less than or equal to minus 1 .5% of t he employer lI ave rage annua l payroll x l 5 0 \ if the e~pl oye r s r eserve exceed II minus 2.S\ but is l ess tha n o r equa l t o Dinus 2.0\ of t he employer' s aver age annual payroll xi) 5 4% if the employer s reserve is equal to or less than minus 2.5% of the employer's average annual payroll equal s or payroll; exceeds i 3.5% of a ble III 0.1% if the employer's the employer s average reserve a nnual ii) O 5~ ii the err,ployer 's .eseP/e e~uals or exceeds 3.0t but is less than 3.5% of the e~ployer's average annual payroll iii) 1.0% if the employer's reserve equals or exceeds 2.0% but is less than 3.0% of the employer's average annual payroll iv) 1 5% if the employer's reserve equals or exceeds 1.5% but is less than 2.0% of the employer's average annual payroll v) 2 0% if the employer's reserve equals or exceeds 1.0% but is less than 1.5% of the employer's average annual payroll vi) 2.5% if the emp l oye.'s reserve equals or exceeds 0.0% but is less than 1. 0% of the employer 's average annual payroll vii) 3.0% if the employer s reserve exceeds minus 0.5% but is less than 0.0% of the employer s average annual payroll viii) 3.5% if the employer's reserve exceeds minus 1.0% but is less than or equal to minus 0.5% of the employer s average annual payroll ix) 4 0% if the employer s reserve exceeds minus 1.5% but is less than or equal to minus 1.0% of the employer s average annual payroll x) 4.5% if the employe r's reserve exceeds minus 2.0% but is less than or equal to minu s 1 S% of the employer's average annual p ayroll xi) 5.0% if the employer's reserve exceeds minus 2 5% but is less than or equal to minus 2 0% of the employer s average annual payroll xii) 5.4% if the employer's reserve is equal to or less than minus 2.5% of the employer's average annual payroll 2) By striking the sentence Effective January 1, 1985, Tax Table IV shall be used to determine each employer's rate of contribution for the applicable ca lenda r year 3) Table IV is repealed bl Section 7(c D.C. Code, sec. 46-108(c» is amended by s t riking the amount 400 and inserting the amount 300" in its place. 3 D.C Code sec. 46·108 (1 988 supp inrcll ed Or!g1~al (c) Section 13(d D C Code, sec 46- 114(d is amended by designating the existing text as paragraph (1) and adding new paragraphs (2) and (3) to read as follows 2) By January 1, 1992, the Hayor shall submit to the Council a report designed to provide sufficient reserves in the Fund on December 30th of each year to meet unemployment benefit pay~ents for the forthcoming calendar year 3) Ey OCtober 15th of each year following the effective date of the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act Amendr.1ent Act of 1987, the l-layor shall submit to the Counc i l an annual status repor t o n the Fund The report shall include information on A) The computation of the employer tax rate to be used for the forthcoming calendar year; and B) A reviow of the prior 2 years and the current year, a forecast of the solvency of the Fund based on provisions of section 3(c)(4)(E)(ii) for the next 5 years, and the statistical and economic assumption s upon which the forecast is based Sec 3 a) Except as provided in subsection (b this act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event o~ veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the Oistrict of Columbia t o overr ide the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self- Governr.1ent and Governmental Reorgan ization Act approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat 813; D. C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(1 b Section 2(a) and (b) of the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act Amendment Act of 1987 Shall be effective beginning January 1, 1988 Cha irman Council of the District of Columbia o. District f COlumbia APPROVED; JANUARY 25, 1988 D.C. Code. sec. 46-114 {1988 supp Note, D.C. Code, sec. 46- 103 t 108 (1988 supp gt COUSCIL OF' THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA C&amp;lt;&amp;gt;llDcil P..ric&amp;gt;d ~V RECORO OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE OOCK€1' 1110 J: II Oft eon CooItO'lCW ACTIO N A1E A"d~"p""ted First Re!!ldinq, 12 8- 87 VOICE VOTE; U:1a:l.i:nous R r&amp;lt;I.cI tft u t AbSent: all p r ese:1t 37 25 6 7-\''I: Oal ACTI ON a DATE A oted Fi f 11 1 RfJadinq 1-5- 88 I VOICE VOTE: Unanimous on 11 present 7 C ACTI ON &amp;amp; CATE o VC*CE VOTE c At&amp;lt an I </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
