<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 7-96">
  <num type="law">7-96</num>
  <heading type="short">Senior Citizens’ Home Repair and Improvement Program Fund Act of 1987</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1988-03-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/7-96.pdf">D.C. Law 7-96</citation>
      <citation type="register">35 DCR 891</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 7-96, the “Senior Citizens’ Home Repair and Improvement Program Fund Act of 1987,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-167, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 8, 1987, and January 5, 1988, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 3, 1988, it was assigned Act No. 7-140 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>CO'JNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU~81A NOTICE D. C. LAW 7-96 "Sen ior Citilens' Home Repa ir and Irnprovement Program Fu~d ct of 19S7 Purs uant to Sectio n 412 of tile District of C()1 umn ia Self- Governrnent and Governmen t al Re orga nization Act, P. L. 93-198 t he lI,t the Council of the District of Col~rnbi dopted Bill No. 7-167 on first and second readings, December 8, 1987, and Januilry 5, 1988 respectiV€ly. Fo11 awi ng the signature of the Major on Feh ruary 3, 1988. thls leyis liltlon Wd&amp;gt; assigned Act 7-140, published in the Februdry 12, 1988, edition of the D.C, Reg ister Vol. 35 page 891) and transmitted to Congre55 on February 5, 1988 for 30-d~J rede\&amp;lt;l, in ~ccordance wit h Section 502(c)l.l) of the Act. TM€ Council of the Di&amp;gt;trict of Colurnbia hereby gives not ice th~t the 30-day Congressional Revie Period has expired, and ther efore cit€5 this en~ctment dS D.C. LdW 7-96. effntive ~arch 24 1988 OAn R Chdirlllan of the Council Dates Counted During the 3D-day Congressional Review Pe riod: Februa ry 5,8,9,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,26,29 MJrch 1,2,3,4,7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17.18,21,22,23 D.C. LAW 7 96 CEf~n MAR 2 4 1988 AN ACT D.C.ACT 7 -14 0 It HE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMbIA FEB 0 a 18Be 1'0 es t abli sh a Sen ior Citizens' Home Repair and lraprovement Prograr-l Fund BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Senior Citizens' Home Repair and Improvement Progr= Fund Act of 1987 Sec 2 Definitions For the purposes of this act, the terra 1 Council" means the Counci l of the Dis t ric t of Columbia 2 District" nlean s t h e District of Columbia 3 Fund" means the Senior Citizens Horne Repa ir and Improvement Program Fund established by sec t i on 3 4 Lower income" means a household within the section 8 lower income guidelines established by the Secretary of the enit ed States Depar tment of Housing a n d Urban Developmen t pursuant to sec t ion 8 of t he United S t ates Housing Act of 1937, ap1'roved August 22, 1974 (BB Stat. 662; 42 U.S C. 1 437£ 5 I ayor· me a ns the ~jayor of the District of Columbia 6 Principal place of rosid(lflce" meanS a dwelling unit in which a person lives in a particular locali ty with the intent to make it a fixed a nd perma nent horne of the senior citizen 7 Senior citizen homeowner leans the m,r.er resident of residential real propert y who is 60 years of age or older. Sec. 3. Senicr Citizens Home Repair a nd Imp rovemen t Program Fund es t abliShed a) There is es t ablished in the District a revolving Senior CitiZens liome Repair and Improvement Progra!:l Fund to be administered by t h e Bayor for the purpose of providing loans up to $5,000 to lower income senior citizen homeowne rs Or1g1aal COD:FICAT:ON ew Chapter 3( of tit l e 45 (l98S $Upo New, D.C Cod, sec. 45 3001 (1988 supp Ne\i, D.C. Code, sec. 45-3002 (1988 'iUpp } to en a ble t hem t o lake re pairs anc i!:lprov cnt s to en sure hea l th and s afe ty i n t heir principa l p l a ces o f resid~nce b hero may be a ppropriated o u t o f the r evenue o f the Dis t rict an amount necessary t o carry o ut th e pu rposes of this a ct Sec 4 rhe fund shall consist of. bu t not be lir.Jited to Jonies fror the followin sou r ces I) Ao;prop riat~ons pursuant to this act 2) Crants and gifts f ram public 01: pl:ivate SOUl:ces t o tlle fun d o r t o t he Di s tric t for t he purposes of the fund 3 Kcpayment s on pr incipa l a nd a ny inte rest all. loar.s prov ided fl:om the fund 4 Pl:ocellds reali~ed fr om t he liquidat ion o f a ny securi t y intereStS he ld by the Distri c t under tho te rms o f any I SS1.stance pr ov i ded from t he fund 5) Interest ea r ned from the deposit or investment of rr.on~es of t he t und l (6) tlon i cs appropriated for the f und by the United S t ates yovernment; anc 7 \ 11 o ther n .venues r ece i pts, and fees derived f rom t he opera tion of t he f und Sec 5 Eliqibility a An &amp;lt;lppli cant is eligible for a loa n if he o r she is a senior c it i zen homeOWner, i s a r eSident o f the Di s t r ic t a nd has ros idee in his o r her pr ~nc~ pal viaco o f residence f o r at least 3 yea r s p r eceding t he date o f the application f or ass istance under this act Lower income apV licants sh al l be give n p r ior ity cons ider &amp;lt;ltion by tho ~jayo r with re spec t to t he i SSUance o f loans b) To dotormine the e l i gibi l i ty o f a n app l icant the lyor sha ll dev e l o p !In «ppli cation form c) In order t o apply f or a loan under this &amp;lt;lc t In a Fp lica nt s hal l oomp l ete t he application form and r e turn i t to the tlayor at the t ime and in tho manner in wh ich the f.Jayor s hall pr escribe Id he tl.ayor shall ver ify the con tents o f the applic" tion fo r m a nd de t e r line he ther t he app lican t meets t he requi r ement S f o r age re sidency and princiV4 l p l ace of residence Sec 6. Repayment aj For each l oan is sued unde r this act, the t:ayor sha ll « r range a repay!;len t sChedu l e f o r whi ch t he repa yment sha ll no t create an economic hardsnip on the sen~o r c1. t i zen homeowner receiv~nq the l oan Loa n r ep.'lY!;lent ma y be de f e rred to avoid oconomic hard ship 2 D.C. Code. set. 45· 3003 (198f\ supp New. D.C Code set. 45 3004 (1 988 supp Je w D.C. Code. 45· 3005 (1988 supp b he lo"ns gr-anted under tr,is act shall be recocded as a lien against the principal place of residence of the ap licant c) If the loan is not fully repaid prior to the death of t he senior citizen horaeowner ho accepted a loan under this act the District may col lect the unsatisfied amount from t he decedent s estat e. Sec 7 Rules Iii thin 120 days of the effective date of this act, the ayor shall, l'ursuant to ti tIe I of the Distric t of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat 1204 D.C. Code, sec 1-1501 et seq issue proposed rules to ir:lplement the provisions of this act The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 4S-day period of ceview excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess If t he Counc il does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part by r esolu tion within this 45- day review period, the proposed rules sh"ll be deemed approved Sec 8 The Nayor shall submit to the Council, not later than 6 month s after the e nd of each fiscal year a report on the financial condition of the fund and the resul t s of t he operation of the fu nd for the fisca l year Sec 9 This act shall take effec t after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the tlayor (or in the event of veto by the Maye r, action by the Counc il o f the District of Columbia to override t he veto) as provided in section 602(c 1 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act at-proved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813 D.C. Code, sec. 1-23 3(c 1 Chairraan Council of the District of Col umbia Hay r District of Columbia AP?R8VED: February 3. 1988 ~ew D.C. Code, sec l5- 3006 (1988 supp New, D.C. Code, sec. 45- 3007 (1988 supP m OOll:O;Cll Of THE DISTRICT OF COLI:MBIA C"uotil P~riod &amp;amp;vn RECORD OF OFFICIAL COU NCIL VOTE D08KET NO E7 -167 Item Con Calond x AcnON 5 0"11: Adop amp;l:l First Redding 12-8-87 51: VOICE VOTE Ro«x gt;ole on r.Qu l U!'lanimous all present 5 n D x CTION CATE K VO ICE 'OTE A_« on fe&amp;lt;lue.t AQQptfld fina l Re..adi 1-5 _C&amp;gt;'O'L Unan imous all presont ROll C" U VOTE RESUlt It Co&amp;lt;&amp;gt;.801' Calen dar ~CTI()N' O.o,TE VOICE VOTE D 0 Q ROLL CJ.LL VOTE AES\)LT c l l 0 </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2201"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2202"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2203"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2204"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2205"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2206"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2207"/>
  </section>
</document>
