<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28-2305</num>
  <heading>Contract to assign future salary or wages.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A contract attempting or purporting to transfer or assign salary or wages to be earned by the debtor, if made in the District of Columbia, is invalid and contrary to public policy and unenforceable, and if made outside the District of Columbia, is unenforceable in any court within the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Whoever, in the District of Columbia demands or receives from a debtor an assignment of salary or wages to be thereafter earned by the debtor, or notifies an employer that he holds an assignment of such salary or wages, upon conviction shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>] or imprisoned not more than sixty days. Prosecutions under this subsection shall be upon information filed in the Criminal Division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia or one of his assistants.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-509" type="History">Aug. 30, 1964, 78 Stat. 670, Pub. L. 88-509, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 285(a), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28-2305.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28-2305.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>]” for “not more than $200” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 285(a) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite>: Section 401 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
