<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28-3104</num>
  <heading>Transfers fraudulent as to present and future creditors.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A transfer made, or obligation incurred, by a debtor is fraudulent as to a creditor, whether the creditor’s claim arose before or after the transfer was made or the obligation was incurred, if the debtor made the transfer or incurred the obligation:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>With actual intent to hinder, delay, or defraud any creditor of the debtor; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Without receiving a reasonably equivalent value in exchange for the transfer or obligation, and the debtor:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Was engaged or was about to engage in a business or a transaction for which the remaining assets of the debtor were unreasonably small in relation to the business or transaction; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Intended to incur, or believed or reasonably should have believed that the debtor would incur, debts beyond the debtor’s ability to pay as they became due.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In determining actual intent under subsection (a)(1) of this section, consideration may be given, among other factors, to whether:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The transfer or obligation was to an insider;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The debtor retained possession or control of the property transferred after the transfer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The transfer or obligation was disclosed or concealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Before the transfer was made or obligation was incurred, the debtor had been sued or threatened with suit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The transfer was of substantially all the debtor’s assets;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The debtor absconded;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The debtor removed or concealed assets;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The value of the consideration received by the debtor was reasonably equivalent to the value of the asset transferred or the amount of the obligation incurred;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The debtor was insolvent or became insolvent shortly after the transfer was made or the obligation was incurred;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The transfer occurred shortly before or shortly after a substantial debt was incurred; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>The debtor transferred the essential assets of the business to a lienor who transferred the assets to an insider of the debtor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-83" type="History">Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-83, § 2, 42 DCR 6773</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28-3103">28-3103</cite>, § <cite path="§28-3108">28-3108</cite>, and § <cite path="§28-3109">28-3109</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28-3104.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 4 of the Uniform Fraudulent Transfer Act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
