<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28-3909</num>
  <heading>Restraining prohibited acts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, if the Corporation Counsel has reason to believe that any person is using or intends to use any method, act, or practice in violation of section 28-3803, 28-3805, 28-3807, 28-3810, 28-3811, 28-3812, 28-3814, 28-3817, 28-3818, 28-3819, or 28-3904, and if it is in the public interest, the Corporation Counsel, in the name of the District of Columbia, may petition the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to issue a temporary or permanent injunction against the use of the method, act, or practice. In any action under this section, the Corporation Counsel shall not be required to prove damages and the injunction shall be issued without bond. The Corporation Counsel may recover restitution for property lost or damages suffered by consumers as a consequence of the unlawful act or practice.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition, in an action under this section, the Corporation Counsel may recover a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 for each violation, the costs of the action, and reasonable attorney’s fees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Corporation Counsel may also:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>represent the interests of consumers before administrative and regulatory agencies and legislative bodies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>assist, advise, and cooperate with private, local, and federal agencies and officials to protect and promote the interests of consumers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>assist, develop, and conduct programs of consumer education and information through public hearings, meetings, publications, or other materials prepared for distribution to consumers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>undertake activities to encourage local business and industry to maintain high standards of honesty, fair business practices, and public responsibility in the production, promotion, and sale of consumer goods and services and in the extension of consumer credit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>perform other functions and duties which are consistent with the purposes or provisions of this chapter, and with the Corporation’s Counsel’s role as <em>parens patriae</em>, which may be necessary or appropriate to protect and promote the welfare of consumers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>negotiate and enter into agreements for compliance by merchants with the provisions of this chapter; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>publicize its own actions taken in the interests of consumers.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-234" type="History">Mar. 8, 1991, D.C. Law 8-234, § 2(h), 38 DCR 296</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 1402(e), 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28-3910">28-3910</cite> and § <cite path="§28-5003">28-5003</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28-3909.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a), deleted from the second sentence thereof “on behalf of any identifiable person,” preceding “may recover restitution”, and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 1402(e) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1402(e) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
