<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28-4804.09</num>
  <heading>Deferred compensation, annuities, and similar payments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Payment” means a payment that a trustee may receive over a fixed number of years or during the life of one or more individuals because of services rendered or property transferred to the payer in exchange for future payments. The term “payment” includes a payment made in money or property from the payer’s general assets or from a separate fund created by the payer. For the purposes of subsections (d), (d-1), (d-2), and (d-3) of this section, the term “payment” also includes any payment from any separate fund, regardless of the reason for the payment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Separate fund” includes a private or commercial annuity, an individual retirement account, and a pension, profit-sharing, stock-bonus, or stock-ownership plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To the extent that a payment is characterized as interest, or a dividend, or a payment made in lieu of interest or a dividend, a trustee shall allocate the payment to income. The trustee shall allocate to principal the balance of the payment and any other payment received in the same accounting period that is not characterized as interest, a dividend, or an equivalent payment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If no part of a payment is characterized as interest, a dividend, or an equivalent payment, and all or part of the payment is required to be made, a trustee shall allocate to income 10 percent of the part that is required to be made during the accounting period and the balance to principal. If no part of a payment is required to be made or the payment received is the entire amount to which the trustee is entitled, the trustee shall allocate the entire payment to principal. For purposes of this subsection, a payment is not required to be made to the extent that it is made because the trustee exercises a right of withdrawal.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d-1) of this section, subsections (d-2) and (d-3) of this section apply, and subsections (b) and (c) of this section do not apply, in determining the allocation of a payment made from a separate fund to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A trust to which an election to qualify for a marital deduction under section 2056(b)(7) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 5, 1997 (68A Stat. 392; 26 U.S.C. § 2056(b)(7)), has been made; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A trust that qualifies for the marital deduction under section 2056(b)(5) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 5, 1997 (68A Stat. 392; 26 U.S.C. § 2056(b)(5)).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-1)</num>
    <text>Subsections (d), (d-2), and (d-3) of this section do not apply if and to the extent that the series of payments would, without the application of subsection (d) of this section, qualify for the marital deduction under section 2056(b)(7)(C) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 5, 1997 (68A Stat. 392; 26 U.S.C. § 2056(b)(7)(C)).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-2)</num>
    <text>A trustee shall determine the internal income of each separate fund for the accounting period as if the separate fund were a trust subject to this chapter. Upon request of the surviving spouse, the trustee shall demand that the person administering the separate fund distribute the internal income to the trust. The trustee shall allocate a payment from the separate fund to income to the extent of the internal income of the separate fund and distribute that amount to the surviving spouse. The trustee shall allocate the balance of the payment to principal. Upon request of the surviving spouse, the trustee shall allocate principal to income to the extent the internal income of the separate fund exceeds payments made from the separate fund to the trust during the accounting period.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-3)</num>
    <text>If a trustee cannot determine the internal income of a separate fund but can determine the value of the separate fund, the internal income of the separate fund is deemed to equal 4 % of the fund’s value, according to the most recent statement of value preceding the beginning of the accounting period. If the trustee can determine neither the internal income of the separate fund nor the fund’s value, the internal income of the fund is deemed to equal the product of the interest rate and the present value of the expected future payments, as determined under section 7520 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved November 10, 1988 (102 Stat. 3668; 26 U.S.C. § 7520), for the month preceding the accounting period for which the computation is made.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>This section does not apply to payments to which <cite path="§28-4804.10">§ 28-4804.10</cite> applies.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-292" type="History">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-292, § 502(c), 48 DCR 2087</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 26(c), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-197" type="History">July 23, 2010, D.C. Law 18-197, § 2(b), 57 DCR 4524</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 409 of the Uniform Principal and Income Act (1997 Act).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-197">D.C. Law 18-197</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite>, in subsec. (d), substituted “marital or domestic partnership” for “marital”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§28-4804.06">§ 28-4804.06</cite>, <cite path="§28-4804.07">§ 28-4804.07</cite>, <cite path="§28-4804.08">§ 28-4804.08</cite>, <cite path="§28-4804.10">§ 28-4804.10</cite>, <cite path="§28-4804.15">§ 28-4804.15</cite>, and <cite path="§28-4806.03">§ 28-4806.03</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
