<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:2-713</num>
  <heading>Buyer’s damages for non-delivery or repudiation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Subject to the provisions of this article with respect to proof of market price (section 28:2-723), the measure of damages for non-delivery or repudiation by the seller is the difference between the market price at the time when the buyer learned of the breach and the contract price together with any incidental and consequential damages provided in this article (section 28:2-715), but less expenses saved in consequence of the seller’s breach.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Market price is to be determined as of the place for tender or, in cases of rejection after arrival or revocation of acceptance, as of the place of arrival.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 668, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="28:2-711">28:2-711</cite> and § <cite root="28:2-723">28:2-723</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 28:2-713.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 28:2-713.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> Section 67(3), Uniform Sales Act.</text>
      <text><strong>Changes:</strong> Rewritten.</text>
      <text><strong>Purposes of Changes:</strong> To clarify the former rule so that:</text>
      <text>1. The general baseline adopted in this section uses as a yardstick the market in which the buyer would have obtained cover had he sought that relief. So the place for measuring damages is the place of tender (or the place of arrival if the goods are rejected or their acceptance is revoked after reaching their destination) and the crucial time is the time at which the buyer learns of the breach.</text>
      <text>2. The market or current price to be used in comparison with the contract price under this section is the price for goods of the same kind and in the same branch of trade.</text>
      <text>3. When the current market price under this section is difficult to prove the section on determination and proof of market price is available to permit a showing of a comparable market price or, where no market price is available, evidence of spot sale prices is proper. Where the unavailability of a market price is caused by a scarcity of goods of the type involved, a good case is normally made for specific performance under this Article. Such scarcity conditions, moreover, indicate that the price has risen and under the section providing for liberal administration of remedies, opinion evidence as to the value of the goods would be admissible in the absence of a market price and a liberal construction of allowable consequential damages should also result.</text>
      <text>4. This section carries forward the standard rule that the buyer must deduct from his damages any expenses saved as a result of the breach.</text>
      <text>5. The present section provides a remedy which is completely alternative to cover under the preceding section and applies only when and to the extent that the buyer has not covered.</text>
      <text><strong>Cross References:</strong> Point 3:  Sections 1-106,  2-716 and  2-723.</text>
      <text>Point 5:  Section 2-712.</text>
      <text><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Buyer”.  Section 2-103.</text>
      <text>“Contract”.  Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>“Seller”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
