<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:11-105</num>
  <heading>Transition provision on change of place of filing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A financing statement or continuation statement filed prior to the effective date of this act (as provided in section 28:11-101) which shall not have lapsed prior to such effective date of this act shall remain effective for the period provided for in article 9 of this subtitle, effective January 1, 1965, but not less than five years after the filing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>With respect to any collateral acquired by the debtor subsequent to the effective date of this act (as provided in section 28:11-101), any effective financing statement or continuation statement described in this section shall apply only if the filing or filings are in the office or offices that would be appropriate to perfect the security interests in the new collateral under this act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The effectiveness of any financing statement or continuation statement filed prior to the effective date of this act (as provided in section 28:11-101) may be continued by a continuation statement as permitted by this act except that if this act requires a filing in an office where there was no previous financing statement, a new financing statement conforming to section 28:11-106 shall be filed in that office.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>If the record of a mortgage of real estate would have been effective as a fixture filing of goods described therein if this act had been in effect on the date of recording the mortgage, the mortgage shall be deemed effective as a fixture filing as to such goods under section 28:9-402 (6) of this act on the effective date of this act (as provided in section 28:11-101).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-85" type="History">Mar. 16, 1982, D.C. Law 4-85, § 40, 29 DCR 309</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“This act”, referred to in this section, is <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-85">D.C. Law 4-85</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:11-105.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:11-103">28:11-103</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
