<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:1-206</num>
  <heading>Presumptions.</heading>
  <text>Whenever this subtitle creates a presumption with respect to a fact, or provides that a fact is presumed, the trier of fact must find the existence of the fact unless and until evidence is introduced that supports a finding of its nonexistence.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 636, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 2, 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28-4902">28-4902</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>2001 Ed., § <cite path="§28:1-201">28:1-201</cite>(31).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 revision of this article deleted former § <cite path="§28:1-206">28:1-206</cite>. Former § <cite path="§28:1-206">28:1-206</cite> concerned a statute of frauds for kinds of personal property not otherwise covered, was derived from Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 636, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Apr. 9, 1997, <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-240">D.C. Law 11-240</cite>, § 3(c),  44 DCR 1087. The other articles of the Uniform Commercial Code make individual determinations as to requirements for memorializing transactions within their scope, so that the primary effect of former  Section 1-206 was to impose a writing requirement on sales transactions not otherwise governed by the UCC. Per the official commentary appearing under § <cite path="§28:1-206">28:1-206</cite>: “Deletion of former  Section 1-206 did not constitute a recommendation as to whether such sales transactions should be covered by a Statute of Frauds; rather, it reflected determination that there was no need for uniform commercial law to resolve that issue.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text><strong>Source:</strong> Former  Section 1-201(31).</text>
      <text><strong>Changes from former law:</strong> None, other than stylistic changes.</text>
      <text>1. Several sections of the Uniform Commercial Code state that there is a “presumption” as to a certain fact, or that the fact is “presumed.” This section, derived from the definition appearing in former  Section 1-201(31), indicates the effect of those provisions on the proof process.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
