<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:1-305</num>
  <heading>Remedies to be liberally administered.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The remedies provided by this subtitle must be liberally administered to the end that the aggrieved party may be put in as good a position as if the other party had fully performed, but neither consequential or special damages nor penal damages may be awarded except as specifically provided in this subtitle or by other rule of law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any right or obligation declared by this subtitle is enforceable by action unless the provision declaring it specifies a different and limited effect.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 637, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 2, 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:1-106.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:1-106.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § 28:1-106.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§28:2A-501">§ 28:2A-501</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. “Consequential” or “special” damages and “penal” damages are not defined in the Uniform Commercial Code; rather, these terms are used in the sense in which they are used outside the Uniform Commercial Code.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Under subsection (b), any right or obligation described in the Uniform Commercial Code is enforceable by action, even though no remedy may be expressly provided, unless a particular provision specifies a different and limited effect. Whether specific performance or other equitable relief is available is determined not by this section but by specific provisions and by supplementary principles. Cf.  Sections 1-103,  2-716.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Subsection (a) is intended to effect three propositions. The first is to negate the possibility of unduly narrow or technical interpretation of remedial provisions by providing that the remedies in the Uniform Commercial Code are to be liberally administered to the end stated in this section. The second is to make it clear that compensatory damages are limited to compensation. They do not include consequential or special damages, or penal damages; and the Uniform Commercial Code elsewhere makes it clear that damages must be minimized. Cf.  Sections 1-304,  2-706(1), and  2-712(2). The third purpose of subsection (a) is to reject any doctrine that damages must be calculable with mathematical accuracy. Compensatory damages are often at best approximate: they have to be proved with whatever definiteness and accuracy the facts permit, but no more. Cf.  Section 2-204(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes from former law:</strong> Other than changes in the form of reference to the Uniform Commercial Code, this section is identical to former  Section 1-106.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Source:</strong> Former  Section 1-106.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
