<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:1-310</num>
  <heading>Subordinated obligations.</heading>
  <text>An obligation may be issued as subordinated to performance of another obligation of the person obligated, or a creditor may subordinate its right to performance of an obligation by agreement with either the person obligated or another creditor of the person obligated. Subordination does not create a security interest as against either the common debtor or a subordinated creditor.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 2, 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Source:</strong> Former  Section 1-209 [not adopted in D.C.].</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes from former law:</strong> This section is substantively identical to former  Section 1-209. The language in that section stating that it “shall be construed as declaring the law as it existed prior to the enactment of this section and not as modifying it” has been deleted.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Billions of dollars of subordinated debt are held by the public and by institutional investors. Commonly, the subordinated debt is subordinated on issue or acquisition and is evidenced by an investment security or by a negotiable or non-negotiable note. Debt is also sometimes subordinated after it arises, either by agreement between the subordinating creditor and the debtor, by agreement between two creditors of the same debtor, or by agreement of all three parties. The subordinated creditor may be a stockholder or other “insider” interested in the common debtor; the subordinated debt may consist of accounts or other rights to payment not evidenced by any instrument. All such cases are included in the terms “subordinated obligation,” “subordination,” and “subordinated creditor.”</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Subordination agreements are enforceable between the parties as contracts; and in the bankruptcy of the common debtor dividends otherwise payable to the subordinated creditor are turned over to the superior creditor. This “turn-over” practice has on occasion been explained in terms of “equitable lien,” “equitable assignment,” or “constructive trust,” but whatever the label the practice is essentially an equitable remedy and does not mean that there is a transaction “that creates a security interest in personal property...by contract” or a “sale of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes” within the meaning of  Section 9-109. On the other hand, nothing in this section prevents one creditor from assigning his rights to another creditor of the same debtor in such a way as to create a security interest within Article 9, where the parties so intend.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. The enforcement of subordination agreements is largely left to supplementary principles under  Section 1-103. If the subordinated debt is evidenced by a certificated security,  Section 8-202(a) authorizes enforcement against purchasers on terms stated or referred to on the security certificate. If the fact of subordination is noted on a negotiable instrument, a holder under  Sections 3-302 and  3-306 is subject to the term because notice precludes him from taking free of the subordination.  Sections 3-302(3)(a),  3-306, and  8-317 severely limit the rights of levying creditors of a subordinated creditor in such cases.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
