<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:1-306</num>
  <heading>Waiver or renunciation of claim or right after breach.</heading>
  <text>A claim or right arising out of an alleged breach may be discharged in whole or in part without consideration by agreement of the aggrieved party in an authenticated record.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 632, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 2, 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§28:1-107">28:1-107</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:1-107.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:1-107.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Source:</strong> Former  Section 1-107.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes from former law:<em>agreement</em>of the aggrieved party. Second, the revised section reflects developments in electronic commerce by providing for memorialization in an authenticated record. In this context, a party may “authenticate” a record by (i) signing a record that is a writing or (ii) attaching to or logically associating with a record that is not a writing an electronic sound, symbol or process with the present intent to adopt or accept the record. See  Sections 1-201(b)(37) and  9-102(a)(7).</strong> This section changes former law in two respects. First, former  Section 1-107, requiring the “delivery” of a “written waiver or renunciation” merges the separate concepts of the aggrieved party’s agreement to forego rights and the manifestation of that agreement. This section separates those concepts, and explicitly requires  </text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. This section makes consideration unnecessary to the effective renunciation or waiver of rights or claims arising out of an alleged breach of a commercial contract where the agreement effecting such renunciation is memorialized in a record authenticated by the aggrieved party. Its provisions, however, must be read in conjunction with the section imposing an obligation of good faith. ( Section 1-304).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
