<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:2-504</num>
  <heading>Shipment by seller.</heading>
  <text>Where the seller is required or authorized to send the goods to the buyer and the contract does not require him to deliver them at a particular destination, then unless otherwise agreed he must</text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>put the goods in the possession of such a carrier and make such a contract for their transportation as may be reasonable having regard to the nature of the goods and other circumstances of the case; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>obtain and promptly deliver or tender in due form any document necessary to enable the buyer to obtain possession of the goods or otherwise required by the agreement or by usage of trade; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>promptly notify the buyer of the shipment. Failure to notify the buyer under paragraph (c) or to make a proper contract under paragraph (a) is a ground for rejection only if material delay or loss ensues.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 656, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:2-319">28:2-319</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2-504.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:2-504.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> Section 46, Uniform Sales Act.</text>
      <text><strong>Changes:</strong> Rewritten.</text>
      <text><strong>Purposes of Changes:</strong> To continue the general policy of the prior uniform statutory provision while incorporating certain modifications with respect to the requirement that the contract with the carrier be made expressly on behalf of the buyer and as to the necessity of giving notice of the shipment to the buyer, so that:</text>
      <text>1. The section is limited to “shipment” contracts as contracted with “destination” contracts or contracts for delivery at the place where the goods are located. The general principles embodied in this section cover the special cases of F.O.B. point of shipment contracts and C.I.F. and C.&amp;F. contracts. Under the preceding section on manner of tender of delivery, due tender by the seller requires that he comply with the requirements of this section in appropriate cases.</text>
      <text>2. The contract to be made with the carrier under paragraph (a) must conform to all express terms of the agreement, subject to any substitution necessary because of failure of agreed facilities as provided in the later provision on substituted performance. However, under the policies of this Article on good faith and commercial standards and on buyer’s rights on improper delivery, the requirements of explicit provisions must be read in terms of their commercial and not their literal meaning. This policy is made express with respect to bills of lading in a set in the provision of this Article on form of bills of lading required in overseas shipment.</text>
      <text>3. In the absence of agreement, the provision of this Article on options and cooperation respecting performance gives the seller the choice of any reasonable carrier, routing and other arrangements. Whether or not the shipment is at the buyer’s expense the seller must see to any arrangements, reasonable in the circumstances, such as refrigeration, watering of live stock, protection against cold, the sending along of any necessary help, selection of specialized cars and the like for paragraph (a) is intended to cover all necessary arrangements whether made by contract with the carrier or otherwise. There is, however, a proper relaxation of such requirements if the buyer is himself in a position to make the appropriate arrangements and the seller gives him reasonable notice of the need to do so. It is an improper contract under paragraph (a) for the seller to agree with the carrier to a limited valuation below the true value and thus cut off the buyer’s opportunity to recover from the carrier in the event of loss, when the risk of shipment is placed on the buyer by his contract with the seller.</text>
      <text>4. Both the language of paragraph (b) and the nature of the situation it concerns indicate that the requirement that the seller must obtain and deliver promptly to the buyer in due form any document necessary to enable him to obtain possession of the goods is intended to cumulate with the other duties of the seller such as those covered in paragraph (a).</text>
      <text>In this connection, in the case of pool car shipments a delivery order furnished by the seller on the pool car consignee, or on the carrier for delivery out of a larger quantity, satisfies the requirements of paragraph (b) unless the contract requires some other form of document.</text>
      <text>5. This Article, unlike the prior uniform statutory provision, makes it the seller’s duty to notify the buyer of shipment in all cases. The consequences of his failure to do so, however, are limited in that the buyer may reject on this ground only where material delay or loss ensues.</text>
      <text>A standard and acceptable manner of notification in open credit shipments is the sending of an invoice and in the case of documentary contracts is the prompt forwarding of the documents as under paragraph (b) of this section. It is also usual to send on a straight bill of lading but this is not necessary to the required notification. However, should such a document prove necessary or convenient to the buyer, as in the case of loss and claim against the carrier, good faith would require the seller to send it on request.</text>
      <text>Frequently the agreement expressly requires prompt notification as by wire or cable. Such a term may be of the essence and the final clause of paragraph (c) does not prevent the parties from making this a particular ground for rejection. To have this vital and irreparable effect upon the seller’s duties, such a term should be part of the “dickered” terms written in any “form,” or should otherwise be called seasonably and sharply to the seller’s attention.</text>
      <text>6. Generally, under the final sentence of the section, rejection by the buyer is justified only when the seller’s dereliction as to any of the requirements of this section in fact is followed by material delay or damage. It rests on the seller, so far as concerns matters not within the peculiar knowledge of the buyer, to establish that his error has not been followed by events which justify rejection.</text>
      <text><strong>Cross References:</strong> Point 1:  Sections 2-319,  2-320 and  2-503(2).</text>
      <text>Point 2:  Sections 1-203,  2-323(2),  2-601 and  2-614(1).</text>
      <text>Point 3:  Section 2-311(2).</text>
      <text>Point 5:  Section 1-203.</text>
      <text><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Agreement”.  Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>“Buyer”.  Section 2-103.</text>
      <text>“Contract”.  Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>“Delivery”.  Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>“Goods”.  Section 2-105.</text>
      <text>“Notifies”.  Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>“Seller”.  Section 2-103.</text>
      <text>“Send”.  Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>“Usage of trade”.  Section 1-205.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
