<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2-304</num>
  <heading>Price payable in money, goods, realty, or otherwise.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The price can be made payable in money or otherwise. If it is payable in whole or in part in goods each party is a seller of the goods which he is to transfer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Even though all or part of the price is payable in an interest in realty the transfer of the goods and the seller’s obligations with reference to them are subject to this article, but not the transfer of the interest in realty or the transferor’s obligations in connection therewith.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 645, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2-304.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:2-304.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> Subsections (2) and (3) of Section 9, Uniform Sales Act.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Rewritten.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes of Changes:</strong> 1. This section corrects the phrasing of the Uniform Sales Act so as to avoid misconstruction and produce greater accuracy in commercial result. While it continues the essential intent and purpose of the Uniform Sales Act it rejects any purely verbalistic construction in disregard of the underlying reason of the provisions.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Under subsection (1) the provisions of this Article are applicable to transactions where the “price” of goods is payable in something other than money. This does not mean, however, that this whole Article applies automatically and in its entirety simply because an agreed transfer of title to goods is not a gift. The basic purposes and reasons of the Article must always be considered in determining the applicability of any of its provisions.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Subsection (2) lays down the general principle that when goods are to be exchanged for realty, the provisions of this Article apply only to those aspects of the transaction which concern the transfer of title to goods but do not affect the transfer of the realty since the detailed regulation of various particular contracts which fall outside the scope of this Article is left to the courts and other legislation. However, the complexities of these situations may be such that each must be analyzed in the light of the underlying reasons in order to determine the applicable principles. Local statutes dealing with realty are not to be lightly disregarded or altered by language of this Article. In contrast, this Article declares definite policies in regard to certain matters legitimately within its scope though concerned with real property situations, and in those instances the provisions of this Article control.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong> Point 1:  Section 1-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 3:  Sections 1-102,  1-103,  1-104 and  2-107.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Goods”.  Section 2-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Money”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Party”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Seller”.  Section 2-103.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
