<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2A-216</num>
  <heading>Third party beneficiaries of express and implied warranties.</heading>
  <text>A warranty to or for the benefit of a lessee under this article, whether express or implied, extends to any person who may reasonably be expected to use, consume, or be affected by the goods and who is injured by breach of the warranty. The operation of this section may not be excluded, modified, or limited with respect to injury to the person of an individual to whom the warranty extends, but an exclusion, modification, or limitation of the warranty, including any with respect to rights and remedies, effective against the lessee is also effective against the beneficiary designated under this section.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-128" type="History">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2A-216.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Uniform Statutory Source:</strong>Section 2-318.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> The provisions of  Section 2-318 have been included in this section, modified in two respects: first, to reflect leasing practice, including the special practices of the lessor under a finance lease; second, to reflect and thus codify elements of the official comment to  Section 2-318 with respect to the effect of disclaimers and limitations of remedies against third parties.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> [Mississippi has adopted Alternative A.]. Alternative A is based on the 1962 version of  Section 2-318 and is least favorable to the injured person as the doctrine of privity imposed by other law is abrogated to only a limited extent. Alternatives B and C are based on later additions to  Section 2-318 and are more favorable to the injured person. In determining which alternative to select, the state legislature should consider making its choice parallel to the choice it made with respect to  Section 2-318, as interpreted by the courts.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The last sentence of each of Alternatives A, B and C does not preclude the lessor from excluding or modifying an express or implied warranty under a lease. Section 2A-214. Further, that sentence does not preclude the lessor from limiting the rights and remedies of the lessee and from liquidating damages. Sections 2A-503 and 2A-504. If the lease excludes or modifies warranties, limits remedies for breach, or liquidates damages with respect to the lessee, such provisions are enforceable against the beneficiaries designated under this section. However, this last sentence forbids selective discrimination against the beneficiaries designated under this section, i.e., exclusion of the lessor’s liability to the beneficiaries with respect to warranties made by the lessor to the lessee.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Other law, including the Article on Sales (Article 2), may apply in determining the extent to which a warranty to or for the benefit of the lessor extends to the lessee and third parties. This is in part a function of whether the lessor has bought or leased the goods.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">This Article does not purport to change the development of the relationship of the common law, with respect to products liability, including strict liability in tort (as restated in Restatement (Second) of Torts, s 402A (1965)), to the provisions of this Act. Compare  Cline v. Prowler Indus. of Maryland, 418 A.2d 968 (Del.1980) and  Hawkins Constr. Co. v. Matthews Co., 190 Neb. 546, 209 N.W.2d 643 (1973) with  Dippel v. Sciano, 37 Wis.2d 443, 155 N.W.2d 55 (1967).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong> Article 2, esp.  Section 2-318, and Sections 2A-214, 2A-503 and 2A-504.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Goods”. Section 2A-103(1)(h).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessee”. Section 2A-103(1)(n).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Person”.  Section 1-201(30).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Remedy”.  Section 1-201(34).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Rights”.  Section 1-201(36).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">HISTORICAL NOTES</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
