<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2-327</num>
  <heading>Special incidents of sale on approval and sale or return.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Under a sale on approval unless otherwise agreed</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>although the goods are identified to the contract the risk of loss and the title do not pass to the buyer until acceptance; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>use of the goods consistent with the purpose of trial is not acceptance but failure seasonably to notify the seller of election to return the goods is acceptance, and if the goods conform to the contract acceptance of any part is acceptance of the whole; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>after due notification of election to return, the return is at the seller’s risk and expense but a merchant buyer must follow any reasonable instructions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Under a sale or return unless otherwise agreed</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>the option to return extends to the whole or any commercial unit of the goods while in substantially their original condition, but must be exercised seasonably; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>the return is at the buyer’s risk and expense.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 652, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> Section 19(3), Uniform Sales Act.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Completely rewritten in preceding and this section.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes of Changes:</strong> To make it clear that:</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. In the case of a sale on approval:</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">If all of the goods involved conform to the contract, the buyer’s acceptance of part of the goods constitutes acceptance of the whole. Acceptance of part falls outside the normal intent of the parties in the “on approval” situation and the policy of this Article allowing partial acceptance of a defective delivery has no application here. A case where a buyer takes home two dresses to select one commonly involves two distinct contracts; if not, it is covered by the words “unless otherwise agreed”.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. In the case of a sale or return, the return of any unsold unit merely because it is unsold is the normal intent of the “sale or return” provision, and therefore the right to return for this reason alone is independent of any other action under the contract which would turn on wholly different considerations. On the other hand, where the return of goods is for breach, including return of items resold by the buyer and returned by the ultimate purchasers because of defects, the return procedure is governed not by the present section but by the provisions on the effects and revocation of acceptance.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. In the case of a sale on approval the risk rests on the seller until acceptance of the goods by the buyer, while in a sale or return the risk remains throughout on the buyer.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Notice of election to return given by the buyer in a sale on approval is sufficient to relieve him of any further liability. Actual return by the buyer to the seller is required in the case of a sale or return contract. What constitutes due “giving” of notice, as required in “on approval” sales, is governed by the provisions on good faith and notice. “Seasonable” is used here as defined in  Section 1-204. Nevertheless, the provisions of both this Article and of the contract on this point must be read with commercial reason and with full attention to good faith.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong> Point 1:  Sections 2-501,  2-601 and  2-603.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 2:  Sections 2-607 and  2-608.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 4:  Sections 1-201 and  1-204.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Agreed”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Buyer”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Commercial unit”.  Section 2-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Conform”.  Section 2-106.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Contract”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”.  Section 2-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Merchant”.  Section 2-104.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Notifies”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Notification”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Sale on approval”.  Section 2-326.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Sale or return”.  Section 2-326.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Seasonably”.  Section 1-204.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Seller”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:2-327.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2-327.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:2-509">28:2-509</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
