<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:2-510</num>
  <heading>Effect of breach on risk of loss.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Where a tender or delivery of goods so fails to conform to the contract as to give a right of rejection the risk of their loss remains on the seller until cure or acceptance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Where the buyer rightfully revokes acceptance he may to the extent of any deficiency in his effective insurance coverage treat the risk of loss as having rested on the seller from the beginning.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Where the buyer as to conforming goods already identified to the contract for sale repudiates or is otherwise in breach before risk of their loss has passed to him, the seller may to the extent of any deficiency in his effective insurance coverage treat the risk of loss as resting on the buyer for a commercially reasonable time.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 658, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:2-509">28:2-509</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 28:2-510.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 28:2-510.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> None.</text>
      <text><strong>Purposes:</strong> To make clear that:</text>
      <text>1. Under subsection (1) the seller by his individual action cannot shift the risk of loss to the buyer unless his action conforms with all the conditions resting on him under the contract.</text>
      <text>2. The “cure” of defective tenders contemplated by subsection (1) applies only to those situations in which the seller makes changes in goods already tendered, such as repair, partial substitution, sorting out from an improper mixture and the like since “cure” by repossession and new tender has no effect on the risk of loss of the goods originally tendered. The seller’s privilege of cure does not shift the risk, however, until the cure is completed.</text>
      <text>Where defective documents are involved a cure of the defect by the seller or a waiver of the defects by the buyer will operate to shift the risk under this section. However, if the goods have been destroyed prior to the cure or the buyer is unaware of their destruction at the time he waives the defect in the documents, the risk of the loss must still be borne by the seller, for the risk shifts only at the time of cure, waiver of documentary defects or acceptance of the goods.</text>
      <text>3. In cases where there has been a breach of the contract, if the one in control of the goods is the aggrieved party, whatever loss or damage may prove to be uncovered by his insurance falls upon the contract breaker under subsections (2) and (3) rather than upon him. The word “effective” as applied to insurance coverage in those subsections is used to meet the case of supervening insolvency of the insurer. The “deficiency” referred to in the text means such deficiency in the insurance coverage as exists without subrogation. This section merely distributes the risk of loss as stated and is not intended to be disturbed by any subrogation of an insurer.</text>
      <text><strong>Cross Reference:</strong>Section 2-509.</text>
      <text><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Buyer”.  Section 2-103.</text>
      <text>“Conform”.  Section 2-106.</text>
      <text>“Contract for sale”.  Section 2-106.</text>
      <text>“Goods”.  Section 2-105.</text>
      <text>“Seller”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
