<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:2A-108</num>
  <heading>Unconscionability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the court as a matter of law finds a lease contract or any clause of a lease contract to have been unconscionable at the time it was made the court may refuse to enforce the lease contract, or it may enforce the remainder of the lease contract without the unconscionable clause, or it may so limit the application of any unconscionable clause as to avoid any unconscionable result.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>With respect to a consumer lease, if the court as a matter of law finds that a lease contract or any clause of a lease contract has been induced by unconscionable conduct or that unconscionable conduct has occurred in the collection of a claim arising from a lease contract, the court may grant appropriate relief.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before making a finding of unconscionability under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the court, on its own motion or that of a party, shall afford the parties a reasonable opportunity to present evidence as to the setting, purpose, and effect of the lease contract or clause thereof, or of the conduct.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In an action in which the lessee claims unconscionability with respect to a consumer lease:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the court finds unconscionability under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees to the lessee.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the court does not find unconscionability and the lessee claiming unconscionability has brought or maintained an action he or she knew to be groundless, the court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees to the party against whom the claim is made.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In determining attorney’s fees, the amount of the recovery on behalf of the claimant under subsections (a) and (b) of this section is not controlling.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-128" type="History">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2A-108.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Uniform Statutory Source:</strong>Section 2-302 and Unif. Consumer Credit Code s 5.108, 7A U.L.A. 167-69 (1974).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Subsection (1) is taken almost verbatim from the provisions of  Section 2-302(1). Subsection (2) is suggested by the provisions of Unif. Consumer Credit Code s 5.108(1), (2), 7A U.L.A. 167 (1974). Subsection (3), taken from the provisions of  Section 2-302(2), has been expanded to cover unconscionable conduct. Unif. Consumer Credit Code s 5.108(3), 7A U.L.A. 167 (1974).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The provision for the award of attorney’s fees to consumers, subsection (4), covers unconscionability under subsection (1) as well as (2). Subsection (4) is modeled on the provisions of Unif. Consumer Credit Code s 5.108(6), 7A U.L.A. 169 (1974).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> Subsections (1) and (3) of this section apply the concept of unconscionability reflected in the provisions of  Section 2-302 to leases.  See Dillman &amp; Assocs. v. Capitol Leasing Co., 110 Ill.App.3d 335, 342, 442 N.E.2d 311, 316 (App.Ct.1982). Subsection (3) omits the adjective “commercial” found in sub section 2-302(2) because subsection (3) is concerned with all leases and the relevant standard of conduct is determined by the context.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The balance of the section is modeled on the provisions of Unif. Consumer Credit Code s 5.108, 7A U.L.A. 167-69 (1974). Thus subsection (2) recognizes that a consumer lease or a clause in a consumer lease may not itself be unconscionable but that the agreement would never have been entered into if unconscionable means had not been employed to induce the consumer to agree. To make a statement to induce the consumer to lease the goods, in the expectation of invoking an integration clause in the lease to exclude the statement’s admissibility in a subsequent dispute, may be unconscionable. Subsection (2) also provides a consumer remedy for unconscionable conduct, such as using or threatening to use force or violence, in the collection of a claim arising from a lease contract. These provisions are not exclusive. The remedies of this section are in addition to remedies otherwise available for the same conduct under other law, for example, an action in tort for abusive debt collection or under another statute of this State for such conduct. The reference to appropriate relief in subsection (2) is intended to foster liberal administration of this remedy. Sections 2A-103(4) and 1-106(1).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (4) authorizes an award of reasonable attorney’s fees if the court finds unconscionability with respect to a consumer lease under subsections (1) or (2). Provision is also made for recovery by the party against whom the claim was made if the court does not find unconscionability and does find that the consumer knew the action to be groundless. Further, subsection (4)(b) is independent of, and thus will not override, a term in the lease agreement that provides for the payment of attorney’s fees.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong>Sections 1-106(1),  2-302 and 2A-103(4).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross Reference:</strong> “Action”.  Section 1-201(1).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Consumer lease”. Section 2A-103(1)(e).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease contract”. Section 2A-103(1)(l).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessee”. Section 2A-103(1)(n).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Party”.  Section 1-201(29).</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
