<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:2-602</num>
  <heading>Manner and effect of rightful rejection.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Rejection of goods must be within a reasonable time after their delivery or tender. It is ineffective unless the buyer seasonably notifies the seller.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Subject to the provisions of the two following sections on rejected goods (sections 28:2-603 and 28:2-604),</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>after rejection any exercise of ownership by the buyer with respect to any commercial unit is wrongful as against the seller; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>if the buyer has before rejection taken physical possession of goods in which he does not have a security interest under the provisions of this article (subsection (3) of section 28:2-711), he is under a duty after rejection to hold them with reasonable care at the seller’s disposition for a time sufficient to permit the seller to remove them; but</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>the buyer has no further obligations with regard to goods rightfully rejected.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The seller’s rights with respect to goods wrongfully rejected are governed by the provisions of this article on seller’s remedies in general (section 28:2-703).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 659, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:2-606">28:2-606</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2-602.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:2-602.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> Section 50, Uniform Sales Act.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Rewritten.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes of Changes:</strong> To make it clear that:</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. A tender or delivery of goods made pursuant to a contract of sale, even though wholly non-conforming, requires affirmative action by the buyer to avoid acceptance. Under subsection (1), therefore, the buyer is given a reasonable time to notify the seller of his rejection, but without such seasonable notification his rejection is ineffective. The sections of this Article dealing with inspection of goods must be read in connection with the buyer’s reasonable time for action under this subsection. Contract provisions limiting the time for rejection fall within the rule of the section on “Time” and are effective if the time set gives the buyer a reasonable time for discovery of defects. What constitutes a due “notifying” of rejection by the buyer to the seller is defined in  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Subsection (2) lays down the normal duties of the buyer upon rejection, which flow from the relationship of the parties. Beyond his duty to hold the goods with reasonable care for the buyer’s [seller’s] disposition, this section continues the policy of prior uniform legislation in generally relieving the buyer from any duties with respect to them, except when the circumstances impose the limited obligation of salvage upon him under the next section.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. The present section applies only to rightful rejection by the buyer. If the seller has made a tender which in all respects conforms to the contract, the buyer has a positive duty to accept and his failure to do so constitutes a “wrongful rejection” which gives the seller immediate remedies for breach. Subsection (3) is included here to emphasize the sharp distinction between the rejection of an improper tender and the non-acceptance which is a breach by the buyer.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. The provisions of this section are to be appropriately limited or modified when a negotiation is in process.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong> Point 1:  Sections 1-201,  1-204(1) and (3), 2-512(2), 2-513(1) and 2-606(1)(b).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 2:  Section 2-603(1).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 3:  Section 2-703.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Buyer”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Commercial unit”.  Section 2-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”.  Section 2-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Merchant”.  Section 2-104.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Notifies”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Reasonable time”.  Section 1-204.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Remedy”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Rights”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Seasonably”.  Section 1-204.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Security interest”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Seller”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
