<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2A-529</num>
  <heading>Lessor’s action for the rent.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After default by the lessee under the lease contract of the type described in § 28:2A-523(a) or § 28:2A-523(c) or, if agreed, after other default by the lessee, if the lessor complies with subsection (b) of this section, the lessor may recover from the lessee as damages:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For goods accepted by the lessee and not repossessed by or tendered to the lessor, and for conforming goods lost or damaged within a commercially reasonable time after risk of loss passes to the lessee (§ 28:2A-219), (i) accrued and unpaid rent as of the date of entry of judgment in favor of the lessor, (ii) the present value as of the same date of the rent for the then remaining lease term of the lease agreement, and (iii) any incidental damages allowed under § 28:2A-530, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessee’s default; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For goods identified to the lease contract if the lessor is unable after reasonable effort to dispose of them at a reasonable price or the circumstances reasonably indicate that effort will be unavailing, (i) accrued and unpaid rent as of the date of default, (ii) the present value as of the date of default of the rent for the remaining lease term of the lease agreement, and (iii) any incidental damages allowed under § 28:2A-530, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessee’s default.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the lessor shall hold for the lessee for the remaining lease term of the lease agreement any goods that have been identified to the lease contract and are in the lessor’s control.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The lessor may dispose of the goods at any time before collection of the judgment for damages obtained pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. If the disposition is before the end of the remaining lease term of the lease agreement, the lessor’s recovery against the lessee for damages is governed by § 28:2A-527 or § 28:2A-528, and the lessor will cause an appropriate credit to be provided against a judgment for damages to the extent that the amount of the judgment exceeds the recovery available pursuant to § 28:2A-527 or § 28:2A-528.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Payment of the judgment for damages obtained pursuant to subsection (a) of this section entitles the lessee to the use and possession of the goods not then disposed of for the remaining lease term of and in accordance with the lease agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>After a lessee has wrongfully rejected or revoked acceptance of goods, has failed to pay rent then due, or has repudiated (§ 28:2A-402), a lessor who is held not entitled to rent under this section must nevertheless be awarded damages for nonacceptance under §§ 28:2A-527 and 28:2A-528.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-128" type="History">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § 28:2A-523.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2A-529.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Uniform Statutory Source:</strong>Section 2-709.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Substantially revised.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> 1. Absent a lease contract provision to the contrary, an action for the full unpaid rent (discounted to present value as of the time of entry of judgment as to rent due after that time) is available as to goods not lost or damaged only if the lessee retains possession of the goods or the lessor is or apparently will be unable to dispose of them at a reasonable price after reasonable effort. There is no general right in a lessor to recover the full rent from the lessee upon holding the goods for the lessee. If the lessee tenders goods back to the lessor, and the lessor refuses to accept the tender, the lessor will be limited to the damages it would have suffered had it taken back the goods. The rule in Article 2 that the seller can recover the price of accepted goods is rejected here. In a lease, the lessor always has a residual interest in the goods which the lessor usually realizes upon at the end of a lease term by either sale or a new lease. Therefore, it is not a substantial imposition on the lessor to require it to take back and dispose of the goods if the lessee chooses to tender them back before the end of the lease term: the lessor will merely do earlier what it would have done anyway, sell or relet the goods. Further, the lessee will frequently encounter substantial difficulties if the lessee attempts to sublet the goods for the remainder of the lease term. In contrast to the buyer who owns the entire interest in goods and can easily dispose of them, the lessee is selling only the right to use the goods under the terms of the lease and the sublessee must assume a relationship with the lessor. In that situation, it is usually more efficient to eliminate the original lessee as a middleman by allowing the lessee to return the goods to the lessor who can then redispose of them.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. In some situations even where possession of the goods is reacquired, a lessor will be able to recover as damages the present value of the full rent due, not under this section, but under 2A-528(2) which allows a lost profit recovery if necessary to put the lessor in the position it would have been in had the lessee performed. Following is an example of such a case. A is a lessor of construction equipment and maintains a substantial inventory. B leases from A a backhoe for a period of two weeks at a rental of $1,000. After three days, B returns the backhoe and refuses to pay the rent. A has five backhoes in inventory, including the one returned by B. During the next 11 days after the return by B of the backhoe, A rents no more than three backhoes at any one time and, therefore, always has two on hand. If B had kept the backhoe for the full rental period. A would have earned the full rental on that backhoe, plus the rental on the other backhoes it actually did rent during that period. Getting this backhoe back before the end of the lease term did not enable A to make any leases it would not otherwise have made. The only way to put A in the position it would have been in had the lessee fully performed is to give the lessor the full rentals. A realized no savings at all because the backhoe was returned early and might even have incurred additional expense if it was paying for parking space for equipment in inventory. A has no obligation to relet the backhoe for the benefit of B rather than leasing the backhoe or any other in inventory for its own benefit. Further, it is probably not reasonable to expect A to dispose of the backhoe by sale when it is returned in an effort to reduce damages suffered by B. Ordinarily, the loss of a two-week rental would not require A to reduce the size of its backhoe inventory. Whether A would similarly be entitled to full rentals as lost profit in a one-year lease of a backhoe is a question of fact: in any event the lessor, subject to mitigation of damages rules, is entitled to be put in as good a position as it would have been had the lessee fully performed the lease contract.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Under subsection (2) a lessor who is able and elects to sue for the rent due under a lease must hold goods not lost or damaged for the lessee. Subsection (3) creates an exception to the subsection (2) requirement. If the lessor disposes of those goods prior to collection of the judgment (whether as a matter of law or agreement), the lessor’s recovery is governed by the measure of damages in Section 2A-527 if the disposition is by lease that is substantially similar to the original lease, or otherwise by the measure of damages in Section 2A-528. Section 2A-523 official comment.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Subsection (4), which is new, further reinforces the requisites of Subsection (2). In the event the judgment for damages obtained by the lessor against the lessee pursuant to subsection (1) is satisfied, the lessee regains the right to use and possession of the remaining goods for the balance of the original lease term; a partial satisfaction of the judgment creates no right in the lessee to use and possession of the goods.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. The relationship between subsections (2) and (4) is important to understand. Subsection (2) requires the lessor to hold for the lessee identified goods in the lessor’s possession. Absent agreement to the contrary, whether in the lease or otherwise, under most circumstances the requirement that the lessor hold the goods for the lessee for the term will mean that the lessor is not allowed to use them. Sections 2A-103(4) and 1-203. Further, the lessor’s use of the goods could be viewed as a disposition of the goods that would bar the lessor from recovery under this section, remitting the lessor to the two preceding sections for a determination of the lessor’s claim for damages against the lessee.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">6. Subsection (5), the analogue of sub section 2-709(3), further reinforces the thrust of subsection (3) by stating that a lessor who is held not entitled to rent under this section has not elected a remedy; the lessor must be awarded damages under Sections 2A-527 and 2A-528. This is a function of two significant policies of this Article—that resort to a remedy is optional, unless expressly agreed to be exclusive (Section 2A-503(2)) and that rights and remedies provided in this Article generally are cumulative. (Section 2A-501(2) and (4)).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong>Sections 1-203,  2-709,  2-709(3), 2A-103(4), 2A-501(2), 2A-501(4), 2A-503(2), 2A-504, 2A-523(1)(e), 2A-525(2), 2A-527, 2A-528 and 2A-529(2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Action”.  Section 1-201(1).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Conforming”. Section 2A-103(1)(d).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”. Section 2A-103(1)(h).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease”. Section 2A-103(1)(j).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease agreement”. Section 2A-103(1)(k).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease contract”. Section 2A-103(1)(l).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessee”. Section 2A-103(1)(n).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessor”. Section 2A-103(1)(p).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Present value”. Section 2A-103(1)(u).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Reasonable time”.  Section 1-204(1) and (2).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
