<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:2A-307</num>
  <heading>Priority of liens arising by attachment or levy on, security interests in, and other claims to goods.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in § 28:2A-306, a creditor of a lessee takes subject to the lease contract.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c) of this section and in §§ 28:2A-306 and 28:2A-308, a creditor of a lessor takes subject to the lease contract unless the creditor holds a lien that attached to the goods before the lease contract became enforceable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in §§ <cite path="§28:9-317">28:9-317</cite>, 28:9-321, and 28:9-323, a lessee takes a leasehold interest subject to a security interest held by a creditor of the lessor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-128" type="History">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 201(d)(3), 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2A-307.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-201">D.C. Law 13-201</cite>, enacting a new Article 9 of the Uniform Commercial Code applicable July 1, 2001, made conforming amendments to this section applicable upon the same date.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Uniform Statutory Source:</strong> None for subsection (1). Subsection (2) is derived from  Section 9-301, and subsections (3) and (4) are derived from  Section 9-307(1) and (3), respectively.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> The provisions of  Sections 9-301 and  9-307(1) and (3) were incorporated, and modified to reflect leasing terminology and the basic concepts reflected in this Article.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> 1. Subsection (1) states a general rule of priority that a creditor of the lessee takes subject to the lease contract. The term lessee (Section 2A-103(1)(n) includes sublessee. Therefore, this subsection not only covers disputes between the prime lessor and a creditor of the prime lessee but also disputes between the prime lessor, or the sublessor, and a creditor of the sublessee. Section 2A-301 official comment 3(g). Further, by using the term creditor ( Section 1-201(12)), this subsection will cover disputes with a general creditor, a secured creditor, a lien creditor and any representative of creditors. Section 2A-103(4).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Subsection (2) states a general rule of priority that a creditor of a lessor takes subject to the lease contract. Note the discussion above with regard to the scope of these rules. Section 2A-301 official comment 3(g). Thus, the section will not only cover disputes between the prime lessee and a creditor of the prime lessor but also disputes between the prime lessee, or the sublessee, and a creditor of the sublessor.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. To take priority over the lease contract, and the interests derived therefrom, the creditor must come within the exception stated in subsection (2) or within one of the provisions of Article 9 mentioned in subsection (3). Subsection (2) provides that where the creditor holds a lien (Section 2A-103(1)(r)) that attached before the lease contract became enforceable (Section 2A-301), the creditor does not take subject to the lease. Subsection (3) provides that a lessee takes its leasehold interest subject to a security interest except as otherwise provided in  Sections 9-317,  9-321, or  9-323.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. The rules of this section operate in favor of whichever party to the lease contract may enforce it, even if one party perhaps may not, e.g., under Section 2A-201(1)(b).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong>Sections 1-201(12),  1-201(25),  1-201(37),  1-201(44), 2A-103(1)(n), 2A-103(1)(o), 2A-103(1)(r), 2A-103(4), 2A-201(1)(b), 2A-301 official comment 3(g), Article 9, especially  Sections 9-301,  9-307(1) and  9-307(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Creditor”.  Section 1-201(12).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”. Section 2A-103(1)(h).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Knowledge” and “Knows”.  Section 1-201(25).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease”. Section 2A-103(1)(j).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease contract”. Section 2A-103(1)(l).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Leasehold interest”. Section 2A-103(1)(m).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessee”. Section 2A-103(1)(n).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessee in the ordinary course of business”. Section 2A-103(1)(o).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessor”. Section 2A-103(1)(p).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lien”. Section 2A-103(1)(r).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Party”.  Section 1-201(29).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Pursuant to commitment”. Section 2A-103(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Security interest”.  Section 1-201(37).</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
