<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2A-516</num>
  <heading>Effect of acceptance of goods; notice of default; burden of establishing default after acceptance; notice of claim or litigation to person answerable over.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A lessee must pay rent for any goods accepted in accordance with the lease contract, with due allowance for goods rightfully rejected or not delivered.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A lessee’s acceptance of goods precludes rejection of the goods accepted. In the case of a finance lease, if made with knowledge of a nonconformity, acceptance cannot be revoked because of it. In any other case, if made with knowledge of a nonconformity, acceptance cannot be revoked because of it unless the acceptance was on the reasonable assumption that the nonconformity would be seasonably cured. Acceptance does not of itself impair any other remedy provided by this article or the lease agreement for nonconformity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a tender has been accepted:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within a reasonable time after the lessee discovers or should have discovered any default, the lessee shall notify the lessor and the supplier, if any, or be barred from any remedy against the party not notified;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Except in the case of a consumer lease, within a reasonable time after the lessee receives notice of litigation for infringement or the like (§ 28:2A-211) the lessee shall notify the lessor or be barred from any remedy over for liability established by the litigation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The burden is on the lessee to establish any default.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a lessee is sued for breach of a warranty or other obligation for which a lessor or a supplier is answerable over the following apply:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The lessee may give the lessor or the supplier, or both, written notice of the litigation. If the notice states that the person notified may come in and defend and that if the person notified does not do so, that person will be bound in any action against that person by the lessee by any determination of fact common to the 2 litigations, then unless the person notified after seasonable receipt of the notice does come in and defend, that person is so bound.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The lessor or the supplier may demand in writing that the lessee turn over control of the litigation including settlement if the claim is one for infringement or the like (§ 28:2A-211) or else be barred from any remedy over. If the demand states that the lessor or the supplier agrees to bear all expense and to satisfy any adverse judgment, then unless the lessee after seasonable receipt of the demand does turn over control the lessee is so barred.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subsections (c) and (d) of this section apply to any obligation of a lessee to hold the lessor or the supplier harmless against infringement or the like (§ 28:2A-211).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-128" type="History">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § 28:2A-519.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2A-516.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Uniform Statutory Source:</strong>Section 2-607.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Substantially revised.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> 1. Subsection (2) creates a special rule for finance leases, precluding revocation if acceptance is made with knowledge of nonconformity with respect to the lease agreement, as opposed to the supply agreement; this is not inequitable as the lessee has a direct claim against the supplier. Section 2A-209(1). Revocation of acceptance of a finance lease is permitted if the lessee’s acceptance was without discovery of the nonconformity (with respect to the lease agreement, not the supply agreement) and was reasonably induced by the lessor’s assurances. Section 2A-517(1)(b). Absent exclusion or modification, the lessor under a finance lease makes certain warranties to the lessee. Sections 2A-210 and 2A-211(1). Revocation of acceptance is not prohibited even after the lessee’s promise has become irrevocable and independent. Section 2A-407 official comment. Where the finance lease creates a security interest, the rule may be to the contrary.  General Elec. Credit Corp. of Tennessee v. Ger-Beck Mach. Co., 806 F.2d 1207 (3rd Cir.1986).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Subsection (3)(a) requires the lessee to give notice of default, within a reasonable time after the lessee discovered or should have discovered the default. In a finance lease, notice may be given either to the supplier, the lessor, or both, but remedy is barred against the party not notified. In a finance lease, the lessor is usually not liable for defects in the goods and the essential notice is to the supplier. While notice to the finance lessor will often not give any additional rights to the lessee, it would be good practice to give the notice since the finance lessor has an interest in the goods. Subsection (3)(a) does not use the term finance lease, but the definition of supplier is a person from whom a lessor buys or leases goods to be leased under a finance lease. Section 2A-103(1)(x). Therefore, there can be a “supplier” only in a finance lease. Subsection (4) applies similar notice rules as to lessors and suppliers if a lessee is sued for a breach of warranty or other obligation for which a lessor or supplier is answerable over.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Subsection (3)(b) requires the lessee to give the lessor notice of litigation for infringement or the like. There is an exception created in the case of a consumer lease. While such an exception was considered for a finance lease, it was not created because it was not necessary—the lessor in a finance lease does not give a warranty against infringement. Section 2A-211(2). Even though not required under subsection (3)(b), the lessee who takes under a finance lease should consider giving notice of litigation for infringement or the like to the supplier, because the lessee obtains the benefit of the suppliers’ promises subject to the suppliers’ defenses or claims. Sections 2A-209(1) and 2-607(3)(b).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong>Sections 2-607(3)(b), 2A-103(1)(x), 2A-209(1), 2A-210, 2A-211(1), 2A-211(2), 2A-407 official comment and 2A-517(1)(b).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Action”.  Section 1-201(1).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Agreement”.  Section 1-201(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Burden of establishing”.  Section 1-201(8).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Conforming”. Section 2A-103(1)(d).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Consumer lease”. Section 2A-103(1)(e).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Delivery”.  Section 1-201(14).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Discover”.  Section 1-201(25).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Finance lease”. Section 2A-103(1)(g).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”. Section 2A-103(1)(h).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Knowledge”.  Section 1-201(25).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease agreement”. Section 2A-103(1)(k).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease contract”. Section 2A-103(1)(l).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessee”. Section 2A-103(1)(n).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessor”. Section 2A-103(1)(p).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Notice”.  Section 1-201(25).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Notifies”.  Section 1-201(26).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Person”.  Section 1-201(30).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Reasonable time”.  Section 1-204(1) and (2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Receipt”.  Section 2-103(1)(c).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Remedy”.  Section 1-201(34).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Seasonably”.  Section 1-204(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Supplier”. Section 2A-103(1)(x).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Written”.  Section 1-201(46).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
