<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2-708</num>
  <heading>Seller’s damages for non-acceptance or repudiation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (2) and to the provisions of this article with respect to proof of market price (section 28:2-723), the measure of damages for non-acceptance or repudiation by the buyer is the difference between the market price at the time and place for tender and the unpaid contract price together with any incidental damages provided in this article (section 28:2-710), but less expenses saved in consequence of the buyer’s breach.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>If the measure of damages provided in subsection (1) is inadequate to put the seller in as good a position as performance would have done then the measure of damages is the profit (including reasonable overhead) which the seller would have made from full performance by the buyer, together with any incidental damages provided in this article (section 28:2-710), due allowance for costs reasonably incurred and due credit for payments or proceeds of resale.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 666, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:2-708.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2-708.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§28:2-703">§ 28:2-703</cite> and <cite path="§28:2-723">§ 28:2-723</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Seller”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Contract”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Buyer”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 3:  Section 2-710.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 2:  Section 2-709.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong> Point 1:  Sections 2-319 through  2-324,  2-503,  2-723 and  2-724.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. In all cases the seller may recover incidental damages.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. The provision of this section permitting recovery of expected profit including reasonable overhead where the standard measure of damages is inadequate, together with the new requirement that price actions may be sustained only where resale is impractical, are designed to eliminate the unfair and economically wasteful results arising under the older law when fixed price articles were involved. This section permits the recover of lost profits in all appropriate cases, which would include all standard priced goods. The normal measure there would be list price less cost to the dealer or list price less manufacturing cost to the manufacturer. It is not necessary to a recovery of “profit” to show a history of earnings, especially if a new venture is involved.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">In the event that there is no evidence available of the current market price at the time and place of tender, proof of a substitute market may be made under the section on determination and proof of market price. Furthermore, the section on the admissibility of market quotations is intended to ease materially the problem of providing competent evidence.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. The prior uniform statutory provision is followed generally in setting the current market price at the time and place for tender as the standard by which damages for non-acceptance are to be determined. The time and place of tender is determined by reference to the section on manner of tender of delivery, and to the sections on the effect of such terms as FOB, FAS, CIF, C &amp; F, Ex Ship and No Arrival, No Sale.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes of Changes:</strong> To make it clear that:</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Rewritten.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> Section 64, Uniform Sales Act.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
