<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2-403</num>
  <heading>Power to transfer; good faith purchase of goods; “entrusting”.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A purchaser of goods acquires all title which his transferor had or had power to transfer except that a purchaser of a limited interest acquires rights only to the extent of the interest purchased. A person with voidable title has power to transfer a good title to a good faith purchaser for value. When goods have been delivered under a transaction of purchase the purchaser has such power even though</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>the transferor was deceived as to the identity of the purchaser, or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>the delivery was in exchange for a check which is later dishonored, or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>it was agreed that the transaction was to be a “cash sale”, or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>the delivery was procured through fraud punishable as larcenous under the criminal law.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Any entrusting of possession of goods to a merchant who deals in goods of that kind gives him power to transfer all rights of the entruster to a buyer in ordinary course of business.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Entrusting” includes any delivery and any acquiescence in retention of possession regardless of any condition expressed between the parties to the delivery or acquiescence and regardless of whether the procurement of the entrusting or the possessor’s disposition of the goods have been such as to be larcenous under the criminal law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The rights of other purchasers of goods and of lien creditors are governed by the articles on secured transactions (Article 9), bulk sales (Article 6) and documents of title (Article 7).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 654, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-239" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-239, § 3(c), 44 DCR 936</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> Sections 20(4), 23, 24, 25, Uniform Sales Act; Section 9, especially 9(2), Uniform Trust Receipts Act; Section 9, Uniform Conditional Sales Act.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Consolidated and rewritten.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes of Changes:</strong> To gather together a series of prior uniform statutory provisions and the case-law thereunder and to state a unified and simplified policy on good faith purchase of goods.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. The basic policy of our law allowing transfer of such title as the transferor has is generally continued and expanded under subsection (1). In this respect the provisions of the section are applicable to a person taking by any form of “purchase” as defined by this Act. Moreover the policy of this Act expressly providing for the application of supplementary general principles of law to sales transactions wherever appropriate joins with the present section to continue unimpaired all rights acquired under the law of agency or of apparent agency or ownership or other estoppel, whether based on statutory provisions or on case law principles. The section also leaves unimpaired the powers given to selling factors under the earlier Factors Acts. In addition subsection (1) provides specifically for the protection of the good faith purchaser for value in a number of specific situations which have been troublesome under prior law.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">On the other hand, the contract of purchase is of course limited by its own terms as in a case of pledge for a limited amount or of sale of a fractional interest in goods.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. The many particular situations in which a buyer in ordinary course of business from a dealer has been protected against reservation of property or other hidden interest are gathered by subsections (2)-(4) into a single principle protecting persons who buy in ordinary course out of inventory. Consignors have no reason to complain, nor have lenders who hold a security interest in the inventory, since the very purpose of goods in inventory is to be turned into cash by sale.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The principle is extended in subsection (3) to fit with the abolition of the old law of “cash sale” by subsection (1)(c). It is also freed from any technicalities depending on the extended law of larceny; such extension of the concept of theft to include trick, particular types of fraud, and the like is for the purpose of helping conviction of the offender; it has no proper application to the long-standing policy of civil protection of buyers from persons guilty of such trick or fraud. Finally, the policy is extended, in the interest of simplicity and sense, to any entrusting by a bailor; this is in consonance with the explicit provisions of  Section 7-205 on the powers of a warehouseman who is also in the business of buying and selling fungible goods of the kind he warehouses. As to entrusting by a secured party, subsection (2) is limited by the more specific provisions of  Section 9-307(1), which deny protection to a person buying farm products from a person engaged in farming operations.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. The definition of “buyer in ordinary course of business” ( Section 1-201) is effective here and preserves the essence of the healthy limitations engrafted by the case-law on the older statutes. The older loose concept of good faith and wide definition of value combined to create apparent good faith purchasers in many situations in which the result outraged common sense;</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">the court’s solution was to protect the original title especially by use of “cash sale” or of overtechnical construction of the enabling clauses of the statutes. But such rulings then turned into limitations on the proper protection of buyers in the ordinary market.  Section 1-201(9) cuts down the category of buyer in ordinary course in such fashion as to take care of the results of the cases, but with no price either in confusion or in injustice to proper dealings in the normal market.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Except as provided in subsection (1), the rights of purchasers other than buyers in ordinary course are left to the Articles on Secured Transactions, Documents of Title, and Bulk Sales.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong> Point 1:  Sections 1-103 and  1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 2:  Sections 1-201,  2-402,  7-205 and  9-307(1).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Points 3 and 4:  Sections 1-102,  1-201,  2-104,  2-707 and Articles 6, 7 and 9.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Buyer in ordinary course of business”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Good faith”.  Sections 1-201 and  2-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”.  Section 2-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Person”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Purchaser”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Signed”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Term”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Value”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:2-403.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2-403.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§28:2-103">§ 28:2-103</cite>, <cite path="§28:2-702">§ 28:2-702</cite>, <cite path="§28:2A-103">§ 28:2A-103</cite>, <cite path="§28:7-209">§ 28:7-209</cite>, <cite path="§28:7-503">§ 28:7-503</cite>, and <cite path="§28:9-315">§ 28:9-315</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
