<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28-2701</num>
  <heading>Holidays designated — Time for performing acts extended.</heading>
  <text>The following days in each year, namely, New Year’s Day, January 1; Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.’s Birthday, the third Monday in January; Washington’s Birthday, the third Monday in February; District of Columbia Emancipation Day, April 16; Memorial Day, the last Monday in May; Independence Day, July 4; Labor Day, the first Monday in September; Columbus Day, the second Monday in October; Veteran’s Day, November 11; Thanksgiving Day, the fourth Thursday in November; Christmas Day, December 25; every Saturday, after twelve o’clock noon; any day appointed by the President of the United States as a day of public feasting or thanksgiving; and the day of the inauguration of the President, in every fourth year, are holidays in the District for all purposes. When a day set apart as a legal holiday, other than the day of the inauguration of the President, falls on a Saturday, the next preceding day is a holiday. When a day set apart as a legal holiday falls on a Sunday, the next succeeding day is a holiday. In such cases, when a Sunday and a holiday or holidays fall on successive days, all commercial papers falling due on any of those days shall, for all purposes of presenting for payment or acceptance, be deemed to mature and be presentable for payment or acceptance on the next secular business day succeeding. Every Saturday is a holiday in the District for (1) every bank or banking institution having an office or banking house located within the District, (2) every Federal savings and loan association whose main office is in the District, and (3) every building association, building and loan association, or savings and loan association, incorporated or unincorporated, organized and operating under the laws of and having an office located within the District. An act which would otherwise be required, authorized, or permitted to be performed on Saturday in the District at the office or banking house of, or by, any such bank or bank institution, Federal savings and loan association, building association, building and loan association, or savings and loan association, if Saturday were not a holiday, shall or may be so performed on the next succeeding business day, and liability or loss of rights of any kind may not result from such delay.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-509" type="History">Aug. 30, 1964, 78 Stat. 671, Pub. L. 88-509, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-11" type="History">Aug. 1, 1975, D.C. Law 1-11, § 103, 22 DCR 1804</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-13" type="History">July 12, 1977, D.C. Law 2-13, § 2, 24 DCR 1443</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-77" type="History">Mar. 16, 1982, D.C. Law 4-77, § 2, 29 DCR 46</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-155" type="History">Mar. 14, 1985, D.C. Law 5-155, § 3, 32 DCR 11</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91" type="History">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, § 109, 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Holidays, recognition of Dr. King’s birthday, see § <cite path="§1-504">1-504</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Merit system, continuation of existing laws, see § <cite path="§1-632.06">1-632.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-632.06">1-632.06</cite> and § <cite path="§47-1401">47-1401</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28-2701.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28-2701.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-91">D.C. Law 16-91</cite>, substituted “the third Monday in February; District of Columbia Emancipation Day, April 16;” for “the third Monday in February;”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-155">D.C. Law 5-155</cite> provided that §§ 2 and 3 of the act shall take effect January 1, 1986.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
