<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:2-601</num>
  <heading>Buyer’s rights on improper delivery.</heading>
  <text>Subject to the provisions of this article on breach in installment contracts (section 28:2-612  ) and unless otherwise agreed under the sections on contractual limitations of remedy (sections 28:2-718   and 28:2-719  ), if the goods or the tender of delivery fail in any respect to conform to the contract, the buyer may</text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>reject the whole; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>accept the whole; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>accept any commercial unit or units and reject the rest.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 659, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2-601.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:2-601.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> No one general equivalent provision but numerous provisions, dealing with situations of non-conformity where buyer may accept or reject, including Sections 11, 44 and 69(1), Uniform Sales Act.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Partial acceptance in good faith is recognized and the buyer’s remedies on the contract for breach of warranty and the like, where the buyer has returned the goods after transfer of title, are no longer barred.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes of Changes:</strong> To make it clear that:</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. A buyer accepting a nonconforming tender is not penalized by the loss of any remedy otherwise open to him. This policy extends to cover and regulate the acceptance of a part of any lot improperly tendered in any case where the price can reasonably be apportioned. Partial acceptance is permitted whether the part of the goods accepted conforms or not. The only limitation on partial acceptance is that good faith and commercial reasonableness must be used to avoid undue impairment of the value of the remaining portion of the goods. This is the reason for the insistence on the “commercial unit” in paragraph (c). In this respect, the test is not only what unit has been the basis of contract, but whether the partial acceptance produces so materially adverse an effect on the remainder as to constitute bad faith.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Acceptance made with the knowledge of the other party is final. An original refusal to accept may be withdrawn by a later acceptance if the seller has indicated that he is holding the tender open. However, if the buyer attempts to accept, either in whole or in part, after his original rejection has caused the seller to arrange for other disposition of the goods, the buyer must answer for any ensuing damage since the next section provides that any exercise of ownership after rejection is wrongful as against the seller. Further, he is liable even though the seller may choose to treat his action as acceptance rather than conversion, since the damage flows from the misleading notice. Such arrangements for resale or other disposition of the goods by the seller must be viewed as within the normal contemplation of a buyer who has given notice of rejection. However, the buyer’s attempts in good faith to dispose of defective goods where the seller has failed to give instructions within a reasonable time are not to be regarded as an acceptance.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong>Sections 2-602(2)(a),  2-612,  2-718 and  2-719.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Buyer”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Commercial unit”.  Section 2-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Conform”.  Section 2-106.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Contract”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”.  Section 2-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Installment contract”.  Section 2-612.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Rights”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
