<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2A-217</num>
  <heading>Identification.</heading>
  <text>Identification of goods as goods to which a lease contract refers may be made at any time and in any manner explicitly agreed to by the parties. In the absence of explicit agreement, identification occurs:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>When the lease contract is made if the lease contract is for a lease of goods that are existing and identified;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>When the goods are shipped, marked, or otherwise designated by the lessor as goods to which the lease contract refers, if the lease contract is for a lease of goods that are not existing and identified; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>When the young are conceived, if the lease contract is for a lease of unborn young of animals.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-128" type="History">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § 28:2A-522.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2A-217.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Uniform Statutory Source:</strong>Section 2-501.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> This section, together with Section 2A-218, is derived from the provisions of  Section 2-501, with changes to reflect lease terminology; however, this section omits as irrelevant to leasing practice the treatment of special property.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> With respect to subsection (b) there is a certain amount of ambiguity in the reference to when goods are designated, e.g., when the lessor is both selling and leasing goods to the same lessee/buyer and has marked goods for delivery but has not distinguished between those related to the lease contract and those related to the sales contract. As in  Section 2-501(1)(b), this issue has been left to be resolved by the courts, case by case.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong>Sections 2-501 and 2A-218.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Agreement”.  Section 1-201(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”. Section 2A-103(1)(h).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease”. Section 2A-103(1)(j).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease contract”. Section 2A-103(1)(l).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessor”. Section 2A-103(1)(p).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Party”.  Section 1-201(29).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
