<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2A-528</num>
  <heading>Lessor’s damages for nonacceptance, failure to pay, repudiation, or other default.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided with respect to damages liquidated in the lease agreement (§ 28:2A-504) or otherwise determined pursuant to agreement of the parties (§§ <cite path="§28:1-302">28:1-302</cite> and 28:2A-503), if a lessor elects to retain the goods or a lessor elects to dispose of the goods and the disposition is by lease agreement that for any reason does not qualify for treatment under § 28:2A-527(b), or is by sale or otherwise, the lessor may recover from the lessee as damages for a default of the type described in § 28:2A-523(c)(1), or, if agreed, for other default of the lessee (i) accrued and unpaid rent as of the date of default if the lessee has never taken possession of the goods, or, if the lessee has taken possession of the goods, as of the date the lessor repossesses the goods or an earlier date on which the lessee makes a tender of the goods to the lessor, (ii) the present value as of the date determined under clause (i) of this subsection of the total rent for the then remaining lease term of the original lease agreement minus the present value as of the same date the market rent at the place where the goods are located computed for the same lease term, and (iii) any incidental damages allowed under § 28:2A-530, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessee’s default.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the measure of damages provided in subsection (a) of this section is inadequate to put a lessor in as good a position as performance would have, the measure of damages is the present value of the profit, including reasonable overhead, the lessor would have made from full performance by the lessee, together with any incidental damages allowed under § 28:2A-530, due allowance for costs reasonably incurred and due credit for payments or proceeds of disposition.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-128" type="History">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 4(i), 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § 28:2A-507, § 28:2A-523, § 28:2A-527, and § 28:2A-529.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2A-528.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-299">D.C. Law 19-299</cite> substituted “§ <cite path="§28:1-302">28:1-302</cite>” for “§ <cite path="§28:1-102">28:1-102</cite>(3)” in (a).</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Uniform Statutory Source:</strong>Section 2-708.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Substantially revised.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> 1. Subsection (1), a substantially revised version of  Section 2-708(1), states the basic rule governing the measure of lessor’s damages for a default described in Section 2A-523(1) or (3)(a), and, if agreed, for a contractual default. This measure will apply if the lessor elects to retain the goods (whether undelivered, returned by the lessee, or repossessed by the lessor after acceptance and default by the lessee) or if the lessor’s disposition does not qualify under subsection 2A-527(2). Section 2A-527(3). Note that under some of these conditions, the lessor may recover damages from the lessee pursuant to the rule set forth in Section 2A-529. There is no sanction for disposition that does not qualify under subsection 2A-527(2). Application of the rule set forth in this section is subject to agreement to the contrary. Sections 2A-504, 2A-103(4) and 1-102(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. If the lessee has never taken possession of the goods, the measure of damage is the accrued and unpaid rent as of the date of default together with the present value, as of the date of default, of the original rent for the remaining term of the lease less the present value as of the same date of market rent, and incidental damages, less expenses saved in consequence of the default. Note that the reference in Section 2A-528(1)(i) and (ii) is to the date of default not to the date of an event of default. An event of default under a lease agreement becomes a default under a lease agreement only after the expiration of any relevant period of grace and compliance with any notice requirements under this Article and the lease agreement. American Bar Foundation, Commentaries on Indentures, s 5- 1, at 216-217 (1971). Section 2A-501(1). This conclusion is also a function of whether, as a matter of fact or law, the event of default has been waived, suspended or cured. Sections 2A-103(4) and 1-103. If the lessee has taken possession of the goods, the measure of damages is the accrued and unpaid rent as of the earlier of the time the lessor repossesses the goods or the time the lessee tenders the goods to the lessor plus the difference between the present value, as of the same time, of the rent under the lease for the remaining lease term and the present value, as of the same time, of the market rent.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Market rent will be computed pursuant to Section 2A-507.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Subsection (2), a somewhat revised version of the provisions of sub section 2-708(2), states a measure of damages which applies if the measure of damages in subsection (1) is inadequate to put the lessor in as good a position as performance would have. The measure of damage is the lessor’s profit, including overhead, together with incidental damages, with allowance for costs reasonably incurred and credit for payments or proceeds of disposition. In determining the amount of due credit with respect to proceeds of disposition a proper value should be attributed to the lessor’s residual interest in the goods. Sections 2A-103(1)(q) and 2A-507(4).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. In calculating profit, a court should include any expected appreciation of the goods, e.g. the foal of a leased brood mare. Because this subsection is intended to give the lessor the benefit of the bargain, a court should consider any reasonable benefit or profit expected by the lessor from the performance of the lease agreement.  See Honeywell, Inc. v. Lithonia Lighting, Inc., 317 F.Supp. 406, 413 (N.D.Ga.1970);  Locks v. Wade, 36 N.J.Super. 128, 131, 114 A.2d 875, 877 (Super.Ct.App.Div.1955). Further, in calculating profit the concept of present value must be given effect. Taylor v. Commercial credit  Equip. Corp., 170 Ga.App. 322, 316 S.E.2d 788 (Ct.App.1984). See generally Section 2A-103(1)(u).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong>Sections 1-102(3),  2-708, 2A-103(1)(u), 2A-402, 2A-504, 2A-507, 2A-527(2) and 2A-529.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Agreement”.  Section 1-201(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”. Section 2A-103(1)(h).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease”. Section 2A-103(1)(j).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease agreement”. Section 2A-103(1)(k).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessee”. Section 2A-103(1)(n).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessor”. Section 2A-103(1)(p).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Party”.  Section 1-201(29).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Present value”. Section 2A-103(1)(u).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Sale”.  Section 2-106(1).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
