<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:2A-103</num>
  <heading>Definitions and index of definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In this article unless the context otherwise requires:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Buyer in ordinary course of business” means a person who in good faith and without knowledge that the sale to him or her is in violation of the ownership rights or security interest or leasehold interest of a third party in the goods buys in ordinary course from a person in the business of selling goods of that kind but does not include a pawnbroker. “Buying” may be for cash or by exchange of other property or on secured or unsecured credit and includes acquiring goods or documents of title under a pre-existing contract for sale but does not include a transfer in bulk or as security for or in total or partial satisfaction of a money debt.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Cancellation” occurs when either party puts an end to the lease contract for default by the other party.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Commercial unit” means such a unit of goods as by commercial usage is a single whole for purposes of lease and division of which materially impairs its character or value on the market or in use. A commercial unit may be a single article, as a machine, or a set of articles, as a suite of furniture or a line of machinery, or a quantity, as a gross or carload, or any other unit treated in use or in the relevant market as a single whole.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Conforming” goods or performance under a lease contract means goods or performance that are in accordance with the obligations under the lease contract.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>“Consumer lease” means a lease that a lessor regularly engaged in the business of leasing or selling makes to a lessee who is an individual and who takes under the lease primarily for a personal, family, or household purpose, if the total payments to be made under the lease contract, excluding payments for options to renew or buy, do not exceed $25,000.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>“Fault” means wrongful act, omission, breach, or default.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>“Finance lease” means a lease with respect to which:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The lessor does not select, manufacture, or supply the goods;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The lessor acquires the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods in connection with the lease; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>One of the following occurs:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The lessee receives a copy of the contract by which the lessor acquired the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods before signing the lease contract;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The lessee’s approval of the contract by which the lessor acquired the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods is a condition to effectiveness of the lease contract;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The lessee, before signing the lease contract, receives an accurate and complete statement designating the promises and warranties, and any disclaimer of warranties, limitations or modifications of remedies, or liquidated damages, including those of a third party, such as the manufacturer of the goods, provided to the lessor by the person supplying the goods in connection with or as part of the contract by which the lessor acquired the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>If the lease is not a consumer lease, the lessor, before the lessee signs the lease contract, informs the lessee in writing of the identity of the person supplying the goods to the lessor, unless the lessee has selected that person and directed the lessor to acquire the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods from that person; that the lessee is entitled under this article to the promises and warranties, including those of any third party, provided to the lessor by the person supplying the goods in connection with or as part of the contract by which the lessor acquired the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods; and that the lessee may communicate with the person supplying the goods to the lessor and receive an accurate and complete statement of those promises and warranties, including any disclaimers and limitations of them or of remedies.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>“Goods” means all things that are movable at the time of identification to the lease contract, or are fixtures (§ 28:2A-309), but the term does not include money, documents, instruments, accounts, chattel paper, general intangibles, or minerals or the like, including oil and gas, before extraction. The term also includes the unborn young of animals.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>“Installment lease contract” means a lease contract that authorizes or requires the delivery of goods in separate lots to be separately accepted, even though the lease contract contains a clause “each delivery is a separate lease” or its equivalent.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>“Lease” means a transfer of the right to possession and use of goods for a term in return for consideration, but a sale, including a sale on approval or a sale or return, or retention or creation of a security interest is not a lease. Unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term includes a sublease.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>“Lease agreement” means the bargain, with respect to the lease, of the lessor and the lessee in fact as found in their language or by implication from other circumstances including course of dealing or usage of trade or course of performance as provided in this article. Unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term includes a sublease agreement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>“Lease contract” means the total legal obligation that results from the lease agreement as affected by this article and any other applicable rules of law. Unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term includes a sublease contract.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>“Leasehold interest” means the interest of the lessor or the lessee under a lease contract.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>“Lessee” means a person who acquires the right to possession and use of goods under a lease. Unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term includes a sublessee.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>“Lessee in ordinary course of business” means a person who in good faith and without knowledge that the lease to him or her is in violation of the ownership rights or security interest or leasehold interest of a third party in the goods leases in ordinary course from a person in the business of selling or leasing goods of that kind but does not include a pawnbroker. “Leasing” may be for cash or by exchange of other property or on secured or unsecured credit and includes acquiring goods or documents of title under a pre-existing lease contract but does not include a transfer in bulk or as security for or in total or partial satisfaction of a money debt.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>“Lessor” means a person who transfers the right to possession and use of goods under a lease. Unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term includes a sublessor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>“Lessor’s residual interest” means the lessor’s interest in the goods after expiration, termination, or cancellation of the lease contract.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(18)</num>
      <text>“Lien” means a charge against or interest in goods to secure payment of a debt or performance of an obligation, but the term does not include a security interest.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(19)</num>
      <text>“Lot” means a parcel or a single article that is the subject matter of a separate lease or delivery, whether or not it is sufficient to perform the lease contract.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(20)</num>
      <text>“Merchant lessee” means a lessee that is a merchant with respect to goods of the kind subject to the lease.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(21)</num>
      <text>“Present value” means the amount as of a date certain of one or more sums payable in the future, discounted to the date certain. The discount is determined by the interest rate specified by the parties if the rate was not manifestly unreasonable at the time the transaction was entered into; otherwise, the discount is determined by a commercially reasonable rate that takes into account the facts and circumstances of each case at the time the transaction was entered into.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(22)</num>
      <text>“Purchase” includes taking by sale, lease, mortgage, security interest, pledge, gift, or any other voluntary transaction creating an interest in goods.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(23)</num>
      <text>“Sublease” means a lease of goods the right to possession and use of which was acquired by the lessor as a lessee under an existing lease.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(24)</num>
      <text>“Supplier” means a person from whom a lessor buys or leases goods to be leased under a finance lease.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(25)</num>
      <text>“Supply contract” means a contract under which a lessor buys or leases goods to be leased.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(26)</num>
      <text>“Termination” occurs when either party pursuant to a power created by agreement or law puts an end to the lease contract otherwise than for default.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Other definitions applying to this article and the sections in which they appear are:</text>
    <text>“Accessions”. § 28:2A-310(a).</text>
    <text>“Construction mortgage”. § 28:2A-309(a)(4).</text>
    <text>“Encumbrance”. § 28:2A-309(a)(5).</text>
    <text>“Fixture filing”. § 28:2A-309(a)(2).</text>
    <text>“Fixtures”. § 28:2A-309(a)(1).</text>
    <text>“Purchase money lease”. § 28:2A-309(a)(3).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The following definitions in other articles apply to this article:</text>
    <text>“Account”. § <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(2).</text>
    <text>“Between merchants”. § <cite path="§28:2-104">28:2-104</cite>(3).</text>
    <text>“Buyer”. § <cite path="§28:2-103">28:2-103</cite>(1)(a).</text>
    <text>“Chattel paper”. § <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(11).</text>
    <text>“Consumer goods”. § <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(23).</text>
    <text>“Document.” § <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(30).</text>
    <text>“Entrusting”. § <cite path="§28:2-403">28:2-403</cite>(3).</text>
    <text>“General intangibles”. § <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(42).</text>
    <text>“Instrument”. § <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(47).</text>
    <text>“Merchant”. § <cite path="§28:2-104">28:2-104</cite>(1).</text>
    <text>“Mortgage”. § <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(55).</text>
    <text>“Pursuant to commitment”. § <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(69).</text>
    <text>“Receipt”. § <cite path="§28:2-103">28:2-103</cite>(1)(c).</text>
    <text>“Sale”. § <cite path="§28:2-106">28:2-106</cite>(1).</text>
    <text>“Sale on approval”. § <cite path="§28:2-326">28:2-326</cite>.</text>
    <text>“Sale or return”. § <cite path="§28:2-326">28:2-326</cite>.</text>
    <text>“Seller”. § <cite path="§28:2-103">28:2-103</cite>(1)(d).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In addition Article 1 contains general definitions and principles of construction and interpretation applicable throughout this article.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-128" type="History">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 201(d)(1), 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 4(a), 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-302" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-302, § 3, 60 DCR 2688</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:7-102">28:7-102</cite> and § <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2A-103.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-201">D.C. Law 13-201</cite>, enacting a new Article 9 of the Uniform Commercial Code applicable July 1, 2001, made conforming amendments to this section applicable upon the same date.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-299">D.C. Law 19-299</cite> substituted “acquiring goods” for “receiving goods” in the second sentence of (a)(1) and (a)(15); and deleted the phrase “ ‘Good faith’. § <cite path="§28:2-103">28:2-103</cite>(1)(b)” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-302">D.C. Law 19-302</cite> substituted “§ <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(69)” for “§ <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(68)” in the definition of “Pursuant to commitment” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-302">D.C. Law 19-302</cite>: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-302">D.C. Law 19-302</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of July 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(a) “Buyer in ordinary course of business”.  Section 1-201(9).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(b) “Cancellation”.  Section 2-106(4). The effect of a cancellation is provided in Section 2A-505(1).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(c) “Commercial unit”.  Section 2-105(6).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(d) “Conforming”.  Section 2-106(2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(e) “Consumer lease”. New. This Article includes a subset of rules that applies only to consumer leases. Sections 2A-106, 2A-108(2), 2A-108(4), 2A-109(2), 2A-221, 2A-309, 2A-406, 2A-407, 2A-504(3)(b), and 2A-516(3)(b).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">For a transaction to qualify as a consumer lease it must first qualify as a lease. Section 2A-103(1)(j). Note that this Article regulates the transactional elements of a lease, including a consumer lease; consumer protection statutes—present and future—, and existing consumer protection decisions are unaffected by this Article. Section 2A-104(1)(c) and (2). Of course, Article 2A as state law also is subject to federal consumer protection law.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">This definition is modeled after the definition of consumer lease in the Consumer Leasing Act,  15 U.S.C. § 1667 (1982), and in the Unif. Consumer Credit Code s 1.301(14), 7A U.L.A. 43 (1974). However, this definition of consumer lease differs from its models in several respects: the lessor can be a person regularly engaged either in the business of leasing or of selling goods, the lease need not be for a term exceeding four months, a lease primarily for an agricultural purpose is not covered and whether there should be a limitation by dollar amount and its amount is left up to the individual states.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">This definition focuses on the parties as well as the transaction. If a lease is within this definition, the lessor must be regularly engaged in the business of leasing or selling, and the lessee must be an individual not an organization; note that a lease to two or more individuals having a common interest through marriage or the like is not excluded as a lease to an organization under  Section 1-201(28). The lessee must take the interest primarily for a personal, family or household purpose. If required by the enacting state, total payments under the lease contract, excluding payments for options to renew or buy, cannot exceed the figure designated.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(f) “Fault”.  Section 1-201(16).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(g) “Finance Lease”. New. This Article includes a subset of rules that applies only to finance leases. Sections 2A-209, 2A-211(2), 2A-212(1), 2A-213, 2A-219(1), 2A-220(1)(a), 2A-221, 2A-405(c), 2A-407, 2A-516(2) and 2A-517(1)(a) and (2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">For a transaction to qualify as a finance lease it must first qualify as a lease. Section 2A-103(1)(j). Unless the lessor is comfortable that the transaction will qualify as a finance lease, the lease agreement should include provisions giving the lessor the benefits created by the subset of rules applicable to the transaction that qualifies as a finance lease under this Article.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">A finance lease is the product of a three party transaction. The supplier manufactures or supplies the goods pursuant to the lessee’s specification, perhaps even pursuant to a purchase order, sales agreement or lease agreement between the supplier and the lessee. After the prospective finance lease is negotiated, a purchase order, sales agreement, or lease agreement is entered into by the lessor (as buyer or prime lessee) or an existing order, agreement or lease is assigned by the lessee to the lessor, and the lessor and the lessee then enter into a lease or sublease of the goods. Due to the limited function usually performed by the lessor, the lessee looks almost entirely to the supplier for representations, covenants and warranties. If a manufacturer’s warranty carries through, the lessee may also look to that. Yet, this definition does not restrict the lessor’s function solely to the supply of funds; if the lessor undertakes or performs other functions, express warranties, covenants and the common law will protect the lessee.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">This definition focuses on the transaction, not the status of the parties; to avoid confusion it is important to note that in other contexts, e.g., tax and accounting, the term finance lease has been used to connote different types of lease transactions, including leases that are disguised secured transactions. M. Rice, Equipment Financing, 62-71 (1981). A lessor who is a merchant with respect to goods of the kind subject to the lease may be a lessor under a finance lease. Many leases that are leases back to the seller of goods (Section 2A-308(3)) will be finance leases. This conclusion is easily demonstrated by a hypothetical. Assume that B has bought goods from C pursuant to a sales contract. After delivery to and acceptance of the goods by B, B negotiates to sell the goods to A and simultaneously to lease the goods back from A, on terms and conditions that, we assume, will qualify the transaction as a lease. Section 2A-103(1)(j). In documenting the sale and lease back, B assigns the original sales contract between B, as buyer, and C, as seller, to A. A review of these facts leads to the conclusion that the lease from A to B qualifies as a finance lease, as all three conditions of the definition are satisfied. Subparagraph (i) is satisfied as A, the lessor, had nothing to do with the selection, manufacture, or supply of the equipment. Subparagraph (ii) is satisfied as A, the lessor, bought the equipment at the same time that A leased the equipment to B, which certainly is in connection with the lease. Finally, subparagraph (iii) (A) is satisfied as A entered into the sales contract with B at the same time that A leased the equipment back to B. B, the lessee, will have received a copy of the sales contract in a timely fashion.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (i) requires the lessor to remain outside the selection, manufacture and supply of the goods; that is the rationale for releasing the lessor from most of its traditional liability. The lessor is not prohibited from possession, maintenance or operation of the goods, as policy does not require such prohibition. To insure the lessee’s reliance on the supplier, and not on the lessor, subsection (ii) requires that the goods (where the lessor is the buyer of the goods) or that the right to possession and use of the goods (where the lessor is the prime lessee and the sublessor of the goods) be acquired in connection with the lease (or sublease) to qualify as a finance lease. The scope of the phrase “in connection with” is to be developed by the courts, case by case. Finally, as the lessee generally relies almost entirely upon the supplier for representations and covenants, and upon the supplier or a manufacturer, or both, for warranties with respect to the goods, subsection (iii) requires that one of the following occur: (A) the lessee receive a copy of the supply contract before signing the lease contract; (B) the lessee’s approval of the supply contract is a condition to the effectiveness of the lease contract; (C) the lessee receive a statement describing the promises and warranties and any limitations relevant to the lessee before signing the lease contract; or (D) before signing the lease contract and except in a consumer lease, the lessee receive a writing identifying the supplier (unless the supplier was selected and required by the lessee) and the rights of the lessee under Section 2A-209, and advising the lessee a statement of promises and warranties is available from the supplier. Thus, even where oral supply orders or computer placed supply orders are compelled by custom and usage the transaction may still qualify as a finance lease if the lessee approves the supply contract before the lease contract is effective and such approval was a condition to the effectiveness of the lease contract. Moreover, where the lessor does not want the lessee to see the entire supply contract, including price information, the lessee may be provided with a separate statement of the terms of the supply contract relevant to the lessee; promises between the supplier and the lessor that do not affect the lessee need not be included. The statement can be a restatement of those terms or a copy of portions of the supply contract with the relevant terms clearly designated. Any implied warranties need not be designated, but a disclaimer or modification of remedy must be designated. A copy of any manufacturer’s warranty is sufficient if that is the warranty provided. However, a copy of any Regulation M disclosure given pursuant to 12 C.F.R. s 213.4(g) concerning warranties in itself is not sufficient since those disclosures need only briefly identify express warranties and need not include any disclaimer of warranty.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">If a transaction does not qualify as a finance lease, the parties may achieve the same result by agreement; no negative implications are to be drawn if the transaction does not qualify. Further, absent the application of special rules (fraud, duress, and the like), a lease that qualifies as a finance lease and is assigned by the lessor or the lessee to a third party does not lose its status as a finance lease under this Article. Finally, this Article creates no special rule where the lessor is an affiliate of the supplier; whether the transaction qualifies as a finance lease will be determined by the facts of each case.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(h) “Goods”.  Section 9-105(1)(h). See Section 2A-103(3) for reference to the definition of “Account”, “Chattel paper”, “Document”, “General intangibles” and “Instrument”. See Section 2A-217 for determination of the time and manner of identification.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(i) “Installment lease contract”.  Section 2-612(1).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(j) “Lease”. New. There are several reasons to codify the law with respect to leases of goods. An analysis of the case law as it applies to leases of goods suggests at least several significant issues to be resolved by codification. First and foremost is the definition of a lease. It is necessary to define lease to determine whether a transaction creates a lease or a security interest disguised as a lease. If the transaction creates a security interest disguised as a lease, the transaction will be governed by the Article on Secured Transactions (Article 9) and the lessor will be required to file a financing statement or take other action to perfect its interest in the goods against third parties. There is no such requirement with respect to leases under the common law and, except with respect to leases of fixtures (Section 2A-309), this Article imposes no such requirement. Yet the distinction between a lease and a security interest disguised as a lease is not clear from the case law at the time of the promulgation of this Article. DeKoven, Leases of Equipment: Puritan Leasing Company v. August, A Dangerous Decision,  12 U.S.F. L.Rev. 257 (1978).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">At common law a lease of personal property is a bailment for hire. While there are several definitions of bailment for hire, all require a thing to be let and a price for the letting. Thus, in modern terms and as provided in this definition, a lease is created when the lessee agrees to furnish consideration for the right to the possession and use of goods over a specified period of time. Mooney, Personal Property Leasing: A Challenge,  36 Bus.Law. 1605, 1607 (1981). Further, a lease is neither a sale ( Section 2-106(1)) nor a retention or creation of a security interest ( Section 1-201(37)). Due to extensive litigation to distinguish true leases from security interests, an amendment to  Section 1-201(37) has been promulgated with this Article to create a sharper distinction.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">This section as well as  Section 1-201(37) must be examined to determine whether the transaction in question creates a lease or a security interest. The following hypotheticals indicate the perimeters of the issue. Assume that A has purchased a number of copying machines, new, for $1,000 each; the machines have an estimated useful economic life of three years. A advertises that the machines are available to rent for a minimum of one month and that the monthly rental is $100.00. A intends to enter into leases where A provides all maintenance, without charge to the lessee. Further, the lessee will rent the machine, month to month, with no obligation to renew. At the end of the lease term the lessee will be obligated to return the machine to A’s place of business. This transaction qualifies as a lease under the first half of the definition, for the transaction includes a transfer by A to a prospective lessee of possession and use of the machine for a stated term, month to month. The machines are goods (Section 2A-103(1)(h)). The lessee is obligated to pay consideration in return, $100.00 for each month of the term.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">However, the second half of the definition provides that a sale or a security interest is not a lease. Since there is no passing of title, there is no sale. Sections 2A-103(3) and 2-106(1). Under pre-Act security law this transaction would have created a bailment for hire or a true lease and not a conditional sale.  Da Rocha v. Macomber, 330 Mass. 611, 614-15, 116 N.E.2d 139, 142 (1953). Under  Section 1-201(37), as amended with the promulgation of this Article, the same result would follow. While the lessee is obligated to pay rent for the one month term of the lease, one of the other four conditions of the second paragraph of  Section 1-201(37) must be met and none is. The term of the lease is one month and the economic life of the machine is 36 months; thus, subparagraph (a) of  Section 1-201(37) is not now satisfied. Considering the amount of the monthly rent, absent economic duress or coercion, the lessee is not bound either to renew the lease for the remaining economic life of the goods or to become the owner. If the lessee did lease the machine for 36 months, the lessee would have paid the lessor $3,600 for a machine that could have been purchased for $1,000; thus, subparagraph (b) of  Section 1-201(37) is not satisfied. Finally, there are no options; thus, subparagraphs (c) and (d) of  Section 1-201(37) are not satisfied. This transaction creates a lease, not a security interest. However, with each renewal of the lease the facts and circumstances at the time of each renewal must be examined to determine if that conclusion remains accurate, as it is possible that a transaction that first creates a lease, later creates a security interest.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Assume that the facts are changed and that A requires each lessee to lease the goods for 36 months, with no right to terminate. Under pre-Act security law this transaction would have created a conditional sale, and not a bailment for hire or true lease.  Hervey v. Rhode Island Locomotive Works, 93 U.S. 664, 672-73 (1876). Under this subsection, and  Section 1-201(37), as amended with the inclusion of this Article in the Act, the same result would follow. The lessee’s obligation for the term is not subject to termination by the lessee and the term is equal to the economic life of the machine.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Between these extremes there are many transactions that can be created. Some of the transactions have not been properly categorized by the courts in applying the 1978 and earlier Official Texts of  Section 1-201(37). This subsection, together with  Section 1-201(37), as amended with the promulgation of this Article, draws a brighter line, which should create a clearer signal to the professional lessor and lessee.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(k) “Lease agreement”. This definition is derived from the first sentence of  Section 1-201(3). Because the definition of lease is broad enough to cover future transfers, lease agreement includes an agreement contemplating a current or subsequent transfer. Thus it was not necessary to make an express reference to an agreement for the future lease of goods ( Section 2-106(1)). This concept is also incorporated in the definition of lease contract. Note that the definition of lease does not include transactions in ordinary building materials that are incorporated into an improvement on land. Section 2A-309(2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The provisions of this Article, if applicable, determine whether a lease agreement has legal consequences; otherwise the law of bailments and other applicable law determine the same. Sections 2A-103(4) and 1-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(l) “Lease contract”. This definition is derived from the definition of contract in  Section 1-201(11). Note that a lease contract may be for the future lease of goods, since this notion is included in the definition of lease.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(m) “Leasehold interest”. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(n) “Lessee”. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(o) “Lessee in ordinary course of business”.  Section 1-201(9).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(p) “Lessor”. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(q) “Lessor’s residual interest”. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(r) “Lien”. New. This term is used in Section 2A-307 (Priority of Liens Arising by Attachment or Levy on, Security Interests in, and Other Claims to Goods).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(s) “Lot”.  Section 2-105(5).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(t) “Merchant lessee”. New. This term is used in Section 2A-511 (Merchant Lessee’s Duties as to Rightfully Rejected Goods). A person may satisfy the requirement of dealing in goods of the kind subject to the lease as lessor, lessee, seller, or buyer.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(u) “Present value”. New. Authorities agree that present value should be used to determine fairly the damages payable by the lessor or the lessee on default.  E.g., Taylor v. Commercial Credit Equip. Corp., 170 Ga.App. 322, 316 S.E.2d 788 (Ct. App. 1984). Present value is defined to mean an amount that represents the discounted value as of a date certain of one or more sums payable in the future. This is a function of the economic principle that a dollar today is more valuable to the holder than a dollar payable in two years. While there is no question as to the principle, reasonable people would differ as to the rate of discount to apply in determining the value of that future dollar today. To minimize litigation, this Article allows the parties to specify the discount or interest rate, if the rate was not manifestly unreasonable at the time the transaction was entered into. In all other cases, the interest rate will be a commercially reasonable rate that takes into account the facts and circumstances of each case, as of the time the transaction was entered into.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(v) “Purchase”.  Section 1-201(32). This definition omits the reference to lien contained in the definition of purchase in Article 1 ( Section 1-201(32)). This should not be construed to exclude consensual liens from the definition of purchase in this Article; the exclusion was mandated by the scope of the definition of lien in Section 2A-103(1)(r). Further, the definition of purchaser in this Article adds a reference to lease; as purchase is defined in  Section 1-201(32) to include any other voluntary transaction creating an interest in property, this addition is not substantive.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(w) “Sublease”. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(x) “Supplier”. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(y) “Supply contract”. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">(z) “Termination”.  Section 2-106(3). The effect of a termination is provided in Section 2A-505(2).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
