<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:3-116</num>
  <heading>Joint and several liability; contribution.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(d), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 5(d), 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Subsection (a) replaces subsection (e) of former  Section 3-118. Subsection (b) states contribution rights of parties with joint and several liability by referring to applicable law. But subsection (b) is subject to  Section 3-419(e). If one of the parties with joint and several liability is an accommodation party and the other is the accommodated party,  Section 3-419(e) applies. Subsection (c) deals with discharge. The discharge of a jointly and severally liable obligor does not affect the right of other obligors to seek contribution from the discharged obligor.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Indorsers normally do not have joint and several liability. Rather, an earlier indorser has liability to a later indorser. But indorsers can have joint and several liability in two cases. If an instrument is payable to two payees jointly, both payees must indorse. The indorsement is a joint indorsement and the indorsers have joint and several liability and subsection (b) applies. The other case is that of two or more anomalous indorsers. The term is defined in  Section 3-205(d). An anomalous indorsement normally indicates that the indorser signed as an accommodation party. If more than one accommodation party indorses a note as an accommodation to the maker, the indorsers have joint and several liability and subsection (b) applies.</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:3-116.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§28:3-103">§ 28:3-103</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
