<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:3-414</num>
  <heading>Obligation of drawer.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This section does not apply to cashier’s checks or other drafts drawn on the drawer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If an unaccepted draft is dishonored, the drawer is obliged to pay the draft (i) according to its terms at the time it was issued or, if not issued, at the time it first came into possession of a holder, or (ii) if the drawer signed an incomplete instrument, according to its terms when completed, to the extent stated in sections 28:3-115 and 28:3-407. The obligation is owed to a person entitled to enforce the draft or to an indorser who paid the draft under section 28:3-415.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a draft is accepted by a bank, the drawer is discharged, regardless of when or by whom acceptance was obtained.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a draft is accepted and the acceptor is not a bank, the obligation of the drawer to pay the draft if the draft is dishonored by the acceptor is the same as the obligation of an indorser under section 28:3-415(a) and (c).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a draft states that it is drawn “without recourse” or otherwise disclaims liability of the drawer to pay the draft, the drawer is not liable under subsection (b) of this section to pay the draft if the draft is not a check. A disclaimer of the liability stated in subsection (b) of this section is not effective if the draft is a check.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If (i) a check is not presented for payment or given to a depositary bank for collection within 30 days after its date, (ii) the drawee suspends payments after expiration of the 30-day period without paying the check, and (iii) because of the suspension of payments, the drawer is deprived of funds maintained with the drawee to cover payment of the check, the drawer to the extent deprived of funds may discharge its obligation to pay the check by assigning to the person entitled to enforce the check the rights of the drawer against the drawee with respect to the funds.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(d), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:3-103">28:3-103</cite>, § <cite path="§28:3-413">28:3-413</cite>, § <cite path="§28:3-503">28:3-503</cite>, and § <cite path="§28:5-108">28:5-108</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:3-414.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text>1. Subsection (a) excludes cashier’s checks because the obligation of the issuer of a cashier’s check is stated in  Section 3-412.</text>
      <text>2. Subsection (b) states the obligation of the drawer on an unaccepted draft. It replaces former  Section 3-413(2). The requirement under former Article 3 of notice of dishonor or protest has been eliminated. Under revised Article 3, notice of dishonor is necessary only with respect to indorser’s liability. The liability of the drawer of an unaccepted draft is treated as a primary liability. Under former  Section 3-102(1)(d) the term “secondary party” was used to refer to a drawer or indorser. The quoted term is not used in revised Article 3. The effect of a draft drawn without recourse is stated in subsection (e).</text>
      <text>3. Under subsection (c) the drawer is discharged of liability on a draft accepted by a bank regardless of when acceptance was obtained. This changes former  Section 3-411(1) which provided that the drawer is discharged only if the holder obtains acceptance.</text>
      <text>Holders that have a bank obligation do not normally rely on the drawer to guarantee the bank’s solvency. A holder can obtain protection against the insolvency of a bank acceptor by a specific guaranty of payment by the drawer or by obtaining an indorsement by the drawer.  Section 3-205(d).</text>
      <text>4. Subsection (d) states the liability of the drawer if a draft is accepted by a drawee other than a bank and the acceptor dishonors. The drawer of an unaccepted draft is the only party liable on the instrument. The drawee has no liability on the draft.  Section 3-408. When the draft is accepted, the obligations change. The drawee, as acceptor, becomes primarily liable and the drawer’s liability is that of a person secondarily liable as a guarantor of payment. The drawer’s liability is identical to that of an indorser, and subsection (d) states the drawer’s liability that way. The drawer is liable to pay the person entitled to enforce the draft or any indorser that pays pursuant to  Section 3-415. The drawer in this case is discharged if notice of dishonor is required by  Section 3-503 and is not given in compliance with that section. A drawer that pays has a right of recourse against the acceptor.  Section 3-413(a).</text>
      <text>5. Subsection (e) does not permit the drawer of a check to avoid liability under subsection (b) by drawing the check without recourse. There is no legitimate purpose served by issuing a check on which nobody is liable. Drawing without recourse is effective to disclaim liability of the drawer if the draft is not a check. Suppose, in a documentary sale, Seller draws a draft on Buyer for the price of goods shipped to Buyer. The draft is payable upon delivery to the drawee of an order bill of lading covering the goods. Seller delivers the draft with the bill of lading to Finance Company that is named as payee of the draft. If Seller draws without recourse Finance Company takes the risk that Buyer will dishonor. If Buyer dishonors, Finance Company has no recourse against Seller but it can obtain reimbursement by selling the goods which it controls through the bill of lading.</text>
      <text>6. Subsection (f) is derived from former  Section 3-502(1)(b). It is designed to protect the drawer of a check against loss resulting from suspension of payments by the drawee bank when the holder of the check delays collection of the check. For example, X writes a check payable to Y for $1,000. The check is covered by funds in X’s account in the drawee bank. Y delays initiation of collection of the check for more than 30 days after the date of the check. The drawee bank suspends payments after the 30-day period and before the check is presented for payment. If the $1,000 of funds in X’s account have not been withdrawn, X has a claim for those funds against the drawee bank and, if subsection (e) were not in effect, X would be liable to Y on the check because the check was dishonored.  Section 3-502(e). If the suspension of payments by the drawee bank will result in payment to X of less than the full amount of the $1,000 in the account or if there is a significant delay in payment to X, X will suffer a loss which would not have been suffered if Y had promptly initiated collection of the check. In most cases, X will not suffer any loss because of the existence of federal bank deposit insurance that covers accounts up to $100,000. Thus, subsection (e) has relatively little importance. There might be some cases, however, in which the account is not fully insured because it exceeds $100,000 or because the account doesn’t qualify for deposit insurance. Subsection (f) retains the phrase “deprived of funds maintained with the drawee“ appearing in former  Section 3-502(1)(b). The quoted phrase applies if the suspension of payments by the drawee prevents the drawer from receiving the benefit of funds which would have paid the check if the holder had been timely in initiating collection. Thus, any significant delay in obtaining full payment of the funds is a deprivation of funds. The drawer can discharge drawer’s liability by assigning rights against the drawee with respect to the funds to the holder.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
