<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:3-105</num>
  <heading>Issue of instrument.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>“Issue” means the first delivery of an instrument by the maker or drawer, whether to a holder or nonholder, for the purpose of giving rights on the instrument to any person.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An unissued instrument, or an unissued incomplete instrument that is completed, is binding on the maker or drawer, but nonissuance is a defense. An instrument that is conditionally issued or is issued for a special purpose is binding on the maker or drawer, but failure of the condition or special purpose to be fulfilled is a defense.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>“Issuer” applies to issued and unissued instruments and means a maker or drawer of an instrument.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(d), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:3-103">28:3-103</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:3-105.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Under former  Section 3-102(1)(a) “issue” was defined as the first delivery to a “holder or a remitter” but the term “remitter” was neither defined nor otherwise used. In revised Article 3,  Section 3-105(a) defines “issue” more broadly to include the first delivery to anyone by the drawer or maker for the purpose of giving rights to anyone on the instrument. “Delivery” with respect to instruments is defined in  Section 1-201(14) as meaning “voluntary transfer of possession.”</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Subsection (b) continues the rule that nonissuance, conditional issuance or issuance for a special purpose is a defense of the maker or drawer of an instrument. Thus, the defense can be asserted against a person other than a holder in due course. The same rule applies to nonissuance of an incomplete instrument later completed.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Subsection (c) defines “issuer” to include the signer of an unissued instrument for convenience of reference in the statute.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
