<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:3-503</num>
  <heading>Notice of dishonor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The obligation of an indorser stated in section 28:3-415(a) and the obligation of a drawer stated in section 28:3-414(d) may not be enforced unless (i) the indorser or drawer is given notice of dishonor of the instrument complying with this section or (ii) notice of dishonor is excused under section 28:3-504(b).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notice of dishonor may be given by any person; may be given by any commercially reasonable means, including an oral, written, or electronic communication; and is sufficient if it reasonably identifies the instrument and indicates that the instrument has been dishonored or has not been paid or accepted.  Return of an instrument given to a bank for collection is sufficient notice of dishonor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to section 28:3-504(c), with respect to an instrument taken for collection by a collecting bank, notice of dishonor must be given (i) by the bank before midnight of the next banking day following the banking day on which the bank receives notice of dishonor of the instrument, or (ii) by any other person within 30 days following the day on which the person receives notice of dishonor. With respect to any other instrument, notice of dishonor must be given within 30 days following the day on which dishonor occurs.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 689, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(d), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:3-415">28:3-415</cite> and § <cite path="§28:4-104">28:4-104</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:3-503.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:3-508.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Subsection (a) is consistent with former  Section 3-501(2)(a), but notice of dishonor is no longer relevant to the liability of a drawer except for the case of a draft accepted by an acceptor other than a bank. Comments 2 and 4 to  Section 3-414. There is no reason why drawers should be discharged on instruments they draw until payment or acceptance. They are entitled to have the instrument presented to the drawee and dishonored ( Section 3-414(b)) before they are liable to pay, but no notice of dishonor need be made to them as a condition of liability. Subsection (b), which states how notice of dishonor is given, is based on former  Section 3-508(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Subsection (c) replaces former  Section 3-508(2). It differs from that section in that it provides a 30-day period for a person other than a collecting bank to give notice of dishonor rather than the three-day period allowed in former Article 3. Delay in giving notice of dishonor may be excused under  Section 3-504(c).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
