<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:3-418</num>
  <heading>Payment or acceptance by mistake.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, if the drawee of a draft pays or accepts the draft and the drawee acted on the mistaken belief that (i) payment of the draft had not been stopped pursuant to section 28:4-403 or (ii) the signature of the drawer of the draft was authorized, the drawee may recover the amount of the draft from the person to whom or for whose benefit payment was made or, in the case of acceptance, may revoke the acceptance. Rights of the drawee under this subsection are not affected by failure of the drawee to exercise ordinary care in paying or accepting the draft.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, if an instrument has been paid or accepted by mistake and the case is not covered by subsection (a) of this section, the person paying or accepting may, to the extent permitted by the law governing mistake and restitution, (i) recover the payment from the person to whom or for whose benefit payment was made or (ii) in the case of acceptance, may revoke the acceptance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The remedies provided by subsection (a) or (b) of this section may not be asserted against a person who took the instrument in good faith and for value or who in good faith changed position in reliance on the payment or acceptance. This subsection does not limit remedies provided by section 28:3-417 or 28:4-407.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding section 28:4-215, if an instrument is paid or accepted by mistake and the payor or acceptor recovers payment or revokes acceptance under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the instrument is deemed not to have been paid or accepted and is treated as dishonored, and the person from whom payment is recovered has rights as a person entitled to enforce the dishonored instrument.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 686, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(d), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:3-301">28:3-301</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:3-418.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:3-418.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. This section covers payment or acceptance by mistake and replaces former  Section 3-418. Under former Article 3, the remedy of a drawee that paid or accepted a draft by mistake was based on the law of mistake and restitution, but that remedy was not specifically stated. It was provided by  Section 1-103. Former  Section 3-418 was simply a limitation on the unstated remedy under the law of mistake and restitution. Under revised Article 3,  Section 3-418 specifically states the right of restitution in subsections (a) and (b). Subsection (a) allows restitution in the two most common cases in which the problem is presented: payment or acceptance of forged checks and checks on which the drawer has stopped payment. If the drawee acted under a mistaken belief that the check was not forged or had not been stopped, the drawee is entitled to recover the funds paid or to revoke the acceptance whether or not the drawee acted negligently. But in each case, by virtue of subsection (c), the drawee loses the remedy if the person receiving payment or acceptance was a person who took the check in good faith and for value or who in good faith changed position in reliance on the payment or acceptance. Subsections (a) and (c) are consistent with former  Section 3-418 and the rule of Price v. Neal. The result in the two cases covered by subsection (a) is that the drawee in most cases will not have a remedy against the person paid because there is usually a person who took the check in good faith and for value or who in good faith changed position in reliance on the payment or acceptance.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. If a check has been paid by mistake and the payee receiving payment did not give value for the check or did not change position in reliance on the payment, the drawee bank is entitled to recover the amount of the check under subsection (a) regardless of how the check was paid. The drawee bank normally pays a check by a credit to an account of the collecting bank that presents the check for payment. The payee of the check normally receives the payment by a credit to the payee’s account in the depositary bank. But in some cases the payee of the check may have received payment directly from the drawee bank by presenting the check for payment over the counter. In those cases the payee is entitled to receive cash, but the payee may prefer another form of payment such as a cashier’s check or teller’s check issued by the drawee bank. Suppose Seller contracted to sell goods to Buyer. The contract provided for immediate payment by Buyer and delivery of the goods 20 days after payment. Buyer paid by mailing a check for $10,000 drawn on Bank payable to Seller. The next day Buyer gave a stop payment order to Bank with respect to the check Buyer had mailed to Seller. A few days later Seller presented Buyer’s check to Bank for payment over the counter and requested a cashier’s check as payment. Bank issued and delivered a cashier’s check for $10,000 payable to Seller. The teller failed to discover Buyer’s stop order. The next day Bank discovered the mistake and immediately advised Seller of the facts. Seller refused to return the cashier’s check and did not deliver any goods to Buyer.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Under  Section 4-215, Buyer’s check was paid by Bank at the time it delivered its cashier’s check to Seller. See Comment 3 to  Section 4-215. Bank is obliged to pay the cashier’s check and has no defense to that obligation. The cashier’s check was issued for consideration because it was issued in payment of Buyer’s check. Although Bank has no defense on its cashier’s check, it may have a right to recover $10,000, the amount of Buyer’s check, from Seller under  Section 3-418(a). Bank paid Buyer’s check by mistake. Seller did not give value for Buyer’s check because the promise to deliver goods to Buyer was never performed.  Section 3-303(a)(1). And, on these facts, Seller did not change position in reliance on the payment of Buyer’s check. Thus, the first sentence of  Section 3-418(c) does not apply and Seller is obliged to return $10,000 to Bank. Bank is obliged to pay the cashier’s check but it has a counterclaim against Seller based on its rights under  Section 3-418(a). This claim can be asserted against Seller, but it cannot be asserted against some other person with rights of a holder in due course of the cashier’s check. A person without rights of a holder in due course of the cashier’s check would take subject to Bank’s claim against Seller because it is a claim in recoupment.  Section 3-305(a)(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">If Bank recovers from Seller under  Section 3-418(a), the payment of Buyer’s check is treated as unpaid and dishonored.  Section 3-418(d). One consequence is that Seller may enforce Buyer’s obligation as drawer to pay the check.  Section 3-414. Another consequence is that Seller’s rights against Buyer on the contract of sale are also preserved. Under  Section 3-310(b) Buyer’s obligation to pay for the goods was suspended when Seller took Buyer’s check and remains suspended until the check is either dishonored or paid. Under  Section 3-310(b)(1)* the obligation is discharged when the check is paid. Since  Section 3-418(d) treats Buyer’s check as unpaid and dishonored, Buyer’s obligation is not discharged and suspension of the obligation terminates. Under  Section 3-310(b)(3), Seller may enforce either the contract of sale or the check subject to defenses and claims of Buyer. * Previous incorrect cross reference corrected by Permanent Editorial Board action November 1992.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">If Seller had released the goods to Buyer before learning about the stop order, Bank would have no recovery against Seller under  Section 3-418(a) because Seller in that case gave value for Buyer’s check.  Section 3-418(c). In this case Bank’s sole remedy is under  Section 4-407 by subrogation.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Subsection (b) covers cases of payment or acceptance by mistake that are not covered by subsection (a). It directs courts to deal with those cases under the law governing mistake and restitution. Perhaps the most important class of cases that falls under subsection (b), because it is not covered by subsection (a), is that of payment by the drawee bank of a check with respect to which the bank has no duty to the drawer to pay either because the drawer has no account with the bank or because available funds in the drawer’s account are not sufficient to cover the amount of the check. With respect to such a case, under Restatement of Restitution s 29, if the bank paid because of a mistaken belief that there were available funds in the drawer’s account sufficient to cover the amount of the check, the bank is entitled to restitution. But s 29 is subject to Restatement of Restitution s 33 which denies restitution if the holder of the check receiving payment paid value in good faith for the check and had no reason to know that the check was paid by mistake when payment was received.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The result in some cases is clear. For example, suppose Father gives Daughter a check for $10,000 as a birthday gift. The check is drawn on Bank in which both Father and Daughter have accounts. Daughter deposits the check in her account in Bank. An employee of Bank, acting under the belief that there were available funds in Father’s account to cover the check, caused Daughter’s account to be credited for $10,000. In fact, Father’s account was overdrawn and Father did not have overdraft privileges. Since Daughter received the check gratuitously there is clear unjust enrichment if she is allowed to keep the $10,000 and Bank is unable to obtain reimbursement from Father. Thus, Bank should be permitted to reverse the credit to Daughter’s account. But this case is not typical. In most cases the remedy of restitution will not be available because the person receiving payment of the check will have given value for it in good faith.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">In some cases, however, it may not be clear whether a drawee bank should have a right of restitution. For example, a check-kiting scheme may involve a large number of checks drawn on a number of different banks in which the drawer’s credit balances are based on uncollected funds represented by fraudulently drawn checks. No attempt is made in  Section 3-418 to state rules for determining the conflicting claims of the various banks that may be victimized by such a scheme. Rather, such cases are better resolved on the basis of general principles of law and the particular facts presented in the litigation.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. The right of the drawee to recover a payment or to revoke an acceptance under  Section 3-418 is not affected by the rules under Article 4 that determine when an item is paid. Even though a payor bank may have paid an item under  Section 4-215, it may have a right to recover the payment under  Section 3-418. National Savings &amp; Trust Co. v. Park Corp., 722 F.2d 1303 (6th Cir.1983)466 U.S. 939 (1984), correctly states the law on the issue under former Article 3. Revised Article 3 does not change the previous law.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
