<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:3-502</num>
  <heading>Dishonor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Dishonor of a note is governed by the following rules:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the note is payable on demand, the note is dishonored if presentment is duly made to the maker and the note is not paid on the day of presentment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the note is not payable on demand and is payable at or through a bank or the terms of the note require presentment, the note is dishonored if presentment is duly made and the note is not paid on the day it becomes payable or the day of presentment, whichever is later.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the note is not payable on demand and paragraph (2) of this subsection does not apply, the note is dishonored if it is not paid on the day it becomes payable.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Dishonor of an unaccepted draft other than a documentary draft is governed by the following rules:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a check is duly presented for payment to the payor bank otherwise than for immediate payment over the counter, the check is dishonored if the payor bank makes timely return of the check or sends timely notice of dishonor or nonpayment under section 28:4-301 or 28:4-302, or becomes accountable for the amount of the check under section 28:4-302.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a draft is payable on demand and paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply, the draft is dishonored if presentment for payment is duly made to the drawee and the draft is not paid on the day of presentment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If a draft is payable on a date stated in the draft, the draft is dishonored if (i) presentment for payment is duly made to the drawee and payment is not made on the day the draft becomes payable or the day of presentment, whichever is later, or (ii) presentment for acceptance is duly made before the day the draft becomes payable and the draft is not accepted on the day of presentment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If a draft is payable on elapse of a period of time after sight or acceptance, the draft is dishonored if presentment for acceptance is duly made and the draft is not accepted on the day of presentment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Dishonor of an unaccepted documentary draft occurs according to the rules stated in subsection (b)(2), (3), and (4) of this section, except that payment or acceptance may be delayed without dishonor until no later than the close of the third business day of the drawee following the day on which payment or acceptance is required by those paragraphs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Dishonor of an accepted draft is governed by the following rules:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the draft is payable on demand, the draft is dishonored if presentment for payment is duly made to the acceptor and the draft is not paid on the day of presentment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the draft is not payable on demand, the draft is dishonored if presentment for payment is duly made to the acceptor and payment is not made on the day it becomes payable or the day of presentment, whichever is later.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>In any case in which presentment is otherwise required for dishonor under this section and presentment is excused under section 28:3-504, dishonor occurs without presentment if the instrument is not duly accepted or paid.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If a draft is dishonored because timely acceptance of the draft was not made and the person entitled to demand acceptance consents to a late acceptance, from the time of acceptance the draft is treated as never having been dishonored.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 689, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(d), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:2-103">28:2-103</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:3-502.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:3-507.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1.  Section 3-415 provides that an indorser is obliged to pay an instrument if the instrument is dishonored and is discharged if the indorser is entitled to notice of dishonor and notice is not given. Under  Section 3-414, the drawer is obliged to pay an unaccepted draft if it is dishonored. The drawer, however, is not entitled to notice of dishonor except to the extent required in a case governed by  Section 3-414(d). Part 5 tells when an instrument is dishonored ( Section 3-502) and what it means to give notice of dishonor ( Section 3-503). Often dishonor does not occur until presentment ( Section 3-501), and frequently presentment and notice of dishonor are excused ( Section 3-504).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. In the great majority of cases presentment and notice of dishonor are waived with respect to notes. In most cases a formal demand for payment to the maker of the note is not contemplated. Rather, the maker is expected to send payment to the holder of the note on the date or dates on which payment is due. If payment is not made when due, the holder usually makes a demand for payment, but in the normal case in which presentment is waived, demand is irrelevant and the holder can proceed against indorsers when payment is not received. Under former Article 3, in the small minority of cases in which presentment and dishonor were not waived with respect to notes, the indorser was discharged from liability (former  Section 3-502(1)(a)) unless the holder made presentment to the maker on the exact day the note was due (former  Section 3-503(1)(c)) and gave notice of dishonor to the indorser before midnight of the third business day after dishonor (former  Section 3-508(2)). These provisions are omitted from Revised Article 3 as inconsistent with practice which seldom involves face-to-face dealings.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Subsection (a) applies to notes. Subsection (a)(1) applies to notes payable on demand. Dishonor requires presentment, and dishonor occurs if payment is not made on the day of presentment. There is no change from previous Article 3. Subsection (a)(2) applies to notes payable at a definite time if the note is payable at or through a bank or, by its terms, presentment is required. Dishonor requires presentment, and dishonor occurs if payment is not made on the due date or the day of presentment if presentment is made after the due date. Subsection (a)(3) applies to all other notes. If the note is not paid on its due date it is dishonored. This allows holders to collect notes in ways that make sense commercially without having to be concerned about a formal presentment on a given day.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Subsection (b) applies to unaccepted drafts other than documentary drafts. Subsection (b)(1) applies to checks. Except for checks presented for immediate payment over the counter, which are covered by subsection (b)(2), dishonor occurs according to rules stated in Article 4. When a check is presented for payment through the check-collection system, the drawee bank normally makes settlement for the amount of the check to the presenting bank. Under  Section 4-301 the drawee bank may recover this settlement if it returns the check within its midnight deadline ( Section 4-104). In that case the check is not paid and dishonor occurs under  Section 3-502(b)(1). If the drawee bank does not return the check or give notice of dishonor or nonpayment within the midnight deadline, the settlement becomes final payment of the check.  Section 4-215. Thus, no dishonor occurs regardless of whether the check is retained or is returned after the midnight deadline. In some cases the drawee bank might not settle for the check when it is received. Under  Section 4-302 if the drawee bank is not also the depositary bank and retains the check without settling for it beyond midnight of the day it is presented for payment, the bank becomes “accountable” for the amount of the check, i.e. it is obliged to pay the amount of the check. If the drawee bank is also the depositary bank, the bank is accountable for the amount of the check if the bank does not pay the check or return it or send notice of dishonor within the midnight deadline. In all cases in which the drawee bank becomes accountable, the check has not been paid and, under  Section 3-502(b)(1), the check is dishonored. The fact that the bank is obliged to pay the check does not mean that the check has been paid. When a check is presented for payment, the person presenting the check is entitled to payment not just the obligation of the drawee to pay. Until that payment is made, the check is dishonored. To say that the drawee bank is obliged to pay the check necessarily means that the check has not been paid. If the check is eventually paid, the drawee bank no longer is accountable.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (b)(2) applies to demand drafts other than those governed by subsection (b)(1). It covers checks presented for immediate payment over the counter and demand drafts other than checks. Dishonor occurs if presentment for payment is made and payment is not made on the day of presentment.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (b)(3) and (4) applies to time drafts. An unaccepted time draft differs from a time note. The maker of a note knows that the note has been issued, but the drawee of a draft may not know that a draft has been drawn on it. Thus, with respect to drafts, presentment for payment or acceptance is required. Subsection (b)(3) applies to drafts payable on a date stated in the draft. Dishonor occurs if presentment for payment is made and payment is not made on the day the draft becomes payable or the day of presentment if presentment is made after the due date. The holder of an unaccepted draft payable on a stated date has the option of presenting the draft for acceptance before the day the draft becomes payable to establish whether the drawee is willing to assume liability by accepting. Under subsection (b)(3)(ii) dishonor occurs when the draft is presented and not accepted. Subsection (b)(4) applies to unaccepted drafts payable on elapse of a period of time after sight or acceptance. If the draft is payable 30 days after sight, the draft must be presented for acceptance to start the running of the 30-day period. Dishonor occurs if it is not accepted. The rules in subsection (b)(3) and (4) follow former  Section 3-501(1)(a).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. Subsection (c) gives drawees an extended period to pay documentary drafts because of the time that may be needed to examine the documents. The period prescribed is that given by  Section 5-112 in cases in which a letter of credit is involved.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">6. Subsection (d) governs accepted drafts. If the acceptor’s obligation is to pay on demand the rule, stated in subsection (d)(1), is the same as for that of a demand note stated in subsection (a)(1). If the acceptor’s obligation is to pay at a definite time the rule, stated in subsection (d)(2), is the same as that of a time note payable at a bank stated in subsection (b)(2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">7. Subsection (e) is a limitation on subsection (a)(1) and (2), subsection (b), subsection (c), and subsection (d). Each of those provisions states dishonor as occurring after presentment. If presentment is excused under  Section 3-504, dishonor occurs under those provisions without presentment if the instrument is not duly accepted or paid.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">8. Under subsection (b)(3)(ii) and (4) if a draft is presented for acceptance and the draft is not accepted on the day of presentment, there is dishonor. But after dishonor, the holder may consent to late acceptance. In that case, under subsection (f), the late acceptance cures the dishonor. The draft is treated as never having been dishonored. If the draft is subsequently presented for payment and payment is refused dishonor occurs at that time.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
