<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:3-416</num>
  <heading>Transfer warranties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who transfers an instrument for consideration warrants to the transferee and, if the transfer is by indorsement, to any subsequent transferee that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The warrantor is a person entitled to enforce the instrument;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All signatures on the instrument are authentic and authorized;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The instrument has not been altered;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The instrument is not subject to a defense or claim in recoupment of any party which can be asserted against the warrantor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The warrantor has no knowledge of any insolvency proceeding commenced with respect to the maker or acceptor or, in the case of an unaccepted draft, the drawer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>With respect to a remotely created consumer item, that the person on whose account the item is drawn authorized the issuance of the item in the amount for which the item is drawn.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person to whom the warranties under subsection (a) of this section are made and who took the instrument in good faith may recover from the warrantor as damages for breach of warranty an amount equal to the loss suffered as a result of the breach, but not more than the amount of the instrument plus expenses and loss of interest incurred as a result of the breach.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The warranties stated in subsection (a) of this section cannot be disclaimed with respect to checks. Unless notice of a claim for breach of warranty is given to the warrantor within 30 days after the claimant has reason to know of the breach and the identity of the warrantor, the liability of the warrantor under subsection (b) of this section is discharged to the extent of any loss caused by the delay in giving notice of the claim.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A cause of action for breach of warranty under this section accrues when the claimant has reason to know of the breach.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 685, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(d), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 5(i), 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:3-416.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:3-416.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-299">D.C. Law 19-299</cite> added (a)(6); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Subsection (a) is taken from subsection (2) of former  Section 3-417. Subsections (3) and (4) of former  Section 3-417 are deleted. Warranties under subsection (a) in favor of the immediate transferee apply to all persons who transfer an instrument for consideration whether or not the transfer is accompanied by indorsement. Any consideration sufficient to support a simple contract will support those warranties. If there is an indorsement the warranty runs with the instrument and the remote holder may sue the indorser-warrantor directly and thus avoid a multiplicity of suits.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Since the purpose of transfer ( Section 3-203(a)) is to give the transferee the right to enforce the instrument, subsection (a)(1) is a warranty that the transferor is a person entitled to enforce the instrument ( Section 3-301). Under  Section 3-203(b) transfer gives the transferee any right of the transferor to enforce the instrument. Subsection (a)(1) is in effect a warranty that there are no unauthorized or missing indorsements that prevent the transferor from making the transferee a person entitled to enforce the instrument.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. The rationale of subsection (a)(4) is that the transferee does not undertake to buy an instrument that is not enforceable in whole or in part, unless there is a contrary agreement. Even if the transferee takes as a holder in due course who takes free of the defense or claim in recoupment, the warranty gives the transferee the option of proceeding against the transferor rather than litigating with the obligor on the instrument the issue of the holder-in-due-course status of the transferee. Subsection (3) of former  Section 3-417 which limits this warranty is deleted. The rationale is that while the purpose of a “no recourse” indorsement is to avoid a guaranty of payment, the indorsement does not clearly indicate an intent to disclaim warranties.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Under subsection (a)(5) the transferor does not warrant against difficulties of collection, impairment of the credit of the obligor or even insolvency. The transferee is expected to determine such questions before taking the obligation. If insolvency proceedings as defined in  Section 1-201(22) have been instituted against the party who is expected to pay and the transferor knows it, the concealment of that fact amounts to a fraud upon the transferee, and the warranty against knowledge of such proceedings is provided accordingly.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. Transfer warranties may be disclaimed with respect to any instrument except a check. Between the immediate parties disclaimer may be made by agreement. In the case of an indorser, disclaimer of transferor’s liability, to be effective, must appear in the indorsement with words such as “without warranties” or some other specific reference to warranties. But in the case of a check, subsection (c) of  Section 3-416 provides that transfer warranties cannot be disclaimed at all. In the check collection process the banking system relies on these warranties.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">6. Subsection (b) states the measure of damages for breach of warranty. There is no express provision for attorney’s fees, but attorney’s fees are not meant to be necessarily excluded. They could be granted because they fit within the phrase “expenses * * * incurred as a result of the breach.“ The intention is to leave to other state law the issue as to when attorney’s fees are recoverable.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">7. Since the traditional term “cause of action” may have been replaced in some states by “claim for relief” or some equivalent term, the words “cause of action” in subsection (d) have been bracketed to indicate that the words may be replaced by an appropriate substitute to conform to local practice.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
