<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:3-301</num>
  <heading>Person entitled to enforce instrument.</heading>
  <text>“Person entitled to enforce” an instrument means (i) the holder of the instrument, (ii) a nonholder in possession of the instrument who has the rights of a holder, or (iii) a person not in possession of the instrument who is entitled to enforce the instrument pursuant to section 28:3-309   or 28:3-418(d)  . A person may be a person entitled to enforce the instrument even though the person is not the owner of the instrument or is in wrongful possession of the instrument.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 680, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(d), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:3-103">28:3-103</cite>, § <cite path="§28:3-308">28:3-308</cite>, and § <cite path="§28:4-104">28:4-104</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:3-301.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:3-301.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">This section replaces former  Section 3-301 that stated the rights of a holder. The rights stated in former  Section 3-301 to transfer, negotiate, enforce, or discharge an instrument are stated in other sections of Article 3. In revised Article 3,  Section 3-301 defines “person entitled to enforce” an instrument. The definition recognizes that enforcement is not limited to holders. The quoted phrase includes a person enforcing a lost or stolen instrument.  Section 3-309. It also includes a person in possession of an instrument who is not a holder. A nonholder in possession of an instrument includes a person that acquired rights of a holder by subrogation or under  Section 3-203(a). It also includes any other person who under applicable law is a successor to the holder or otherwise acquires the holder’s rights.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
