<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28-4101</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Natural disaster” means the actual or imminent consequence of any disaster, catastrophe, or emergency, including fire, other than a fire caused by human error or arson, flood, earthquake, storm, or other serious act of nature, which threatens the health, safety, or welfare of persons or causes damage to property in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Normal average retail price” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>In the case of services, not more than 10% more than the price at which similar services were sold or offered in the Washington Metropolitan Area during the 90-day period that preceded an emergency that resulted from a natural disaster, if an emergency is declared pursuant to § <cite path="§28-4102">28-4102</cite>(b); or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>In the case of merchandise, the price equal to the wholesale cost plus a retail mark-up that is the same percentage over wholesale cost as the retail mark-up for similar merchandise sold in the Washington Metropolitan Area during the 90-day period that immediately preceded an emergency that resulted from a natural disaster, if an emergency has been declared pursuant to § <cite path="§28-4102">28-4102</cite>(b).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Person” means a corporation, firm, agency, company, association, organization, partnership, society, joint stock company, or an individual.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-80" type="History">Mar. 20, 1992, D.C. Law 9-80, § 2, 39 DCR 675</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-68" type="History">Feb. 5, 1994, D.C. Law 10-68, § 27(g), 40 DCR 6311</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-255" type="History">May 16, 1995, D.C. Law 10-255, § 23, 41 DCR 5193</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28-4101.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
