<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:4-503</num>
  <heading>Responsibility of presenting bank for documents and goods; report of reasons for dishonor; referee in case of need.</heading>
  <text>Unless otherwise instructed and except as provided in Article 5, a bank presenting a documentary draft:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Must deliver the documents to the drawee on acceptance of the draft if it is payable more than 3 days after presentment; otherwise, only on payment; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Upon dishonor, either in the case of presentment for acceptance or presentment for payment, may seek and follow instructions from any referee in case of need designated in the draft or, if the presenting bank does not choose to utilize the referee’s services, it must use diligence and good faith to ascertain the reason for dishonor, must notify its transferor of the dishonor and of the results of its effort to ascertain the reasons therefor, and must request instructions. However, the presenting bank is under no obligation with respect to goods represented by the documents except to follow any reasonable instructions seasonably received; it has a right to reimbursement for any expense incurred in following instructions and to prepayment of or indemnity for those expenses.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 707, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(e), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:4-503.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:4-503.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. This section states the rules governing, in the absence of instructions, the duty of the presenting bank in case either of honor or of dishonor of a documentary draft. The section should be read in connection with  Section 2-514 on when documents are deliverable on acceptance, when on payment.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. If the draft is drawn under a letter of credit, Article 5 controls. See  Sections 5-109 through  5-114.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Reason for 1990 Change [<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-249">D.C. Law 10-249</cite>]</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Modified to conform with current drafting practices; no intent to change substance.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
