<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28-4805.05</num>
  <heading>Income taxes.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A tax required to be paid by a trustee based on receipts allocated to income shall be paid from income.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A tax required to be paid by a trustee based on receipts allocated to principal shall be paid from principal, even if the tax is called an income tax by the taxing authority.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A tax required to be paid by a trustee on the trust’s share of an entity’s taxable income shall be paid:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>From income to the extent that receipts from the entity are allocated only to income;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>From principal to the extent that receipts from the entity are allocated only to principal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Proportionately from principal and income to the extent that receipts from the entity are allocated to both income and principal; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>From principal to the extent that the tax exceeds the total receipts from the entity.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>After applying subsections (a) through (c) of this section, the trustee shall adjust income or principal receipts to the extent that the trust’s taxes are reduced because the trust receives a deduction for payments made to a beneficiary.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-292">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-292, § 502(c), 48 DCR 2087</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-197">July 23, 2010, D.C. Law 18-197, § 2(c), 57 DCR 4524</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-197">D.C. Law 18-197</cite> rewrote subsecs. (c) and (d).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 505 of the Uniform Principal and Income Act (1997 Act).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
