<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:4-215</num>
  <heading>Final payment of item by payor bank; when provisional debits and credits become final; when certain credits become available for withdrawal.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An item is finally paid by a payor bank when the bank has first done any of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Paid the item in cash;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Settled for the item without having a right to revoke the settlement under statute, clearing-house rule, or agreement; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Made a provisional settlement for the item and failed to revoke the settlement in the time and manner permitted by statute, clearing-house rule, or agreement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If provisional settlement for an item does not become final, the item is not finally paid.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If provisional settlement for an item between the presenting and payor banks is made through a clearing house or by debits or credits in an account between them, then to the extent that provisional debits or credits for the item are entered in accounts between the presenting and payor banks or between the presenting and successive prior collecting banks seriatim, they become final upon final payment of the items by the payor bank.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a collecting bank receives a settlement for an item which is or becomes final, the bank is accountable to its customer for the amount of the item and any provisional credit given for the item in an account with its customer becomes final.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subject to (i) applicable law stating a time for availability of funds and (ii) any right of the bank to apply the credit to an obligation of the customer, credit given by a bank for an item in a customer’s account becomes available for withdrawal as of right:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the bank has received a provisional settlement for the item, when the settlement becomes final and the bank has had a reasonable time to receive return of the item and the item has not been received within that time; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the bank is both the depositary bank and the payor bank, and the item is finally paid, at the opening of the bank’s second banking day following receipt of the item.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Subject to applicable law stating a time for availability of funds and any right of a bank to apply a deposit to an obligation of the depositor, a deposit of money becomes available for withdrawal as of right at the opening of the bank’s next banking day after receipt of the deposit.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 703, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(e), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:3-418">28:3-418</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:4-215.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:4-213.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. By the definition and use of the term “settle” ( Section 4-104(a)(11)) this Article recognizes that various debits or credits, remittances, settlements or payments given for an item may be either provisional or final, that settlements sometimes are provisional and sometimes are final and sometimes are provisional for awhile but later become final. Subsection (a) defines when settlement for an item constitutes final payment.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Final payment of an item is important for a number of reasons. It is one of several factors determining the relative priorities between items and notices, stop-payment orders, legal process and setoffs ( Section 4-303). It is the “end of the line” in the collection process and the “turn around” point commencing the return flow of proceeds. It is the point at which many provisional settlements become final. See  Section 4-215(c). Final payment of an item by the payor bank fixes preferential rights under  Section 4-216.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. If an item being collected moves through several states, e.g., is deposited for collection in California, moves through two or three California banks to the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco, to the Federal Reserve Bank of Boston, to a payor bank in Maine, the collection process involves the eastward journey of the item from California to Maine and the westward journey of the proceeds from Maine to California. Subsection (a) recognizes that final payment does not take place, in this hypothetical case, on the journey of the item eastward. It also adopts the view that neither does final payment occur on the journey westward because what in fact is journeying westward are proceeds of the item.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Traditionally and under various decisions payment in cash of an item by a payor bank has been considered final payment. Subsection (a)(1) recognizes and provides that payment of an item in cash by a payor bank is final payment.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4.  Section 4-104(a)(11) defines “settle” as meaning “to pay in cash, by clearing-house settlement, in a charge or credit or by remittance, or otherwise as agreed. A settlement may be either provisional or final.“ Subsection (a)(2) of  Section 4-215 provides that an item is finally paid by a payor bank when the bank has “settled for the item without having a right to revoke the settlement under statute, clearing-house rule or agreement.“ Former subsection (1)(b) is modified by subsection (a)(2) to make clear that a payor bank cannot make settlement provisional by unilaterally reserving a right to revoke the settlement. The right must come from a statute (e.g.,  Section 4-301), clearing-house rule or other agreement. Subsection (a)(2) provides in effect that if the payor bank finally settles for an item this constitutes final payment of the item. The subsection operates if nothing has occurred and no situation exists making the settlement provisional. If under statute, clearing-house rule or agreement, a right of revocation of the settlement exists, the settlement is provisional. Conversely, if there is an absence of a right to revoke under statute, clearing-house rule or agreement, the settlement is final and such final settlement constitutes final payment of the item.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">A primary example of a statutory right on the part of the payor bank to revoke a settlement is the right to revoke conferred by  Section 4-301. The underlying theory and reason for deferred posting statutes ( Section 4-301) is to require a settlement on the date of receipt of an item but to keep that settlement provisional with the right to revoke prior to the midnight deadline. In any case in which  Section 4-301 is applicable, any settlement by the payor bank is provisional solely by virtue of the statute, subsection (a)(2) of  Section 4-215 does not operate, and such provisional settlement does not constitute final payment of the item.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">With respect to checks, Regulation CC Section 229.36(d) provides that settlement between banks for the forward collection of checks is final. The relationship of this provision to Article 4 is discussed in the Commentary to that section.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">A second important example of a right to revoke a settlement is that arising under clearing-house rules. It is very common for clearing-house rules to provide that items exchanged and settled for in a clearing (e.g., before 10:00 a.m. on Monday) may be returned and the settlements revoked up to but not later than 2:00 p.m. on the same day (Monday) or under deferred posting at some hour on the next business day (e.g., 2:00 p.m. Tuesday). Under this type of rule the Monday morning settlement is provisional and being provisional does not constitute a final payment of the item.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">An example of an agreement allowing the payor bank to revoke a settlement is a case in which the payor bank is also the depositary bank and has signed a receipt or duplicate deposit ticket or has made an entry in a passbook acknowledging receipt, for credit to the account of A, of a check drawn on it by B. If the receipt, deposit ticket, passbook or other agreement with A is to the effect that any credit so entered is provisional and may be revoked pending the time required by the payor bank to process the item to determine if it is in good form and there are funds to cover it, the agreement keeps the receipt or credit provisional and avoids its being either final settlement or final payment.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The most important application of subsection (a)(2) is that in which presentment of an item has been made over the counter for immediate payment. In this case  Section 4-301(a) does not apply to make the settlement provisional, and final payment has occurred unless a rule or agreement provides otherwise.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. Former  Section 4-213(1)(c) provided that final payment occurred when the payor bank completed the “process of posting.” The term was defined in former  Section 4-109. In the present Article,  Section 4-109 has been deleted and the process-of-posting test has been abandoned in  Section 4-215(a) for determining when final payment is made. Difficulties in determining when the events described in former  Section 4-109 take place make the process-of-posting test unsuitable for a system of automated check collection or electronic presentment.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">6. The last sentence of former  Section 4-213(1) is deleted as an unnecessary source of confusion. Initially the view that payor bank may be accountable for, that is, liable for the amount of, an item that it has already paid seems incongruous. This is particularly true in the light of the language formerly found in  Section 4-302 stating that the payor bank can defend against liability for accountability by showing that it has already settled for the item. But, at least with respect to former  Section 4-213(1)(c), such a provision was needed because under the process-of-posting test a payor bank may have paid an item without settling for it. Now that Article 4 has abandoned the process-of-posting test, the sentence is no longer needed. If the payor bank has neither paid the item nor returned it within its midnight deadline, the payor bank is accountable under  Section 4-302.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">7. Subsection (a)(3) covers the situation in which the payor bank makes a provisional settlement for an item, and this settlement becomes final at a later time by reason of the failure of the payor bank to revoke it in the time and manner permitted by statute, clearing-house rule or agreement. An example of this type of situation is the clearing-house settlement referred to in Comment 4. In the illustration there given if the time limit for the return of items received in the Monday morning clearing is 2:00 p.m. on Tuesday and the provisional settlement has not been revoked at that time in a manner permitted by the clearing-house rules, the provisional settlement made on Monday morning becomes final at 2:00 p.m. on Tuesday. Subsection (a)(3) provides specifically that in this situation the item is finally paid at 2:00 p.m. Tuesday. If on the other hand a payor bank receives an item in the mail on Monday and makes some provisional settlement for the item on Monday, it has until midnight on Tuesday to return the item or give notice and revoke any settlement under  Section 4-301. In this situation subsection (a)(3) of  Section 4-215 provides that if the provisional settlement made on Monday is not revoked before midnight on Tuesday as permitted by  Section 4-301, the item is finally paid at midnight on Tuesday. With respect to checks, Regulation CC Section 229.30(c) allows an extension of the midnight deadline under certain circumstances. If a bank does not expeditiously return a check liability may accrue under Regulation CC Section 229.38. For the relationship of that liability to responsibility under this Article, see Regulation CC Sections 229.30 and 229.38.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">8. Subsection (b) relates final settlement to final payment under  Section 4-215. For example, if a payor bank makes provisional settlement for an item by sending a cashier’s or teller’s check and that settlement fails to become final under  Section 4-213(c), subsection (b) provides that final payment has not occurred. If the item is not paid, the drawer remains liable, and under  Section 4-302(a) the payor bank is accountable unless it has returned the item before its midnight deadline. In this regard, subsection (b) is an exception to subsection (a)(3). Even if the payor bank has not returned an item by its midnight deadline there is still no final payment if provisional settlement had been made and settlement failed to become final. However, if presentment of the item was over the counter for immediate payment, final payment has occurred under  Section 4-215(a)(2). Subsection (b) does not apply because the settlement was not provisional.  Section 4-301(a). In this case the presenting person, often the payee of the item, has the right to demand cash or the cash equivalent of federal reserve credit. If the presenting person accepts another medium of settlement such as a cashier’s or teller’s check, the presenting person takes the risk that the payor bank may fail to pay a cashier’s check because of insolvency or that the drawee of a teller’s check may dishonor it.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">9. Subsection (c) states the country-wide usage that when the item is finally paid by the payor bank under subsection (a) this final payment automatically without further action “firms up” other provisional settlements made for it. However, the subsection makes clear that this “firming up” occurs only if the settlement between the presenting and payor banks was made either through a clearing house or by debits and credits in accounts between them. It does not take place if the payor bank remits for the item by sending some form of remittance instrument. Further, the “firming up” continues only to the extent that provisional debits and credits are entered seriatim in accounts between banks which are successive to the presenting bank. The automatic “firming up” is broken at any time that any collecting bank remits for the item by sending a remittance draft, because final payment to the remittee then usually depends upon final payment of the remittance draft.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">10. Subsection (d) states the general rule that if a collecting bank receives settlement for an item which is or becomes final, the bank is accountable to its customer for the amount of the item. One means of accounting is to remit to its customer the amount it has received on the item. If previously it gave to its customer a provisional credit for the item in an account its receipt of final settlement for the item “firms up” this provisional credit and makes it final. When this credit given by it so becomes final, in the usual case its agency status terminates and it becomes a debtor to its customer for the amount of the item. See  Section 4-201(a). If the accounting is by a remittance instrument or authorization to charge further time will usually be required to complete its accounting ( Section 4-213).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">11. Subsection (e) states when certain credits given by a bank to its customer become available for withdrawal as of right. Subsection (e)(1) deals with the situation in which a bank has given a credit (usually provisional) for an item to its customer and in turn has received a provisional settlement for the item from an intermediary or payor bank to which it has forwarded the item. In this situation before the provisional credit entered by the collecting bank in the account of its customer becomes available for withdrawal as of right, it is not only necessary that the provisional settlement received by the bank for the item becomes final but also that the collecting bank has a reasonable time to receive return of the item and the item has not been received within that time. How much time is “reasonable” for these purposes will of course depend on the distance the item has to travel and the number of banks through which it must pass (having in mind not only travel time by regular lines of transmission but also the successive midnight deadlines of the several banks) and other pertinent facts. Also, if the provisional settlement received is some form of a remittance instrument or authorization to charge, the “reasonable” time depends on the identity and location of the payor of the remittance instrument, the means for clearing such instrument, and other pertinent facts. With respect to checks Regulation CC Sections 229.10-229.13 or similar applicable state law (Section 229.20) control. This is also time for the situation described in Comment 12.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">12. Subsection (e)(2) deals with the situation of a bank that is both a depositary bank and a payor bank. The subsection recognizes that if A and B are both customers of a depositary-payor bank and A deposits B’s check on the depositary-payor in A’s account on Monday, time must be allowed to permit the check under the deferred posting rules of  Section 4-301 to reach the bookkeeper for B’s account at some time on Tuesday, and, if there are insufficient funds in B’s account, to reverse or charge back the provisional credit in A’s account. Consequently this provisional credit in A’s account does not become available for withdrawal as of right until the opening of business on Wednesday. If it is determined on Tuesday that there are insufficient funds in B’s account to pay the check, the credit to A’s account can be reversed on Tuesday. On the other hand if the item is in fact paid on Tuesday, the rule of subsection (e)(2) is desirable to avoid uncertainty and possible disputes between the bank and its customer as to exactly what hour within the day the credit is available.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Reason for 1990 Change [<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-249">D.C. Law 10-249</cite>]</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (a)(2) is amended to provide that a payor bank cannot make settlement provisional by unilaterally reserving a right to revoke the settlement. The right to revoke must come from a statute (e.g.,  Section 4-301), clearing-house rule or other agreement.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Former subsection (1)(c) is deleted for the reason stated in the Reason for 1990 Change for former  Section 4-109. Subsection (a)(3) is amended to remove the final sentence as an unnecessary source of confusion. Initially the view that payor bank may be accountable for, that is, liable for the amount of, an item that it has already paid seems incongruous. This is particularly true in the light of the language formerly found in former  Section 4-302 stating that the payor bank can defend against liability for accountability by showing that it has already settled for the item. But, at least with respect to former  Section 4-213(1)(c), such a provision was needed because under the process-of-posting test a payor bank may have paid an item without settling for it. Now that Article 4 has abandoned the process-of-posting test, the sentence is no longer needed. If the payor bank has neither paid the item not returned it within its midnight deadline, the payor bank is accountable under  Section 4-302.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (b) was added to clarify the relationship of final settlement to final payment under  Section 4-215. For example, if a payor bank makes provisional settlement for an item by sending a cashier’s or teller’s check and that settlement fails to become final under  Section 4-213(c), subsection (b) provides that final payment has not occurred. Under  Section 4-302(a) the payor bank is accountable unless it has returned the item before its midnight deadline. In this regard, subsection (b) is an exception to subsection (a)(3). Even if the payor bank has not returned an item by its midnight deadline there is still no final payment if provisional settlement had been made and settlement failed to become final. However, if presentment of the item was over the counter for immediate payment, final payment has occurred under  Section 4-215(a)(2). Subsection (b) does not apply because the settlement was not provisional.  Section 4-301(a). In this case the presenting person, often the payee of the item, has the right to demand cash or the cash equivalent of federal reserve credit. If the presenting person accepts another medium of settlement such as a cashier’s or teller’s check, the presenting person takes the risk that the payor bank may fail to pay a cashier’s check because of insolvency or that the drawee of a teller’s check may dishonor it.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (d) is amended to delete the cross references to former  Sections 4-211 and  4-213. The reason for the deletion is to remove any implication that final settlement is determined by only those provisions. See Reasons for 1990 Change for  Section 4-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The preamble to subsection (e), as well as subsection (f), is amended to recognize that Regulation CC Sections 229.10-229.13 and the laws of several states (Regulation CC Section 229.20) prescribe times for availability of a depositor’s funds. Subsections (e) and (f) are expressly made subject to these funds availability laws. Paragraph (1) of subsection (e) is amended to delete the test that a customer may withdraw funds after the bank has had a reasonable time to “learn that the settlement is final.” The depositary bank may never affirmatively learn that a settlement is final. The substituted test is that the bank may delay making funds available to a customer until it has had a reasonable time to receive return of the item and the item has not been returned. The other modifications are made to conform with current legislative drafting practices, with no intent to change substance.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
