<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:4-207</num>
  <heading>Transfer warranties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A customer or collecting bank that transfers an item and receives a settlement or other consideration warrants to the transferee and to any subsequent collecting bank that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The warrantor is a person entitled to enforce the item;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All signatures on the item are authentic and authorized;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The item has not been altered;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The item is not subject to a defense or claim in recoupment (section 28:3-305(a)) of any party that can be asserted against the warrantor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The warrantor has no knowledge of any insolvency proceeding commenced with respect to the maker or acceptor or, in the case of an unaccepted draft, the drawer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>With respect to any remotely created consumer item, that the person on whose account the item is drawn authorized the issuance of the item in the amount for which the item is drawn.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If an item is dishonored, a customer or collecting bank transferring the item and receiving settlement or other consideration is obliged to pay the amount due on the item (i) according to the terms of the item at the time it was transferred, or (ii) if the transfer was of an incomplete item, according to its terms when completed as stated in sections 28:3-115 and 28:3-407. The obligation of a transferor is owed to the transferee and to any subsequent collecting bank that takes the item in good faith. A transferor cannot disclaim its obligation under this subsection by an indorsement stating that it is made “without recourse” or otherwise disclaiming liability.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person to whom the warranties under subsection (a) of this section are made and who took the item in good faith may recover from the warrantor as damages for breach of warranty an amount equal to the loss suffered as a result of the breach, but not more than the amount of the item plus expenses and loss of interest incurred as a result of the breach.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The warranties stated in subsection (a) of this section cannot be disclaimed with respect to checks. Unless notice of a claim for breach of warranty is given to the warrantor within 30 days after the claimant has reason to know of the breach and the identity of the warrantor, the warrantor is discharged to the extent of any loss caused by the delay in giving notice of the claim.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A cause of action for breach of warranty under this section accrues when the claimant has reason to know of the breach.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 699, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(e), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 6(d), 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:4-207.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:4-207.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-299">D.C. Law 19-299</cite> added (a)(6); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Except for subsection (b), this section conforms to  Section 3-416 and extends its coverage to items. The substance of this section is discussed in the Comment to  Section 3-416. Subsection (b) provides that customers or collecting banks that transfer items, whether by indorsement or not, undertake to pay the item if the item is dishonored. This obligation cannot be disclaimed by a “without recourse” indorsement or otherwise. With respect to checks, Regulation CC Section 229.34 states the warranties made by paying and returning banks.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
