<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:4-504</num>
  <heading>Privilege of presenting bank to deal with goods; security interest for expenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A presenting bank that, following the dishonor of a documentary draft, has seasonably requested instructions but does not receive them within a reasonable time may store, sell, or otherwise deal with the goods in any reasonable manner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For its reasonable expenses incurred by action under subsection (a) of this section, the presenting bank has a lien upon the goods or their proceeds, which may be foreclosed in the same manner as an unpaid seller’s lien.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 708, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(e), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:4-504.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:4-504.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The section gives the presenting bank, after dishonor, a privilege to deal with the goods in any commercially reasonable manner pending instructions from its transferor and, if still unable to communicate with its principal after a reasonable time, a right to realize its expenditures as if foreclosing on an unpaid seller’s lien ( Section 2-706). The provision includes situations in which storage of goods or other action becomes commercially necessary pending receipt of any requested instructions, even if the requested instructions are later received.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The “reasonable manner” referred to means one reasonable in the light of business factors and the judgment of a business man.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Reason for 1990 Change [<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-249">D.C. Law 10-249</law-cite>]</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Modified to conform with current drafting practices; no intent to change substance.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
