<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:4A-209</num>
  <heading>Acceptance of payment order.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (d) of this section, a receiving bank other than the beneficiary’s bank accepts a payment order when it executes the order.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsections (c) and (d) of this section, a beneficiary’s bank accepts a payment order at the earliest of the following times:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When the bank (i) pays the beneficiary as stated in <cite path="§28:4A-405|(a)">§ 28:4A-405(a)</cite> or <cite path="§28:4A-405|(b)">§ 28:4A-405(b)</cite>, or (ii) notifies the beneficiary of receipt of the order or that the account of the beneficiary has been credited with respect to the order unless the notice indicates that the bank is rejecting the order or that funds with respect to the order may not be withdrawn or used until receipt of payment from the sender of the order;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When the bank receives payment of the entire amount of the sender’s order pursuant to <cite path="§28:4A-403|(a)|(1)">§ 28:4A-403(a)(1)</cite> or <cite path="§28:4A-403|(a)|(2)">§ 28:4A-403(a)(2)</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The opening of the next funds-transfer business day of the bank following the payment date of the order if, at that time, the amount of the sender’s order is fully covered by a withdrawable credit balance in an authorized account of the sender or the bank has otherwise received full payment from the sender, unless the order was rejected before that time or is rejected within (i) one hour after that time, or (ii) one hour after the opening of the next business day of the sender following the payment date if that time is later. If notice of rejection is received by the sender after the payment date and the authorized account of the sender does not bear interest, the bank is obliged to pay interest to the sender on the amount of the order for the number of days elapsing after the payment date to the day the sender receives notice or learns that the order was not accepted, counting that day as an elapsed day. If the withdrawable credit balance during that period falls below the amount of the order, the amount of interest payable is reduced accordingly.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Acceptance of a payment order cannot occur before the order is received by the receiving bank. Acceptance does not occur under subsection (b)(2) or (b)(3) of this section if the beneficiary of the payment order does not have an account with the receiving bank, the account has been closed, or the receiving bank is not permitted by law to receive credits for the beneficiary’s account.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A payment order issued to the originator’s bank cannot be accepted until the payment date if the bank is the beneficiary’s bank, or the execution date if the bank is not the beneficiary’s bank. If the originator’s bank executes the originator’s payment order before the execution date or pays the beneficiary of the originator’s payment order before the payment date and the payment order is subsequently cancelled pursuant to <cite path="§28:4A-211|(b)">§ 28:4A-211(b)</cite>, the bank may recover from the beneficiary any payment received to the extent allowed by the law governing mistake and restitution.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-95" type="History">Apr. 30, 1992, D.C. Law 9-95, § 2(c), 39 DCR 1595</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. This section treats the sender’s payment order as a request by the sender to the receiving bank to execute or pay the order and that request can be accepted or rejected by the receiving bank. Section 4A-209 defines when acceptance occurs. Section 4A-210 covers rejection. Acceptance of the payment order imposes an obligation on the receiving bank to the sender if the receiving bank is not the beneficiary’s bank, or to the beneficiary if the receiving bank is the beneficiary’s bank. These obligations are stated in Section 4A-302 and Section 4A-404.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Acceptance by a receiving bank other than the beneficiary’s bank is defined in Section 4A-209(a). That subsection states the only way that a bank other than the beneficiary’s bank can accept a payment order. A payment order to a bank other than the beneficiary’s bank is, in effect, a request that the receiving bank execute the sender’s order by issuing a payment order to the beneficiary’s bank or to an intermediary bank. Normally, acceptance occurs at the time of execution, but there is an exception stated in subsection (d) and discussed in Comment 9. Execution occurs when the receiving bank “issues a payment order intended to carry out“ the sender’s order. Section 4A-301(a). In some cases the payment order issued by the receiving bank may not conform to the sender’s order. For example, the receiving bank might make a mistake in the amount of its order, or the order might be issued to the wrong beneficiary’s bank or for the benefit of the wrong beneficiary. In all of these cases there is acceptance of the sender’s order by the bank when the receiving bank issues its order intended to carry out the sender’s order, even though the bank’s payment order does not in fact carry out the instruction of the sender. Improper execution of the sender’s order may lead to liability to the sender for damages or it may mean that the sender is not obliged to pay its payment order. These matters are covered in Section 4A-303, Section 4A-305, and Section 4A-402.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. A receiving bank has no duty to accept a payment order unless the bank makes an agreement, either before or after issuance of the payment order, to accept it, or acceptance is required by a funds transfer system rule. If the bank makes such an agreement it incurs a contractual obligation based on the agreement and may be held liable for breach of contract if a failure to execute violates the agreement. In many cases a bank will enter into an agreement with its customer to govern the rights and obligations of the parties with respect to payment orders issued to the bank by the customer or, in cases in which the sender is also a bank, there may be a funds transfer system rule that governs the obligations of a receiving bank with respect to payment orders transmitted over the system. Such agreements or rules can specify the circumstances under which a receiving bank is obliged to execute a payment order and can define the extent of liability of the receiving bank for breach of the agreement or rule. Section 4A-305(d) states the liability for breach of an agreement to execute a payment order.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. In the case of a payment order issued to the beneficiary’s bank, acceptance is defined in Section 4A-209(b). The function of a beneficiary’s bank that receives a payment order is different from that of a receiving bank that receives a payment order for execution. In the typical case, the beneficiary’s bank simply receives payment from the sender of the order, credits the account of the beneficiary and notifies the beneficiary of the credit. Acceptance by the beneficiary’s bank does not create any obligation to the sender. Acceptance by the beneficiary’s bank means that the bank is liable to the beneficiary for the amount of the order. Section 4A-404(a). There are three ways in which the beneficiary’s bank can accept a payment order which are described in the following comments.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. Under Section 4A-209(b)(1), the beneficiary’s bank can accept a payment order by paying the beneficiary. In the normal case of crediting an account of the beneficiary, payment occurs when the beneficiary is given notice of the right to withdraw the credit, the credit is applied to a debt of the beneficiary, or “funds with respect to the order” are otherwise made available to the beneficiary. Section 4A-405(a). The quoted phrase covers cases in which funds are made available to the beneficiary as a result of receipt of a payment order for the benefit of the beneficiary but the release of funds is not expressed as payment of the order. For example, the beneficiary’s bank might express a release of funds equal to the amount of the order as a “loan” that will be automatically repaid when the beneficiary’s bank receives payment by the sender of the order. If the release of funds is designated as a loan pursuant to a routine practice of the bank, the release is conditional payment of the order rather than a loan, particularly if normal incidents of a loan such as the signing of a loan agreement or note and the payment of interest are not present. Such a release of funds is payment to the beneficiary under Section 4A-405(a). Under Section 4A-405(c) the bank cannot recover the money from the beneficiary if the bank does not receive payment from the sender of the payment order that it accepted. Exceptions to this rule are stated in s 4A-405(d) and (e). The beneficiary’s bank may also accept by notifying the beneficiary that the order has been received. “Notifies” is defined in  Section 1-201(26). In some cases a beneficiary’s bank will receive a payment order during the day but settlement of the sender’s obligation to pay the order will not occur until the end of the day. If the beneficiary’s bank wants to defer incurring liability to the beneficiary until the beneficiary’s bank receives payment, it can do so. The beneficiary’s bank incurs no liability to the beneficiary with respect to a payment order that it receives until it accepts the order. If the bank does not accept pursuant to subsection (b)(1), acceptance does not occur until the end of the day when the beneficiary’s bank receives settlement. If the sender settles, the payment order will be accepted under subsection (b)(2) and the funds will be released to the beneficiary the next morning. If the sender doesn’t settle, no acceptance occurs. In either case the beneficiary’s bank suffers no loss.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">6. In most cases the beneficiary’s bank will receive a payment order from another bank. If the sender is a bank and the beneficiary’s bank receives payment from the sender by final settlement through the Federal Reserve System or a funds transfer system (Section 4A-403(a)(1)) or, less commonly, through credit to an account of the beneficiary’s bank with the sender or another bank (Section 4A-403(a)(2)), acceptance by the beneficiary’s bank occurs at the time payment is made. Section 4A-209(b)(2). A minor exception to this rule is stated in Section 4A-209(c). Section 4A-209(b)(2) results in automatic acceptance of payment orders issued to a beneficiary’s bank by means of Fedwire because the Federal Reserve account of the beneficiary’s bank is credited and final payment is made to that bank when the payment order is received.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (b)(2) would also apply to cases in which the beneficiary’s bank mistakenly pays a person who is not the beneficiary of the payment order issued to the beneficiary’s bank. For example, suppose the payment order provides for immediate payment to Account #12345. The beneficiary’s bank erroneously credits Account #12346 and notifies the holder of that account of the credit. No acceptance occurs in this case under subsection (b)(1) because the beneficiary of the order has not been paid or notified. The holder of Account #12345 is the beneficiary of the order issued to the beneficiary’s bank. But acceptance will normally occur if the beneficiary’s bank takes no other action, because the bank will normally receive settlement with respect to the payment order. At that time the bank has accepted because the sender paid its payment order. The bank is liable to pay the holder of Account #12345. The bank has paid the holder of Account #12346 by mistake, and has a right to recover the payment if the credit is withdrawn, to the extent provided in the law governing mistake and restitution.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">7. Subsection (b)(3) covers cases of inaction by the beneficiary’s bank. It applies whether or not the sender is a bank and covers a case in which the sender and the beneficiary both have accounts with the receiving bank and payment will be made by debiting the account of the sender and crediting the account of the beneficiary. Subsection (b)(3) is similar to subsection (b)(2) in that it bases acceptance by the beneficiary’s bank on payment by the sender. Payment by the sender is effected by a debit to the sender’s account if the account balance is sufficient to cover the amount of the order. On the payment date (Section 4A-401) of the order the beneficiary’s bank will normally credit the beneficiary’s account and notify the beneficiary of receipt of the order if it is satisfied that the sender’s account balance covers the order or is willing to give credit to the sender. In some cases, however, the bank may not be willing to give credit to the sender and it may not be possible for the bank to determine until the end of the day on the payment date whether there are sufficient good funds in the sender’s account. There may be various transactions during the day involving funds going into and out of the account. Some of these transactions may occur late in the day or after the close of the banking day. To accommodate this situation, subsection (b)(3) provides that the status of the account is determined at the opening of the next funds transfer business day of the beneficiary’s bank after the payment date of the order. If the sender’s account balance is sufficient to cover the order, the beneficiary’s bank has a source of payment and the result in almost all cases is that the bank accepts the order at that time if it did not previously accept under subsection (b)(1). In rare cases, a bank may want to avoid acceptance under subsection (b)(3) by rejecting the order as discussed in Comment 8.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">8. Section 4A-209 is based on a general principle that a receiving bank is not obliged to accept a payment order unless it has agreed or is bound by a funds transfer system rule to do so. Thus, provision is made to allow the receiving bank to prevent acceptance of the order. This principle is consistently followed if the receiving bank is not the beneficiary’s bank. If the receiving bank is not the beneficiary’s bank, acceptance is in the control of the receiving bank because it occurs only if the order is executed. But in the case of the beneficiary’s bank acceptance can occur by passive receipt of payment under subsection (b)(2) or (3). In the case of a payment made by Fedwire acceptance cannot be prevented. In other cases the beneficiary’s bank can prevent acceptance by giving notice of rejection to the sender before payment occurs under Section 4A-403(a)(1) or (2). A minor exception to the ability of the beneficiary’s bank to reject is stated in Section 4A-502(c)(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Under subsection (b)(3) acceptance occurs at the opening of the next funds transfer business day of the beneficiary’s bank following the payment date unless the bank rejected the order before that time or it rejects within one hour after that time. In some cases the sender and the beneficiary’s bank may not be in the same time zone or the beginning of the business day of the sender and the funds transfer business day of the beneficiary’s bank may not coincide. For example, the sender may be located in California and the beneficiary’s bank in New York. Since in most cases notice of rejection would be communicated electronically or by telephone, it might not be feasible for the bank to give notice before one hour after the opening of the funds transfer business day in New York because at that hour, the sender’s business day may not have started in California. For that reason, there are alternative deadlines stated in subsection (b)(3). In the case stated, the bank acts in time if it gives notice within one hour after the opening of the business day of the sender. But if the notice of rejection is received by the sender after the payment date, the bank is obliged to pay interest to the sender if the sender’s account does not bear interest. In that case the bank had the use of funds of the sender that the sender could reasonably assume would be used to pay the beneficiary. The rate of interest is stated in Section 4A-506. If the sender receives notice on the day after the payment date the sender is entitled to one day’s interest. If receipt of notice is delayed for more than one day, the sender is entitled to interest for each additional day of delay.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">9. Subsection (d) applies only to a payment order by the originator of a funds transfer to the originator’s bank and it refers to the following situation. On April 1, Originator instructs Bank A to make a payment on April 15 to the account of Beneficiary in Bank B. By mistake, on April 1, Bank A executes Originator’s payment order by issuing a payment order to Bank B instructing immediate payment to Beneficiary. Bank B credited Beneficiary’s account and immediately released the funds to Beneficiary. Under subsection (d) no acceptance by Bank A occurred on April 1 when Originator’s payment order was executed because acceptance cannot occur before the execution date which in this case would be April 15 or shortly before that date. Section 4A-301(b). Under Section 4A-402(c), Originator is not obliged to pay Bank A until the order is accepted and that can’t occur until the execution date. But Bank A is required to pay Bank B when Bank B accepted Bank A’s order on April 1. Unless Originator and Beneficiary are the same person, in almost all cases Originator is paying a debt owed to Beneficiary and early payment does not injure Originator because Originator does not have to pay Bank A until the execution date. Section 4A-402(c). Bank A takes the interest loss. But suppose that on April 3, Originator concludes that no debt was owed to Beneficiary or that the debt was less than the amount of the payment order. Under Section 4A-211(b) Originator can cancel its payment order if Bank A has not accepted. If early execution of Originator’s payment order is acceptance, Originator can suffer a loss because cancellation after acceptance is not possible without the consent of Bank A and Bank B. Section 4A-211(c). If Originator has to pay Bank A, Originator would be required to seek recovery of the money from Beneficiary. Subsection (d) prevents this result and puts the risk of loss on Bank A by providing that the early execution does not result in acceptance until the execution date. Since on April 3 Originator’s order was not yet accepted, Originator can cancel it under Section 4A-211(b). The result is that Bank A is not entitled to payment from Originator but is obliged to pay Bank B. Bank A has paid Beneficiary by mistake. If Originator’s payment order is cancelled, Bank A becomes the originator of an erroneous funds transfer to Beneficiary. Bank A has the burden of recovering payment from Beneficiary on the basis of a payment by mistake. If Beneficiary received the money in good faith in payment of a debt owed to Beneficiary by Originator, the law of mistake and restitution may allow Beneficiary to keep all or part of the money received. If Originator owed money to Beneficiary, Bank A has paid Originator’s debt and, under the law of restitution, which applies pursuant to  Section 1-103, Bank A is subrogated to Beneficiary’s rights against Originator on the debt.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">If Bank A is the Beneficiary’s bank and Bank A credited Beneficiary’s account and released the funds to Beneficiary on April 1, the analysis is similar. If Originator’s order is cancelled, Bank A has paid Beneficiary by mistake. The right of Bank A to recover the payment from Beneficiary is similar to Bank A’s rights in the preceding paragraph.</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:4A-209.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§28:4A-105">§ 28:4A-105</cite>, <cite path="§28:4A-212">§ 28:4A-212</cite>, and <cite path="§28:4A-302">§ 28:4A-302</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
