<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:4-403</num>
  <heading>Customer’s right to stop payment; burden of proof of loss.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A customer, or any person authorized to draw on the account if there is more than one person, may stop payment of any item drawn on the customer’s account or close the account by an order to the bank describing the item or account with reasonable certainty received at a time and in a manner that affords the bank a reasonable opportunity to act on it before any action by the bank with respect to the item described in section 28:4-303. If the signature of more than one person is required to draw on an account, any of these persons may stop payment or close the account.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A stop-payment order is effective for 6 months, but it lapses after 14 calendar days if the original order was oral and was not confirmed in a record within that period. A stop-payment order may be renewed for additional 6-month periods by a record given to the bank within a period during which the stop-payment order is effective.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The burden of establishing the fact and amount of loss resulting from the payment of an item contrary to a stop-payment order or order to close an account is on the customer. The loss from payment of an item contrary to a stop-payment order may include damages for dishonor of subsequent items under section 28:4-402.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 705, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-249" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(e), 42 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 6(i), 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:3-418">28:3-418</cite> and § <cite path="§28:4-401">28:4-401</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:4-403.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:4-403.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-299">D.C. Law 19-299</cite>, in (b), substituted “in a record” for “in writing” in the first sentence and substituted “by a record” for “by a writing” in the second sentence.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. The position taken by this section is that stopping payment or closing an account is a service which depositors expect and are entitled to receive from banks notwithstanding its difficulty, inconvenience and expense. The inevitable occasional losses through failure to stop or close should be borne by the banks as a cost of the business of banking.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Subsection (a) follows the decisions holding that a payee or indorsee has no right to stop payment. This is consistent with the provision governing payment or satisfaction. See  Section 3-602. The sole exception to this rule is found in  Section 4-405 on payment after notice of death, by which any person claiming an interest in the account can stop payment.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Payment is commonly stopped only on checks; but the right to stop payment is not limited to checks, and extends to any item payable by any bank. If the maker of a note payable at a bank is in a position analogous to that of a drawer ( Section 4-106) the maker may stop payment of the note. By analogy the rule extends to drawees other than banks.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. A cashier’s check or teller’s check purchased by a customer whose account is debited in payment for the check is not a check drawn on the customer’s account within the meaning of subsection (a); hence, a customer purchasing a cashier’s check or teller’s check has no right to stop payment of such a check under subsection (a). If a bank issuing a cashier’s check or teller’s check refuses to pay the check as an accommodation to its customer or for other reasons, its liability on the check is governed by  Section 3-411. There is no right to stop payment after certification of a check or other acceptance of a draft, and this is true no matter who procures the certification. See  Sections 3-411 and  4-303. The acceptance is the drawee’s own engagement to pay, and it is not required to impair its credit by refusing payment for the convenience of the drawer.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. Subsection (a) makes clear that if there is more than one person authorized to draw on a customer’s account any one of them can stop payment of any check drawn on the account or can order the account closed. Moreover, if there is a customer, such as a corporation, that requires its checks to bear the signatures of more than one person, any of these persons may stop payment on a check. In describing the item, the customer, in the absence of a contrary agreement, must meet the standard of what information allows the bank under the technology then existing to identify the item with reasonable certainty.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">6. Under subsection (b), a stop-payment order is effective after the order, whether written or oral, is received by the bank and the bank has a reasonable opportunity to act on it. If the order is written it remains in effect for six months from that time. If the order is oral it lapses after 14 days unless there is written confirmation. If there is written confirmation within the 14-day period, the six-month period dates from the giving of the oral order. A stop-payment order may be renewed any number of times by written notice given during a six-month period while a stop order is in effect. A new stop-payment order may be given after a six-month period expires, but such a notice takes effect from the date given. When a stop-payment order expires it is as though the order had never been given, and the payor bank may pay the item in good faith under  Section 4-404 even though a stop-payment order had once been given.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">7. A payment in violation of an effective direction to stop payment is an improper payment, even though it is made by mistake or inadvertence. Any agreement to the contrary is invalid under  Section 4-103(a) if in paying the item over the stop-payment order the bank has failed to exercise ordinary care. An agreement to the contrary which is imposed upon a customer as part of a standard form contract would have to be evaluated in the light of the general obligation of good faith.  Sections 1-203 and  4-104(c). The drawee is, however, entitled to subrogation to prevent unjust enrichment ( Section 4-407); retains common law defenses, e.g., that by conduct in recognizing the payment the customer has ratified the bank’s action in paying over a stop-payment order ( Section 1-103); and retains common law rights, e.g., to recover money paid under a mistake under  Section 3-418. It has sometimes been said that payment cannot be stopped against a holder in due course, but the statement is inaccurate. The payment can be stopped but the drawer remains liable on the instrument to the holder in due course ( Sections 3-305,  3-414) and the drawee, if it pays, becomes subrogated to the rights of the holder in due course against the drawer.  Section 4-407. The relationship between  Sections 4-403 and  4-407 is discussed in the comments to  Section 4-407. Any defenses available against a holder in due course remain available to the drawer, but other defenses are cut off to the same extent as if the holder were bringing the action.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Reason for 1990 Change [<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-249">D.C. Law 10-249</cite>]</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (a) removes any ambiguity that may have been present under former subsection (1) by making clear that if there is more than one person authorized to draw on a customer’s account any one of them can stop payment of any check drawn on the account or can order the account closed. Moreover, if there is a customer, such as a corporation, that requires its checks to bear the signatures of more than one person, any of these persons may stop payment on a check. In describing the item, the customer, in the absence of a contrary agreement, must meet the standard of what information allows the bank under the technology then existing to identify the item with reasonable certainty. An order to close an account is assimilated to an order to stop payment in this section and in  Section 4-407.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (b) restates and clarifies former subsection (2). Subsection (c) is amended by the addition of the last sentence to provide expressly for what was only assumed under the former section: that a customer’s damages for payment contrary to a stop-payment order may include damages for wrongful dishonor of subsequent items. The word “binding” is deleted as superfluous.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The other modifications are made to conform with current legislative drafting practices, with no intent to change substance.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
