<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28-5205</num>
  <heading>Exemptions.</heading>
  <text>This chapter does not apply to:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Prepackaged food that contains separately identifiable items that are separated by physical division within the package;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Any item sold only by prescription;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Any item subject to the packaging or labeling requirements of the federal Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms or to any pricing requirements under federal law;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Any item actually being sold through a vending machine;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Any item delivered directly to a retail sales agency without passing through warehousing or other inventory facility used by the agency;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Commodities packaged in quantities of less than 28 grams (one ounce) or 29 milliliters (one fluid ounce) or when the total retail price is 50 cents or less;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>When only one brand of a particular commodity in only one size is offered for sale in a particular retail establishment;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Variety packages;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Combination packages; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>A person with less than $30 million in gross volume of sales of consumer commodities and to whom at least one of the following applies:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>During the preceding calendar year, sold a gross volume of consumer commodities of less than $750,000;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is not part of a company which consists of 10 or more sales agencies in or out of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Derives less than 15% of its total revenues from consumer commodities subject to this chapter; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Is owned and operated by not more than one individual and the members of the person’s immediate family.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-282" type="History">Apr. 23, 2013, D.C. Law 19-282, § 2(c), 60 DCR 2132</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
