<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:5-103</num>
  <heading>Scope.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This article applies to letters of credit and to certain rights and obligations arising out of transactions involving letters of credit.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The statement of a rule in this article does not by itself require, imply, or negate application of the same or a different rule to a situation not provided for, or to a person not specified, in this article.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>With the exception of this subsection, subsections (a) and (d) of this section, §§ <cite path="§28:5-102">28:5-102</cite>(a)(9) and (10), 28:5-106(d), and 28:5-114(d), and except to the extent prohibited in §§ <cite path="§28:1-302">28:1-302</cite> and 28:5-117(d), the effect of this article may be varied by agreement or by a provision stated or incorporated by reference in an undertaking. A term in an agreement or undertaking generally excusing liability or generally limiting remedies for failure to perform obligations is not sufficient to vary obligations prescribed by this article.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Rights and obligations of an issuer to a beneficiary or a nominated person under a letter of credit are independent of the existence, performance, or nonperformance of a contract or arrangement out of which the letter of credit arises or which underlies it, including contracts or arrangements between the issuer and the applicant and between the applicant and the beneficiary.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 708, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-238" type="History">renumbered and amended Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-238, § 2, 44 DCR 923</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 8, 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:5-116">28:5-116</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:5-103.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:5-103.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-299">D.C. Law 19-299</cite> substituted “28:1-302” for “28:1-102(3)” in the first sentence of (c).</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1.  Sections 5-102(a)(10) and  5-103 are the principal limits on the scope of Article 5. Many undertakings in commerce and contract are similar, but not identical to the letter of credit. Principal among those are “secondary,” “accessory,” or “suretyship” guarantees. Although the word “guarantee” is sometimes used to describe an independent obligation like that of the issuer of a letter of credit (most often in the case of European bank undertakings but occasionally in the case of undertakings of American banks), in the United States the word “guarantee” is more typically used to describe a suretyship transaction in which the “guarantor” is only secondarily liable and has the right to assert the underlying debtor’s defenses. This article does not apply to secondary or accessory guarantees and it is important to recognize the distinction between letters of credit and those guarantees. It is often a defense to a secondary or accessory guarantor’s liability that the underlying debt has been discharged or that the debtor has other defenses to the underlying liability. In letter of credit law, on the other hand, the independence principle recognized throughout Article 5 states that the issuer’s liability is independent of the underlying obligation. That the beneficiary may have breached the underlying contract and thus have given a good defense on that contract to the applicant against the beneficiary is no defense for the issuer’s refusal to honor. Only staunch recognition of this principle by the issuers and the courts will give letters of credit the continuing vitality that arises from the certainty and speed of payment under letters of credit. To that end, it is important that the law not carry into letter of credit transactions rules that properly apply only to secondary guarantees or to other forms of engagement.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Like all of the provisions of the Uniform Commercial Code, Article 5 is supplemented by  Section 1-103 and, through it, by many rules of statutory and common law. Because this article is quite short and has no rules on many issues that will affect liability with respect to a letter of credit transaction, law beyond Article 5 will often determine rights and liabilities in letter of credit transactions. Even within letter of credit law, the article is far from comprehensive; it deals only with “certain” rights of the parties. Particularly with respect to the standards of performance that are set out in  Section 5-108, it is appropriate for the parties and the courts to turn to customs and practice such as the Uniform Customs and Practice for Documentary Credits, currently published by the International Chamber of Commerce as I.C.C. Pub. No. 500 (hereafter UCP). Many letters of credit specifically adopt the UCP as applicable to the particular transaction. Where the UCP are adopted but conflict with Article 5 and except where variation is prohibited, the UCP terms are permissible contractual modifications under  Sections 1-102(3) and  5-103(c).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">See  Section 5-116(c). Normally Article 5 should not be considered to conflict with practice except when a rule explicitly stated in the UCP or other practice is different from a rule explicitly stated in Article 5.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Except by choosing the law of a jurisdiction that has not adopted the Uniform Commercial Code, it is not possible entirely to escape the Uniform Commercial Code. Since incorporation of the UCP avoids only “conflicting” Article 5 rules, parties who do not wish to be governed by the nonconflicting provisions of Article 5 must normally either adopt the law of a jurisdiction other than a State of the United States or state explicitly the rule that is to govern. When rules of custom and practice are incorporated by reference, they are considered to be explicit terms of the agreement or undertaking.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Neither the obligation of an issuer under  Section 5-108 nor that of an adviser under  Section 5-107 is an obligation of the kind that is invariable under  Section 1-102(3).  Section 5-103(c) and Comment 1 to  Section 5-108 make it clear that the applicant and the issuer may agree to almost any provision establishing the obligations of the issuer to the applicant. The last sentence of subsection (c) limits the power of the issuer to achieve that result by a nonnegotiated disclaimer or limitation of remedy.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">What the issuer could achieve by an explicit agreement with its applicant or by a term that explicitly defines its duty, it cannot accomplish by a general disclaimer. The restriction on disclaimers in the last sentence of subsection (c) is based more on procedural than on substantive unfairness. Where, for example, the reimbursement agreement provides explicitly that the issuer need not examine any documents, the applicant understands the risk it has undertaken. A term in a reimbursement agreement which states generally that an issuer will not be liable unless it has acted in “bad faith” or committed “gross negligence” is ineffective under  Section 5-103(c). On the other hand, less general terms such as terms that permit issuer reliance on an oral or electronic message believed in good faith to have been received from the applicant or terms that entitle an issuer to reimbursement when it honors a “substantially” though not “strictly” complying presentation, are effective. In each case the question is whether the disclaimer or limitation is sufficiently clear and explicit in reallocating a liability or risk that is allocated differently under a variable Article 5 provision.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Of course, no term in a letter of credit, whether incorporated by reference to practice rules or stated specifically, can free an issuer from a conflicting contractual obligation to its applicant. If, for example, an issuer promised its applicant that it would pay only against an inspection certificate of a particular company but failed to require such a certificate in its letter of credit or made the requirement only a nondocumentary condition that had to be disregarded, the issuer might be obliged to pay the beneficiary even though its payment might violate its contract with its applicant.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Parties should generally avoid modifying the definitions in  Section 5-102. The effect of such an agreement is almost inevitably unclear. To say that something is a “guarantee” in the typical domestic transaction is to say that the parties intend that particular legal rules apply to it. By acknowledging that something is a guarantee, but asserting that it is to be treated as a “letter of credit,” the parties leave a court uncertain about where the rules on guarantees stop and those concerning letters of credit begin.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4.  Section 5-102(2) and (3) of Article 5 are omitted as unneeded; the omission does not change the law.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
