<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:5-115</num>
  <heading>Statute of limitations.</heading>
  <text>An action to enforce a right or obligation arising under this article must be commenced within one year after the expiration date of the relevant letter of credit or one year after the cause of action accrues, whichever occurs later. A cause of action accrues when the breach occurs, regardless of the aggrieved party’s lack of knowledge of the breach.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-238" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-238, § 2, 44 DCR 923</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. This section is based upon  Sections 4-111 and  2-725(2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. This section applies to all claims for which there are remedies under  Section 5-111 and to other claims made under this article, such as claims for breach of warranty under  Section 5-110. Because it covers all claims under  Section 5-111, the statute of limitations applies not only to wrongful dishonor claims against the issuer but also to claims between the issuer and the applicant arising from the reimbursement agreement. These might be for reimbursement (issuer v. applicant) or for breach of the reimbursement contract by wrongful honor (applicant v. issuer).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. The statute of limitations, like the rest of the statute, applies only to a letter of credit issued on or after the effective date and only to transactions, events, obligations, or duties arising out of or associated with such a letter. If a letter of credit was issued before the effective date and an obligation on that letter of credit was breached after the effective date, the complaining party could bring its suit within the time that would have been permitted prior to the adoption of  Section 5-115 and would not be limited by the terms of  Section 5-115.</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:5-115.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:5-115.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
