<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:5-104</num>
  <heading>Formal requirements.</heading>
  <text>A letter of credit, confirmation, advice, transfer, amendment, or cancellation may be issued in any form that is a record and is authenticated (i) by a signature or (ii) in accordance with the agreement of the parties or the standard practice referred to in § <cite path="§28:5-108">28:5-108</cite>(e).</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 709, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-238" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-238, § 2, 44 DCR 923</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Neither  Section 5-104 nor the definition of letter of credit in  Section 5-102(a)(10) requires inclusion of all the terms that are normally contained in a letter of credit in order for an undertaking to be recognized as a letter of credit under Article 5. For example, a letter of credit will typically specify the amount available, the expiration date, the place where presentation should be made, and the documents that must be presented to entitle a person to honor. Undertakings that have the formalities required by  Section 5-104 and meet the conditions specified in  Section 5-102(a)(10) will be recognized as letters of credit even though they omit one or more of the items usually contained in a letter of credit.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. The authentication specified in this section is authentication only of the identity of the issuer, confirmer, or adviser.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">An authentication agreement may be by system rule, by standard practice, or by direct agreement between the parties. The reference to practice is intended to incorporate future developments in the UCP and other practice rules as well as those that may arise spontaneously in commercial practice.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Many banking transactions, including the issuance of many letters of credit, are now conducted mostly by electronic means. For example, S.W.I.F.T. is currently used to transmit letters of credit from issuing to advising banks. The letter of credit text so transmitted may be printed at the advising bank, stamped “original” and provided to the beneficiary in that form. The printed document may then be used as a way of controlling and recording payments and of recording and authorizing assignments of proceeds or transfers of rights under the letter of credit. Nothing in this section should be construed to conflict with that practice.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">To be a record sufficient to serve as a letter of credit or other undertaking under this section, data must have a durability consistent with that function. Because consideration is not required for a binding letter of credit or similar undertaking ( Section 5-105) yet those undertakings are to be strictly construed ( Section 5-108), parties to a letter of credit transaction are especially dependent on the continued availability of the terms and conditions of the letter of credit or other undertaking. By declining to specify any particular medium in which the letter of credit must be established or communicated,  Section 5-104 leaves room for future developments.</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:5-104.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:5-104.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:5-102">28:5-102</cite> and § <cite path="§28:5-116">28:5-116</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
