<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <num>28:6-104</num>
  <heading>Obligations of buyer.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 715, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-239" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-239, § 2, 44 DCR 936</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-215" type="History">Oct. 23, 2014, D.C. Law 20-215, § 31, 61 DCR 13083</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:6-105">28:6-105</cite>, § <cite path="§28:6-107">28:6-107</cite>, § <cite path="§28:6-108">28:6-108</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-4461">47-4461</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:6-104.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:6-104.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-215">D.C. Law 20-215</cite>: Section 32 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-215">D.C. Law 20-215</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2016.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:Section 6-104 (1987 Official Text).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Changes: Revised and rewritten.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Purposes of Changes and New Matter: 1. Subsection (1) sets forth the buyer’s duties in a bulk sale conducted by the seller. The buyer’s failure to perform these duties may result in liability under  Section 6-107. An auctioneer in a bulk sale by auction and a liquidator in a bulk sale that the liquidator conducts on the seller’s behalf have similar duties but may face somewhat different liability. See  Section 6-108(1). The buyer’s duties are designed to afford the seller’s claimants the opportunity to learn of the bulk sale before the seller has removed the assets from their reach and has received payment that is easily secreted.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2.  Section 6-104(3) (1987 Official Text) provides that “[r]esponsibility for the completeness and accuracy of the list of creditors rests on the transferor, and the transfer is not rendered ineffective by errors or omissions therein unless the transferee is shown to have had knowledge.“ This sentence has been deleted as superfluous. Nothing in this Article suggests that the buyer is responsible for the completeness or accuracy of the list of claimants. The buyer’s only obligations with respect to the list are to obtain it from the seller and to make it available. A buyer who sends or delivers notice of the bulk sale in accordance with  Section 6-105(1) may rely in good faith on the list supplied by the seller unless, at the time the notice is sent or delivered, the buyer has knowledge of a claimant not on the list. A buyer who knows of a claimant not on the list is obligated to send notice of the bulk sale to that claimant.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. The buyer’s only obligation with respect to the net contract price is to comply with the schedule of distribution. The schedule may provide for the buyer to pay the entire net contract price to the seller. If so, the buyer complies with the requirements of  Section 6-104(1)(e) by paying the entire net contract price to the seller.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. The purpose of the list of claimants is to enable the buyer to give claimants notice of the bulk sale. If the buyer gives notice by filing in a public office ( Section 6-105(2)), then the buyer need not obtain or preserve a list of the seller’s claimants.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Cross-References: Point 1:  Sections 6-107 and  6-108.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 2:  Sections 6-105 and  1-203.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 3:  Section 6-106.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 4:  Section 6-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Definitional Cross-References: “Buyer”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Bulk sale”.  Section 6-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Claimant”.  Section 6-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Date of the bulk sale”.  Section 6-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Net contract price”.  Section 6-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Notice”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Seller”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Verified”.  Section 6-102.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
