<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:7-302</num>
  <heading>Through bills of lading and similar documents of title.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The issuer of a through bill of lading, or other document of title embodying an undertaking to be performed in part by a person acting as its agent or by a performing carrier, is liable to any person entitled to recover on the bill or other document for any breach by the other person or the performing carrier of its obligation under the bill or other document. However, to the extent that the bill or other document covers an undertaking to be performed overseas or in territory not contiguous to the continental United States or an undertaking including matters other than transportation, this liability for breach by the other person or the performing carrier may be varied by agreement of the parties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If goods covered by a through bill of lading or other document of title embodying an undertaking to be performed in part by a person other than the issuer are received by that person, the person is subject, with respect to its own performance while the goods are in its possession, to the obligation of the issuer. The person’s obligation is discharged by delivery of the goods to another person pursuant to the bill or other document and does not include liability for breach by any other person or by the issuer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The issuer of a through bill of lading or other document of title described in subsection (a) of this section is entitled to recover from the performing carrier, or other person in possession of the goods when the breach of the obligation under the bill or other document occurred:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The amount it may be required to pay to any person entitled to recover on the bill or other document for the breach, as may be evidenced by any receipt, judgment, or transcript of judgment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amount of any expense reasonably incurred by the issuer in defending any action commenced by any person entitled to recover on the bill or other document for the breach.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 724, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 9, 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:7-302.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:7-302.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> None.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> 1. The purpose of this section is to subject the initial carrier under a through bill to suit for breach of the contract of carriage by any connecting carrier and to make it clear that any such connecting carrier holds the goods on terms which are defined by the document of title even though such connecting carrier did not issue the document. Since the connecting carrier does hold on the terms of the document, it must honor a proper demand for delivery or a diversion order just as the original bailee would have to. Similarly it has the benefits of the excuses for nondelivery and limitations of liability provided for the original bailee. Unlike the original bailee-issuer, the connecting carrier’s responsibility is limited to the period while the goods are in its possession. The section is patterned generally after the Interstate Commerce Act, but does not impose any obligation to issue through bills.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. The reference to documents other than through bills looks to the possibility that multi-purpose documents may come into use, e.g., combination warehouse receipts and bills of lading.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Where the obligations or standards applicable to different parties bound by a document of title are different, the initial carrier’s responsibility for portions of the journey not on its own lines will be determined by the standards appropriate to the connecting carrier. Thus a land carrier issuing a through bill of lading involving water carriage at a later stage will have the benefit of the water carrier’s immunity from liability for negligence of its servants in navigating the vessel, where the law provides such an immunity for water carriers and the loss occurred while the goods were in the water carrier’s possession.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Under Subsection (1) the issuer of a through bill of lading may become liable for the fault of another person. Subsection (3) gives it appropriate rights of recourse.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Agreement”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Bailee”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Bill of lading”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Delivery”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Document”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Issuer”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Overseas”.  Section 2-323.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Party”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Person”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> Former  Section 7-302.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> To conform to current terminology and for style.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> 1. This section continues the rules from former  Section 7-302 without substantive change. The term “performing carrier” is substituted for the term “connecting carrier” to conform the terminology of this section with terminology used in recent UNCITRAL and OAS proposals concerning transportation and through bills of lading. This change in terminology is not substantive. This section is compatible with liability on carriers under federal law. See  49 U.S.C. §§ 11706,  14706 and  15906.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The purpose of this section is to subject the initial carrier under a through bill to suit for breach of the contract of carriage by any performing carrier and to make it clear that any such performing carrier holds the goods on terms which are defined by the document of title even though such performing carrier did not issue the document. Since the performing carrier does hold the goods on the terms of the document, it must honor a proper demand for delivery or a diversion order just as the original bailee would have to. Similarly it has the benefits of the excuses for non-delivery and limitations of liability provided for the original bailee who issued the bill. Unlike the original bailee-issuer, the performing carrier’s responsibility is limited to the period while the goods are in its possession. The section does not impose any obligation to issue through bills.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. The reference to documents other than through bills looks to the possibility that multi-purpose documents may come into use, e.g., combination warehouse receipts and bills of lading. As electronic documents of title come into common usage, storage documents (e.g. warehouse receipts) and transportation documents (e.g. bills of lading) may merge seamlessly into one electronic document that can serve both the storage and transportation segments of the movement of goods.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Under subsection (a) the issuer of a through bill of lading may become liable for the fault of another person. Subsection (c) gives the issuer appropriate rights of recourse.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Despite the broad language of subsection (a),  Section 7-302 is subject to preemption by federal laws and treaties.  Section 7-103. The precise scope of federal preemption in the transportation sector is a question determined under federal law.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Cross reference:  Section 7-103</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Agreement”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Bailee”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Bill of lading”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Delivery”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Document of title”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Issuer”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Party”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Person”.  Section 1-201.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
