<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:7-602</num>
  <heading>Judicial process against goods covered by negotiable document of title.</heading>
  <text>Unless a document of title was originally issued upon delivery of the goods by a person that did not have power to dispose of them, a lien does not attach by virtue of any judicial process to goods in the possession of a bailee for which a negotiable document of title is outstanding unless possession or control of the document is first surrendered to the bailee or the document’s negotiation is enjoined. The bailee may not be compelled to deliver the goods pursuant to process until possession or control of the document is surrendered to the bailee or to the court. A purchaser of the document for value without notice of the process or injunction takes free of the lien imposed by judicial process.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 731, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 9, 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:7-602.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:7-602.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provisions:</strong> Section 25, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act; Section 24, Uniform Bills of Lading Act.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Consolidated and rewritten.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes of Changes:</strong> 1. The purpose of the section is to protect the bailee from conflicting claims of the document holder and the judgment creditors of the person who deposited the goods. The rights of the former prevail unless, in effect, the judgment creditors immobilize the negotiable document. However, if the document was issued upon deposit of the goods by a person who had no power to dispose of the goods so that the document is ineffective to pass title, judgment liens are valid to the extent of the debtor’s interest in the goods.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. The last sentence covers the possibility that the holder of a document who has been enjoined from negotiating it will violate the injunction by negotiating to an innocent purchaser for value. In such case the lien will be defeated.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross Reference:</strong> Point 1:  Section 7-503.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Bailee”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Delivery”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Document”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Notice”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Person”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Purchase”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Value”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provisions:</strong> Former  Section 7-602.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Changes to accommodate electronic documents of title and for style.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> 1. The purpose of the section is to protect the bailee from conflicting claims of the document of title holder and the judgment creditors of the person who deposited the goods. The rights of the former prevail unless, in effect, the judgment creditors immobilize the negotiable document of title through the surrender of possession of a tangible document or control of an electronic document. However, if the document of title was issued upon deposit of the goods by a person who had no power to dispose of the goods so that the document is ineffective to pass title, judgment liens are valid to the extent of the debtor’s interest in the goods.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. The last sentence covers the possibility that the holder of a document who has been enjoined from negotiating it will violate the injunction by negotiating to an innocent purchaser for value. In such case the lien will be defeated.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross Reference:</strong>Sections 7-106 and  7-501 through  7-503.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Bailee”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Delivery”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Document of title”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”.  Section 7-102.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Notice”.  Section 1-202.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Person”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Purchase”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Value”.  Section 1-204.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
