<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:7-506</num>
  <heading>Delivery without indorsement: right to compel indorsement.</heading>
  <text>The transferee of a negotiable tangible document of title has a specifically enforceable right to have its transferor supply any necessary indorsement, but the transfer becomes a negotiation only as of the time the indorsement is supplied.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 730, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 9, 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:7-506.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:7-506.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> Section 35, Uniform Sales Act; Section 43, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act; Section 34, Uniform Bills of Lading Act.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Consolidated and rewritten; former requirement that transfer be “for value” eliminated.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes of Changes:</strong> 1. From a commercial point of view the intention to transfer a negotiable document of title which requires an indorsement for its transfer, is incompatible with an intention to withhold such indorsement and so defeat the effective use of the document. This position is sustained by the absence of any reported case applying the prior provisions in almost forty years of decisions. Further, the preceding section and the Comment thereto make it clear that an indorsement generally imposes no responsibility on the indorser.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Although this section provides that delivery of a document of title without the necessary indorsement is effective as a transfer, the transferee, of course, has not regularized his position until such indorsement is supplied. Until this is done he cannot claim rights under due negotiation within the requirements of this Article (subsection (4) of  Section 7-501) on “due negotiation.“ Similarly despite the transfer to him of his transferor’s title, he cannot demand the goods from the bailee until the negotiation has been completed and the document is in proper form for surrender. See  Section 7-403(2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong> Point 1:  Section 7-505.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 2:  Sections 7-501(4) and  7-403(2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Document of title”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Rights”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> Former  Section 7-506.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Limited to tangible documents of title.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> 1. This section is limited to tangible documents of title as the concept of indorsement is irrelevant to electronic documents of title. Electronic documents of title will be transferred by delivery of control.  Section 7-106. From a commercial point of view the intention to transfer a tangible negotiable document of title which requires an indorsement for its transfer, is incompatible with an intention to withhold such indorsement and so defeat the effective use of the document. Further, the preceding section and the Comment thereto make it clear that an indorsement generally imposes no responsibility on the indorser.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Although this section provides that delivery of a tangible document of title without the necessary indorsement is effective as a transfer, the transferee, of course, has not regularized its position until such indorsement is supplied. Until this is done the transferee cannot claim rights under due negotiation within the requirements of this Article ( Section 7-501(a)(5)) on “due negotiation”. Similarly, despite the transfer to the transferee of the transferor’s title, the transferee cannot demand the goods from the bailee until the negotiation has been completed and the document is in proper form for surrender. See  Section 7-403(c).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross References:</strong> Point 1:  Sections 7-106 and  7-505.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Point 2:  Sections 7-501(a)(5) and  7-403(c).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Document of title”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Rights”.  Section 1-201.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
