<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:8-507</num>
  <heading>Duty of securities intermediary to comply with entitlement order.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A securities intermediary shall comply with an entitlement order if the entitlement order is originated by the appropriate person, the securities intermediary has had reasonable opportunity to assure itself that the entitlement order is genuine and authorized, and the securities intermediary has had reasonable opportunity to comply with the entitlement order. A securities intermediary satisfies the duty if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The securities intermediary acts with respect to the duty as agreed upon by the entitlement holder and the securities intermediary; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In the absence of agreement, the securities intermediary exercises due care in accordance with reasonable commercial standards to comply with the entitlement order.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a securities intermediary transfers a financial asset pursuant to an ineffective entitlement order, the securities intermediary shall reestablish a security entitlement in favor of the person entitled to it, and pay or credit any payments or distributions that the person did not receive as a result of the wrongful transfer. If the securities intermediary does not reestablish a security entitlement, the securities intermediary is liable to the entitlement holder for damages.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-240" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:8-507.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Subsection (a) of this section states another aspect of duties of securities intermediaries that make up security entitlements—the securities intermediary’s duty to comply with entitlement orders. One of the main reasons for holding securities through securities intermediaries is to enable rapid transfer in settlement of trades. Thus the right to have one’s orders for disposition of the security entitlement honored is an inherent part of the relationship. Subsection (b) states the correlative liability of a securities intermediary for transferring a financial asset from an entitlement holder’s account pursuant to an entitlement order that was not effective.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. The duty to comply with entitlement orders is subject to several qualifications. The intermediary has a duty only with respect to an entitlement order that is in fact originated by the appropriate person. Moreover, the intermediary has a duty only if it has had reasonable opportunity to assure itself that the order is genuine and authorized, and reasonable opportunity to comply with the order. The same “agreement/due care” formula is used in this section as in the other Part 5 sections on the duties of intermediaries, and the rules of  Section 8-509 apply to the  Section 8-507 duty.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Appropriate person is defined in  Section 8-107. In the usual case, the appropriate person is the entitlement holder, see  Section 8-107(a)(3). Entitlement holder is defined in  Section 8-102(a)(7) as the person “identified in the records of a securities intermediary as the person having a security entitlement.“ Thus, the general rule is that an intermediary’s duty with respect to entitlement orders runs only to the person with whom the intermediary has established a relationship. One of the basic principles of the indirect holding system is that securities intermediaries owe duties only to their own customers. See also  Section 8-115. The only situation in which a securities intermediary has a duty to comply with entitlement orders originated by a person other than the person with whom the intermediary established a relationship is covered by  Section 8-107(a)(4) and (a)(5), which provide that the term “appropriate person” includes the successor or personal representative of a decedent, or the custodian or guardian of a person who lacks capacity. If the entitlement holder is competent, another person does not fall within the defined term “appropriate person” merely by virtue of having power to act as an agent for the entitlement holder. Thus, an intermediary is not required to determine at its peril whether a person who purports to be authorized to act for an entitlement holder is in fact authorized to do so. If an entitlement holder wishes to be able to act through agents, the entitlement holder can establish appropriate arrangements in advance with the securities intermediary.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">One important application of this principle is that if an entitlement holder grants a security interest in its security entitlements to a third-party lender, the intermediary owes no duties to the secured party, unless the intermediary has entered into a “control” agreement in which it agrees to act on entitlement orders originated by the secured party. See  Section 8-106. Even though the security agreement or some other document may give the secured party authority to act as agent for the debtor, that would not make the secured party an “appropriate person” to whom the security intermediary owes duties. If the entitlement holder and securities intermediary have agreed to such a control arrangement, then the intermediary’s action in following instructions from the secured party would satisfy the subsection (a) duty. Although an agent, such as the secured party in this example, is not an “appropriate person,” an entitlement order is “effective” if originated by an authorized person. See  Section 8-107(a) and (b). Moreover,  Section 8-507(a) provides that the intermediary satisfies its duty if it acts in accordance with the entitlement holder’s agreement.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Subsection (b) provides that an intermediary is liable for a wrongful transfer if the entitlement order was “ineffective.”  Section 8-107 specifies whether an entitlement order is effective. An “effective entitlement order” is different from an “entitlement order originated by an appropriate person.” An entitlement order is effective under  Section 8-107(b) if it is made by the appropriate person, or by a person who has power to act for the appropriate person under the law of agency, or if the appropriate person has ratified the entitlement order or is precluded from denying its effectiveness. Thus, although a securities intermediary does not have a duty to act on an entitlement order originated by the entitlement holder’s agent, the intermediary is not liable for wrongful transfer if it does so.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (b), together with  Section 8-107, has the effect of leaving to other law most of the questions of the sort dealt with by Article 4A for wire transfers of funds, such as allocation between the securities intermediary and the entitlement holder of the risk of fraudulent entitlement orders.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. The term entitlement order does not cover all directions that a customer might give a broker concerning securities held through the broker. Article 8 is not a codification of all of the law of customers and stockbrokers. Article 8 deals with the settlement of securities trades, not the trades. The term entitlement order does not refer to instructions to a broker to make trades, that is, enter into contracts for the purchase or sale of securities. Rather, the entitlement order is the mechanism of transfer for securities held through intermediaries, just as indorsements and instructions are the mechanism for securities held directly. In the ordinary case the customer’s direction to the broker to deliver the securities at settlement is implicit in the customer’s instruction to the broker to sell. The distinction is, however, significant in that this section has no application to the relationship between the customer and broker with respect to the trade itself. For example, assertions by a customer that it was damaged by a broker’s failure to execute a trading order sufficiently rapidly or in the proper manner are not governed by this Article.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References</strong> “Agreement”.  Section 1-201(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Appropriate person”.  Section 8-107.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Effective”.  Section 8-107.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Entitlement holder”.  Section 8-102(a)(7).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Entitlement order”.  Section 8-102(a)(8).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Financial asset”.  Section 8-102(a)(9).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Securities intermediary”.  Section 8-102(a)(14).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Security entitlement”.  Section 8-102(a)(17).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
