<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:8-115</num>
  <heading>Securities intermediary and others not liable to adverse claimant.</heading>
  <text>A securities intermediary that has transferred a financial asset pursuant to an effective entitlement order, or a broker or other agent or bailee that has dealt with a financial asset at the direction of its customer or principal, is not liable to a person having an adverse claim to the financial asset, unless the securities intermediary, or broker or other agent or bailee:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Took the action after it had been served with an injunction, restraining order, or other legal process enjoining it from doing so, issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, and had a reasonable opportunity to act on the injunction, restraining order, or other legal process; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Acted in collusion with the wrongdoer in violating the rights of the adverse claimant; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>In the case of a security certificate that has been stolen, acted with notice of the adverse claim.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 741, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-196" type="History">Mar. 16, 1993, D.C. Law 9-196, § 4, 39 DCR 9165</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-240" type="History">renumbered and amended, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:8-115.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:8-318.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text>1. Other provisions of Article 8 protect certain purchasers against adverse claims, both for the direct holding system and the indirect holding system. See  Sections 8-303 and  8-502. This section deals with the related question of the possible liability of a person who acted as the “conduit” for a securities transaction. It covers both securities intermediaries—the “conduits” in the indirect holding system—and brokers or other agents or bailees—the “conduits” in the direct holding system. The following examples illustrate its operation:</text>
      <text>Example 1. John Doe is a customer of the brokerage firm of Able &amp; Co. Doe delivers to Able a certificate for 100 shares of XYZ Co. common stock, registered in Doe’s name and properly indorsed, and asks the firm to sell it for him. Able does so. Later, John Doe’s spouse Mary Doe brings an action against Able asserting that Able’s action was wrongful against her because the XYZ Co. stock was marital property in which she had an interest, and John Doe was acting wrongfully against her in transferring the securities.</text>
      <text>Example 2. Mary Roe is a customer of the brokerage firm of Baker &amp; Co. and holds her securities through a securities account with Baker. Roe instructs Baker to sell 100 shares of XYZ Co. common stock that she carried in her account. Baker does so. Later, Mary Roe’s spouse John Roe brings an action against Baker asserting that Baker’s action was wrongful against him because the XYZ Co. stock was marital property in which he had an interest, and Mary Roe was acting wrongfully against him in transferring the securities. Under common law conversion principles, Mary Doe might be able to assert that Able &amp; Co. is liable to her in Example 1 for exercising dominion over property inconsistent with her rights in it. On that or some similar theory John Roe might assert that Baker is liable to him in Example 2.  Section 8-115 protects both Able and Baker from liability.</text>
      <text>2. The policy of this section is similar to that of many other rules of law that protect agents and bailees from liability as innocent converters. If a thief steals property and ships it by mail, express service, or carrier, to another person, the recipient of the property does not obtain good title, even though the recipient may have given value to the thief and had no notice or knowledge that the property was stolen. Accordingly, the true owner can recover the property from the recipient or obtain damages in a conversion or similar action. An action against the postal service, express company, or carrier presents entirely different policy considerations. Accordingly, general tort law protects agents or bailees who act on the instructions of their principals or bailors. See Restatement (Second) of Torts s 235. See also  UCC Section 7-404.</text>
      <text>3. Except as provided in paragraph 3, this section applies even though the securities intermediary, or the broker or other agent or bailee, had notice or knowledge that another person asserts a claim to the securities. Consider the following examples:</text>
      <text>Example 3. Same facts as in Example 1, except that before John Doe brought the XYZ Co. security certificate to Able for sale, Mary Doe telephoned or wrote to the firm asserting that she had an interest in all of John Doe’s securities and demanding that they not trade for him.</text>
      <text>Example 4. Same facts as in Example 2, except that before Mary Roe gave an entitlement order to Baker to sell the XYZ Co. securities from her account, John Roe telephoned or wrote to the firm asserting that he had an interest in all of Mary Roe’s securities and demanding that they not trade for her.  Section 8-115 protects Able and Baker from liability. The protections of  Section 8-115 do not depend on the presence or absence of notice of adverse claims. It is essential to the securities settlement system that brokers and securities intermediaries be able to act promptly on the directions of their customers. Even though a firm has notice that someone asserts a claim to a customer’s securities or security entitlements, the firm should not be placed in the position of having to make a legal judgment about the validity of the claim at the risk of liability either to its customer or to the third party for guessing wrong. Under this section, the broker or securities intermediary is privileged to act on the instructions of its customer or entitlement holder, unless it has been served with a restraining order or other legal process enjoining it from doing so. This is already the law in many jurisdictions. For example a section of the New York Banking Law provides that banks need not recognize any adverse claim to funds or securities on deposit with them unless they have been served with legal process. N.Y. Banking Law s 134. Other sections of the UCC embody a similar policy. See  Sections 3-602,  5-114(2)(b).</text>
      <text>Paragraph (1) of this section refers only to a court order enjoining the securities intermediary or the broker or other agent or bailee from acting at the instructions of the customer. It does not apply to cases where the adverse claimant tells the intermediary or broker that the customer has been enjoined, or shows the intermediary or broker a copy of a court order binding the customer.</text>
      <text>Paragraph (3) takes a different approach in one limited class of cases, those where a customer sells stolen certificated securities through a securities firm. Here the policies that lead to protection of securities firms against assertions of other sorts of claims must be weighed against the desirability of having securities firms guard against the disposition of stolen securities. Accordingly, paragraph (3) denies protection to a broker, custodian, or other agent or bailee who receives a stolen security certificate from its customer, if the broker, custodian, or other agent or bailee had notice of adverse claims. The circumstances that give notice of adverse claims are specified in  Section 8-105. The result is that brokers, custodians, and other agents and bailees face the same liability for selling stolen certificated securities that purchasers face for buying them.</text>
      <text>4. As applied to securities intermediaries, this section embodies one of the fundamental principles of the Article 8 indirect holding system rules—that a securities intermediary owes duties only to its own entitlement holders. The following examples illustrate the operation of this section in the multi-tiered indirect holding system:</text>
      <text>Example 5. Able &amp; Co., a broker-dealer, holds 50,000 shares of XYZ Co. stock in its account at Clearing Corporation. Able acquired the XYZ shares from another firm, Baker &amp; Co., in a transaction that Baker contends was tainted by fraud, giving Baker a right to rescind the transaction and recover the XYZ shares from Able. Baker sends notice to Clearing Corporation stating that Baker has a claim to the 50,000 shares of XYZ Co. in Able’s account. Able then initiates an entitlement order directing Clearing Corporation to transfer the 50,000 shares of XYZ Co. to another firm in settlement of a trade. Under  Section 8-115, Clearing Corporation is privileged to comply with Able’s entitlement order, without fear of liability to Baker. This is so even though Clearing Corporation has notice of Baker’s claim, unless Baker obtains a court order enjoining Clearing Corporation from acting on Able’s entitlement order.</text>
      <text>Example 6. Able &amp; Co., a broker-dealer, holds 50,000 shares of XYZ Co. stock in its account at Clearing Corporation. Able initiates an entitlement order directing Clearing Corporation to transfer the 50,000 shares of XYZ Co. to another firm in settlement of a trade. That trade was made by Able for its own account, and the proceeds were devoted to its own use. Able becomes insolvent, and it is discovered that Able has a shortfall in the shares of XYZ Co. stock that it should have been carrying for its customers. Able’s customers bring an action against Clearing Corporation asserting that Clearing Corporation acted wrongfully in transferring the XYZ shares on Able’s order because those were shares that should have been held by Able for its customers. Under  Section 8-115, Clearing Corporation is not liable to Able’s customers, because Clearing Corporation acted on an effective entitlement order of its own entitlement holder, Able. Clearing Corporation’s protection against liability does not depend on the presence or absence of notice or knowledge of the claim by Clearing Corporation.</text>
      <text>5. If the conduct of a securities intermediary or a broker or other agent or bailee rises to a level of complicity in the wrongdoing of its customer or principal, the policies that favor protection against liability do not apply. Accordingly, paragraph (2) provides that the protections of this section do not apply if the securities intermediary or broker or other agent or bailee acted in collusion with the customer or principal in violating the rights of another person. The collusion test is intended to adopt a standard akin to the tort rules that determine whether a person is liable as an aider or abettor for the tortious conduct of a third party. See Restatement (Second) of Torts s 876.</text>
      <text>Knowledge that the action of the customer is wrongful is a necessary but not sufficient condition of the collusion test. The aspect of the role of securities intermediaries and brokers that Article 8 deals with is the clerical or ministerial role of implementing and recording the securities transactions that their customers conduct. Faithful performance of this role consists of following the instructions of the customer. It is not the role of the record-keeper to police whether the transactions recorded are appropriate, so mere awareness that the customer may be acting wrongfully does not itself constitute collusion. That, of course, does not insulate an intermediary or broker from responsibility in egregious cases where its action goes beyond the ordinary standards of the business of implementing and recording transactions, and reaches a level of affirmative misconduct in assisting the customer in the commission of a wrong.</text>
      <text><strong>Definitional Cross References</strong> “Broker”.  Section 8-102(a)(3).</text>
      <text>“Effective”.  Section 8-107.</text>
      <text>“Entitlement order”.  Section 8-102(a)(8).</text>
      <text>“Financial asset”.  Section 8-102(a)(9).</text>
      <text>“Securities intermediary”.  Section 8-102(a)(14).</text>
      <text>“Security certificate”.  Section 8-102(a)(16).</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
