<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:8-103</num>
  <heading>Rules for determining whether certain obligations and interests are securities or financial assets.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A share or similar equity interest issued by a corporation, business trust, joint stock company, or similar entity is a security.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An “investment company security” is a security. The term “investment company security” means a share or similar equity interest issued by an entity that is registered as an investment company under the federal investment company laws, an interest in a unit investment trust that is so registered, or a face-amount certificate issued by a face-amount certificate company that is so registered. Investment company security does not include an insurance policy or endowment policy or annuity contract issued by an insurance company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An interest in a partnership or limited liability company is not a security unless it is dealt in or traded on securities exchanges or in securities markets, its terms expressly provide that it is a security governed by this article, or it is an investment company security. However, an interest in a partnership or limited liability company is a financial asset if it is held in a securities account.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A writing that is a security certificate is governed by this article and not by Article 3, even though it also meets the requirements of that article. However, a negotiable instrument governed by Article 3 is a financial asset if it is held in a securities account.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An option or similar obligation issued by a clearing corporation to its participants is not a security, but is a financial asset.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A commodity contract, as defined in § <cite path="§28:9-102">28:9-102</cite>(a)(15), is not a security or a financial asset.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A document of title is not a financial asset unless § <cite path="§28:8-102">28:8-102</cite>(a)(9)(iii) applies.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-240" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 201(i)(1), 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 10(b), 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:8-102">28:8-102</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:8-103.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:8-103.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-201">D.C. Law 13-201</cite>, enacting a new Article 9 of the Uniform Commercial Code applicable July 1, 2001, made conforming amendments to this section applicable upon the same date.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-299">D.C. Law 19-299</cite> added (g).</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. This section contains rules that supplement the definitions of “financial asset” and “security” in  Section 8-102. The  Section 8-102 definitions are worded in general terms, because they must be sufficiently comprehensive and flexible to cover the wide variety of investment products that now exist or may develop. The rules in this section are intended to foreclose interpretive issues concerning the application of the general definitions to several specific investment products. No implication is made about the application of the  Section 8-102 definitions to investment products not covered by this section.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Subsection (a) establishes an unconditional rule that ordinary corporate stock is a security. That is so whether or not the particular issue is dealt in or traded on securities exchanges or in securities markets. Thus, shares of closely held corporations are Article 8 securities.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Subsection (b) establishes that the Article 8 term “security” includes the various forms of the investment vehicles offered to the public by investment companies registered as such under the federal Investment Company Act of 1940, as amended. This clarification is prompted principally by the fact that the typical transaction in shares of open-end investment companies is an issuance or redemption, rather than a transfer of shares from one person to another as is the case with ordinary corporate stock. For similar reasons, the definitions of indorsement, instruction, and entitlement order in  Section 8-102 refer to “redemptions” as well as “transfers,” to ensure that the Article 8 rules on such matters as signature guaranties,  Section 8-306, assurances,  Sections 8-402 and  8-507, and effectiveness,  Section 8-107, apply to directions to redeem mutual fund shares. The exclusion of insurance products is needed because some insurance company separate accounts are registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940, but these are not traded under the usual Article 8 mechanics.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Subsection (c) is designed to foreclose interpretive questions that might otherwise be raised by the application of the “of a type“ language of  Section 8-102(a)(15)(iii) to partnership interests. Subsection (c) establishes the general rule that partnership interests or shares of limited liability companies are not Article 8 securities unless they are in fact dealt in or traded on securities exchanges or in securities markets. The issuer, however, may explicitly “opt-in” by specifying that the interests or shares are securities governed by Article 8. Partnership interests or shares of limited liability companies are included in the broader term “financial asset.” Thus, if they are held through a securities account, the indirect holding system rules of Part 5 apply, and the interest of a person who holds them through such an account is a security entitlement.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. Subsection (d) deals with the line between Article 3 negotiable instruments and Article 8 investment securities. It continues the rule of the prior version of Article 8 that a writing that meets the Article 8 definition is covered by Article 8 rather than Article 3, even though it also meets the definition of negotiable instrument. However, subsection (d) provides that an Article 3 negotiable instrument is a “financial asset” so that the indirect holding system rules apply if the instrument is held through a securities intermediary. This facilitates making items such as money market instruments eligible for deposit in clearing corporations.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">6. Subsection (e) is included to clarify the treatment of investment products such as traded stock options, which are treated as financial assets but not securities. Thus, the indirect holding system rules of Part 5 apply, but the direct holding system rules of Parts 2, 3, and 4 do not.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">7. Subsection (f) excludes commodity contracts from all of Article 8. However, the Article 9 rules on security interests in investment property do apply to security interests in commodity positions. See  Section 9-115 and Comment 8 thereto. “Commodity contract“ is defined in  Section 9-115.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References</strong> “Clearing corporation”.  Section 8-102(a)(5).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Commodity contract”.  Section 9-115.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Financial asset”.  Section 8-102(a)(9).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Security”.  Section 8-102(a)(15).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Security certificate”.  Section 8-102(a)(16).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
