<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:8-506</num>
  <heading>Duty of securities intermediary to exercise rights as directed by entitlement holder.</heading>
  <text>A securities intermediary shall exercise rights with respect to a financial asset if directed to do so by an entitlement holder. A securities intermediary satisfies the duty if:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The securities intermediary acts with respect to the duty as agreed upon by the entitlement holder and the securities intermediary; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>In the absence of agreement, the securities intermediary either places the entitlement holder in a position to exercise the rights directly or exercises due care in accordance with reasonable commercial standards to follow the direction of the entitlement holder.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-240" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:8-506.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Another of the core elements of the securities account relationships for which the Part 5 rules were designed is that although the intermediary may, by virtue of the structure of the indirect holding system, be the party who has the power to exercise the corporate and other rights that come from holding the security, the intermediary exercises these powers as representative of the entitlement holder rather than at its own discretion. This characteristic is one of the things that distinguishes a securities account from other arrangements where one person holds securities “on behalf of” another, such as the relationship between a mutual fund and its shareholders or a trustee and its beneficiary.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. The fact that the intermediary exercises the rights of security holding as representative of the entitlement holder does not, of course, preclude the entitlement holder from conferring discretionary authority upon the intermediary. Arrangements are not uncommon in which investors do not wish to have their intermediaries forward proxy materials or other information. Thus, this section provides that the intermediary shall exercise corporate and other rights “if directed to do so” by the entitlement holder. Moreover, as with the other Part 5 duties, the “agreement/due care” formulation is used in stating how the intermediary is to perform this duty. This section also provides that the intermediary satisfies the duty if it places the entitlement holder in a position to exercise the rights directly. This is to take account of the fact that some of the rights attendant upon ownership of the security, such as rights to bring derivative and other litigation, are far removed from the matters that intermediaries are expected to perform.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. This section, and the two that follow, deal with the aspects of securities holding that are related to investment decisions. For example, one of the rights of holding a particular security that would fall within the purview of this section would be the right to exercise a conversion right for a convertible security. It is quite common for investors to confer discretionary authority upon another person, such as an investment adviser, with respect to these rights and other investment decisions. Because this section, and the other sections of Part 5, all specify that a securities intermediary satisfies the Part 5 duties if it acts in accordance with the entitlement holder’s agreement, there is no inconsistency between the statement of duties of a securities intermediary and these common arrangements.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4.  Section 8-509 also applies to the  Section 8-506 duty, so that compliance with applicable regulatory requirements constitutes compliance with this duty. This is quite important in this context, since the federal securities laws establish a comprehensive system of regulation of the distribution of proxy materials and exercise of voting rights with respect to securities held through brokers and other intermediaries. By virtue of  Section 8-509(a), compliance with such regulatory requirement constitutes compliance with the  Section 8-506 duty.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References</strong> “Agreement”.  Section 1-201(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Entitlement holder”.  Section 8-102(a)(7).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Financial asset”.  Section 8-102(a)(9).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Securities intermediary”.  Section 8-102(a)(14).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Security entitlement”.  Section 8-102(a)(17).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
