<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:8-502</num>
  <heading>Assertion of adverse claim against entitlement holder.</heading>
  <text>An action based on an adverse claim to a financial asset, whether framed in conversion, replevin, constructive trust, equitable lien, or other theory, may not be asserted against a person who acquires a security entitlement under § <cite path="§28:8-501">28:8-501</cite> for value and without notice of the adverse claim.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-240" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:8-510">28:8-510</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:8-502.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. The section provides investors in the indirect holding system with protection against adverse claims by specifying that no adverse claim can be asserted against a person who acquires a security entitlement under  Section 8-501 for value and without notice of the adverse claim. It plays a role in the indirect holding system analogous to the rule of the direct holding system that protected purchasers take free from adverse claims ( Section 8-303).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">This section does not use the locution “takes free from adverse claims” because that could be confusing as applied to the indirect holding system. The nature of indirect holding system is that an entitlement holder has an interest in common with others who hold positions in the same financial asset through the same intermediary. Thus, a particular entitlement holder’s interest in the financial assets held by its intermediary is necessarily “subject to” the interests of others. See  Section 8-503. The rule stated in this section might have been expressed by saying that a person who acquires a security entitlement under  Section 8-501 for value and without notice of adverse claims takes “that security entitlement” free from adverse claims. That formulation has not been used, however, for fear that it would be misinterpreted as suggesting that the person acquires a right to the underlying financial assets that could not be affected by the competing rights of others claiming through common or higher tier intermediaries. A security entitlement is a complex bundle of rights. This section does not deal with the question of what rights are in the bundle. Rather, this section provides that once a person has acquired the bundle, someone else cannot take it away on the basis of assertion that the transaction in which the security entitlement was created involved a violation of the claimant’s rights.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Because securities trades are typically settled on a net basis by book-entry movements, it would ordinarily be impossible for anyone to trace the path of any particular security, no matter how the interest of parties who hold through intermediaries is described. Suppose, for example, that S has a 1000 share position in XYZ common stock through an account with a broker, Able &amp; Co. S’s identical twin impersonates S and directs Able to sell the securities. That same day, B places an order with Baker &amp; Co., to buy 1000 shares of XYZ common stock. Later, S discovers the wrongful act and seeks to recover “her shares.” Even if S can show that, at the stage of the trade, her sell order was matched with B’s buy order, that would not suffice to show that “her shares” went to B. Settlement between Able and Baker occurs on a net basis for all trades in XYZ that day; indeed Able’s net position may have been such that it received rather than delivered shares in XYZ through the settlement system.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">In the unlikely event that this was the only trade in XYZ common stock executed in the market that day, one could follow the shares from S’s account to B’s account. The plaintiff in an action in conversion or similar legal action to enforce a property interest must show that the defendant has an item of property that belongs to the plaintiff. In this example, B’s security entitlement is not the same item of property that formerly was held by S, it is a new package of rights that B acquired against Baker under  Section 8-501. Principles of equitable remedies might, however, provide S with a basis for contending that if the position B received was the traceable product of the wrongful taking of S’s property by S’s twin, a constructive trust should be imposed on B’s property in favor of S. See G. Palmer, The Law of Restitution s 2.14.  Section 8-502 ensures that no such claims can be asserted against a person, such as B in this example, who acquires a security entitlement under  Section 8-501 for value and without notice, regardless of what theory of law or equity is used to describe the basis of the assertion of the adverse claim.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">In the above example, S would ordinarily have no reason to pursue B unless Able is insolvent and S’s claim will not be satisfied in the insolvency proceedings. Because S did not give an entitlement order for the disposition of her security entitlement, Able must recredit her account for the 1000 shares of XYZ common stock. See  Section 8-507(b).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. The following examples illustrate the operation of  Section 8-502.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Example 1. Thief steals bearer bonds from Owner. Thief delivers the bonds to Broker for credit to Thief’s securities account, thereby acquiring a security entitlement under  Section 8-501(b). Under other law, Owner may have a claim to have a constructive trust imposed on the security entitlement as the traceable product of the bonds that Thief misappropriated. Because Thief was himself the wrongdoer, Thief obviously had notice of Owner’s adverse claim. Accordingly,  Section 8-502 does not preclude Owner from asserting an adverse claim against Thief.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Example 2. Thief steals bearer bonds from Owner. Thief owes a personal debt to Creditor. Creditor has a securities account with Broker. Thief agrees to transfer the bonds to Creditor as security for or in satisfaction of his debt to Creditor. Thief does so by sending the bonds to Broker for credit to Creditor’s securities account. Creditor thereby acquires a security entitlement under  Section 8-501(b). Under other law, Owner may have a claim to have a constructive trust imposed on the security entitlement as the traceable product of the bonds that Thief misappropriated. Creditor acquired the security entitlement for value, since Creditor acquired it as security for or in satisfaction of Thief’s debt to Creditor. See  Section 1-201(44). If Creditor did not have notice of Owner’s claim,  Section 8-502 precludes any action by Owner against Creditor, whether framed in constructive trust or other theory.  Section 8-105 specifies what counts as notice of an adverse claim.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Example 3. Father, as trustee for Son, holds XYZ Co. shares in a securities account with Able &amp; Co. In violation of his fiduciary duties, Father sells the XYZ Co. shares and uses the proceeds for personal purposes. Father dies, and his estate is insolvent. Assume—implausibly—that Son is able to trace the XYZ Co. shares and show that the “same shares” ended up in Buyer’s securities account with Baker &amp; Co.  Section 8-502 precludes any action by Son against Buyer, whether framed in constructive trust or other theory, provided that Buyer acquired the security entitlement for value and without notice of adverse claims.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Example 4. Debtor holds XYZ Co. shares in a securities account with Able &amp; Co. As collateral for a loan from Bank, Debtor grants Bank a security interest in the security entitlement to the XYZ Co. shares. Bank perfects by a method which leaves Debtor with the ability to dispose of the shares. See  Section 9-312. In violation of the security agreement, Debtor sells the XYZ Co. shares and absconds with the proceeds. Assume—implausibly—that Bank is able to trace the XYZ Co. shares and show that the “same shares” ended up in Buyer’s securities account with Baker &amp; Co.  Section 8-502 precludes any action by Bank against Buyer, whether framed in constructive trust or other theory, provided that Buyer acquired the security entitlement for value and without notice of adverse claims.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Example 5. Debtor owns controlling interests in various public companies, including Acme and Ajax. Acme owns 60% of the stock of another public company, Beta. Debtor causes the Beta stock to be pledged to Lending Bank as collateral for Ajax’s debt. Acme holds the Beta stock through an account with a securities custodian, C Bank, which in turn holds through Clearing Corporation. Lending Bank is also a Clearing Corporation participant. The pledge of the Beta stock is implemented by Acme instructing C Bank to instruct Clearing Corporation to debit C Bank’s account and credit Lending Bank’s account. Acme and Ajax both become insolvent. The Beta stock is still valuable. Acme’s liquidator asserts that the pledge of the Beta stock for Ajax’s debt was wrongful as against Acme and seeks to recover the Beta stock from Lending Bank. Because the pledge was implemented by an outright transfer into Lending Bank’s account at Clearing Corporation, Lending Bank acquired a security entitlement to the Beta stock under  Section 8-501. Lending Bank acquired the security entitlement for value, since it acquired it as security for a debt. See  Section 1-201(44). If Lending Bank did not have notice of Acme’s claim,  Section 8-502 will preclude any action by Acme against Lending Bank, whether framed in constructive trust or other theory.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Example 6. Debtor grants Alpha Co. a security interest in a security entitlement that includes 1000 shares of XYZ Co. stock that Debtor holds through an account with Able &amp; Co. Alpha also has an account with Able. Debtor instructs Able to transfer the shares to Alpha, and Able does so by crediting the shares to Alpha’s account. Alpha has control of the 1000 shares under  Section 8-106(d). (The facts to this point are identical to those in  Section 8-106, Comment 4, Example 1, except that Alpha Co. was Alpha Bank.) Alpha next grants Beta Co. a security interest in the 1000 shares included in Alpha’s security entitlement. See  Section 9-207(c)(3). Alpha instructs Able to transfer the shares to Gamma Co., Beta’s custodian. Able does so, and Gamma credits the 1000 shares to Beta’s account. Beta now has control under  Section 8-106(d). By virtue of Debtor’s explicit permission or by virtue of the permission inherent in Debtor’s creation of a security interest in favor of Alpha and Alpha’s resulting power to grant a security interest under  Section 9-207, Debtor has no adverse claim to assert against Beta, assuming implausibly that Debtor could “trace” an interest to the Gamma account. Moreover, even if Debtor did hold an adverse claim, if Beta did not have notice of Debtor’s claim,  Section 8-502 will preclude any action by Debtor against Beta, whether framed in constructive trust or other theory.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Although this section protects entitlement holders against adverse claims, it does not protect them against the risk that their securities intermediary will not itself have sufficient financial assets to satisfy the claims of all of its entitlement holders. Suppose that Customer A holds 1000 shares of XYZ Co. stock in an account with her broker, Able &amp; Co. Able in turn holds 1000 shares of XYZ Co. through its account with Clearing Corporation, but has no other positions in XYZ Co. shares, either for other customers or for its own proprietary account. Customer B places an order with Able for the purchase of 1000 shares of XYZ Co. stock, and pays the purchase price. Able credits B’s account with a 1000 share position in XYZ Co. stock, but Able does not itself buy any additional XYZ Co. shares. Able fails, having only 1000 shares to satisfy the claims of A and B. Unless other insolvency law establishes a different distributional rule, A and B would share the 1000 shares held by Able pro rata, without regard to the time that their respective entitlements were established. See  Section 8-503(b).  Section 8-502 protects entitlement holders, such as A and B, against adverse claimants. In this case, however, the problem that A and B face is not that someone is trying to take away their entitlements, but that the entitlements are not worth what they thought. The only role that  Section 8-502 plays in this case is to preclude any assertion that A has some form of claim against B by virtue of the fact that Able’s establishment of an entitlement in favor of B diluted A’s rights to the limited assets held by Able.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References</strong> “Adverse claim”.  Section 8-102(a)(1).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Financial asset”.  Section 8-102(a)(9).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Notice of adverse claim”.  Section 8-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Security entitlement”.  Section 8-102(a)(17).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Value”.  Sections 1-201(44) and  8-116.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
