<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:8-109</num>
  <heading>Warranties in indirect holding.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who originates an entitlement order to a securities intermediary warrants to the securities intermediary that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The entitlement order is made by an appropriate person, or if the entitlement order is by an agent, the agent has actual authority to act on behalf of the appropriate person; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>There is no adverse claim to the security entitlement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who delivers a security certificate to a securities intermediary for credit to a securities account or originates an instruction with respect to an uncertificated security directing that the uncertificated security be credited to a securities account makes to the securities intermediary the warranties specified in § <cite path="§28:8-108">28:8-108</cite>(a) or (b).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a securities intermediary delivers a security certificate to its entitlement holder or causes its entitlement holder to be registered as the owner of an uncertificated security, the securities intermediary makes to the entitlement holder the warranties specified in § <cite path="§28:8-108">28:8-108</cite>(a) or (b).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-240" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:8-109.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Subsection (a) provides that a person who originates an entitlement order warrants to the securities intermediary that the order is authorized, and warrants the absence of adverse claims. Subsection (b) specifies the warranties that are given when a person who holds securities directly has the holding converted into indirect form. A person who delivers a certificate to a securities intermediary or originates an instruction for an uncertificated security gives to the securities intermediary the transfer warranties under  Section 8-108. If the securities intermediary in turn delivers the certificate to a higher level securities intermediary, it gives the same warranties.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Subsection (c) states the warranties that a securities intermediary gives when a customer who has been holding securities in an account with the securities intermediary requests that certificates be delivered or that uncertificated securities be registered in the customer’s name. The warranties are the same as those that brokers make with respect to securities that the brokers sell to or buy on behalf of the customers. See  Section 8-108(i).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. As with the  Section 8-108 warranties, the warranties specified in this section may be modified by agreement under  Section 1-102(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References</strong> “Adverse claim”.  Section 8-102(a)(1).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Appropriate person”.  Section 8-107.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Entitlement holder”.  Section 8-102(a)(7).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Entitlement order”.  Section 8-102(a)(8).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Instruction”.  Section 8-102(a)(12).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Person”.  Section 1-201(30).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Securities account”.  Section 8-501.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Securities intermediary”.  Section 8-102(a)(14).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Security certificate”.  Section 8-102(a)(16).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Uncertificated security”.  Section 8-102(a)(18).</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
