<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:8-306</num>
  <heading>Effect of guaranteeing signature, indorsement, or instruction.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who guarantees a signature of an indorser of a security certificate warrants that at the time of signing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The signature was genuine;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The signer was an appropriate person to indorse, or if the signature is by an agent, the agent had actual authority to act on behalf of the appropriate person; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The signer had legal capacity to sign.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who guarantees a signature of the originator of an instruction warrants that at the time of signing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The signature was genuine;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The signer was an appropriate person to originate the instruction, or if the signature is by an agent, the agent had actual authority to act on behalf of the appropriate person, if the person specified in the instruction as the registered owner was, in fact, the registered owner, as to which fact the signature guarantor does not make a warranty; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The signer had legal capacity to sign.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person who specially guarantees the signature of an originator of an instruction makes the warranties of a signature guarantor under subsection (b) of this section and also warrants that at the time the instruction is presented to the issuer:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The person specified in the instruction as the registered owner of the uncertificated security will be the registered owner; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The transfer of the uncertificated security requested in the instruction will be registered by the issuer free from all liens, security interests, restrictions, and claims other than those specified in the instruction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A guarantor under subsections (a) and (b) of this section or a special guarantor under subsection (c) of this section does not otherwise warrant the rightfulness of the transfer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A person who guarantees an indorsement of a security certificate makes the warranties of a signature guarantor under subsection (a) of this section and also warrants the rightfulness of the transfer in all respects.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A person who guarantees an instruction requesting the transfer of an uncertificated security makes the warranties of a special signature guarantor under subsection (c) of this section and also warrants the rightfulness of the transfer in all respects.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>An issuer may not require a special guaranty of signature, a guaranty of indorsement, or a guaranty of instruction as a condition to registration of transfer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The warranties under this section are made to a person taking or dealing with the security in reliance on the guaranty, and the guarantor is liable to the person for loss resulting from their breach. An indorser or originator of an instruction whose signature, indorsement, or instruction has been guaranteed is liable to a guarantor for any loss suffered by the guarantor as a result of breach of the warranties of the guarantor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 739, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-196">Mar. 16, 1993, D.C. Law 9-196, § 4, 39 DCR 9165</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-240">renumbered and amended, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 28:8-306.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 28:8-306.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text>1. Subsection (a) provides that a guarantor of the signature of the indorser of a security certificate warrants that the signature is genuine, that the signer is an appropriate person or has actual authority to indorse on behalf of the appropriate person, and that the signer has legal capacity. Subsection (b) provides similar, though not identical, warranties for the guarantor of a signature of the originator of an instruction for transfer of an uncertificated security.</text>
      <text>Appropriate person is defined in  Section 8-107(a) to include a successor or person who has power under other law to act for a person who is deceased or lacks capacity. Thus if a certificate registered in the name of Mary Roe is indorsed by Jane Doe as executor of Mary Roe, a guarantor of the signature of Jane Doe warrants that she has power to act as executor.</text>
      <text>Although the definition of appropriate person in  Section 8-107(a) does not itself include an agent, an indorsement by an agent is effective under  Section 8-107(b) if the agent has authority to act for the appropriate person. Accordingly, this section provides an explicit warranty of authority for agents.</text>
      <text>2. The rationale of the principle that a signature guarantor warrants the authority of the signer, rather than simply the genuineness of the signature, was explained in the leading case of  Jennie Clarkson Home for Children v. Missouri, K. &amp; T. R. Co., 182 N.Y. 47, 74 N.E. 571, 70 A.L.R. 787 (1905), which dealt with a guaranty of the signature of a person indorsing on behalf of a corporation. “If stock is held by an individual who is executing a power of attorney for its transfer, the member of the exchange who signs as a witness thereto guaranties not only the genuineness of the signature affixed to the power of attorney, but that the person signing is the individual in whose name the stock stands. With reference to stock standing in the name of a corporation, which can only sign a power of attorney through its authorized officers or agents, a different situation is presented.</text>
      <text>If the witnessing of the signature of the corporation is only that of the signature of a person who signs for the corporation, then the guaranty is of no value, and there is nothing to protect purchasers or the companies who are called upon to issue new stock in the place of that transferred from the frauds of persons who have signed the names of corporations without authority. If such is the only effect of the guaranty, purchasers and transfer agents must first go to the corporation in whose name the stock stands and ascertain whether the individual who signed the power of attorney had authority to so do. This will require time, and in many cases will necessitate the postponement of the completion of the purchase by the payment of the money until the facts can be ascertained. The broker who is acting for the owner has an opportunity to become acquainted with his customer, and may readily before sale ascertain, in case of a corporation, the name of the officer who is authorized to execute the power of attorney. It was therefore, we think, the purpose of the rule to cast upon the broker who witnesses the signature the duty of ascertaining whether the person signing the name of the corporation had authority to so do, and making the witness a guarantor that it is the signature of the corporation in whose name the stock stands.”</text>
      <text>3. Subsection (b) sets forth the warranties that can reasonably be expected from the guarantor of the signature of the originator of an instruction, who, though familiar with the signer, does not have any evidence that the purported owner is in fact the owner of the subject uncertificated security. This is in contrast to the position of the person guaranteeing a signature on a certificate who can see a certificate in the signer’s possession in the name of or indorsed to the signer or in blank. Thus, the warranty in paragraph (2) of subsection (b) is expressly conditioned on the actual registration’s conforming to that represented by the originator. If the signer purports to be the owner, the guarantor under paragraph (2), warrants only the identity of the signer. If, however, the signer is acting in a representative capacity, the guarantor warrants both the signer’s identity and authority to act for the purported owner. The issuer needs no warranty as to the facts of registration because those facts can be ascertained from the issuer’s own records.</text>
      <text>4. Subsection (c) sets forth a “special guaranty of signature” under which the guarantor additionally warrants both registered ownership and freedom from undisclosed defects of record. The guarantor of the signature of an indorser of a security certificate effectively makes these warranties to a purchaser for value on the evidence of a clean certificate issued in the name of the indorser, indorsed to the indorser or indorsed in blank. By specially guaranteeing under subsection (c), the guarantor warrants that the instruction will, when presented to the issuer, result in the requested registration free from defects not specified.</text>
      <text>5. Subsection (d) makes clear that the warranties of a signature guarantor are limited to those specified in this section and do not include a general warranty of rightfulness. On the other hand subsections (e) and (f) provide that a person guaranteeing an indorsement or an instruction does warrant that the transfer is rightful in all respects.</text>
      <text>6. Subsection (g) makes clear what can be inferred from the combination of  Sections 8-401 and  8-402, that the issuer may not require as a condition to transfer a guaranty of the indorsement or instruction nor may it require a special signature guaranty.</text>
      <text>7. Subsection (h) specifies to whom the warranties in this section run, and also provides that a person who gives a guaranty under this section has an action against the indorser or originator for any loss suffered by the guarantor.</text>
      <text><strong>Definitional Cross References</strong> “Appropriate person”.  Section 8-107.</text>
      <text>“Genuine”.  Section 1-201(18).</text>
      <text>“Indorsement”.  Section 8-102(a)(11).</text>
      <text>“Instruction”.  Section 8-102(a)(12).</text>
      <text>“Issuer”.  Section 8-201.</text>
      <text>“Security certificate”.  Section 8-102(a)(16).</text>
      <text>“Uncertificated security”.  Section 8-102(a)(18).</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
