<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:8-404</num>
  <heading>Wrongful registration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in § <cite path="§28:8-406">28:8-406</cite>, an issuer is liable for wrongful registration of transfer if the issuer has registered a transfer of a security to a person not entitled to it, and the transfer was registered:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Pursuant to an ineffective indorsement or instruction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>After a demand that the issuer not register transfer became effective under § <cite path="§28:8-403">28:8-403</cite>(a) and the issuer did not comply with § <cite path="§28:8-403">28:8-403</cite>(b);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>After the issuer had been served with an injunction, restraining order, or other legal process enjoining it from registering the transfer, issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, and the issuer had a reasonable opportunity to act on the injunction, restraining order, or other legal process; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>By an issuer acting in collusion with the wrongdoer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An issuer that is liable for wrongful registration of transfer under subsection (a) of this section on demand shall provide the person entitled to the security with a like certificated or uncertificated security, and any payments or distributions that the person did not receive as a result of the wrongful registration. If an overissue would result, the issuer’s liability to provide the person with a like security is governed by § <cite path="§28:8-210">28:8-210</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (a) of this section or in a law relating to the collection of taxes, an issuer is not liable to an owner or other person suffering loss as a result of the registration of a transfer of a security if registration was made pursuant to an effective indorsement or instruction.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 739, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-196" type="History">Mar. 16, 1993, D.C. Law 9-196, § 4, 39 DCR 9165</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-240" type="History">renumbered and amended, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Subsection (a)(1) provides that an issuer is liable if it registers transfer pursuant to an indorsement or instruction that was not effective. For example, an issuer that registers transfer on a forged indorsement is liable to the registered owner. The fact that the issuer had no reason to suspect that the indorsement was forged or that the issuer obtained the ordinary assurances under  Section 8-402 does not relieve the issuer from liability. The reason that issuers obtain signature guaranties and other assurances is that they are liable for wrongful registration.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (b) specifies the remedy for wrongful registration. Pre-Code cases established the registered owner’s right to receive a new security where the issuer had wrongfully registered a transfer, but some cases also allowed the registered owner to elect between an equitable action to compel issue of a new security and an action for damages.  Cf. Casper v. Kalt-Zimmers Mfg. Co., 159 Wis. 517, 149 N.W. 754 (1914). Article 8 does not allow such election. The true owner of a certificated security is required to take a new security except where an overissue would result and a similar security is not reasonably available for purchase. See  Section 8-210. The true owner of an uncertificated security is entitled and required to take restoration of the records to their proper state, with a similar exception for overissue.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Read together, subsections (c) and (a) have the effect of providing that an issuer has no duties to an adverse claimant unless the claimant serves legal process on the issuer to enjoin registration. Issuers, or their transfer agents, perform a record-keeping function for the direct holding system that is analogous to the functions performed by clearing corporations and securities intermediaries in the indirect holding system. This section applies to the record-keepers for the direct holding system the same standard that  Section 8-115 applies to the record-keepers for the indirect holding system. Thus, issuers are not liable to adverse claimants merely on the basis of notice. As in the case of the analogous rules for the indirect holding system, the policy of this section is to protect the right of investors to have their securities transfers processed without the disruption or delay that might result if the record-keepers risked liability to third parties. It would be undesirable to apply different standards to the direct and indirect holding systems, since doing so might operate as a disincentive to the development of a book-entry direct holding system.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. This section changes prior law under which an issuer could be held liable, even though it registered transfer on an effective indorsement or instruction, if the issuer had in some fashion been notified that the transfer might be wrongful against a third party, and the issuer did not appropriately discharge its duty to inquire into the adverse claim. See  Section 8-403 (1978).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The rule of former  Section 8-403 was anomalous inasmuch as  Section 8-207 provides that the issuer is entitled to “treat the registered owner as the person exclusively entitled to vote, receive notifications, and otherwise exercise all the rights and powers of an owner.“ Under  Section 8-207, the fact that a third person notifies the issuer of a claim does not preclude the issuer from treating the registered owner as the person entitled to the security.  See Kerrigan v. American Orthodontics Corp., 960 F.2d 43 (7th Cir. 1992). The change made in the present version of  Section 8-404 ensures that the rights of registered owners and the duties of issuers with respect to registration of transfer will be protected against third-party interference in the same fashion as other rights of registered ownership.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References</strong> “Certificated security”.  Section 8-102(a)(4).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Effective”.  Section 8-107.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Indorsement”.  Section 8-102(a)(11).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Instruction”.  Section 8-102(a)(12).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Issuer”.  Section 8-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Security”.  Section 8-102(a)(15).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Uncertificated security”.  Section 8-102(a)(18).</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:8-404.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:8-404.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:8-406">28:8-406</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
