<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:8-402</num>
  <heading>Assurance that indorsement or instruction is effective.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An issuer may require the following assurance that each necessary indorsement or each instruction is genuine and authorized:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In all cases, a guaranty of the signature of the person making an indorsement or originating an instruction including, in the case of an instruction, reasonable assurance of identity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the indorsement is made or the instruction is originated by an agent, appropriate assurance of actual authority to sign;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the indorsement is made or the instruction is originated by a fiduciary pursuant to § <cite path="§28:8-107">28:8-107</cite>(a)(4) or (a)(5), appropriate evidence of appointment or incumbency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If there is more than one fiduciary, reasonable assurance that all who are required to sign have done so; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>If the indorsement is made or the instruction is originated by a person not covered by another provision of this subsection, assurance appropriate to the case corresponding as nearly as may be to the provisions of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An issuer may elect to require reasonable assurance beyond that specified in this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Guaranty of the signature” means a guaranty signed by or on behalf of a person reasonably believed by the issuer to be responsible. An issuer may adopt standards with respect to responsibility if they are not manifestly unreasonable.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Appropriate evidence of appointment or incumbency” means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of a fiduciary appointed or qualified by a court, a certificate issued by or under the direction or supervision of the court or an officer thereof and dated within 60 days before the date of presentation for transfer; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In any other case, a copy of a document showing the appointment or a certificate issued by or on behalf of a person reasonably believed by an issuer to be responsible or, in the absence of that document or certificate, other evidence the issuer reasonably considers appropriate.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 742, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-196">Mar. 16, 1993, D.C. Law 9-196, § 4, 39 DCR 9165</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-240">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:8-401">28:8-401</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 28:8-402.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 28:8-402.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text>1. An issuer is absolutely liable for wrongful registration of transfer if the indorsement or instruction is ineffective. See  Section 8-404. Accordingly, an issuer is entitled to require such assurance as is reasonable under the circumstances that all necessary indorsements are effective, and thus to minimize its risk. This section establishes the requirements the issuer may make in terms of documentation which, except in the rarest of instances, should be easily furnished. Subsection (b) provides that an issuer may require additional assurances if that requirement is reasonable under the circumstances, but if the issuer demands more than reasonable assurance that the instruction or the necessary indorsements are genuine and authorized, the presenter may refuse the demand and sue for improper refusal to register.  Section 8-401(b).</text>
      <text>2. Under subsection (a)(1), the issuer may require in all cases a guaranty of signature. See  Section 8-306. When an instruction is presented the issuer always may require reasonable assurance as to the identity of the originator. Subsection (c) allows the issuer to require that the person making these guaranties be one reasonably believed to be responsible, and the issuer may adopt standards of responsibility which are not manifestly unreasonable. Regulations under the federal securities laws, however, place limits on the requirements transfer agents may impose concerning the responsibility of eligible signature guarantors. See  17 CFR 240.17Ad-15.</text>
      <text>3. This section, by paragraphs (2) through (5) of subsection (a), permits the issuer to seek confirmation that the indorsement or instruction is genuine and authorized. The permitted methods act as a double check on matters which are within the warranties of the signature guarantor. See  Section 8-306. Thus, an agent may be required to submit a power of attorney, a corporation to submit a certified resolution evidencing the authority of its signing officer to sign, an executor or administrator to submit the usual “short-form certificate,” etc. But failure of a fiduciary to obtain court approval of the transfer or to comply with other requirements does not make the fiduciary’s signature ineffective.  Section 8-107(c). Hence court orders and other controlling instruments are omitted from subsection (a).</text>
      <text>Subsection (a)(3) authorizes the issuer to require “appropriate evidence” of appointment or incumbency, and subsection (c) indicates what evidence will be “appropriate”. In the case of a fiduciary appointed or qualified by a court that evidence will be a court certificate dated within sixty days before the date of presentation, subsection (c)(2)(i). Where the fiduciary is not appointed or qualified by a court, as in the case of a successor trustee, subsection (c)(2)(ii) applies. In that case, the issuer may require a copy of a trust instrument or other document showing the appointment, or it may require the certificate of a responsible person. In the absence of such a document or certificate, it may require other appropriate evidence. If the security is registered in the name of the fiduciary as such, the person’s signature is effective even though the person is no longer serving in that capacity, see  Section 8-107(d), hence no evidence of incumbency is needed.</text>
      <text>4. Circumstances may indicate that a necessary signature was unauthorized or was not that of an appropriate person. Such circumstances would be ignored at risk of absolute liability. To minimize that risk the issuer may properly exercise the option given by subsection (b) to require assurance beyond that specified in subsection (a). On the other hand, the facts at hand may reflect only on the rightfulness of the transfer. Such facts do not create a duty of inquiry, because the issuer is not liable to an adverse claimant unless the claimant obtains legal process. See  Section 8-404.</text>
      <text><strong>Definitional Cross References</strong> “Appropriate person”.  Section 8-107.</text>
      <text>“Genuine”.  Section 1-201(18).</text>
      <text>“Indorsement”.  Section 8-102(a)(11).</text>
      <text>“Instruction”.  Section 8-102(a)(12).</text>
      <text>“Issuer”.  Section 8-201.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
