<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:9-627</num>
  <heading>Determination of whether conduct was commercially reasonable.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The fact that a greater amount could have been obtained by a collection, enforcement, disposition, or acceptance at a different time or in a different method from that selected by the secured party is not of itself sufficient to preclude the secured party from establishing that the collection, enforcement, disposition, or acceptance was made in a commercially reasonable manner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A disposition of collateral is made in a commercially reasonable manner if the disposition is made:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the usual manner on any recognized market;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At the price current in any recognized market at the time of the disposition; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Otherwise in conformity with reasonable commercial practices among dealers in the type of property that was the subject of the disposition.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A collection, enforcement, disposition, or acceptance is commercially reasonable if it has been approved:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In a judicial proceeding;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By a bona fide creditors’ committee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By a representative of creditors; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>By an assignee for the benefit of creditors.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Approval under subsection (c) need not be obtained, and lack of approval does not mean that the collection, enforcement, disposition, or acceptance is not commercially reasonable.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Source. Former  Section 9-507(2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Relationship of Price to Commercial Reasonableness. Some observers have found the notion contained in subsection (a) (derived from former  Section 9-507(2)) (the fact that a better price could have been obtained does not establish lack of commercial reasonableness) to be inconsistent with that found in  Section 9-610(b) (derived from former  Section 9-504(3) (every aspect of the disposition, including its terms, must be commercially reasonable). There is no such inconsistency. While not itself sufficient to establish a violation of this Part, a low price suggests that a court should scrutinize carefully all aspects of a disposition to ensure that each aspect was commercially reasonable.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">The law long has grappled with the problem of dispositions of personal and real property which comply with applicable procedural requirements (e.g., advertising, notification to interested persons, etc.) but which yield a price that seems low. This Article addresses that issue in  Section 9-615(f). That section applies only when the transferee is the secured party, a person related to the secured party, or a secondary obligor. It contains a special rule for calculating a deficiency or surplus in a complying disposition that yields a price that is “significantly below the range of proceeds that a complying disposition to a person other than the secured party, a person related to the secured party, or a secondary obligor would have brought.”</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Determination of Commercial Reasonableness; Advance Approval. It is important to make clear the conduct and procedures that are commercially reasonable and to provide a secured party with the means of obtaining, by court order or negotiation with a creditors’ committee or a representative of creditors, advance approval of a proposed method of enforcement as commercially reasonable. This section contains rules that assist in that determination and provides for advance approval in appropriate situations. However, none of the specific methods of disposition specified in subsection (b) is required or exclusive.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. “Recognized Market.” As in  Sections 9-610(c) and  9-611(d), the concept of a “recognized market” in subsections (b)(1) and (2) is quite limited; it applies only to markets in which there are standardized price quotations for property that is essentially fungible, such as stock exchanges.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
