<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:9-107</num>
  <heading>Control of letter-of-credit right.</heading>
  <text>A secured party has control of a letter-of-credit right to the extent of any right to payment or performance by the issuer or any nominated person if the issuer or nominated person has consented to an assignment of proceeds of the letter of credit under § <cite path="§28:5-114">28:5-114</cite>(c) or otherwise applicable law or practice.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:9-203">28:9-203</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-207">28:9-207</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-208">28:9-208</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-314">28:9-314</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-329">28:9-329</cite>, and § <cite path="§28:9-601">28:9-601</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Source. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. “Control” of Letter-of-Credit Right. Whether a secured party has control of a letter-of-credit right may determine the secured party’s priority as against competing secured parties. See  Section 9-329. This section provides that a secured party acquires control of a letter-of-credit right by receiving an assignment if the secured party obtains the consent of the issuer or any nominated person, such as a confirmer or negotiating bank, under  Section 5-114 or other applicable law or practice. Because both issuers and nominated persons may give or be obligated to give value under a letter of credit, this section contemplates that a secured party obtains control of a letter-of-credit right with respect to the issuer or a particular nominated person only to the extent that the issuer or that nominated person consents to the assignment. For example, if a secured party obtains control to the extent of an issuer’s obligation but fails to obtain the consent of a nominated person, the secured party does not have control to the extent that the nominated person gives value. In many cases the person or persons who will give value under a letter of credit will be clear from its terms. In other cases, prudence may suggest obtaining consent from more than one person. The details of the consenting issuer’s or nominated person’s duties to pay or otherwise render performance to the secured party are left to the agreement of the parties.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. “Proceeds of a Letter of Credit.”  Section 5-114 follows traditional banking terminology by referring to a letter of credit beneficiary’s assignment of its right to receive payment thereunder as an assignment of the “proceeds of a letter of credit.“ However, as the seller of goods can assign its right to receive payment (an ‘’account“) before it has been earned by delivering the goods to the buyer, so the beneficiary of a letter of credit can assign its contingent right to payment before the letter of credit has been honored. See  Section 5-114(b). If the assignment creates a security interest, the security interest can be perfected at the time it is created. An assignment of, including the creation of a security interest in, a letter-of-credit right is an assignment of a present interest.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. “Transfer” vs. “Assignment.” Letter-of-credit law and practice distinguish the “transfer” of a letter of credit from an “assignment.” Under a transfer, the transferee itself becomes the beneficiary and acquires the right to draw. Whether a new, substitute credit is issued or the issuer advises the transferee of its status as such, the transfer constitutes a novation under which the transferee is the new, substituted beneficiary (but only to the extent of the transfer, in the case of a partial transfer).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Section 5-114(e) provides that the rights of a transferee beneficiary or nominated person are independent of the beneficiary’s assignment of the proceeds of a letter of credit and are superior to the assignee’s right to the proceeds. For this reason, transfer does not appear in this Article as a means of control or perfection.  Section 9-109(c)(4) recognizes the independent and superior rights of a transferee beneficiary under  Section 5-114(e); this Article does not apply to the rights of a transferee beneficiary or nominated person to the extent that those rights are independent and superior under  Section 5-114.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. Supporting Obligation: Automatic Attachment and Perfection. A letter-of-credit right is a type of “supporting obligation,” as defined in  Section 9-102. Under  Sections 9-203 and  9-308, a security interest in a letter-of-credit right automatically attaches and is automatically perfected if the security interest in the supported obligation is a perfected security interest. However, unless the secured party has control of the letter-of-credit right or itself becomes a transferee beneficiary, it cannot obtain any rights against the issuer or a nominated person under Article 5. Consequently, as a practical matter, the secured party’s rights would be limited to its ability to locate and identify proceeds distributed by the issuer or nominated person under the letter of credit.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
