<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:9-340</num>
  <heading>Effectiveness of right of recoupment or set-off against deposit account.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c), a bank with which a deposit account is maintained may exercise any right of recoupment or set-off against a secured party that holds a security interest in the deposit account.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c), the application of this article to a security interest in a deposit account does not affect a right of recoupment or set-off of the secured party as to a deposit account maintained with the secured party.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The exercise by a bank of a set-off against a deposit account is ineffective against a secured party that holds a security interest in the deposit account which is perfected by control under § <cite path="§28:9-104">28:9-104</cite>(a)(3), if the set-off is based on a claim against the debtor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:9-109">28:9-109</cite> and § <cite path="§28:9-341">28:9-341</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Source. New; subsection (b) is based on a nonuniform Illinois amendment.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Set-off vs. Security Interest. This section resolves the conflict between a security interest in a deposit account and the bank’s rights of recoupment and set-off.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (a) states the general rule and provides that the bank may effectively exercise rights of recoupment and set-off against the secured party. Subsection (c) contains an exception: if the secured party has control under  Section 9-104(a)(3) (i.e., if it has become the bank’s customer), then any set-off exercised by the bank against a debt owed by the debtor (as opposed to a debt owed to the bank by the secured party) is ineffective. The bank may, however, exercise its recoupment rights effectively. This result is consistent with the priority rule in  Section 9-327(4), under which the security interest of a bank in a deposit account is subordinate to that of a secured party who has control under  Section 9-104(a)(3).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">This section deals with rights of set-off and recoupment that a bank may have under other law. It does not create a right of set-off or recoupment, nor is it intended to override any limitations or restrictions that other law imposes on the exercise of those rights.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Preservation of Set-Off Right. Subsection (b) makes clear that a bank may hold both a right of set-off against, and an Article 9 security interest in, the same deposit account. By holding a security interest in a deposit account, a bank does not impair any right of set-off it would otherwise enjoy. This subsection does not pertain to accounts evidenced by an instrument (e.g., certain certificates of deposit), which are excluded from the definition of “deposit accounts.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
