<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:9-201</num>
  <heading>General effectiveness of security agreement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in Subtitle I of Title 28, a security agreement is effective according to its terms between the parties, against purchasers of the collateral, and against creditors.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A transaction subject to this article is subject to any applicable rule of law which establishes a different rule for consumers and §§ <cite path="§28-3301">28-3301</cite> to 28-3314.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In case of conflict between this article and a rule of law, statute, or regulation described in subsection (b), the rule of law, statute, or regulation controls. Failure to comply with a statute or regulation described in subsection (b) has only the effect the statute or  regulation specifies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This article does not:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Validate any rate, charge, agreement, or practice that violates a rule of law, statute, or regulation described in subsection (b); or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Extend the application of the rule of law, statute, or regulation to a transaction not otherwise subject to it.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text>1. Source. Former  Sections 9-201,  9-203(4).</text>
      <text>2. Effectiveness of Security Agreement. Subsection (a) provides that a security agreement is generally effective. With certain exceptions, a security agreement is effective between the debtor and secured party and is likewise effective against third parties.</text>
      <text>Note that “security agreement” is used here (and elsewhere in this Article) as it is defined in  Section 9-102: “an agreement that creates or provides for a security interest.“ It follows that subsection (a) does not provide that every term or provision contained in a record that contains a security agreement or that is so labeled is effective. Properly read, former  Section 9-201 was to the same effect. Exceptions to the general rule of subsection (a) arise where there is an overriding provision in this Article or any other Article of the UCC. For example,  Section 9-317 subordinates unperfected security interests to lien creditors and certain buyers, and several provisions in Part 3 subordinate some security interests to other security interests and interests of purchasers.</text>
      <text>3. Law, Statutes, and Regulations Applicable to Certain Transactions. Subsection (b) makes clear that certain transactions, although subject to this Article, also are subject to other applicable laws relating to consumers or specified in that subsection. Subsection (c) provides that the other law is controlling in the event of a conflict, and that a violation of other law does not ipso facto constitute a violation of this Article. Subsection (d) provides that this Article does not validate violations under or extend the application of the other applicable laws.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
