<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:9-313</num>
  <heading>When possession by or delivery to secured party perfects security interest without filing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b), a secured party may perfect a security interest in tangible negotiable documents, goods, instruments, money, or tangible chattel paper by taking possession of the collateral. A secured party may perfect a security interest in certificated securities by taking delivery of the certificated securities under § <cite path="§28:8-301">28:8-301</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>With respect to goods covered by a certificate of title issued by the District, a secured party may perfect a security interest in the goods by taking possession of the goods only in the circumstances described in § <cite path="§28:9-316">28:9-316</cite>(d).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>With respect to collateral other than certificated securities and goods covered by a document, a secured party takes possession of collateral in the possession of a person other than the debtor, the secured party, or a lessee of the collateral from the debtor in the ordinary course of the debtor’s business, when:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The person in possession authenticates a record acknowledging that it holds possession of the collateral for the secured party’s benefit; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person takes possession of the collateral after having authenticated a record acknowledging that it will hold possession of collateral for the secured party’s benefit.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If perfection of a security interest depends upon possession of the collateral by a secured party, perfection occurs no earlier than the time the secured party takes possession and continues only while the secured party retains possession.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A security interest in a certificated security in registered form is perfected by delivery when delivery of the certificated security occurs under § <cite path="§28:8-301">28:8-301</cite> and remains perfected by delivery until the debtor obtains possession of the security certificate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A person in possession of collateral is not required to acknowledge that it holds possession for a secured party’s benefit.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If a person acknowledges that it holds possession for the secured party’s benefit:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The acknowledgment is effective under subsection (c) of this section or § <cite path="§28:8-301">28:8-301</cite>(a), even if the acknowledgment violates the rights of a debtor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Unless the person otherwise agrees or law other than this article otherwise provides, the person does not owe any duty to the secured party and is not required to confirm the acknowledgment to another person.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A secured party having possession of collateral does not relinquish possession by delivering the collateral to a person other than the debtor or a lessee of the collateral from the debtor in the ordinary course of the debtor’s business if the person was instructed before the delivery or is instructed contemporaneously with the delivery:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To hold possession of the collateral for the secured party’s benefit; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To redeliver the collateral to the secured party.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>A secured party does not relinquish possession, even if a delivery under subsection (h) violates the rights of a debtor. A person to which collateral is delivered under subsection (h) does not owe any duty to the secured party and is not required to confirm the delivery to another person unless the person otherwise agrees or law other than this article otherwise provides.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 11(j), 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:9-203">28:9-203</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-310">28:9-310</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-311">28:9-311</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-312">28:9-312</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-316">28:9-316</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-320">28:9-320</cite>, and § <cite path="§28:9-328">28:9-328</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-299">D.C. Law 19-299</cite> inserted “tangible” preceding “negotiable documents” in the first sentence of (a).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text>1. Source. Former  Sections 9-305,  9-115(6).</text>
      <text>2. Perfection by Possession. As under the common law of pledge, no filing is required by this Article to perfect a security interest if the secured party takes possession of the collateral. See  Section 9-310(b)(6).</text>
      <text>This section permits a security interest to be perfected by the taking of possession only when the collateral is goods, instruments, negotiable documents, money, or tangible chattel paper. Accounts, commercial tort claims, deposit accounts, investment property, letter-of-credit rights, letters of credit, money, and oil, gas, or other minerals before extraction are excluded. (But see Comment 6, below, regarding certificated securities.) A security interest in accounts and payment intangibles-property not ordinarily represented by any writing whose delivery operates to transfer the right to payment-may under this Article be perfected only by filing. This rule would not be affected by the fact that a security agreement or other record described the assignment of such collateral as a “pledge.”  Section 9-309(2) exempts from filing certain assignments of accounts or payment intangibles which are out of the ordinary course of financing. These exempted assignments are perfected when they attach. Similarly, under  Section 9-309(3), sales of payment intangibles are automatically perfected.</text>
      <text>3. “Possession.” This section does not define “possession.” It adopts the general concept as it developed under former Article 9. As under former Article 9, in determining whether a particular person has possession, the principles of agency apply. For example, if the collateral is in possession of an agent of the secured party for the purposes of possessing on behalf of the secured party, and if the agent is not also an agent of the debtor, the secured party has taken actual possession, and subsection (c) does not apply. Sometimes a person holds collateral both as an agent of the secured party and as an agent of the debtor. The fact of dual agency is not of itself inconsistent with the secured party’s having taken possession (and thereby having rendered subsection (c) inapplicable). The debtor cannot qualify as an agent for the secured party for purposes of the secured party’s taking possession. And, under appropriate circumstances, a court may determine that a person in possession is so closely connected to or controlled by the debtor that the debtor has retained effective possession, even though the person may have agreed to take possession on behalf of the secured party. If so, the person’s taking possession would not constitute the secured party’s taking possession and would not be sufficient for perfection. See also  Section 9-205(b). In a typical escrow arrangement, where the escrowee has possession of collateral as agent for both the secured party and the debtor, the debtor’s relationship to the escrowee is not such as to constitute retention of possession by the debtor.</text>
      <text>4. Goods in Possession of Third Party: Perfection. Former  Section 9-305 permitted perfection of a security interest by notification to a bailee in possession of collateral. This Article distinguishes between goods in the possession of a bailee who has issued a document of title covering the goods and goods in the possession of a third party who has not issued a document.  Section 9-312(c) or (d) applies to the former, depending on whether the document is negotiable.  Section 9-313(c) applies to the latter. It provides a method of perfection by possession when the collateral is possessed by a third person who is not the secured party’s agent.</text>
      <text>Notification of a third person does not suffice to perfect under  Section 9-313(c). Rather, perfection does not occur unless the third person authenticates an acknowledgment that it holds possession of the collateral for the secured party’s benefit. Compare  Section 9-312(d), under which receipt of notification of the security party’s interest by a bailee holding goods covered by a nonnegotiable document is sufficient to perfect, even if the bailee does not acknowledge receipt of the notification. A third person may acknowledge that it will hold for the secured party’s benefit goods to be received in the future. Under these circumstances, perfection by possession occurs when the third person obtains possession of the goods.</text>
      <text>Under subsection (c), acknowledgment of notification by a “lessee ... in ... ordinary course of ... business” (defined in Section 2A-103) does not suffice for possession. The section thus rejects the reasoning of  In re Atlantic Systems, Inc., 135 B.R. 463 (Bankr. S.D.N.Y.1992) (holding that notification to debtor-lessor’s lessee sufficed to perfect security interest in leased goods). See Steven O. Weise, Perfection by Possession: The Need for an Objective Test,  29 Idaho Law Rev. 705 (1992-93) (arguing that lessee’s possession in ordinary course of debtor-lessor’s business does not provide adequate public notice of possible security interest in leased goods). Inclusion of a per se rule concerning lessees is not meant to preclude a court, under appropriate circumstances, from determining that a third person is so closely connected to or controlled by the debtor that the debtor has retained effective possession. If so, the third person’s acknowledgment would not be sufficient for perfection.</text>
      <text>In some cases, it may be uncertain whether a person who has possession of collateral is an agent of the secured party or a non-agent bailee. Under those circumstances, prudence might suggest that the secured party obtain the person’s acknowledgment to avoid litigation and ensure perfection by possession regardless of how the relationship between the secured party and the person is characterized.</text>
      <text>5. No Relation Back. Former  Section 9-305 provided that a security interest is perfected by possession from the time possession is taken “without a relation back.” As the Comment to former  Section 9-305 observed, the relation-back theory, under which the taking of possession was deemed to relate back to the date of the original security agreement, has had little vitality since the 1938 revision of the Federal Bankruptcy Act. The theory is inconsistent with former Article 9 and with this Article. See  Section 9-313(d). Accordingly, this Article deletes the quoted phrase as unnecessary. Where a pledge transaction is contemplated, perfection dates only from the time possession is taken, although a security interest may attach, unperfected. The only exceptions to this rule are the short, 20-day periods of perfection provided in  Section 9-312(e), (f), and (g), during which a debtor may have possession of specified collateral in which there is a perfected security interest.</text>
      <text>6. Certificated Securities. The second sentence of subsection (a) reflects the traditional rule for perfection of a security interest in certificated securities. Compare  Section 9-115(6) (1994 Official Text);  Sections 8-321,  8-313(1)(a) (1978 Official Text);  Section 9-305 (1972 Official Text). It has been modified to refer to “delivery” under  Section 8-301. Corresponding changes appear in  Section 9-203(b).</text>
      <text>Subsections (e), (f), and (g), which are new, apply to a person in possession of security certificates or holding security certificates for the secured party’s benefit under  Section 8-301. For delivery to occur when a person other than a secured party holds possession for the secured party, the person may not be a securities intermediary.</text>
      <text>Under subsection (e), a possessory security interest in a certificated security remains perfected until the debtor obtains possession of the security certificate. This rule is analogous to that of  Section 9-314(c), which deals with perfection of security interests in investment property by control. See  Section 9-314, Comment 3.</text>
      <text>7. Goods Covered by Certificate of Title. Subsection (b) is necessary to effect changes to the choice-of-law rules governing goods covered by a certificate of title. These changes are described in the Comments to  Section 9-311. Subsection (b), like subsection (a), does not create a right to take possession. Rather, it indicates the circumstances under which the secured party’s taking possession of goods covered by a certificate of title is effective to perfect a security interest in the goods: the goods become covered by a certificate of title issued by this State at a time when the security interest is perfected by any method under the law of another jurisdiction.</text>
      <text>8. Goods in Possession of Third Party: No Duty to Acknowledge; Consequences of Acknowledgment. Subsections (f) and (g) are new and address matters as to which former Article 9 was silent. They derive in part from  Section 8-106(g). Subsection (f) provides that a person in possession of collateral is not required to acknowledge that it holds for a secured party. Subsection (g)(1) provides that an acknowledgment is effective even if wrongful as to the debtor. Subsection (g)(2) makes clear that an acknowledgment does not give rise to any duties or responsibilities under this Article. Arrangements involving the possession of goods are hardly standardized. They include bailments for services to be performed on the goods (such as repair or processing), for use (leases), as security (pledges), for carriage, and for storage. This Article leaves to the agreement of the parties and to any other applicable law the imposition of duties and responsibilities upon a person who acknowledges under subsection (c). For example, by acknowledging, a third party does not become obliged to act on the secured party’s direction or to remain in possession of the collateral unless it agrees to do so or other law so provides.</text>
      <text>9. Delivery to Third Party by Secured Party. New subsections (h) and (i) address the practice of mortgage warehouse lenders. These lenders typically send mortgage notes to prospective purchasers under cover of letters advising the prospective purchasers that the lenders hold security interests in the notes. These lenders relied on notification to maintain perfection under former 9-305. Requiring them to obtain authenticated acknowledgments from each prospective purchaser under subsection (c) could be unduly burdensome and disruptive of established practices. Under subsection (h), when a secured party in possession itself delivers the collateral to a third party, instructions to the third party would be sufficient to maintain perfection by possession; an acknowledgment would not be necessary. Under subsection (i), the secured party does not relinquish possession by making a delivery under subsection (h), even if the delivery violates the rights of the debtor. That subsection also makes clear that a person to whom collateral is delivered under subsection (h) does not owe any duty to the secured party and is not required to confirm the delivery to another person unless the person otherwise agrees or law other than this Article provides otherwise.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
