<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:9-619</num>
  <heading>Transfer of record or legal title.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In this section, “transfer statement” means a record authenticated by a secured party stating:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That the debtor has defaulted in connection with an obligation secured by specified collateral;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That the secured party has exercised its post-default remedies with respect to the collateral;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That, by reason of the exercise, a transferee has acquired the rights of the debtor in the collateral; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The name and mailing address of the secured party, debtor, and transferee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A transfer statement entitles the transferee to the transfer of record of all rights of the debtor in the collateral specified in the statement in any official filing, recording, registration, or certificate-of-title system covering the collateral. If a transfer statement is presented with the applicable fee and request form to the official or office responsible for maintaining the system, the official or office shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Accept the transfer statement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Promptly amend its records to reflect the transfer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If applicable, issue a new appropriate certificate of title in the name of transferee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A transfer of the record or legal title to collateral to a secured party under subsection (b) or otherwise is not of itself a disposition of collateral under this article and does not of itself relieve the secured party of its duties under this article.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Source. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Transfer of Record or Legal Title. Potential buyers of collateral that is covered by a certificate of title (e.g., an automobile) or is subject to a registration system (e.g., a copyright) typically require as a condition of their purchase that the certificate or registry reflect their ownership. In many cases, this condition can be met only with the consent of the record owner. If the record owner is the debtor and, as may be the case after the default, the debtor refuses to cooperate, the secured party may have great difficulty disposing of the collateral.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (b) provides a simple mechanism for obtaining record or legal title, for use primarily when other law does not provide one. Of course, use of this mechanism will not be effective to clear title to the extent that subsection (b) is preempted by federal law. Subsection (b) contemplates a transfer of record or legal title to a third party, following a secured party’s exercise of its disposition or acceptance remedies under this Part, as well as a transfer by a debtor to a secured party prior to the secured party’s exercise of those remedies. Under subsection (c), a transfer of record or legal title (under subsection (b) or under other law) to a secured party prior to the exercise of those remedies merely puts the secured party in a position to pass legal or record title to a transferee at foreclosure. A secured party who has obtained record or legal title retains its duties with respect to enforcement of its security interest, and the debtor retains its rights as well.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Title-Clearing Systems Under Other Law. Applicable non-UCC law (e.g., a certificate-of-title statute, federal registry rules, or the like) may provide a means by which the secured party may obtain or transfer record or legal title for the purpose of a disposition of the property under this Article. The mechanism provided by this section is in addition to any title-clearing provision under law other than this Article.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
