<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:9-314</num>
  <heading>Perfection by control.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A security interest in investment property, deposit accounts, letter-of-credit rights, electronic chattel paper, or electronic documents may be perfected by control of the collateral under § <cite path="§28:7-106">28:7-106</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-104">28:9-104</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-105">28:9-105</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-106">28:9-106</cite>, or § <cite path="§28:9-107">28:9-107</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A security interest in deposit accounts, electronic chattel paper, or letter-of-credit rights, or electronic documents is perfected by control under § <cite path="§28:7-106">28:7-106</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-104">28:9-104</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-105">28:9-105</cite>, or § <cite path="§28:9-107">28:9-107</cite> when the secured party obtains control and remains perfected by control only while the secured party retains control.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A security interest in investment property is perfected by control under § <cite path="§28:9-106">28:9-106</cite> from the time the secured party obtains control and remains perfected by control until:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The secured party does not have control; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One of the following occurs:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If the collateral is a certificated security, the debtor has or acquires possession of the security certificate;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If the collateral is an uncertificated security, the issuer has registered or registers the debtor as the registered owner; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If the collateral is a security entitlement, the debtor is or becomes the entitlement holder.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 11(k), 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:9-310">28:9-310</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-312">28:9-312</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-327">28:9-327</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-328">28:9-328</cite>, and § <cite path="§28:9-329">28:9-329</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-299">D.C. Law 19-299</cite> rewrote (a) and (b).</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Source. Substantially new; derived in part from former  Section 9-115(4).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Control. This section provides for perfection by control with respect to investment property, deposit accounts, letter-of-credit rights, and electronic chattel paper. For explanations of how a secured party takes control of these types of collateral, see  Sections 9-104 through  9-107. Subsection (b) explains when a security interest is perfected by control and how long a security interest remains perfected by control. Like  Section 9-313(d) and for the same reasons, subsection (b) makes no reference to the doctrine of “relation back.” See  Section 9-313, Comment 5.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Investment Property. Subsection (c) provides a special rule for investment property. Once a secured party has control, its security interest remains perfected by control until the secured party ceases to have control and the debtor receives possession of collateral that is a certificated security, becomes the registered owner of collateral that is an uncertificated security, or becomes the entitlement holder of collateral that is a security entitlement. The result is particularly important in the “repledge” context. See  Section 9-207, Comment 5.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">In a transaction in which a secured party who has control grants a security interest in investment property or sells outright the investment property, by virtue of the debtor’s consent or applicable legal rules, a purchaser from the secured party typically will cut off the debtor’s rights in the investment property or be immune from the debtor’s claims. See  Section 9-207, Comments 5 and 6.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">If the investment property is a security, the debtor normally would retain no interest in the security following the purchase from the secured party, and a claim of the debtor against the secured party for redemption ( Section 9-623) or otherwise with respect to the security would be a purely personal claim. If the investment property transferred by the secured party is a financial asset in which the debtor had a security entitlement credited to a securities account maintained with the secured party as a securities intermediary, the debtor’s claim against the secured party could arise as a part of its securities account notwithstanding its personal nature. (This claim would be analogous to a “credit balance” in the securities account, which is a component of the securities account even though it is a personal claim against the intermediary.) In the case in which the debtor may retain an interest in investment property notwithstanding a repledge or sale by the secured party, subsection (c) makes clear that the security interest will remain perfected by control.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
