<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:9-613</num>
  <heading>Contents and form of notification before disposition of collateral: general.</heading>
  <text>Except in a consumer-goods transaction, the following rules apply:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The contents of a notification of disposition are sufficient if the notification:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Describes the debtor and the secured party;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Describes the collateral that is the subject of the intended disposition;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>States the method of intended disposition;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>States that the debtor is entitled to an accounting of the unpaid indebtedness and states the charge, if any, for an accounting; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>States the time and place of a public disposition or the time after which any other disposition is to be made.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Whether the contents of a notification that lacks any of the information specified in paragraph (1) are nevertheless sufficient is a question of fact.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The contents of a notification providing substantially the information specified in paragraph (1) are sufficient, even if the notification includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Information not specified by that paragraph; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Minor errors that are not seriously misleading.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>A particular phrasing of the notification is not required.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The following form of notification and the form appearing in § <cite path="§28:9-614">28:9-614</cite>(3), when completed, each provides sufficient information:</text>
    <text>
      <center>
        <strong>NOTIFICATION OF DISPOSITION OF COLLATERAL</strong>
      </center>
    </text>
    <text>“To: [Name of debtor, obligor, or other person to which the notification is sent]</text>
    <text>“From: [Name, address, and telephone number of secured party]</text>
    <text>“Name of Debtor(s): [Include only if debtor(s) are not an addressee]</text>
    <text>“[For a public disposition:]</text>
    <text>“We will sell [or lease or license, as applicable] the [describe collateral] [to the highest qualified bidder] in public as follows:</text>
    <text>“Day and Date: ...............</text>
    <text>“Time: ...............</text>
    <text>“Place: ...............</text>
    <text>“Time: ...............</text>
    <text>“[For a private disposition:]</text>
    <text>“We will sell [or lease or license, as applicable] the [describe collateral] privately sometime after [day and date].</text>
    <text>“You are entitled to an accounting of the unpaid indebtedness secured by the property that we intend to sell [or lease or license, as applicable] [for a charge of $..........]. You may request an accounting by calling us at [telephone number]</text>
    <text>
      <center>
        <strong>“[End of Form]”</strong>
      </center>
    </text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Source. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Contents of Notification. To comply with the “reasonable authenticated notification” requirement of  Section 9-611(b), the contents of a notification must be reasonable. Except in a consumer-goods transaction, the contents of a notification that includes the information set forth in paragraph (1) are sufficient as a matter of law, unless the parties agree otherwise. (The reference to “time” of disposition means here, as it did in former  Section 9-504(3), not only the hour of the day but also the date.) Although a secured party may choose to include additional information concerning the transaction or the debtor’s rights and obligations, no additional information is required unless the parties agree otherwise. A notification that lacks some of the information set forth in paragraph (1) nevertheless may be sufficient if found to be reasonable by the trier of fact, under paragraph (2). A properly completed sample form of notification in paragraph (5) or in  Section 9-614(a)(3) is an example of a notification that would contain the information set forth in paragraph (1). Under paragraph (4), however, no particular phrasing of the notification is required.</text>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:9-602">28:9-602</cite> and § <cite path="§28:9-614">28:9-614</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
