<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:9-511</num>
  <heading>Secured party of record.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A secured party of record with respect to a financing statement is a person whose name is provided as the name of the secured party or a representative of the secured party in an initial financing statement that has been filed. If an initial financing statement is filed under § <cite path="§28:9-514">28:9-514</cite>(a), the assignee named in the initial financing statement is the secured party of record with respect to the financing statement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If an amendment of a financing statement which provides the name of a person as a secured party or a representative of a secured party is filed, the person named in the amendment is a secured party of record. If an amendment is filed under § <cite path="§28:9-514">28:9-514</cite>(b), the assignee named in the amendment is a secured party of record.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person remains a secured party of record until the filing of an amendment of the financing statement which deletes the person.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text>1. Source. New.</text>
      <text>2. Secured Party of Record. This new section explains how the secured party of record is to be determined. If SP-1 is named as the secured party in an initial financing statement, it is the secured party of record. Similarly, if an initial financing statement reflects a total assignment from SP-0 to SP-1, then SP-1 is the secured party of record. See subsection (a). If, subsequently, an amendment is filed assigning SP-1’s status to SP-2, then SP-2 becomes the secured party of record in place of SP-1. The same result obtains if a subsequent amendment deletes the reference to SP-1 and substitutes therefor a reference to SP-2. If, however, a subsequent amendment adds SP-2 as a secured party but does not purport to remove SP-1 as a secured party, then SP-2 and SP-1 each is a secured party of record. See subsection (b). An amendment purporting to remove the only secured party of record without providing a successor is ineffective. See  Section 9-512(e). At any point in time, all effective records that comprise a financing statement must be examined to determine the person or persons that have the status of secured party of record.</text>
      <text>3. Successor to Secured Party of Record. Application of other law may result in a person succeeding to the powers of a secured party of record. For example, if the secured party of record (A) merges into another corporation (B) and the other corporation (B) survives, other law may provide that B has all of A’s powers. In that case, B is authorized to take all actions under this Part that A would have been authorized to take. Similarly, acts taken by a person who is authorized under generally applicable principles of agency to act on behalf of the secured party of record are effective under this Part.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
