<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:9-615</num>
  <heading>Application of proceeds of disposition; liability for deficiency and right to surplus.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A secured party shall apply or pay over for application the cash proceeds of disposition under § <cite path="§28:9-610">28:9-610</cite> in the following order to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The reasonable expenses of retaking, holding, preparing for disposition, processing, and disposing, and, to the extent provided for by agreement and not prohibited by law, reasonable attorney’s fees and legal expenses incurred by the secured party;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The satisfaction of obligations secured by the security interest or agricultural lien under which the disposition is made;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The satisfaction of obligations secured by any subordinate security interest in or other subordinate lien on the collateral if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The secured party receives from the holder of the subordinate security interest or other lien an authenticated demand for proceeds before distribution of the proceeds is completed; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In a case in which a consignor has an interest in the collateral, the subordinate security interest or other lien is senior to the interest of the consignor; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A secured party that is a consignor of the collateral if the secured party receives from the consignor an authenticated demand for proceeds before distribution of the proceeds is completed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If requested by a secured party, a holder of a subordinate security interest or other lien shall furnish reasonable proof of the interest or lien within a reasonable time. Unless the holder does so, the secured party need not comply with the holder’s demand under subsection (a)(3).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A secured party need not apply or pay over for application noncash proceeds of disposition under § <cite path="§28:9-610">28:9-610</cite> unless the failure to do so would be commercially unreasonable. A secured party that applies or pays over for application noncash proceeds shall do so in a commercially reasonable manner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the security interest under which a disposition is made secures payment or performance of an obligation, after making the payments and applications required by subsection (a) and permitted by subsection (c):</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Unless subsection (a)(4) of this section requires the secured party to apply or pay over cash proceeds to a consignor, the secured party shall account to and pay a debtor for any surplus; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The obligor is liable for any deficiency.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If the underlying transaction is a sale of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The debtor is not entitled to any surplus; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The obligor is not liable for any deficiency.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The surplus or deficiency following a disposition is calculated based on the amount of proceeds that would have been realized in a disposition complying with this part to a transferee other than the secured party, a person related to the secured party, or a secondary obligor if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The transferee in the disposition is the secured party, a person related to the secured party, or a secondary obligor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amount of proceeds of the disposition is significantly below the range of proceeds that a complying disposition to a person other than the secured party, a person related to the secured party, or a secondary obligor would have brought.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A secured party that receives cash proceeds of a disposition in good faith and without knowledge that the receipt violates the rights of the holder of a security interest or other lien that is not subordinate to the security interest or agricultural lien under which the disposition is made:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Takes the cash proceeds free of the security interest or other lien;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is not obligated to apply the proceeds of the disposition to the satisfaction of obligations secured by the security interest or other lien; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Is not obligated to account to or pay the holder of the security interest or other lien for any surplus.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:9-602">28:9-602</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-616">28:9-616</cite>, § <cite path="§28:9-623">28:9-623</cite>, and § <cite path="§28:9-626">28:9-626</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Source. Former  Section 9-504(1), (2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Application of Proceeds. This section contains the rules governing application of proceeds and the debtor’s liability for a deficiency following a disposition of collateral. Subsection (a) sets forth the basic order of application. The proceeds are applied first to the expenses of disposition, second to the obligation secured by the security interest that is being enforced, and third, in the specified circumstances, to interests that are subordinate to that security interest.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsections (a) and (d) also address the right of a consignor to receive proceeds of a disposition by a secured party whose interest is senior to that of the consignor. Subsection (a) requires the enforcing secured party to pay excess proceeds first to subordinate secured parties or lienholders whose interests are senior to that of a consignor and, finally, to a consignor. Inasmuch as a consignor is the owner of the collateral, secured parties and lienholders whose interests are junior to the consignor’s interest will not be entitled to any proceeds. In like fashion, under subsection (d)(1) the debtor is not entitled to a surplus when the enforcing secured party is required to pay over proceeds to a consignor.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Noncash Proceeds. Subsection (c) addresses the application of noncash proceeds of a disposition, such as a note or lease. The explanation in  Section 9-608, Comment 4, generally applies to this subsection.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Example: A secured party in the business of selling or financing automobiles takes possession of collateral (an automobile) following its debtor’s default. The secured party decides to sell the automobile in a private disposition under  Section 9-610 and sends appropriate notification under  Section 9-611. After undertaking its normal credit investigation and in accordance with its normal credit policies, the secured party sells the automobile on credit, on terms typical of the credit terms normally extended by the secured party in the ordinary course of its business. The automobile stands as collateral for the remaining balance of the price. The noncash proceeds received by the secured party are chattel paper. The secured party may wish to credit its debtor (the assignor) with the principal amount of the chattel paper or may wish to credit the debtor only as and when the payments are made on the chattel paper by the buyer.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Under subsection (c), the secured party is under no duty to apply the noncash proceeds (here, the chattel paper) or their value to the secured obligation unless its failure to do so would be commercially unreasonable. If a secured party elects to apply the chattel paper to the outstanding obligation, however, it must do so in a commercially reasonable manner. The facts in the example indicate that it would be commercially unreasonable for the secured party to fail to apply the value of the chattel paper to the original debtor’s secured obligation. Unlike the example in Comment 4 to  Section 9-608, the noncash proceeds received in this example are of the type that the secured party regularly generates in the ordinary course of its financing business in nonforeclosure transactions. The original debtor should not be exposed to delay or uncertainty in this situation. Of course, there will be many situations that fall between the examples presented in the Comment to  Section 9-608 and in this Comment. This Article leaves their resolution to the court based on the facts of each case.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">One would expect that where noncash proceeds are or may be material, the secured party and debtor would agree to more specific standards in an agreement entered into before or after default. The parties may agree to the method of application of noncash proceeds if the method is not manifestly unreasonable. See  Section 9-603.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">When the secured party is not required to “apply or pay over for application noncash proceeds,” the proceeds nonetheless remain collateral subject to this Article. See  Section 9-608, Comment 4.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. Surplus and Deficiency. Subsection (d) deals with surplus and deficiency. It revises former  Section 9-504(2) by imposing an explicit requirement that the secured party “pay” the debtor for any surplus, while retaining the secured party’s duty to “account.” Inasmuch as the debtor may not be an obligor, subsection (d) provides that the obligor (not the debtor) is liable for the deficiency. The special rule governing surplus and deficiency when receivables have been sold likewise takes into account the distinction between a debtor and an obligor. Subsection (d) also addresses the situation in which a consignor has an interest that is subordinate to the security interest being enforced.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">5. Collateral Under New Ownership. When the debtor sells collateral subject to a security interest, the original debtor (creator of the security interest) is no longer a debtor inasmuch as it no longer has a property interest in the collateral; the buyer is the debtor. See  Section 9-102. As between the debtor (buyer of the collateral) and the original debtor (seller of the collateral), the debtor (buyer) normally would be entitled to the surplus following a disposition. Subsection (d) therefore requires the secured party to pay the surplus to the debtor (buyer), not to the original debtor (seller) with which it has dealt. But, because this situation typically arises as a result of the debtor’s wrongful act, this Article does not expose the secured party to the risk of determining ownership of the collateral. If the secured party does not know about the buyer and accordingly pays the surplus to the original debtor, the exculpatory provisions of this Article exonerate the secured party from liability to the buyer. See  Sections 9-605,  9-628(a), (b). If a debtor sells collateral free of a security interest, as in a sale to a buyer in ordinary course of business (see  Section 9-320(a)), the property is no longer collateral and the buyer is not a debtor.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">6. Certain “Low-Price” Dispositions. Subsection (f) provides a special method for calculating a deficiency or surplus when the secured party, a person related to the secured party (defined in  Section 9-102), or a secondary obligor acquires the collateral at a foreclosure disposition. It recognizes that when the foreclosing secured party or a related party is the transferee of the collateral, the secured party sometimes lacks the incentive to maximize the proceeds of disposition. As a consequence, the disposition may comply with the procedural requirements of this Article (e.g., it is conducted in a commercially reasonable manner following reasonable notice) but nevertheless fetch a low price.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (f) adjusts for this lack of incentive. If the proceeds of a disposition of collateral to a secured party, a person related to the secured party, or a secondary obligor are “significantly below the range of proceeds that a complying disposition to a person other than the secured party, a person related to the secured party, or a secondary obligor would have brought,“ then instead of calculating a deficiency (or surplus) based on the actual net proceeds, the calculation is based upon the amount that would have been received in a commercially reasonable disposition to a person other than the secured party, a person related to the secured party, or a secondary obligor. Subsection (f) thus rejects the view that the secured party’s receipt of such a price necessarily constitutes noncompliance with Part 6. However, such a price may suggest the need for greater judicial scrutiny. See  Section 9-610, Comment 10.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">7. “Person Related To.”  Section 9-102 defines “person related to.” That term is a key element of the system provided in subsection (f) for low-price dispositions. One part of the definition applies when the secured party is an individual, and the other applies when the secured party is an organization. The definition is patterned closely on the corresponding definition in Section 1.301(32) of the Uniform Consumer Credit Code.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
