<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:9-506</num>
  <heading>Effect of errors or omissions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A financing statement substantially satisfying the requirements of this part is effective, even if it has minor errors or omissions, unless the errors or omissions make the financing statement seriously misleading.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c), a financing statement that fails sufficiently to provide the name of the debtor in accordance with § <cite path="§28:9-503">28:9-503</cite>(a) is seriously misleading.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a search of the records of the filing office under the debtor’s correct name, using the filing office’s standard search logic, if any, would disclose a financing statement that fails sufficiently to provide the name of the debtor in accordance with § <cite path="§28:9-503">28:9-503</cite>(a), the name provided does not make the financing statement seriously misleading.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For purposes of § <cite path="§28:9-508">28:9-508</cite>(b), the “debtor’s correct name” in subsection (c) means the correct name of the new debtor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:9-507">28:9-507</cite> and § <cite path="§28:9-508">28:9-508</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Source. Former  Section 9-402(8).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Errors. Like former  Section 9-402(8), subsection (a) is in line with the policy of this Article to simplify formal requisites and filing requirements. It is designed to discourage the fanatical and impossibly refined reading of statutory requirements in which courts occasionally have indulged themselves. Subsection (a) provides the standard applicable to indications of collateral. Subsections (b) and (c), which are new, concern the effectiveness of financing statements in which the debtor’s name is incorrect. Subsection (b) contains the general rule: a financing statement that fails sufficiently to provide the debtor’s name in accordance with  Section 9-503(a) is seriously misleading as a matter of law. Subsection (c) provides an exception: If the financing statement nevertheless would be discovered in a search under the debtor’s correct name, using the filing office’s standard search logic, if any, then as a matter of law the incorrect name does not make the financing statement seriously misleading. A financing statement that is seriously misleading under this section is ineffective even if it is disclosed by (i) using a search logic other than that of the filing office to search the official records, or (ii) using the filing office’s standard search logic to search a data base other than that of the filing office.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">In addition to requiring the debtor’s name and an indication of the collateral,  Section 9-502(a) requires a financing statement to provide the name of the secured party or a representative of the secured party. Inasmuch as searches are not conducted under the secured party’s name, and no filing is needed to continue the perfected status of security interest after it is assigned, an error in the name of the secured party or its representative will not be seriously misleading. However, in an appropriate case, an error of this kind may give rise to an estoppel in favor of a particular holder of a conflicting claim to the collateral. See  Section 1-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. New Debtors. Subsection (d) provides that, in determining the extent to which a financing statement naming an original debtor is effective against a new debtor, the sufficiency of the financing statement should be tested against the name of the new debtor.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
