<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:9-321</num>
  <heading>Licensee of general intangible and lessee of goods in ordinary course of business.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In this section, “licensee in ordinary course of business” means a person that becomes a licensee of a general intangible in good faith, without knowledge that the license violates the rights of another person in the general intangible, and in the ordinary course from a person in the business of licensing general intangibles of that kind. A person becomes a licensee in the ordinary course if the license to the person comports with the usual or customary practices in the kind of business in which the licensor is engaged or with the licensor’s own usual or customary practices.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A licensee in ordinary course of business takes its rights under a nonexclusive license free of a security interest in the general intangible created by the licensor, even if the security interest is perfected and the licensee knows of its existence.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A lessee in ordinary course of business takes its leasehold interest free of a security interest in the goods created by the lessor, even if the security interest is perfected and the lessee knows of its existence.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § 28:2A-307, § <cite path="§28:7-209">28:7-209</cite>, § <cite path="§28:7-503">28:7-503</cite>, and § <cite path="§28:9-317">28:9-317</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text>1. Source. Derived from Sections 2A-103(1)(o), 2A-307(3).</text>
      <text>2. Licensee in Ordinary Course. Like the analogous rules in  Section 9-320(a) with respect to buyers in ordinary course and subsection (c) with respect to lessees in ordinary course, the new rule in subsection (b) reflects the expectations of the parties and the marketplace: a licensee under a nonexclusive license takes subject to a security interest unless the secured party authorizes the license free of the security interest or other, controlling law such as that of this section (protecting ordinary-course licensees) dictates a contrary result. See  Sections 9-201,  9-315. The definition of “licensee in ordinary course of business“ in subsection (a) is modeled upon that of ‘’buyer in ordinary course of business.”</text>
      <text>3. Lessee in Ordinary Course. Subsection (c) contains the rule formerly found in Section 2A-307(3). The rule works in the same way as that of  Section 9-320(a).</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
