<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:9-807</num>
  <heading>Amendment of pre-effective-date financing statement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section and § <cite path="§28:9-806">28:9-806</cite>, “pre-effective-date financing statement” means a financing statement filed before the applicability date.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After the applicability date, a person may add or delete collateral covered by, continue or terminate the effectiveness of, or otherwise amend the information provided in a pre-effective-date financing statement only in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in Article 9 as amended by the 2012 Act. However, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement also may be terminated in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction in which the financing statement is filed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, if the law of the District governs perfection of a security interest, the information in a pre-effective-date financing statement may be amended after the applicability date only if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The pre-effective-date financing statement and an amendment are filed in the office specified in § <cite path="§28:9-501">28:9-501</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An amendment is filed in the office specified in § <cite path="§28:9-501">28:9-501</cite> concurrently with, or after the filing in that office of, an initial financing statement that satisfies § 28:9- 806(c); or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An initial financing statement that provides the information as amended and satisfies § <cite path="§28:9-806">28:9-806</cite>(c) is filed in the office specified in § <cite path="§28:9-501">28:9-501</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the law of the District governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement may be continued only under § <cite path="§28:9-805">28:9-805</cite>(c) and (e) or § <cite path="§28:9-806">28:9-806</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Whether or not the law of the District governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement filed in the District may be terminated after the applicability date by filing a termination statement in the office in which the pre-effective-date financing statement is filed, unless an initial financing statement that satisfies § <cite path="§28:9-806">28:9-806</cite>(c) has been filed in the office specified by the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in Article 9 as amended by the 2012 Act as the office in which to file a financing statement.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-302">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-302, § 2(s), 60 DCR 2688</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-302">D.C. Law 19-302</cite>: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-302">D.C. Law 19-302</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of July 1, 2013.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
