<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:9-409</num>
  <heading>Restrictions on assignment of letter-of-credit rights ineffective.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A term in a letter of credit or a rule of law, statute, regulation, custom, or practice applicable to the letter of credit which prohibits, restricts, or requires the consent of an applicant, issuer, or nominated person to a beneficiary’s assignment of or creation of a security interest in a letter-of-credit right is ineffective to the extent that the term or rule of law, statute, regulation, custom, or practice:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Would impair the creation, attachment, or perfection of a security interest in the letter-of-credit right; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provides that the assignment or the creation, attachment, or perfection of the security interest may give rise to a default, breach, right of recoupment, claim, defense, termination, right of termination, or remedy under the letter-of-credit right.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To the extent that a term in a letter of credit is ineffective under subsection (a) but would be effective under law other than this article or a custom or practice applicable to the letter of credit, to the transfer of a right to draw or otherwise demand performance under the letter of credit, or to the assignment of a right to proceeds of the letter of credit, the creation, attachment, or perfection of a security interest in the letter-of-credit right:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is not enforceable against the applicant, issuer, nominated person, or transferee beneficiary;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Imposes no duties or obligations on the applicant, issuer, nominated person, or transferee beneficiary; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Does not require the applicant, issuer, nominated person, or transferee beneficiary to recognize the security interest, pay or render performance to the secured party, or accept payment or other performance from the secured party.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Source. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Purpose and Relevance. This section, patterned on  Section 9-408, limits the effectiveness of attempts to restrict the creation, attachment, or perfection of a security interest in letter-of-credit rights, whether the restriction appears in the letter of credit or a rule of law, custom, or practice applicable to the letter of credit. It protects the creation, attachment, and perfection of a security interest while preventing these events from giving rise to a default or breach by the assignor or from triggering a remedy or defense of the issuer or other person obligated on a letter of credit. Letter-of-credit rights are a type of supporting obligation. See  Section 9-102. Under  Sections 9-203 and  9-308, a security interest in a supporting obligation attaches and is perfected automatically if the security interest in the supported obligation attaches and is perfected. See  Section 9-107, Comment 5. The automatic attachment and perfection under Article 9 would be anomalous or misleading if, under other law (e.g., Article 5), a restriction on transfer or assignment were effective to block attachment and perfection.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Relationship to Letter-of-Credit Law. Although restrictions on an assignment of a letter of credit are ineffective to prevent creation, attachment, and perfection of a security interest, subsection (b) protects the issuer and other parties from any adverse effects of the security interest by preserving letter-of-credit law and practice that limits the right of a beneficiary to transfer its right to draw or otherwise demand performance ( Section 5-112) and limits the obligation of an issuer or nominated person to recognize a beneficiary’s assignment of letter-of-credit proceeds ( Section 5-114). Thus, this section’s treatment of letter-of-credit rights differs from this Article’s treatment of instruments and investment property. Moreover, under  Section 9-109(c)(4), this Article does not apply to the extent that the rights of a transferee beneficiary or nominated person are independent and superior under  Section 5-114, thereby preserving the “independence principle” of letter-of-credit law.</text>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:9-401">28:9-401</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
