<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:9-338</num>
  <heading>Priority of security interest or agricultural lien perfected by filed financing statement providing certain incorrect information.</heading>
  <text>If a security interest or agricultural lien is perfected by a filed financing statement providing information described in § <cite path="§28:9-516">28:9-516</cite>(b)(5) which is incorrect at the time the financing statement is filed:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The security interest or agricultural lien is subordinate to a conflicting perfected security interest in the collateral to the extent that the holder of the conflicting security interest gives value in reasonable reliance upon the incorrect information; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A purchaser, other than a secured party, of the collateral takes free of the security interest or agricultural lien to the extent that, in reasonable reliance upon the incorrect information, the purchaser gives value and, in the case of tangible chattel paper, tangible documents, goods, instruments, or a security certificate, receives delivery of the collateral.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201" type="History">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-299" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 11(m), 60 DCR 2634</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§28:9-520">28:9-520</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-299">D.C. Law 19-299</cite> substituted “tangible chattel paper, tangible documents” for “chattel paper, documents” in (2).</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">1. Source. New.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Effect of Incorrect Information in Financing Statement.  Section 9-520(a) requires the filing office to reject financing statements that do not contain information concerning the debtor as specified in  Section 9-516(b)(5). An error in this information does not render the financing statement ineffective. On rare occasions, a subsequent purchaser of the collateral (i.e., a buyer or secured party) may rely on the misinformation to its detriment. This section subordinates a security interest or agricultural lien perfected by an effective, but flawed, financing statement to the rights of a buyer or holder of a perfected security interest to the extent that, in reasonable reliance on the incorrect information, the purchaser gives value and, in the case of tangible collateral, receives delivery of the collateral. A purchaser who has not made itself aware of the information in the filing office with respect to the debtor cannot act in “reasonable reliance” upon incorrect information.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. Relationship to  Section 9-507. This section applies to financing statements that contain information that is incorrect at the time of filing and imposes a small risk of subordination on the filer. In contrast,  Section 9-507 deals with financing statements containing information that is correct at the time of filing but which becomes incorrect later. Except as provided in  Section 9-507 with respect to changes in the debtor’s name, an otherwise effective financing statement does not become ineffective if the information contained in it becomes inaccurate.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
