<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:2A-218</num>
  <heading>Insurance and proceeds.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A lessee obtains an insurable interest when existing goods are identified to the lease contract even though the goods identified are nonconforming and the lessee has an option to reject them.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a lessee has an insurable interest only by reason of the lessor’s identification of the goods, the lessor, until default or insolvency or notification to the lessee that identification is final, may substitute other goods for those identified.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding a lessee’s insurable interest under subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the lessor retains an insurable interest until an option to buy has been exercised by the lessee and risk of loss has passed to the lessee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section impairs any insurable interest recognized under any other statute or rule of law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The parties by agreement may determine that one or more parties have an obligation to obtain and pay for insurance covering the goods and by agreement may determine the beneficiary of the proceeds of the insurance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-128">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 28:2A-218.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text><strong>Uniform Statutory Source:</strong>Section 2-501.</text>
      <text><strong>Changes:</strong> This section, together with Section 2A-217, is derived from the provisions of  Section 2-501, with changes and additions to reflect leasing practices and terminology.</text>
      <text><strong>Purposes:</strong> Subsection (2) states a rule allowing substitution of goods by the lessor under certain circumstances, until default or insolvency of the lessor, or until notification to the lessee that identification is final. Subsection (3) states a rule regarding the lessor’s insurable interest that, by virtue of the difference between a sale and a lease, necessarily is different from the rule stated in  Section 2-501(2) regarding the seller’s insurable interest. For this purpose the option to buy shall be deemed to have been exercised by the lessee when the resulting sale is closed, not when the lessee gives notice to the lessor. Further, subsection (5) is new and reflects the common practice of shifting the responsibility and cost of insuring the goods between the parties to the lease transaction.</text>
      <text><strong>Cross References:</strong>Sections 2-501,  2-501(2) and 2A-217.</text>
      <text><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Agreement”.  Section 1-201(3).</text>
      <text>“Buying”. Section 2A-103(1)(a).</text>
      <text>“Conforming”. Section 2A-103(1)(d).</text>
      <text>“Goods”. Section 2A-103(1)(h).</text>
      <text>“Insolvent”.  Section 1-201(23).</text>
      <text>“Lease contract”. Section 2A-103(1)(l).</text>
      <text>“Lessee”. Section 2A-103(1)(n).</text>
      <text>“Lessor”. Section 2A-103(1)(p).</text>
      <text>“Notification”.  Section 1-201(26).</text>
      <text>“Party”.  Section 1-201(29).</text>
      <text>HISTORICAL NOTES</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
