<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:4A-502</num>
  <heading>Creditor process served on receiving bank; setoff by beneficiary’s bank.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>As used in this section, “creditor process” means levy, attachment, garnishment, notice of lien, sequestration, or similar process issued by or on behalf of a creditor or other claimant with respect to an account.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>This subsection applies to creditor process with respect to an authorized account of the sender of a payment order if the creditor process is served on the receiving bank. For the purpose of determining rights with respect to the creditor process, if the receiving bank accepts the payment order the balance in the authorized account is deemed to be reduced by the amount of the payment order to the extent the bank did not otherwise receive payment of the order, unless the creditor process is served at a time and in a manner affording the bank a reasonable opportunity to act on it before the bank accepts the payment order.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a beneficiary’s bank has received a payment order for payment to the beneficiary’s account in the bank, the following rules apply:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The bank may credit the beneficiary’s account. The amount credited may be set off against an obligation owed by the beneficiary to the bank or may be applied to satisfy creditor process served on the bank with respect to the account.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The bank may credit the beneficiary’s account and allow withdrawal of the amount credited unless creditor process with respect to the account is served at a time and in a manner affording the bank a reasonable opportunity to act to prevent withdrawal.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If creditor process with respect to the beneficiary’s account has been served and the bank has had a reasonable opportunity to act on it, the bank may not reject the payment order except for a reason unrelated to the service of process.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Creditor process with respect to a payment by the originator to the beneficiary pursuant to a funds transfer may be served only on the beneficiary’s bank with respect to the debt owed by that bank to the beneficiary. Any other bank served with the creditor process is not obliged to act with respect to the process.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-95">Apr. 30, 1992, D.C. Law 9-95, § 2(c), 39 DCR 1595</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 28:4A-502.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text>1. When a receiving bank accepts a payment order, the bank normally receives payment from the sender by debiting an authorized account of the sender. In accepting the sender’s order the bank may be relying on a credit balance in the account. If creditor process is served on the bank with respect to the account before the bank accepts the order but the bank employee responsible for the acceptance was not aware of the creditor process at the time the acceptance occurred, it is unjust to the bank to allow the creditor process to take the credit balance on which the bank may have relied. Subsection (b) allows the bank to obtain payment from the sender’s account in this case. Under that provision, the balance in the sender’s account to which the creditor process applies is deemed to be reduced by the amount of the payment order unless there was sufficient time for notice of the service of creditor process to be received by personnel of the bank responsible for the acceptance.</text>
      <text>2. Subsection (c) deals with payment orders issued to the beneficiary’s bank. The bank may credit the beneficiary’s account when the order is received, but under Section 4A-404(a) the bank incurs no obligation to pay the beneficiary until the order is accepted pursuant to Section 4A-209(b). Thus, before acceptance, the credit to the beneficiary’s account is provisional. But under Section 4A-209(b) acceptance occurs if the beneficiary’s bank pays the beneficiary pursuant to Section 4A-405(a). Under that provision, payment occurs if the credit to the beneficiary’s account is applied to a debt of the beneficiary. Subsection (c)(1) allows the bank to credit the beneficiary’s account with respect to a payment order and to accept the order by setting off the credit against an obligation owed to the bank or applying the credit to creditor process with respect to the account.</text>
      <text>Suppose a beneficiary’s bank receives a payment order for the benefit of a customer. Before the bank accepts the order, the bank learns that creditor process has been served on the bank with respect to the customer’s account. Normally there is no reason for a beneficiary’s bank to reject a payment order, but if the beneficiary’s account is garnished, the bank may be faced with a difficult choice. If it rejects the order, the garnishing creditor’s potential recovery of funds of the beneficiary is frustrated. It may be faced with a claim by the creditor that the rejection was a wrong to the creditor. If the bank accepts the order, the effect is to allow the creditor to seize funds of its customer, the beneficiary. Subsection (c)(3) gives the bank no choice in this case. It provides that it may not favor its customer over the creditor by rejecting the order. The beneficiary’s bank may rightfully reject only if there is an independent basis for rejection.</text>
      <text>3. Subsection (c)(2) is similar to subsection (b). Normally the beneficiary’s bank will release funds to the beneficiary shortly after acceptance or it will accept by releasing funds. Since the bank is bound by a garnishment order served before funds are released to the beneficiary, the bank might suffer a loss if funds were released without knowledge that a garnishment order had been served. Subsection (c)(2) protects the bank if it did not have adequate notice of the garnishment when the funds were released.</text>
      <text>4. A creditor may want to reach funds involved in a funds transfer. The creditor may try to do so by serving process on the originator’s bank, an intermediary bank or the beneficiary’s bank. The purpose of subsection (d) is to guide the creditor and the court as to the proper method of reaching the funds involved in a funds transfer. A creditor of the originator can levy on the account of the originator in the originator’s bank before the funds transfer is initiated, but that levy is subject to the limitations stated in subsection (b). The creditor of the originator cannot reach any other funds because no property of the originator is being transferred. A creditor of the beneficiary cannot levy on property of the originator and until the funds transfer is completed by acceptance by the beneficiary’s bank of a payment order for the benefit of the beneficiary, the beneficiary has no property interest in the funds transfer which the beneficiary’s creditor can reach. A creditor of the beneficiary that wants to reach the funds to be received by the beneficiary must serve creditor process on the beneficiary’s bank to reach the obligation of the beneficiary’s bank to pay the beneficiary which arises upon acceptance by the beneficiary’s bank under Section 4A-404(a).</text>
      <text>5. “Creditor process” is defined in subsection (a) to cover a variety of devices by which a creditor of the holder of a bank account or a claimant to a bank account can seize the account. Procedure and nomenclature varies widely from state to state. The term used in Section 4A-502 is a generic term.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
