<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>28:9-405</num>
  <heading>Modification of assigned contract.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A modification of or substitution for an assigned contract is effective against an assignee if made in good faith. The assignee acquires corresponding rights under the modified or substituted contract. The assignment may provide that the modification or substitution is a breach of contract by the assignor. This subsection is subject to subsections (b) through (d).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a) applies to the extent that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The right to payment or a part thereof under an assigned contract has not been fully earned by performance; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The right to payment or a part thereof has been fully earned by performance and the account debtor has not received notification of the assignment under § <cite root="28:9-406">28:9-406</cite>(a).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section is subject to law other than this article which establishes a different rule for an account debtor who is an individual and who incurred the obligation primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section does not apply to an assignment of a health-care-insurance receivable.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-201">Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Uniform Commercial Code Comment</heading>
      <text>1. Source. Former  Section 9-318(2).</text>
      <text>2. Modification of Assigned Contract. The ability of account debtors and assignors to modify assigned contracts can be important, especially in the case of government contracts and complex contractual arrangements (e.g., construction contracts) with respect to which modifications are customary. Subsections (a) and (b) provide that good-faith modifications of assigned contracts are binding against an assignee to the extent that (i) the right to payment has not been fully earned or (ii) the right to payment has been earned and notification of the assignment has not been given to the account debtor. Former  Section 9-318(2) did not validate modifications of fully-performed contracts under any circumstances, whether or not notification of the assignment had been given to the account debtor. Subsection (a) protects the interests of assignees by (i) limiting the effectiveness of modifications to those made in good faith, (ii) affording the assignee with corresponding rights under the contract as modified, and (iii) recognizing that the modification may be a breach of the assignor’s agreement with the assignee.</text>
      <text>3. Consumer Account Debtors. Subsection (c) is new. It makes clear that the rules of this section are subject to other law establishing special rules for consumer account debtors.</text>
      <text>4. Account Debtors on Health-Care-Insurance Receivables. Subsection (d) also is new. It provides that this section does not apply to an assignment of a health-care-insurance receivable. The obligation of an insurer with respect to a health-care-insurance receivable is governed by other law.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
