<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-2408</num>
  <heading>Records; reports; returns.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may require licensed wholesalers, retailers, vending machine operators, and every other person liable for or exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter or otherwise subject to the provisions of this chapter or the regulations issued by the Mayor pursuant to this chapter, to keep, maintain, and preserve records, books, and other documents; to file reports, statements, and returns; and to comply with such regulations relating thereto as the Mayor may prescribe. The Mayor may require that any reports, statements, or returns be verified by oath. The records, books, and other documents which the Mayor requires to be kept, maintained, and preserved shall be made available for examination and copying by the Mayor at the place or places prescribed by him at the time specified in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For purposes of ascertaining the correctness of any report, statement, or return; making a report, statement, or return where a complete and accurate report, statement, or return has not been filed; determining that all taxes due under this chapter have been properly paid; and determining compliance with the provisions of this chapter and the regulations issued hereunder, the Mayor may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Examine and copy any records, books, or other documents which may be relevant to such inquiry;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Summon any person to appear before him at the time and place specified in the summons and produce such records, books, or other documents and give such testimony and answer such interrogatories, under oath, as may be relevant to such inquiry;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Upon presenting appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, enter any building or place during the usual business hours or any other time when such building or place is open:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Where required records, books, or other documents are kept, maintained, or preserved for purposes of examining and copying such records, books, or other documents; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Where cigarettes or other tobacco product are manufactured, kept for sale, offered for sale, or sold by a licensed wholesaler, retailer, or vending machine operator; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Stop any conveyance that the Mayor has knowledge or reasonable cause to believe is carrying more than 200 cigarettes or other tobacco products with a value exceeding the wholesale price of 200 cigarettes and, upon presenting appropriate credentials to the operator of the conveyance, examine the invoices or delivery tickets for such cigarettes or other tobacco products and inspect the conveyance for contraband cigarettes or other tobacco products.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any owner, operator, or agent in charge of any building or place where required records, books, or other documents are kept, maintained, or preserved or where cigarettes or other tobacco product are manufactured, kept for sale, offered for sale, or sold by a licensed wholesaler, retailer, or vending machine operator who refuses to permit the Mayor, acting under the authority of subsection (b)(3) of this section, to enter and examine such records, books, or other documents or to inspect such cigarettes or other tobacco product, or who obstructs, impedes, or interferes with the Mayor while he is engaged in the performance of his official duties under subsection (b)(3) of this section shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite root="22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>] or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any person who, having been summoned, neglects or refuses to obey the summons issued as herein provided, shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite root="22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>] or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both. If any person, having been summoned, neglects or refuses to obey the summons issued as herein provided, the Mayor may report that fact to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, or 1 of the judges thereof, and that Court, or any judge thereof, is empowered to compel obedience of such summons to the same extent and under the same penalties as witnesses may be compelled to obey the subpoenas of that Court. Any failure to obey the order of the Court may be punished by the Court as a contempt thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>No person shall willfully file an application for a license, permit, authorization, or refund; request for revision or abatement; claim for refund or allowance; or report, statement, or return; or keep or maintain any records, books, or other documents which are known to him to be false or fraudulent as to any material matter. No person shall willfully aid or assist in, or procure, counsel, or advise, the preparation, filing, or keeping of any applications, requests, claims, reports, statements, returns, records, books, or other documents which are false or fraudulent as to any material matter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Any person required to file any report, statement, or return or to keep, maintain, and preserve any records, books, or other documents, who fails to file a complete and accurate report, statement, or return on or before the date that such report, statement, or return is due (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing granted by the Mayor) or who fails to keep, maintain, and preserve complete and accurate records, books, or other documents, unless it is shown by such person that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to neglect, shall pay a penalty of $10 for each day during which such failure continues. The provisions of §§ <cite root="47-412">47-412</cite> [repealed] and 47-413 [repealed] shall be applicable to the tax imposed by this chapter, but the period of limitations upon assessment and collections shall be determined by § <cite root="47-4301">47-4301</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If any person required to keep, maintain, and preserve any records, books, or other documents relating to exempt sales or possessions of cigarettes or other tobacco product fails to keep, maintain, and preserve complete and accurate records, books, or other documents relating thereto, such sales and possessions shall, unless it is shown by such person that failure is due to reasonable cause and not to neglect, be deemed taxable sales and possessions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may, upon written application made before the date prescribed for filing any report, statement, or return, grant a reasonable extension of time for filing the report, statement or return required by this chapter, whenever good cause exists for such extension.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>May 27, 1949, 63 Stat. 139, ch. 146, title VI, § 609</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-71">Mar. 10, 1982, D.C. Law 4-71, § 2, 28 DCR 5243</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 406(rr), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 286(m), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7012(e)(8), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Tax rates, records and surplus funds, authority of Council to change certain tax rates, see § <cite root="47-504">47-504</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-2408.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 47-2808.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite>, in the second sentence of subsec. (f), substituted “this chapter, but the period of limitations upon assessment and collections shall be determined by § <cite root="47-4301">47-4301</cite>” for “this chapter”.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite root="22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>]” for “not more than $1,000” in (c) and (d).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added “or other tobacco products” in (b)(3)(B); rewrote (4); and added “or other tobacco product” in (c) and (g).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 286(m) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7022(e)(8) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7012(e)(8) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7012(e)(8) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 410(d) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> provided: “Section 406(a), (c), (j), (m), (p), (q), (s), (w), (bb), (dd), (ee), (hh) through (kk), (mm) through (oo), (qq) through (uu), (yy), (zz), (bbb), (ddd), and (fff) shall apply for all tax years or taxable periods beginning after December 31, 2000.”</text>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
