<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-2853.42</num>
  <heading>Eligibility requirements.</heading>
  <text>An applicant for licensure as a certified public accountant shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board of Accountancy that he or she:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Is of good moral character;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Is a resident of the District or has been regularly employed in the District for the immediate 6 months prior to the final date for accepting applications for the examinations, or, in the case of an employee of a certified public accountant or a firm of certified public accountants registered to practice in the District, has been a bona fide resident of a foreign country for a period of not less than 18 months preceding the date of filing an application and is not qualified to be examined and to receive a certificate of certified public accountant in the state of last residence solely because of the aforesaid residence abroad;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Has passed an examination in accounting and auditing and such related subjects as the Board shall determine to be appropriate;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Holds a baccalaureate degree with a concentration in accounting conferred by a college or university recognized by the Board or holds that which the Board determines to be substantially the equivalent thereof; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Holds a baccalaureate degree acceptable to the Board supplemented with the equivalent of an accounting concentration including related courses in other areas of business administration; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>For applicants receiving a baccalaureate degree after January 1, 2000, in addition to meeting the requirements of either subparagraphs (A) or (B) of this paragraph, possesses 150 semester hours of college education.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 1002, 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-130">June 16, 2006, D.C. Law 16-130, § 2(c), 53 DCR 4718</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="47-2853.49">47-2853.49</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-2853.42.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-130">D.C. Law 16-130</cite>, in par. (2), substituted “the examinations” for “the written examinations”; in par. (3), substituted “an examination” for “a written examination”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>Section 2(d) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-101">D.C. Law 16-101</cite>, in par. (2), substituted “examination” for “written examinations”; and in par. (3), substituted “an examination.” for “a written examination”.</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-101">D.C. Law 16-101</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(d) of Non-Health Related Occupations and Professions Licensure Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-255, January 26, 2006,  53 DCR 763).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
