<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-361</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Agency” means the highest organizational unit of the District of Columbia government at which budgeting data is aggregated.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Agency funding source” means the designated resource or fund to which expenditures shall be charged.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Budget” means the entire annual appropriation, including borrowing and spending authority, for all activities of all agencies of the District of Columbia government financed from all existing, proposed, or anticipated resources.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Budget category” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>For the operating budget: agencies, programs, agency funding sources, object categories, and object classes, as shown in the budget; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For the capital budget: agencies, agency funding sources, and capital projects and subprojects, as shown in the budget.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Capital budget” means that part of the budget that describes the annual element of the multiyear capital improvements plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Capital project” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 103(8) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 777; D.C. Official Code § 1-201.03(8)).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Highway Trust Fund” means the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, established by section 102 of the Highway Trust Fund Establishment Act and the Water and Sewer Authority Amendment Act of 1996, effective April, 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-184">D.C. Law 11-184</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite root="9-111.01">9-111.01</cite>), and the Federal Highway Trust Fund, established pursuant to Title 23 of the United States Code.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Intra-District transfer” means a budget modification that involves the movement of $50,000 or more in funds from one agency to another agency for the same purpose for which the funds were appropriated.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Object category” means the 2 major types of expenditures, which are personal services and non-personal services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Object class” means the subdivision of specific types of expenditures in the operating budget, such as fringe benefits and supplies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Offsetting” means an increase that is matched by a decrease with no change occurring in budget authority.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Operating budget” means that part of the budget for the operation of the District government, excluding the capital budget.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Program” means the highest level of budgeting and expenditure control within an agency that is designated for a specific purpose in the operating budget, which may consist of multiple actions necessary to achieve the stated purpose and goals.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>“Reprogramming” means a budget modification of $500,000 or more for purposes other than those originally authorized that results in an offsetting reallocation of budget authority from one budget category to another budget category; provided, that with respect to a capital reprogramming, the term “reprogramming” means a cumulative adjustment to a project’s capital budget during a fiscal year of $500,000 or more.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-100">Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-100, § 2, 27 DCR 3617</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-70">Apr. 3, 1984, D.C. Law 5-70, § 2(a), 31 DCR 628</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 102(a), 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 1131(a), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 122(b), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 7034, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-361.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite> added pars. (8A) and (8B).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, in par. (2A), substituted “centers, responsibility centers, capital projects, capital sub-projects, and, in a performance-based agency, includes programs, activities, and object classes” for “centers and responsibility centers”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> rewrote the section, which formerly read:</annotation>
      <annotation>“As used in this subchapter, the term:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(1) ‘Agency’ means the highest organizational structure of the District of Columbia government at which budgeting data is aggregated.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(2) ‘Appropriated budget authority’ means authorization by an act of the Congress that permits the District of Columbia government to incur obligations and make payments for specific purposes against funds included in the annual appropriations act for the District of Columbia.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(2A) ‘Budget category’ includes control centers, responsibility centers, capital projects, capital sub-projects, and, in a performance-based agency, includes programs, activities, and object classes.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(3) ‘Control center’ means the organizational authority subject to approval by Congress in the annual appropriations act for the District of Columbia.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(4) ‘Council’ means the Council of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(5) ‘Gross-obligation budget’ means budget authority from all sources of funding.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(6) ‘Non-appropriated budget authority’ means the ability of the District of Columbia government to incur obligations and make payments for specified purposes against funds which are not subject to approval by the Congress in the annual appropriations act for the District of Columbia.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(7) ‘Non-offsetting’ means an increase or decrease that occurs in the gross-obligation budget or in the appropriated budget authority.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(8) ‘Offsetting’ means an increase that is matched by a decrease such that no change occurs in the gross-obligation budget or in the appropriated budget authority.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(8A) ‘Performance-based budgeting’ shall have the same meaning as the term is defined in § <cite root="47-308.01">47-308.01</cite>(a).</annotation>
      <annotation>“(8B) ‘Program’ means the highest level, for budgeting and expenditure control, within an agency that the District of Columbia government uses for a specific purpose for appropriated budget authority, which may consist of multiple activities that combined, assist the program in achieving the stated purpose and goals.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(9) ‘Reprogramming’ means any budget modification which results in an offsetting reallocation of funds from 1 budget category to another, for purposes other than those originally planned.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(10) ‘Responsibility center’ means the organizational component below the control center level.”</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> added “provided, that with respect to a capital reprogramming, the term ‘reprogramming’ means a cumulative adjustment to a project's capital budget during a fiscal year of $ 500,000 or more” in (14).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 102(a) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1002(a) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-187, August 26, 2009,  56 DCR 7374).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1131(a) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1131(a) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 122(b) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7013 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title of title I of Law 14-190: Section 101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite> provided that title I of the act may be cited as the Reprogramming Policy Act of 2002.</text>
      <text>Short title: Section 1130 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle N of title I of the act may be cited as the “Reprogramming Policy Act of 2009”.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Appropriations authorized for reprogramming: Section 118 of Pub. L. 102-382, 106 Stat. 1432, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1993, provided that none of the funds appropriated by this Act may be obligated or expended by reprogramming except pursuant to advance approval of the reprogramming granted according to the procedure set forth in the Joint Explanatory Statement of the Committee of Conference (House Report No. 96-443), which accompanied the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1980, approved October 30, 1979 (93 Stat. 713; Public Law 96-93), as modified in House Report No. 98-265, and in accordance with § <cite root="47-361">47-361</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
