<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1806.12</num>
  <heading>Tax on residents and non-residents — Credits — Alternative fuel infrastructure credit.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning with the taxable year after December 31, 2013, through the taxable year ending December 31, 2026, there shall be allowed against the tax imposed on an eligible applicant by § <cite root="47-1806.03">47-1806.03</cite> a credit in the amount of 50% of the equipment and labor costs directly attributable to the purchase and installation of alternative fuel storage and dispensing or charging equipment on a qualified alternative fuel vehicle refueling property or in a qualified private residence; provided, that the credit shall not exceed:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For a qualified private residence, $1,000 per vehicle charging station; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a qualified alternative fuel vehicle refueling property, $10,000 per qualified alternative fuel vehicle refueling property or vehicle charging station.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The equipment and labor costs for which a tax credit may be claimed under this section shall not include costs associated with the:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Purchase of land, or access to land, to be used as a qualified alternative fuel vehicle refueling property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Purchase of an existing qualified alternative fuel vehicle refueling property; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Construction or purchase of any structure.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The credit claimed under this section in any one tax year may not exceed the taxpayer’s tax liability under § <cite root="47-1806.03">47-1806.03</cite> for that year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the amount of the tax credit permitted under this section exceeds the tax otherwise due under § <cite root="47-1806.03">47-1806.03</cite>, the amount of the credit not used may be carried forward for up to 2 tax years. The credit shall not be refundable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If the alternative fuel storage and dispensing equipment or charging equipment on a qualified alternative fuel vehicle refueling property is no longer used to dispense or sell alternative fuel to the public, any unused tax credit shall be forfeited and the taxpayer may not claim a tax credit for the portion of the tax year after the date on which the alternative fuel storage and dispensing equipment or charging equipment was no longer used to dispense or sell alternative fuel to the public.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Alternative fuel” means a fuel used to power a motor vehicle that consists of one or more of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>At least 85% ethanol;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Natural gas;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Compressed natural gas;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Liquefied natural gas;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Liquefied petroleum gas;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Biodiesel, excluding kerosene;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Electricity provided by a vehicle-charging station; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Hydrogen.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Eligible applicant” means a resident who is an owner or lessee of a qualified alternative fuel vehicle refueling property or a qualified private residence.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Qualified alternative fuel vehicle refueling property” means a property in the District that contains equipment available for use by the public for storing and dispensing alternative fuel, including charging electrically.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Qualified private residence” means a property that is the dwelling of a person that has a vehicle-charging station.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  7072(b), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7082(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7072(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7072(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
