<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1078</num>
  <heading>SOME, Inc. and Affiliates Property Tax Exemption.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The real properties listed in paragraph (2) of this subsection and owned by SOME, Inc., Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by SOME, Inc., or Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., shall be exempt from real property taxation, effective as of the dates stated in paragraph (2) of this subsection, so long as:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The real property continues to be used in accordance with the application for property tax exemption filed for that particular property;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The owner continues to be SOME, Inc., or Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by SOME, Inc., or Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc.; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The owner is any entity, for-profit or nonprofit; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The real property continues to be under applicable use restrictions during a:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>Federal low-income housing tax credit compliance period; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>Department of Housing and Community Development compliance period.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The following real properties shall be exempt from real property taxation in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Lot 811, Square 3567, located at 1876 4th Street, N.E., effective August 1, 2006;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Lot 812, Square 3567, located at 1876 4th Street, N.E., effective August 1, 2006;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Lot 33, Square 5322, located at 360 50th Street, S.E., effective June 1, 2007;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Lot 34, Square 5322, located at 350 50th Street, S.E., effective June 1, 2007;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Parcel 2180096, Square 5616, located at 1701 19th Street, S.E., effective April 1, 2006;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Lot 815, Square 5637, located at 2810-2872 Texas Avenue, S.E., effective June 1, 2007;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Lot 47, Square 5760, located at 2125 18th Street, S.E., effective July 1, 2005;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Lot 894, Square 5765, located at 1667 Good Hope Road, S.E., effective January 1, 2007;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Lot 811, Square 6129, located at 3828—3830 South Capitol Street, S. E., effective June 1, 2007;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Lot 822, Square 6164, located at 740 Barnaby Street, S.E., effective March 1, 2007; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>Lots 2086—2127, Square 6164, located at 730—736 Chesapeake Street, S.E., effective November 1, 2007.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The properties contained in this section shall make the annual reports required by § <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The conveyance of any of the properties described in subsection (a) of this section to SOME, Inc., Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc. or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by either of them shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 11 of Title 42, and the transfer of any of the properties described in subsection (a) of this section by SOME, Inc., Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by either of them shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 9 of this title.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-185" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-185, § 2(b), 55 DCR 6104</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-212" type="History">Aug. 6, 2010, D.C. Law 18-212, § 2(b), 57 DCR 4953</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 7092(a), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 114(d), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1084">47-1084</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-212">D.C. Law 18-212</cite>, in the section heading, substituted “SOME, Inc.” for “So Others Might Eat, Inc.”; and rewrote subsec. (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> substituted “this title” for “Title 47 of this District of Columbia Code” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-296">D.C. Law 17-296</cite> substituted “SOME, Inc.” for “So Others Might Eat, Inc.” wherever it appears; and substituted “Inc., or the property continues to be under applicable use restrictions during a federal low-income housing tax credit compliance period:” for “Inc.:”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-296">D.C. Law 17-296</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-168">D.C. Law 18-168</cite> substituted “SOME, Inc.” for “So Others Might Eat, Inc.” wherever it appears and substituted “Housing Opportunity, Inc., or the owner is an entity (for profit or nonprofit) and the property continues to be under applicable use restrictions during a federal low-income housing tax credit compliance period or a Department of Housing and Community Development compliance period:” for “Housing Opportunity, Inc.:”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-168">D.C. Law 18-168</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-276">D.C. Law 17-276</cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“§ <cite path="§47-1079">47-1079</cite>. Washington Parks &amp; People Property Tax Exemption.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Council of the District of Columbia orders that all real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against real property located at Square 2841, Lots 0841, 0847, 0848, and 0851, for the period of tax years 1998 to 2008, be forgiven, as of August 4, 2008; provided, that this property is owned and used by Washington Parks &amp; People as a public park, which is available for use by the public, and not used for commercial purposes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The one-time transfer of the property specified in subsection (a) of this section to Washington Parks &amp; People shall not be subject to the recordation and transfer taxes and fees under Chapters 9 or 14 of this title.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Upon the transfer of the property described in subsection (a) of this section to Washington Parks &amp; People, the property shall be exempt from all taxation so long as the same is used in carrying out the public purposes and activities of Washington Parks &amp; People, and not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-276">D.C. Law 17-276</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 7012(b) of Fiscal Year 2009 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-468, July 28, 2008,  55 DCR 8746).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of Washington Parks &amp; People Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-489, August 4, 2008,  55 DCR 9160).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of Washington Parks &amp; People Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-540, October 20, 2008,  55 DCR 11421).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of SOME, Inc. Technical Amendments Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-542, October 20, 2008,  55 DCR 11426).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-185">D.C. Law 17-185</cite>, see § 7023 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-185">D.C. Law 17-185</cite>, see § 7023 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of SOME, Inc., Technical Amendments Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-340, March 22, 2010,  57 DCR 2848).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 7091 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle J of title VII of the act may be cited as “SOME, Inc. and Affiliates Transfer and Recordation Exemption and Equitable Tax Relief Act of 2011”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-185">D.C. Law 17-185</cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7023 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> repealed section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-185">D.C. Law 17-185</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
