<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1340</num>
  <heading>Notice to agencies; certification of taxes due agencies; General Fund; disbursement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>At least 60 days before the mailing of the notices required by § <cite path="§47-1341">47-1341</cite>, the Mayor shall notify all taxing agencies (other than the agency to whom the Mayor has delegated his authority under § <cite path="§47-1332">47-1332</cite>) of the Mayor’s intention to hold a tax sale and shall state the time and place of the sale. Subject to the limitation set forth in § <cite path="§34-2407.02">34-2407.02</cite>, each of the taxing agencies shall, within 30 days after receiving the notice, submit a statement to the Mayor certifying all taxes appearing on its records then due to the District as of the date of the Mayor’s notice that have not been previously certified to the Mayor. The statement shall be in the form and medium, and shall contain the information, that the Mayor requires. In addition to the real property taxes due, the Mayor shall include in the notices required by § <cite path="§47-1341">47-1341</cite> and § <cite path="§47-1353.01">47-1353.01</cite> and in the public notice required by § <cite path="§47-1342">47-1342</cite> the taxes certified to him by the taxing agencies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>When a taxing agency certifies a tax to the Mayor under subsection (a) of this section for which tax a lien was filed with the Recorder of Deeds, the taxing agency shall file with the Recorder of Deeds a Notice of Converted Real Property Tax releasing the prior lien as of the date of certification. The notice shall state the name of the owner, describe the real property by taxation square, suffix, and lot number, or parcel and lot number, and specify the amount of the lien.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a taxing agency does not certify a tax that is due to the District as of the date of the Mayor’s notice under subsection (a) of this section, the tax shall not be collected through such tax sale.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall not sell a real property for which taxes have not been certified by a taxing agency. Unpaid real property taxes, business improvement district taxes, and vault rents shall not be required to be certified.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, payments received for taxes that have been certified to the Mayor shall be credited to the General Fund of the District in the same manner as real property tax payments are credited.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a taxing agency certifies taxes (for which real property is offered for sale) to the Mayor under subsection (a) of this section, and the payment of taxes to the Mayor as specified in § <cite path="§47-1361">47-1361</cite>(a) or by a purchaser under § <cite path="§47-1382">47-1382</cite>(c) has occurred for the real property, or the amount in the notices under § <cite path="§47-1341">47-1341</cite> is paid before the tax sale, the taxing agency may submit an accounting to the designated agency under § <cite path="§47-1332">47-1332</cite>(b) in the form that the Mayor requires.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of the accounting and verification of the payment of taxes to the Mayor as specified in § <cite path="§47-1361">47-1361</cite>(a) or if payment to the Mayor is made by a purchaser under § <cite path="§47-1382">47-1382</cite>(c), or the amount in the notices under § <cite path="§47-1341">47-1341</cite> is paid before the tax sale, the amount of taxes collected that are not imposed under Chapter 8 of this title shall be disbursed regardless of lien priority from the General Fund for the purpose designated by, and in accordance with, the law creating the obligation for such taxes; provided, that, in the case of a sale under § <cite path="§47-1353">47-1353</cite>(b), the disbursement shall be limited to the amount available after application of lien priorities to such taxes before certification.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Any omission by the Mayor or any taxing agency under this section shall not adversely affect a sale or a purchaser’s interest. This section shall be construed pursuant to §§ <cite path="§47-1341">47-1341</cite>(b) and <cite path="§47-1342">47-1342</cite>(b)(2).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>When a tax is certified by a taxing agency to the agency designated under § <cite path="§47-1332">47-1332</cite>(b), the designated agency may charge an amount not to exceed 10% of the redemptive value of the tax, to be retained by the designated agency as compensation for the use of its resources. Charges collected under this subsection shall be deposited into the Recorder of Deeds Automation and Infrastructure Improvement Fund under § <cite path="§42-1214">42-1214</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 507(a)(2), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 11(aa), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-141" type="History">Dec. 4, 2014, D.C. Law 20-141, § 101(c)(6), 61 DCR 7763</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §§  7102(c)(6), 7104, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1215.15">2-1215.15</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1802.03">2-1802.03</cite>, § <cite path="§6-805">6-805</cite>, § <cite path="§8-807">8-807</cite>, § <cite path="§42-1214">42-1214</cite>, § <cite path="§42-3131.01">42-3131.01</cite>, § <cite path="§42-3131.14">42-3131.14</cite>, § <cite path="§42-3141.09">42-3141.09</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1331">47-1331</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-1382">47-1382</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</cite> added subsec. (h).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite>, repealed before its effective date, would have, in (a), substituted “Subject to the limitation set forth in section 104(a) of the District of Columbia Public Works Act of 1954, approved May 18, 1954 (68 Stat. 102; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§34-2407.02">34-2407.02</cite>), each of the taxing” for “Each of the taxing” at the beginning of the second sentence and “notices required by § <cite path="§47-1341">47-1341</cite> and § <cite path="§47-1353.01">47-1353.01</cite>” for “notice of delinquency required by § <cite path="§47-1341">47-1341</cite>” in the last sentence; in (c), deleted “sale under this chapter unless the taxing agency files a lien with the Recorder of Deeds within the time required for certification. If such lien is filed, the taxing agency may later certify such lien for collection in accordance with subsection (a) of this section” at the end and made minor stylistic changes; substituted “Unpaid real property taxes, business improvement district taxes, and vault rents” for “Unpaid real property taxes” in (d); and would have rewritten (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, in (a), added “Subject to the limitation set forth in  Section 34-2407.02” and substituted “notices required by  Section 47-1341 and  Section 47-1353.01” for “notice of delinquency required by  Section 47-1341”; rewrote (c); added “business improvement district taxes, and vault rents” in (d); and rewrote (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(ff) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(ff) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(oo) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002, 49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002, 49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002, 49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(6) of the Residential Real Property Equity  and Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-342, May 28, 2014,  61 DCR 5691).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(6) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-409, Aug. 1, 2014,  61 DCR 8281).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7112(c)(6) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(6) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014,  61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(6) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite> became effective on Dec. 4, 2014, but was repealed prior to its effective date by emergency D.C. Act 20-377, § 7114, eff. July 14, 2014,   61 DCR 7598, by emergency D.C. Act 20-449, § 7104, eff. October 10, 2014,   61 DCR 10915, by emergency D.C. Act 20-566, § 7104, eff. January 9, 2015,   62 DCR 884, and by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7104,   61 DCR 9990.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
