<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1807.08</num>
  <heading>Tax credit for corporations that provide an employee paid leave to serve as an organ or bone marrow donor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “donor” means an individual who makes a gift of an organ, including eyes, or bone marrow.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If in addition to any medical, personal, or other paid leave, including credit for time of service, provided by a corporation, the corporation provides an employee a paid leave of absence to serve as an organ or bone marrow donor, the corporation may claim a nonrefundable credit equal to 25% of the regular salary paid during the taxable year for the leave of absence, not to exceed 30 days for an organ donation and 7 days for a bone marrow donation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the corporation elects to claim the credit, an amount equal to the salary or wages upon which the 25% credit is computed shall not be allowed as a deduction.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The credit shall not reduce the minimum tax liability of $100 [now $250] under <cite path="§47-1807.02|(b)">§ 47-1807.02(b)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply if the employee is eligible for leave under the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, approved February 5, 1993 (107 Stat. 6; 29 U.S.C. § 2601 et seq.).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Chief Financial Officer or his delegate shall promulgate regulations as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-211" type="History">Mar. 6, 2007, D.C. Law 16-211, § 2(b), 53 DCR 9852</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 144, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability: Section 7080 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> repealed section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-211">D.C. Law 16-211</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(c) of Employment of Returning Veteran’s Tax Credit Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-654, January 6, 2009,  56 DCR 933).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-384">D.C. Law 17-384</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) If the qualified veteran moves his or her residence outside the District of Columbia during the 24-month period.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) If the qualified veteran is a member of the board of directors of the business, directly or indirectly owns a majority of its stock, or is related to a member of the board of directors or a majority stockholder as a spouse or as any relative listed in the definition of dependent in  section 152 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 without regard to source of income; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) If the employer does not meet, with respect to the employment of the qualified veteran, all federal and District laws and regulations, including those concerning health, safety, child labor, work/hour, and equal employment opportunity;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) If the qualified veteran was employed as the result of the displacement, other than for cause, of another employee, or as the result of a strike or lockout, a layoff in which other employees are awaiting recall, or a reduction of the regular wages, benefits, or rights of other employees in similar jobs;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) If the employer accords the qualified veteran lesser benefits or rights than the employer accords other employees in similar jobs;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) If the employer pays the qualified veteran less than the greater of the legal minimum wage or the wage the employer pays other employees in similar jobs;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) For any wages paid in a calendar month in which the employer has not employed the qualified veteran for at least 90 hours;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The credit under subsection (b) of this section shall not be valid:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) A total of $2,500 for each eligible veteran.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The total income taxes imposed on the business during the tax year in which the credit is sought; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Ten percent of the wages paid to a qualified veteran during the tax year in which the credit is claimed;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The maximum annual credit allowed under this section shall not exceed the lesser of:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2009, an employer shall be allowed a credit against the tax imposed by <cite path="§47-1807.02">§ 47-1807.02</cite> in an amount equal to 10% of the wages paid by the employer to a qualified veteran during the first 24 calendar months in which the employer employs the qualified veteran. The credit under this section shall not exceed $5,000 in the aggregate for each qualified veteran who is employed.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F) Is not currently employed in a facility owned or operated by the District business seeking the tax credit under this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) Is a District resident at the time of hiring and maintains District residency for the duration of the 2-year tax credit period; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) Is hired within 5 years after being discharged from the Armed Forces or within 2 years of a continuous 6-month National Guard deployment;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) Is hired to fill a position of indefinite duration consisting of a minimum of 35 hours per week for not less than 48 weeks per year;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Is not currently employed in a facility owned or operated by the District business with an exemption under <cite path="§47-4605">§ 47-4605</cite>;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) Has previously served in a branch of the Armed Forces and who was honorably or generally discharged;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) ’Qualified veteran’ means an individual subject to the District’s personal income tax who:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) ‘Armed Forces’ shall include any branch of the United States Military, including the Army, Navy, Marines, Air Force, Coast Guard, or any National Guard or reserve deployment lasting 6 continuous months or longer.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) For the purposes of this section, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“<cite path="§47-1807.09">§ 47-1807.09</cite>. Tax credit for hiring qualified veterans.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-384">D.C. Law 17-384</cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in subsec. (b)(3).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
