<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1057</num>
  <heading>Crispus Attucks Development Corporation, lot 0046 in square 3117.</heading>
  <text>The real property located at 77 U Street, N.W., Washington, D.C., lot 0046 in square 3117, shall be exempt from all taxation so long as it is used to carry out the public purposes and activities of the Crispus Attucks Development Corporation and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-142" type="History">Apr. 22, 2004, D.C. Law 15-142, § 2, 51 DCR 2589</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For Temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of Crispus Attucks Development Corporation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Temporary Act of 2003 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-303">D.C. Law 14-303</law-cite>, May 3, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 3777).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For Temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Crispus Attucks Development Corporation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-121">D.C. Law 15-121</law-cite>, March 30, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 3808).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§47-1055">47-1055</cite>, see § 2 of Crispus Attucks Development Corporation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-597, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 654).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Crispus Attucks Development Corporation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-68, April 16, 2003,  50 DCR 3401).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of Crispus Attucks Development Corporation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Assistance Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-287, December 22, 2003,  51 DCR 3180).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of Crispus Attucks Development Corporation Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Assistance Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-401, March 18, 2004,  51 DCR 3639).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Sections 4 and 5 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-142">D.C. Law 15-142</law-cite> provided: “Sec. 4. Applicability. Section 2 shall apply as of February 1, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7041 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</law-cite> repealed section 5 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-142">D.C. Law 15-142</law-cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-91">D.C. Law 16-91</law-cite> made a technical correction in the effective date clause of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-142">D.C. Law 15-142</law-cite> that resulted in no change to the text.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
