<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1315</num>
  <heading>Liens for taxes or assessments — Confirmation of sale; amount payable; disposition of surplus; delivery of deed.</heading>
  <text>Every such sale shall be reported to and confirmed by said equity Court, and no sale shall be made for an amount less than such aggregate taxes, interest, and costs incurred in the institution of suit, including advertising and sale, unless by express order of the Court. Any surplus remaining from sales made under §§ <cite path="§47-1312">47-1312</cite> to 47-1315 shall be paid by the Collector of Taxes into the registry of the Court, to abide its further order for payment to the person or persons entitled thereto; and any such moneys remaining unclaimed for a period of 5 years after confirmation of any such sale shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States and credited to the revenues of the District of Columbia. Upon confirmation of such sale by order of Court and payment of the purchase price, and upon full compliance with all of the terms of sale, the Clerk of the Court shall execute and deliver to the purchaser a deed to the property so sold, which deed shall convey to said purchaser all of the right, title, and estate of all persons whether named in such suit or not.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 2, 1936, 49 Stat. 1155, ch. 111, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1303.04">47-1303.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1315.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-1014.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Office of Collector of Taxes abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§47-401">47-401</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
