<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1077</num>
  <heading>Tregaron Conservancy, Lots 848, 857, 859, and 860.</heading>
  <text>The real property described as Lots 848, 857, 859, and 860, shall be exempt from real property taxation so long as:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The real property is owned by the Tregaron Conservancy, a District corporation which is exempt from federal taxes, and is used solely to further its tax-exempt purposes;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The real property is not improved further (except as necessary for maintenance), is maintained as open space and parkland in a manner consistent with the real property’s historical significance, and is reasonably accessible to the general public without charge or payment of a fee of any kind; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>All reports required by <cite path="§47-1007">§ 47-1007</cite> are properly made by the Tregaron Conservancy.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-119" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-119, § 2(b), 55 DCR 1473</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 742(b), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-117" type="History">June 26, 2014, D.C. Law 20-117, § 13, 61 DCR 2032</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 7222(b), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Sections 3 and 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-119">D.C. Law 17-119</cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 3. Transfer exempt from transfer and recordation taxes.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“The conveyance of the real property in Lots 842 and 843 (formerly Lot 839), Square 2084 from Tregaron Limited Partnership to Tregaron Conservancy and the Washington International School shall be exempt from the tax imposed by section 303 of the District of Columbia Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 11; D.C. Official Code <cite path="§42-1103">§ 42-1103</cite>), and D.C. Official Code <cite path="§47-903">§ 47-903</cite>.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 5. Inclusion in the budget and financial plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan or a revised revenue estimate certified by the Chief Financial Officer.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-117">D.C. Law 20-117</cite>: Section 18 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-117">D.C. Law 20-117</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7223 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> provided that the conveyance of the real property described as Lot 848, Square 2084 to the Tregaron Conservancy shall be exempt from the tax imposed by §§ <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite> and <cite path="§47-903">47-903</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite>: Section 7224 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> provided that §§ 7222 and 7223 of the act shall apply as of March 1, 2015.</text>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 741 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> provided that subtitle E of title VII of the act may be cited as “Tregaron Conservancy Tax Exemption Clarification Act of 2010”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ <cite path="§7192-7194" proof="true">7192-7194</cite> of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-170">D.C. Law 18-170</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-170">D.C. Law 18-170</cite> rewrote the section heading to read as follows: “<cite path="§47-1077">§ 47-1077</cite>. Tregaron Conservancy, Lots 849 and 857, Square 2084.”; and substituted “The real property described as Lots 849 and 857, Square 2084,” for “The portion of real property described as Lots 842 and 843 (formerly Lot 839), Square 2084, which will be transferred from Tregaron Limited Partnership to Tregaron Conservancy,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-99">D.C. Law 17-99</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) All real property and transfer and recordation taxes, along with any interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges, assessed against the real property described as Lot 802, Square 5357 for the period of August 21, 2006, through March 22, 2007, shall be forgiven, and any payments made for these purposes during this period shall be refunded to the payer.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The real property, described as Lot 802, Square 5357 in the District of Columbia, is exempt from real property and recordation and transfer taxes for the period from August 21, 2006 through March 22, 2007, the period in which the property was owned by Building Hope, an organization that provides funding for public charter school facilities in the District.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“<cite path="§47-1077">§ 47-1077</cite>. Building Hope; Lot 802, Square 5357.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-99">D.C. Law 17-99</cite> added <cite path="§47-1077">§ 47-1077</cite> to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-54">D.C. Law 17-54</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Remains unimproved (except as necessary for maintenance), is maintained as open space and parkland in a manner consistent with the real property’s historical significance, and is reasonably accessible to the general public without charge or payment of a fee of any kind.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Is owned by the Tregaron Conservancy, a District corporation which is exempt from federal taxes and is used solely to further its tax-exempt purposes; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“The portion of real property described as lots 842 and 843 (formerly lot 839) in square 2084, which will be transferred from Tregaron Limited Partnership to Tregaron Conservancy, shall be exempt from real property taxation so long as the real property:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“<cite path="§47-1076">§ 47-1076</cite>. Tregaron Conservancy, lots 842 and 843 in square 2084.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of Law 17-54 added <cite path="§47-1076">§ 47-1076</cite> to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “Lots 848, 857, 859, and 860” for “Lots 857, 859, and 860” in the section heading and in the introductory language.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-117">D.C. Law 20-117</cite> substituted “Lots 857, 859, and 860” for “Lots 849 and 857” in the introductory language.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> rewrote the section heading which had read: “Tregaron Conservancy, Tregaron Limited Partnership, and Washington International School, Lots 842 and 843, Square 2084”; and substituted “The real property described as Lots 849 and 857, Square 2084” for “The portion of real property described as Lots 842 and 843 (formerly Lot 839), Square 2084, which will be transferred from Tregaron Limited Partnership to Tregaron Conservancy,”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
