<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1061</num>
  <heading>Capitol Hill Community Garden Land Trust; lot 0109 in square 1100.</heading>
  <text>Upon the transfer of real property located at square 1100, lot 0109 to the Capitol Hill Community Garden Land Trust, the property shall be exempt from all taxation so long as the same is available for use by the public generally, not used for commercial purposes, and subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite> as if the exemption were granted administratively under this chapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-284" type="History">Apr. 5, 2005, D.C. Law 15-284, § 2(b), 52 DCR 855</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Sections 3 and 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-284">D.C. Law 15-284</cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 3. Equitable real property tax relief; exemption from transfer taxes, penalties, interest or fees.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) The Council orders that all real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against real property located at square 1100, lot 0109, since October 1, 1994 through the first day of the month following the effective date of this act, be forgiven, and that any payment already made for this period be refunded; provided, that this property is owned by the Capitol Hill Community Garden Land Trust, available for use by the public generally, and not used for commercial purposes.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The one-time transfer of the property described in subsection (a) of this section to the Capitol Hill Community Garden Land Trust shall not be subject to any taxes, penalties, interest, or fees.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7056 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> repealed section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-284">D.C. Law 15-284</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
