<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1806.09</num>
  <heading>Tax on residents and nonresidents; credits; lower income, long-term homeowner credit — Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of §§ <cite path="§47-1806.09">47-1806.09</cite> through <cite path="§47-1806.09f">47-1806.09f</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>“Area median income” means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>For a household of 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the periodic calculation provided by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>For a household of 3 persons, 90% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>For a household of 2 persons, 80% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>For a household of one person, 70% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>For a household of more than 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons, increased by 10% of the area median income for a family of 4 persons for each household member exceeding 4 persons (e.g., the area median income for a family of 5 shall be 110% of the area median income for a family of 4; the area median income for a household of 6 shall be 120% of the area median income for a family of 4).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Any percentage of household income referenced in §§ <cite path="§47-1806.09">47-1806.09</cite> through <cite path="§47-1806.09e">47-1806.09e</cite> (e.g., 80% of household income) shall be determined through a direct mathematical calculation and shall not take into account any adjustments made by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development for the purposes of the programs it administers. A determination required by this subparagraph shall be calculated for the fiscal year ending in the tax year for which the credit is claimed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Eligible residence” means a real property receiving the homestead deduction under § <cite path="§47-850">47-850</cite> or a unit within a cooperative housing association for which the cooperative housing association is receiving the homestead deduction under § <cite path="§47-850.01">47-850.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Eligible resident” means a resident, as defined in § <cite path="§47-1801.04">47-1801.04</cite>(17), who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Owns an eligible residence as his principal place of residence and has resided in the eligible residence for at least 7 consecutive years immediately prior to the last day of the tax year; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Is a shareholder or member of a cooperative housing association, occupies by right an eligible residence by reason of his ownership of a stock or membership certificate, proprietary lease, or other evidence of membership in the cooperative housing association, and has resided in the eligible residence as his or her principal place of residence for at least 7 consecutive years immediately prior to the last day of the tax year; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Has a household income equal to or less than 50% of the area median income.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Household income” means the total “adjusted gross income”, as defined in § <cite path="§47-1803.02">47-1803.02</cite>(b), of every member of the household.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-114" type="History">Apr. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-114, § 401(b), 49 DCR 1468</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, §§ 33(s), 35(a), 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1172(b), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 77, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1806.09f">47-1806.09f</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite>, in the introductory paragraph, substituted “§ <cite path="§47-1806.09f">47-1806.09f</cite>” for “§ <cite path="§4-1806.09f">4-1806.09f</cite>”; and made a technical change in the enacting clause of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-114">D.C. Law 14-114</cite>, § 401(b), which resulted in no change in text.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> added a new sentence at the end of par. (1)(B); in par. (2), substituted “real property receiving the homestead deduction under § <cite path="§47-850">47-850</cite> or a unit within a cooperative housing association for which the cooperative housing association is receiving the homestead deduction under § <cite path="§47-850.01">47-850.01</cite>.” for “Class 1 property as defined in § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>(c-4)(1)”; in par. (3), substituted “resident, as defined in § <cite path="§47-1801.04">47-1801.04</cite>(17)” for “taxpayer, as defined in § <cite path="§47-1801.04">47-1801.04</cite>(7)”, and rewrote subpar. (A); and, in par. (4), substituted “means the total ‘adjusted gross income,’ as defined in § <cite path="§47-1803.02">47-1803.02</cite>(b), of every member of the household” for “have the same meaning as ‘household income’ in § <cite path="§47-1806.06">47-1806.06</cite>(b)(2)”. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) of par. (3) had read as follows: “(A) Owns an eligible residence as his or her principal place of residence and has resided in the eligible residence for at least 7 years; and,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in par. (4), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Lower Income, Long-Term Homeowner Credit Administration Temporary Act of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-179">D.C. Law 15-179</cite>, September 8, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 9221).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Lower Income, Long-term Homeowner Credit Administration Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-421, May 10, 2004,  51 DCR 5174).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1172(b) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1172(b) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004, 51 DCR).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 10 of Finance and Revenue Technical Amendments Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-585, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 340).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle P of title I of Law 15-205: Section 1171 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite> provided that subtitle P of title I of the act may be cited as Lower Income, Long-Term Homeowner Credit Administration Act of 2004.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 1101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-114">D.C. Law 14-114</cite> provided: “The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), shall promulgate rules to implement this act.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
