<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1268</num>
  <heading>Federal determinations; suspension and termination of assessment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the federal government determines that an assessment imposed on nursing facilities pursuant to this chapter does not satisfy the requirements for federal financial participation set forth in section 1903(w) of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (70 Stat. 349; 42 U.S.C. § 1396b(w)), monies collected pursuant to the assessment shall be refunded to the nursing facilities that paid the assessment and the assessment shall be null and void as of the effective date of the federal determination.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An adverse determination under subsection (a) of this section with respect to an assessment imposed on one or more, but not all nursing facilities pursuant to this chapter shall not affect the validity, amount, applicable rate, or any other terms of an assessment on other nursing facilities imposed by this chapter. An adverse determination with respect to all assessments imposed by this chapter shall be governed by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, if the federal government determines that any exclusions from nursing facilities specified under this chapter would prevent an assessment imposed by this chapter from qualifying as a broad-based health care related tax, as that term is defined in section 1903(w)(3)(B) of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 349; 42 U.S.C. § 1396b(w)(3)(B)), the exclusions shall not be made.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The assessment imposed under § <cite root="47-1263">47-1263</cite>(a) shall not be due at the time required by this chapter, or by rules issued pursuant to § <cite root="47-1267">47-1267</cite>, if the Department suspends or postpones regular Medicaid payment to nursing facilities beyond the regular monthly payment cycle, but shall be due when the regular monthly payment cycle resumes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The assessment imposed under § <cite root="47-1263">47-1263</cite>(a) shall be null and void if either of the following occurs:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The case mix rate methodology for nursing facilities is altered or amended in a way that has the effect of reducing or adversely affecting the Medicaid rates for nursing facilities; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In subsequent fiscal years, general funding levels for Medicaid rates for nursing facilities fall below the fiscal year 2005 level of funding, on a per-Medicaid-resident, per-day basis.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For purposes of this subsection, the term “effect of reducing or adversely affecting the Medicaid rates” means the overall average Medicaid per diem rate for nursing facilities is decreased or the altered or amended Medicaid rates, on an overall average per diem basis, are less than they would have been if the case mix reimbursement methodology had not been changed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If the assessment imposed under § <cite root="47-1263">47-1263</cite>(a) becomes null and void, for any reason, the Mayor may seek to amend the State Medicaid plan to adjust the case mix reimbursement methodology.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 5202(c), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5202(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5202(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
