<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1265</num>
  <heading>Confidentiality; audit; determination or redetermination of assessment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise provided by law or necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter, proprietary information submitted by a nursing facility under this chapter is confidential and shall not be disclosed by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may audit the information required to be reported by a nursing facility under this chapter, or any rules issued pursuant to § <cite path="§47-1267">47-1267</cite>, and may use the audited information to determine or redetermine the amount of the assessment due under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may summon any person to appear before the Mayor to give testimony or answer interrogatories, or to produce books, records, or other pertinent information relating to matters subject to an audit. The summons may be served by a member of the Metropolitan Police Department or by registered mail or certified mail addressed to the person at the person’s last dwelling place or principal place of business. A verified return by the person serving the summons, or, in the case of service by registered or certified mail, the return post office receipt signed by the person served, shall be proof of service.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may report a person who, having been served pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, neglects or refuses to obey the summons, to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. The Superior Court may compel obedience to the summons to the same extent as witnesses may be compelled to obey subpoenas of the Superior Court.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 5202(c), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5202(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5202(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1266">47-1266</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
