<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1087</num>
  <heading>Hill Center at the Old Naval Hospital; Lot 5, Square 948.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The real property, described as Lot 5, in Square 948 (commonly known as Hill Center), and any successor lots or any assessment and taxation lots created within Lot 5, (“property”) shall be exempt for 5 years from real property, recordation, and transfer taxation imposed under this title, so long as the real property continues to be leased by the Old Naval Hospital Foundation (“ONHF”) under and according to the terms of the lease between the District of Columbia and ONHF, dated December 12, 2010, (“2010 lease”) and any holder of a possessory interest in the property shall be exempt from possessory interest taxation imposed under § <cite path="§47-1005.01">47-1005.01</cite> for the length of the 2010 lease, notwithstanding any sublease, license, assignment, or other conveyance of the right to use the property from ONHF to any sub-lessee, licensee, assignee, or other conveyee (“receiving entity”); provided, that the receiving entity uses the property pursuant to, and in conformance with, the use provisions of the 2010 lease and subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite> and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>; provided further, that both the special exemptions from real property tax and the possessory interest tax under this section shall expire upon the expiration of the extension described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Upon the expiration of the extension, the property, ONHF, and the possessory interest of a receiving entity that could not qualify for a real property tax exemption under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite> were it the owner of the property shall be subject, as applicable, to § <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, and ONHF, additionally, shall be subject to §§ <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite> and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding the 5-year exemption granted in paragraph (1) of this subsection, ONHF shall be given an extension of up to 12 months; provided, that ONHF has applied for its categorical exemption from real property taxation under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite> no later than 6 weeks after the exhaustion of the tax relief under the Federal Historic Preservation Tax Credit Program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The lease, sublease, license, assignment, or other conveyance of any interest for any use of the property described in subsection (a) of this section that is not prohibited by the 2010 lease shall be exempt from recordation and transfer taxation during the period of the 5-year exemption and any extension.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-116" type="History">Mar. 14, 2012, D.C. Law 19-116, § 2(b), 59 DCR 467</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 113, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of Old Naval Hospital Real Property Tax Exemption Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-241, December 15, 2011,  58 DCR 11019).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of Old Naval Hospital Real Property Tax Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-337, March 30, 2012,  59 DCR 2564).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-116">D.C. Law 19-116</cite> provided: “Sec. 4. Applicability. This act shall apply as of January 1, 2011.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
