<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1276</num>
  <heading>Appeals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An ICF-IDD may contest the amount of an assessment, including any interest or administrative penalties, imposed under this chapter, or by rules issued pursuant to § <cite path="§47-1277">47-1277</cite>, by filing a notice of appeal with the Office of Administrative Hearings within 60 days after the date of the notice of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An annual assessment under § <cite path="§47-1273">47-1273</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A determination or redetermination of an assessment based on an audit of information under § <cite path="§47-1275">47-1275</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An imposition of interest or administrative penalties under § <cite path="§47-1274">47-1274</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Office of Administrative Hearings shall conduct a hearing on the appeal filed under subsection (a) of this section subject to the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), and pursuant to the rules of the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before filing an appeal pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the ICF-IDD shall pay the assessment, together with any administrative penalties and interest due on the assessment. In no case shall the filing of a notice of appeal act as a stay on the payment of the assessment, interest, or administrative penalties.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-68" type="History">Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-68, § 2(b), 53 DCR 47</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 33(b)(9), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “ICF-IDD” for “ICF-MR” in the introductory language of (a) and in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
