<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1806.13</num>
  <heading>Tax on residents and non-residents — Credits — Alternative fuel vehicle conversion credit.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning with the taxable year after December 31, 2013, through the taxable year ending December 31, 2026, there shall be allowed against the tax imposed by § <cite path="§47-1806.03">47-1806.03</cite> a credit in the amount of 50% of the equipment and labor costs directly attributable to the cost to convert a motor vehicle licensed in the District that operates on petroleum diesel or petroleum derived gasoline to a motor vehicle that operates on an alternative fuel, not to exceed $19,000 per vehicle.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The credit claimed under this section in any one tax year may not exceed the taxpayer’s tax liability under § <cite path="§47-1806.03">47-1806.03</cite> for that year. The credit shall not be refundable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “alternative fuel” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§47-1806.12">47-1806.12</cite>(f)(1).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  7072(b), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7082(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7072(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7072(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
