<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1271</num>
  <reason>ICF/IID</reason>
  <heading>ICF/IDD</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a fund designated as the Stevie Sellows Quality Improvement Fund (“Fund”), which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia and shall be used for the purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section. All assessments collected under this chapter, any and all interest earned on those assessments, and any and all interest and penalties collected under <cite path="§47-1274">§ 47-1274</cite>, shall be deposited into the Fund, and shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fund quality of care improvements for those facilities that meet the requirements of the District’s State Plan for Medical Assistance and the accompanying rules governing the reimbursement of ICF/IID.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Cover administrative costs of the DHCF in administering the ICF/IID reimbursement program and the Stevie Sellows quality improvement funding support, which costs shall not be more than 10% of the Fund’s total revenues; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Cover administrative costs of DHCF in auditing the ICF/IID in a rebasing year or as necessary to ensure the integrity of the ICF/IID reimbursement methodology, which costs shall not be more than 15% of the Fund’s total revenues.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, of the revenues deposited in the Fund in fiscal year 2011, at least $1 million shall be used to support quality of care improvements for those facilities that meet the requirements of <cite path="§47-1272">§ 47-1272</cite>, and up to $3.7 million may be used to support Medicaid services in the District of Columbia, including reimbursements for ICF/IIDs for the services that they provide.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit to the Council, as a part of the annual budget, a requested appropriation for expenditures from the Fund for a fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall audit all income and expenses of the Fund annually and provide the annual report to the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-68" type="History">Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-68, § 2(b), 53 DCR 47</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 5032(a), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 33(b)(4), 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5022(b), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 5031 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle D of title V of the act may be cited as the “Intermediate Care Facilities Amendment Act of 2010”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 5021 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle C of Title V of the act may be cited as the “Stevie Sellows Intermediate Care Facility Quality Improvement Act of 2013”.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5022(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5022(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5032(a) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> rewrote (b); and substituted “ICF/IIDs” for “ICD/IDDs” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “ICF-IDD” for “ICF-MR” in the section heading; and substituted “ICF-IDDs” for “ICF-MRs” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in subsec. (b)(1), substituted “per hour, or a higher amount as determined through rulemaking” for “per hour”; in subsec. (b)(2), substituted “Department of Health Care Finance (’DHCF’)” for “Medical Assistance Administration (’MAA’)”; and rewrote subsec. (c), which had read as follows: “(c) Amounts remaining in the Fund after the disbursements required by subsection (b) of this section shall be used for an increase in the Medicaid per diem reimbursement rate for each ICF-MR above the fiscal year 2006 rate.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§47-1273">§ 47-1273</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
