<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1317</num>
  <heading>Refunds — Taxes erroneously paid.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and instructed to cause all taxes erroneously paid in the District of Columbia to be refunded by the proper accounting and disbursing officers of said District, upon the certificate of the Collector of such erroneous payment, which certificate shall state the nature of the error, the name of the person or persons by whom such excessive payment was made, and such other particulars as may be necessary to satisfy the accounting officers that such claim for reimbursement is just and equitable; and the said accounting and disbursing officers shall pay all moneys so refunded out of, and charge the same to, the fund which was credited with the erroneous payment. “Taxes” as discussed herein do not include the “special franchise tax” as provided for in § <cite path="§34-912">34-912</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Leg. Assem., Jan. 19, 1872, ch. 31, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 20, 1874, 18 Stat. 116, ch. 337, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-153" type="History">Mar. 14, 1985, D.C. Law 5-153, § 5, 31 DCR 6440</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Income and franchise taxes, refunds, see § <cite path="§47-1812.11">47-1812.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Real property assessments and taxes, reassessment of void assessments, see §§ <cite path="§47-839">47-839</cite> and <cite path="§47-1206">47-1206</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Street repairs, sidewalk, curbing, and alley improvements, cancellation and reassessment of assessments, see § <cite path="§9-421.11">9-421.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Superior Court Tax Division, erroneously paid taxes, refunds, see § <cite path="§47-3306">47-3306</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Unemployment compensation, employer contribution payments, refunds, see § <cite path="§51-104">51-104</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Void and erroneous assessments, remedies, see § <cite path="§2-403">2-403</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Water supply, water main assessments and water rents, refunds, see §§ <cite path="§34-2401.09">34-2401.09</cite> and <cite path="§34-2401.10">34-2401.10</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1317.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-1016.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Disbursing Office abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§47-111">47-111</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Office of Collector of Taxes abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§47-401">47-401</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
