<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1341</num>
  <heading>Notice of delinquency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>On or before May 1, the Mayor shall send a notice of tax delinquency by first class mail, postage prepaid, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, to the person who last appears as the owner of the real property on the tax roll, at the last mailing address shown on the tax roll, as updated by the filing of a change of address in accordance with § <cite path="§42-405">42-405</cite>. If the premises address is different from the address of record of the owner, the Mayor shall send a duplicate copy of the notice to the premises address, addressed to “Property Owner.”</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The notice required pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be in substantively the following form and may include a payment coupon or enclosed bill:</text>
      <text>“THIS IS A NOTICE OF DELINQUENCY FAILURE TO PAY TAXES WILL HAVE SERIOUS CONSEQUENCES WHICH MAY INCLUDE LOSS OF TITLE TO THE PROPERTY</text>
      <text>“Subject Property: [Identify by taxation square, suffix, and lot number, or parcel and lot number, and by premises address, the real property to be sold]</text>
      <text>“TO AVOID TAX SALE YOU MUST PAY $ [Amount Subject to Sale] by May 31, 20)</text>
      <text>“The amount that you must pay to avoid the tax sale may be less than the total amount owed on the real property account. This amount may include fees or fines due to other DC agencies that have been certified to the Office of Tax and Revenue to be included in a tax sale pursuant to D.C. Code § 47-1340.</text>
      <text>“According to the Mayor’s tax roll, you own or may have an interest in the real property listed above. Notice is given that unless you pay the amount stated above or fall within one of the limited exemptions from the tax sale, the Office of Tax and Revenue may sell this real property at tax sale.</text>
      <text>“If the property is sold at tax sale, the purchaser may have the right to file a lawsuit to foreclose on the property. You must act now to avoid additional costs and significant expenses.</text>
      <text>“If the property is sold at tax sale, the purchaser may have the right to file a lawsuit to foreclose on the property. You must act now to avoid additional costs and significant expenses, as well as potential loss of title to the property.</text>
      <text>“Payment to the “DC Treasurer” may be made online at www.taxpayerservicecenter.com or at any District branch of Wells Fargo Bank or mailed (with payment coupon from tax bill) to the Office of Tax and Revenue, Real Property Tax Administration, PO Box 98095, Washington, DC 20090-8095 (please write your square, suffix and lot numbers on the check). You should keep a copy of your proof of payment in case there is a later dispute about the payment.</text>
      <text>“If payment is not made before May 31, 20__, the amount listed on this notice may no longer be accurate. In that case, you must contact the Office of Tax and Revenue at ..... to obtain an updated payoff amount.</text>
      <text>“YOU MAY BE ELIGIBLE FOR ASSISTANCE, INCLUDING A HARDSHIP FORBEARANCE OR FREE LEGAL SERVICES. PLEASE SEE THE NEXT PAGE FOR ADDITIONAL INFORMATION.</text>
      <text>“Should you have additional questions, please call the Customer Service Center for the Office of Tax and Revenue at (202) 727-4TAX (4829).</text>
      <text>“RESOURCES FOR REAL PROPERTY TAXPAYERS IN THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</text>
      <text>“Real Property Tax Ombudsman. Homeowners and other interested parties may be eligible for assistance from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman. If you need assistance with a tax sale or related property tax matters, contact the Real Property Tax Ombudsman at</text>
      <text>“Classification Disputes. If your real property is classified as vacant or blighted and you believe this classification is incorrect, contact the Vacant Building Enforcement Unit of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs at ..... for information on how to appeal the property classification.</text>
      <text>“Hardship Forbearance. You may be eligible to defer, or postpone, payment of the past due amount. For information on how to apply for this deferral, please contact the Office of Tax and Revenue at</text>
      <text>“Senior Citizen and Low-Income Tax Relief. Senior citizens and low-income households may have additional rights to defer property taxes. If think you may be eligible for this tax relief, please contact the Office of Tax and Revenue at  for more information.</text>
      <text>“Tax Sale Resource Center. Resource Center attorneys provide legal information to taxpayers and interested parties who do not have their own lawyers on Wednesday mornings from 10:00am to 12:00pm when court is in session. The Resource Center is located in the Moultrie Courthouse at 500 Indiana Ave. NW.</text>
      <text>“Additional Legal Services. Free and reduced-cost legal services may be available to low- and moderate-income households. You can get a list of service providers from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (above).</text>
      <text>“Housing Counseling Services. The U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (“HUD”) sponsors housing counseling agencies throughout the country that can provide advice on buying a home, renting, defaults, foreclosures, and credit issues. You can get a list of HUD-approved housing counseling agencies from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (above).”</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to the Mayor’s authority to cancel the sale under § <cite path="§47-1366">47-1366</cite>(b)(3)(A) and (B), the failure of the Mayor to mail the notices of delinquency as provided in subsections (a) and (b-1) of this section, or to include any taxes in the notice of delinquency, shall not:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Invalidate or otherwise affect a tax;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Invalidate or otherwise affect a sale made under this chapter to enforce payment of taxes;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Prevent or stay any proceedings under this chapter; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Affect the title of a purchaser.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least 2 weeks before real property is offered at a tax sale under this chapter, the Mayor shall send a final notice of delinquency, by first class mail, postage prepaid, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, to the person who last appears as the owner of the real property on the tax roll, at the last address shown on the tax roll, as updated by the filing of a change of address in accordance with § 42- 405. If the premises address is different from the address of record of the owner, the Mayor shall send a duplicate copy of the notice to the premises address, addressed to “Property Owner.”</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The notice required pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be in substantively the following form, and may include a payment coupon or enclosed bill:</text>
      <text>“THIS IS A NOTICE OF DELINQUENCY. FAILURE TO PAY TAXES IMMEDIATELY MAY HAVE SERIOUS CONSEQUENCES WHICH MAY INCLUDE LOSS OF TITLE TO THE PROPERTY</text>
      <text>“Subject Property: [Identify by taxation square, suffix, and lot number, or parcel and lot number, and by premises address, the real property to be sold]</text>
      <text>“TO AVOID TAX SALE YOU MUST PAY $[Amount Subject to Sale] by [Last Business Day before tax sale]</text>
      <text>“The amount that you must pay to avoid the tax sale may be less than the total amount owed on the real property account. This amount may include fees or fines due to other DC agencies that have been certified to the Office of Tax and Revenue to be included in a tax sale pursuant to D.C. Code § 47-1340.</text>
      <text>“According to the Mayor’s tax roll, you own or may have an interest in the real property listed above. Notice is given that unless you pay the amount stated above or fall within one of the limited exemptions from the tax sale, the Office of Tax and Revenue may sell this real property at tax sale.</text>
      <text>“If the property is sold at tax sale, the purchaser may have the right to file a lawsuit to foreclose on the property. You must act now to avoid additional costs and significant expenses, as well as potential loss of title to the property.</text>
      <text>“Payment to the “DC Treasurer” may be made online at www.taxpayerservicecenter.com, at any District branch of Wells Fargo Bank, or mailed (with payment coupon from tax bill) to the Office of Tax and Revenue, Real Property Tax Administration, PO Box 98095, Washington, DC 20090-8095 (please write your square, suffix and lot numbers on the check). You should keep a copy of your proof of payment in case there is a later dispute about the payment.</text>
      <text>“If payment is made less than 10 calendar days before [the last business day before tax sale], you must provide a copy of the receipt directly to the Office of Tax and Revenue in order to ensure that your property is removed from the tax sale.</text>
      <text>•“You may FAX the receipt to (202) 478-5995; EMAIL the receipt to [email address]; or HAND-DELIVER a copy of the paid receipt to a Tax Sale Unit representative in the Customer Service Center located at 1101 4th Street, SW, Suite 270W, Washington, DC 20024.</text>
      <text>•“Do not mail your paid receipt.</text>
      <text>“YOU MAY BE ELIGIBLE FOR ASSISTANCE, INCLUDING A HARDSHIP FORBEARANCE OR FREE LEGAL SERVICES. PLEASE SEE THE NEXT PAGE FOR ADDITIONAL INFORMATION.</text>
      <text>“Should you have additional questions, please call the Customer Service Center for the Office of Tax and Revenue at (202) 727-4TAX (4829).</text>
      <text>“RESOURCES FOR REAL PROPERTY TAXPAYERS IN THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</text>
      <text>“Real Property Tax Ombudsman. Homeowners and other interested parties may be eligible for assistance from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman. If you need assistance with a tax sale or related property tax matters, contact the Real Property Tax Ombudsman at</text>
      <text>“Classification Disputes. If your real property is classified as vacant or blighted and you believe this classification is incorrect, contact the Vacant Building Enforcement Unit of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs at  for information on how to appeal the property classification.</text>
      <text>“Hardship Forbearance. You may be eligible to defer, or postpone, payment of the past due amount. For information on how to apply for this deferral, please contact the Office of Tax and Revenue at</text>
      <text>“Senior Citizen and Low-Income Tax Relief. Senior citizens and low-income households may have additional rights to defer property taxes. If you think you may be eligible for this tax relief, please contact the Office of Tax and Revenue at for more information.</text>
      <text>“Tax Sale Resource Center. Resource Center attorneys provide legal information to taxpayers and interested parties who do not have their own lawyers on Wednesday mornings from 10:00am to 12:00pm when court is in session. The Resource Center is located in the Moultrie Courthouse at 500 Indiana Ave. NW.</text>
      <text>“Additional Legal Services. Free and reduced-cost legal services may be available to low- and moderate-income households. You can get a list of service providers from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (above).</text>
      <text>“Additional Legal Services. Free and reduced-cost legal services may be available to low- and moderate-income households. You can get a list of service providers from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (above).</text>
      <text>“Housing Counseling Services. The U.S Department of Housing and Urban Development (“HUD”) sponsors housing counseling agencies throughout the country that can provide advice on buying a home, renting, defaults, foreclosures, and credit issues. You can get a list of HUD-approved housing counseling agencies from the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (above).”</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Payment of the total amount stated in the notice of delinquency and as directed in the notice shall preclude the real property from being offered at the tax sale to which the notice corresponds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Action taken under § <cite path="§47-1336">47-1336</cite>, relating to energy efficient loans, shall be exempt from the notice requirements of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 507(a)(2), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 11(bb), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-192" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-192, § 1112, 53 DCR 6899</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-141" type="History">Dec. 4, 2014, D.C. Law 20-141, § 101(c)(7), 61 DCR 7763</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7102(c)(7), 7104, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 7037(c), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1336">47-1336</cite> and § <cite path="§47-1340">47-1340</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “amount of taxes due (whether included in the actual notice or by attached tax bill)” for “amount of taxes due”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “The notice of delinquency may also include the following” for “The notice of delinquency shall also include the following”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite>, repealed before its effective date, would have rewritten (a) and the introductory language of (b); and added (b-1) and (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> rewrote (a); substituted “Subject to the Mayor's authority to cancel the sale under  Section 47-1366(b)(3)(A) and (B), the failure of the Mayor to mail the notices of delinquency as provided in subsections (a) and (b-1) of this section” for “Failure of the Mayor to mail the notice of delinquency as provided in subsection (a) of this section” in (b); and added (b-1) and (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> rewrote (a)(2) and (b-1)(2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(gg) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(gg) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(r)(8) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-179">D.C. Law 20-179</cite>, March 7, 2015,  62 DCR 424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 13(a) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-76">D.C. Law 21-76</cite>, Feb. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 264).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(oo) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002, 49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002, 49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002, 49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(7) of the Residential Real Property Equity  and Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-342, May 28, 2014,  61 DCR 5691).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(7) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-409, Aug. 1, 2014,  61 DCR 8281).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7112(c)(7) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(7) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014,  61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(7) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2013 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of section, see § 10(a) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-164, Oct. 16, 2015,  62 DCR 13734).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 10(a)(1) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-292, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1211).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1111 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</cite> provided that subtitle J of title I of the act may be cited as the “Real Property Tax Sale Notice Act of 2006”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite> became effective on Dec. 4, 2014, but was repealed prior to its effective date by emergency D.C. Act 20-377, § 7114, eff. July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, by emergency D.C. Act 20-449, § 7104, eff. October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, by emergency D.C. Act 20-566, § 7104, eff. January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, and by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7104, 61 DCR 9990.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite>: Section 7048(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> provided that §§ 7027, 7031, 7036, and 7037 of the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
