<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1094</num>
  <heading>Supreme Council of Scottish Rite Free Masonry of the Southern Jurisdiction of the United States; Lot 108, Square 192.</heading>
  <text>The real property described as Lot 108 in Square 192 shall be exempt from real property taxation so long as the real property is owned by The Supreme Council (Mother Council of the World) of the Inspectors General Knights Commanders of the House of the Temple of Solomon of the Thirty-Third Degree of the Ancient and Accepted Scottish Rite of Free Masonry of the Southern Jurisdiction of the United States of America (“Supreme Council”) or its subsidiaries, including the House of the Temple Historic Preservation Foundation, Inc., and is used by the Supreme Council or its subsidiaries to carry on their purposes and activities, and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite> as if the exemption had been granted administratively under this chapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7232(b), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7242(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7232(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7232(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
