<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1809.10</num>
  <heading>Tax on estates and trusts — Employees’ trusts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Exempt status. —</heading>
    <text>A trust forming part of a stock bonus, pension, or profit-sharing plan of an employer for the exclusive benefit of his employees or their beneficiaries shall not be taxable under this chapter and, except as expressly provided in this section, no other provision of this chapter shall apply with respect to such trust or to its beneficiary if such trust meets the requirements for exemption from federal income tax under sections 401, 402, and 501(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; provided, that to the extent that the trusts have unrelated business income subject to tax under section 511 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the unrelated business income shall be taxed in the same manner and to the same extent as the tax imposed by subchapter VII of this chapter, except as hereinafter in this section expressly provided.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Distributions. —</heading>
    <text>The amount actually distributed or made available to any distributee by any such trust shall be taxable to him, in the year in which so distributed or made available, under § <cite path="§47-1803.02">47-1803.02</cite>(b)(2) as if it were an annuity the consideration for which is the amount contributed by the employee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Nonexempt contributions. —</heading>
    <text>Contribution to a trust made by an employer during a taxable year of the employer which ends within or with a taxable year of the trust for which the trust is not exempt under subsection (a) of this section shall be included in the gross income of an employee for the taxable year in which the contribution is made to the trust in the case of an employee whose beneficial interest in such contribution is nonforfeitable at the time the contribution is made.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>July 16, 1947, 61 Stat. 348, ch. 258, art. I, title IX, § 10</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-9">June 24, 1987, D.C. Law 7-9, § 2(j), 34 DCR 3283</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-29">Oct. 1, 1987, D.C. Law 7-29, § 2(i), 34 DCR 5097</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 202(d), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-1809.10.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 47-1577i.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> rewrote subsec. (a) which had read:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(a) Exempt status.—A trust forming part of a stock bonus, pension, or profit-sharing plan of an employer for the exclusive benefit of his employees or their beneficiaries shall not be taxable under this chapter and no other provision of this chapter shall apply with respect to such trust or to its beneficiary, except as hereinafter in this section expressly provided, if such trust meets the requirements for exemption from federal income tax under  §§ 401,  402, and  501(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (§§ 401, 402, and 501(a) of Title 26, United States Code).”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Section 203(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> provided: “(a) Section 202(a) through (e) shall apply for all tax years beginning after December 31, 2000.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
