<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1084</num>
  <heading>Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc. residential rental project; Lot 800, Square 5984, and Lot 916, Square 5730.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The real properties described as Lot 800, Square 5984, and Lot 916, Square 5730, owned by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., shall be exempt from real property taxation so long as the real properties continue to be owned by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or continue to be under applicable use restrictions during a federal low-income housing tax credit compliance period, and not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The conveyance of any of the properties described in subsection (a) of this section to Affordable housing [Housing] Opportunities, Inc. or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by it shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 11 of Title 42 of the District of Columbia Official Code, and the transfer of any of the properties described in subsection (a) of this section by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by it shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 9 of this title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All recordation and transfer taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or SOME, Inc. or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc. or SOME, Inc. with respect to real property located at Lot 800, Square 5984, or Lot 916, Square 5730, or any of the properties described in § <cite path="§47-1078">47-1078</cite>(a)(2), for any conveyance or transfer prior to [September 14, 2011], shall be forgiven, and any payments already made shall be refunded.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-129" type="History">Mar. 23, 2010, D.C. Law 18-129, § 2(b), 57 DCR 1189</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 7092(b), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 114(e), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> substituted “this title” for “Title 47 of this District of Columbia Code” in (b); and substituted “the effective date of the SOME, Inc. and Affiliates Transfer and Recordation Exemption and Equitable Tax Relief Act of 2011, effective September 14, 2011 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>;  58 DCR 6226)” for “the effective date of this subtitle” in (c).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-72">D.C. Law 19-72</cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“§ <cite path="§47-1087">47-1087</cite>. Meridian Public Charter School—Harrison Campus Property; Lot 814, Square 235.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The real property located at 2120 13th Street, N.W., Washington, D.C., and described as Lot 814 in Square 235, shall be exempt from real property taxation, including possessory interests, so long as the real property continues to be owned, or occupied under a ground lease, by Meridian Public Charter School or any subsidiary of Meridian Public Charter School.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) Any transfer, assignment, or other disposition of all or any portion of the real property described in subsection (a) of this section, including an assignment of leasehold interest in the real property or a sublease of the real property, between Meridian Public Charter School and any subsidiary of Meridian Public Charter School, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by § <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite> and § <cite path="§47-903">47-903</cite>.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-72">D.C. Law 19-72</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-129">D.C. Law 18-129</cite>, see § 7004 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-129">D.C. Law 18-129</cite> provided: “Sec. 4. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7004 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> repealed section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-129">D.C. Law 18-129</cite>.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
