<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1817.04</num>
  <heading>Tax credit to Qualified High Technology Companies for retraining costs for qualified disadvantaged employees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For purposes of this section, the term “qualified disadvantaged employee” means a District resident who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is a recipient of Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (“TANF”);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Was a recipient of TANF in the period immediately proceeding employment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Was released from incarceration within 24 months before the date of employment by a Qualified High Technology Company; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Is an employee hired, or relocated to the District, after December 31, 2000 and for which a Qualified High Technology company also is eligible to claim the Welfare to Work Tax Credit or the Work Opportunity Tax Credit under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The term “qualified disadvantaged employee” shall not mean or include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A temporary or seasonal employee; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An employee who was employed as the result of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The displacement, other than for cause of another employee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>A strike or lockout;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A layoff in which other employees are awaiting recall; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>A reduction of the regular wages, benefits, or rights of other employees in similar jobs.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2000, a Qualified High Technology Company shall be allowed a credit against taxes imposed by § <cite path="§47-1817.06">47-1817.06</cite> for expenditures paid or incurred during the taxable year for retraining of a qualified disadvantaged employee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Qualified disadvantaged employee retraining expenditures which are eligible for the tax credit are:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Tuition, costs, or fees for credit or noncredit courses leading to academic degrees or certification of professional, technical, or administrative skills taken at District-based accredited colleges or universities or the cost for formal enrollment in training programs offered by nonprofit training providers (including community or faith-based organizations certified for the provision of training or job-readiness preparation at skill levels suitable for immediate performance of entry-level jobs), in demand among technology companies in general, and information and telecommunications companies in particular. Eligible training programs, other than those at District-based accredited colleges or universities, shall be pre-qualified for participation under this section by the Department of Employment Services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Worker retraining programs undertaken through an apprenticeship agreement approved by the District of Columbia Apprenticeship Council.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The credit claimed under this section shall be limited to $20,000 for each qualified disadvantaged employee during the first 18 months of employment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If the amount of the credit allowable under this section exceeds the tax otherwise due from a Qualified High Technology Company, the unused amount of the credit may be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Carried forward for 10 years; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Taken as a refundable credit in an amount up to 50% of the credit.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-256" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-256, § 203(b), 48 DCR 730</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-42" type="History">Oct. 26, 2001, D.C. Law 14-42, § 10(i), 48 DCR 7612</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 10(i) of Technical Amendments Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-108, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7622).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(iv) A reduction of the regular wages, benefits, or rights of other employees in similar jobs.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(iii) A layoff in which other employees are awaiting recall; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(ii) A strike or lockout;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(i) The displacement, other than for cause, of another employee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(B) An employee who was employed as the result of:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-42">D.C. Law 14-42</cite>, in subsec. (a)(1), deleted the second subparagraph (B) which had read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1817.05">47-1817.05</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
