<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1809.01</num>
  <heading>Tax on estates and trusts — Residency definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, estates and trusts are: (1) Resident estates or trusts, or (2) nonresident estates or trusts. If the decedent was at the time of his death domiciled within the District, his estate is a resident estate, and any trust created by his will is a resident trust. If the decedent was not at the time of his death domiciled within the District, his estate is a nonresident estate, and any trust created by his will is a nonresident trust. If the creator of a trust was at the time the trust was created domiciled within the District, or if the trust consists of property of a person domiciled within the District, the trust is a resident trust. If the creator of the trust was not at the time the trust was created domiciled within the District, the trust is a nonresident trust. If the trust resulted from the dissolution of a corporation organized under the laws of the District of Columbia the trust is a resident trust. If the trust resulted from the dissolution of a foreign corporation, the trust is a nonresident trust.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 16, 1947, 61 Stat. 346, ch. 258, art. I, title IX, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-1577.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1809.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§47-1809.02">§ 47-1809.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
