<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1370</num>
  <heading>Complaints by purchasers to foreclose the right of redemption; exercise of authority by form of complaint.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>At any time after the expiration of a 6-month waiting period following the date of the tax sale, a purchaser may file a complaint to foreclose the right of redemption of the real property to which the certificate of sale corresponds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In a suit to foreclose the right of redemption, the Superior Court may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Bar the right of redemption and foreclose (A) all transfers of the real property occurring before the judgment of the court as provided in this chapter and (B) all liens and encumbrances on the real property except as provided in § <cite path="§47-1382">47-1382</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Vest title in fee simple in the purchaser; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Set aside the sale and determine the amount required to redeem the real property.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A complaint filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall state:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The fact of the issuance of the certificate of sale and the date of the certificate;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A description of the real property in substantially the same form as the description appearing on the certificate along with the street address, if any;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>An itemization of the amount paid at tax sale by the purchaser for each year or period of taxes, including costs of sale.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The fact that the real property has not been redeemed by a person having an interest in the real property;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>A request for an order of publication directed to all persons having an interest in the real property; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>A request that the court pass a judgment that forecloses the right of redemption of the defendants and any other person having any interest in the real property.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The caption of the complaint filed for relief under subsection (a) of this section shall comply with §§ <cite path="§47-1373">47-1373</cite>(a) and <cite path="§47-1374">47-1374</cite>(a).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The certificate of sale issued by the Mayor to the purchaser or a photocopy of the certificate shall be attached to the complaint and shall be made part of the complaint.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Proof of the posting required under § <cite path="§47-1353.01">47-1353.01</cite> shall be attached to and made part of the complaint. The posting shall be held to the same standard as the proof of posting required under § <cite path="§47-1372">47-1372</cite>(f).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The right of redemption shall continue until a judgment foreclosing the right of redemption becomes final.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The purchaser shall immediately notify the Chief Financial Officer and the Real Property Tax Ombudsman, established by § <cite path="§47-805">47-805</cite>, upon the filing of a complaint under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 507(a)(2), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-141" type="History">Dec. 4, 2014, D.C. Law 20-141, § 101(c)(23), 61 DCR 7763</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §§  7102(c)(23), 7104, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1336">47-1336</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1353">47-1353</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-1354">47-1354</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite>, repealed before its effective date, would have substituted “date of the tax sale” for “date of the sale” in (a); and added (c)(4) and (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> substituted “date of the tax sale” for “date of sale” in (a); and added (c)(4) and (e).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(oo) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002, 49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002, 49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002, 49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(23) of the Residential Real Property Equity  and Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-342, May 28, 2014,  61 DCR 5691).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7112(c)(23) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(24) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-409, Aug. 1, 2014,  61 DCR 8281).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(23) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014,  61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(23) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite> became effective on Dec. 4, 2014, but was repealed prior to its effective date by emergency D.C. Act 20-377, § 7114, eff. July 14, 2014,   61 DCR 7598, by emergency D.C. Act 20-449, § 7104, eff. October 10, 2014,   61 DCR 10915, by emergency D.C. Act 20-566, § 7104, eff. January 9, 2015,   62 DCR 884, and by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7104,   61 DCR 9990.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
