<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1431</num>
  <heading>In general.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 30 days after the execution of a deed or other document by which legal title to real property, an estate for life or a lease or ground rent (including renewals) for a term that is at least 30 years, or an economic interest in real property is transferred, or after a security interest in a real property is given pursuant to a construction loan deed of trust or mortgage or a permanent loan deed of trust or mortgage, or by which a security interest in the real property is conveyed, all transferees of, and all holders of the security interest in, real property shall record a fully acknowledged copy of the deed or other document, including the lot and square number of the real property transferred or encumbered, with the Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia. If the 30th day is a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday, the time limitation for recording shall be extended to include the first day after the 30th day which is not a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Whenever any portion of an instrument, which conveys or provides for the conveyance of equitable title to a real property, is transferred by or on behalf of a party to such instrument to a 3rd party, then the party so transferring shall record, at the same time as provided by subsection (a) of this section, a fully-acknowledged copy of said instrument, including the lot and square number of the real property transferred, with the Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia, and the 3rd party shall record, at the same time as provided by subsection (a) of this section, with the Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia a fully-acknowledged instrument, including the lot and square number of the property transferred, evidencing the transfer to himself (or herself or itself as the case may be). All subsequent transfers of equitable title made prior to the transfer of legal title shall be recorded by each subsequent transferee thereto, in the same manner and at the same time as provided in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-91" type="History">July 13, 1978, D.C. Law 2-91, § 301, 24 DCR 9765</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-92" type="History">Sept. 13, 1980, D.C. Law 3-92, § 102, 27 DCR 3390</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-128" type="History">June 14, 1994, D.C. Law 10-128, § 102, 41 DCR 2096</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 505(f), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282,§ 11(nn), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Deed recordation tax, recordation procedures, see § <cite path="§42-1106">42-1106</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Deed recordation tax, required records, power to investigate, see § <cite path="§42-1105">42-1105</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite>, § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>, § <cite path="§47-845.03">47-845.03</cite>, § <cite path="§47-850.02">47-850.02</cite>, § <cite path="§47-863">47-863</cite>, § <cite path="§47-903">47-903</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1401">47-1401</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1432">47-1432</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-1433">47-1433</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1431.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-3313.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), inserted “, or an estate for life or a lease or ground rent (including renewals) for a term that is at least 30 years” and substituted “all transferees of, and all holders of the security interest in,” for “all transferees of the legal or economic interest in the real estate and all holders of the security interest in”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “, an estate for life” for “or an estate for life.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 5(g) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</law-cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(ss) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</law-cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(ss) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</law-cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5(f) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(rr) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(ss) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(ss) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
