<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1039</num>
  <heading>Veterans of Foreign Wars; lots 38, 20, 19, and 841, square 757 and lot 0001 in square 2709.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The property situated in square 757 in the City of Washington, District of Columbia, described as lots 38, 20, 19, and 841 owned by the Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States, is hereby exempt with respect to taxable years beginning on and after July 1, 1959, from all taxation so long as the same is owned and occupied by the Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite root="47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite root="47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite root="47-1009">47-1009</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The property situated in square 2709 in the District of Columbia, described as lot 0001, owned, occupied, and used by the Bethea-Welch Post 7284, Veterans of Foreign Wars, is hereby exempt from all taxation so long as this property continues to be so owned and occupied, and not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of § <cite root="47-1002">47-1002</cite>, providing for exemptions of church and school property.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>July 19, 1954, 68 Stat. 493, ch. 543, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 86-333">Sept. 21, 1959, 73 Stat. 599, Pub. L. 86-333, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 86-430">Apr. 22, 1960, 74 Stat. 68, Pub. L. 86-430, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-169">Oct. 16, 1998, D.C. Law 12-169, § 102(b), 45 DCR 5187</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-1039.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 47-832.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Bethea-Welch Post 7284 Tax Provisions: Section 101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-169">D.C. Law 12-169</cite> provided that title I of the act, which amended this section, may be cited as the “Bethea-Welch Post 7284, Veterans of Foreign Wars Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 1998.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
