<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-138</num>
  <heading>Use of appropriated funds to promote demonstrations to influence legislation or other governmental actions.</heading>
  <text>No funds appropriated for the government of the District of Columbia may be used to furnish materials or services to promote or further any demonstration in the District of Columbia undertaken for the purpose of influencing legislation or other governmental actions of the United States government or the government of the District of Columbia, except that nothing in this section shall preclude the government of the District of Columbia from taking such emergency action as the Mayor of the District of Columbia determines necessary for the preservation of the health, safety, or welfare of any person within the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-450" type="History">Aug. 2, 1968, 82 Stat. 615, Pub. L. 90-450, title IV, § 402</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-138.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-145.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 7 of Finance and Revenue Technical Amendments Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-585, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 340).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">No appropriations to be used for publicity, propaganda or lobbying: Section 116 of Pub. L. 101-168, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1990, provided that no part of this appropriation shall be used for publicity or propaganda purposes or implementation of any policy including boycott designed to support or defeat legislation pending before Congress or any state legislature.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
