<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1091</num>
  <heading>Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception Property; Lot 6, Square 3663.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception Property, Lot 6, Square 3663, located in the northeast quadrant of the District of Columbia and comprising approximately 5 acres of land, generally bounded by the Basilica’s parking lot, Harewood Road, and the Catholic University of America, together with the improvements thereon and owned by the Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception (“Property”) shall be exempt from all taxation so long as it is owned and planned for use by, or actually used by, the Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception for its purposes and activities and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the owner applies for and is granted a real property tax exemption under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>, the exemption provided under subsection (a) of this section shall terminate on the day before the effective date of the exemption granted under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against the Property for the period of July 1, 2012, through the end of the month following [Dec. 24, 2013], as well as transfer and recordation taxes, interest, and penalties incurred as a result of the conveyance of Lot 6 in Square 3663 to the Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception Property, shall be forgiven, and any payments made for the period or on account of the conveyance shall be refunded.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 7262(b), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7262 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7262 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 7261 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle Z of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
