<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1042</num>
  <heading>National Guard Association; lot 60, square 625.</heading>
  <text>The property situated in square 625 in the City of Washington, District of Columbia, described as lot 60, together with the improvements thereon, shall be exempt from all taxation so long as the property is owned by and titled in the name of the National Guard Association of the United States, a District of Columbia nonprofit corporation, is occupied by the Association, is used solely for purposes of the Association, and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>. The transfer of the property to the National Guard Association of the United States shall be exempt from all transfer and recordation taxes of the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 86-727" type="History">Sept. 8, 1960, 74 Stat. 856, Pub. L. 86-727</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-276" type="History">Apr. 5, 2005, D.C. Law 15-276, § 2, 52 DCR 831</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1042.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-835.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-276">D.C. Law 15-276</cite> rewrote the section which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“The property situated in square 625 in the City of Washington, District of Columbia, described as lot 60, together with the improvements thereon, owned by the President, Vice-President, Secretary, and Treasurer of the National Guard Association of the United States, as trustees and in trust for the use and benefit of the National Guard Association of the United States, a voluntary unincorporated association with principal headquarters in the District of Columbia, is hereby exempt from all taxation from and after July 1, 1961, so long as the same is owned by the President, Vice-President, Secretary, and Treasurer of the National Guard Association of the United States, as trustees and in trust for the use and benefit of the National Guard Association of the United States and occupied by the National Guard Association of the United States, is used solely for the purposes of said Association, and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of National Guard Association of the United States Real Property Tax Exemption Reconfirmation and Modification Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-40">D.C. Law 15-40</cite>, November 26, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 10698).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of National Guard Association of the United States Real Property Tax Exemption Reconfirmation and Modification Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-115, July 29, 2003,  50 DCR 6592).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of National Guard Association of the United States Real Property Tax Exemption Reconfirmation and Modification Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-217, November 7, 2003,  50 DCR 10039).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
