<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1804.01</num>
  <heading>Accounting periods — Computation of income.</heading>
  <text>The net income shall be computed upon the basis of the taxpayer’s annual accounting period (fiscal year or calendar year, as the case may be) in accordance with the method of accounting regularly employed in keeping the books of such taxpayer; but if no such method of accounting has been so employed, or if the method employed does not clearly reflect the income, the computation shall be made in accordance with such method as in the opinion of the Mayor does clearly reflect the income. If the taxpayer’s annual accounting period is other than a fiscal year as defined in § <cite path="§47-1801.04">47-1801.04</cite>(8) or if the taxpayer has no annual accounting period or does not keep books, the net income shall be computed on the basis of the calendar year. If the taxpayer makes a federal income tax return, his income shall be computed, for the purposes of this subchapter, on the basis of the same calendar or fiscal year as in such federal income tax return, if the basis is accepted and approved by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 16, 1947, 61 Stat. 339, ch. 258, art. I, title IV, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-158" type="History">Mar. 6, 1979, D.C. Law 2-158, § 4, 25 DCR 7002</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1804.02">47-1804.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1804.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-1561.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-126">D.C. Law 13-126</cite>, rewrote subd. (28A), which previously read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“The term ‘Internal Revenue Code of 1986’ means the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (100 Stat. 2085;  26 U.S.C. 1 et seq.), as amended through August 20, 1996. The provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be effective on the same dates that they are effective for Federal tax purposes.”</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
