<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1204</num>
  <heading>Condemnation proceedings; payment; interest; delinquency sale.</heading>
  <text>Special assessments authorized to be levied in condemnation proceedings instituted by the District of Columbia may be paid without interest within 60 days after the ratification or confirmation of the verdict of the jury. Interest of one-third of 1% for each month or part thereof shall be charged on all unpaid amounts from the expiration of 60 days from the date of the ratification or confirmation of the verdict of the jury. Any such assessment may be paid in 5 equal installments with interest thereon. If any such assessment or any part thereof shall remain unpaid after the expiration of 4 years from the date of the ratification or confirmation of the verdict of the jury the property against which said assessment was levied may be sold for such assessment or unpaid portion thereof with interest and penalties thereon at the next ensuing annual tax sale conducted under Chapter 13A of this title, in the same manner and under the same conditions as property sold for delinquent general taxes, if said assessment with interest and penalties thereon shall not have been paid in full prior to said sale. This section shall apply only to assessments ratified or confirmed by the court after June 25, 1938, and assessments ratified or confirmed on or before June 25, 1938, shall be levied and collected and bear interest as if §§ <cite path="§47-1201">47-1201</cite> to 47-1206 had not been passed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1938, 52 Stat. 1200, ch. 702, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-198" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-198,§ 204(b), 43 DCR 4569</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 508(e)(3), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 8(e)(3) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 8(e)(3) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> substituted “under Chapter 13A” for “pursuant to § 1301”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-1104.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1204.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
