<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1816.03</num>
  <heading>Report by Mayor concerning amendment, repeal, or replacement of Internal Revenue Code.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 90 days after any amendment, repeal, or replacement of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as that term is defined in <cite path="§47-1801.04|(28A)" proof="true">§ 47-1801.04(28A)</cite>, the Mayor shall report to the Council of the District of Columbia concerning the amendment, repeal, or replacement. The report shall include, but not be limited to, an analysis of the impact of conformity to the amendment, repeal, or replacement on District of Columbia taxpayers, and on District of Columbia government revenues for 5 years thereafter, and a recommendation as to whether any change in District of Columbia law should be made as a result of the amendment, repeal, or replacement. The Mayor shall publish the report in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On or before July 1, 1988, the Mayor shall report to Council concerning taxpayers whose tax liability exceeds the amount by which their taxable income exceeds the tax threshold, as defined in <cite path="§47-1806.04|(e)">§ 47-1806.04(e)</cite>. The report shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An assessment of the number and income levels of the taxpayers affected;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Methods for, and the revenue impact of eliminating these tax liabilities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor’s recommendation as to what action, if any, should be taken.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-32" type="History">Oct. 8, 1983, D.C. Law 5-32, § 8, 30 DCR 4013</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-29" type="History">Oct. 1, 1987, D.C. Law 7-29, § 3, 34 DCR 5097</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-126" type="History">June 24, 2000, D.C. Law 13-126, § 3, 47 DCR 2643</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue regulations: Section 9 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-32">D.C. Law 5-32</cite> provided that the Mayor shall issue regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-126">D.C. Law 13-126</cite>, in subsec. (a) substituted “<cite path="§47-1801.4|(28A)" proof="true">§ 47-1801.4(28A)</cite>” for “<cite path="§47-1801.4|(28)" proof="true">§ 47-1801.4(28)</cite>, and added “The Mayor shall publish the report in the District of Columbia Register”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1816.3.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
