<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1088.01</num>
  <heading>Meridian International Center.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning on  the effective date of this section, the real property designated as  Lots 806, 808, and 809 in Square 2568, known as the Meridian House  and the White-Meyer House, and Lots 2369 through 2401, 2413 through  2417, 2423, 2441, and 2442 in Square 2567, together with any improvements  and furnishings (“Property”) shall be exempt from all  taxation; provided, that the Property is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Owned by the  Meridian International Center, a District of Columbia nonprofit corporation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Used for the  purposes and activities of the Meridian International Center; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Not used for  any commercial purposes, except as provided in subsection (b) of this  section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Use of the premises  by agencies of the United States of America or by any organization  exempt from federal income taxation shall not affect the exemption  from taxation provided for in this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Section 47-1005  shall apply with respect to the Property; provided, that a portion  of the Property may be rented out to another person or entity as long  as the rent or other income generated shall be used for the maintenance  and preservation of the Property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Meridian International  Center shall comply with the reporting requirement of § <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>  and have the appeal rights provided by § <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7222(b), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7232(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7222(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7222(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
