<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1382</num>
  <heading>Purchaser’s deed; payment; compliance with terms of judgment as to payments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § <cite path="§47-1382.01">47-1382.01</cite>, a final judgment foreclosing the right of redemption shall direct the Mayor to execute and deliver a deed to the purchaser in fee simple on payment to the Mayor of the amount required under this section. No deed shall be executed before such payment is received. The final judgment shall direct the Mayor to enroll the purchaser in fee simple as the owner of the real property. The fee simple interest shall be conveyed subject to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A taxing agency lien that is recorded in the Office of the Recorder of Deeds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The tenancy of a residential tenant (other than a tenant described in § <cite path="§47-1371">47-1371</cite>(b)(1)(C) and (D));</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Easements of record and any other easement that may be observed by an inspection of the real property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An instrument securing payment of a promissory note executed under § <cite path="§47-1353">47-1353</cite>(a)(3);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>An energy efficiency loan agreement under subchapter IX of Chapter 8 of Title 47, and related documents or instruments and the obligation to pay the special assessment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A ground lease described in § <cite path="§47-1345">47-1345</cite>(b), any recorded covenant, agreement, or other instrument, and any other document incorporated by reference into a recorded covenant, agreement, or other instrument, to which a ground lessor as described in § <cite path="§47-1345">47-1345</cite>(b) is a party or beneficiary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a)(1) of this section, the fee simple interest conveyed of a real property sold under § <cite path="§47-1353">47-1353</cite>(a)(3) or (b) shall not be subject to a lien filed by the taxing agency under § <cite path="§47-1340">47-1340</cite>(c).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The purchaser shall pay all amounts that would be required of a person redeeming under § <cite path="§47-1361">47-1361</cite>; provided, that the purchaser shall not make payment for taxes and periods for which the purchaser purchased the certificate of sale, was assigned a certificate of sale under § <cite path="§47-1349">47-1349</cite>, and made payment under § <cite path="§47-1354">47-1354</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (c) of this section, a purchaser under § <cite path="§47-1336">47-1336</cite> shall not pay an amount that is a Special Assessment under subchapter IX of Chapter 8 of Title 47, unless otherwise agreed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The deed shall be prepared by the purchaser or the attorney for the purchaser and all expenses incident to the preparation, execution, delivery, and recordation of the deed shall be paid by the purchaser.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The plaintiff shall provide a certified copy of the final judgment to the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If the purchaser fails to pay to the Mayor the amount required under this section within 30 days of the final judgment, the final judgment may be vacated as void by the Superior Court on the motion of any party. If the purchaser does not record the deed in the Recorder of Deeds within 30 days of the execution of the deed, the final judgment may be vacated as void by the Superior Court on the motion of any party. If a final judgment is so vacated, the deed and the certificate of sale are void and all money paid by the purchaser to the Mayor is forfeited except as provided in § <cite path="§47-1354">47-1354</cite>(c).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Any surplus paid for a real property by a purchaser shall be applied against other taxes, interest thereon, and expenses owing on the real property for which a deed is sought if the application and timely balance payment shall result in the full payment required to obtain the deed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Any overpayment, including expenses, shall be paid by the Mayor to the person who made the overpayment. If there is a dispute regarding payment of the overpayment, the Mayor shall hold the overpayment until a court of competent jurisdiction determines the proper distribution of the overpayment.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 507(a)(2), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 11(mm), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-262" type="History">Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-262, § 103(e), 60 DCR 1300</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-141" type="History">Dec. 4, 2014, D.C. Law 20-141, § 101(c)(29), 61 DCR 7763</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §§  7102(c)(29), 7104, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1355">47-1355</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1370">47-1370</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-1383">47-1383</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</cite>, in subsec. (a), made nonsubstantive changes in pars. (2) and (3), and added par. (4); and in subsec. (b), substituted “§ <cite path="§47-1353">47-1353</cite>(a)(3) or (b)” for “§ <cite path="§47-1353">47-1353</cite>(b)”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-262">D.C. Law 19-262</cite> added (a)(5) and made related changes; and added (c-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite>, repealed before its effective date, would have substituted “Except as provided in § <cite path="§47-1382.01">47-1382.01</cite>, a final” for “a final” at the beginning of the introductory language of (a); rewritten (a)(1); and would have added (a)(6) and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added “Except as provided in  Section 47-1382.01” in the introductory language e of (a); rewrote (a)(1); and added (a)(6) and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(rr) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(rr) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(oo) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002, 49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002, 49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002, 49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(30) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-342, May 28, 2014,  61 DCR 5691).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of § <cite path="§47-1382.01">47-1382.01</cite>, concerning post-judgment equity distribution for owner-occupant properties, see § 101(c)(31) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-342, May 28, 2014,  61 DCR 5691).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7112(c)(29) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of §  47–1382.01, see §  101(c)(31) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-409, Aug. 1, 2014,  61 DCR 8281).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(29) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014,  61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(29) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite> became effective on Dec. 4, 2014, but was repealed prior to its effective date by emergency D.C. Act 20-377, § 7114, eff. July 14, 2014,   61 DCR 7598, by emergency D.C. Act 20-449, § 7104, eff. October 10, 2014,   61 DCR 10915, by emergency D.C. Act 20-566, § 7104, eff. January 9, 2015,   62 DCR 884, and by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7104,   61 DCR 9990.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
