<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1522</num>
  <heading>Levy of annual tax on personal property.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each year the district shall levy a tax against every person on the tangible personal property owned or held in trust in that person’s trade or business in the District. The rate of tax shall be $3.40 for each $100 of value of the taxable personal property, in excess of $225,000 in value.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Construction equipment, vehicles, trailers, tools, and any other tangible personal property brought into the District on a temporary basis and used in a trade or business shall be taxed for the period that the property was physically located in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Persons owning leased personal property having a taxable situs in the District shall be subject to the tax and to the filing requirement of § <cite path="§47-1524">47-1524</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Real property improvements that do not become an integral part of the realty shall be subject to the personal property tax imposed by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Persons owning or holding in trust any tangible personal property located or having a taxable situs in the District on July 1st of the tax year that is used or available for use in a trade or business, whether or not operated for profit, shall file a return according to § <cite path="§47-1524">47-1524</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-212" type="History">Feb. 28, 1987, D.C. Law 6-212, § 3, 34 DCR 850</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-145" type="History">Sept. 10, 1992, D.C. Law 9-145, § 106, 39 DCR 4895</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-38" type="History">Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-38, § 2702(d), 46 DCR 6373</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-123" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-123, § 3(b), 55 DCR 1513</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1522.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-123">D.C. Law 17-123</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “$225,000” for “$50,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-38">D.C. Law 13-38</cite> in subsec. (a) inserted the phrase “, in excess of $50,000 in value” immediately following the phrase “The rate of tax shall be $3.40 for each $100 of value of the taxable personal property”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
