<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-119</num>
  <heading>Independent annual audit.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the fiscal year beginning October 1, 1982, and each fiscal year thereafter, the government of the District of Columbia shall conduct, out of funds of the government of the District of Columbia, an audit of the financial operations of such government, and shall include in such independent audit a report of the revenues of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year, broken down by revenues derived from the Federal Government and revenues derived from sources other than the Federal Government during that fiscal year. Each such audit shall be conducted by a certified public accountant licensed in the District of Columbia and carried out in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards and the financial statements shall be prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of conducting an audit for each such fiscal year as required by subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall, on or after January 2, 1982, select, subject to the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia, a qualified person to conduct such audits for the fiscal year commencing October 1, 1982, and the next following 3 fiscal years. Thereafter, each individual elected as Mayor in a general election held for Mayor of the District of Columbia shall on or after January 2nd next following his or her election to, and the assuming of the Office of Mayor, select, subject to the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia, a qualified person to conduct such audits for the fiscal year commencing October 1st of the calendar year in which the Mayor takes office, and the next following 3 fiscal years. The person previously selected for a 4-year period shall not succeed himself or herself. If the Council fails to act, by resolution on any such selection within a 30-day period following the date on which it receives from the Mayor the name of such person so selected, the Mayor shall be authorized to enter into a contract with that person for the conduct of such audits. If any person so selected by the Mayor to conduct any such audits for such fiscal years is rejected by the Council, the Mayor shall submit to the Council the name of another qualified person selected by the Mayor to conduct such audits. In the event that the Council rejects the 2nd person so selected by the Mayor, the Mayor shall, within 30 days following that rejection, notify the Chairman of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Chairman of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, in writing, of that fact. Within 15 days following the receipt of that notice, such Chairmen shall jointly select a person to conduct such audits and shall inform the Mayor, in writing, of the name of the person so selected. Within 10 days following the receipt by the Mayor of such name, the Mayor shall enter into a contract with such person pursuant to which that person shall conduct such audits for such fiscal years as herein provided.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit a copy of the audit report with respect to each such audit so conducted to the Congress, the President of the United States, the Council of the District of Columbia, and the Comptroller General.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to the District of Columbia Courts or the financial operations thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 94-399" type="History">Sept. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1208, Pub. L. 94-399, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 95-386" type="History">Sept. 26, 1978, 92 Stat. 750, Pub. L. 95-386, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-231" type="History">May 10, 1989, D.C. Law 7-231, § 48, 36 DCR 492</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 102-102" type="History">Aug. 17, 1991, 105 Stat. 496, Pub. L. 102-102, § 2(c)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 754, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11244(c)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-371">47-371</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-119.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-120-2.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
