<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1512</num>
  <heading>Rolling stock.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The rolling stock of railroad companies, refrigerator-car companies, parlor-car companies, sleeping-car companies, tank-car companies, express companies, car-renting companies, and all other companies owning parlor, sleeping, dining, tank, freight, or any other cars which are operated or run over or upon the line or lines of any railroad or terminal company in the District of Columbia, shall be deemed to be located in said District for purposes of taxation, whether or not the individual units are continuously in the District or are constantly changing, and such property shall be reported, assessed, and taxed within the time, and at the rates prescribed by law, for the reporting and taxation of other personal property in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Such rolling stock as is primarily located in the District of Columbia shall be reported and taxed at its full and true value on the last day of the calendar year preceding the tax date.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Such rolling stock as is not primarily located in the District of Columbia shall be reported and taxed in the manner following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Every railroad company operating rolling stock over or upon the line or lines of any railroad or terminal company in the District shall report to the Mayor of the District of Columbia the various classes of such rolling stock so operated by such company whether owned by it or any other railroad company; the number of miles traveled by each class of such rolling stock within the District during the calendar year next preceding the tax date; the total number of miles traveled by each class of such rolling stock on all lines over which such company operates during the calendar year next preceding the tax date; the total full and true value of each class of such rolling stock owned by such company on the last day of the calendar year next preceding the tax date; and such other facts and information as the Mayor may require. The taxable portion of the rolling stock of each such company shall be determined by applying the mileage traveled in the District by the various classes of such rolling stock operated in the District by such company to the total mileage traveled by the various classes of such rolling stock on all lines over which such company operates, and the tax shall be assessed on that portion of such rolling stock owned by such company on the last day of the calendar year next preceding the tax date. The mileage and value of the rolling stock owned by such company which is permanently located outside of the District of Columbia shall not be included in the computation of such assessment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Every parlor-car company and sleeping-car company owning parlor and sleeping cars (except those owned by railroad companies and described in paragraph (1) of this subsection) which are operated in the District over or upon the tracks of any railroad or terminal company, shall report to the Mayor of the District of Columbia the total number of miles traveled by all such cars, and also the miles traveled by such cars within the District, during the calendar year next preceding the tax date; the total full and true value of all such cars so used as of the last day of the calendar year next preceding the tax date; and such other facts and information as the Mayor may require. The taxable portion of the value of the cars owned by any such company and used within the District shall be determined by applying to such value the ratio between the mileage traveled by such cars in the District and the total mileage traveled by such cars within and without the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Every car company, mercantile company, corporation or individual (other than railroad, parlor-car, and sleeping-car companies described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection) owning or leasing any stock cars, furniture cars, fruit cars, refrigerator cars, meat cars, oil cars, tank cars, or other similar cars, which are run over or upon the line or lines of any railroad or terminal company in the District of Columbia, shall furnish to the Mayor of the District of Columbia, on forms prescribed by the Mayor, a true, full, and accurate statement, verified by the affidavit of the officer or person making the same, showing the aggregate number of miles made by their several cars over or upon the several lines of railroad within the District of Columbia during the calendar year next preceding the tax date; the average number of miles traveled per day within the District of Columbia by the cars covered by the statement in the ordinary course of business during the year; and such other pertinent facts and information as the Mayor may require.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Every railroad company whose lines run through or into the District of Columbia shall annually furnish to the Mayor a statement showing the name and address of every car company, mercantile company, corporation, or individual (other than railroad, parlor-car, and sleeping-car companies described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection) whose cars made mileage over its tracks in the District of Columbia during the calendar year next preceding the tax date, and the total number of miles made within the District of Columbia by each during said period.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>It shall be the duty of the Mayor to ascertain from the best and most reliable information that can be obtained and from said statements the number of cars required to make the total mileage of each such car company, mercantile company, corporation, or individual within the District of Columbia during the period aforesaid, and to ascertain and fix the valuation upon each particular class of such cars, and the number so ascertained to be required to make the total mileage within the District of Columbia of the cars of each such car company, mercantile company, corporation, or individual within said period shall be assessed against the respective car companies, mercantile companies, corporations, or individuals. The valuation thus obtained shall be the full and true value and shall be the taxable portion of the cars owned by any such car company, mercantile company, corporation, or individual and used within the District of Columbia.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All of the provisions of law relating to the filing of returns, assessment, payment, and collection of personal property taxes in the District of Columbia shall be applicable to the companies described in the foregoing subsections.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Any individual, partnership, unincorporated association, or corporation aggrieved by any assessment of taxes made pursuant to the provisions of this section may appeal therefrom to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the same manner and to the same extent as set forth in §§ <cite path="§47-3303">47-3303</cite>, <cite path="§47-3304">47-3304</cite>, and <cite path="§47-3306">47-3306</cite> to 47-3308.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall be applicable to the taxable year beginning July 1, 1945, and each taxable year thereafter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Dec. 15, 1945, 59 Stat. 610, ch. 579</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 574, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 156(d)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-212">Feb. 28, 1987, D.C. Law 6-212, § 17, 34 DCR 850</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Heating oil and gas, delivery services, applicable taxes, see § <cite path="§47-2501">47-2501</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Telecommunications companies, gross receipts taxes, credit for personal property taxes, see § <cite path="§47-2501">47-2501</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Television, video, or radio service taxes, personal property tax, see § <cite path="§47-2501.01">47-2501.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-1512.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 47-1215.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
