<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1806.09a</num>
  <heading>Tax on residents and nonresidents; credits; lower income, long-term homeowner credit — Allowable credit.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section and § <cite path="§47-1806.09b">47-1806.09b</cite>, an eligible resident shall be allowed a credit against the tax imposed by § <cite path="§47-1806.03">47-1806.03</cite> computed as follows: the amount of the real property tax imposed on the eligible residence under § <cite path="§47-811">47-811</cite> during the real property tax year ending in the tax year for which the credit is allowed, less 105% of the real property tax under § <cite path="§47-811">47-811</cite> imposed on the eligible residence under § <cite path="§47-811">47-811</cite> during the prior real property tax year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If an eligible residence is a unit within a cooperative housing association, the credit shall be computed in accordance with subsection (a) of this section using the net amount of real property tax apportioned to the eligible residence by the cooperative housing association as the amount of real property tax imposed. The cooperative housing association shall provide to the eligible resident upon his request data concerning the amount of real property taxes apportioned to his or her eligible residence by the cooperative housing association for the real property tax year ending in the tax year for which the credit is allowed and the prior real property tax year, accounting for real property tax credits and deductions passed through to the eligible resident to include the homestead deduction under § <cite path="§47-850.01">47-850.01</cite> and the senior citizen deduction under § <cite path="§47-863">47-863</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-114">Apr. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-114, § 401(b), 49 DCR 1468</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1172(c), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1806.09b">47-1806.09b</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1806.09e">47-1806.09e</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-1806.09f">47-1806.09f</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “§ <cite path="§47-1806.09b">47-1806.09b</cite>” for “§ <cite path="§47-1806.08b">47-1806.08b</cite>” and substituted “prior real property tax year” for “prior tax year”; and rewrote subsec. (b) which had read as follows: “(b) The credit allowed by this section shall be allowed for tax years beginning on or after October 1, 2002.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Lower Income, Long-Term Homeowner Credit Administration Temporary Act of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-179">D.C. Law 15-179</cite>, September 8, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 9221).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Lower Income, Long-term Homeowner Credit Administration Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-421, May 10, 2004,  51 DCR 5174).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1172(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1172(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004, 51 DCR).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
