<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1056</num>
  <heading>Rosedale Conservancy, lot 817 in square 1954.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The property located in the District of Columbia described as part of lot 817 in square 1954 situated at 3501 Newark Street, N.W., owned, occupied, and used by the Rosedale Conservancy, is hereby exempt from all taxation so long as:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The real property remains unimproved (except for repairs or maintenance), is maintained as open space and parkland in a manner consistent with the real property’s historical significance, and is reasonably accessible to the general public without charge or payment of a fee of any kind; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>After the transfer of the real property from The Conservation Fund, Inc.:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The real property is owned by the Rosedale Conservancy, an organization qualifying under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 22, 1986 (100 Stat. 2085; 26 U.S.C. § 501(c)(3)), and is used solely to further the tax-exempt purposes of the Rosedale Conservancy; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Rosedale Conservancy does not lease or otherwise allow other persons to occupy the real property in whole or in part.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Sections 47-1005, 47-1007, and 47-1009 shall apply to the real property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, recordation and transfer taxes, and other related charges assessed against real property located on part of square 1954, lot 817, for the period beginning September 25, 2002, including all taxes related to the transfer of the real property from Youth for Understanding to The Conservation Fund, Inc., the interim ownership of the real property by The Conservation Fund, Inc., and the subsequent transfer of the real property from The Conservation Fund, Inc., to the Rosedale Conservancy, shall be forgiven, and any payments already made for this period shall be refunded; provided, that this property is transferred to the Rosedale Conservancy.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-11" type="History">June 21, 2003, D.C. Law 15-11, § 2, 50 DCR 3152</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(a) of the Rosedale Conservancy Real Property Tax Exemption and Relief Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-50, March 28, 2003,  50 DCR 2951).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
