<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1433</num>
  <heading>Violations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Where a dealer fails to record, as required by § <cite path="§47-1431">47-1431</cite>, and such failure is due to negligence, there shall be imposed on said dealer, a penalty of $25 for each month or portion thereof that such failure continues, not to exceed $250.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a person fails to record the deed or other document, as required by § <cite path="§47-1431">47-1431</cite>, there shall be imposed on the person an additional penalty in the amount of $250. The penalty provided herein shall not be imposed if the deed or other document is a security instrument. The Mayor may waive the penalty in accordance with § <cite path="§47-4221">47-4221</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The penalty fees provided under this section shall be collected at the same time and in the same manner and as a part of the deed recordation tax. If the transaction is exempt from the deed recordation tax, then the Mayor shall collect the fees in a manner prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor determines that a person has failed to record or has failed to pay any fee as required by this chapter, the procedures set forth in § <cite path="§42-1108">42-1108</cite> [repealed] shall apply.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall authorize the imposition of a penalty for the failure to record a deed or any instrument that conveys legal title to real property, if failure to record is due solely to the refusal of the Recorder of Deeds to record the deed or other instrument based on the existence of a lien against the property for unpaid water, sanitary sewer, or meter service charges.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-91" type="History">July 13, 1978, D.C. Law 2-91, § 303, 24 DCR 9765</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104" type="History">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 35(b), 35 DCR 147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-136" type="History">June 13, 1990, D.C. Law 8-136, § 6, 37 DCR 2620</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 505(g), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282,§ 11(oo), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-4221">47-4221</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1433.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-3315.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite>, in subsec. (c), rewrote the first sentence which had read: “Where a person other than a dealer fails to record, as required by 47-1431, there shall be imposed on such person a penalty in the amount of $10 for each month or portion thereof that such failure continues, not to exceed $50.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</cite> rewrote subsec. (c) which had read as follows: “(c) If a person other than a dealer fails to record, as required by § <cite path="§47-1431">47-1431</cite>, there shall be imposed on the person a penalty in the amount of $250. Whenever it is shown by such person that failure to record was due to reasonable cause and was not due to knowing omission or neglect, the Mayor may waive part of or all of the penalty fee provided by this subsection. In every case of a partial or total waiver, the reason for the waiver shall be stated clearly on a public record determined by the Mayor.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 5(h) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(tt) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(tt) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5(g) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12§§ of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(tt) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(tt) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority under <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-136">D.C. Law 8-136</cite>, the “D.C. Water and Sewer Operations Act of 1990.”, see Mayor’s Order 91-176, Oct. 24, 1991.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 8 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-136">D.C. Law 8-136</cite> provided that within 60 days of June 13, 1990, the Mayor shall, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, issue proposed rules to implement the provisions of this act including rules regarding deposits, meters, liens, the sale and redemption of real property, the amnesty program, receivership, termination of water and sewer services, and administrative review; that the proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess, and, if the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved; and that if after 90 days from June 13, 1990 the Mayor has failed to issue proposed rules to implement the provisions of this act as provided in subsection (a) of this section, the Council may adopt any legislation necessary to accomplish the purposes of this act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
