<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1810.05</num>
  <heading>Determination of the business income of the combined group.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The business income of a combined group is determined as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>From the total income of the combined group as determined under paragraph (2) of this subsection and subsection (b) of this section, subtract any income and add any expense or loss, other than the business income, expense, or loss of the combined group.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided, the total income of the combined group is the sum of the income of each member of the combined group determined under federal income tax laws, as adjusted for District purposes, as if the member were not consolidated for federal purposes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In the case of any person entitled to the distributive share of a trade or business net income, the Chief Financial Officer shall adopt regulations as necessary to determine the methodology of including the distributive share but provide an exclusion for the portion of the distributive share that is reported by and taxed against any person under the provisions of this chapter to prevent double taxation or double deduction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The income of each member of the combined group shall be determined as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For any member incorporated in the United States, or included in a consolidated federal corporate income tax return, the income to be included in the total income of the combined group shall be the taxable income for the corporation after making appropriate adjustments under this chapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For any member not included in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the income to be included in the total income of the combined group shall be determined as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A profit and loss statement shall be prepared for each foreign branch or corporation in the currency in which the books of account of the branch or corporation are regularly maintained.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Adjustments shall be made to the profit and loss statement to conform it to the accounting principles generally accepted in the United States for the preparation of such statements, except as modified by regulation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Adjustments shall be made to the profit and loss statement to conform it to the tax accounting standards required by this chapter.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Except as otherwise provided by regulation, the profit and loss statement of each member of the combined group, and the apportionment factors related thereto, whether United States or foreign, shall be translated into the currency in which the parent company maintains its books and records.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Income apportioned to the District shall be expressed in United States dollars.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In lieu of the procedures set forth in paragraph (2) of this subsection, and subject to the determination of the Chief Financial Officer that it reasonably approximates income as determined under this chapter, any member not subject to paragraph (1) of this subsection may determine its income on the basis of the consolidated profit and loss statement that includes the member and that is prepared for filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission by related corporations.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If the member is not required to file with the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Chief Financial Officer may allow the use of the consolidated profit and loss statement prepared for reporting to shareholders and subject to review by an independent auditor.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If the statements described in subparagraphs (A) or (B) of this paragraph do not reasonably approximate income as determined under this chapter, the Chief Financial Officer may accept those statements with appropriate adjustments to approximate that income.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>All dividends paid by one to another of the members of the combined group shall, to the extent those dividends are paid out of the earnings and profits of the unitary business included in the combined report, in the current or an earlier year, be eliminated from the income of the recipient.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Except as otherwise provided, this paragraph shall not apply to dividends received from members of the unitary business that are not a part of the combined group. Except when specifically required by the Chief Financial Officer to be included, all dividends paid by an insurance company directly or indirectly to a corporation that is part of a unitary business with the insurance company shall be deducted or eliminated from the income of the recipient of the dividend.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Except as otherwise provided by regulation, business income from an inter-company transaction between members of the same combined group shall be deferred in a manner similar to 26 CFR § 1.1502-13.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Upon the occurrence of any of the following events, deferred business income resulting from an inter-company transaction between members of a combined group shall be restored to the income of the seller and shall be apportioned as business income earned immediately before the event:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The object of a deferred inter-company transaction is:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>Resold by the buyer to an entity that is not a member of the combined group;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>Resold by the buyer to an entity that is a member of the combined group for use outside the unitary business in which the buyer and seller are engaged; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(III)</num>
            <text>Converted by the buyer to a use outside the unitary business in which the buyer and seller are engaged; or</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The buyer and seller are no longer members of the same combined group, regardless of whether the members remain unitary.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A charitable expense incurred by a member of a combined group shall, to the extent allowable as a deduction pursuant to section 170 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, be subtracted first from the business income of the combined group, subject to the income limitations of that section applied to the entire business income of the group, and any remaining amount shall then be treated as a nonbusiness expense allocable to the member that incurred the expense, subject to the income limitations of that section applied to the nonbusiness income of that specific member.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any charitable deduction disallowed under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, but allowed as a carryover deduction in a subsequent year, shall be treated as originally incurred in the subsequent year by the same member, and the rules set forth in this section shall apply in the subsequent year in determining the allowable deduction in that year.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Gain or loss from the sale or exchange of capital assets, property described by section 1231(a)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and property subject to an involuntary conversion shall be removed from the total separate net income of each member of a combined group and shall be apportioned and allocated as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>For each class of gain or loss (short-term capital, long-term capital, section 1231 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and involuntary conversions) all members’ business gain and loss for the class shall be combined without netting between classes and each class of net business gain or loss separately apportioned to each member using the member’s apportionment percentage determined under § <cite path="§47-1810.04">47-1810.04</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Each taxpayer member shall then net its apportioned business gain or loss for all classes, including any such apportioned business gain and loss from other combined groups, against the taxpayer member’s nonbusiness gain and loss for all classes allocated to the District, using the rules of sections 1222 and 1231 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, without regard to any of the taxpayer member’s gains or losses from the sale or exchange of capital assets, section 1231 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 property, and involuntary conversions that are nonbusiness items allocated to another state.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any resulting District source income or loss, if the loss is not subject to the limitations of section 1211 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, of a taxpayer member produced by the application of the preceding subparagraphs shall then be applied to all other District source income or loss of that member.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Any resulting District source loss of a member that is subject to the limitations of section 1211 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be carried over by that member and shall be treated as District source short-term capital loss incurred by that member for the year for which the carryover applies.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Any expense of one member of the unitary group that is directly or indirectly attributable to the nonbusiness or exempt income of another member of the unitary group shall be allocated to that other member as a corresponding nonbusiness or exempt expense, as appropriate.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 8002(d), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 7102(d), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1805.02a">47-1805.02a</cite> and § <cite path="§47-1810.04">47-1810.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 302(d) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-226">D.C. Law 19-226</law-cite> amended this section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“§ <cite path="§47-1810.05">47-1810.05</cite>. Determination of the business income of the combined group.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The business income of a combined group is determined as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) From the total income of the combined group as determined under paragraph (2) of this subsection and subsection (b) of this section, subtract any income and add any expense or loss, other than the business income, expense, or loss of the combined group.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Except as otherwise provided, the total income of the combined group is the sum of the income of each member of the combined group determined under federal income tax laws, as adjusted for District purposes, as if the member were not consolidated for federal purposes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or the combined reporting regulations, if the combined group includes or any member owns an unincorporated business that would be subject to the tax imposed under § <cite path="§47-1808.03">47-1808.03</cite>, the income or loss of such unincorporated business shall be apportioned to the District using the apportionment factor of the unincorporated business, and the combined group member- partner’s distributive share of such income shall be added to the combined group member- partner’s income. A combined group member-partner’s distributive share of an unincorporated business’s income that was actually taxed under § <cite path="§47-1808.03">47-1808.03</cite> shall be subtracted from the combined group member-partner’s income.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The income of each member of the combined group shall be determined as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) For any member incorporated in the United States, or included in a consolidated federal corporate income tax return, the income to be included in the total income of the combined group shall be the taxable income for the corporation after making appropriate adjustments under this chapter.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) For any member not included in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the income to be included in the total income of the combined group shall be determined as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) A profit and loss statement shall be prepared for each foreign branch or corporation in the currency in which the books of account of the branch or corporation are regularly maintained.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Adjustments shall be made to the profit and loss statement to conform it to the accounting principles generally accepted in the United States for the preparation of such statements, except as modified by regulation.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) Adjustments shall be made to the profit and loss statement to conform it to the tax accounting standards required by this chapter.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) Except as otherwise provided by regulation, the profit and loss statement of each member of the combined group, and the apportionment factors related thereto, whether United States or foreign, shall be translated into the currency in which the parent company maintains its books and records.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) Income apportioned to the District shall be expressed in United States dollars.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3)(A) In lieu of the procedures set forth in paragraph (2) of this subsection, and subject to the determination of the Chief Financial Officer that it reasonably approximates income as determined under this chapter, any member not subject to paragraph (1) of this subsection may determine its income on the basis of the consolidated profit and loss statement that includes the member and that is prepared for filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission by related corporations.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) If the member is not required to file with the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Chief Financial Officer may allow the use of the consolidated profit and loss statement prepared for reporting to shareholders and subject to review by an independent auditor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) If the statements described in subparagraphs (A) or (B) of this paragraph do not reasonably approximate income as determined under this chapter, the Chief Financial Officer may accept those statements with appropriate adjustments to approximate that income.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) If a unitary business includes income from a partnership, the income to be included in the total income of the combined group shall be the member of the combined group’s direct and indirect distributive share of the partnership’s unitary business income.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5)(A) All dividends paid by one to another of the members of the combined group shall, to the extent those dividends are paid out of the earnings and profits of the unitary business included in the combined report, in the current or an earlier year, be eliminated from the income of the recipient.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Except as otherwise provided, this paragraph shall not apply to dividends received from members of the unitary business that are not a part of the combined group. Except when specifically required by the Chief Financial Officer to be included, all dividends paid by an insurance company directly or indirectly to a corporation that is part of a unitary business with the insurance company shall be deducted or eliminated from the income of the recipient of the dividend.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6)(A) Except as otherwise provided by regulation, business income from an inter-company transaction between members of the same combined group shall be deferred in a manner similar to  26 C.F.R. § 1.1502-13.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Upon the occurrence of any of the following events, deferred business income resulting from an inter-company transaction between members of a combined group shall be restored to the income of the seller and shall be apportioned as business income earned immediately before the event:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) The object of a deferred inter-company transaction is:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(I) Resold by the buyer to an entity that is not a member of the combined group;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(II) Resold by the buyer to an entity that is a member of the combined group for use outside the unitary business in which the buyer and seller are engaged; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(III) Converted by the buyer to a use outside the unitary business in which the buyer and seller are engaged; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii) The buyer and seller are no longer members of the same combined group, regardless of whether the members remain unitary.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7)(A) A charitable expense incurred by a member of a combined group shall, to the extent allowable as a deduction pursuant to  section 170 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, be subtracted first from the business income of the combined group, subject to the income limitations of that section applied to the entire business income of the group, and any remaining amount shall then be treated as a nonbusiness expense allocable to the member that incurred the expense, subject to the income limitations of that section applied to the nonbusiness income of that specific member.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Any charitable deduction disallowed under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, but allowed as a carryover deduction in a subsequent year, shall be treated as originally incurred in the subsequent year by the same member, and the rules set forth in this section shall apply in the subsequent year in determining the allowable deduction in that year.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) Gain or loss from the sale or exchange of capital assets, property described by  section 1231(a)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and property subject to an involuntary conversion shall be removed from the total separate net income of each member of a combined group and shall be apportioned and allocated as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) For each class of gain or loss (short-term capital, long-term capital,  section 1231 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and involuntary conversions) all members’ business gain and loss for the class shall be combined without netting between classes and each class of net business gain or loss separately apportioned to each member using the member’s apportionment percentage determined under § <cite path="§47-1810.04">47-1810.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Each taxpayer member shall then net its apportioned business gain or loss for all classes, including any such apportioned business gain and loss from other combined groups, against the taxpayer member’s nonbusiness gain and loss for all classes allocated to the District, using the rules of  sections 1222 and  1231 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, without regard to any of the taxpayer member’s gains or losses from the sale or exchange of capital assets,  section 1231 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 property, and involuntary conversions that are nonbusiness items allocated to another state.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) Any resulting District source income or loss, if the loss is not subject to the limitations of  section 1211 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, of a taxpayer member produced by the application of the preceding subparagraphs shall then be applied to all other District source income or loss of that member.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) Any resulting District source loss of a member that is subject to the limitations of  section 1211 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be carried over by that member and shall be treated as District source short-term capital loss incurred by that member for the year for which the carryover applies.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9) Any expense of one member of the unitary group that is directly or indirectly attributable to the nonbusiness or exempt income of another member of the unitary group shall be allocated to that other member as a corresponding nonbusiness or exempt expense, as appropriate.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 303 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-226">D.C. Law 19-226</law-cite> provided that § 302 of the act shall apply for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2010.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 402(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-226">D.C. Law 19-226</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 302(d) of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-482, October 12, 2012,  59 DCR 12478), applicable for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2010.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 302(d) of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-482, October 12, 2012,  59 DCR 12478), applicable for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2010.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 7102(d) and 7103 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 7102(d) and 7103 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 7101 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that Subtitle J of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Combined Reporting Clarification Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 8004 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</law-cite> provided: “Sec. 8004. Applicability. This subtitle shall apply for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2010.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite>: Section 7103 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</law-cite> provided that § 7102 of the act shall apply for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2010.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
