<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1805.01</num>
  <heading>Returns — Forms.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Forms. —</heading>
    <text>The Mayor is hereby authorized and directed to prescribe the forms of returns. All returns required under this subchapter shall be filed on the forms and in the manner prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Duty of Mayor; obligation of taxpayer. —</heading>
    <text>Blank forms of returns of income shall be supplied by the Mayor. It shall be the duty of the Mayor to obtain an income tax return from every taxpayer who is liable under this chapter to file such return; but this duty shall in no manner diminish the obligation of the taxpayer to file a return without being called upon to do so.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Information returns. —</heading>
    <text>Every person subject to the jurisdiction of the District in whatever capacity acting, including receivers or mortgagors of real or personal property, fiduciaries, partnerships, and employers making payment of dividends, interest, rent, premiums, annuities, compensations, remunerations, emoluments, or other income to any person subject to tax under this chapter, shall render such returns thereof to the Mayor as he may by rule prescribe.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <heading>Certificates of nonresidence. —</heading>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <heading>Requirement to file joint federal returns. —</heading>
    <text>Whenever a taxpayer is required by the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to file a joint income tax return with his or her spouse in order to qualify for a tax benefit under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the taxpayer and spouse shall file either a joint return or separate returns on a combined individual form prescribed by the Mayor in order to qualify for a similar benefit afforded under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <heading>Joint filing of returns for domestic partners. —</heading>
    <text>Domestic partners may file either a joint return or separate returns on a combined form prescribed by the Mayor as if the federal government recognized the right of domestic partners to file jointly.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <heading>Joint filing of returns for married same-sex individuals. —</heading>
    <text>Married same-sex individuals may file either a joint return or separate returns on a combined form prescribed by the Mayor as if the federal government recognized the right of married same-sex individuals to file jointly.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 16, 1947, 61 Stat. 340, ch. 258, art. I, title V, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-70" type="History">June 15, 1976, D.C. Law 1-70, title XI, § 1102, 23 DCR 563</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-158" type="History">Mar. 6, 1979, D.C. Law 2-158,§ 4, 25 DCR 7002</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-118" type="History">June 11, 1982, D.C. Law 4-118, § 119, 29 DCR 1770</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-32" type="History">Oct. 8, 1983, D.C. Law 5-32, § 4, 30 DCR 4013</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-9" type="History">June 24, 1987, D.C. Law 7-9, § 2(h), 34 DCR 3283</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-29" type="History">Oct. 1, 1987, D.C. Law 7-29, § 2(e)(1), 34 DCR 5097</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-292" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-292, § 2(b), 54 DCR 1080</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-108" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-108, § 2(b), 57 DCR 22</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1805.03">47-1805.03</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1805.04">47-1805.04</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1812.08">47-1812.08</cite>, § <cite path="§47-4212">47-4212</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-4432">47-4432</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1805.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-1564.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-292">D.C. Law 16-292</cite> added subsec. (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-108">D.C. Law 18-108</cite> added subsec. (g).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue regulations: Section 9 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-32">D.C. Law 5-32</cite> provided that the Mayor shall issue regulations necessary to carry out the provision of the act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability; conditional effect: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-292">D.C. Law 16-292</cite>, provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) Section 2 shall apply as of January 1, 2007.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The Chief Financial Officer shall include the fiscal effect of the act in the next revised quarterly revenue estimate, less the amount to be allocated to section 1043 of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, signed by the Mayor on August 8, 2006 (D.C. Act 16-476;  53 DCR 6899), the Washington Stage Guild Exemption Act of 2006, effective September 26, 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-172">D.C. Law 16-172</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§10-1074">10-1074</cite>), and the Organ and Bone Marrow Donor Act of 2006, signed by the Mayor on December 4, 2006 (D.C. Act 16-536;  53 DCR 9852).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) This act shall take effect subject to the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-108">D.C. Law 18-108</cite> provided: “Section 2 shall apply for tax years beginning January 1, 2009.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
