<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1342</num>
  <heading>Public notice; costs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>At any time after 30 days from the mailing of the notice of delinquency required by § <cite path="§47-1341">47-1341</cite>(a), the Mayor shall, simultaneously:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Cause to be advertised, at least once in not less than 2 newspapers of general circulation in the District that are published at least once every 2 weeks, a public notice stating that listed real property will be sold at public auction because of taxes on the date and at the place named in the public notice; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Post the list of real property in the public notice on the Office of Tax and Revenue’s website.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The list in the public notice shall contain, with substantial accuracy, at least the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A description of the real property, by premises address, taxation square, suffix, and lot number, or parcel and lot number;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The name of the person who last appears on the Mayor’s tax roll as the owner of the real property; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The amount of all taxes for which the real property shall be sold at the scheduled sale; provided, that costs need not be included in the public notice, but, if not included, costs shall be included in the opening bid amount at the time of the sale.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Failure of the Mayor to include a tax in the published notice of sale shall not:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Affect the validity or collectibility of the taxes or the validity of a sale to enforce the payment of taxes;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Prevent or stay proceedings under this chapter; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Affect the title of a purchaser.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The following fees, in an amount prescribed by regulation, shall be costs payable by the purchaser (and paid into the General Fund of the District) and shall be included in the certificate of sale as provided in § <cite path="§47-1348">47-1348</cite>:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A fee for the mailing of a notice;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A fee for publication of notices when a real property is offered for sale, including newspaper advertisements;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>An auctioneer’s fee when a real property is offered for sale at public auction, whether or not the auctioneer is a District employee; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A fee assessed against each real property to reimburse the District for legal representation, whether or not the provider of the service is a District employee.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A redeeming party shall pay the costs to redeem real property bid off to the District, and such costs shall be deemed included in the amount for which the real property was bid off regardless of whether a certificate of sale was issued.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Action taken under § <cite path="§47-1336">47-1336</cite>, relating to energy efficient loans, shall be exempt from the notice requirements of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 507(a)(2), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-141">Dec. 4, 2014, D.C. Law 20-141, § 101(c)(8), 61 DCR 7763</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §§  7102(c)(8), 7104, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1336">47-1336</cite> and § <cite path="§47-1340">47-1340</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite>, repealed before its effective date, would have substituted “the notice of delinquency required by  section 47-1341(a)” for “the notice of delinquency”; substituted “by premises address, taxation square” for “by taxation square”; and added (d).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> rewrote (a); substituted “by premises address, taxation square” for “by taxation square” in (b)(1)(A); and added (d).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(oo) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002, 49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002, 49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002, 49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(8) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-342, May 28, 2014, 61 DCR 5691).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(8) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-409, Aug. 1, 2014,  61 DCR 8281).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7112(c)(8) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(8) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014,  61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(8) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite> became effective on Dec. 4, 2014, but was repealed prior to its effective date by emergency D.C. Act 20-377, § 7114, eff. July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, by emergency D.C. Act 20-449, § 7104, eff. October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, by emergency D.C. Act 20-566, § 7104, eff. January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, and by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7104, 61 DCR 9990.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
