<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1817.03</num>
  <heading>Tax credit to Qualified High Technology Companies for wages to qualified employees; exceptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2000, a Qualified High Technology Company shall be allowed a credit against the tax imposed by § <cite path="§47-1817.06">47-1817.06</cite> equal to 10% of the wages paid during the first 24 calendar months of employment to a qualified employee hired after December 31, 2000.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The credit under subsection (a) of this section shall not be allowed:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To exceed, for each qualified employee, $5,000 in a taxable year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the Qualified High Technology Company accords the qualified employee lesser benefits or rights than it accords other employees in similar jobs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the qualified employee was employed as the result of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The displacement, other than for cause, of another employee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A strike or lockout;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A layoff in which other employees are awaiting recall; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A reduction of the regular wages, benefits, or rights of other employees in similar jobs; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the qualified employee is a member of the board of directors of the Qualified High Technology Company or, directly or indirectly, owns a majority of its stock.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the amount of the credit allowable under this section exceeds the tax otherwise due from a Qualified High Technology Company, the unused amount of the credit may be carried forward for 10 years.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-256" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-256, § 202(b), 48 DCR 730</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-1818.01">47-1818.01</cite> and § <cite path="§47-1818.06">47-1818.06</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
