<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1812.11b</num>
  <heading>Public Fund for Drug Prevention and Children at Risk tax check-off.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the calendar year beginning January 1, 1995, and for each subsequent calendar year, there shall be provided on the District of Columbia individual income tax return a voluntary check-off that indicates that an individual may contribute a minimum donation or gift of $1 to the Public Fund for Drug Prevention and Children at Risk established by § <cite root="47-4002">47-4002</cite>. The contribution shall reduce any refund owed to the individual taxpayer or increase the tax owed by the individual taxpayer on the taxpayer’s tax return. The funds generated from the tax check-off shall be earmarked for the Fund except that any cost incurred by the Mayor in collecting, processing, accounting, or disbursing the funds generated by the tax check-off shall be reimbursed to the Mayor from the funds generated by the tax check-off.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The funds generated by the tax check-off established by subsection (a) of this section shall be transferred to the Fund pursuant to rules issued by the Mayor. The rules shall establish timetables and procedures for transfer. Check-off funds shall be transferred to the Fund only after the costs of the Mayor described in subsection (a) of this section are reimbursed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, any unpaid District tax liability on an individual income tax return shall render any voluntary tax check-off election void. Any amount paid for the purpose of contributing to the Fund shall be used first to satisfy any unpaid tax liability in whole or in part.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If there is any amount that remains after satisfaction of the unpaid tax liability, the amount shall be transferred to the Fund.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the terms “drug prevention”, “children at risk”, “Fund”, and “tax check-off” shall have the same meaning as the terms have in § <cite root="47-4001">47-4001</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-236">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-236, § 2(c), 46 DCR 660</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-226">Mar. 16, 2005, D.C. Law 15-226, § 202(b), 51 DCR 10539</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Public Fund for Drug Prevention and Children at Risk, funding and allocation, see § <cite root="47-4002">47-4002</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Public Fund for Drug Prevention and Children at Risk, “tax check-off” defined, see § <cite root="47-4001">47-4001</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="47-4001">47-4001</cite> and § <cite root="47-4002">47-4002</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-1812.11b.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-226">D.C. Law 15-226</cite>, in the section name line, substituted “Public Fund for Drug Prevention and Children at Risk tax” for “Tax”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 808 of Child and Youth, Safety And Health Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-310, March 26, 2002,  49 DCR 3420).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
