<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1093</num>
  <heading>American Academy of Achievement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning on  [February 26, 2015], the real property designated as Lot 0829 in Square  0182, known as the American Academy of Achievement building, together  with any improvements and furnishings (“Property”) shall  be exempt from all taxation; provided, that the Property is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Owned by the  American Academy of Achievement, a nonprofit corporation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Used for the  purposes and activities of the American Academy of Achievement; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Not used for  any commercial purposes, except as provided in subsection (b) of this  section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Use of the premises  by agencies of the United States of America or by any organization  exempt from federal income taxation shall not affect the exemption  from taxation provided for in this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Section 47-1005 shall apply  with respect to the Property; provided, that a portion of the Property  may be rented out to another person or entity as long as the rent  or other income generated shall be used for the maintenance and preservation  of the Property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The American  Academy of Achievement shall comply with the reporting requirement  of § <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite> and have the appeal rights provided by § <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7242(b), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7242(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7242(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7252(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
