<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-1371</num>
  <heading>Parties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The plaintiff in an action to foreclose the right of redemption shall be the purchaser.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the defendants in an action to foreclose the right of redemption shall be:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The record title holder of the real property;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The legal title holder, if different from the record title holder;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If the real property is encumbered by a recorded life tenancy, the record life tenant and record remaindermen;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>If the real property is subject to an estate for life or a lease or ground rent for a term (with renewals) that is at least 30 years, the record title holder of the fee simple title and the owner of the possessory interest as disclosed by a search performed in accordance with generally accepted standards of title examination of the records of the Recorder of Deeds and the Probate Division of the Superior Court;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Any mortgagee of the real property, or any assignee of the mortgage of record, named as such in an unreleased mortgage recorded in the records of the Recorder of Deeds;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The trustee of record under a deed of trust recorded against the real property and a holder of a beneficial interest in a deed of trust who files notice of the interest, which notice includes identification of the deed of trust, the book and page or roll and frame where the deed of trust is recorded, and the current address at which the holder may be served with a summons; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>The District.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The plaintiff shall certify, under penalties of perjury, to the Superior Court that a search for the defendants has been performed in accordance with generally accepted standards of title examination of the records of the Recorder of Deeds and probate decisions of the Superior Court.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2A)</num>
      <text>The plaintiff shall certify to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, under penalties of perjury, that a search was conducted for the record owner in bankruptcy records.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The plaintiff may elect not to include as a defendant any of the persons named in paragraph (1) of this subsection. However, the rights of any person not included as a defendant shall not be affected by the action.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The plaintiff shall not be required to name as defendant any other person that has, or claims to have, any right, title, interest, claim, lien, or equity of redemption in the real property sold by the Mayor. Any of these persons shall be included as defendants by the designation “all persons that have or claim to have any interest in real property... (giving a description of the real property in substantially the same form as the description that appears on the Mayor’s certificate of sale along with the street address, if any).” Any of these persons shall be designated throughout the action by the above designation, may participate as defendants in the action, and the action may proceed against them by publication under order of court as provided in this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 507(a)(2), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-141">Dec. 4, 2014, D.C. Law 20-141, § 101(c)(24), 61 DCR 7763</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §§  7102(c)(24), 7104, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="47-1372">47-1372</cite>, § <cite root="47-1373">47-1373</cite>, § <cite root="47-1375">47-1375</cite>, and § <cite root="47-1382">47-1382</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite>, repealed before its effective date, would have added (b)(24A).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added (b)(2A).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(oo) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002, 49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002, 49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002, 49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(25) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-342, May 28, 2014, 61 DCR 5691).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7112(c)(24) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(c)(25) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-409, Aug. 1, 2014,  61 DCR 8281).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(24) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014,  61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(c)(24) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(c), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite> became effective on Dec. 4, 2014, but was repealed prior to its effective date by emergency D.C. Act 20-377, § 7114, eff. July 14, 2014,   61 DCR 7598, by emergency D.C. Act 20-449, § 7104, eff. October 10, 2014,   61 DCR 10915, by emergency D.C. Act 20-566, § 7104, eff. January 9, 2015,   62 DCR 884, and by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7104,   61 DCR 9990.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
