<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-2885.11</num>
  <heading>Pharmacy personnel.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No personnel working in any capacity, the activities of which include contact with any merchandise or drugs in a pharmacy or the care of dispensing, manufacturing, or storage facilities, who is affected by, or believed by the Mayor, upon reasonable grounds to be affected by, a communicable disease and no person who is or is believed by the Mayor, upon reasonable grounds, to be a carrier of a communicable disease shall actively engage in any work in a pharmacy.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No proprietor of any pharmacy or manager of any pharmacy shall intentionally permit any person who is, or is believed by the Mayor, upon reasonable grounds, to be, a carrier of a communicable disease to engage or continue to be engaged in any work in the pharmacy.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No person shall work in any capacity in a pharmacy if he or she:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has the following conditions: boils, infectious wounds, sores, or an acute respiratory infection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is wearing unclean garments;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Is a chronic alcoholic as that term is defined in § <cite path="§24-602">24-602</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Does not follow hygienic work practices, including the washing of hands thoroughly before commencing work and as often as is necessary thereafter to remove soil and contamination.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-98">Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-98, § 12, 27 DCR 3528</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-231">May 10, 1989, D.C. Law 7-231, § 10, 36 DCR 492</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 73(g), 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 172(e)(1), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 2-2011.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, in subsec. (b)(1), substituted “Has the following conditions” for “Is afflicted with”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite>, in subsec. (b)(1), inserted a colon following “conditions”.</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 302 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
