<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2412</num>
  <heading>Refunds.</heading>
  <text>Where any tax, penalty, or interest has been erroneously or illegally collected by the Mayor, the tax, penalty, or interest shall be refunded if an application for such refund, under oath, is filed with the Office of Administrative Hearings within 1 year after the date of the payment of such tax. An application for a refund may be filed only by the person upon whom such tax, penalty, or interest was imposed and who has actually paid the tax, penalty, or interest. An application for a refund shall be deemed a request for revision or abatement of an assessment. Upon filing of a valid application for refund, the Office of Administrative Hearings shall either (1) grant the application, or (2) grant the applicant a hearing. After such hearing, the Office of Administrative Hearings shall make findings, grant or deny the application for a refund in accordance with such findings, and notify the applicant of the findings and decision of the Office of Administrative Hearings by regular mail. This section does not authorize the filing of a request for a hearing with respect to any tax, penalty, or interest that was, or could have been, at issue in any prior proceeding that was conducted by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia or the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 27, 1949, 63 Stat. 139, ch. 146, title VI, § 613</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-71" type="History">Mar. 10, 1982, D.C. Law 4-71, § 2, 28 DCR 5243</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-217" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-217, § 4(f), 51 DCR 9126</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2412.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-217">D.C. Law 15-217</cite> rewrote the section which had read as follows: “Where any tax, penalty, or interest has been erroneously or illegally collected by the Mayor, the tax, penalty, or interest shall be refunded if an application for such refund, under oath, is filed with the Mayor within 1 year after the date of the payment of such tax. An application for a refund may be filed only by the person upon whom such tax, penalty, or interest was imposed and who has actually paid the tax, penalty, or interest. An application for a refund shall be deemed a request for revision or abatement of an assessment. Upon filing of a valid application for refund, the Mayor shall either (1) grant the application, or (2) grant the applicant a hearing. After such hearing, the Mayor shall make findings, grant or deny the application for a refund in accordance with such findings, and notify the applicant of the findings and decision of the Mayor by regular mail.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(f) of Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-513, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8976).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(f) of Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-553, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 10359).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
