<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2851.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Basic business license” means the single document designed for public display issued by the business license center that certifies District agency license approval and that incorporates the endorsements for individual licenses included in the basic business license system that the District requires for any person subject to this subchapter. The term “basic business license” shall include a master business license issued prior to the effective date of the Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003, passed on an emergency basis on July 8, 2003 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-317) [August 11, 2003].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1A)</num>
    <text>“Basic business license application” means a document incorporating pertinent data from existing applications for licenses covered under this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1B)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>“Business” means any trade, profession, or activity which provides, or holds itself out to provide, goods or services to the general public or to any portion of the general public, for hire or compensation in the District of Columbia[.]</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>“Business” shall not include the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The activities of any political subdivision, or of any authority created and organized under and pursuant to law of the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>The activities of any compact entered into by the District with any state or political subdivision of a state; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Any employment for wages or salary.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Business License Center” means the business registration and licensing center established by this subchapter and located in and under the administrative control of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Director” means the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“License” means the whole or part of any agency permit, license, certificate, approval, registration, charter, or any form or permission required by law, including agency rule, to engage in any activity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5A)</num>
    <text>“License information packet” means a collection of information about licensing requirements and application procedures custom-assembled for each request.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Person” means any individual, sole proprietorship, partnership, association, cooperative, corporation, nonprofit organization, and any other organization required to obtain one or more licenses from the District or any of its agencies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Regulation” means any licensing or other governmental or statutory requirements pertaining to business or professional activities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Regulatory agency” means any District agency, board, commission, or division which regulates one or more professions, occupations, industries, businesses, or activities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Renewal application” means a document used to collect pertinent data for renewal of licenses covered under this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“System” means the mechanism by which basic business licenses are issued and renewed, license and regulatory information is disseminated, and account data is exchanged by the agencies.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-86" type="History">Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-86, § 101(b), 45 DCR 1172</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2002(b), (c), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38" type="History">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 2(c), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38" type="History">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 2(c), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 73(l)(5), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§22-4510">22-4510</cite>, § <cite path="§37-131.02">37-131.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-2855.01">47-2855.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2851.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-38">D.C. Law 15-38</law-cite>, added new par. (1); added par. (1A); redesignated existing par. (1)(A) as par. (1B)(A); in redesignated par. (1B)(A), substituted “in the District of Columbia.” for “, and which pays, or is subject to the payment of, taxes on earnings, or fees in lieu of taxes, to the District of Columbia, or which qualifies for tax-exempt status under District law.”; repealed pars. (6) and (7); in par. 8, deleted “to register with the District to do business in the District and”; and, in par. (12), substituted “basic” for “master”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</law-cite>, in par. (1B), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Religious Organization Exemption Amendment Temporary Act of 2002 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-216">D.C. Law 14-216</law-cite>, March 25, 2002, law notification  50 DCR 2729).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Religious Organization Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-535, December 2, 2002,  49 DCR 11645).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Religious Organization Exemption Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-415, July 17, 2002,  49 DCR 7382).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Religious Organization Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-45, March 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2812).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 4 of Law 15-38 provided: “Within 16 months of the effective date of this act, the Mayor shall provide the Council with a 12-month report on the effect of this act on the regulatory, economic development, and consumer protection operations of the District of Columbia, with recommendations for modification to the District of Columbia’s regulatory framework, as warranted.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
