<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2832.02</num>
  <heading>Tire dealers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The owners or managers of establishments where waste tires are generated shall pay a license fee as established by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any license for a waste tire generator issued under this chapter shall be issued as a General Services and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No license shall be issued to any waste tire generator that fails to provide the Mayor with information concerning the site’s location, size, and the approximate number of waste tires that have been accumulated at the site, which may not exceed 500.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, pursuant to [subchapter I of Chapter 2 of Title 5, § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], shall issue rules pertaining to the collection and storage of waste tires, which shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A prohibition on outdoor storage of waste tires;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Methods of collection, storage, and processing of waste tires; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Record-keeping procedures for waste tire generators.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The methods of collection, storage, and processing of waste tires shall consider the general location of waste tires being stored with regard to property boundaries and buildings, pest control, accessibility by firefighting equipment, and other considerations as they relate to public health and safety.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The record-keeping procedures for waste tire generators shall include the source and number or weight of tires received and the destination and number of tires or weight of tires or tire pieces shipped or otherwise disposed of. The records shall be maintained for at least 3 years following the end of the calendar year of such activity. Record keeping shall not be required for any charitable, fraternal, or other type of nonprofit organization or association that conducts programs that result in the voluntary cleanup of land, water resources, or collection for disposal of waste tires.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Waste tire” means any automobile, motorcycle, heavy equipment, or truck tire stored or offered for sale by a waste tire generator or otherwise retained by a waste tire generator after having replaced a customer’s tire with a new or used tire.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Waste tire generator” means any person who buys, sells, or stores new or used tires for use on automobiles, motorcycles, heavy equipment, or trucks and which retains any of the customer’s used tires after replacement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-279" type="History">Apr. 23, 2013, D.C. Law 19-279, § 2, 60 DCR 2122</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
