<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2855.04</num>
  <heading>Rules; fees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall adopt rules as necessary to administer this subchapter. The rules may include the specifying of forms and the setting of fees for trade name registrations, amendments, searches, renewals, and copies of registration documents.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Fees set pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall not exceed the actual cost of administering this title [subchapter]; provided, that</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For expedited same-day service, there shall be a fee of $100 in addition to other fees required by statute or rule;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For expedited 3-day service, there shall be a fee of $50 in addition to other fees required by statute or rule.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2005(b), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2041(d), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Rulemaking Authority Pursuant to DC Law 12-261, the Business Regulatory Reform Act of 1998, see Mayor’s Order 2001-123, August 9, 2001 ( 48 DCR 7814).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title of title II of Law 12-261: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§47-2855.01">47-2855.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2041(d) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2041(d) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “The Mayor shall adopt rules as necessary to administer this subchapter. The rules may include the specifying of forms and the setting of fees for trade name registrations, amendments, searches, renewals, and copies of registration documents. Fees shall not exceed the actual cost of administering this subchapter.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2855.4.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
