<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2601</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Alien” means organized under the laws of any country other than the United States or a territory or insular possession of the United States.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Domestic” means organized under the laws of the District of Columbia or under federal legislation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Foreign” means organized under the laws of any state of the United States, or of any territory or insular possession of the United States.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Foreign country” means a country where an insurer, not organized under the laws of the United States, is organized or formally located.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Net premium receipts” or “consideration received” means gross premiums or consideration received less the sum of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Premiums received for reinsurance assumed and consideration returned on contracts not taken or cancelled; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Dividends paid in cash or used by policyholders to pay renewal premiums.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“State” means the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, a state in the United States of America, or a United States possession or territory other than the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 17, 1937, ch. 690, title II, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-113" type="History">as added Sept. 26, 1984, D.C. Law 5-113, § 401, 31 DCR 3974</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 12 of Title 2 of the Act of August 17, 1937, as added by § 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-113">D.C. Law 5-113</cite>, provided that the Mayor shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this chapter pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 901 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-113">D.C. Law 5-113</cite> provided that the Mayor shall issue rules to implement the provisions of the act pursuant to <cite path="1|15|I">subchapter I of Chapter 15 of Title 1</cite>.</text>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2601.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
