<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2886.15</num>
  <heading>Prosecutions; legal services to Board; investigations; injunctions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All violations of laws relating to the practice of engineering in the District of Columbia shall be prosecuted in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia. The Attorney General for the District of Columbia shall render such other legal services as may from time to time be required by the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police of the Metropolitan Police Department shall detail such members of his force as may be necessary to assist the Board in the investigations and prosecutions incident to the enforcement of this part.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia is hereby authorized to apply for relief by injunction to restrain a person from the commission of any act which is prohibited by this part. In such proceedings it shall not be necessary for the Attorney General for the District of Columbia to allege or prove either that an adequate remedy at law does not exist, or that substantial and irreparable damage would result, from the continued violation thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Sept. 19, 1950, 64 Stat. 866, ch. 953, § 15</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-60" type="History">July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 76, 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-2315.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 2-1815.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> substituted “Attorney General for the District of Columbia” for “Corporation Counsel”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Board of Registration for Professional Engineers abolished: See note to § <cite path="§47-2886.05">47-2886.05</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
