<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2884.04</num>
  <heading>Bond.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall file with his application a bond running to the District in the sum of $5,000 with 2 or more sufficient sureties, whose liability as such securities shall not exceed the said sum in the aggregate; except that the execution of any such bond by a fidelity or surety company authorized by the laws of the United States to transact business in the District shall be equivalent to the execution thereof by 2 sureties, but such company, if excepted to, shall justify in the manner required by law of fidelity and surety companies. Such bond shall be approved by the Mayor and conditioned upon the compliance by the applicant with all the provisions of this part and all rules and regulations lawfully made pursuant thereto. Any person injured by the noncompliance with any such provision, rule, or regulation by any licensee under this part may maintain a suit in his own name in any court of competent jurisdiction and recover on the bond such damages as shall be adjudged by such court together with costs of such suit. Recovery upon any such bond shall not preclude recovery against such licensee for any liability in excess of the amount recovered upon the bond, and such recovery shall not be held to extinguish any remedy under other law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The bond or bonds which the licensee is required to file hereunder shall be renewed and refiled annually at the time of making payment of the annual license fee. If the Mayor shall find that any such bond has for any reason become insecure or exhausted, an additional bond in the sum of not more than $5,000 shall be filed by the licensee within 10 days after written demand therefor by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 6, 1956, 70 Stat. 1037, ch. 970, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-1904.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 2-2004.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
