<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2885.17</num>
  <heading>Peddling drugs prohibited.</heading>
  <text>It shall be unlawful for any person to sell or offer for sale by peddling, or to offer for sale from house to house, or to offer for sale by public outcry, or by vending in the street, any drug, medicine, chemical, or controlled substance as defined in the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, or any compound or combination thereof, or any implement, appliance, or other agency for the treatment of disease, injury, or deformity; except, as may be otherwise authorized by law, no person shall throw, cast, deposit, drop, scatter, or leave, or cause to be thrown, cast, deposited, dropped, scattered, or left, any drug, medicine, chemical, or controlled substance as defined in the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, or any compound or combination thereof, upon any public highway or place, or, without the consent of the owner or occupant thereof, upon any premises in the District of Columbia. An offer for sale by peddling includes remaining or wandering about a public place and:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Repeatedly beckoning to, repeatedly stopping, repeatedly attempting to stop, or repeatedly attempting to engage passers-by in conversation;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Repeatedly stopping or attempting to stop motor vehicles; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Repeatedly interfering with the free passage of other persons for the purpose of selling any controlled substance proscribed by the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-98" type="History">Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-98, § 18, 27 DCR 3528</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-57" type="History">Dec. 10, 1981, D.C. Law 4-57, § 4, 28 DCR 4652</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-2885.17a">47-2885.17a</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-2017.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981,” referred to throughout this section, is <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-29">D.C. Law 4-29</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
