<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2853.06</num>
  <heading>Establishment of boards.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Board of Architecture and Interior Designers to consist of 7 members of whom 3 shall be architects, 3 shall be interior designers and one shall be a consumer member. The Board shall regulate the practice of architecture and the practice of interior design.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is hereby established a Board of Accountancy to consist of 5 members. Of the members of the Board, one shall be a consumer member and 4 shall be licensed as certified public accountants who, at the time of their appointments, have been engaged in the practice of public accountancy as certified public accountants in the District for a period of not less than 5 years. The Board shall regulate the practice of public accountants and certified public accountants.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The standards of attestation specified in § <cite path="§47-2853.41">47-2853.41</cite>(1) shall be adopted by reference by the Board pursuant to rulemaking and shall be those developed for general application by recognized national accountancy organizations, such as the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants and the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>There is established a Board of Barber and Cosmetology consisting of 14 members of whom 3 shall be barbers, 3 shall be cosmetologists, 3 shall be specialty cosmetologists, 3 shall be body artists, and 2 shall be consumer members. The Board shall regulate the practice of barbers, body artists, and cosmetologists, including specialty cosmetology practices such as braiding, electrolysis, esthetics, manicuring and others as the Mayor may from time to time establish by rule, instructors and managers of these practices, and owners of such facilities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>There is established a Board of Industrial Trades consisting of 15 members, of whom 3 shall be plumbers licensed in the District, 2 shall be electricians licensed in the District, 2 shall be refrigeration and air conditioning mechanics licensed in the District, 2 shall be steam and other operating engineers licensed in the District, 2 shall be asbestos workers, one shall be an elevator mechanic licensed in the District, one shall be an elevator inspector licensed in the District, one shall be an elevator contractor licensed in the District, and one shall be a consumer member. The Board of Industrial Trades shall regulate the practice of plumbers, gasfitters, electricians, refrigeration and air conditioning mechanics, steam and other operating engineers, asbestos workers, elevator mechanics, elevator inspectors, except for those employed by the District of Columbia or by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, and elevator contractors. The Board may establish bonding and insurance requirements, subcategories of licensure, education, and experience requirements for licensure, and other requirements.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>There is established a Board of Professional Engineering consisting of 7 members of whom 4 shall be professional engineers licensed in the District in various disciplines, 2 shall be land surveyors licensed in the District, and one shall be a consumer member. The Board shall regulate the practice of professional engineers and land surveyors.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>There is established a Board of Funeral Directors consisting of 5 members of whom 4 shall be funeral directors licensed in the District and one shall be a consumer member. The Board shall regulate the practice of funeral directors.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>There is established a Board of Real Estate Appraisers consisting of 5 members, of whom 3 shall be real estate appraisers licensed and in good standing in the District with not less than 3 years experience in real estate appraising immediately preceding his or her appointment to the Board, one of whom shall be a real estate broker licensed and in good standing in the District, and one shall be a consumer member. The Board shall regulate the practice of real estate appraisal, including the functions of a state appraiser certifying and licensing agency under Title XI of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989, approved August 9, 1989 (103 Stat. 511; 12 U.S.C. §§ 3331 through 3351).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>There is established a Board of Real Estate consisting of 9 members of whom 3 shall be real estate brokers licensed in the District, 2 shall be real estate salespersons licensed in the District, 2 shall be property managers licensed in the District, one shall be an attorney admitted to the bar of the District of Columbia and engaged in the practice of real estate law, and one shall be a consumer member. All members of the Board shall be residents of the District during their tenure. The Board shall regulate the practices of real estate brokers, real estate salespersons, and property managers.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 1002, 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-130" type="History">June 16, 2006, D.C. Law 16-130, § 2(b), 53 DCR 4718</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2151(c), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-43" type="History">Dec. 2, 2011, D.C. Law 19-43, § 2(b), 58 DCR 8928</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-193" type="History">Oct. 23, 2012, D.C. Law 19-193, § 3(d), 59 DCR 10388</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-271" type="History">Apr. 23, 2013, D.C. Law 19-271, § 2(a), 60 DCR 1727</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mayoral nomination of agency heads, review and approval of Council, boards established under this section, see § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>, § <cite path="§47-2853.02">47-2853.02</cite>, § <cite path="§47-2853.41">47-2853.41</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-2853.221">47-2853.221</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2853.6.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-130">D.C. Law 16-130</cite> rewrote subsecs. (b) and (g).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> rewrote subsec. (d), which had read as follows: “(d) There is established a Board of Industrial Trades consisting of 15 members of whom 3 shall be plumbers licensed in the District, 3 shall be electricians licensed in the District, 3 shall be refrigeration and air conditioning mechanics licensed in the District, 3 shall be steam and other operating engineers licensed in the District, 2 shall be asbestos workers, and one shall be a consumer member. The Board shall regulate the practice of plumbers, gasfitters, electricians, refrigeration and air conditioning mechanics, steam and other operating engineers, and asbestos workers.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-43">D.C. Law 19-43</cite>, in subsec. (b), designated the existing text as par. (1), and added par. (2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-193">D.C. Law 19-193</cite> in (c), substituted “14 members” for “11 members” in the first sentence and substituted “practice of barbers, body artists, and cosmetologists” for “practice of barbers and cosmetologists.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-271">D.C. Law 19-271</cite> added “3 shall be body artists” in the first sentence of (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-101">D.C. Law 16-101</cite> amended subsecs. (b) and (g) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) There is established a Board of Accountancy to consist of 5 members. Of the members of the Board, one shall be a consumer member and 4 shall be licensed as certified public accountants who, at the time of their appointments, have been engaged in the practice of public accountancy as certified public accountants in the District for a period of not less than 5 years. The Board shall regulate the practice of public accountants and certified public accountants.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(g) There is established a Board of Real Estate Appraisers consisting of 5 members, of whom 3 shall be real estate appraisers licensed and in good standing in the District with not less than 3 years experience in real estate appraising immediately preceding his or her appointment to the Board, one shall be a real estate broker licensed and in good standing in the District, and one shall be a consumer member. In addition to assuming the powers enumerated in § <cite path="§47-2853.08">47-2853.08</cite>, the Board shall regulate the practice of real estate appraisal, including the functions of a state appraiser certifying and licensing agency under Title XI of the Financial Institutions Recovery, Reform, and Enforcement Act of 1989, approved August 9, 1989 (103 Stat. 183; 12 U.S.C. §§ 3331 through  3351).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-101">D.C. Law 16-101</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Non-Health Related Occupations and Professions Licensure Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-255, January 26, 2006,  53 DCR 763).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2151(c) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2151(c) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Re-Designation of the Board of Real Estate as the Real Estate Commission, see Mayor’s Order 2009-11, February 2, 2009 ( 56 DCR 2030).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 134 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, as amended by section 18(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-313">D.C. Law 13-313</cite>, transferred the authority established by the District of Columbia Funeral Services Regulatory Act of 1984 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 5-84">D.C. Law 5-84</cite>) to the Board of Funeral Directors established by this section.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Although a new Board of Funeral Directors has been established by the Second Omnibus Regulatory Reform Act of 1998, effective April 20, 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-261">D.C. Law 12-261</cite>), codified under D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§47-2853.06">47-2853.06</cite>(f), the old board, codified under D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§3-401">3-401</cite> et seq. has not been abolished by law.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-43">D.C. Law 19-43</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-43">D.C. Law 19-43</cite>, § 3, was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite>, § 7010.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
