<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2010</num>
  <heading>Presumption of taxability.</heading>
  <text>It shall be presumed that all receipts from the sale of tangible personal property and services mentioned in this chapter are subject to tax until the contrary is established, and the burden of proving that a receipt is not taxable hereunder shall be upon the vendor or the purchaser as the case may be. Except as provided in § <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>(3), unless the vendor shall have taken from the purchaser a certificate signed by and bearing the name and address of the purchaser and the number of his registration certificate to the effect that the property or service was purchased for resale or the property or service is exempt under § <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>, the receipts from all sales shall be deemed taxable. The certificate herein required shall be in such form as the Mayor shall prescribe and, in case no certificate is furnished or obtained prior to the time the sale is consummated, the tax shall apply to the gross receipts therefrom as if the sale were made at retail.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 27, 1949, 63 Stat. 117, ch. 146, title I, § 130</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-131" type="History">July 24, 1982, D.C. Law 4-131, § 223, 29 DCR 2418</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 102(d), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Compensating-use tax, collection of tax by vendor, see § <cite path="§47-2203">47-2203</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Compensating-use tax, nonresident vendors, see § <cite path="§47-2204">47-2204</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-2203">47-2203</cite> and § <cite path="§47-2204">47-2204</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2010.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-2607.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite>, in the second sentence, substituted “the property or service was purchased for resale or the property or service is exempt under 47-2005,” for “the property or service was purchased for resale,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 103 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> provided: “Sec. 103. Applicability. Section 102(a) through (c) shall apply beginning April 1, 2001. Section 102(d) shall apply beginning October 1, 2001.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
