<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2834</num>
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <heading>Sales on streets or public places.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 1, 1902, 32 Stat. 627, ch. 1352, § 7, par. 36</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 1, 1932, 47 Stat. 557, ch. 366</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-82" type="History">Sept. 14, 1976, D.C. Law 1-82, title I, § 104(aa), 23 DCR 2461</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-113" type="History">Sept. 26, 1984, D.C. Law 5-113, § 501, 31 DCR 3974</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-86" type="History">Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-86,§ 1102, 45 DCR 1172</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(pp)(30), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 52(s), 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38" type="History">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 3(hh)(4)(S), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 73(l)(2), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-72" type="History">Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-72, § 2, 53 DCR 372</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-71" type="History">Oct. 22, 2009, D.C. Law 18-71, § 12(c)(2), 56 DCR 6619</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2834.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-2336.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-252">D.C. Law 16-252</cite> amended subsec. (c) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs may, by rule, establish and revise every 2 years a site specific schedule of license fees to replace the fees listed under subsection (a) of this section to reflect the adoption of a regulatory system that assigns specific vending sites and assesses a license fee that reflects the administrative cost of licensure and periodic inspection of food and merchandise vendors.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 7(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-252">D.C. Law 16-252</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-241">D.C. Law 17-241</cite> added subsec. (c-1) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c-1)(1) No later than July 21, 2008, the Mayor shall establish 14 additional vendor locations to be added to the 28 currently identified to increase the number of viable sites to 42 to adhere to the requirements of subsection (c) of this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) No later than July 21, 2008, the Mayor shall hold a lottery for the 14 additional vending locations and those vendors selected shall be assigned vending locations, as specifically herein provided, for the duration of the 2008 baseball season.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The 14 sites assigned pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be located as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) Two sites on First Street, S.E., between N Street, S.E., and N Place, S.E. (Eastside);</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Two sites on First Street, S.E., between N Place, S.E., and O Street, S.E. (Eastside);</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) Seven sites on Half Street, S.E., between M Street, S.E., and N Street, S.E. (Westside); and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) Three sites on N Street, S.E., between Half Street, S.E., and Van Street, S.E. (Northside).”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-241">D.C. Law 17-241</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-252">D.C. Law 16-252</cite> provided:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Pursuant to Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), the Department of Transportation, the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, the Department of Health, and the Metropolitan Police Department may promulgate rules specific to their vending responsibilities, incorporating the best practices for the planning, cart design, management, site identification, fees and applicable taxes, and enforcement of sidewalk and roadway vendors to ensure public health and safety. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 30-day period of review. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules by resolution within the 30-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed disapproved. In no event shall there be an interpretation of this section that rulemaking shall be necessary for the issuance of licenses or permits.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 7(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-252">D.C. Law 16-252</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Sections 2 to 10 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-172">D.C. Law 17-172</cite> added sections to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Definitions.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“For the purposes of this act, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) ‘Vending location’ means the specific locations on sidewalks, roadways, and other public space from which a person may vend.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) ‘Vending site permit’ means a permit or other authorization to vend from a vending location.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 3. Vending from public space.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Except as set forth in subsection (b) of this section, a person shall not vend from a sidewalk, roadway, or other public space in the District of Columbia unless the person holds:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) A basic business license properly endorsed for sidewalk or roadway vending;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) A vending site permit; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Such other licenses, permits, and authorizations as the Mayor may require by rule.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Mayor may authorize the following persons to vend from public space without a basic business license or vending site permit:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) An employee or youth assistant of a licensed vendor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) A person vending at a licensed special event; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) A person vending from a public market holding a valid permit issued by the Mayor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 4. Vending locations and assignment.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Mayor shall designate vending locations; provided, that no vending locations shall be established in Ward 2 of the District of Columbia other than those previously authorized under the District of Columbia Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Temporary Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-252">D.C. Law 16-252</cite>;  54 DCR 631), who are vending in a location that is in compliance with Chapter 5 of Title 24 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, except as may be established through a vending development zone authorized under section 5; provided further, that no more than 350 vending locations shall be permitted in any single Ward of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) A person shall not vend from a location other than a vending location unless the person is vending at a special event or public market holding a valid license or permit issued by the Mayor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) A person shall not vend from a vending location without first obtaining a vending site permit from the Mayor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d)(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, vending locations shall be assigned by lottery, unless:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) The Mayor establishes an alternate means of assignment by rule; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) The vending location is located in a vending development zone, in which case the vending location may be assigned by lottery or such other means as may be established for the vending development zone pursuant to section 5.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Vendors who received vending site permits for a vending location pursuant to the District of Columbia Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Temporary Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-252">D.C. Law 16-252</cite>;  54 DCR 631), who are vending in a location that is in compliance with Chapter 5 of Title 24 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, shall have first right of preference for the issuance of a vending site permit for the same vending location.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 5. Vending development zones..</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“The Mayor may establish vending development zones, upon application and after public hearing, in which the Mayor may waive the regulatory provisions, such as the design standards, the standards for designation of vending locations, and the procedure for assigning vending locations, otherwise applicable to vendors; provided, that the Mayor shall establish, by rule, a procedure for reviewing applications for the establishment of a vending development zone.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 6. Capitol Riverfront Vending Development Zone.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Notwithstanding section 5, but subject to subsection (f) of this section, there is established the Capitol Riverfront Vending Development Zone (’CRVDZ’).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The boundaries of the CRVDZ shall be the same as the boundaries for the Capitol Riverfront BID, established by section 208 of the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996, effective October 18, 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-27">D.C. Law 17-27</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-1215.58">2-1215.58</cite>).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The Mayor shall issue no fewer than 40 vendor locations, with preference to the vendors who are legally licensed to vend at Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium, within 21 days of the effective date of the Expanding Opportunities for Vending Around the Baseball Stadium Emergency Amendment Act of 2008, passed on emergency basis on April 1, 2008 (Enrolled version of Bill 17-690), and shall designate and assign vending locations within the CRVDZ.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) Vending locations assigned within the CRVDZ shall be assigned by lottery.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) Except as provided in this section, the Mayor may waive the regulatory provisions otherwise applicable to vendors, such as design standards, siting standards, and the types of permitted vending.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(f) The CRVDZ, and any licenses or permits issued therefor, shall expire if any new development zone is hereafter established with the boundaries of the CRVDZ pursuant to section 5.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(g) Pursuant to Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), the Mayor may issue rules to implement this section; provided, that the Mayor may also issue emergency rules to implement this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 7. Public markets.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“The Mayor may require the permitting of public markets on public space and may require the licensing of managers of public markets on public space and private space.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 8. Fees and funding.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Mayor may establish fees, by rule, for the application for, and issuance of, each license, permit, and authorization required under this act or the rules promulgated pursuant to this act. The Mayor may differentiate the fees based on the class of license, vending location, and other relevant factors.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b)(1) There is established as a nonlapsing fund within the General Fund of the District of Columbia the Vending Regulation Fund (‘Fund’), which shall be used solely for the purposes set forth in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Deposits into the Fund shall include:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) Fees paid for the application for, and issuance or renewal of, a vending permit;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Fees paid for the application for, and issuance or renewal of, the permit or other authorization issued by the Mayor setting forth the specific location on public space from which a person may vend;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) Funds authorized by an act of Congress, reprogramming, or intra-District transfer to be deposited into the Fund;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) Any other funds designated by law or rule to be deposited into the Fund; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) Interest on funds deposited in the Fund.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) All funds deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in paragraph (4) of this subsection, subject to authorization by Congress.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) Funds in the Fund may be used to pay the costs of administering this act, including costs associated with the issuance of licenses and permits described in paragraph (2)(A) and (B) of this subsection and the administration and enforcement of any rules promulgated under this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 9. Penalties.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“The Mayor may establish civil penalties for the violation of this act and rules promulgated pursuant to this act, including the establishment of civil penalties pursuant to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 6-42">D.C. Law 6-42</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-1801.01">2-1801.01</cite> et seq.).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 10. Rules.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“The Mayor, pursuant to Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), may issue rules to implement this act, including rules regulating the design and maintenance of vendor carts, stands, vehicles, and other equipment and rules requiring that persons vending from public space maintain insurance in such form and amount as may be required by the Mayor. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 60-day period of review, excluding weekends, holidays, and days of Council recess; provided, that rules regarding fees shall be submitted separately. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, by resolution, within the 60-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed disapproved.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 13(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-172">D.C. Law 17-172</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-205">D.C. Law 17-205</cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 5a. Capitol Riverfront Vending Development Zone.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Notwithstanding section 5, but subject to subsection (f) of this section, there is established the Capitol Riverfront Vending Development Zone (’CRVDZ’).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The boundaries of the CRVDZ shall be the same as the boundaries for the Capitol Riverfront BID, established by section 208 of the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996, effective October 18, 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-27">D.C. Law 17-27</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-1215.58">2-1215.58</cite>).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The Mayor shall issue no fewer than 40 vendor locations, with preference to the vendors who are legally licensed to vend at Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium, on or before the effective date of the Expanding Opportunities for Vending Around the Baseball Stadium Emergency Amendment Act of 2008, effective April 17, 2008 (D.C. Act 17-353;  55 DCR 5370, and shall designate and assign vending locations within the CRVDZ.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) Vending locations assigned within the CRVDZ shall be assigned by lottery.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) Except as provided in this section, the Mayor may waive the regulatory provisions otherwise applicable to vendors, such as design standards, siting standards, and the types of permitted vending.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(f) The CRVDZ, and any licenses or permits issued therefor, shall expire if any new development zone is hereafter established with the boundaries of the CRVDZ pursuant to section 5.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(g) Pursuant to Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), the Mayor may issue rules to implement this section; provided, that the Mayor may also issue emergency rules to implement this section.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-205">D.C. Law 17-205</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Sections 2 to 9 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-4">D.C. Law 18-4</cite> added sections to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Definitions.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“For the purposes of this act, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) ‘Vending location’ means the specific locations on sidewalks, roadways, and other public space from which a person may vend.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) ‘Vending site permit’ means a permit or other authorization to vend from a vending location.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 3. Vending from public space.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Except as set forth in subsection (b) of this section, a person shall not vend from a sidewalk, roadway, or other public space in the District of Columbia unless the person holds:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) A basic business license properly endorsed for sidewalk or roadway vending;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) A vending site permit; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Such other licenses, permits, and authorizations as the Mayor may require by rule.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Mayor may authorize the following persons to vend from public space without a basic business license or vending site permit:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) An employee or youth assistant of a licensed vendor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) A person vending at a licensed special event; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) A person vending from a public market holding a valid permit issued by the Mayor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) No authorization from the Mayor is required for vending pursuant to section 105(h) of the First Amendment Assemblies Act of 2004, effective April 13, 2005 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-532">D.C. Law 15-532</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§5-331.05">5-331.05</cite>(h)).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 4. Vending locations and assignment.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Mayor shall designate vending locations; provided, that no vending locations shall be established in Ward 2 of the District of Columbia other than those previously authorized under the District of Columbia Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Temporary Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-252">D.C. Law 16-252</cite>;  54 DCR 631), who are vending in a location that is in compliance with Chapter 5 of Title 24 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, except as may be established through a vending development zone authorized under section 5; provided further, that no more than 350 vending locations shall be permitted in any single Ward of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) A person shall not vend from a location other than a vending location unless the person is vending at a special event or public market holding a valid license or permit issued by the Mayor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) A person shall not vend from a vending location without first obtaining a vending site permit from the Mayor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d)(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, vending locations shall be assigned by lottery, unless:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) The Mayor establishes an alternate means of assignment by rule; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) The vending location is located in a vending development zone, in which case the vending location may be assigned by lottery or such other means as may be established for the vending development zone pursuant to section 5.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Vendors who received vending site permits for a vending location pursuant to the District of Columbia Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Temporary Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-252">D.C. Law 16-252</cite>;  54 DCR 631), who are vending in a location that is in compliance with Chapter 5 of Title 24 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, shall have first right of preference for the issuance of a vending site permit for the same vending location.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 5. Vending development zones.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“The Mayor may establish vending development zones, upon application and after public hearing, in which the Mayor may waive the regulatory provisions, such as the design standards, the standards for designation of vending locations, and the procedure for assigning vending locations, otherwise applicable to vendors; provided, that the Mayor shall establish, by rule, a procedure for reviewing applications for the establishment of a vending development zone.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 6. Public markets.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“The Mayor may require the permitting of public markets on public space and may require the licensing of managers of public markets on public space and private space.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 7. Fees and funding.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Mayor may establish fees, by rule, for the application for, and issuance of, each license, permit, and authorization required under this act or the rules promulgated pursuant to this act. The Mayor may differentiate the fees based on the class of license, vending location, and other relevant factors.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b)(1) There is established as a nonlapsing fund within the General Fund of the District of Columbia the Vending Regulation Fund (”Fund“), which shall be used solely for the purposes set forth in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Deposits into the Fund shall include:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) Fees paid for the application for, and issuance or renewal of, a vending permit;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Fees paid for the application for, and issuance or renewal of, the permit or other authorization issued by the Mayor setting forth the specific location on public space from which a person may vend;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) Funds authorized by an act of Congress, reprogramming, or intra-District transfer to be deposited into the Fund;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) Any other funds designated by law or rule to be deposited into the Fund; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) Interest on funds deposited in the Fund.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) All funds deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in paragraph (4) of this subsection, subject to authorization by Congress.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) Funds in the Fund may be used to pay the costs of administering this act, including costs associated with the issuance of licenses and permits described in paragraph (2)(A) and (B) of this subsection and the administration and enforcement of any rules promulgated under this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 8. Penalties.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“The Mayor may establish civil penalties for the violation of this act and rules promulgated pursuant to this act, including the establishment of civil penalties pursuant to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 6-42">D.C. Law 6-42</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-1801.01">2-1801.01</cite> et seq.).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 9. Rules.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“The Mayor, pursuant to Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), may issue rules to implement this act, including rules regulating the design and maintenance of vendor carts, stands, vehicles, and other equipment and rules requiring that persons vending from public space maintain insurance in such form and amount as may be required by the Mayor. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 60-day period of review, excluding weekends, holidays, and days of Council recess; provided, that rules regarding fees shall be submitted separately. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, by resolution, within the 60-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed disapproved.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 12(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-4">D.C. Law 18-4</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 11(c)(2) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-172">D.C. Law 17-172</cite> repealed this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 13(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-172">D.C. Law 17-172</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 10(c)(2) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-4">D.C. Law 18-4</cite> repealed this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 12(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-4">D.C. Law 18-4</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(hh)(4)(S) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003,  50 DCR 6896).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-564, December 19, 2006,  53 DCR 10264).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) enactment, see § 5 of Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C.   Act 16-564, December 19, 2006,  53 DCR 10264).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 2 to 9 of Vending Regulation Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-322, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3445).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section, see §  10(c)(2) of Vending Regulation Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-322, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3445).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §  2 of Expanding Opportunities for Street Vending Around the Baseball Stadium Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-353, April 17, 2008,  55 DCR 5370).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section 6 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-172">D.C. Law 17-172</cite>, see §  2 of Expanding Opportunities for Street Vending Around the Baseball Stadium Clarifying Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-427, July 16, 2008,  55 DCR 8250).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§  2 to 9 of Vending Regulation Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-9, January 29, 2009,  56 DCR 1638).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal, see §  10(c)(2) of Vending Regulation Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-9, January 29, 2009,  56 DCR 1638).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§  2 to 9 of Vending Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-47, April 27, 2009,  56 DCR 3574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal, see §  10(c)(2) of Vending Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-47, April 27, 2009,  56 DCR 3574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 502 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-113">D.C. Law 5-113</cite> provided that § 501 shall take effect April 1, 1985.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to an Act Making Appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes, see Mayor’s Order 98-139, August 20, 1998 ( 45 DCR 6591).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: See second paragraph of note to § <cite path="§47-2601">47-2601</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
