<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2403</num>
  <heading>Exemptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Sale or possession of cigarettes in the District under the following circumstances shall be exempt from the tax levied and imposed by § <cite path="§47-2402">47-2402</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Sales of cigarettes or other tobacco products to or by the United States or the District government, or any instrumentalities thereof; possession of cigarettes or other tobacco products lawfully purchased from such governmental entities by persons legally entitled to purchase or receive such cigarettes or other tobacco products; and transfers, without consideration, of cigarettes or other tobacco products lawfully purchased from such governmental entities by persons legally entitled to purchase or receive such cigarettes or other tobacco products to other persons legally entitled to purchase or receive such cigarettes or other tobacco products from such governmental entities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>[Repealed];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Possession of cigarettes by licensed wholesalers for sale outside of the limits of the District or for sale to other licensed wholesalers as provided for in § <cite path="§47-2402">47-2402</cite>(f); sales of cigarettes by licensed wholesalers to other licensed wholesalers as provided for in § <cite path="§47-2402">47-2402</cite>(f); and possession by authorized licensed retailers and vending machine operators of cigarettes bearing cigarette tax stamps issued by any other state or jurisdiction for sale in such other state or jurisdiction; provided, that such authorized licensed retailers and vending machine operators are licensed under the laws of such other state or jurisdiction to engage in the business of selling cigarettes therein;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Possession by a consumer of 200 or fewer cigarettes, which do not bear proper evidence of the payment of the tax levied and imposed by § <cite path="§47-2402">47-2402</cite>, transported into the District by a consumer or manufactured in the District by a consumer; transfers, without consideration, of such cigarettes from 1 consumer to another consumer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Possession of cigarettes or other tobacco products while being transported under such conditions that they are not deemed contraband under the provisions of § <cite path="§47-2405">47-2405</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Possession of other tobacco product by licensed wholesalers for sale outside of the limits of the District or for sale to other licensed wholesalers as provided for in § <cite path="§47-2402">47-2402</cite>(f), sales of other tobacco products by licensed wholesalers to other licensed wholesalers as provided for in § <cite path="§47-2402">47-2402</cite>(f), and possession by authorized licensed retailers and vending machine operators of other tobacco products on which the tax rate for any other state or jurisdiction has been paid, for sale in such other state or jurisdiction; provided, that such authorized licensed retailers and vending machine operators are licensed under the laws of such other state or jurisdiction to engage in the business of selling other tobacco products therein.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The burden of proof that any cigarettes or other tobacco products are exempt from taxation under this chapter shall be upon the person who sells or possesses such cigarettes or other tobacco products.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 27, 1949, 63 Stat. 138, ch. 146, title VI, § 604</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-71" type="History">Mar. 10, 1982, D.C. Law 4-71, § 2, 28 DCR 5243</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-33" type="History">Sept. 10, 1985, D.C. Law 6-33, § 2(b), 32 DCR 3774</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7012(e)(5), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-2402">47-2402</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2403.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-2803.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added “or other tobacco products” throughout this section; and added (a)(6) and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7022(e)(5) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7012(e)(5) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7012(e)(5) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 3(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-33">D.C. Law 6-33</cite> provided that the provisions of the act shall not operate before the 1st day of the 1st month which begins more than 30 days after September 10, 1985.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
