<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-2884.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>As used in this part:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term “person” means an individual, firm, voluntary association, joint-stock company, incorporated society, or corporation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term “District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District or the agent or agents designated by him to perform any function vested in the Mayor by this part; provided, that for the purposes of subsection (e) of § <cite path="§47-2884.07">47-2884.07</cite> no such agent shall, by way of appeal, review his own action, decision, or ruling.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term “pawnbroker” means any person who shall in any manner lend or advance money or other things for profit on pledge and possession of personal property or other valuable thing, other than securities or written or printed evidences of indebtedness or who deals in the purchasing of personal property or other valuable thing on condition of selling the same back again at a  stipulated price, and shall include all pawnbrokers referred to in §§ <cite path="§5-117.01">5-117.01</cite>, <cite path="§5-117.02">5-117.02</cite>, and <cite path="§5-117.03">5-117.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 6, 1956, 70 Stat. 1036, ch. 970, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-1901.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 2-2001.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
