<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2885.15</num>
  <heading>Records.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There shall be maintained in every pharmacy, or in the establishment or institution where a pharmacy is located, a suitable book, file, or other easily retrievable record, in which shall be preserved for a period of not less than 2 years every prescription compounded or dispensed at said pharmacy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There shall be maintained a bound volume recording the information required by law or regulation concerning the over-the-counter sales of those drugs which are listed in schedule V established or amended pursuant to the federal Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (21 U.S.C. § 801 et seq.).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>There shall also be maintained a bound volume in which shall be entered similar information concerning each sale of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Hypodermic syringes, needles, or other medical devices which may be used in the administration of controlled substances;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Gelatin capsules and glassine envelopes in quantities sufficient to indicate an intention to use such items in the distribution of controlled substances; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Diluents or adulterants, such as lactose or quinine, in quantities sufficient to indicate an intention to use such substances for the illegal distribution or dispensing of any controlled substance.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The records required to be maintained by this section shall be available for inspection by the Mayor during regular business hours.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-98" type="History">Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-98, § 16, 27 DCR 3528</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-2015.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
