<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2351</num>
  <heading>Reciprocal agreements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to enter into reciprocal agreements on behalf of the District with the duly authorized representatives of any jurisdiction of the United States or of a foreign country to satisfy the requirements of the IFTA. The Mayor is expressly authorized to enter into the IFTA and become a member of the International Fuel Tax Association, Inc., or such other organization that may, from time to time, be created to implement the reporting requirements of the IFTA.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The IFTA and any other agreements associated with the IFTA that are entered into by the Mayor shall take precedence over any District law or regulation that may be in conflict with such agreements.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The District, as a member jurisdiction to the IFTA, shall provide reciprocity to motor vehicle carriers that are engaged in interjurisdictional movement and intrajurisdictional movement, and are properly registered with another member jurisdiction.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-153" type="History">Sept. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-153, § 2(d), 45 DCR 3853</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2351.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Withdrawal from Compact on Taxation of Motor Fuels Consumed by Interstate Buses: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-153">D.C. Law 12-153</cite> provided that the District of Columbia withdraws from participation in the Compact on Taxation of Motor Fuels Consumed by Interstate Buses, approved April 14, 1965 (P.L. 89-11; 79 Stat. 58).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Complementary Legislation: D.C.—D.C. Official Code, 2001 Ed. §§ <cite path="§47-2351">47-2351</cite> to 47-2354. Neb.—R.R.S. 1943, §§ <cite path="§66-1401">66-1401</cite> to 66-1415.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
