<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2422</num>
  <heading>Civil penalties and administrative sanctions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may revoke, suspend, or deny under § <cite path="§47-2405">47-2405</cite> the general sales license endorsement on the master business license of any cigarette or other tobacco product dealer for a violation of this chapter or any implementing rule promulgated by the Mayor as provided under § <cite path="§47-2415">47-2415</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of § <cite path="§47-2404">47-2404</cite>, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of that section, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infraction of § <cite path="§47-2404">47-2404</cite>, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of that section, shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may (1) impose a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed the greater of 500% of the retail value of the cigarettes or other tobacco product involved or $5,000 for a violation of this chapter, or (2) assess tax due and interest on any product acquired, possessed, sold, or offered for sale in violation of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The license or authorization to affix stamps of an agent, distributor, dealer, or person found liable for a civil penalty under subsection (b)(1) of this section on 2 or more occasions shall be revoked and the agent, distributor, dealer, or person shall not be eligible for a license or authorized by the District to affix tax stamps under this chapter for one year.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-225" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-225, § 2(c), 48 DCR 35</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-313" type="History">June 19, 2001, D.C. Law 13-313, § 16(c)(3), 48 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-189" type="History">July 23, 2010, D.C. Law 18-189, § 4(d), 57 DCR 3019</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7012(e)(9), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-313">D.C. Law 13-313</cite> inserted the section symbol in the section heading.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-189">D.C. Law 18-189</cite> added subsec. (a-1); and, in subsec. (b), substituted “cigarettes or other tobacco product” for “cigarettes”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added “or other tobacco product” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7022(e)(9) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7012(e)(9) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7012(e)(9) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
