<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2885.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For purposes of this part:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term “Board” means the District of Columbia Board of Pharmacy established by the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term “dispense” means to sell, distribute, leave with, give away, dispose of, prepare or deliver a drug.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “drug” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any substance recognized as a drug, medicine, or medicinal chemical in the official United States Pharmacopoeia, official National Formulary, official Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia, or official Veterinary Medicine Compendium or other official drug compendium or any supplement to any of them;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Any substance intended for use in the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease in man or other animal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Any chemical substance (other than food) intended to affect the structure or any function of the body of man or other animal; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Any substance intended for use as a component of any items specified in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of this paragraph, but does not include medical devices or their components, parts, or accessories.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term “labeling” means the process of affixing a label to any drug container, but does not include the labeling by a manufacturer, packer, or distributor of an over-the-counter drug, packaged legend drug, or medical device.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or the Mayor’s designated agent.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The term “medical device” means an instrument, apparatus, implement, machine, contrivance, implant, in vitro reagent, or other similar or related article, including any component, part, or accessory, which is:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Recognized in the official National Formulary, the official United States Pharmacopoeia, or any supplement thereto;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Intended for use in the diagnosis of disease or any other condition, or in the cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease in man or other animal; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Intended to affect the structure or any function of the body of man or other animal, and which does not achieve any of its principal intended purposes through chemical action within or on the body of man or other animal, and which does not depend upon being metabolized for the achievement of any of its principal intended purposes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The term “medicinal chemicals” means chemicals used in the treatment of illness or disease.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>The term “over-the-counter drug” means drugs which may be sold without a prescription and which are prepackaged for use by the consumer and labeled in accordance with the requirements of the laws and regulations of the District of Columbia and the federal government.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>The term “person” means any individual, partnership, association, corporation, company, joint stock association, or any organized group of persons whether incorporated or not, or any trustee, receiver, or assignee thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>The term “pharmacist” means any person who is licensed in the District of Columbia to engage in the practice of pharmacy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>The term “pharmacy intern” means any person who is registered in the District of Columbia to engage in the practice of pharmacy under the direct supervision of a pharmacist.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>The term “practice of pharmacy” means the practice defined in § <cite path="§3-1201.02">3-1201.02</cite>(11).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>The term “practitioner” means a person licensed and permitted by such license (other than a pharmacist) to prescribe, to dispense, or to conduct research with respect to, or to administer, drugs within the course of such person’s professional practice or research.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>The term “proprietor of a pharmacy” means a person designated as proprietor in an application for a pharmacy license under § <cite path="§47-2885.08">47-2885.08</cite>. The proprietor may be an individual, a corporation, a partnership, or an unincorporated association, and shall at all times own a controlling interest in the pharmacy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>The term “radiopharmaceuticals” means radioactive drugs and chemicals within the classification of legend drugs as defined under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. § 301 et seq.) or regulations issued by the Mayor pursuant to this part.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-98" type="History">Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-98, § 3, 27 DCR 3528</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 1102(a), 33 DCR 729</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§48-701">48-701</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-2002.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Section 302 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985”, referred to in paragraph (1), is <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-99">D.C. Law 6-99</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
