<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-2352</num>
  <heading>Registration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall implement a program for a uniform system of licensing and payment of fuel taxes by interjurisdictional motor carriers fleets consistent with the IFTA.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Commercial vehicles exhibiting the following characteristics shall declare a jurisdictional base and obtain the apportioned credentials issued under the terms of the IFTA:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Vehicles with 2 axles and GVWR of more than 26,000 pounds;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Vehicles with 3 or more axles regardless of weight; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>When used in combination, the weight of the combination exceeds 26,000 pounds.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any vehicle required or eligible to obtain registration under the IFTA that lists the District as the established place of business must declare the District of Columbia as its jurisdictional base pursuant to the IFTA.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-153" type="History">Sept. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-153, § 2(d), 45 DCR 3853</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 302(e), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Traffic regulation, rules, fees, fines and penalties, original certificate of title, certain motor vehicles and trailers exempt, see § <cite path="§50-2201.03">50-2201.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-2201.03">50-2201.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2352.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> repealed subsec. (b), rewrote subsec. (c), and repealed subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Prior to repeal, subsecs. (b) and (e) read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b) All commercial vehicles with a GVWR of over 10,000 pounds and engaged in the interjurisdictional transport of goods or passengers shall be eligible for uniform licensing and payment of fuel taxes.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(e) Vehicles qualifying for registration for the IFTA under subsection (b) of this section, but not apportioned or covered by reciprocity, and engaged in interjurisdictional movement, shall acquire a trip pass prior to entering the District.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) Vehicles exhibiting the following characteristics shall declare a jurisdictional base and obtain the apportioned credentials issued under the terms of the IFTA:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) Vehicles with two axles and a GVWR of 26,000 pounds or more; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) Vehicles with three or more axles.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
