<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2885.10</num>
  <heading>Denial, suspension, or revocation of pharmacy license.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may refuse the issuance or renewal, or may revoke, or may suspend for not more than 90 days, a license issued pursuant to this part for any 1 or a combination of the following reasons:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Conviction of any felony, or a finding by the Mayor that any provision of this part has been violated, or that any law or regulation of the District of Columbia or of the United States relating to drugs has been violated by any person named in the application for pharmacy licensure;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Furnishing false or misleading information to the Mayor, or failing to furnish information requested by the Mayor, or refusing to allow an inspection in accordance with this section and <cite path="§47-2885.16">§ 47-2885.16</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Selling, or offering for sale, adulterated or misbranded drugs or devices.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall forthwith suspend a license issued pursuant to this part whenever the Mayor finds that the failure of a pharmacy to comply with any provision of this part or with any District of Columbia or federal law or regulation applicable to such pharmacy is of such a serious nature and magnitude that an imminent danger to the health or safety of the public is presented. In such a case, if a hearing is requested, such request or hearing shall not serve to stay the issuance of an order suspending the license.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-98" type="History">Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-98, § 11, 27 DCR 3528</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-255" type="History">May 16, 1995, D.C. Law 10-255, § 5, 41 DCR 5193</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Section 302 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-2010.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
