<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2853.194</num>
  <heading>Fiduciary duties when representing a tenant.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A licensee engaged by a tenant shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Perform in accordance with the terms of the brokerage relationship;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Promote the interests of the tenant by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Seeking a lease at a price and with terms acceptable to the tenant; however, the licensee shall not be obligated to seek other properties for the tenant while the tenant is a party to a lease or a letter of intent to lease exists under which the tenant has not yet taken possession, unless agreed to as part of the brokerage relationship, or unless the lease or the letter of intent to lease so provides;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Presenting in a timely fashion all written offers or counter-offers to and from the tenant, even when the tenant is already a party to a lease or a letter of intent to lease;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Disclosing to the tenant material facts related to the property or concerning the transaction of which the licensee has actual knowledge, provided that nothing in this section shall amend or limit in any way the provisions of § <cite path="§42-1755">42-1755</cite>(f) [repealed]; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Accounting for in a timely manner all money and property received in which the tenant has or may have an interest;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Maintain confidentiality of all personal and financial information received from the client during the brokerage relationship and any other information that the client requests during the brokerage relationship be maintained confidential unless otherwise provided by law or the tenant consents in writing to the release of such information;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Exercise ordinary care; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Comply with all requirements of this section, fair housing statutes and regulations, and all other applicable statutes and regulations which are not in conflict with this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A licensee engaged by a tenant shall treat all prospective landlords honestly and shall not knowingly give them false information. No cause of action shall arise against any licensee for revealing information as required by this section or applicable law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A licensee engaged by a tenant in a real estate transaction may provide assistance to the landlord or prospective landlord by performing ministerial acts. Performing such ministerial acts that are not inconsistent with subsection (a) of this section shall not be construed to violate the licensee’s brokerage relationship with the tenant unless expressly prohibited by the terms of the brokerage relationship, nor shall performing such ministerial acts be construed to form a brokerage relationship with the landlord or prospective landlord.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A licensee engaged by a tenant does not breach any duty or obligation to the tenant by showing properties in which the tenant is interested to other prospective tenants, whether as clients or customers, by representing other tenants looking for the same or other properties to lease, or by representing landlords relative to other properties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Licensees shall disclose brokerage relationships pursuant to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 1002, 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2853.194.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
