<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2853.152</num>
  <heading>Eligibility requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board shall establish, by rule, the education, experience, and examination requirements that individuals must meet or exceed to obtain licensure, certification, or registration as an appraiser trainee, a licensed residential real property appraiser, a certified residential real property appraiser, or a certified general real property appraiser.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The licensure requirements established by the Board shall meet or exceed any applicable federal requirements that are necessary for the federal financial institution’s regulatory agencies to recognize and accept licenses for licensed residential real estate appraisers, certified residential real estate appraisers, and certified general real estate appraisers licensed by the Board. If the federal requirements change and the rules of the Board do not satisfy the minimum federal standards, the federal standards established by the Appraisal Qualifications Board and the Appraisal Standards Board of the Appraisal Foundation when reviewing an application for licensure, certification, or registration shall apply until the Board’s rules satisfy minimum federal standards.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Board shall establish, by rule, the requirements that individuals licensed in jurisdictions other than the District of Columbia as a certified residential real property appraiser or a certified general real property appraiser must satisfy to obtain a temporary license from the Board. The Board’s requirements shall comply with applicable federal law, but the Mayor may require the applicant to pay a license fee to the Department and may place restrictions on the temporary license.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board shall establish rules governing the supervision of appraiser trainees, the definition and enforcement of standards of professional appraiser practice, and the disposition of complaints from any person or from any federal agency or instrumentality regarding improper appraiser conduct.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Board shall establish, by rule, continuing education requirements necessary for renewal or reinstatement of any license, certification, or registration that meet or exceed the continuing education requirements established under the authority of federal law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Board may establish, by rule, practice requirements or standards. The Board may enforce requirements or standards established under federal law.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 1002, 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-130" type="History">June 16, 2006, D.C. Law 16-130, § 2(j), 53 DCR 4718</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, §§ 118, 180, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2853.152.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-130">D.C. Law 16-130</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “registration shall apply until the Board’s rules” for “registration until the Board rules”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(k) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-101">D.C. Law 16-101</cite> amended this section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“§ <cite path="§47-2853.152">47-2853.152</cite>. Eligibility requirements.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Board shall establish by regulation the education, experience, and examination requirements that individuals must meet or exceed as conditions for obtaining licensure, certification, or registration as an appraiser trainee, a licensed residential real property appraiser, a certified residential real property appraiser, or a certified general real property appraiser.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The licensure requirements established by the Board shall comply with this part and shall meet or exceed any applicable federal requirements that are necessary in order that the federal financial institution’s regulatory agencies recognize and accept licenses for licensed residential real estate appraisers, certified residential real estate appraisers, and certified general real estate appraisers issued by the Board. If the federal requirements change and the Board’s regulations do not meet the minimum federal standards, the Board may substitute the federal standards established by the Appraisal Qualifications Board and the Appraisal Standards Board of the Appraisal Foundation when reviewing an application for licensure, certification, or registration until the Board is able to amend its regulations.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The Board shall establish by regulation the requirements that individuals licensed in jurisdictions other than the District of Columbia as a certified residential real property appraiser or a certified general real property appraiser must satisfy prior to obtaining a temporary license from the Board. The Board’s requirements shall comply with applicable federal law, but the Mayor may require the applicant to pay a license fee to the Department and may place restrictions on the validity of the temporary license.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The Board shall establish by regulation provisions for the supervision of appraiser trainees, provisions for defining and enforcing the standards of professional appraiser practice, and provisions for the disposition of complaints from any person or from any federal agency or instrumentality regarding improper appraiser conduct.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The Board shall establish continuing education requirements necessary for renewal or reinstatement of any license, certification, or registration that meet or exceed the continuing education requirements established under the authority of federal law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(f) By regulation, the Board may establish and enforce practice requirements or standards pursuant to District law and may enforce practice requirements or standards established under the authority of federal law.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-101">D.C. Law 16-101</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(k) of Non-Health Related Occupations and Professions Licensure Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-255, January 26, 2006,  53 DCR 763).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
