<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2888.04</num>
  <heading>Denial, suspension, or revocation of veterinary facility license.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may deny issuance or renewal of or suspend or revoke a license issued pursuant to this part for any one of a combination of the following reasons:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Conviction of any person named on an application of any felony or any crime of moral turpitude, as defined in 3-1205.14(a)(4);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A finding, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, that any person named on an application has violated this part or any rules issued pursuant to this part;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A finding by the Mayor that any provision of this part has been violated, or that any law or regulation of the District or of the United States relating to animals or drugs has been violated by any person named in the application for a veterinary facility; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Furnishing false or misleading information to the Mayor, failing to furnish information required by the Mayor, or refusing to allow an inspection in accordance with § <cite path="§47-2888.05">47-2888.05</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall summarily suspend a license issued pursuant to this part whenever the Mayor finds that a veterinary facility’s failure to comply with a provision of this part or with any District or federal law or regulation applicable to the facility is of such a serious nature and magnitude that it presents an imminent danger to the health or safety of a person or animal. The Mayor shall impound any animals remaining at the facility without an owner present and shall care for those animals until they can be restored to their owners or adopted. The licensee shall be responsible for all costs incurred by the impoundment, care, restoration, or adoption of the impounded animals. The Mayor shall provide the licensee with written notice that states the action being taken, the basis of the action, and the right of the licensee to request a hearing within 5 days. The Mayor shall hold a hearing within 5 days of receiving a timely request, and shall issue a written decision, including findings of fact and conclusions of law, within 5 days of the conclusion of the hearing. The Mayor shall provide a copy of the decision to each party by mailing a copy to the licensee and the licensee’s counsel of record. A request for a hearing shall not act to stay the suspension pending the outcome of the hearing.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-96" type="History">March 26, 2014, D.C. Law 20-96, § 302(b), 61 DCR 1184</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
