<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-2818</num>
  <heading>Mattress manufacture, renovation, storage, or sale; “mattress” defined.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Persons engaged in the business of manufacturing or renovating mattresses shall pay a license fee of $476 biennially.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any license issued pursuant to this subsection shall be issued as a Manufacturing endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Owners or managers of establishments where mattresses are stored, sold, or kept for sale shall pay a license fee of $34 biennially.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any license issued pursuant to this subsection shall be issued as a General Sales endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Within the meaning of this section, the term “mattress” shall be deemed to include any quilt, comforter, pad, pillow, cushion, or bag stuffed with hair, down, feathers, wool, cotton, excelsior, jute, or any other soft material and designed for use for sleeping or reclining purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 1, 1902, 32 Stat. 625, ch. 1352, § 7, par. 18</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 1, 1932, 47 Stat. 553, ch. 366</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-82" type="History">Sept. 14, 1976, D.C. Law 1-82, title I, § 104(j), 23 DCR 2461</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 302(c), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(pp)(15), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38" type="History">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 3(hh)(4)(G), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mattresses, manufacture, renovation and sale, see § <cite path="§8-501">8-501</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mayor, Council and other offices, application of certain sections to boards, commissions and committees, see § <cite path="§1-321.02">1-321.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2818.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-2318.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-38">D.C. Law 15-38</cite>, in subsec. (a)(2), substituted “Manufacturing endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” for “Class A Manufacturing endorsement to a master business license under the master”; and in subsec. (b)(2), substituted “General Sales endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” for “Class B General Sales endorsement to a master business license under the master”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(hh)(4)(G) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003,  50 DCR 6896).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
