<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-2855.02</num>
  <heading>Registration required.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who carries on, conducts, or transacts business in the District of Columbia under any trade name shall register that trade name with the Department as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A sole proprietorship or general partnership shall register by setting forth the true and real name or names of each person comprising the sole proprietorship or general partnership, the post office address or addresses of each person, and the name of the general partnership, if applicable.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A foreign or domestic limited partnership shall register by setting forth the limited partnership name as filed with the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A foreign or domestic limited liability company shall register by setting forth the limited liability company name as filed with the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A foreign or domestic for-profit or nonprofit corporation shall register by setting forth the corporate name as filed with the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A domestic or foreign statutory trust shall register by setting forth the statutory trust name as filed by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A domestic or foreign limited cooperative association shall register by setting forth the association name as filed by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A domestic or foreign general cooperative association shall register by setting forth the association name as filed by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>A domestic or foreign limited liability partnership shall register by setting forth the partnership name as filed by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The trade name application shall contain the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the person applying for the trade name;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name of proposed trade name;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Name and address of the governor of the entity; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the registered agent if person is located outside the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The trade name application shall be executed by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The sole proprietor of a sole proprietorship; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The governor of the entity or authorized person on behalf of the governor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The trade name shall be distinguishable on the records of the Mayor from any:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Name of domestic or foreign filing entity as defined by Title 29.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Name that is reserved under § <cite path="§29-103.03">29-103.03</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Name that is registered under § <cite path="§29-103.04">29-103.04</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Another trade name registered under this chapter; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The name of an agency or instrumentality of the United States or District of Columbia or another state or a subdivision thereof.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2005(b), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 4(c), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2855.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title of title II of Law 12-261: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§47-2855.01">47-2855.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
