<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2842</num>
  <heading>Council of the District of Columbia may regulate, modify, or eliminate license requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered, when in its discretion such is deemed advisable, to require a license of other businesses or callings not listed in this chapter or Chapter 30 [repealed] of this title and which, in its judgment, require inspection, supervision, regulation, or any other activity or expenditure by any municipal agencies; and the Council of the District of Columbia is further authorized and empowered to fix the license fee therefor in such amount as, in its judgment, will be not less than the cost to the District of Columbia of such inspection, supervision, regulation, or other activity or expenditure. The Council is further authorized and empowered in its discretion to modify any of the provisions of this chapter or Chapter 30 [repealed] of this title so far as eliminating therefrom any business or calling in this chapter or Chapter 30 [repealed] of this title required to be licensed, and the Council is further authorized and empowered in its discretion to raise or lower the amount of the license fee provided in this chapter or Chapter 30 [repealed] of this title, when in its judgment such increase or decrease is warranted.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The fee for an original or renewal license for motor vehicle driving instructors shall be $78.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Council shall make such regulations, modifications, or eliminations of licensing requirements consistent with the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 1, 1902, 32 Stat. 628, ch. 1352, § 7, par. 45</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 1, 1932, 47 Stat. 562, ch. 366</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-82" type="History">Sept. 14, 1976, D.C. Law 1-82, title I, § 108, 23 DCR 2461</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-97" type="History">Apr. 3, 1982, D.C. Law 4-97, § 7, 29 DCR 765</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-30" type="History">Aug. 17, 1991, D.C. Law 9-30, § 7, 38 DCR 4215</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-255" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-255, § 3(b), 46 DCR 1279</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(pp)(37), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-307" type="History">June 5, 2003, D.C. Law 14-307, § 1702, 49 DCR 11664</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 73(l)(3), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 5003, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Drug Manufacture and Distribution Licensure Act of 1990: See <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-137">D.C. Law 8-137</cite>, codified as §§ <cite path="§8-131">8-131</cite>, <cite path="§8-137">8-137</cite> and <cite path="§33-1001">33-1001</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Chapter 30 of this title, referred to throughout subsection (a) of this section, was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-136">D.C. Law 5-136</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5003 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1702 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1702 of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1702 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite> repealed subsec. (c) which had read as follows: “(c) Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, no licensing fees shall be charged to any child development home as defined in § <cite path="§4-401">4-401</cite>(3).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite>, in subsec. (d), substituted “basic business license system” for “master business licensing scheme”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “$78” for “$50”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-2344.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2842.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mayor, Council and other offices, application of certain sections to boards, commissions and committees, see § <cite path="§1-321.02">1-321.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
