<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-2851.06</num>
  <heading>Public information.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Center shall compile information regarding the regulatory programs associated with each of the licenses obtainable under the basic business license system.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This information shall include a listing of  all laws and administrative rules that require the issuance of licenses.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Center shall provide the information required by this section to any person requesting it.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Materials used by the Center to describe the services provided by the Center shall indicate that this information is available upon request.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of District law, information submitted to the Center under this subchapter shall not be made available to the public; provided, that a person may be furnished with such information for one registrant based upon the submission of either the name or address of the registrant; provided further, that the person shall be limited to one request per day.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Federal Employer Identification numbers and social security numbers shall not be released to the public, except if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Requested by a law enforcement agency; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Directed by a court order.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-86">Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-86, § 101(b), 45 DCR 1172</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2002(b), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 2(h), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-534">2-534</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-2851.6.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-38">D.C. Law 15-38</cite>, in subsec. (a)(1), substituted “basic” for “master”; and added subsecs. (c) and (d).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Master Business Registration Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-302">D.C. Law 14-302</cite>, May 3, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 3776).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Master Business Registration Delay Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-595, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 647).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Master Business Registration Delay Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-73, April 16, 2003,  50 DCR 3616).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Master Business Registration Second Delay Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-83, May 19, 2003,  50 DCR 4100).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(h) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003,  50 DCR 6896).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
