<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-2909</num>
  <heading>Transmission of price list to Assessor.</heading>
  <text>On or before the first day of November in each year the proprietor or proprietors, keeper or keepers, of each licensed restaurant, eating house, barroom, sample room, ice cream saloon, and soda fountain room or establishment in said District, as aforesaid, shall transmit to the Assessor of said District a printed copy of the usual or common price or prices of articles or things kept for sale by him, her, or them, as aforesaid, which shall be filed by the Assessor in his office, and unless he is notified of changes therein, the copy transmitted and filed in said office may be used in any case or proceeding under §§ <cite path="§47-2909">47-2909</cite> to 47-2911 as prima facie evidence of the common or usual prices charged for the articles or things mentioned therein by the proprietor or proprietors, keeper or keepers, of any of the places or establishments aforesaid, and in a failure of any proprietor or proprietors, keeper or keepers, to transmit the copy aforesaid, the Assessor shall notify such person of such failure, and require such copy to be forthwith transmitted to him.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>3 Leg. Assem., June 26, 1873, ch. 46, § 2</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-2911">47-2911</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-2909.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 47-2909.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Office of Assessor abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§47-413">47-413</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
