<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2835</num>
  <heading>Solicitors.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Solicitors shall pay a license fee of $316 biennially. Any person who goes from house to house, or place to place, within the District of Columbia, selling or taking orders for or offering to sell or take orders for goods, wares, merchandise, or any article or thing of value for future delivery, or for services to be performed in the future or for the making, manufacturing, or repairing of any article or thing whatsoever for future delivery, and requiring or accepting a deposit for such future delivery or service, shall be deemed to be a “solicitor,” within the meaning of this section; provided, however, that this definition shall not apply to persons selling goods, wares, merchandise, or any article or thing of value for resale to retailers in that commodity. Any person desiring a solicitor’s license shall make application to the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designated agent on forms to be provided for that purpose, stating the name of the applicant, the name and address of the person whom he represents, the class and kind of goods offered for sale, or the kind of service to be performed. Such application shall be accompanied by a bond in the penal sum of $500, running to the District of Columbia, conditioned upon the making of final delivery of the goods ordered, or services to be performed, in accordance with the terms of such order, or failing therein, that the advance payment on such order be refunded. Any person aggrieved by the action of any such solicitor shall have the right of action on the bond for the recovery of money, or damages, or both. All orders taken by licensed solicitors shall be in writing in duplicate, stating the terms thereof and the amount paid in advance, and 1 copy shall be given to the purchaser.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as a General Services and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 1, 1902, 32 Stat. 627, ch. 1352, § 7, par. 37</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 1, 1932, 47 Stat. 557, ch. 366</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-82" type="History">Sept. 14, 1976, D.C. Law 1-82, title I, § 104(v), 23 DCR 2461</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 302(g), 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(pp)(31), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38" type="History">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 3(hh)(4)(T), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Mayor, Council and other offices, application of certain sections to boards, commissions and committees, see § 1-32</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2835.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-2337.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-38">D.C. Law 15-38</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “General Services and Repair endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” for “Class B General Services and Repair endorsement to a master business license under the master”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(hh)(4)(T) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003,  50 DCR 6896).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
