<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-2405</num>
  <heading>Transportation of cigarettes and other tobacco products.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person, other than a consumer, who transports cigarettes not bearing District cigarette tax stamps or other tobacco products over the public highways, roads, streets, waterways, or other public space of the District, shall have in his actual possession invoices or delivery tickets for such cigarettes or other tobacco products, which show the true name and address of the consignor or seller, the true name and address of the consignee or purchaser, and the quantity and brands of the cigarettes or other tobacco products so transported.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the cigarettes or other tobacco products are consigned to or purchased by any person in the District, such purchaser or consignee must be a person authorized by this chapter to possess unstamped cigarettes or untaxed other tobacco products in the District. If the invoice or delivery ticket specifies that the cigarettes or other tobacco products are to be delivered to any person in any state or jurisdiction other than the District, such person must be licensed under the laws of such other state or jurisdiction to engage in the business of selling cigarettes or other tobacco products within that state or jurisdiction. Any cigarettes or other tobacco products transported in violation of any of the provisions of this section shall be deemed contraband cigarettes and other tobacco products and such cigarettes or other tobacco products, the conveyance in which such cigarettes or other tobacco products are being transported, and any equipment or devices used in connection with, or to facilitate, the transportation of such cigarettes or other tobacco products shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture as provided for in § <cite path="§47-2409">47-2409</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any person who transports cigarettes in violation of this section shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not more than $25 for each 200 contraband cigarettes or fraction thereof so transported by him, or by imprisonment for not more than 3 years, or both, and in addition, shall be liable for the tax imposed by § <cite path="§47-2402">47-2402</cite> and the interest and penalties imposed by §§ <cite path="§47-4201.01">47-4201.01</cite> [§ <cite path="§47-4201">47-4201</cite>] and subchapter II of Chapter 42 of this title.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>May 27, 1949, 63 Stat. 138, ch. 146, title VI, § 606</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-82">Sept. 14, 1976, D.C. Law 1-82, title I, § 105, 23 DCR 2461</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-71">Mar. 10, 1982, D.C. Law 4-71, § 2, 28 DCR 5243</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 406(qq), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7012(e)(7), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1803.06">7-1803.06</cite>, § <cite path="§47-2403">47-2403</cite>, § <cite path="§47-2409">47-2409</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-2422">47-2422</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-2405.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 47-2805.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “§§ <cite path="§47-4201.01">47-4201.01</cite> and subchapter II of Chapter 42 of this title” for “§ <cite path="§47-2411.01">47-2411.01</cite>”.</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7022(e)(7) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7022(e)(7) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7012(e)(7) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7012(e)(7) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Office of Collector of Taxes abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§47-401">47-401</cite>.</text>
      <text>Section 410(d) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> provided: “Section 406(a), (c), (j), (m), (p), (q), (s), (w), (bb), (dd), (ee), (hh) through (kk), (mm) through (oo), (qq) through (uu), (yy), (zz), (bbb), (ddd), and (fff) shall apply for all tax years or taxable periods beginning after December 31, 2000.”</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
