<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2885.06</num>
  <heading>Registration of pharmacy interns.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To register as a pharmacy intern, a person shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board of Pharmacy that the applicant:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is currently registered in and attending a duly accredited college or school of pharmacy or is a graduate of such college or school of pharmacy; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has provided such additional evidence as the Board has determined is necessary for the position of pharmacy intern; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has complied with the other standards required for registration by the Non-Health Related Professions and Occupations Licensure Act of 1998.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may, by regulation, provide for the registration of pharmacy interns who obtain their practical experience outside of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Registration as a pharmacy intern may be renewed for successive periods of 1 year if the Mayor is satisfied that the applicant is in good faith and with reasonable diligence working toward his or her pharmaceutical degree or, if he or she has already received his or her degree, has been unable with reasonable diligence to accumulate the number of hours of service required by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-98" type="History">Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-98, § 7, 27 DCR 3528</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 1244, 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000, D.C. Law 13-91, § 157(c), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-2006.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite> validated a previously made technical amendment.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Section 302 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“The Non-Health Related Professions and Occupations Licensure Act of 1998,” referenced in (a)(3), is title I of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-261">D.C. Law 12-261</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
