<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-351.13</num>
  <heading>Protection of District funds at risk.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), may take the action provided for in subsection (b) of this section to protect District funds if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A financial institution fails to return a deposit upon demand or upon the termination of or pursuant to the terms of an agreement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A financial institution fails to pay a valid check, draft, or warrant issued by the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A financial institution fails to honor a request for the electronic transfer of District funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A financial institution fails to account for a check, draft, warrant, order, deposit, certificate, or money that the District entrusts to it;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A financial institution fails to return an investment under the terms of an agreement or upon the termination of an agreement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A financial institution fails to perform under the terms of an agreement involving banking business;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A financial institution fails to maintain the required collateral pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.08">47-351.08</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>A court or a federal, District, or state banking regulator orders a financial institution to refrain from making payments on its liabilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>A court or a federal, District, or state banking regulator appoints a conservator or receiver for the financial institution;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), determines that the financial institution is financially unsound;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>A financial institution fails to comply with this subchapter; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Any other action has occurred or is impending which the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), decides would place District funds in jeopardy.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), determines that any condition under subsection (a) of this section exists, the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), may, without any further action:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Withdraw or demand the return of District funds immediately;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Take action to seize all collateral provided under section 9;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Liquidate collateral and retain proceeds in the amount equal to District funds held by the financial institution plus liquidation costs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Direct the financial institution to immediately stop performing any financial services for the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Terminate any agreement relating to banking business;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Remove the financial institution from the eligible bidder’s list; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Take other action deemed necessary for the protection of District funds.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-56" type="History">Mar. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-56, § 2(c), 44 DCR 6933</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-351.04">47-351.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-351.13.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§47-351.01">47-351.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
