<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-355.07</num>
  <heading>Board of Review for Anti-Deficiency Violations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Review for Anti-Deficiency Violations (“Review Board”) is established as an independent agency within the District of Columbia government, consistent with the meaning of the term independent agency, as provided in [<cite path="§1-603.01|(13)">§ 1-603.01(13)</cite>].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Review Board shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Advise and make recommendations to the Mayor, Council, Chief Financial Officer, and Inspector General on issues relative to anti-deficiency law violations in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Convene within 30 days of learning of an alleged violation of <cite path="§47-355.02">§ 47-355.02</cite> to determine whether a violation occurred.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Review Board shall be comprised of 5 members of the District of Columbia government appointed as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Two representatives who serve at the pleasure of the Chief Financial Officer, one of whom shall be appointed by the Chief Financial Officer to serve as Chairperson of the Review Board;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>One representative who serves at the pleasure of the Mayor;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>One representative of the Council, who shall be an employee of the Council and shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Council; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>One representative who serves at the pleasure of the Inspector General.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Members shall be appointed to a term of 3 years. Each member may serve beyond the end of their term until reappointed or replaced by the appropriate appointing authority.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Members shall serve without compensation; provided, that a member may be reimbursed for expenses incurred in the authorized execution of official duties of the Review Board if those expenses are approved in advance by the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the Review Board determines that a violation of <cite path="§47-355.02">§ 47-355.02</cite> has occurred, it shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assess the responsibility of culpable employees;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, recommend an appropriate disciplinary action; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Present a report to the Council within 30 days of the determination of a violation that includes all relevant facts, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The violation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The name and title of the employees who were responsible for the violation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any justification; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A statement of the action taken or proposed to be taken.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A finding by the Review Board that a violation of <cite path="§47-355.02">§ 47-355.02</cite> has occurred shall not be a prerequisite for adverse personnel action under <cite path="§47-355.06">§ 47-355.06</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In recommending appropriate disciplinary action under subsection (d) of this section, the Review Board may make a recommendation that no action be taken where it finds justification for the violation. Justification may include overspending as a result of court orders, entitlements, or explicit authorization in an appropriations act.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Review Board is authorized to establish subcommittees as needed. A subcommittee may include District government employees who are not members of the Review Board; provided, that each subcommittee is chaired by a member of the Review Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Review Board may establish its own bylaws and rules of procedure, subject to the approval of the Chief Financial Officer or his or her designee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall provide administrative and staff support to the Review Board.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-285" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-285, § 2, 50 DCR 940</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, §§ 12(b), 77(d), 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-293" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-293, § 2(f), 54 DCR 1083</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-271" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-271, § 231, 62 DCR 1884</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Establishment—Board of Review for Anti-Deficiency Violations, see Mayor’s Order 2003-156, November 7, 2003 ( 50 DCR 10187).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Mayor’s Rulemaking Authority to the Board of Review for Anti-Deficiency Violations, see Mayor’s Order 2004-125, August 2, 2004 ( 51 DCR 8006).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-307, Feb. 18, 2016,  63 DCR 2182).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of section, see § 5 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Second Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-202, Nov. 23, 2015,  62 DCR 15276).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 231 of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-7, Feb. 26, 2015,  62 DCR 2646, 21 STAT 807).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 231 of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-481, Nov. 18, 2014,  61 DCR 12133, 20 STAT 4405).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 12 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-76">D.C. Law 21-76</cite>, Feb. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 264).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-271">D.C. Law 20-271</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) The review board may recommend that no action be taken where it finds a justification for the violation. Justification may include overspending as a result of court orders, entitlements, or explicit authorization in an appropriations act.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) Within 30 days of April 4, 2003, the Mayor and Chief Financial Officer shall establish a review board, which shall within 30 days of learning of a violation specified in <cite path="§47-355.06">§ 47-355.06</cite> by an agency convene a review board to investigate the causes of the violation. The review board shall assess the culpability of responsible employees, recommend an appropriate disciplinary action, and report to the Council the actions proposed to be taken based on the review board’s findings.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-293">D.C. Law 16-293</cite>, rewrote subsecs. (a) and (c), which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “<cite path="§47-355.06">§ 47-355.06</cite>” for “subsection (a) of this section”; and, in subsec. (c), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
