<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-351.11</num>
  <heading>District funds reserved for certain insured institutions.</heading>
  <text>Without regard to the competitive bidding requirements of §§ <cite path="§47-351.05">47-351.05</cite> and <cite path="§47-351.07">47-351.07</cite>, the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), may reserve up to 10% of District funds available for deposit or investment in order to make an investment or a deposit with one or more insured financial institutions located in the District that have less than $550 million in assets. The amount available for deposit or investment is to be calculated based upon the prior year’s average investment balance. In selecting an insured financial institution under this section, the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), shall follow the provisions of § <cite path="§47-351.04">47-351.04</cite> and shall encourage the use of women-owned banks and federally or District chartered minority-owned banks certified by the Small and Local Business Opportunity Commission in accordance with [subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2]. The amount of District funds deposited in any such institution shall not exceed the federally insured amount, unless the amount of District funds deposited that exceed the federally insured amount meet the collateral requirements set forth in § <cite path="§47-351.08">47-351.08</cite> and the permitted investment instrument provisions set forth in § <cite path="§47-351.03">47-351.03</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-56" type="History">Mar. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-56, § 2(c), 44 DCR 6933</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-169" type="History">October 4, 2000, D.C. Law 13-169, § 8, 47 DCR 5846</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2381(c), 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-124" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-124, § 2, 55 DCR 1516</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-351.05">47-351.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-351.11.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-169">D.C. Law 13-169</cite> authorized striking the phrase “Minority Business Opportunity Commission in accordance with § <cite path="§1-1141">1-1141</cite> et seq.” and inserting the phrase “Local Business Opportunity Commission in accordance with subchapter II-B of Chapter 2 of Title 2.” in its place.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite> substituted “Small and Local Business Opportunity Commission in accordance with subchapter IX-A if Chapter 2 of Title 2 ” for “District of Columbia Local Business Opportunity Commission in accordance with subchapter IX of Chapter 2 of Title 2”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-124">D.C. Law 17-124</cite> substituted “10%” for “1%”; substituted “550” for “350”; and inserted “, unless the amount of District funds deposited that exceed the federally insured amount meet the collateral requirements set forth in § <cite path="§47-351.08">47-351.08</cite> and the permitted investment instrument provisions set forth in § <cite path="§47-351.03">47-351.03</cite>”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2381(c) of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
