<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-355.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Agency” means an agency, office, department, board, commission, or independent agency or instrumentality of the District Government.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Apportionment” means the division of an agency’s appropriated budget authority by periods within a fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2A)</num>
    <text>“Emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property” does not include ongoing, regular functions of government the suspension of which would not imminently threaten the safety of human life or the protection of property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Employee” means an individual who performs a function of the District Government and who receives compensation for the performance of that function.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Manager” means an individual chosen or appointed to manage, direct, or administer some affairs of the agency, including the expenditure of funds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Program” means the highest level, for budgeting and expenditure control, within the agency that the District of Columbia Government uses for a specific purpose for appropriated budget authority. A program may consist of multiple activities, which combined achieve the stated purpose and goals.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-285">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-285, § 2, 50 DCR 940</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 77(a), 51 DCR 881</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 1102(a), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in the introductory paragraph, validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added (2A).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1102(a) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1102(a) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Mayor's Orders</heading>
      <text>Allocation of Spending (FY 2011), see Mayor’s Order 2010-160, October 8, 2010 ( 57 DCR 9559).</text>
      <text>Rescission of Quarterly Apportionment Provisions and Non-Personal Services Restrictions for Subordinate Executive Branch Agencies Imposed Under Mayor’s Order 2010-160, see Mayor’s Order 2011-35, January 19, 2011 ( 58 DCR 869).</text>
      <text>NPS Restrictions for Subordinate Executive Branch Agencies, see Mayor’s Order 2011-102, May 18, 2011 ( 58 DCR 4678).</text>
      <text>Allocation of Spending (FY 2012), see Mayor’s Order 2011-188, December 1, 2011 ( 58 DCR 10385).</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
