<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-351.04</num>
  <heading>Eligibility requirements; bidding; awards process.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To become eligible to submit a bid under this subsection:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An insured institution shall provide the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), with information from which the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), can calculate a community development score under § <cite path="§47-351.07">47-351.07</cite>. This information may include, but need not be limited to, current community development data, Community Reinvestment Act statement and evaluation with a minimum of “satisfactory” rating on its latest Community Reinvestment Act examination, and Home Mortgage Disclosure Act reports.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A noninsured institution shall submit to the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), a statement of Equal Employment Opportunity or Affirmative Action.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each year the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), shall compile a list of eligible financial institutions that submit the information pursuant to the requirements of subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), shall send the solicitations for bids to all financial institutions that are eligible. The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), shall remove from the eligible list those financial institutions that the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), has deemed to be financially unsound and those bidders that have put District funds at risk pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.13">47-351.13</cite>(a).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In solicitations for bids, the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), shall include the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the case of deposits or investments:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The term of the deposit or investments;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The approximate amount available for deposit or investment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The evaluation criteria; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>All other information required by the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), or that is necessary for compliance with this subchapter.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In the case of financial services:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A list of the financial services needed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The evaluation criteria; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>All other information required by the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), or that is necessary for compliance with this subchapter.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), may solicit bids for either single financial services or groups of financial services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If applicable, a bidder shall provide the following information in a bid:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The identity of the bidder;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The minimum and maximum amount of District funds the bidder will accept;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The rate of return;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The type of financial services to be provided and the cost to the District for the financial services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The amount of the compensating balances, if any, and the rate of return on any deposit used for a compensating balance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A description of the experience and capacity of the financial institution to perform the banking business for which the bid is submitted;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Information necessary to assess risk and liquidity; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Any other information required by the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), shall make available to each bidder the notice of the bid award including the terms of the bid award.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Two or more eligible financial institutions may submit a joint bid.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), may at any time prior to the notice of award withdraw a bid solicitation for good cause. The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), shall notify any financial institution that has submitted a bid prior to the withdrawal of the bid solicitation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § <cite path="§47-351.02">47-351.02</cite>(c), may retain or maintain deposits, investments, or financial services agreements at a financial institution which is a successor to the contractual agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-56" type="History">Mar. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-56, § 2(c), 44 DCR 6933</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 52(b), 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-351.01">47-351.01</cite>, § <cite path="§47-351.10">47-351.10</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-351.11">47-351.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-351.4.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§47-351.01">47-351.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
