<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-3908</num>
  <heading>Authority of Mayor to determine tax; deficiencies in tax.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall have the authority to determine, redetermine, assess, or reassess any tax due under this chapter. Assessments of any deficiencies in the tax due under this chapter, or any interest and penalties thereon, shall be governed by § <cite root="47-4312">47-4312</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any assessment of tax, penalties, and interest that has become final pursuant to § <cite root="47-4312">47-4312</cite> shall be due and payable within 10 days after service of a final assessment by the Mayor or service of a final order by the Office of Administrative Hearings, as applicable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § <cite root="47-4312">47-4312</cite>, any person aggrieved by an assessment of a deficiency in tax under the provisions of this section may appeal to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the same manner and to the same extent as set forth in §§ <cite root="47-3303">47-3303</cite>, <cite root="47-3304">47-3304</cite>, and <cite root="47-3308">47-3308</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-26">Sept. 20, 1989, D.C. Law 8-26, § 9, 36 DCR 4723</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-217">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-217, § 4(i), 51 DCR 9126</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-3908.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-217">D.C. Law 15-217</cite> rewrote subsecs. (a) and (b); and, in subsec. (c), substituted “Except as provided in § <cite root="47-4312">47-4312</cite>, any person aggrieved by an assessment of a deficiency in tax” for “Any person aggrieved by an assessment of a deficiency in tax finally determined by the Mayor”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(i) of Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-513, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8976).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(i) of Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-553, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 10359).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
