<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-3708</num>
  <heading>Amended returns.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the personal representative files an amended federal estate tax return, he or she shall, within 30 days after filing the amended federal estate tax return, file with the Mayor an amended return covering the tax imposed by this chapter, accompanying the amended return with a copy of the amended federal estate tax return. If the personal representative is required to pay an additional tax under this chapter pursuant to the amended return, he or she shall pay the tax, together with interest in accordance with § <cite path="§47-4201.01">47-4201.01</cite> at the time of filing the amended return.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If, upon final determination of the federal estate tax due, a deficiency is assessed, the personal representative shall within 30 days after this determination give written notice of the deficiency to the Mayor. If any additional tax is due under this chapter by reason of this determination, the personal representative shall pay the additional tax, together with interest in accordance with § <cite path="§47-4201.01">47-4201.01</cite> at the time of filing the notice.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-168" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-168, § 9, 33 DCR 7008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-209" type="History">Feb. 28, 1987, D.C. Law 6-209, § 402(c), 34 DCR 689</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 406(yy), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-3708.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “§ <cite path="§47-4201.01">47-4201.01</cite>” for “§§ <cite path="§47-453">47-453</cite> through <cite path="§47-458">47-458</cite>”; and, in subsec. (b), substituted “§ <cite path="§47-4201.01">47-4201.01</cite> at the time of filing the notice” for “§§ <cite path="§47-453">47-453</cite> through <cite path="§47-458">47-458</cite>” at the time he or she files the notice”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 601(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-209">D.C. Law 6-209</cite> provided that title III and sections 401, 402, 404, 405 and 406 of the act shall take effect on October 1, 1987.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 410(d) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> provided: “Section 406(a), (c), (j), (m), (p), (q), (s), (w), (bb), (dd), (ee), (hh) through (kk), (mm) through (oo), (qq) through (uu), (yy), (zz), (bbb), (ddd), and (fff) shall apply for all tax years or taxable periods beginning after December 31, 2000.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
