<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-363</num>
  <heading>Council approval of reprogrammings.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit to the Council for approval a reprogramming request that individually or on a cumulative basis would result in a change to the original appropriated authority, along with certification by the Chief Financial Officer of the availability of funds for the reprogramming. The request shall include an analysis of its effect on the budget and on the purposes for which the funds were originally appropriated.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of a reprogramming request, the Chairman of the Council shall cause a notice of the request to be published in the District of Columbia Register, together with a statement that the request shall be deemed approved 14 days from the date of its receipt, unless a proposed disapproval resolution is filed prior to that time by a Councilmember, and that if a proposed disapproval resolution is filed, the request shall be deemed approved 30 days from the date of the receipt of the reprogramming request, unless prior to the end of the 30-day review period the Council adopts a resolution of disapproval or approval.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The publication of a notice of a reprogramming request shall satisfy the public notice requirements of this section and the rules of the Council and no further notice shall be necessary for the Council to adopt a resolution affecting the request.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Council shall consider the request according to its rules. No request may be submitted to the Chairman of the Council under this subsection during such time as the Council is on recess, according to its rules, nor shall any time period provided in this subsection or in the Council’s rules with respect to the requests continue to run during such time as the Council is on recess.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If no proposed disapproval resolution of a reprogramming request is filed with the Secretary to the Council (“Secretary”) within 14 days of the receipt of the request from the Mayor, the request shall be deemed approved.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a proposed disapproval resolution is filed with the Secretary within 14 days of receipt of the request from the Mayor, the Council may approve or disapprove the reprogramming request by resolution within 30 days of the receipt of the request from the Mayor. If the Council neither affirmatively approves or disapproves the request within 30 days of the receipt of the request, the request shall be deemed approved.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>At any time prior to final action by the Council on a reprogramming request, or prior to the date the reprogramming request is deemed approved pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, the Mayor may withdraw the reprogramming request.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An operating budget reprogramming request shall include for each budget category from or to which funds are being transferred a list of the funding reductions or additions by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Agency;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Activity;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Object class; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Funding sources.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A capital reprogramming request shall include for each project or subproject from or to which funds are being transferred a list of the funding reductions or additions by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Agency;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Project and subproject; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Funding sources.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-100" type="History">Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-100, § 4, 27 DCR 3617</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-106" type="History">Apr. 30, 1982, D.C. Law 4-106, § 2, 29 DCR 1407</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-70" type="History">Apr. 3, 1984, D.C. Law 5-70, § 2(b), 31 DCR 628</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104" type="History">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 34, 35 DCR 147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-110" type="History">Apr. 18, 1996, D.C. Law 11-110, § 52, 43 DCR 530</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254,§ 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 754, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11245(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 52(e), 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 102(b), 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 108-7" type="History">Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 129, Pub. L. 108-7, Div. C, title III, § 136</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39,§ 102, 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 78, 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct, 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 1132, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-192" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-192, § 1002, 53 DCR 6899</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 209, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 1131(c), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 122(c), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-363.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-105">D.C. Law 14-105</cite>, in subsec. (a-1)(2), purported to substitute “section, § <cite path="§47-363.01">47-363.01</cite>, and” for “section and” and added a new § <cite path="§47-363.01">47-363.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite> added subsec. (i).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Section 136 of Public Law 108-7, in subsec. (a-1), added par. (3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite>, in subsec. (h), substituted “the thresholds established pursuant to section 109 of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2003, approved February 20, 2003 (Pub. L. 108-7; 117 Stat. 11)” for “$50,000 at the control center level”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in subsec. (i)(1), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted, “$860,000” for “$25,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “$1 million” for “$860,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite>, in subsec. (e)(1), deleted “and requests pursuant to § <cite path="§47-364">47-364</cite>(a)” following “section”; and, in subsec. (h), deleted “and the D.C. General Hospital Commission” preceding “for estimated”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “any responsibility center, or, in a performance-based agency, of any program or activity of $500,000 or more” for “any responsibility center of more than $400,000”; and rewrote subsec. (c), which had read as follows: “(c) The Mayor shall submit to the Council for approval any reprogramming request(s) which individually or considered on a cumulative basis would result in a movement of funds from 1 capital project to another of more than $1 million in any fiscal year.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> rewrote the section, which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) The Mayor shall submit to the Council for approval any reprogramming request(s) which individually or on a cumulative basis would result in a change to the original appropriated or estimated non-appropriated authority of any responsibility center, or, in a performance-based agency, of any program or activity of $500,000 or more or 10% (whichever is less) of the original appropriated or estimated non-appropriated authority in any fiscal year; provided, however, that Council approval shall not be required for any reprogramming of up to $25,000. Council approval is required for any subsequent reprogrammings which individually or considered on a cumulative basis would result in additional changes of more than $100,000 or 10% (whichever is less) of the original appropriated or estimated non-appropriated authority of any responsibility center.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a-1)(1) The Mayor shall also submit reprogramming requests to the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as required by § <cite path="§47-392.03">47-392.03</cite>(c)(1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) The Council may only approve a reprogramming submitted by the Mayor to the Council pursuant to the provisions of this section and § <cite path="§47-392.03">47-392.03</cite>(c)(2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3)(A) After the adoption of the annual budget for a fiscal year that is not a control year, no reprogramming of amounts in the budget may occur unless;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(i) The Mayor submits a request for such reprogramming to the Council and the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(ii) The Chief Financial Officer transmits to the Council a statement certifying the availability of funds for the reprogramming and containing an analysis of the effect of the reprogramming on the financial plan and budget for the fiscal year; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(iii) The Council approves the request after receiving the statement described in sub-sub-paragraph (ii) of this paragraph, but only if any additional expenditures provided under the request are offset by reductions in expenditures for another activity.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(B) If the Chief Financial Officer does not transmit to the Council the statement described in subparagraph (A)(ii) of this paragraph during the 15-day period which begins on the date the Chief Financial Officer receives the request for the reprogramming from the Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer shall be deemed to have transmitted the statement to the Council. Upon written notice to the Mayor and Council, the Chief Financial Officer may extend the time period to transmit the statement and analysis to the Council, not to exceed 10 additional days.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(C) In this paragraph, the term ‘control year’ has the meaning given such term in § <cite path="§47-393">47-393</cite>(4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b) The Mayor shall submit to the Council for approval any shift(s) in funding among object categories within the same responsibility center which individually exceed $50,000 in any fiscal year. Council approval is required for any subsequent actions which individually would move funds in excess of $50,000 among object categories within the same responsibility center in any fiscal year.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) The Mayor shall submit to the Council for approval a reprogramming request when an agency proposes to:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) Transfer funds of $500,000 or more in any fiscal year from one capital project or sub-project to another capital project or sub-project;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) Transfer funds of $500,000 or more in any fiscal year from one agency to another agency;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) Establish a new capital project or sub-project; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(4) Change the capital project or sub-project description to alter the:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(A) Scope;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(B) Purpose; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(C) Location.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(d) Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (a) through (c) of this section, the Mayor shall submit to the Council for approval any reprogramming request(s) which individually or considered on a cumulative basis would result in change to the original appropriated or estimated non-appropriated authority of any responsibility or control centers within the Department of Human Services, by more than $50,000 in any fiscal year. Additional Council approval shall be required for additional reprogrammings which individually or considered on a cumulative basis would result in additional changes of more than $50,000 to the original appropriated or estimated non-appropriated authority of any responsibility centers within the Department of Human Services.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(e)(1) The Mayor shall transmit reprogramming requests as provided in subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d) of this section to the Chairman of the Council, who shall immediately circulate the requests to the members of the Council.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) The Council shall consider the request(s) according to its rules. Should no written notice of disapproval of such request(s) be filed with the Secretary to the Council within 14 calendar days of the receipt of a request from the Mayor, or no oral notice of disapproval is given during a meeting of the Council during such 14 calendar day period, the request shall be deemed to be approved. Should notice of disapproval be given during such initial 14-calendar day period, the Council may approve or disapprove the reprogramming request by resolution within 30 calendar days of the initial receipt of the request from the Mayor, or such request shall be deemed to be approved.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) No request may be submitted to the Chairman of the Council under this subsection during such time as the Council is on recess, according to its rules, nor shall any time period provided in this subsection or in the Council’s rules with respect to the requests continue to run during such time as the Council is on recess.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(4)(A) Upon receipt of a reprogramming request submitted pursuant to this subchapter, the Chairman of the Council shall cause a ‘notice of a reprogramming request’ to be published in the District of Columbia Register, together with a statement that the request will be deemed approved 14 days from the date of its receipt unless a ‘notice of disapproval’ has been filed prior to that time by any member of the Council, and if such ‘notice of disapproval’ has been filed, that the request will be deemed approved 30 days from the date of the receipt of the reprogramming request unless prior to that time the Council has adopted a resolution of disapproval or approval.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(B) The publication of the ‘notice of a reprogramming request’ pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall satisfy the public notice requirements of this section and the rules of the Council and no further notice shall be necessary for the Council to adopt a resolution affecting the reprogramming request.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(5) At any time prior to final action by the Council on a reprogramming request submitted pursuant to this subchapter, or prior to a reprogramming becoming effective without Council action as provided in this subchapter, the Mayor may withdraw the reprogramming request.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(e-1) Reprogrammings transmitted to the Council pursuant to subsections (a), (b), (c), and (e) of this section shall include a specific listing of responsibility centers and control centers, or both, from which funds are being reduced and a specific listing of responsibility centers and control centers, or both, to which funds are being added. Each separate reprogramming request shall be for the total net sum of zero dollars.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(f) If the Council disapproves a reprogramming request the Mayor may, on a clear showing of changed circumstances, new information, or additional administrative hardship, ask for a reconsideration of the previous action of the Council. The Council may at its discretion reconsider its previous action.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(g) All reprogrammings which occur, regardless of amount, shall be reported by the Mayor to the Council on a monthly basis. A monthly reprogramming summary shall set forth clearly and concisely each reprogramming activity by original object category and new object category. It shall specify the amount of funds shifted and other consequences where appropriate (such as personnel shifts, equipment transfers, etc.). The monthly reprogramming summary shall also include a brief explanation of the administrative necessity that was served by the reprogramming activity. The Mayor shall be responsible for assembling and transmitting the monthly reprogramming summary. The Council committee staff responsible for the budget process shall receive and analyze the monthly reprogramming summary.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(h) The District of Columbia Board of Education, and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall be excluded for appropriated authority and the District of Columbia Board of Education, the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia for estimated nonappropriated authority shall be excluded from the provisions of this section; provided, that reprogramming requests in excess of the thresholds established pursuant to section 109 of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2003, approved February 20, 2003 (Pub. L. 108-7; 117 Stat. 122 ), shall be submitted to the Mayor and the Council for review and comment prior to their transmittal to the Congress.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(i)(1) Notwithstanding any other provision in this section, a reprogramming request made as part of performance-based budgeting shall be approved by the Mayor and Council pursuant to § <cite path="§47-308.01">47-308.01</cite> and this subsection.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) A reprogramming for performance-based budgeting shall be made at the program level; provided, that the Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall submit to the Council for approval any performance-based budgeting reprogramming request that moves funds between programs in excess of $840,000 in any fiscal year.”</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Chief Financial Officer Establishment Reprogramming During Non-Control Years Technical Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-67">D.C. Law 14-67</cite>, February 27, 2001, law notification  49 DCR 2277).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For purported temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Chief Financial Officer Establishment Reprogramming During Non-Control Years Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-161, November 2, 2001,  48 DCR 10399).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For purported temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Chief Financial Officer Establishment Reprogramming During Non-control Years Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-243, January 28, 2002,  49 DCR 1032).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 102(b) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 102 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 102 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Council Review Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-514, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8981).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1132 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1002 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-477, August 8, 2006,  53 DCR 7068).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1002 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-499, October 23, 2006,  53 DCR 8845).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1002 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-1, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1165).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1002(c) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-187, August 26, 2009,  56 DCR 7374).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1131(c) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1131(c) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 122(c) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of title I of Law 15-39: Section 101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite> provided that title I of the act may be cited as the Reprogramming Policy Amendment Act of 2003.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle R of title I of Law 16-33: Section 1131 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite> provided that subtitle R of title I of the act may be cited as the Reprogramming Act of 2005.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</cite> provided that subtitle A of title I of the act may be cited as the Reprogramming Policy Act of 2006.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-105">D.C. Law 14-105</cite> amended D.C. Act 14-89, section 17 of which states the following:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">“Sec. 17. Effective date. This act shall take effect on the later of:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">“(1) completion of a 30-day period of Congressional review, as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Official Code § 47-392.03(a)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">“(2) enactment by Congress of a repeal of section 424 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act and a repeal of the provisions in sections 448 and 449 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act which conflict with section 6 of the Independence of the Chief Financial Officer Establishment Act of 2001, passed on 2nd reading on July 10, 2001 (Enrolled version of Bill 14-354).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">As of the printing of this supplement, Act 14-89 has not become law. Therefore, the amendments made to Act 14-89 by Law 14-105 have not been given effect.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 47-364(a), which is referred to in (e)(1), was repealed by 109 Stat. 142, Pub. L. 104-8, § 301(b)(2), approved April 17,</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Resolutions">Resolution 14-99, the “Reprogramming of $1,259,000 from the Taxicab Commission and the Department of Motor Vehicles to the Department of Public Works Disapproval Resolution of 2001”, was approved effective May 1, 2001.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Resolutions</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Allocation of Funds from the Rainy Day Fund to the Washington Convention Center Fund and the Starplex Fund Conditional Approval Resolution of 1994: Pursuant to Resolution 10-453, effective November 1, 1994, the Council conditionally approved the transfer of funds from the Rainy Day Fund to the Washington Convention Center Fund and the Starplex Fund.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of Reprogramming from Governmental Direction and Support Agencies to the Department of Administrative Services Emergency Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Resolution 11-82, effective June 6, 1995, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the reprogramming, within the Congressionally-approved Fiscal Year 1995 appropriation for Governmental Direction and Support, of $2.9 million from the Offices of the City Administrator, Secretary, Communications, Intergovernmental Relations, Deputy Mayor for Finance and Budget, the Department of Finance and Revenue, within the Department of Administrative Services, and the Board of Elections and Ethics, to the Department of Administrative Services.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
