<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-355.02</num>
  <heading>Limitations on expenditures and obligating amounts.</heading>
  <text>A District agency head, deputy agency head, agency fiscal officer, agency budget director, agency controller, manager, or other employee may not:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Make or authorize an expenditure or obligation exceeding an amount available in an appropriation for an agency, fund, or capital project;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Obligate the District for the payment of money before an appropriation is made or before a certification of the availability of funds is made, unless authorized by law; provided, that this paragraph shall not prohibit the acceptance of voluntary services or employment of personal services exceeding that authorized by law during emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Approve a disbursement without appropriate authorization;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Defer recording a transaction incurred in the current fiscal year to a future fiscal year;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Allow an expenditure or obligation to exceed apportioned amounts;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Fail to submit a required plan or projection in a timely manner;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Knowingly report incorrectly on spending to date or on projected total annual spending;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Fail to adhere to a spending plan through overspending that is greater than 5% of the agency’s budget, or $1 million, regardless of the percentage; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Make or authorize an expenditure or obligation for one capital project from another capital project.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-285" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-285, § 2, 50 DCR 940</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-293" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-293, § 2(a), 54 DCR 1083</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 1102(b), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-355.06">47-355.06</cite> and § <cite path="§47-355.07">47-355.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-293">D.C. Law 16-293</cite> rewrote the section, which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“A District agency head, deputy agency head, agency chief financial officer, agency budget director, agency controller, manager, or other employee may not:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) Make or authorize an expenditure or obligation exceeding an amount available in an appropriation or fund;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) Involve the District in a contract or obligation for the payment of money before an appropriation is made unless authorized by law;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) Approve a disbursement without appropriate authorization; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(4) Defer recording a transaction incurred in the current fiscal year to a future fiscal year.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> substituted “agency, fund, or capital project” for “agency or fund” in (1); added “provided, that this paragraph shall not prohibit the acceptance of voluntary services or employment of personal services exceeding that authorized by law during emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property” in (2); added (9); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1102(b) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1102(b) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Orders">Allocation of Spending (FY 2010), see Mayor’s Order 2010-24, February 5, 2010 ( 57 DCR 1276).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
