<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-368.06</num>
  <heading>Limitation on grant-making authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An agency with grant-making authority shall not issue grants using any funds it receives through an intra-District transfer, a memorandum of understanding, or a reprogramming from any agency that does not have grant-making authority.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, an agency with grant-making authority may issue grants using any funds it receives through an intra-District transfer, a memorandum of understanding, or a reprogramming from an agency that does not have grant-making authority for purposes of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Effectuating the Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Amendment Act of 2009, passed on 4th reading on September 22, 2009 (Enrolled version of Bill 18-203) [Subtitle N of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, which added § <cite path="§31-3514.02">31-3514.02</cite>(d)]; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Implementing projects and programs funded by the Nursing Facility Quality of Care Fund, established by § <cite path="§47-1262">47-1262</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 1121(b), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-328.02">1-328.02</cite> and § <cite path="§1-328.05">1-328.05</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-120">D.C. Law 18-120</cite> provided clarification of the fiscal year 2010 limited grant-making authority.</annotation>
      <annotation>Sections 2 through 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-138">D.C. Law 18-138</cite> provided limitations on the Mayor’s grant-making authority, including limitations on Executive agencies and independent Executive branch agencies.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1121(b) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1121(b) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 2 to 4 of Executive Grant-Making Authority Limitation Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-280, January 13, 2010,  57 DCR 945).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 7063 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title: Section 1120 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle M of title I of the act may be cited as the “Grant-Making Authority Act of 2009”.</text>
      <text>Short title: Section 7061 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle G of title VII of the act may be cited as the “FY 2011 Capital Projects Modification Act of 2010”.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>The Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Amendment Act of 2009, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is subtitle N of title V of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, §§ 5130, 5131, which amended § <cite path="§31-3514.02">31-3514.02</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 7063 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided: “Sec. 7063. Grant-making authority for Ft. Lincoln and Lincoln Theater capital projects.</text>
      <text>“The Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development shall have grant-making authority for the purpose of providing funds to implement capital projects for the Ft. Lincoln and the Lincoln Theater capital projects.”</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
