<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-335.02</num>
  <heading>Borrowing limitation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council shall not approve proposed District Bonds if the applicable annual Debt Service on the proposed District Bonds would cause the Debt Service on all District Bonds in the fiscal year in which the proposed District Bonds are issued, or in any of the 5 succeeding fiscal years, to exceed 12% of Total Expenditures in any applicable fiscal year, as contained in the most recently enacted District Budget and Financial Plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Obligations incurred pursuant to the authority contained in subchapter II of Chapter 3 of Title 3, obligations incurred by the agencies transferred or established by sections 201 or 202 of the Home Rule Act [§ 1-202.01 or § 1-202.02], whether incurred before or after such transfer or establishment, and obligations incurred pursuant to District Bonds issued prior to October 1, 1996, for the financing of Department of Public Works, Water and Sewer Utility Administration capital projects shall not be included in determining the aggregate amount of Debt Service on all outstanding District Bonds subject to the 12% limitation specified in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The 12% limitation specified in subsection (a) of this section shall be calculated by the Office of the Chief Financial Officer as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Determine the dollar amount equivalent to 12% of the Total Expenditures during the fiscal year for which the proposed District Bonds will be issued and the 5 succeeding fiscal years;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Determine the actual total amount of Debt Service to be paid during the fiscal year for which the proposed District Bonds will be issued and the 5 succeeding fiscal years for all outstanding District Bonds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Determine the amount of Debt Service to be paid during the fiscal year for which the proposed District Bonds will be issued and the 5 succeeding fiscal years; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If in any applicable fiscal year the sum of paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection exceeds the amount determined under paragraph (1) of this subsection, then the proposed District Bonds or Treasury loan shall not be issued.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-360" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-360, § 2(c), 56 DCR 1200</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 7211(b), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 752(b), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> substituted “5 succeeding fiscal years” for “3 succeeding fiscal years”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Limitation on Borrowing and Establishment of the Operating Cash Reserve Technical Amendment Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-174, August 3, 2009,  56 DCR 6639).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7081(b) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-187, August 26, 2009,  56 DCR 7374).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7211(b) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7211(b) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 752(b) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
