<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-369.01</num>
  <heading>General Fund surplus.</heading>
  <text>Beginning in fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, the amount appropriated to the District of Columbia may be increased by no more than $100,000,000 from funds identified in the annual comprehensive annual financial report as the District’s immediately preceding fiscal year’s unexpended general fund surplus. The District may obligate and expend these amounts only in accordance with the following conditions:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia shall certify that the use of any such amounts is not anticipated to have a negative impact on the District’s long-term financial, fiscal, and economic vitality.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia may only use these funds for the following expenditures:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>One-time expenditures.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Expenditures to avoid deficit spending.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Debt Reduction.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Program needs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Expenditures to avoid revenue shortfalls.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The amounts shall be obligated and expended in accordance with laws enacted by the Council in support of each such obligation or expenditure.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The amounts may not be used to fund the agencies of the District of Columbia government under court ordered receivership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The amounts may not be obligated or expended unless the Mayor notifies the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate not fewer than 30 days in advance of the obligation or expenditure.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 111-8" type="History">Mar. 11, 2009, 123 Stat. 698, Pub. L. 111-8, § 816</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 301, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) FY 2013 Revised Budget Request adjustment, see § 2 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Revised Budget Request Temporary Adjustment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-14">D.C. Law 20-14</cite>, September 19, 2013,  60 DCR 9554, 20 DCSTAT 1764).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) FY 2013 Revised Budget Request adjustment, see § 2 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Revised Budget Request Emergency Adjustment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-74, May 23, 2013,  60 DCR 7592, 20 DCSTAT 1424).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 301 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
