<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-4614</num>
  <heading>East of the river hospital tax exemptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The transfer of Lots 3 and 4, Square 5919, transferred to Specialty Hospitals of Washington-GSE Holdings, LLC, or certain of its subsidiary entities, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by ยง <cite root="42-1103">42-1103</cite> and ยง <cite root="47-903">47-903</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The real property, including land and improvements, designated for tax purposes as Lots 3 and 4, Square 5919, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title; provided, that the exemption shall commence on the date that Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiary entities, acquires the property and terminates on the earlier to occur of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The date that the Mayor certifies to the District of Columbia Treasurer that Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiaries, or any party that subsequently acquires the property or any part thereof by purchase, lease, or exchange, fails to comply with the terms of an agreement between Specialty Hospital of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiaries, and Greater Southeast Investment, L.P., to pay an amount equal to the real property taxes that the owner of the property would be obligated to pay on the property, or any part thereof, in the absence of this section; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The date that the Mayor certifies to the District of Columbia Treasurer that the acquisition loan in the maximum principal amount of $29 million by Greater Southeast Investment, L.P., to Capitol Medical Center, LLC, and CMC Realty, LLC, has been paid in full.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-186">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-186, ยง 3(b), 55 DCR 6113</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
