<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4106</num>
  <heading>Fraud and false statements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who willfully makes and subscribes, delivers, or discloses a return, statement, list, account, or other document required under this title, or under regulations made under authority thereof, which he or she does not believe to be true and correct as to every material matter, shall, in addition to other penalties provided by law, be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both, together with costs of prosecution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who willfully aids or assists in, procures, counsels, or advises the preparation or presentation under, or in connection with, a matter arising under this title, or under regulations made under authority thereof, of a return, affidavit, claim, list, account, or other document, which is fraudulent or is false as to any material matter, whether or not the falsity or fraud is with the knowledge or consent of the person authorized or required to present the return, affidavit, claim, list, account, or document, shall, in addition to other penalties provided by law, be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both, together with costs of prosecution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person who willfully makes and subscribes, delivers, or discloses a return, statement, list, account, or other document required under this title, or under regulations made under authority thereof, which he or she does not believe to be true and correct as to every matter, shall, in addition to other penalties provided by law, be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than $3,000, or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both, together with costs of prosecution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person who willfully aids or assists in, procures, counsels, or advises the preparation or presentation under, or in connection with, any matter arising under this title, or under regulations made under authority thereof, of a return, affidavit, claim, list, account, or other document, which is fraudulent or is false as to any matter, whether or not the falsity or fraud is with the knowledge or consent of the person authorized or required to present the return, affidavit, claim, list, account, or document, shall, in addition to other penalties provided by law, be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than $3,000, or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both, together with costs of prosecution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>All prosecutions under this section shall be brought in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia on information by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia in the name of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The fines set forth in this section shall not be limited by [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-204" type="History">Oct. 4, 2000, D.C. Law 13-204, § 2(b), 47 DCR 5799</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-310" type="History">June 12, 2003, D.C. Law 14-310, § 11(c), 50 DCR 1092</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 73(n)(6), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 113(d)(2), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-801">16-801</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-310">D.C. Law 14-310</cite>, in subsec. (c), deleted “material” preceding “matter”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> substituted “Attorney General for the District of Columbia” for “Corporation Counsel”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> added (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 113(d)(2) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
