<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4639</num>
  <heading>King Towers residential housing rental project; Lot 49, Square 281.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>As of August 13, 2010, the real property described as Lot 49, Square 281, owned by King Housing, LLC, or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by King Housing, LLC, shall be exempt from taxation under Chapter 8 of this title so long as the real property continues to be owned by King Housing, LLC., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by King Housing, LLC, or continues to be under applicable use restrictions during a federal low-income housing tax credit compliance period or any other federal program governing income and use restrictions at the property, and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The conveyance of the real property to King Housing, LLC, to or an entity controlled directly or indirectly by King Housing, LLC, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by §§ <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite> and <cite path="§47-903">47-903</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The exemptions provided in this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to either the real property or its owner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Council orders that all economic interest transfer tax, penalties, interest, fees, and other related charges assessed against the real property as described in this section be forgiven, and that any payments already made be refunded.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-237" type="History">Oct. 15, 2010, D.C. Law 18-237, § 2(b), 57 DCR 7162</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-153" type="History">July 13, 2012, D.C. Law 19-153, § 2, 59 DCR 5138</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-153">D.C. Law 19-153</cite> rewrote the section, which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“The real property described as Lot 49, Square 281, owned by King Housing, LLC., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by King Housing, LLC., shall be exempt from taxation under Chapter 8 of this title so long as the real property continues to be owned by King Housing, LLC., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by King Housing, LLC., or continues to be under applicable use restrictions during a federal low-income housing tax credit compliance period or any other federal program governing income and use restrictions at the property, and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of King Towers Residential Housing Real Property Tax Exemption Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-453, June 28, 2010,  57 DCR 5671).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-153">D.C. Law 19-153</cite>, § 3, see § 7006 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-153">D.C. Law 19-153</cite>, § 3, see § 7006 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 7001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-153">D.C. Law 19-153</cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7006 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-153">D.C. Law 19-153</cite>, § 3.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
