<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-4650</num>
  <heading>International House of Pancakes Restaurant #3221 Tax Exemption Clarification.</heading>
  <text>The real property described as Lot 819, in Square 5912, known as the International House of Pancakes Restaurant #3221, owned by CHR, LLC, and leased to Fathers and Sons, LLC, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title for the period beginning October 1, 2007, and ending September 7, 2009. The tax exemption pursuant to this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to the International House of Pancakes Restaurant located at the real property described as Lot 819, Square 5912.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 732(b), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-169">D.C. Law 18-169</cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“§ <cite path="§47-4631">47-4631</cite>. International House of Pancakes Restaurant #3221-tax exemption clarification.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“The real property, described as Lot 819, Square 5912, known as the International House of Pancakes Restaurant #3221, owned by CHR, LLC, and leased to Fathers and Sons, LLC (’Property’), shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title for the period beginning October 1, 2007, and ending September 7, 2009, in accordance with § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(23), notwithstanding the requirements of § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(23)(B)(iv). The tax exemption pursuant to this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to the International House of Pancakes Restaurant located on the Property.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-169">D.C. Law 18-169</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of IHOP Restaurant #3221 Tax Exemption Clarification Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-343, March 22, 2010,  57 DCR 2854).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§47-4650">47-4650</cite>, see § 732(b) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 731 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> provided that subtitle D of title VII of the act may be cited as “IHOP Restaurant #3221 Tax Exemption Clarification Act of 2010”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 7010 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> repealed section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-169">D.C. Law 18-169</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
