<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4211</num>
  <heading>Imposition of accuracy-related penalty.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Negligence” means a failure to make a reasonable attempt to comply with the provisions of this title or to exercise ordinary and reasonable care in the preparation of a tax return without the intent to defraud. A position with respect to an item is attributable to negligence if it lacks a reasonable basis. Negligence is indicated where:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The taxpayer fails to include on an income tax return an amount of income shown on an information return;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The taxpayer fails to make a reasonable attempt to ascertain the correctness of a deduction, credit, or exclusion on a return; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The taxpayer fails to keep adequate books and records or to substantiate items properly.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Gross valuation misstatement” means the reporting on any return for a tax imposed by this title of the value of a property or the adjusted basis of a property which is greater than or equal to 400%, or less than or equal to 25%, of the amount determined to be the correct amount of the valuation or adjusted basis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>“Substantial understatement of income tax” means, for a taxable year, an understatement made by taxpayer in filing an individual or estate tax return if the amount of the understatement for the taxable year exceeds the greater of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Ten percent of the tax required to be shown on the return for the taxable year; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>$2,000.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of a taxpayer other than an individual or estate, subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall be applied by substituting “$4,000” for “$2,000”.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>For purposes of this section, the term “understatement” means the excess of the amount of tax required to be shown on a return less the tax shown on the return.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The amount of the understatement under sub-subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be reduced by the portion of the understatement which is attributable to:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>The tax treatment of an item by the taxpayer if there is or was substantial authority for the treatment; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>An item if:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(aa)</num>
              <text>The relevant facts affecting the item’s tax treatment are adequately disclosed in a statement attached to the return; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(bb)</num>
              <text>There is a reasonable basis for the tax treatment of the item by the taxpayer.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Substantial valuation misstatement” means the reporting on any return for a tax imposed by this title of the value of a property or the adjusted basis of a property which is greater than or equal to 200%, or less than or equal to 50%, of the amount determined to be the correct amount of the valuation or adjusted basis.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There shall be added to a tax imposed by this title an amount equal to 20% of the portion of an underpayment which is attributable to one or more of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Negligence;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A substantial understatement of income tax; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A substantial valuation misstatement.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>There shall be added to the tax imposed by this title an amount equal to 40% of the portion of an underpayment which is attributable to a gross valuation misstatement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b) of this section shall not apply to the portion of an underpayment on which a penalty is imposed under § <cite path="§47-4212">47-4212</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No penalty shall be imposed under subsection (b) of this section by reason of a substantial valuation misstatement or a gross valuation misstatement unless the portion of the underpayment for the taxable year attributable to the substantial valuation misstatement exceeds $5,000 ($10,000 in the case of a corporation).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 403(b), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 11(xx), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(ggg) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(ggg) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(fff) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(ggg) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(ggg) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</cite>, in subsec. (a)(2), substituted “greater than or equal to 400%, or less than or equal to 25%, of” for “400% or more greater or less than”; and in subsec. (a)(4), substituted “greater than or equal to 200%, or less than or equal to 50%, of” for “200% or more greater or less than”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-2763">47-2763</cite> and § <cite path="§47-4221">47-4221</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
