<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4304</num>
  <heading>Limitations on credit or refund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A credit or refund of an overpayment of a tax imposed by this title shall not be allowed unless the taxpayer files a claim within the later of 3 years from the due date of the return or 3 years from the date that the tax was paid.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If, before the expiration of the period of limitation prescribed in subsection (a) of this section, both the Mayor and the taxpayer have consented in writing, the period of limitation may be extended. The period may be extended further by subsequent agreement in writing made before the expiration of the extended period.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the amount of taxable income for a taxable year (or portion of a taxable year) of a taxpayer as reported by the taxpayer, or his duly authorized agent, to the United States Department of the Treasury for federal income tax purposes is changed or corrected by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, by a court of the United States, or by a court of the District of Columbia, or if the amount of taxable income for a taxable year (or portion of a taxable year) of a taxpayer as reported by the taxpayer, or his duly authorized agent, to the District of Columbia for District of Columbia income or franchise tax purposes is changed or corrected by a court of the United States or the District of Columbia, a claim for credit or refund shall not be allowed unless the taxpayer files a claim for refund or credit with respect to the correction or change in the amount of taxable income within 180 days after the date that the change or correction is made or ordered.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the case of an individual, the running of the period of limitation specified in subsection (a) of this section shall be suspended during any period that the individual is financially disabled.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, an individual is “financially disabled” if the individual’s ability to receive and evaluate information effectively or to communicate decisions is impaired to such an extent that he or she lacks the capacity to manage some or all of his or her financial resources. An individual shall not be treated as financially disabled during any period that the individual’s spouse, domestic partner, or another person may act on behalf of the individual in financial matters.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, there shall be no period of limitations if the taxpayer filed an application for a real property tax exemption on or before the date of recordation of the deed and paid the recordation tax.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “domestic partner” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§32-701">32-701</cite>(3).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 404(b), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 11(ccc), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 41(p), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</cite> added subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite>, in subsec. (d)(2), substituted “spouse, domestic partner,” for “spouse”; and added subsec. (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see 12(lll) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see 12(lll) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(kkk) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(lll) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(lll) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
