<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4801</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Administrative costs” means the costs of the Department to administer, manage, and monitor the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Program, including personnel costs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the Department of Housing and Community Development, or its successor agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Developer” means a person or entity that proposes to cause the construction of affordable housing using tax credits provided under the District of Columbia’s Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Director” means the Director of the Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“District of Columbia low-income housing tax credit” means the tax credit established by <cite path="§47-4802">§ 47-4802</cite> pursuant to the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Program” means the program authorized by section 42 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 22, 1986 (100 Stat. 2085; 26 U.S.C. § 42) (“1986 Internal Revenue Code”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Pilot period” means the initial year of the credit program established under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Qualified project” means a rental housing development that receives an allocation of federal Low-Income Housing Tax Credits from the Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“User fee” means a fee charged by the Department to a developer in connection with the District of Columbia's Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Program, including application, reservation, allocation, and monitoring fees.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7142(b), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the ABLE Program Trust Establishment Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-161, Oct. 19, 2015,  62 DCR 13725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this chapter, see § 7142 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this chapter, see § 7142 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this chapter, see § 7152 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
