<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-4310</num>
  <heading>Summons authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of ascertaining the correctness of a return; making a return where none has been made; determining the liability of a person or real property for a tax imposed under this title; determining the liability at law or in equity of a transferee or fiduciary of a person for a tax under this title; collecting tax; or inquiring into an offense connected with the administration or enforcement of a law, the Mayor may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Summon any person to appear and produce all books, records, or other data which may be relevant or material to the inquiry;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Summon any person to give testimony under oath as may be relevant or material to the inquiry;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Summon any person to answer interrogatories under oath as may be relevant or material to the inquiry; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Administer oaths to a person summoned.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A summons under this section shall be served by the Mayor or by a member of the Metropolitan Police Department in the same manner as a subpoena issued by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may report to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia the failure of a person to obey a summons.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court of the District of Columbia may compel obedience of a summons under this section to the same extent as witnesses may be compelled to obey the subpoenas of the Court.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 404(b), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 11(ddd), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-875">47-875</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “liability of a person or real property” for “liability of a person”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see 12(mmm) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see 12(mmm) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(lll) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(mmm) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(mmm) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <annotation>Delegation of Authority Pursuant to  D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. § <cite path="§47-4310">47-4310</cite> to the Director of the Office of Tax and Revenue, see Mayor’s Order 2001-162, November 2, 2001 ( 48 DCR 10785).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
