<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4620</num>
  <heading>St. Martin’s Apartments project tax exemptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Affordable rental housing project” means a housing development in which units are rented to households with not more than 60% of area median income (adjusted for household size) as such amount of area median income is determined by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development when they qualify for admission and for a rent not to exceed the rent ceiling for each unit size, as determined by the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency in accordance with the Federal Low Income Housing Tax Credit regulations.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Developer Owner” means St. Martin’s Apartments, LP, and its successors, affiliates, and assigns.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Developer Sponsor” means C.C.S. Housing, Inc., its successors, affiliates, and assigns.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“St. Martin’s Apartments project” means the acquisition, rehabilitation, and equipping, including the financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of costs incurred, of an affordable housing project located on the land in St. Martin’s Parish located on Lot 116, Square 3531 and leased from the Roman Catholic Archdiocese of Washington or Roman Catholic Archbishop of Washington property, consisting of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A building containing 178 units of rental housing on the St. Martin’s Apartments property; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Other ancillary improvements, including the parking facility included within the building and any cellular tower or cellular equipment on or in the building.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>“St. Martin’s Apartments property” means the real property, including any improvements thereon, located on Lot 116, Square 3531.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The following conveyances with respect to the St. Martin’s Apartments project or property shall be exempt from the tax imposed by §§ <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite> and <cite path="§47-903">47-903</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any conveyances to the Developer Sponsor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any conveyances from the Developer Sponsor to an entity that operates the St. Martin’s Apartments project or property as an affordable rental housing project.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The St. Martin’s Apartments property shall be exempt from all property tax so long as the property is operated as an affordable rental housing project, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite> as if the exemption were granted administratively.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The St. Martin’s Apartments project and the St. Martin’s Apartments property shall be exempt from any public space permit fees imposed by § <cite path="§47-2718">47-2718</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The exemptions pursuant to subsections (c) and (d) of this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to the St. Martin’s Apartments project or the St. Martin’s Apartments property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>This section shall not prevent or restrict the Developer Sponsor or Developer Owner from utilizing any other tax, development, or other economic incentives available to the St. Martin’s Apartments project or the St. Martin’s Apartments property.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-355" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-355, § 2, 56 DCR 1159</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 127, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-355">D.C. Law 17-355</cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Applicability; refund. This act shall apply, upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as of August 4, 2008; provided, that if St. Martin’s Apartments, LP has paid any of the fees or taxes referred to in section 2, the fees or taxes shall be refunded.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7025 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> repealed section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-355">D.C. Law 17-355</cite>.</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-355">D.C. Law 17-355</cite>, see § 7025 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-355">D.C. Law 17-355</cite>, see § 7025 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of St. Martin’s Apartments Tax Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-541, October 20, 2008,  55 DCR 11423).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(b) of St. Martin Apartments Tax Exemption Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-491, August 4, 208,  55 DCR 9164).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-255">D.C. Law 17-255</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(f) This section shall not prevent or restrict the Developer Sponsor from utilizing any other tax, development, or other economic incentives available to the St. Martin Apartments project or the St. Martin Apartments property.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The exemptions pursuant to subsections (c) and (d) of this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to the St. Martin Apartments project or the St. Martin Apartments property.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The St. Martin Apartments project shall be exempt from any public space permit fees imposed by § <cite path="§47-2718">47-2718</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The St. Martin Apartments property shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title so long as the property is operated as an affordable rental housing project, subject to the provisions of D.C. Official Code §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>, as if the exemption were granted administratively.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Any conveyances from the Developer Sponsor to an entity that operates the St. Martin Apartments project as an affordable rental housing project.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Any conveyances to the Developer Sponsor; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The following conveyances with respect to the St. Martin Apartments project shall be exempt from the tax imposed by §§ <cite path="§42-1103">42-1103</cite> and <cite path="§47-903">47-903</cite>:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) ‘St. Martin Apartments property’ means the real property, including any improvements thereon, located in Lots 114 and 115, Square 3531.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Other ancillary improvements.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) A building containing 178 units of rental housing on the St. Martin Apartments property; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) ‘St. Martin Apartments project’ means the acquisition, rehabilitation, and equipping, including the financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of costs incurred therefore, of an affordable housing project, located on the St. Martin Parish of the Roman Catholic Archdiocese of Washington property, consisting of:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) ‘Developer Sponsor’ means St. Martin Apartments LP, its successors, affiliates, and assigns.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) ‘Affordable rental housing project’ means a housing development in which units are rented to elderly households with not more than 60% of area median income (adjusted for household size) for a rent not exceeding 30% of 60% area median income of such household, as such amount of area median income is determined by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) For the purposes of this section, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-255">D.C. Law 17-255</cite> added a section to read as follows: “§ <cite path="§47-4616">47-4616</cite>. St. Martin Apartments project-tax exemptions.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
