<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4212</num>
  <heading>Imposition of fraud penalty.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a portion of an underpayment of tax required to be shown on a return is attributable to fraud, there shall be added to the tax imposed by this title an amount equal to 75% of the portion of the underpayment which is attributable to fraud.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor establishes that a portion of an underpayment is attributable to fraud, the entire underpayment shall be deemed to be attributable to fraud, except with respect to any portion of the underpayment which the taxpayer establishes, by a preponderance of the evidence, is not attributable to fraud.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In the case of a joint return, this section shall not apply with respect to a spouse (including a domestic partner who files under § <cite path="§47-1805.01">47-1805.01</cite>(f)) unless a portion of the underpayment is attributable to the fraud of the spouse (including a domestic partner who files under § <cite path="§47-1805.01">47-1805.01</cite>(f)).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Fraud is indicated where a taxpayer willfully:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fails to pay a tax imposed by this title; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Attempts to evade or defeat in any way the tax or the payment thereof.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 403(b), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-292" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-292, § 2(f), 54 DCR 1080</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 168(b), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-4211">47-4211</cite> and § <cite path="§47-4478">47-4478</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-292">D.C. Law 16-292</cite> substituted “spouse (including a domestic partner who files under § <cite path="§47-1805.01">47-1805.01</cite>(f))” for “spouse”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
