<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-4633</num>
  <heading>Jubilee Housing residential rental project; Lot 863 in Square 2560, and Lot 873, Square 2563.</heading>
  <text>The real properties described as Lot 863 in Square 2560, and Lot 873, Square 2563, owned by Jubilee Housing Inc., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by Jubilee Housing Inc., including Jubilee Housing Limited Partnership II, shall be exempt from taxation under Chapter 8 of this title so long as the real properties continue to be owned by Jubilee Housing Inc., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by Jubilee Housing Inc., or continue to be under applicable use restrictions during a federal low-income housing tax credit compliance period, and are not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite> and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-163" type="History">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-163, § 2(b), 57 DCR 3032</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-158" type="History">July 13, 2012, D.C. Law 19-158, § 2(b), 59 DCR 5689</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-158">D.C. Law 19-158</cite>, in the section heading, substituted “rental project; Lot 863 in Square 2560, and Lot 873, Square 2563.” for “rental project; Lots 107 and 108, Square 2560, and Lot 863, Square 2560.”; substituted “described as Lot 863 in Square 2560, and Lot 873, Square 2563, owned by Jubilee Housing Inc.,” for “described as Lots 107 and 108, Square 2560, and Lot 863, Square 2560, owned by Jubilee Housing Inc.,”; and substituted “provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite> and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.” for “provisions of § <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, 47-1007, and 47-1009.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-73">D.C. Law 19-73</cite>, in the section heading, substituted “rental project; Lots 107 and 108, now known as Lot 863 in Square 2560, and Lot 873, Square 2563” for “rental project; Lots 107 and 108, Square 2560, and Lot 863, Square 2560”; substituted “described as Lots 107 and 108, now known as Lot 863 in Square 2560, and Lot 873, Square 2563, owned by Jubilee Housing Inc.,” for “described as Lots 107 and 108, Square 2560, and Lot 863, Square 2560, owned by Jubilee Housing Inc.,”; and substituted “provisions of §§ <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>” for “provisions of § <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, 47-1007, and 47-1009”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-73">D.C. Law 19-73</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-163">D.C. Law 18-163</cite>, see § 7008 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Jubilee Housing Residential Rental Project Real Property Tax Exemption Clarification Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-205, October 17, 2011,  58 DCR 9326).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Jubilee Housing Residential Rental Project Real Property Tax Exemption Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-295, January 20, 2012,  59 DCR 489).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-163">D.C. Law 18-163</cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7008 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> repealed section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-163">D.C. Law 18-163</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-158">D.C. Law 19-158</cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Applicability. Section 2(a) and (b) shall apply as of October 1, 2010.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
