<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4646</num>
  <heading>NCBA Housing Development Corporation of the District of Columbia and Samuel J. Simmons NCBA Estates No. 1 Limited Partnership; Lot 78, Square 2855.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The real property, described as Lot 78, Square 2855 (“real property”), which will be transferred from NCBA Housing Development Corporation of the District of Columbia, a District of Columbia nonprofit corporation, to Samuel J. Simmons NCBA Estates No. 1 Limited Partnership, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title so long as the real property is owned by Samuel J. Simmons NCBA Estates No. 1 Limited Partnership, or its successors and assigns, and is used to provide housing for low-income and moderate-income elderly District residents.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The exemption under subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to the provisions of §§  <cite path="§47-1005">47-1005</cite>, <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>, and <cite path="§47-1009">47-1009</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The conveyance of the real property from NCBA Housing Development Corporation of the District of Columbia to Samuel J. Simmons NCBA Estates No. 1 Limited Partnership shall be exempt from the tax imposed by §  42-1103 and §  47-903.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-311" type="History">Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-311, § 2(b), 57 DCR 12396</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-311">D.C. Law 18-311</cite>, see § 7003 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-311">D.C. Law 18-311</cite>, see § 7003 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Sections 3 and 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-311">D.C. Law 18-311</cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 3. Sunset. This act shall expire 360 months after its effective date.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 4. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-311">D.C. Law 18-311</cite>, § 4, was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite>, § 7003.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
