<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4104</num>
  <heading>Fraudulent statements or failure to make statements to employee.</heading>
  <text>A person required under this title, or under regulations made under authority thereof, to furnish a statement or supply information to an employee, who willfully furnishes a false or fraudulent statement or false or fraudulent information, or who willfully fails to furnish a statement or supply information to an employee in the manner and at the time prescribed under this title, or under regulations made under authority thereof, shall, in addition to other penalties provided by law, be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>], or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both, together with costs of prosecution. All prosecutions under this section shall be brought in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia on information by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia in the name of the District.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-204" type="History">Oct. 4, 2000, D.C. Law 13-204, § 2(b), 47 DCR 5799</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 73(n)(4), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 286(ee), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§16-801">16-801</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> substituted “Attorney General for the District of Columbia” for “Corporation Counsel”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>]” for “not more than $3,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 286(ee) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
