<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4618</num>
  <heading>Eckington One Residential Project tax exemptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Developer” means NoMa West Residential I, LLC, its successors, affiliates, and assigns.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Eckington One Residential Project” means the acquisition, development, construction, installation, and equipping, including the financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of costs incurred, of the mixed-use, multi-family residential and ground-floor retail project located on the Eckington One Residential Property, consisting of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Approximately 600 units of residential condominium/apartment house use totaling approximately 560,000 square feet of floor area and housed in 3 buildings, including approximately 48 units of affordable housing;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Approximately 1,000 square feet of ground-floor retail space;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Below-grade parking garages; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Other ancillary improvements, including extension of Q Street, N.E., from Eckington Place to Harry Thomas Way.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Eckington One Residential Property” means the real property, including any improvements constructed thereon, located in Lots 816, 817, 818, 819, and 820, Square 3576 (or as the land for such lots may be subdivided into a record lot or lots or assessment and taxation lots, condominium lots, air rights lots, or any combination in the future).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title on the Eckington One Residential Property shall be abated as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In tax year 2010, taxes in excess of 107% of the taxes paid for tax year 2009;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In tax year 2011, taxes in excess of 113.96% of the taxes paid for tax year 2009; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>In tax year 2012 and each year thereafter, taxes in excess of 121.25% of the taxes paid for tax year 2009.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The real property tax abatement granted by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall only apply for the 10 consecutive real property tax years beginning in the tax year in which the developer begins development on the Eckington One Residential Property. The developer shall notify the Director of the Real Property Tax Administration of the Office of Tax and Revenue by certified mail that development has started within 30 days of the commencement of development.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The real property tax abatements granted by paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall not exceed, in the aggregate, $5 million, plus 6% per year of the unused amount of the real property tax abatement from the commencement of development.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The abatement pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to the Eckington One Residential Project or the Eckington One Residential Property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section shall not:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Prevent or restrict the developer from utilizing any other tax, development, or other economic incentives available to the Eckington One Residential Project or the Eckington One Residential Property; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Limit the owner of the Eckington One Residential Property from appealing or contesting its real estate tax assessment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-348" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-348, § 2, 56 DCR 971</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 125, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-348">D.C. Law 17-348</cite> provided that this act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7030 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> repealed section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-348">D.C. Law 17-348</cite>.</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-348">D.C. Law 17-348</cite>, see § 7030 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-348">D.C. Law 17-348</cite>, see § 7030 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
