<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-503</num>
  <heading>Disposition of excess money; collection of federal revenue; submission of budget estimates.</heading>
  <text>If, for any fiscal year, the District of Columbia should raise and deposit in the Treasury to its credit, more money derived from taxation, privileges, and other sources authorized in this chapter than may be necessary for the purposes therein, such excess shall be available the succeeding year, in the discretion of the Council of the District of Columbia, either for the purpose of meeting the expense chargeable to the District of Columbia and/or for the further purpose of enabling the Council to fix a lower rate of taxation for the year following the one in which said excess accrued than it might otherwise be able to do; and the agencies through which the District of Columbia collects its revenue derived from taxation shall also collect for the United States any revenues which by § <cite path="§47-502">47-502</cite> become the sole property of the United States, and said revenues shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as “miscellaneous receipts”; and the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall not be restricted in submitting to the Office of Management and Budget his estimates of the needs of the District, but he shall, as near as may be, bring them within the probable aggregate of the fixed proportionate appropriations to be paid by the United States and the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 29, 1922, 42 Stat. 669, ch. 249</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-503.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-503.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(364) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
