<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-705</num>
  <heading>System to be used outside City — Numbering of blocks, squares, lots, or parcels.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and directed to cause to be given numbers to all of said blocks or squares, lots or parcels of land as said blocks, squares, lots, or parcels of land have been formed by the highway extension plan, of record on February 23, 1905, in the Office of Surveyor of the District of Columbia, and subdivisions existing on February 23, 1905, and to place the numbers so given upon the said highway extension plan; provided, that in all cases where 2 or more blocks or parts of contiguous existing subdivisions are surrounded as a group by existing streets or roads, or by proposed streets of the highway extension plan, such group shall be numbered as a block or square upon the recorded plats of the highway extension plan; provided further, that where lots are numbered in duplicate in any block or square which includes parts of 2 or more existing subdivisions, new lot numbers shall be given said lots numbered in duplicate, and new lot numbers shall also be given to all parts of lots remaining after the extension of streets or alleys by dedication, condemnation, or purchase, whereby parts of lots have become public property; provided further, that new lot numbers shall also be given to all parts of original and subdivided lots existing on February 23, 1905, on the records of the Assessor and the Surveyor of the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 23, 1905, 33 Stat. 737, ch. 735, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-705.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-405.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
