<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-830</num>
  <heading>New buildings; complaints and appeals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any owner aggrieved by any supplemental assessment, made in accordance with <cite path="§47-829">§ 47-829</cite>, may appeal from the assessment to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>September 30 for a supplemental assessment conducted between January 1 and June 30; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>March 31 for a supplement assessment conducted between July 1 and December 31.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia shall hear an appeal of the supplemental assessment if the appeal is filed by the prescribed due date and shall make a final determination of the appeal no later than October 15 of the same calendar year for a supplemental assessment conducted between January 1 and June 30, and by April 15 of the next calendar year for a supplemental assessment conducted between July 1 and December 31.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any owner aggrieved by any supplemental assessment, made in accordance with <cite path="§47-829">§ 47-829</cite>, may appeal from the assessment to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia within 6 months after April 15 following the year in which the assessment is made, in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in §§ <cite path="§47-3303">47-3303</cite> and <cite path="§47-3304">47-3304</cite> for a supplemental assessment conducted between January 1 and June 30, if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An appeal of the supplemental assessment has been filed with the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia by September 30; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Mayor failed to provide notice to the affected owner, as required by <cite path="§47-829|(f)|(2)">§ 47-829(f)(2)</cite>, by September 1 of the year in which the supplemental assessment was conducted; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any owner aggrieved by any supplemental assessment, made in accordance with <cite path="§47-829">§ 47-829</cite>, may appeal from the assessment to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia within 6 months after the April 15th following the year in which the assessment is made, in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in §§ <cite path="§47-3303">47-3303</cite> and <cite path="§47-3304">47-3304</cite> for a supplemental assessment conducted between July 1 and December 31, if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An appeal of the supplemental assessment has been filed with the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia by March 31; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Mayor failed to provide notice to the affected owner, as required by <cite path="§47-829|(f)|(2)">§ 47-829(f)(2)</cite>, by the March 1st following the year in which the supplemental assessment was conducted.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <text>Beginning with the real property assessments for Tax Year 1999 and for each tax year thereafter:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An owner may petition for an administrative review of a supplemental assessment conducted between January 1 and June 30 in accordance with <cite path="§47-829">§ 47-829</cite> on or before October 1 following the date of the notice of supplemental assessment.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An owner may petition for an administrative review of a supplemental assessment conducted between July 1 and December 31 in accordance with <cite path="§47-829">§ 47-829</cite>, or on or before April 1 following the date of the notice of supplemental assessment.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The petition for an administrative review shall be made in writing on a form and in a manner as the Mayor may prescribe.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any owner aggrieved by a final determination made on an administrative review may appeal the supplemental assessment to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia within 45 days from the date of a notice of a final determination on an administrative review. The Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia shall hear an appeal of the supplemental assessment only if a request for an administrative review was timely filed with the Mayor. All notices of final determination shall be accompanied by assessor’s worksheets indicating the rationale for the determination, if the assessment is raised or lowered.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>No administrative review shall be required before an owner may appeal to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia a supplemental assessment conducted between January 1 and June 30 if:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The Mayor fails to notify the owner of the supplemental assessment on or before September 1; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The Mayor fails to notify the owner of a final determination on an administrative review of the supplemental assessment on or before December 30 following the date of the notice of supplemental assessment.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Under the circumstance described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the owner may appeal the supplemental assessment to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia on or before February 1 without first petitioning for an administrative review of the supplemental assessment.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>No administrative review shall be required before an owner may appeal to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia a supplemental assessment conducted between July 1 and December 31 if:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The Mayor fails to provide notice of the supplemental assessment on or before March 1; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The Mayor fails to notify the owner of a final determination on an administrative review of the supplemental assessment on or before June 30.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Under the circumstances described in subparagraph (D) of this paragraph, the owner may appeal the supplemental assessment to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia on or before August 1 without first petitioning for an administrative review of the supplemental assessment.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An owner may appeal from either a supplemental assessment conducted between January 1 and June 30 or a supplemental assessment conducted between July 1 and December 31 on or before December 31st of the year following the year in which the supplemental assessment was conducted in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in §§ <cite path="§47-3303">47-3303</cite> and <cite path="§47-3304">47-3304</cite>. An appeal from the supplemental assessment filed with the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia shall be a prerequisite to filing an appeal with the Superior Court of the District of Columbia; provided, that written notice of the supplemental assessment was given to the taxpayer before December 2 for a supplemental assessment conducted between January 1 and June 30 and before May 31 of the following year for a supplemental assessment conducted between July 1 and December 31.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Repealed.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="§47-829">§ 47-829</cite> and this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Improvement” means a building or other relatively permanent structure or development located on or attached to real property.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Construction in progress” means the on-site work done in the building or the alteration of an improvement, whether a new improvement, an addition, or a renovation, including, but not limited to, the assembly and installation of components and equipment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Conversion” means a change in use of real property or a change in the type of ownership of residential real property that results in a change of residential use. A conversion includes, but is not limited to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A change in use from a residential, commercial, office, hotel or motel, industrial, or other type of real property to a residential, commercial, office, hotel or motel, industrial or other type of real property, regardless of whether the change in use results in a reclassification of the real property; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A change in the type of ownership of residential real property that results in a change in residential use of the real property from a rental housing accommodation, a condominium, or cooperative housing association to a rental housing accommodation, a condominium, or a cooperative housing association.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of paragraph (3) of this subsection, the term “housing accommodation” has the same meaning as that term has in <cite path="§42-3501.03|(14)">§ 42-3501.03(14)</cite>; and the terms “condominium” and “cooperative housing association” have the same meaning as the terms have in <cite path="§47-813|(d)">§ 47-813(d)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the definition of owner and taxpayer in <cite path="§47-802|(5)">§ 47-802(5)</cite> to include persons other than the owner of record of real property, the owner of record of real property shall retain the right to appeal an assessment under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 17, 1937, 50 Stat. 693, ch. 690, title IX, § 5(c)</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 16, 1938, 52 Stat. 372, ch. 223, § 8</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 26, 1939, 53 Stat. 1109, ch. 367, title IV, § 5(b)</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 10, 1952, 66 Stat. 545, ch. 649, § 3(c)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 580, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 161(a)(5)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-14" type="History">June 22, 1983, D.C. Law 5-14, § 703, 30 DCR 2632</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-207" type="History">Mar. 6, 1991, D.C. Law 8-207, § 2(b), 37 DCR 8453</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-241" type="History">Mar. 17, 1993, D.C. Law 9-241, § 6, 40 DCR 629</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-127" type="History">June 14, 1994, D.C. Law 10-127, § 4(a), 41 DCR 2050</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-40" type="History">Oct. 23, 1997, D.C. Law 12-40, § 101(f), 44 DCR 4859</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 502(t), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 33(g), 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-307" type="History">June 5, 2003, D.C. Law 14-307, § 1303(d), 49 DCR 11664</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 73(b)(4), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-159" type="History">Sept. 19, 2006, D.C. Law 16-159, § 2(d), 53 DCR 5385</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-363" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-363, § 3(g)(7), 58 DCR 963</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 136(b), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority under <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-207">D.C. Law 8-207</cite>, the Real Property Improvements and New Construction Tax Amendment Act of 1990, see Mayor’s Order 93-66, May 25, 1993.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority under Law 5-14, see Mayor’s Order 83-190, July 25, 1983.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 1303(d) and 1304 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 1303(d) and 1304 of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 1303(d) and 1304 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2(g), 3 of Real Property Tax Assessment Transition Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-116, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7659).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2(g), 3 of Real Property Tax Assessment Transition Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-44, April 18, 2001,  48 DCR 3844).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(s) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Real Property Tax Assessment Transition Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-23">D.C. Law 14-23</cite>, September 6, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 9093).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(q) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> made a technical correction to <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-363">D.C. Law 18-363</cite> which did not affect this section as codified.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-363">D.C. Law 18-363</cite>, in subsecs. (a), (b), (c)(1)(A), and (c)(2)(A), substituted “Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia” for “Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals”; in subsec. (c-1)(2)(A), substituted “Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia” for “Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals (’Board’)”; and, in subsecs. (c-1)(2), (B), (C), (D), and (E), and (3), substituted “Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia” for “Board”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-159">D.C. Law 16-159</cite>, in subsec. (c-1)(2)(A), substituted “45” for “30”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite>, in subsec. (c-1)(2)(A), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</cite>, in subsec. (c-1)(2)(A), substituted “rationale for determination, if the assessment is raised or lowered” for “any determination”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite> validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(B) A real property owner may appeal from the supplemental assessment conducted between July 1 and December 31 in accordance with subsection (b) of this section to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia within 6 months from April 15 following the year in which the assessment is made in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in 47-3303 and 47-3304. An appeal from the supplemental assessment filed with the Board shall be a prerequisite to filing an appeal with the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3)(A) A real property owner may appeal from a supplemental assessment conducted between January 1 and June 30 in accordance with subsection (b) of this section to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia within 6 months from October 15 following the year in which the assessment is made in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in 47-3303 and 47-3304. An appeal from the supplemental assessment filed with the Board shall be a prerequisite to filing an appeal with the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Prior to amendment, subsec. (c-1)(3) read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> substituted “owner” for “real property owner” and “any real property owner” wherever they appear; in subsec. (c-1), inserted the last sentence in par. (2)(A) and rewrote par. (3); and added subsec. (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-711.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-830.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§47-820">§ 47-820</cite>, <cite path="§47-825.01a">§ 47-825.01a</cite>, and <cite path="§47-829">§ 47-829</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Superior Court Tax Division, appeals of real estate assessments, see <cite path="§47-3305">§ 47-3305</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall appoint the members of the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia with the advice and consent of the Council in accordance with the provisions of section 2(b)(3).”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) Sections 2 and 3 shall apply upon Council approval and appointment by the Mayor of a full-time Chairperson and a full-time Vice Chairperson to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-363">D.C. Law 18-363</cite>: Section 3a of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-363">D.C. Law 18-363</cite>, as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-155">D.C. Law 19-155</cite>, § 4, provided: “Sec. 3a. Applicability; transition.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Expiration and review of title I of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite>: Section 2003 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite> repealed the expiration provision of section 105(b) and the review provision of section 105(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Review of title I provisions after 3 years: Section 105(a) of title I of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite> provided that after 3 years, the Committee on Finance and Revenue shall review the provisions of this title and make recommendations for their continuance, amendment, or termination.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Audit of triennial assessment process: Section 103 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite> provided that at the end of the first triennial assessment cycle, an audit of the assessment process shall be conducted by an outside firm, under the auspices of the International Association of Assessing Officers, for the purposes of examining the methodology, procedures, and accuracy of real property assessments under the triennial assessment process. The results of the audit shall be provided to the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 104 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite> provided that the Mayor may promulgate rules necessary for the implementation of this title.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Expiration of title I of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite>: Section 105(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite> provided that title I of that act shall expire 4 years from its effective date. <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite> became effective on October 23, 1997.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-207">D.C. Law 8-207</cite> provided that the Mayor shall, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, issue proposed rules to implement the provisions of this act. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 60-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 60-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved. Nothing in this section shall affect any requirements imposed upon the Mayor by <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 1102 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-14">D.C. Law 5-14</cite> provided that the Mayor shall issue rules necessary to carry out the provisions of the act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 14-307: Section 1304 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</cite> provided: “Sections 1302 and 1303 shall apply as of October 1, 2002.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
