<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-845</num>
  <heading>Tax deferral — Amount.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An eligible taxpayer may defer each year any real property tax owed in excess of 110% of his or her immediately preceding year’s real property tax liability for Class 1 Property as defined in § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>(c)(1). To be eligible for such deferral the taxpayer must:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Have owned for at least 1 year the property for which the deferral is claimed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Certify that such property is currently occupied by the taxpayer and that such property was occupied by the taxpayer for the 12 month period immediately preceding the application for deferral; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>File a written application for deferral on a form provided by the Mayor. An application for real property tax deferral shall be filed with the Mayor before the last date an installment payment of the real property taxes which are to be deferred is due.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>— (7) Repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a taxpayer submits a timely application for deferral of real property taxes, the amount of real property tax owed in excess of 110% of the prior year’s tax bill shall not constitute delinquent taxes nor shall the taxpayer be assessed any interest for the period said application is pending. A taxpayer shall be eligible to start deferring portions of the increased property tax liability immediately after his or her application has been approved by the Mayor. If the application for deferral is disapproved, the taxpayer shall be notified, in writing, of said disapproval and the reasons therefor and granted an additional 30 days to pay said taxes without interest.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Taxes deferred under this section shall bear simple interest at the rate of ½% per month or portion of a month until paid.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No further deferrals of real property tax shall be granted to a taxpayer when the aggregate amount of the deferred real property tax plus interest from previous tax years, under this section, § <cite path="§47-845.02">47-845.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-845.03">47-845.03</cite>, is equal to or greater than 25% of the assessed value of the real property for the tax year for which the deferral is requested.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Taxes deferred under this section, together with all accumulated interest, shall constitute a preferential lien upon the real property which shall be immediately payable by the seller, transferor, or conveyor whenever the real property is sold, refinanced, transferred, or conveyed in any manner, or whenever additional co-owners (other than spouse or domestic partner) are added to the real property; except, that whenever such real property is sold, transferred, or conveyed to the mother, father, spouse, domestic partner, children by blood or legally adopted children of the seller, transferor, or conveyor, the deferred taxes lien, if not satisfied, shall remain in full force and effect.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-407" type="History">Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1058, Pub. L. 93-407, title IV, § 435</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-119" type="History">Oct. 13, 1978, D.C. Law 2-119, § 3, 25 DCR 1514</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-128" type="History">July 24, 1982, D.C. Law 4-128, § 2, 29 DCR 2401</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct, 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 1143(c), 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 41(b), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 7036(a), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Real property tax sales, see § <cite path="§47-1301">47-1301</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Tax on residents and nonresidents, property tax credit, “property taxes accrued” defined, see § <cite path="§47-1806.06">47-1806.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-405">47-405</cite>, § <cite path="§47-845.02">47-845.02</cite>, § <cite path="§47-845.03">47-845.03</cite>, § <cite path="§47-862">47-862</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-1806.06">47-1806.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-845.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-655.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite>, rewrote subsec. (d), which had read as follows: “(d) No further deferrals of real property tax shall be granted to a taxpayer when the aggregate amount of the deferred tax plus interest equals 25% of the assessed value of the property for the tax year for which the deferral is requested.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite>, in subsec. (e), substituted “(other than spouse or domestic partner)” for “(other than spouse)” and “spouse or domestic partner” for “husband, wife”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “simple interest at the rate of 1/2% per month or portion of a month until paid” for “interest at the rate of 8% per annum” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(r)(1) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-179">D.C. Law 20-179</cite>, March 7, 2015,  62 DCR 424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 1143(c), 1144 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7052(a)(1) of the Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, and amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7052(a), see § 2(m) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014,  61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7052(a)(1) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, and amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7052(a), see § 2(m) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7016(v)(1) and (y)(2) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 1144 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite> provided that §§ 1142 and 1143 shall apply to tax periods beginning after September 30, 2005.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite>: Section 7048(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> provided that §§ 7027, 7031, 7036, and 7037 of the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
