<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-848</num>
  <heading>Sale of tax delinquent property — Transference of ownership.</heading>
  <text>The Council is hereby authorized to establish a program whereby title to properties acquired by tax sale pursuant to §§ <cite path="§47-847">47-847</cite> and <cite path="§47-1303">47-1303</cite> may, for whatever consideration or sum it deems appropriate, be transferred to persons, nonprofit organizations or nonprofit developers, meeting criteria which shall be established by the Council, and who:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Guarantee to pay taxes on the property;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Live in the property for at least 5 years (for residential property owners), or maintain active ownership and legal possession of the property for at least 10 years and provide needed community services in the District for at least 10 years (for nonprofit organizations or developers); and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Give assurance of bringing the property into reasonable compliance with the building code in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-407" type="History">Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1059, Pub. L. 93-407, title IV, § 438</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-11" type="History">June 11, 1999, D.C. Law 13-11, § 3(b), 46 DCR 5487</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-310" type="History">June 12, 2003, D.C. Law 14-310, § 14(b), 50 DCR 1092</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Financial institutions, application to conduct business, loan policies and homestead development programs, see § <cite path="§26-704">26-704</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Savings and loan association acquisitions, applications, loan policies and homestead development programs, see § <cite path="§26-1204">26-1204</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§26-704">26-704</cite> and § <cite path="§26-1204">26-1204</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-848.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-658.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-11">D.C. Law 13-11</cite> provided alternatively to living on the property for 5 years that one “maintain active ownership and legal possession of the property for at least 10 years and provide needed community services in the District for at least 10 years (for nonprofit organizations or developers).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-310">D.C. Law 14-310</cite>, in the introductory paragraph, substituted “§§ <cite path="§47-847">47-847</cite> and <cite path="§47-1303">47-1303</cite>” for “§ <cite path="§47-847">47-847</cite>”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 3(d)(1) and 6(b) of the Redevelopment Land Agency Disposition Review Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-524, January 11, 2001,  48 DCR 624).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
