<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-881</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Chief Financial Officer” or “CFO” means the Chief Financial Officer of the District established by § <cite path="§47-317.01">47-317.01</cite>(a) [see now § <cite path="§1-204.24a">1-204.24a</cite>].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“General Obligation Bonds” means the District of Columbia general obligation bonds issued, or to be issued, by the District, of which net proceeds in the amount of $25 million shall be paid to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority to be used to pay costs of the New York Avenue Metro Project.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“New York Avenue Metro Project” means the acquisition, construction, and equipping of a new Metrorail station to be located in the vicinity of New York and Florida Avenues, N.E., Washington, D.C.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“New York Avenue Metrorail Benefit Area” or “MBA” means the special assessment district established under § <cite path="§47-882">47-882</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“New York Avenue Metrorail Benefit Area Account” means the account established under § <cite path="§47-884">47-884</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Special Assessment Annual Collection Amount” means the amount established under § <cite path="§47-883">47-883</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Special Assessment Factor” means the Special Collection Amount divided by the aggregate assessed value of real property subject to this subchapter, as determined and adjusted under § <cite path="§47-883">47-883</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Special Assessment Total Collection Amount” means the aggregate amount of collections under this subchapter established under § <cite path="§47-883">47-883</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Tax lot” means a tax lot as shown on the real property tax records of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-44" type="History">Oct. 26, 2001, D.C. Law 14-44, § 2, 48 DCR 7665</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of New York Avenue Metro Special Assessment Authorization Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-115, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7652).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of New York Avenue Metro Special Assessment Authorization Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-64, June 6, 2001,  48 DCR 5714).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of New York Avenue Metro Special Assessment Authorization Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-25">D.C. Law 14-25</cite>, October 2, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 9564).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
