<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-823</num>
  <heading>Assessments — Preliminary roll; public inspections and copying of material; sales ratio studies; listing of assessed values.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall compile the estimated assessment roll and, for every property, indicate at least the following: the name of the owner; address of the property; lot and square; assessed value; and whether the property is taxable or exempt.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The roll shall also include the total aggregate estimated assessed value of all real property, listing the values of the properties by class as set forth in § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall transmit to the Council, no later than May 15 of each fiscal year, a mid-year financial report. The report shall contain:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Schedules which reflect actual obligations for the General Fund object classes of the District government for the first 6 months of the fiscal and a forecast of full-year obligations compared to the most recent Congressionally-approved budget;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A comparison of the most recent Congressionally-approved budget to the mid-year forecast for the full fiscal year by appropriations title and agency; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A schedule of revenue estimates for the full fiscal year comparing the current approved revenue estimates to revenue estimates revised as of the end of the first 6 months of the fiscal year.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The estimated assessment roll, together with all maps, field books, assessment-sales ratio studies, surveys, and plats, shall be open to public inspection during normal business hours. In addition, any notes and memorandums relating to the assessment of his real property, or a statement clearly indicating the basis upon which his real property has been assessed, shall be open to inspection by the owner or his designated representative during normal business hours. Provision shall be made to furnish copies of all material to any person, upon request, at the lowest charge which covers cost of making such copies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall undertake, publish, and otherwise publicize the results of assessment-sales ratio studies for different types of real property for the entire District and for different types of real property within each of the districts utilized in making assessments. If, for a given year, adequate sales data are lacking for particular studies, the Mayor shall so indicate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall, either himself or in a newspaper of general circulation, publish a listing of the assessed value of each property by address, lot, and square, and he shall also make such listing available at the main Public Library in the District and at such other points as he may determine. Such publication can be by neighborhood areas so long as maps showing the assessment areas are generally available.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The estimated assessment roll, sales price information, description of each property, owner’s mailing address, property use information, valuation history, other information in the public record, and information not made confidential in this chapter may be published by the Mayor by any form of electronic media, including the Internet.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-407" type="History">Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1054, Pub. L. 93-407, title IV, § 424</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-113" type="History">Sept. 26, 1984, D.C. Law 5-113, § 803, 31 DCR 3974</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-160" type="History">Sept. 20, 1990, D.C. Law 8-160, § 2(c), 37 DCR 4653</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-241" type="History">Mar. 17, 1993, D.C. Law 9-241, § 2(b), 40 DCR 629</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-127" type="History">June 14, 1994, D.C. Law 10-127, § 5(d), 41 DCR 2050</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 502(p), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-824">47-824</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-823.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-644.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-350">D.C. Law 13-350</cite> rewrote subsec. (a); in subsec. (b), substituted “estimated” for “preliminary” in the first sentence and substituted “owner” for “taxpayer” in the second sentence; and added subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a)(1) The Mayor shall, on or before February 15 of each year, compile in tabular form and place in a book, known as the preliminary assessment roll, the name of the owner, address, lot and square, amount, description, and value, as of January 1 of that year, of the land and improvements of all real property whether such property is taxable or exempt.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) Such roll shall also include the total aggregate preliminary assessed value of all taxable real property listing the values of such properties by class as set forth in § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>(c-1), (c-2), and (c-3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) The Mayor shall transmit to the Council, no later than May 15 of each fiscal year, a mid-year financial report. The report shall contain:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(A) Schedules which reflect actual obligations for the general fund object classes of the government for the first 6 months and a forecast of full-year obligations compared against the most recent Congressionally approved budget;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(B) A comparison of the most recent Congressionally approved budget against a mid-year forecast for the full fiscal year by appropriations title and agency; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(C) A schedule of revenue estimates for the full fiscal year comparing the current approved revenue estimates to revenue estimates revised as of the end of the first 6 months of the fiscal year.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(m) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(p) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 901 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-113">D.C. Law 5-113</cite> provided that the Mayor shall issue rules to implement the provisions of the act pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
