<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-815</num>
  <heading>Submission of estimated assessment roll.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before September 16th of each year, the Mayor shall estimate the assessment roll and submit the estimate to the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-2)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-3)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-4)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>If the Council establishes the real property tax rates and real property special tax rates as a sum under § <cite path="§47-812">47-812</cite>, the Chief Financial Officer shall determine and publish in the District of Columbia Register before September 16th of each preceding tax year the real property special tax rates to be applied, during the tax year, to the classes of real property set forth in § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>For the real property tax year beginning July 1, 1989, and ending June 30, 1990, and for each tax year thereafter, the tax liability resulting from applying the rates established in § <cite path="§47-812">47-812</cite>, to qualified real property approved pursuant to § <cite path="§6-1503">6-1503</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Shall be reduced by 80% in the first tax year beginning after the date of issuance of the certificate of occupancy for the qualified real property; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shall be reduced by 64%, 48%, 32%, and 16% in the second, third, fourth, and fifth tax years, respectively, beginning after the issuance of the certificate of occupancy for the qualified real property.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-407" type="History">Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1052, Pub. L. 93-407, title IV, § 413</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-635" type="History">Jan. 3, 1975, 88 Stat. 2176, Pub. L. 93-635, § 6(a)(1), (b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-70" type="History">June 15, 1976, D.C. Law 1-70, title III, §§ 302(b), 305, 23 DCR 539</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-130" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-130, § 3(b), 25 DCR 2517</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-37" type="History">Nov. 20, 1979, D.C. Law 3-37, § 2(c), 26 DCR 1564</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-14" type="History">June 22, 1983, D.C. Law 5-14, § 602, 30 DCR 2632</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-177" type="History">Oct. 20, 1988, D.C. Law 7-177, § 6(a), 35 DCR 6158</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-160" type="History">Sept. 20, 1990, D.C. Law 8-160,§ 2(b), 37 DCR 4653</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-241" type="History">Mar. 17, 1993, D.C. Law 9-241, § 2(a), 40 DCR 629</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-115" type="History">Apr. 30, 1994, D.C. Law 10-115, § 201, 41 DCR 1216</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-127" type="History">June 14, 1994, D.C. Law 10-127, § 5(b), 41 DCR 2050</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 104-134" type="History">Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 132 211, Pub. L. 104-134, § 135(2)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-143" type="History">June 13, 1996, D.C. Law 11-143, § 6, 43 DCR 2170</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-223" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-223, § 2(a), 44 DCR 111</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-40" type="History">Oct. 23, 1997, D.C. Law 12-40, § 101(b), 44 DCR 4859</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 502(g), (h), (i), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 2002(c), 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Economic development zones, available incentives, see § <cite path="§6-1503">6-1503</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§6-1503">6-1503</cite> and § <cite path="§47-816">47-816</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-815.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-633.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> rewrote the section heading and the section which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“§ <cite path="§47-815">47-815</cite>. Submission and publication of proposed rates and certain assessed values.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) Except as provided in subsection (a-4) of this section, on or before the third Friday in August of each year, the Mayor shall publish in the District of Columbia Register proposed real property tax rates to be applied, during the tax year, to the classes of real property set forth in § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>. The Mayor shall certify the assessment roll and calculate the proposed rates pursuant to § <cite path="§47-825.01">47-825.01</cite>(h). On or before September 15th of each year, the Mayor shall submit to the Council these same rates.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a-1) Repealed .</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a-2) Repealed .</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a-3) Notwithstanding the first sentence of subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall publish in the District of Columbia Register the proposed 1997 real property tax rates by the third Friday following the date the 1997 real property assessment roll is certified.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a-4) Beginning with real property assessments for Tax Year 1999, and for each tax year thereafter, the Mayor shall estimate the assessment roll on or before September 15th of each year.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b) At the time the Mayor publishes in the District of Columbia Register the proposed real property tax rates under subsection (a) of this section, he or she shall also submit the following:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) The total aggregate assessed value of taxable real property for the year preceding the tax year for which the rates are being recommended, listing the values of such properties by class as set forth in § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>(c-1), (c-2), and (c-3);</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) The estimated total aggregate assessed value of taxable real property for the tax year for which the property tax rates are being recommended, listing the values of such properties by class as set forth in § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>(c-1), (c-2), and (c-3) and indicating separately for each class the estimated value, if any, attributable to new construction; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) The real property tax rates (rounded to the nearest penny) calculated to yield in the tax year the same amount of revenue (exclusive of the revenue attributable to new construction) as was raised by that tax at the rate or rates applicable during the preceding tax year, plus a percentage of such revenue equal to the percentage change between the consumer price index for the first calendar year preceding the tax year and the consumer price index for the 2nd calendar year preceding the tax year. The consumer price index referred to in the preceding sentence shall be the Annual Average Washington, D.C., All-Items Consumer Price Index, For All Urban Consumers, as published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States Department of Labor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) Repealed .</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(d) As soon as possible after the Mayor publishes in the District of Columbia Register the proposed real property tax rates under subsection (a) of this section, he or she shall also publish such proposed real property tax rates and the information submitted pursuant to subsection (b) of this section in at least 1 daily newspaper of general circulation published in the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(e) No later than 4 days (not including Saturdays, Sundays or holidays) after the official release of the consumer price index referred to in subsection (b)(3) of this section, the Mayor shall estimate as closely as possible the rates of taxation for real property pursuant to subsection (b)(3) of this section and shall inform the Council.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(f) For the real property tax year beginning July 1, 1989, and ending June 30, 1990, and for each tax year thereafter, the tax liability resulting from applying the rates established in this section and § <cite path="§47-812">47-812</cite>, to qualified real property approved pursuant to § <cite path="§6-1503">6-1503</cite>:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) Shall be reduced by 80% in the first tax year beginning after the date of issuance of the certificate of occupancy for the qualified real property; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) Shall be reduced by 64%, 48%, 32%, and 16% in the second, third, fourth, and fifth tax years, respectively, beginning after the issuance of the certificate of occupancy for the qualified real property.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite> added subsec. (b-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(h), (i) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001,  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Real Property Tax Assessment Transition Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-23">D.C. Law 14-23</cite>, September 6, 2001,  48 DCR 9093).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g)(2), (h), (i) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Real Property Tax Assessment Transition Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-44, April 18, 2001,  48 DCR 3844).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Real Property Tax Assessment Transition Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-116, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7659).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority under Law 5-14, see Mayor’s Order 83-190, July 25, 1983.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 1102 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-14">D.C. Law 5-14</cite> provided that the Mayor shall issue rules necessary to carry out the provisions of the act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 13 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-177">D.C. Law 7-177</cite> provided that the Mayor shall issue rules to implement the provisions of the act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">See note to § <cite path="§47-813">47-813</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Special tax requirement: <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-115">D.C. Law 5-115</cite> requires the Mayor to certify to the Council the amount required to pay the principal of, and interest on, general obligation bonds coming due for any reason during that real property tax year.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Definitions applicable: The definitions in § <cite path="§47-803">47-803</cite> apply to this section.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Expiration of title I of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite>: Section 105(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite> provided that title I of that act shall expire 4 years from its effective date. <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite> became effective on October 23, 1997.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 104 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite> provided that the Mayor may promulgate rules necessary for the implementation of this title.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Audit of triennial assessment process: Section 103 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite> provided that at the end of the first triennial assessment cycle, an audit of the assessment process shall be conducted by an outside firm, under the auspices of the International Association of Assessing Officers, for the purposes of examining the methodology, procedures, and accuracy of real property assessments under the triennial assessment process. The results of the audit shall be provided to the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Review of title I provisions after 3 years: Section 105(a) of title I of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite> provided that after 3 years, the Committee on Finance and Revenue shall review the provisions of this title and make recommendations for their continuance, amendment, or termination.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Expiration and review of title I of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite>: Section 2003 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite> repealed the expiration provision of section 105(b) and the review provision of section 105(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-40">D.C. Law 12-40</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
