<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-811.02</num>
  <heading>Overpayment; credit or refund; interest.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, if there is a payment of real property tax that results in an overpayment for a billing period or levy with priority, the overpayment shall be credited in order of priority against the real property tax owing on the property for a subsequent billing period or levy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall refund the payment, less the real property tax owing, to the person who made the payment; provided, that the refund shall not be allowed unless:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A claim for refund within 3 years from the date the payment was made;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office of Tax and Revenue has corrected or changed an assessment or real property classification under § <cite path="§47-825.01a">47-825.01a</cite>(f) which created the overpayment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The property has been so reassessed under § <cite path="§47-831">47-831</cite> that an overpayment resulted for the periods of reassessment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The tax was abated for reasonable cause under § <cite path="§47-1007">47-1007</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The refund results from the grant of a real property tax exemption.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A claim for refund shall be made in the manner prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia shall pay interest on the overpayment beginning 90 days after the receipt of the claim for refund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The interest payable by the District under subsection (d) of this section shall be at the rate provided in § <cite path="§47-3310">47-3310</cite>(c).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The owner, after seeking refund of the overpayment as set forth in this section, may, within one year from the last day of the tax year in which the claim for refund was made, file suit in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in §§ <cite path="§47-3303">47-3303</cite> and <cite path="§47-3304">47-3304</cite>; provided, that the real property tax, including any penalties and interest, shall have first been paid.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to an action timely filed under § <cite path="§47-825.01a">47-825.01a</cite>(g) and (h).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 504(a)(2), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 11(f), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-155" type="History">July 13, 2012, D.C. Law 19-155, § 3(a), 59 DCR 5590</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-4630">47-4630</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</law-cite> made nonsubstantive changes to subsecs. (b)(3) and (b)(4); and added subsec. (b)(5).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-155">D.C. Law 19-155</law-cite>, in subsec. (b)(2), substituted “The Office of Tax and Revenue has” for “The Mayor” and “§ <cite path="§47-825.01a">47-825.01a</cite>(f)” for “§ <cite path="§47-825.01">47-825.01</cite>(h-1)”; in subsec. (g), substituted “§ <cite path="§47-825.01a">47-825.01a</cite>(g) and (h)” for “§ <cite path="§47-825.01">47-825.01</cite>(j-1) and (j-2)”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 4(b) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</law-cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(g) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</law-cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(g) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</law-cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 4(a)(2) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(g) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(g) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(g) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
