<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>47-902</num>
  <heading>Enumeration of transfers exempt from tax.</heading>
  <text>The following transfers shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Repealed;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Transfers of property by the United States of America or the District of Columbia governments, unless its taxation has been authorized by Congress;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Transfers of real property by an institution, organization, corporation, or government receiving a valid real property tax exemption for the real property under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite> (or exempt from transfer taxes under a law of the United States of America or the District of Columbia); provided further, that this exemption shall not apply to property which is exempt under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(29) or § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(30);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Repealed;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Transfers between spouses, parent and child, grandparent and grandchild, or domestic partners as defined in § <cite path="§32-701">32-701</cite>(3), without actual consideration therefor;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Transfers evidenced by deeds of release of property which is security for a debt or other obligation;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Transfers which secure a debt or other obligation;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Transfers which, without additional consideration, confirm, correct, modify, or supplement a transfer previously recorded;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Transfers of property to a qualifying lower income homeownership household in accordance with § <cite path="§47-3503">47-3503</cite>(b);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>Transfers of property to a qualifying nonprofit housing organization in accordance with § <cite path="§47-3505">47-3505</cite>(b);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>Transfers of property to a cooperative housing association in accordance with § <cite path="§47-3503">47-3503</cite>(b)(2);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>A transfer of bare legal title into a revocable trust, without actual consideration for the transfer, where the transferor is the current beneficiary of the trust;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>A transfer of property to a named beneficiary of a revocable trust by reason of the death of the grantor of the revocable trust;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>A transfer of property by the trustee of a revocable trust if the transfer would otherwise be exempt under this section if made by the grantor of the revocable trust;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>The transfer of property to a resident management corporation in accordance with § <cite path="§47-3506.01">47-3506.01</cite>;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A transfer of property to an entity in accordance with § <cite path="§29-204.06">29-204.06</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>In order for limited liability companies to receive the exemption provided in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue shall be notified, within 30 days, of any change to the members or interests in profits and losses during the 12-month period following the effective date of the conversion so that the applicable transfer tax can be imposed; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Violation of the provisions of subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall be punishable pursuant to § <cite path="§47-918">47-918</cite> [repealed];</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Transfers with respect to the real property (and any improvements thereon) described as Square 454, Lots 41, 824, 838, 857, 877, 878; the portion of the public alley that reverted to (i) former Lot 820, (which is currently known as Lot 866), and (ii) former Lot 821 (which is currently known as Lot 867) pursuant to the Plat of Alley Closing filed with the Surveyor of the District of Columbia in Liber 17 at folio 74; the portions of the public alley that will revert to Lots 41, 824, 838, 857, 877 and 878, all in Square 454, pursuant to the alley closing approved by the Closing of Public Alleys in Square 454 and Square 455, S.O. 98-194 Act of 1999, effective October 22, 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-48">D.C. Law 13-48</cite>; 46 DCR 6768).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The amount of all taxes, fees, and deposits exempt, abated, or waived under this paragraph, section 2(b) of the Gallery Place Economic Development Amendment Act of 2000, effective April 3, 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-241">D.C. Law 13-241</cite>; 48 DCR 610) [§ <cite path="§2-1217.31">2-1217.31</cite>(b)], and §§ <cite path="§45-922">45-922</cite>(24) [§ <cite path="§42-1102">42-1102</cite>(24)], 47-1002(26), and 47-2005(32) [§ <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>(30)], shall not exceed, in the aggregate, $7 million;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(18)</num>
    <text>Deeds of personal representatives of decedents, acting under the provisions of Title 20, transferring to a distributee, without additional consideration, real property of a decedent or a life estate in real property;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(19)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Transfers with respect to the real property (and any improvements thereon) described as Square 299, Lot 831, in connection with the debt or equity financing for the Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project until the Development Sponsor sells the Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project, as evidenced by the recordation of a deed conveying title to Square 299, Lot 831, at which time such amounts shall be due and payable without penalty or interest.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The amount of all taxes, fees, and deposits deferred under this paragraph, section 2(b) of the Mandarin Oriental Hotel Tax Deferral Act of 2002, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2002 (Enrolled version of Bill 14-466) [<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-232">D.C. Law 14-232</cite>], and §§ <cite path="§42-1102">42-1102</cite>(25), <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(27), and <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>(33) [§ <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>(34)], shall not exceed, in the aggregate, $4 million.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>“Development Sponsor” means Portals Hotel Site, LLC, a Delaware limited liability company, and its successors and assigns.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>“Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project” means the acquisition and initial development, construction, equipping, and furnishing of a Mandarin Oriental hotel within the Portals project, located on Square 299, Lot 831, consisting of a 400-room hotel with approximately 33,000 square feet of associated meeting and banquet space, 2 restaurants, a health spa and fitness center totaling approximately 10,000 square feet, and approximately 90,000 square feet of public parking space for approximately 200 cars.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>“Mandarin TIF Bonds” means the tax increment financing bonds issued in connection with the Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project pursuant to the Tax Increment Revenue Bonds Mandarin Hotel Project Emergency Approval Resolution of 2000, effective March 7, 2000 (Res. 13-510; 47 DCR 2133), and the Mandarin Hotel Project Modification Approval Resolution of 2000, effective December 19, 2000 (Res. 13-745; 48 DCR 83).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>This paragraph shall apply upon the closing of the sale of the Mandarin TIF Bonds;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(20)</num>
    <text>Transfers pursuant to a decree of divorce or of separate maintenance or pursuant to a written instrument incident to such divorce or separation;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(21)</num>
    <text>Transfers by an entity described in paragraph (3) of this section of a lease or ground rent for a term (including renewals) that is at least 30 years;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(22)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Transfers of residential real property, without consideration for the transfer, to the trustee of a special needs trust established for the benefit of a trust beneficiary who has a disability, as defined in section 1614(a)(3) of the Social Security Act, 86 Stat. 1471; 42 U.S.C. § 1382c(a)(3)), or from the trustee of a special needs trust that, by its terms, terminates upon the death of the trust beneficiary with a disability.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, a trust is a special needs trust if the trust instrument:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>States, among its purposes, that the trust assets are not intended to be counted in determining the beneficiary’s eligibility for needs-based governmental benefits; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(I)</num>
          <text>Names the beneficiary with a disability as the sole trust beneficiary during his or her lifetime; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(II)</num>
          <text>Provides that the beneficiary with a disability may not serve as trustee.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(23)</num>
    <text>Transfers of property to a qualifying low- or moderate-income household pursuant to the Inclusionary Zoning Program established by subchapter II-A of Chapter 10 of Title 6.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(24)</num>
    <text>Transfer of real property to the District of Columbia, without consideration for the transfer, at the request of the District of Columbia, and conveyed as a bona fide gift to the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(25)</num>
    <text>Transfers of property to which there is a valid certification by the Mayor that both the property and transferor are eligible for exemption from property taxation pursuant to § <cite path="§47-1005.02">47-1005.02</cite>; provided, that, unless waived by regulation, a copy of the certification shall accompany the deed at the time it is submitted for recordation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(26)</num>
    <text>Transfers of property transferred to a named beneficiary of a revocable transfer on death deed under Subchapter IV of Chapter 6 of Title 19, by reason of the death of the grantor of the revocable transfer on death deed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-92">Sept. 13, 1980, D.C. Law 3-92, § 402, 27 DCR 3390</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-72">Mar. 10, 1982, D.C. Law 4-72, § 2, 28 DCR 5273</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-31">Oct. 8, 1983, D.C. Law 5-31, § 10(a), 30 DCR 3879</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-205">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-205, § 4, 36 DCR 457</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-56">Mar. 7, 1992, D.C. Law 9-56, § 2, 38 DCR 7281</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-120">June 11, 1992, D.C. Law 9-120, § 4(b), 39 DCR 3195</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-38">Sept. 8, 1995, D.C. Law 11-38, § 4(c), 42 DCR 3269</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-241">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-241, § 4(a), 48 DCR 610</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 505(b), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, §§ 33(k), 36(d), 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-232">Mar. 25, 2003, D.C. Law 14-232, § 4(a), 49 DCR 9764</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 11(o), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 38(b)(1), 51 DCR 881</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-176">Sept. 8, 2004, D.C. Law 15-176, § 5, 51 DCR 5707</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-293">Apr. 5, 2005, D.C. Law 15-293, § 13(a), 52 DCR 1465</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 73(c), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, §§ 1213, 1297(b), 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-275">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-275, § 204, 54 DCR 880</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 73(c), 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-118">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-118, § 202(a), 55 DCR 1461</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 41(d), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 7052, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 4(a), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 7153(a), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-141">Dec. 4, 2014, D.C. Law 20-141, § 101(b), 61 DCR 7763</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §§   7102(b), 7104, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Lower income homeownership tax abatement, real property transfer tax exemption, qualifying households and cooperative housing associations, see § <cite path="§47-3503">47-3503</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Lower income homeownership tax abatement, real property transfer tax exemption, qualifying nonprofit housing organizations, see § <cite path="§47-3505">47-3505</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Lower income homeownership tax abatement, real property transfer tax exemption, qualifying resident management corporations, see § <cite path="§47-3506.01">47-3506.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1217.31">2-1217.31</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1217.32">2-1217.32</cite>, § <cite path="§42-1102">42-1102</cite>, § <cite path="§47-903">47-903</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>, § <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>, § <cite path="§47-3503">47-3503</cite>, § <cite path="§47-3505">47-3505</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-3506.01">47-3506.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 47-902.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-241">D.C. Law 13-241</cite>, in par. (15), deleted “and” from the end; in par. (16), substituted “; and” for a semicolon; and added par. (17).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite>, in par. (15), deleted “and” from the end; in par. (16), substituted a semicolon for a period at the end of subpars. (A) to (C); and added par. (18).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite>, in par. (16)(C), made a nonsubstantive change; in par. (17)(B), substituted “§ <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>(32)” for “§ <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>(28)”; and in pars. (16)(B), (17)(B) and (18), validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-232">D.C. Law 14-232</cite> substituted a semicolon for “; and” at the end of par. (17); substituted “; and” for a period at the end of par. (18); and added par. (19).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</cite> repealed par. (1); in par. (2), substituted “governments, unless its taxation has been authorized by Congress;” for “governments;”; rewrote par. (3); repealed par. (4); made nonsubstantive changes in par. (18) and (19); and added pars. (20) and (21).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-176">D.C. Law 15-176</cite>, in par. (5), substituted “parent and child, or domestic partner as defined in § <cite path="§32-701">32-701</cite>(3),” for “or parent and child,”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-293">D.C. Law 15-293</cite>, in par. (3), substituted “District of Columbia); provided further, that this exemption shall not apply to property which is exempt under § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(29);” for “District of Columbia);”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite>, in pars. (16)(C) and (17)(B), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite>, substituted “parent and child, grandparent and grandchild, or domestic partners,” for “or parent and child, or domestic partners”; in par. (20) substituted a semicolon for “; and”; in par. (21), substituted “; and” for a period; and added par. (22).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-275">D.C. Law 16-275</cite> added par. (23).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, in par. (22)(A), substituted “has a disability” for “is disabled”, and “trust beneficiary with a disability” for “disabled trust beneficiary”; and, in par. (22)(B)(ii), substituted “beneficiary with a disability” for “disabled beneficiary”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-118">D.C. Law 17-118</cite>, in par. (3), inserted “or § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(30)”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite>, in par. (5), substituted “spouses” for “husband and wife”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> added par. (24).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “to an entity in accordance with § <cite path="§29-204.06">29-204.06</cite>” for “to a limited liability company in accordance with § <cite path="§29-1013">29-1013</cite>” in (16)(A).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added (25).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite>, repealed before its effective date, would have added (26).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added (26).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 5(b) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4(a) of Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project Tax Deferral Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-143">D.C. Law 14-143</cite>, May 21, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 5060).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(o) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Property Dedication Transfer Tax Exemption Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-220">D.C. Law 14-220</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2733).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(o) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 3(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-76">D.C. Law 17-76</cite> added par. (24) to read as follows: “(24) Transfer of Lots 3 and 4, Square 5919 to Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiary entities.”</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 8(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-76">D.C. Law 17-76</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 104 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-226">D.C. Law 19-226</cite> amended this section by adding a new paragraph (25) to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(25) Transfers of property if the Mayor has certified that the property and purchaser are eligible for exemption from property taxation pursuant to § <cite path="§47-1005.02">47-1005.02</cite>.”</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 402(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-226">D.C. Law 19-226</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(a) of the Gallery Place Economic Development Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-500, January 5, 2001,  48 DCR 562).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5(b) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(a) of Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project Tax Deferral Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-227, January 8, 2002,  49 DCR 682).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(a) of Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project Tax Deferral Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-563, December 23, 2002,  50 DCR 278).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 4(a) and 5 of Mandarin Oriental Hotel Project Tax Deferral Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-345, April 24, 2002,  49 DCR 4300).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(o) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Property Dedication Transfer Tax Exemption Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-421, July 17, 2002,  49 DCR 7416).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(o) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Property Dedication Transfer Exemption Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-412, April 21, 2004,  51 DCR 4682).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(o) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Property Dedication Transfer Tax Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-512, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10473).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 1213, 1297(f), 1298, 1299 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(a) of East of the River Hospital Revitalization Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-168, October 19, 2007,  54 DCR 10978).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(a) of East of the River Hospital Revitalization Tax Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-174, November 2, 2007,  54 DCR 11216).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 202(a) of Arthur Capper/Carrollsburg Public Improvement Revenue Bonds Technical Correction Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-318, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3418).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary addition of (25), see § 104 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-482, October 12, 2012,  59 DCR 12478).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary addition of (25), see § 104 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-604, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1045), applicable as of January 10, 2013.</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary tax exemption for the transfer of Lot 20 in Square 532, located at 441   Street, N.W., to the District of Columbia, see § 2 of the Transfer of Real Property   Street, N.W., to the District of Columbia Transfer Tax Exemption Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-58, April 23, 2013,  60 DCR 6396).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7153 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the District Real Property Tax Sale Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-179, October 4, 2013,  60 DCR 14947.</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7153 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(a)(5) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-342, May 28, 2014,  61 DCR 5691).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(b) of the Residential Real Property Equity and Transparency Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-409, Aug. 1, 2014,  61 DCR 8281).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7112(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(b), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014,  61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7102(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7102(b), see the first § 2(q) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 7151 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle O of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Tax Clarification Amendment Act of 2013”.</text>
      <text>Short title: Section 7051 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle F of title VII of the act may be cited as “Real Property Transfer Tax Exemption Act of 2011”.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
      <annotation>Section 5 of Law 14-232 provided that this act shall take effect subject to the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>Section 2(b) of the Mandarin Oriental Hotel Tax Deferral Act of 2002, passed on 2nd reading on September 17, 2002 (Enrolled version of Bill 14-466), referred to in par. (19)(B), is <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-232">D.C. Law 14-232</cite>, § 2(b), set out as a note under § <cite path="§42-1102">42-1102</cite>.</text>
      <text>Pursuant to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer’s “Notice of Public Interest” published in the April 18, 1997, issue of the District of Columbia Register ( 44 DCR 2345) the Office of Tax and Revenue assumed all of the duties and functions previously performed by the Department of Finance and Revenue, as set forth in Commissioner’s Order 69-96, dated March 7, 1969. This action was made effective January 22, 1997, nunc pro tunc.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 6 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-56">D.C. Law 9-56</cite> provided that the Mayor shall, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, issue rules to implement the provisions of the act.</text>
      <text>Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 9-120">D.C. Law 9-120</cite> provided that the Mayor may issue rules to implement the provisions of the act.</text>
      <text>Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-241">D.C. Law 13-241</cite>, as amended by section 40 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite>, provided:</text>
      <text>“Tax and fee abatements Gallery Place Project .</text>
      <text>“(a) For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
      <text>“(1) ‘Development Sponsor’ means Gallery Place Holdings LLC, a Delaware limited liability company, and its successors and assigns.</text>
      <text>“(2) ‘Gallery Place Project’ means the acquisition, construction, installing, and equipping of a mixed-use complex located on Square 454, Lots 41, 824, 838, 857, 877, 878; the portion of the public alley that reverted to former Lot 820 (which is currently known as Lot 866), and former Lot 821 (which is currently known as Lot 867) pursuant to the Plat of Alley Closing filed with the Surveyor of the District of Columbia in Liber 17 at folio 74; and the portions of the public alley that will revert to Lots 41, 824, 838, 857, 877 and 878, all in Square 454, pursuant to the alley closing approved by the Closing of Public Alleys in Square 454 and Square 455, S.O. 98-194, Act of 1999, effective October 22, 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-48">D.C. Law 13-48</cite>;  46 DCR 6768), and consisting of:</text>
      <text>“(A) An approximately 60,000-square-foot multiplex cinema;</text>
      <text>“(B) A mixed-use facility providing for retail stores, dining, entertainment, a health and fitness club, offices, and related facilities;</text>
      <text>“(C) A market-rate housing complex consisting of approximately 170 residential units;</text>
      <text>“(D) A parking garage containing approximately 850 parking spaces; and</text>
      <text>“(E) Other ancillary improvements.</text>
      <text>“(b) All fees to be paid, and any deposits to be made, by or on behalf of the Development Sponsor in connection with the Gallery Place Project under the eighth unnumbered paragraph of the General Expenses title of An Act Making Appropriations to provide for the expense of the Government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and ten, and for other purposes are hereby waived.</text>
      <text>“(c) The amount of all taxes, fees, and deposits exempt, abated, or waived under subsection (b) of this section, section 302(24) of the District of Columbia Recordation Tax Act and  D.C. Code 47-902(17),  47-1002(26), and  47-2005(32), shall not exceed, in the aggregate, $7 million.</text>
      <text>“(d) In accordance with section 5 of An Act providing a permanent form of government for the District of Columbia the Mayor shall expend up to $2 million to improve and repair the streets, sewers, alleys, sidewalks, curbs, and gutters abutting the Gallery Place Project. All assessments upon abutting property for the cost of improvements to such streets, sewers, alleys, sidewalks, curbs, and gutters, including any expenses of assessment, shall be waived.”</text>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-176">D.C. Law 15-176</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-176">D.C. Law 15-176</cite> provided: “Sections 2 through 6 shall apply as of October 1, 2003.”</text>
      <text>Applicability and expiration of subtitle KK of title I, §§ 1295 to 1300, of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite>: Sections 1298 and 1299, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite>, § 7068(l), (m) provided:</text>
      <text>“Sec. 1298. Conditional applicability.</text>
      <text>(a) Sections 1296 and 1297 shall apply for taxable years beginning after September 30, 2005.</text>
      <text>“(b) Repealed.</text>
      <text>“Sec. 1299. Repealed.”</text>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210. Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 7153(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that § 7153(a) (which added § <cite path="§47-902">47-902</cite>(25)) shall apply as of September 20, 2012.</text>
      <text><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-141">D.C. Law 20-141</cite> became effective on Dec. 4, 2014, but was repealed prior to its effective date by emergency D.C. Act 20-377, § 7114, eff. July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, by emergency D.C. Act 20-449, § 7104, eff. October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, by emergency D.C. Act 20-566, § 7104, eff. January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, and by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7104, 61 DCR 9990.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
