<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>46-358.02</num>
  <heading>Conditions of rendition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before making a demand that the governor of another state surrender an individual charged criminally in the District with having failed to provide for the support of an obligee, the Mayor may require a prosecutor of the District to demonstrate that at least 60 days previously the obligee had initiated proceedings for support pursuant to this chapter or that the proceeding would be of no avail.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If, under this chapter or a law substantially similar to this chapter, the governor of another state makes a demand that the Mayor surrender an individual charged criminally in that state with having failed to provide for the support of a child or other individual to whom a duty of support is owed, the Mayor may require a prosecutor to investigate the demand and report whether a proceeding for support has been initiated or would be effective. If it appears that a proceeding would be effective but has not been initiated, the Mayor may delay honoring the demand for a reasonable time to permit the initiation of a proceeding.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a proceeding for support has been initiated and the individual whose rendition is demanded prevails, the Mayor may decline to honor the demand. If the petitioner prevails and the individual whose rendition is demanded is subject to a support order, the governor may decline to honor the demand if the individual is complying with the support order.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-73" type="History" path="ยง802">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-73, ยง 802, 63 DCR 222</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
