<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="Pub. L. 116-283">
  <num>116-283</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>2021-01-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law">Pub. L. 116-283, § 1103</citation>
    </citations>
  </meta>
  <page citation="134 Stat. 3388"/>
  <section>
    <num>1103</num>
    <heading>PAID PARENTAL LEAVE TECHNICAL CORRECTIONS.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>SHORT TITLE.—This section may be cited as the "Paid Parental Leave Technical Corrections Act of 2020".</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>PAID PARENTAL LEAVE FOR EMPLOYEES OF DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COURTS AND DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA PUBLIC DEFENDER SERVICE.—</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COURTS.—Section 11-1726, District of Columbia Official Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§11-1726"/>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>In carrying out the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (29 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.) with respect to nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia courts, the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration shall, notwithstanding any provision of such Act, establish a paid parental leave program for the leave described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 102(a)(1) of such Act (29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)) (relating to leave provided in connection with the birth of a child or a placement of a child for adoption or foster care). In developing the terms and conditions for this program, the Joint Committee may be guided by the terms and conditions applicable to the provision of paid parental leave for employees of the Federal Government under chapter 63 of title 5, United States Code, and any corresponding regulations.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA PUBLIC DEFENDER SERVICE.—Section 305 of the District of Columbia Court Reform and Criminal Procedure Act of 1970 (section 2-1605, D.C. Official Code) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1605"/>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>In carrying out the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (29 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.) with respect to employees of the Service, the Director shall, notwithstanding any provision of such Act, establish a paid parental leave program for the leave described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 102(a)(1) of such Act (29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)) (relating to leave provided in connection with the birth of a child or the placement of a child for adoption or foster care). In developing the terms and conditions for this program, the Director may be guided by the terms and conditions applicable to the provision of paid parental leave for employees of the Federal Government under chapter 63 of title 5, United States Code, and any corresponding regulations.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
