<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 23-126">
  <num type="law">23-126</num>
  <num type="bill">23-34</num>
  <num type="act">23-302</num>
  <heading type="short">Ivory and Horn Trafficking Prohibition Act of 2020</heading>
  <heading type="long">To prohibit the distribution of a prohibited animal product, including ivory and rhinoceros horn, to exempt certain activities from the prohibition, to provide penalties, and to require the Mayor to issue rules to implement the provisions of this act.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-01-08</introduced>
    <effective>2020-08-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/41624/Signed_Act/B23-0034-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 23-126</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/41623/B23-0034-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 23-302</citation>
      <citation type="register">67 DCR 5060</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0034">
      <vote date="2020-03-03" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2020-04-07" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2020-04-27</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced it prohibits the import, sale, offer for sale, purchase, barter, or possession with intent to sell ivory products and rhinoceros horn products. </summary>
      <committee>Judiciary and Public Safety</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="22" after="18A" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
      <num>18B</num>
      <heading>Ivory and Horn Trafficking.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Ivory and Horn Trafficking Prohibition Act of 2020".</text>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="22|18B" num-value="22-1861"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Definitions.</heading>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="22|18B">this act</code-cite>, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>"Educational or scientific institution" means an entity that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Receives an educational or scientific tax exemption from the federal Internal Revenue Service or the institution's national, state, or local tax authority; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Is accredited as an educational or scientific institution from a qualified national, regional, state, or local authority for the institution's location.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>"Prohibited animal product" means:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>The tooth or tusk composed of ivory, whether raw or worked, from any species of elephant, hippopotamus, mammoth, mastodon, narwhal, or whale;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>The horn of any species of rhinoceros; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>An item that is wholly or partially composed of any material described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of this paragraph.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1861" applicability-path="§6" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="22|18B" num-value="22-1862"/>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Unlawful distribution of a prohibited animal product.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Beginning one year after <span codify:value="[insert applicability date]">the applicability date of this act</span>, a person commits the offense of unlawful distribution of a prohibited animal product if that person knowingly imports, sells, offers for sale, purchases, barters, trades, or possesses with intent to sell a prohibited animal product.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, a person does not commit the offense of unlawful distribution of a prohibited animal product if the person:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Bequeaths the prohibited animal product to the legal beneficiary of an estate or trust upon the death of the owner;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Gifts or donates the prohibited animal product without remuneration;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Is a government employee or agent conducting law enforcement activities pursuant to federal, state, or local law;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Is an educational or scientific institution that imports, sells, offers for sale, purchases, barters, trades, or possesses with intent to sell a prohibited animal product for educational or scientific purposes;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Is engaging in an activity that is expressly authorized by federal law or a permit issued pursuant to federal law;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>Imports, sells, offers for sale, purchases, barters, trades, or possesses with intent to sell a prohibited animal product that is part of an antique that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Is composed of not more than 20% of a prohibited animal product by volume; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>The person can, through documentation, establish provenance and demonstrate that the antique is at least 100 years old; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>Imports, sells, offers for sale, purchases, barters, trades, or possesses with intent to sell a prohibited animal product that is part of a musical instrument that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Is composed of less than 20% of a prohibited animal product by volume; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>The person can establish provenance and demonstrate that the musical instrument was manufactured before 1976.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The act of obtaining an appraisal of a prohibited animal product alone shall not constitute possession with intent to sell or offer for sale.</text>
    </para>
    <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1862" applicability-path="§6" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="22|18B" num-value="22-1863"/>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Penalties.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a person convicted of unlawful distribution of a prohibited animal product shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>For a first offense, be fined no more than $1,000 or twice the value of the prohibited animal product, whichever is greater, incarcerated for no more than 30 days, or both;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>For a second offense, be fined no more than $5,000 or twice the value of the prohibited animal product, whichever is greater, incarcerated for no more than one year, or both; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>For a third or subsequent offense, be fined no more than $25,000 or thrice the value of the prohibited animal product, whichever is greater, incarcerated for no more than 3 years, or both.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For any offense where the total value of the prohibited animal product is greater than $25,000, a person convicted of unlawful distribution of a prohibited animal product shall be fined thrice the value of the prohibited animal product, incarcerated for no more than 3 years, or both.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the person convicted of unlawful distribution of a prohibited animal product is not an individual, the court may double the applicable fine specified in subsection (a) or subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The fines set forth in this section shall not be limited by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-3571.01">section 101 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012, effective June 11, 2013 (D.C. Law 19-317; D.C. Official Code § 22-3571.01)</code-cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1863" applicability-path="§6" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="22|18B" num-value="22-1864"/>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Rules.</heading>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|I">Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>, shall issue rules to implement the provisions of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="22|18B">this act</code-cite>.</text>
    <codify:not-funded-anno doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1864" applicability-path="§6" action="creation of" display-template=""/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="22|18B" num-value="22-1865"/>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="22|18B">This act</code-cite> shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§2" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§3" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§4" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
      <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§5" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="22|18B">this act.</code-cite></text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 60-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(2)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
