<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 23-160">
  <num type="law">23-160</num>
  <num type="bill">23-302</num>
  <num type="act">23-471</num>
  <heading type="short">Big Brown Bat Official State Mammal Designation Act of 2020</heading>
  <heading type="long">To designate the Big Brown Bat as the official state mammal of the District of Columbia.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-05-17</introduced>
    <effective>2020-12-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/42638/Signed_Act/B23-0302-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Law 23-160</citation>
      <citation type="register">67 DCR 13256</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0302">
      <vote date="2020-09-22" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2020-10-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2020-11-02</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced it designates the Little Brown Bat as the official state mammal of the District of Columbia. </summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Big Brown Bat Official State Mammal Designation Act of 2020".</text>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="1|1" after="IV-D" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>IV-E</num>
      <heading>Official State Mammal of the District of Columbia.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="1|1|IV-E" num-value="1-167.31"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Official state mammal of the District of Columbia.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Big Brown Bat (<em>Eptesicus fuscus</em>) is a species of mouse-eared bat found throughout the United States, including the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Bats are the only flying mammals.  The Big Brown Bat can fly up to 40 miles per hour, one of the fastest bats.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Big Brown Bat is considered large for an American bat, and has a wingspan of 12-16 inches and a weight of 14-21 grams.  A big brown bat can live up to 18-20 years in the wild.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Big Brown Bat uses echolocation to forage for insects, preferring to eat beetles with its jaws that can chew through the hard exoskeletons, but also eating a variety of other insects including moths, flies, wasps, and flying ants that they capture in flight.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Big Brown Bat (<em>Eptesicus fuscus</em>) is hereby designated the official state mammal of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
