<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 23-615">
  <num type="bill">23-1020</num>
  <num type="act">23-615</num>
  <heading type="short">UDC PR Harris Exclusive Use Repeal Temporary Amendment Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the University of the District of Columbia Expansion Act of 2010 to limit the University of the District of Columbia's permitted use of the Patricia R. Harris Facility.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2020-11-30</introduced>
    <effective>2021-01-29</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/46070/Signed_Act/B23-1020-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 23-615</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-1020">
      <vote date="2020-12-15" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2020-12-15" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2021-01-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2021-01-29</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "UDC PR Harris Exclusive Use Repeal Temporary Amendment Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 422 of the University of the District of Columbia Expansion Act of 2010, effective April 8, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-370; D.C. Official Code ยง 10-507.01, note) is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>The University of the District of Columbia may maintain a Ward 8 food hub and sufficient office space at the closed Patricia R. Harris Educational Center school building and site ("PR Harris").</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(i)</num>
                <text>"Sufficient office space" means office space sufficient for the purposes of the University of the District of Columbia, as agreed upon by the Mayor and the University of the District of Columbia no later than 45 days after the effective date of the UDC PR Harris Exclusive Use Repeal Emergency Amendment Act, passed on emergency basis on December 15, 2020 (Enrolled version of Bill 23-1019).</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <text>"Ward 8 food hub" means food production and distribution operations similar in scope to those engaged in by the University of the District of Columbia as of the effective date of the UDC PR Harris Exclusive Use Repeal Emergency Amendment Act, passed on emergency basis on December 15, 2020 (Enrolled version of Bill 23-1019), or of a different scope as agreed upon by the Mayor and the University of the District of Columbia no later than 45 days after the effective date of the UDC PR Harris Exclusive Use Repeal Emergency Amendment Act, passed on emergency basis on December 15, 2020 (Enrolled version of Bill 23-1019).</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The District of Columbia shall assume any rights and obligations of the University of the District of Columbia as lessor under any existing lease or leases for PR Harris.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>If the Mayor leases or subleases PR Harris in accordance with An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code ยง 10-801 <em>et. seq</em>), the University of the District of Columbia shall retain the right to maintain a Ward 8 food hub and sufficient space at PR Harris.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b) is repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
