<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 23-84">
  <num type="law">23-84</num>
  <num type="bill">23-130</num>
  <num type="act">23-262</num>
  <heading type="short">Office of Resilience and Recovery Establishment Act of 2020</heading>
  <heading type="long">To establish an Office of Resilience and Recovery within the Office of the City Administrator to develop short- and long-term action plans and strategies that promote adaptation and resilience of the District's economy, communities, infrastructure, and natural resources in response to shocks and chronic stresses, including natural or man-made challenges that threaten the District, monitor the District's resilience readiness, and provide guidance and assistance to District agencies and community organizations to develop and implement resilience measures.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-02-05</introduced>
    <effective>2020-05-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/41817/B23-0130-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Law 23-84</citation>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/41817/B23-0130-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 23-262</citation>
      <citation type="register">67 DCR 3531</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0130">
      <vote date="2020-02-04" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2020-03-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2020-03-23</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced it establishes an Office of Resilience within the City Administrator's Office to develop and report on the implementation of policies, programs and actions with respect to Urban Resilience. Urban Resilience is defined as the capacity of individuals, communities, institutions, businesses, and systems within a system to survive, adapt, and thrive regardless of stresses and shocks encountered.</summary>
      <committee>Committee on Government Operations</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="1|3|I" after="L" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Part</prefix>
      <num>M</num>
      <heading>Office of Resilience and Recovery.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Office of Resilience and Recovery Establishment Act of 2020".</text>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="1|3|I|M" num-value="1-301.201"/>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Establishment of the Office of Resilience and Recovery.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is established an Office of Resilience and Recovery ("ORR") within the Office of the City Administrator. ORR shall develop short- and long-term action plans and strategies to promote the adaptation and resilience of the District's economy, communities, infrastructure, and natural resources in response to shocks and chronic stresses, including natural or man-made challenges that threaten the District, monitor the District's resilience readiness, and provide guidance and assistance to District agencies and community organizations to develop and implement resilience measures.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>ORR shall be headed by a Chief Resilience Officer ("CRO"), appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council pursuant <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-523.01|(a)">to section 2(a) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(a))</code-cite>. The CRO shall be a full-time position, for which annual compensation shall be fixed in accordance with <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="1|6|X-A">Title X-A of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective June 10, 1998 (D.C. Law 12-124; D.C. Official Code § 1-610.51 <em>et seq</em>.)</code-cite>. The CRO shall have such staff as is appropriated in an approved budget and financial plan or provided through federal or private grants.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The CRO shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Lead the District's efforts to build and implement the District's resilience action plans and strategies;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Review and update the District's resilience action plans and strategies, including the Resilient DC initiative, annually;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Provide guidance and assistance to District agencies and community organizations to develop and implement resilience measures;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Publish an annual progress report by October 1 to be submitted to the Mayor and Council that provides an update on the District's progress in the areas of sustainability and resiliency;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Develop and track metrics to measure the District's resilience readiness;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>Develop strategies to build partnerships between the District and the private sector that promote and further the District's resilience readiness, including climate adaption to prevent and recover from natural disasters;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>Respond to recommendations and policy statements from the Commission on Climate Change and Resiliency, established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-181.02">section 3 of the Commission on Climate Change and Resiliency Establishment Act of 2016, effective February 18, 2017 (D.C. Law 21-185; D.C. Official Code § 8-181.02)</code-cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(8)</num>
        <text>Collaborate with other Chief Resilience Officers to achieve common goals, leverage experiences, and share strategies;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(9)</num>
        <text>Develop a communications strategy for the District's resilience efforts, including creating an online campaign to build public awareness of climate adaption and resilience planning; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(10)</num>
        <text>Perform other relevant duties as the Mayor may assign.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="1|3|I|M" num-value="1-301.202"/>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Rules.</heading>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|5|I">Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>, may issue rules to implement the provisions of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="1|3|I|M">this act</code-cite>.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
