<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1103.03</num>
  <heading>Fixed by Council; waiver.</heading>
  <text>Each owner of property abutting public space in which a vault is located shall pay an annual rent fixed from time to time by the Council of the District of Columbia for such vault, but such annual rent shall not be less than $10, and such rent shall be subject to collection from said owner in the manner prescribed by this part, regardless of whether any use is made of such vault, and regardless of the extent of any use; provided, that no rent for any rental year for a vault shall be charged to the owner of abutting property if said owner, prior to July 1st of such year, has notified the Mayor in writing that he has abandoned such vault and has performed such work as may be required by the District in connection with the sealing off or filling of such vault, or both.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-596" type="History" path="§304">Oct. 17, 1968, 82 Stat. 1159, Pub. L. 90-596, title III, § 304</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-910.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-1009.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
