<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1601.31</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this part, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Ballpark”, “Ballpark Site”, and “MLB Team” shall have the same meanings as provided in § <cite path="§10-1601.05">10-1601.05</cite>(a)(1), (2), and (4), respectively.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Bonds” shall have the same meaning as in § <cite path="§10-1601.03">10-1601.03</cite>(a)(2).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Hard costs” means the direct construction costs and builders contingency costs, estimated as $295,075,993 and $24,924,007, respectively, in the revised budget for the ballpark transmitted by the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission to the Council on February 3, 2006, for the construction of the ballpark.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Soft costs” means the soft, ancillary, contingency, completion guarantee fee, and financing fee costs for the construction of the ballpark, excluding the land acquisition, environmental remediation, relocation, and demolition costs, estimated as $117,342,193, and excluding the $24 million utilized for the renovation of RFK Stadium, as reflected in the May 31, 2007 revised budget for the ballpark transmitted by the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission to the Council on June 15, 2007.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-22" type="History">Oct. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-22, § 2, 54 DCR 8006</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Ballpark Hard and Soft Costs Cap and Ballpark Lease Conditional Approval Temporary Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-115">D.C. Law 16-115</cite>, June 9, 2006, law notification  53 DCR 5353).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Ballpark Hard and Soft Costs Cap Temporary Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-1">D.C. Law 17-1</cite>, April 18, 2007, law notification  54 DCR 6580).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Ballpark Hard and Soft Costs Cap and Ballpark Lease Conditional Approval Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-277, February 14, 2006,  53 DCR 1341).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Ballpark Hard and Soft Costs Cap and Ballpark Lease Conditional Approval Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-378, May 19, 2006,  53 DCR 4399).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Ballpark Hard and Soft Costs Cap Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-11, January 26, 2007,  54 DCR 1514).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
