<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1202.02c</num>
  <heading>Transfer of assets, rights, and obligations of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Legal and equitable title to all real property, personal property, records, capital, and intangible assets of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission shall transfer, vest, and be titled in the name of the Authority.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, income, and other funds available to the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission shall transfer to the Authority and shall be deposited in the Sports and Entertainment Fund.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>All lawful existing non-employment and non-employment-related contractual rights and obligations of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission shall transfer to the Authority, which shall assume all rights, duties, liabilities, and obligations as a successor in interest.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the rights of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission under section 8.4 of the Lease Agreement, dated March 6, 2006, between the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission and the Baseball Expos, L.P., as may be amended, shall be assigned 1/2 to the Mayor and 1/2 to the Council.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>No rights and obligations of employment or employment-related contracts of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission, except for lawful rights and obligations of individual employment contracts, shall transfer to the Authority, which shall assume all rights, duties, liabilities, and obligations as a successor in interest.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>All other existing rights and obligations, and all causes of actions of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission shall transfer to the Authority.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No existing lawful contract or other lawful legal obligation of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission transferred pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, shall be abrogated or impaired by the repeal of Chapter 14 of Title 3 [§ <cite path="§3-1401">3-1401</cite> et seq.] or the superceding of Mayor’s Order 79-218, dated September 14, 1979, except for any obligation of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission to the District of Columbia related to personnel expenses.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Other than with respect to the rights and obligations of employment and employment-related contracts of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission not transferred pursuant to subsection (a)(4), nothing in § <cite path="§10-1202.01">10-1202.01</cite> or § <cite path="§10-1202.02">10-1202.02</cite> shall impair the obligations, commitments, pledges, or covenants, or the security made or provided by the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission; provided, that the liability of the Authority with respect to any such obligation, commitment, pledge, covenant, or security made or provided by the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission shall be limited to the assets and property of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission transferred pursuant to this section and any income derived from such assets.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-188" type="History">Sept. 28, 1994, D.C. Law 10-188, § 202c</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">as added Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2081(d), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2081(d) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2081(d) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
